I'm gonna introduce Eleanor and let her
give her a little background she's going
to get into some ethics and genetics and
kind of take it from there but why don't
you say a few things
hi it's really awesome to be in such an
amazing group and get to talk about one
of my most passionate subjects which is
genetics so so just to give you a
background of Who I am I am a population
geneticist my specialty is in the
intersection between agriculture and
wild plants and how those groups talk to
each other so that's what I did in my
dissertation in I'm also a trained
herbalist and I went to herbalism school
not because I like sick people i I went
because I loved those plants and I
really wanted to understand how the
usage of those plants impacts the
populations from which we're drawing in
particular our wild crafted local native
endemic plants I'm from the south so
ginseng goldenseal cohosh a lot of
plants that we all love and use and how
do those plant populations react to our
usage of them so that's a little bit
about where I come from and so with that
background I've done a lot of work in
compliance and best agricultural
practices working for a lot of bigger
natural products companies to look at
how they grow their plants and how those
growing methodologies affect the quality
of those plants and so when I was in
that world it became very clear that the
largest issue in the botanical trade
globally is plant identity so fraud is
rampant everywhere and we see this
within our own community just with a
naming issue right so one of the reasons
we have a naming issue is because we
have in corporate structure whether we
want to see it as that or not that the
name of that plant drives value and so
there's incentive to rename plants to
gain value and this is deeply
problematic especially if you're dealing
with a community that is utilizing those
plants for medicine where you don't have
consistency so how do you know if
something works if we're not calling the
same thing the same thing
and then if you go and you expand out
into the agricultural setting how do you
know how your environment we're talking
about Appalachians and I'm so on board
I'm really involved in this conversation
but how do you move that direction if
you're not holding those plants constant
right
and so with all of this background I
started a company called leaf forks with
my co-founder Karen uh my affection I'd
call her my work wife which is how a
reference her my normally and our goal
was to develop genetic tools that can
identify plants ginkgo cohosh cannabis
varietals well that becomes deeply
problematic because the community itself
is the group that needs to do that work
right it's not my job to define those
plants right and so this you know comes
to the ethics of genetics and really
understanding what what are those plants
who are those plants what holds them
constant and so when doing any kind of
good science especially in the botanical
world one of the most critical resources
you have to do that good science is an
herbarium so an herbarium is a physical
repository where you take physical
plants you take cuttings of them you
press them and you define them so if you
go out and you find a new species this
is the first thing you do first and then
you write your description of what that
new species is if it's an insect it's an
Insectarium we've got all these fancy
words for basically the same thing which
is a physical encyclopedia and so
because this resource wasn't available
we didn't have the resources to do that
good work of ID in which plants were
which cultivars or varietals and so we
started an herbarium this is very much a
community run process you're defining
your material you know these plants I
know the few plants that I've grown but
that's you know it's small little drop
in the bucket compared to the diversity
that's out there and so it's really I
want to charge this group to to get
involved with that project because it's
it's important for this community to do
those definitions I can't say that
enough ik no outside group should come
in and tell you what you have that's
backwards it's not how it's ever worked
in cultivars it's not how it works in
domestication in general and so we need
to remember that like we have the power
and that also moves into this you know
when you're talking about
corporatization and what's happening
within the that world you know you can
see kind of this narrowing down of the
things that are available and talking
about ethics I mean my big stick is
diversity and if you're only growing
those things that are gonna get you the
most money which is completely
understandable what happens to all those
other plants that are so important to
the diversity in the fabric of not only
the cultural history that we have
together but also moving forward to have
those resources to be able to leverage
and grow with as we need I'm in
particular there's you know land races
and very unique medicinal plants that
have specific purposes that aren't gonna
drive a big dollar in a dispensary but
are really important to a group of
people for their health and well-being
and so that's another ethical thing I
think we all collectively have to
grapple with is how to maintain those
plants in community setting I mean I
don't have the answers it's like this
group together can figure a lot of this
stuff out but how do you keep those
plants going as well is it seed banks is
it everyone growing 2 or 3 things that
aren't commercially viable but are
important culturally I don't know
there's you know many ways to approach
this and so I know there's a lot of
questions people have about genetics and
genetics companies especially in the
light I rarely say this out loud and in
the wake of the Philo's ordeal and that
idea that you need to pay to play you
need to give me your samples I'm going
to sequence them and now you own them
it's like mm hmm that's wrong it's
completely wrong and it's inaccurate
it's completely inaccurate that's like
saying if I go to the grocery store and
buy a gala apple and sequence it I own
it I have no connection to that plan
right and so that's why the herbarium is
so important because it's a physical
tangible record that is free that you
can then link yourself to and ref
and then when we go to the PTO or we go
somewhere we have evidence that we can
all then collectively reference as the
community say no that patent doesn't
hold up because look at all these other
plants that fit that bill you know we
have arguments what is this plant you
know named X who cares what it is we
have a reference to go back to to have a
constructive argument because two people
yelling across the room is not gonna do
anything to move those conversations
forward so many co A's certificate of
analysis so many of so much of what I've
been working with like I know that's got
to be somewhat of a valuable thing in a
potential weird scenario future but how
much weight are these Co is carrying in
any kind of law form yeah I'm gonna
avoid the legal questions and punt them
to Dale but I know have to deal with
somebody saying anything to you
you could be like I've been growing this
for so long and keeping references of
batch samples because a piece of paper
without a reference to the batch is
meaningless right so every like so I do
a lot of work for traditional medicinals
and every time they make a batch of tea
they save a certain number of boxes of
that tea right so it's kind of the same
thing like it's just good manufacturing
practices that every time you make a
batch every time you have a particular
plant that you're growing in a season
save some of it that then links to your
coa
so then you have a chemistry aspect and
you can reference back to the material
that's powerful it just told me that all
my stuff is meaningless I mean we start
somewhere
what are you gonna get stapling it to
you saying yeah it really can be
anything again or is there in natural
products the company itself does that
work send you some weed yeah yeah so the
what oppressing is okay wait so the way
that we operate is very much in the same
light that you would for other
botanicals right so we're not
reinventing the wheel we're just
applying the wheel to this plant and so
you take generally speaking a vegetative
pressing to get the structure there and
you take an early flower I wish we could
take the glorious final Cola but no one
wants to give them up understandably and
they're really unwieldy to press in in a
press right so then you get those two
stages and then you fill out a form and
that form is evolving and we're really
open to any kind of additional
information we've taken the IUCN's hemp
form for their cultivar registration and
added things that apply to cannabis
which include chemistry flowering time
other aspects that aren't necessarily
included in that hemp form and to start
taking that data it's linked to you it
can be linked to a pseudonym if you
don't want it to be linked to you and
you can have that connection that you
can then reference in that physical
sample the herbarium keeps one and then
you keep one so you keep each other
accountable in that way yes so we are a
non-profit so it's been bootstrapping
bootstrap II as we all know and the more
we grow and the more momentum the easier
we'll get so we've been having press
parties this year has been a little bit
difficult to facilitate a lot of those
things since I'm running two
organizations but in different areas we
come together you bring those plants at
that time I have presses there it's free
you just have to show up we have
volunteers that mount things afterwards
at the end of season we give you your
pressed replicate back so that then we
each have one of those
pressings um it's really fun there's
herbarium everywhere so I have a really
large network in Vermont in New England
also in the South in North Carolina
South Carolina somewhere the more like
illegal all over California up into
Oregon so but in the the plants are held
locally right so the plants from Vermont
are held at a herbarium in Vermont and
so that's one thing we're also looking
for organizations that would be willing
to hold the material as public service
right so it is much like a library and
so the bigger the herbarium gets the
more locations there should be because
it you know Northern California okay now
we're going into County and then
hopefully we have more than one location
because we have so many people that are
involved it can become more of more of a
local resource and it really should grow
into a resource that everyone can
utilize and you know if the Appalachians
projects wants to reference it for
certain things then ulsan you have a
resource where you can reference those
to do other kinds of good projects or if
you have a project looking at PTSD or
sleep and you want to reference samples
and you could have a medical group
that's doing a research reference it so
that's you know it should be a resource
that's utilized for those different
projects and the way we utilize it for
full transparency is if you so whenever
we take in clients for leaf works and we
do genetic work for them we mandate that
they press plants and give it to or the
herbarium because it's what makes their
genetics worth something without a
physical sample it's just data I can go
and pull it from a joint I can go and
take us you know it's not reference to
anything tangible so our clients we
mandate that they do that good work
because it validates the work they're
doing with us and then other people give
to the herbarium and want to have
nothing to do with genetics that's fine
other individuals want to join we have a
cultivar identification program going on
right now and so if you donate and you
opt in to that program we may or may not
utilize those to then make markers for
different cultivars which is important
just like we
for a ginkgo test or a black cohosh test
so that we're referencing material that
is correctly named and has history and
traceability attached to it and it adds
value to that farm so if I had seen you
have seeds of the same vino I grow them
here you grow them in southern LA the
genetics can be slightly different there
the value of that healing property will
be different depending on where it's
home so do we do you keep samples of
those and keep that listed you're like
cinnamon if we source cinnamon from
specific spots to get the strength and
potency of the medicinal strain is it is
this geared to that as well absolutely
so we don't make any requirements of
individuals this community doesn't like
to be told what to do right and we're
not here to mandate we're here to to
really serve as a container but if you
have COAS from labs if you've done
sequencing with another lab if you've
done chemical testing you can link all
of that stuff to your samples there's no
requirement but that is something that
you can absolutely do it an adds value
especially as a farmer I have a couple
farmers that have different locations
and they're growing like six things in
all of their locations and so they're
really seeing it as a you tool and a
utility to their own process to
understand how do those different
locations affect the quality of those
plants so you can start to get at that G
by E that genetics by environment which
is what we're all a product of right
genetics is just the backbone the
environment is you know the nurturing
that gets us to our true phenotype are
true outward expression regardless if
we're a plant or an animal and so we do
do that but it's not mandatory
and I I just wanna I guess also open it
up and say I know in these situations
when it comes to genetics and ethics and
like what are people doing with my data
and what kind of data do I not want to
share and what kind of data is really in
our best interest to share I think it's
a really good opportunity to have some
of those conversations and be really
open about it because there's a lot of
fear understandably there's a lot of
fear of thievery there's a lot of fear
of ownership and who owns what and I
don't know exactly where everyone sits
but that's a conversation I would love
to have with people this is something
that I'm very passionate about and you
know I'm here with the plants and so
it's really about stewarding them and
then taking care of those individuals
and humans that are taking care of those
plants yeah so right now we're
fundraising to digitize the samples that
we have and it wouldn't be public it
would be if you contribute to the
herbarium you have access to those
resources and that's the ways in and we
made wheat it may change and grow so you
but it's really to stop outside entities
that are really that just there to pull
data and not support the mission of the
organization so that's that's why we
made that decision and we're of course
open to discussion but that's why we
stand there at the moment and your data
is your data right so you pull that data
whenever like you're if you're
contributing plants
the pressings are really beautiful to
look at
and if you're going to the Emerald cup
both leaf works and candor will have
separate booths and you can see some of
these pressings and we've made some
posters of some of them wait one of
Wade's plants is one of those posters
you can check out
want to talk about like protecting data
and genetic material for ethical
business strategies that would help that
help us yeah
[Music]
so I I thought it was really graceful
how Eleanor kind of avoided talking
about Philo's and I want to make sure
that we're not gonna get stuck on
rehashing or complaining but it is it's
like the asteroid impact that changed
life after that it changed our industry
and it's important to take that into
account and some lessons and I some of
us got very burned by Philo's and others
just watched it but we're all here so
what matters is do we take any lessons
from that and I think a couple of things
that that we can take from it I wrote a
blog post called demand this and all
your business relationships transparency
accountability and trustworthiness and
if you think about the problems that we
learned from hopefully that we the
lessons we learned are was your
transparency was there accountability
and did that lead us to did it did it
create the appearance of trustworthiness
or actual trustworthiness and so much
more important is going forward do we do
that in our own in our own activities in
our own businesses and as we look at
groups that are offering to receive and
store data or handle your data or we
look at groups that are offering to
receive and store genetic material like
seeds you you need to understand they're
trustworthy all their accountability and
their transparency and that means you
need to ask hard questions and I think
one of the fundamentals is that if you
put in data you still own the data right
that's that's really fundamental so
Eleanor Eleanor and I Eleanor Eleanor
and I are both involved in something
called the ethical data Alliance it's an
open group
we have calls every Wednesday morning at
8:00 except this week it's Thursday
morning it's essentially trying to
achieve something that the open cannabis
project was trying to do until we just
kind of closed the doors and walked away
because of the the situation with
Philo's it's that the goal is one of the
goals is to have a genuinely ethical
opportunity to receive and relay data to
other people this is an organization
that won't do any of its own breeding
there's one there's one an important
point
it's an also an organization that if you
submit data it's still your data this is
something right now we're just talking
about we're talking about forming the
right way of organizing it with the
right ground rules the right statement
of ethics the right operate operational
procedures and then once we get all that
in place and we think that people will
want to take advantage of it then we
will have to get to the infrastructure
the IT capabilities of handling those
data and everything but one of the I
think one of our key principles is you
put in your data on whatever terms you
you wish so it might be I don't want
this to be used for any commercial
purpose or I want it to only be used by
members in good standing of this
organization or I just want this out
there and this is a convenient way to
put it out and I put no restrictions on
it it might be you can use this for a
commercial purpose but then I want a
certain defined royalty from anything
you get and I think different people who
own data and have different reasons for
sharing it can have can be ethical and
still have any one of those approaches
to how their data are used in a similar
way for a while we were looking at doing
that having the same organization handle
seeds because a lot of people have have
come to me and told me look I've got
these legacy collections of seeds rare
seeds landraces
what is something somebody gave me
whatever and I want to make sure that
they are that they're going to
ultimately
to the genetic diversity as planned we
all know that there's vast diversity in
cannabis genetics but most of what
people are working with right now
suffers from something called the
founder effect you've all heard of the
founder effect is basically if you have
okay let's say that people got stuck on
Gilligan's Island forever and they had
babies well everybody would either have
mr. Howells DNA or the professor's or
Gilligan's or the skipper's right no
Gilligan well he got around you know
Gilligan got around everybody got
Gilligan's DNA at one point or another
point is there would be a limited
diversity no matter how many people
ended up on that island and if let's say
the island was huge you could have a
billion people on that island but they
would have gone through a genetic
bottleneck where there were only a small
number of possible parents and all the
rest of the genetic diverted have been
white by the way there wouldn't there
wouldn't be there'd be vastly limited
diversity and that's what's happened
with cannabis the cannabis that has been
bred for the last couple of generations
to maximize THC and do this in that it
has disproportionately been selected
from a certain collection of original
parents instead of sampling from the
whole wide diversity so I'm telling you
what you already know but our goal with
the with this group and this this
project is to have a way that people can
can trust putting their seeds in for
safekeeping or for whatever else what
other cheese I didn't even smoke very
much
I need to smoke more and more often the
the goal is that what
at first we were thinking of doing this
all in one organization and then we
realized okay genetic material that's
really important first of all you don't
want to have it all in one place you
don't want to have something bad happen
and everything die you also you can as
much as you can abuse data you can abuse
genetic information even more you can
you you you know it's it's got to be
really trustworthy you can't have one
let's say you have one aggregator let's
say I'm the aggregator and I tell you
trust me I just want all your seeds but
you can trust me
maybe you can but you don't know that
and so what we've decided to do instead
is a kind of a like a library system of
local seed banks that all agree to play
by certain principles it'll you know
it'll give people who put their seeds in
there some options about what they want
the use to be they want it just for
safekeeping
do they want it again same same list of
options share it non-commercially share
it commercially but with a royalty share
it commercially without a whatever and
so the person who puts the seeds in
should still own the seeds and they
should have be able to have their rules
for putting that in govern the rules for
taking it out and we're thinking that if
we can come up with a coherent set of
rules that aren't two rules easy they
don't do alienate everybody we can
actually have a bunch of independent
seed libraries sign onto this and then
it would almost it would really be like
a library system we if we can if we can
actually create corresponding
information then it could be ok I'm a
breeder I want to bring in some some
Southern African whatever and and what
are my choices and who's offering it for
for no royalty or for a modest royalty
and you can really start we will see a
huge increase in the diversity of the
genetics of commercial cannabis which
would be really cool so that we did
decide to do that differently from the
ethical data Alliance so we really are
creating two separate structures
right now it is we're just a lot of
people with good intentions talking
every Wednesday morning we do intend to
take it to actual fruition we've got
we've all got better things to do than
just talk on the phone once a week so we
are gonna make it happen we'd love the
support of this group or anybody else if
you're interested send me an email and
I'll get you on the on the call-in list
I mean I think it's just we'll send you
the dial and information there's no it's
an open group