[Music]
do any of you have any questions high
THC is not except for pain isn't really
needed and I'd like to have you guys
comment on what do you see in terms of
the CBN CBG
thca the whole whole most of things
which we know have medical value I
didn't hear you talk much about that and
I would like to have you know the Swami
is talking about spiritual and
recreational uh Mr Raider is talking
about medical and I think those are two
somewhat different things I'd like to
hear what you have to great I mean I'll
jump right into it I mean I think that
the the one of the things we are going
to see with with uh with regulation is
um increased availability of some of the
canab noids we currently don't have
access to um there's a huge CBD bubble
in world right now there's I I've been
told there's as much as 50,000 kilos of
CBD basically sitting around the world
right now going nowhere just because
everybody decided oh we're going to be
in the CBD business um but what I want
to see is I want to see thcv I want to
see cbdv I want to see um I want to see
some of these really weird breakdown
products I mean there are only really
everybody always says there's 120 canabo
no there aren't there are four canabo
okay and then there are are their
breakdown products okay and there are
their propyl variants and that's it all
right and but some of these breakdown
products these are metabolites and they
have different effects and we've only
started to explore them and so I think
that exploring from a medicinal
standpoint the incredible utility of
this plant um is amazing and I I think
we're going to be doing it for decades
which is really cool one of the coolest
Parts about legalization and and in in
and recreational marijuana or
recreational marijuana becom illegal is
or cannabis s is um is is that the the
the medical side of things can
concentrate on on on what's best for
them the the recreational side of things
can concentrate on what's best for them
but there's somewhere in the middle
that's your maybe neutral you know take
your daily cannabis supplement for for
for General Health maybe I don't have a
specific Wellness Wellness exactly and
so so I I I don't necessarily see them
as having to be completely different
things I think there's it's a spectrum I
think it's more of a bell curve than
necessarily a black and white issue U my
question is um about testing Josh you
mentioned that thank you you mentioned
that uh somebody asked you to retest it
again
that is the problem that I have with
testing Labs because um I'm new I
understand that I'm in the edible
business and I want to be exact by my
standards and my standards are very
severe And yet when you when I test it
it comes back how could that be and they
test it again and okay now it's accurate
and they just send it back to you to
retest it again and you retested it and
found out in their favor so how can
anybody me um feel comfortable and
secure in paying for a testing lab and
it's not accurate okay well so there's a
lot of issues with that and and with
Edibles it gets to be this whole whole
kind of conflated issue so so first of
all with Edibles um I I have this
presentation I do about stratified
sampling and and in in testing multiple
samples through through a production run
and and having some sort of idea of the
variance so so it's it's it's a number
of things first Edibles are extremely
hard to test to bring to bring a sample
into a Testing Lab that sees a cookie a
gummy bear a piece of beef jerky um and
all these things as you know as Edibles
they're all completely different tests
and really need their
own validated test for each one of those
types of samples um because you're
testing in completely different products
when I test a gummy bear versus a
brownie it's a completely different
extraction process a completely
different test so the testing lab needs
to have different procedures for the
different types of Ed
and and I think again we're really glad
to see people with with budgets get into
this because a lot of your edible
producers don't want to spend the money
they really should be spending to make a
proper product um you know if if if if I
was producing say omega-3 infused
gummies each production run I'd be doing
dozens of tests throughout that
production run now do I do do I run hot
at the very beginning of the run and
then then it then about you know 10
units in all of a sudden it starts to
level off and I get homogeneity there's
also the issue with Edibles is is one
side of the cookie completely different
than the other side of the cookie how
many chocolate chips did you put in the
cookie are the chocolate chips infused
and so I think what we get is we get
edible makers that bring in one cookie
from one batch and then the next B and
these are these are the ones that that
are doing a lot of testing and then the
next batch they bring in one cookie and
they're like well last batch it was you
know 30% higher what what's going on
here it's like well the next cookie off
the line would have been 50% higher do
you know that you know do you have an
idea of what your production process is
doing and then so I could go on and on
about all the problems with with edible
standardization let me jump into one
thing on that which is the idea is that
in every other industry a wine maker
doesn't go down always to the wine
Testing Lab the wine maker has a lab
yeah okay and I think that what you're
going to see is is that you're going to
see a lot more companies take this in
and then go to somebody who's expert and
say test my testing all right and then I
think it's going to become a lot more
prevalent I and when you when you hear
yeah when you hear a retest I mean
that's most often because they didn't
believe the value it wasn't because the
lab's trying to give them what they want
to hear it's a very important
distinction you know um yeah and I mean
flower testing can be hugely variable so
the top of the plant can be twice as
much as the bottom so how do I
homogenize my entire batch so that I can
get a good accurate value across the
entire picture that's really the goal of
testing and we'll see this whole
standardization effort be forced upon us
with regulations so you're going to be
required to do statistically valid
testing not just one sample not just a
sample but across your batch and make
sure that that distributor actually
really knows what's on the label of
their product and and also when when
when you look at the when you look at
the composition of let's say alcoholic
beverages okay like wine you don't go in
and pick up a bottle of wine and go oh I
wonder what the of terpinolene is in
this Cabernet all right the reason is is
that you're buying the wine you're
buying the kind of totality the gestal
of it and right now I think we're
getting a little too granular sometimes
in our look at this product all right it
may not be as easily sliced and diced as
everybody wants it we just need to have
a well-characterized safe pure
product um my question was kind of you
know a little obscure on
um you know kind of the future of pot
but how much you know in the past and
the traditions of the past have have had
some type of possibly biological
relevant or psych you know
pharmacologically relevant uh benefits
the thing that's coming to mind is have
if if any of you have um ever tried like
the Malawi cobs and my questions kind of
to you know what could have happened
there to where you know you take a fresh
Cola and you wrap it in a certain type
of leaf you bury it in the ground and
there's this decomposing process and so
I'm wondering what kind of degradative
Tarpin unique kind of you know
degradated cannaboids come about CU it's
like this whole legend of you know
process and is there anything Rel to
that what's the hive from
apoxin I mean honestly because I
remember I remember there was a whole
phase in Mendo you'll remember this
Swami there was a whole phase for a
while where people were burying their
weed and and you know pulling out the
ground and saying man this mold gets you
what's really interesting all the guys
who are like promoting that died
relatively
young it's like oh yeah Fred he checked
out at about 47 you know but I I think
that there are indigenous techniques
that we're we're going to learn from and
I think that I mean I I think Malawi is
a great place where there's a whole
tradition of these gold lighter strains
in Colombia um the Colombian Golds were
often created
by breaking the primary stem on the
plant and bleaching it out right before
it was finally
harvested stressing the plant well
there's a whole tradition of stressing
the plant in many ways some people used
to drive a a spike right through the
base of of the of the Stu and so on I
just want to put a shout out for Panama
Red anybody remember Panama Red
psychedelic man
absolutely so high high carry offing
strain okay strains that smell like
pepper like can like are basically High
bet carry offing strains and and what's
funny is the closest thing out there are
some of the C cookies variants now that
are super super high in carry offing and
relatively low in miring so I want some
opinion I have a question here that um
I've been listening to some of the
panels over the last few days and I've
heard a lot of lawyers speak tell us
about how you can't patent strains and
you're not going to be able to do these
things but I didn't hear anybody talk
about the future of um a breeder such as
ourselves are going to go into the
future and other than the old term
hoarding strains um I'd like to know if
anybody up here can give us any
practical advice on um how we're going
to go into the future uh creating this
intellectual property and identifying it
and owning it well oops wrong one again
all right speaking with uh I think
Andrea Brooks yesterday I'm one of the
panelists I spoke to her afterwards
about uh you know the idea of patenting
uh these different strains that or
cultivars I should say that you that you
people were getting just from Crossing
you know endlessly Crossing these
hybrids and you even if you come up with
something unique uh once you put it out
in the public domain you sell clones of
it or you sell seeds of it or whatever
it's gone in terms of your patent right
you have to patent it first before it is
ever commercialized uh but I think that
really the patents besides that the
patents that will really make a big
difference are the ones that dise that
uh uh are about Disease Control about uh
having resistance to btis and and PM and
that sort of thing and I think that
somebody who finds those genes and
incorporates them into strains that's
really going to be something so I can I
address a little bit this so plant
variety rights okay that's one kind of
plant patent all right and that is a
that's a clone okay it's not seed and
you can't prevent somebody from breeding
with your plant which is great that
means Innovation so you can have your
version of Strawberry Cough okay and if
there's no prior art out there that that
precludes that or nobody can say he's
actually growing my plant if you can
prove it to the satisfaction of the
patent office that you're novel and and
meet all the requirements for that
particular kind of plant as long as it's
clonally propagated or probably tissue
propagated you're cool seed you're not
cool at all okay and a deposit actually
has to be that plant okay now a utility
PL patent which I got okay a Utility
Patent on cannabis is is that you have a
class that is novel okay we bred a group
of cannabis plants and man I'll tell you
the patent office because we were the
first application they are really trying
to bust us they they were sending us
results from analytical 360 and
Washington about a CBD crew variety from
the south south of Spain and and I had
to drive all over the West Coast getting
samples of these varieties and test them
with a validated method and submit him
to the patent office for every rejection
letter we got and that went on for
months and months and months until
finally they said okay you win here's
the patent and we have a patent on a
very narrow range of type twos CBD and
together that don't produce Mir scene
okay and that's the key this is that CU
finding High miren plants with CBD in
them that's super easy finding CBD
plants that don't have mine in them
that's really hard and that's what we
did we spent three years breeding it so
two more question you can get a patter
two kinds thanks everybody said that
here is cannabis medical cannabis here
is medicine here's the FDA here's all
this stuff and no one talked about
integrating all that stuff the problem
with medicine and as far as I'm
concerned and I've been in it for my
entire life is that we have so siloed
every specialty every new thing that's
come along and the worst thing we want
is to be siloed as a
different
alternative
oppositional type of therapy and the
real success is going to be if we follow
the biopsychosocial model all chronic
disease involves all those aspects and
what kind of combination of specific can
cannabinoids specific cannaboid plants
with other types of traditional and
Medical Treatments is going to really
help that particular patient in front of
you and all the rest I think is just
going to drive a wedge in us that the
that the AMA and FDA and farmer just are
very happy to see happen
can talk to that um our last question I
just met Dave at lunch the other day we
had a wonderful little conversation so I
thank you for that question because uh I
actually uh I don't think there's a
difference between uh what's called
recreational and medicinal use I really
don't think that's the case at all and
there are people say well I want to just
have fun well how many medicines are out
there for mood alteration right how many
medicines are out there with
unbelievable side effects right so I
think that the spiritual as aspect of
cannabis is essentially why it heals and
all the different specific ways that it
heals we're going to have Jeff and
various people pinpoint that for us when
you need it for that but I think it's
they did test with CBD you know about
the see they repress CBD and these
people got suicidal when they had a a
drug that rep we have CBD we need CBD as
our basic health Wellness in our body so
I don't think there's really a
difference we use this this cannabis to
alter our Consciousness and to elevate
us and that's part of the healing
process and yeah I find it a false
dichotomy and I also think that we we do
want to have we do want all the Muggles
to be here we want it to be mainstream
because it's really an essential part of
of of really coming
alive that's good that's good great
thank
[Applause]
you I write books on efficient cannabis
youth
and my specialty is lowd dose cannabis
unless you're a grower like Kyle kushman
or Swami these two are brothers from
another mother to
me smoking a joint is the least
efficient way to use cannabis for the
average user they're wasting their money
and the cannabis strains that are
available today one hit is enough to get
you completely high and then you put
your joint out and when you light it
again you just get a massive dose of
hydrocarbons any comments Swami Kyle
kushman the board this on well one of
the things that I think is is wrong uh
well I'll give you an example uh uh I
was on a team that was Consulting with a
group from uh uh Vegas uh who wanted to
build a a grow and and so forth and and
the investors were absolutely fascinated
by how strong uh the
uh the cultivars that we had and we had
to offer and at at a certain point I
said you know you're really looking at
this the wrong way I said most of your
people are not going to be uh Native uh
uh Las Vegas they're going to be you
know tourists coming in here and uh
they're going to get their their medical
thing here what they thought at the time
that that would happen and uh then go
and and they're going to buy something
so I said you're going to sell them
joints that have 20% th seeing them
they're going to have a bad experience
they're naive right they're going to
smoke that joint and they're going to
say oh I forgot how to breathe my heart
is explosing you know this sort of thing
they're going to end up in the emergency
Ward you know I said you don't want that
experience I said you could much more
easily just roll up uh fan uh leaves
from this stuff and and have have 5% THC
joined as their first experience I mean
we were smoking stuff back in the' 60s
and70s that was like 2 to 3% THC I mean
really and had a great time with it
exactly I mean so the idea of having
these massive amounts uh to me you know
I mean the the idea that you're wasting
this the the point is this stuff is not
going to be that expensive and
especially if you're growing it yourself
I mean I throw away when I'm finished
with that joint probably what most
people start their joints with you know
it's just yeah let me let me let me jump
in so one thing that we didn't talk
about in The Evolution of cannabis is
the evolution of dose okay and that's a
whole another panel and I hope we have
it someday because the future of this is
understanding that a lot of the
constituents of cannabis um exhibit
basic dose in other words it does one
thing at one dose and one thing and
another and there's this whole
interesting concept and there's a bunch
of really cool papers by GW guy found in
GW
Pharmaceuticals um about
hormesis and hormesis is this idea of a
very very very small
actually causing a profound change in an
organism and it's it has it works on
scientific levels it works on spiritual
levels it's it's a fascinating
fascinating topic and there's a
scientist in Israel who's been doing
research on showing that your first dose
of THC is
neurotoxic and it works almost like an
inoculant like a vaccine all right to
adjust how you will respond to a canab a
phyto canabo from that point forward
this guy's published like six or seven
really good papers and um and he's from
a really prestigious University in
Israel and what it is is that we don't
know and I'll tell you one thing that I
do know is we don't have a good
conception of cannabis dose today and
that part of the evolution of our
discussion about cannabis will take that
Focus towards those because there's room
in this tent for somebody who wants to
smoke a joint and there's room in this
tent for somebody who wants to take a
hit okay yeah well there's the micro do
people are talking about micro doing
quite a bit we're done we're done I I
don't I don't micros
[Applause]
[Music]