[Music]
demolition of canvas is really actually
a really really interesting subject
because if you talk to a lot of people
today the impression that one would get
is is that oh my gosh were we're in the
Golden Age we we you know technology has
has dragged this plan up a hill and and
it's never been better and and I think
that that's controversial actually I
think that we have lost some things
along the way and so what we're going to
talk about today is both a very very
bright future an interesting future but
also I think we're going to address some
of the things that maybe kind of got
lost in the in the green rush and
so I'm gonna I'm gonna kind of open up
with the panel on with very very short
bio so I want you to basically just kind
of help the audience get some sense of
who you are and what you're into hi I'm
Swami Chaitanya visvakarma brahmacharya
Gandhi Ananda and you say that again
rapidly right so I've been initiated in
several branches of yoga in India by
various priests and temples and gurus up
in the mountains and so on at the moment
you don't need to know where I went to
grammar school right and at the moment I
am a cannabis grower up at Mendocino
County where we grow the best cannabis
in the world and we're proud of it and I
have
90 acre farm and because of our legal
restrictions I've been able to grow very
few plants so I can't supply all of you
just yet but I'm hoping to get there
someday I'm very happy to be on this
panel and I think the idea of evolution
of cannabis is actually something we
really need to pay attention to so
thanks for being here
and I'm I'm Josh wars er the president
of SC labs analytical testing laboratory
and
before I was a chemist I was I loved
cannabis
as soon as I first started smoking it
than I had to start growing it and see
see how that worked and and so I saw it
through college and from high school to
college I was thinking of the cannabis
industry got my degree in chemistry
moved to California worked in
pharmaceutical industry electronic
materials doing research and development
and
saw saw a job opening for for laboratory
director at that time was the only lab
in the state
where was the only lab in the state that
would do cannabis testing and that was
that was Steve Bell sorry I took that
job and it realized like that I could
actually marry my two loves and from
from then on
I've been testing cannabis so I worked
there for about a year and then we
started SC labs so I've been doing this
now for over seven years so it's been
really cool to kind of see the evolution
of at least the testing industry for
cannabis and as such that the labs kind
of the nexus in the industry the
producers come through the dispensaries
come through and a lot of patients come
through and so it's been a really cool
window to be able to kind of just watch
the last seven or eight years of the
industry of all ml prank and I've been
write writing about menopause since 1971
so I've written three books 1974
1977 and 1988 on growing marijuana also
published them the last one was I
updated in 1997 the marijuana growers
guide deluxe
also in the editor and publisher for Rob
Clark's hashish and to currently iced
consult I still contribute botanical
texts and photographs most recently the
survive days encyclopedia of cannabis
over 100 photographs - that also - Ken
morose
marijuana horticultural fundamentals
also botanical information over
good morning Jeff Raber I'm the CEO and
founder of the workshop in analytical
testing laboratory I got a bachelor's in
biochemistry and a PhD in synthetic
organic chemistry from the University of
Southern California I don't for any
Trojans out here and I you know
certainly got an interesting perspective
in cannabis being in the testing lab as
Josh mentioned do you kind of have a
bird's-eye view of the entire industry
and what we've been able to do with that
position is publish 5 peer-reviewed
literature articles most noted probably
on the chemo taxonomic profiling how to
look at terpenes and many of the
secondary metabolites of the plant to
start a identification system that means
more towards patients and doctors and
how he can communicate better about
which cannabis compositions were using
as opposed to just calling them an
indica and sativa and I'm very grateful
to be here today and appreciate the time
this idea that the evolution of the
plant and our relationship with the
plant we potentially may have lost a few
things on the way or we may want to look
back a little bit not that we've lost
but there are things that we can learn
from the past so I'd like to have each
of the panelists kind of address um what
are the things from from the past a
little bit you're interested in learning
about whether you're a lab or a
cultivator
what kind of opportunities are on the
horizon that could have enabled the past
a little bit for example in the case for
me I'm really interested in heirloom
varieties I'm interested in the low
yielding ultra interesting chemistry's
of some of the tropical varieties that
really are easy to spot by a helicopter
and but don't yield much and so I'm not
interested always in these the mythical
7-pound plant I'm interested in the one
pound of crazy interesting or I'm
interested in that one gram of dry sieve
that
really retains a terpene profile that I
current currently cannot find in
conventional extraction so that that's
we're looking to the past I think I can
actually bring a better future I'd like
to have any of your ideas on it well we
were talking the other day and you said
is there any skunk left right is there
any true skunk and so you know in a
sense like we don't really know how to
make stained glass for Gothic cathedrals
anymore so stuff gets lost you know and
with a skunk well is there some so
anybody have a skunk out there we want
some seeds because we want to grow it
but there's something well I just want
to make a little statement about what we
lost in terms of our cannabis culture
because of all this regulation and
we used to be in the cannabis community
could deliver cannabis to every small
town in this country for the last 40 50
years California's been doing that and
we've done that without brick and mortar
we've done that without advertising
we've done that without bank account's
without cash we've done that without it
you know without any protection every
police force is trying to stop us right
and there was no plan and there was an
amazing way that we could do this and no
one quite knows how but the cannabis
community could deliver all across the
country a cannabis to just about anyone
right and that was done by a million
random decisions of a million different
people that Johnny knew Susie back in
Ohio and you know Sam knew Linda back in
Boston and they sent them a pound and
this went across and you know whatever
trillions of dollars have been spent on
it they couldn't stop it right and
that's because the plant has this innate
character the plant has this innate
spirituality that connects to everyone
on a Bay but what I want to talk about
is that community that we had that you
know thousand dollar ten thousand
hundred thousand dollar deals were done
between people on a handshake and a look
in the eye and it worked and we were
able to do this and it's something that
I don't there's this community feeling
that we were all together and there's
another thing also just about the fact
that it was in legal that we had an
underground community that actually came
out of the anti-war movement that can
came out of the civil rights movement we
were all used to being in opposition as
activists who are used to being
underground and just cannabis came along
and and chilled us all out so is that
underground community of recognition
that were a secret you know where is you
know it's almost like the Harry Potter
thing we're all the Wizards in here and
we're trying to and we keep this
knowledge amongst ourselves and we pass
it around and and it is a sacred
knowledge and it's a sacred knowledge
that's at least 10,000 years old and so
we want to keep that sacred knowledge
amongst us Wizards but now
so so what's funny is is that if you go
back to the 1940s one of the popular
slang terms for cannabis was muggle yeah
alright so if you go back to miss miss
Rose
yeah so um Josh what do you think of
what about the best well I agree with
everything Tommy just said it I I do a
hundred percent it and I think you know
it's sad but at the same time you know
I'm glad people aren't gonna get locked
in cages anymore for for forgetting
cannabis out there and but but it is sad
to see see see kind of the culture go
and it's just inevitable it's it's I
guess everything changes but but I give
you a hundred percent with all of that
it is kind of sad and you know there
used to be a secret place where you know
you go to any party and you know the
people you're going in let's go let's go
stand over here and now now everyone's
showing up to that circus a look in the
eye little not ya know woman but but but
but beyond that and I'm gonna I'm gonna
rip on the lab industry for a second um
you know we I think it's great that
we're finally you know getting quality
control for the plant and I and I think
it absolutely needs it and it's such a
safe plant that it were very lucky that
that we haven't had any any anyone died
or any instances of you know for
instance e.coli outbreaks in cannabis
that would have really put a damper on
legalization but but nonetheless
cannabis does need quality control just
like everything else and who knows was
sprayed on your your pot and us doing
their testing there's there's a lot of
things sprayed on your pot is the answer
but I think one of the real detriments
the testing industry has done to the
cannabis industry is is you know no one
wants to grow plants at tests under 20%
now and we've lost a lot of great
strains a lot of interesting strains
that really unique protein profiles
really unique eyes because no one's
growing those 14% 12% strains no one's
growing then the public pushes and in
the great be purples anymore because
they don't test too low and hopefully
that'll go away as as prices come down I
think of you know that as I said the
pressure I think a big part of it was
getting the most bang for your buck and
maybe that's one of the good things
that's coming along with legalization is
that prices have come down to to where
people can afford it people who want to
pay more for
really high quality cannabis can but
people who don't have the money and just
need to go in and get some cannabis law
will have their options too but but I
think that the the laboratory industry
really kind of did a disservice by by
just testing for for THC content and it
got to be just a numbers game bigger is
better now that terpene testing is
available we're realizing that that
really THC content is is I guess
irrelevant as far as quality goes you
you know take an extra hit I I enjoy the
process of smoking I'd rather smoke
twice as much and smoke a joint all the
way down then get a few hits and have to
put it down and you have a taster
so so I'm you know it's just kind of a
byproduct of what we did and so
hopefully now people are going to start
realizing that that what's interesting
about one kind of a strain or another it
has nothing to do with you know how much
THC it has and it's it's all about
what's the terpene profile how are those
terpenes preserved in a growing process
who can who can grow and dry their
cannabis in a way that preserves those
terpenes and who can grow unique strains
that have unique profiles so and I'll
riff on that that's a great comment one
of the things I'm really interested in
is this thing that I interviewed Raphael
Michelle and we got discovered THC and
CBD and what he said was he was talking
about the stinkiness of nature where
where the plant basically only has a
limited number of chemical precursors
from which to make these compounds of
interest and if you skewed the plant
towards cannabinoids which have no
flavor or aroma then you're sacrificing
something and I remember the great
Hawaiian strange like Kona gold in the
70s that probably tested around 1012
percent but it literally was one of
those things where you opened a bag and
you could smell it a block away it
smelled like a Christmas tree and that
that kind of terpene profile has become
rather scarce these days those Christmas
tree the altar of roadkill skunk that
we're in the case of skunk you probably
have a some kind of
sulfur molecule a sequester in there as
a precursor to coenzyme a and that's
part of the process of making these
chemicals and a little bit hangs out it
really reeks and
just one more thing if I can get a
little bit do a little bit of math this
morning
we test for the Emerald cup every year
we have since we opened and it's a
really great kind of testbed before in
the Northern California market and you
would get a lot of unique strains it's
not just 20 different flavors of OG I
mean last year we had you know 450 500
flower entries and if you graph the
winners the top 25 samples and in the
testing the way they do the testing
there they do a great job of actually
testing each strain and they get a
really good panel of experts to do the
testing in if you graph the the THC
content of the overall population of
Navarone cup samples versus the winners
versus the overall population of samples
we see in the lab they're all the same
the mean is the same so what that means
is
the amount of THC has no oh come on
whether a sample is judged or our entry
is judged better than another the winner
never has the highest THC and the
Emerald Cup since we've been testing out
one of the judges emerald-cut
the highest THC that year was number 20
but but if you if you graph the chirping
content of the winners versus the
chirping content of the overall
population the chirping content the
winners is one full standard deviation
higher than the chirping content so you
see all these bell curves lined up are
these distributions line up with each
other with them with with THC content
but then you graph chirping content and
the winners are way over here and the
top 20 the top 20 SERP themselves out
just rise to the top is so obvious and
the judges in the ammo cup it's a
phenomenal amount of agreement about
what are the top 20 it's pretty it's
truly amazing actually
well I can I can talk to what it used to
be also I actually had about 200 land
raises back in the 70s early 80s and
lost them all one in the fortunate legal
thing
but I donated nine land races to the
University of Mississippi in 1977 to get
them started because they had heard
about this such potent marijuana out in
California and they hadn't been testing
any
but the two things that came up one is
about the skunk at that time I was being
visited because I had books out by
growers from around the country and a
lot of them at that time you had the
hippie hashish trail
we're hippies would go through
Afghanistan in Nepal and Lebanon and and
bring back seeds it wasn't the political
situation you would have now or that's
very dangerous
and we would trade seeds and a lot of
the seeds that they they were using
especially in the East were short season
Afghan ease and these Afghan ease
smelled like skunk a lot of them did I
mean like a skunk the problem was is
that all we had then we didn't have labs
we had smoke testing and they didn't get
your very stoned and we now know
looking back that that's because they
had a lot of CBD in them also all right
so unfortunately that small group of us
who are breeding at that time we
basically got rid of all the CBD plants
right and that's why it's been so hard
to bring those back
so that was an unfortunate consequence
of the illegality and the lack of lab
testing but in speaking of the terpenes
when I started to grow some of these
popular varieties here I actually
thought
that the lack of fragrance was due to
the consequence of old age and I was
losing my sense of smell because the
smells was so weak because I I got Dave
Watson was one of the breeders he
brought skunk number one and haze to
Amsterdam along with two varieties that
I had which was Afghani one and Durban
poison they along with one another one
Hindu cush he brought those two camps at
him and started that basically that
started the entire seed industry out of
EMC Dale
but anyway he had given me a South
Indian strain that was so sweet when I
walked into my greenhouse I almost
wanted to bite it I mean it was that
overwhelming and and there were other
strains also that was just really
incredible in terms of fragrance I had a
cross between an Afghani and the Durban
that I've never smelled anything like it
since and these were things that you
could literally just walk into the the
greenhouse to say oh my god this is
overwhelming and a lot of that has
definitely been lost now fortunately
the emphasis now is totally on terpenes
I mean that's all I based my breeding on
now is is really the fragrance the
fragrance and the taste
because once you get up into the teens
really it makes little difference
whether you're a 20 or you're 15 right
one other thing about the potency back
then now the reason why I gave these
strains to the University of Mississippi
or the government wasn't necessarily
altruistic I I wanted to get the an
actual lab result which I did get and
someone tested almost 12 percent now
that doesn't sound high now but when you
consider what my sampling was what I was
giving them were lower buds that were
fully seated and not manicured and I'm
sure they tested in the high teens the
sense of me I had at the top of the
plant so I mean I think this is kind of
mythical that there was nothing really
strong back then
so
when I think backwards and I hear from
other people they've definitely
mentioned how we've lost a lot of
varieties where's the Acapulco gold
where's the Colombian red where are the
things that made me feel like they did
back in the 60s and 70s and I think
we've unfortunately had a bit of
unnatural selection and trying to select
against those types of plants that would
smell very effervescent and strong and
alert the neighbor or the authorities or
someone else and we've definitely been
selecting against that for rapid highs
and very different types of profiles
than what we might see otherwise I mean
you look at John McPartland work and
what he's done across the entire history
of saying where cannabis may have
evolved from how it's been spread across
the globe and what we see today is very
tight genetic constriction inside of at
least the western United States even
over in the Netherlands we can see from
their terpene profiling that they've got
a lot of different varieties that we
don't have over here so I'm hopeful that
when looking back we can actually try
and guide some of the breeding today
like Mel was saying using advanced
techniques and analytical approaches to
say let's create different terpene
profiles let's create different
cannabinoids profiles and let's maximize
the diversity of what we're seeing
instead of restricting it like we have
so far up to today so I'm kind of
hopeful and looking backwards we may
have temporarily only lost them it's a
flexible plan we know that if we bread
this way maybe we can start breeding
backwards and capture a lot of those and
I'm hoping that you know we can
accelerate that using advanced
techniques in the laboratory
yeah that's a great point thanks Jeff
yeah I think that's not this idea it is
really really fundamental is is that a
lot of people will walk into a
dispensary that lists potency and kind
of mentally grade the board based on THC
content and I think the message that
we'll try to convey pretty consistently
across the board today is this that
there really is a lot more to it a lot
of a segment embrace this idea of
terpene chemistry as being a fundamental
part of that but I guarantee you there's
a lot more to the chemistry than you
might imagine a friend of mine Matt wall
in England does functional magnetic
resonance imaging of the human brain and
he recently did a study of cannabis
users while they were on campus and and
he found something really really
interesting in the last six years
neuroscientists have discovered that our
brain is a bunch of modules and those
modules work together in networks and
there are three principal networks
there's the executive control Network
I'm gonna do this there's the the
default mode which is daydreaming
thinking about your past thinking about
the future and it's funny that it's
called default mode because it's where
we spend most of our time
what I'm gonna have for lunch today
whatever records yesterday what am I
gonna call my mom and all that stuff and
then there's the salience network and
the salience network is really really
important to cannabis users
salient what's important what is salient
you know and so what it does is it looks
at all the sensory inputs we have and it
assigns important to them now if you've
ever gotten paranoid on cannabis you can
see that THC can interfere with your
salience network because suddenly you
think that that thing at the door could
be
fill in the blank okay what's really
fascinating is is that when Matt was
doing these studies when people were on
THC cannabis alone Jack Herer
they they really had salience problems
and they can have paranoia and they
could have dysphoric reactions all this
and when they were on THC and CBD
together even a small amount of CBD they
still showed all of the kind of
psychoactive
impairment associated with THC but they
had no problems with their salient
network at all there's their ability to
distinguish what was a threat what was
important etc etc in their environment
um didn't change that's really important
because there's evidence coming out of
Australia England and the US right now
that maybe a tiny tiny CBD buffer might
be a really really smart thing to have
in your cannabis diet alright and and
there's a reason that all of these great
hash countries around the world when
it's grown as a field crop you end up
with a considerably higher titer of CBD
in your resin than when you're just
singly selecting plants for potency
which have a tendency to skew the
population towards THC content so I'm
going to talk a little bit about the
future right now I want to ask you what
in the last couple of years as far as
the evolution of cannabis have you been
most excited about and what have you
seen either in your garden or your
laboratory or your life that really has
gotten you kind of excited about where
cannabis is going right now okay I want
to bring the TA the CBD thing also
because you said though that we kind of
lost the CBD thing and we did for a long
while and then it became kind of the
Holy Grail and now we've got it back and
you could say we some people are
reporting what 20 percent CBD and so on
but the research is showing that all the
different healing aspects of the can of
plan are a function of all the different
400 least elements and we call out the
entourage effect the totality of it and
that's why I extractions don't really
know I mean this sense of sin that
Sabbath anyway the synthesizing a
singular molecule or something like that
to say this it's not really working
because it's the whole plant that really
does it now we've got the CBD back I've
got CBD plants that and the people who
brought Harlequin from from Switzerland
and he's a good friend of mine and so on
so now the genetics it's happening
that's the future right now in the
growing world and the genetics is
happening up in Mendocino County I use
seeds that all come from my area with
young guys who are crossing this and
they've been doing it since they're 12
years old and they're master geneticists
and they're creating some wonderful new
strains with amazing terpene profiles as
well so that's that's and the other part
about future in farming is that
particularly in the Emerald triangle
Mendocino County and so on there's a
whole movement towards either
biodynamic gardening or
by a pro diet probiotic gardening and
things of nature where you're using only
natural ingredients and also going more
towards sustainability so that having
fewer and fewer things come off your
ranch to grow your plants that you grow
your plants you know with a better with
with plant material that using compost
teas using Bokashi fermentation things
and you're using ways to make the soil
come alive that the soil is actually
biologically and fungicide fungally
alive and that's what grows your plants
and that's what actually is the best way
to grow cannabis in the most natural way
that we recreate the conditions that are
in in the forest and in nature and not
putting other attitude
[Applause]
and in what we're seeing too I think
along those same lines is cannabis is
going to be a really interesting kind of
I guess test bet because it is you know
essentially until we get directives on
from the EPA and whatnot about which
pesticides can be used on cannabis we
can't use can pesticides in cannabis
that's gonna be one of the only crops I
know where you're gonna have a total
restriction on or at least supposedly
you have a total restriction on
pesticide use should be and exactly and
it really should be two because we're
not eating it cannabis we can't wash it
off so it'll be interesting to see that
and I think some of the things I'm
excited about too is is you know one
again you know I'm sad to see the kind
of the culture kind of get get faded
away maybe a little bit it is
interesting for me to see some of these
people come in who actually can can
invest money in cannabis and who can in
and you can do it safely and confess
money on creating new new cannabis based
products infused products I'm
old-fashioned I like to smoke my joints
but it's really cool to see some of the
things we're doing with concentrates
with infused products for people with
medical conditions we're making products
that that look more like medical
products that that use this natural
plant-based medicine but deliver it in a
way that's that's efficacious for
someone for people with different
diseases we're starting to specialize
those products for people with specific
ailments and and so that's that's been
really cool to see is just kind of once
we can actually safely put some research
dollars into cannabis what's coming from
that and it's been that's been really
exciting I think one of the things
that's really compelling too is this
idea that I'm Kevin mckernon who works
for a company called
quarter turn on the East Coast
he's been
sequencing the canvas genome for a while
with other groups around the United
States but what he's also been doing is
sequencing the microbiome of the plant
in other words what grows on the plant
what bacteria grow on the plant because
there's a single network alright you
know we've always said oh there's a soil
web there's this and that there's hard
core science now that you're terpene
expression on your plan is going to be
highly driven by the microbial life on
your plant now that's interesting
because right now certain jurisdictions
are rushing out saying oh torille total
aerobic count is really important no it
isn't it isn't at all it's like saying
Oh total aerobic count in your yogurt
could kill you okay no it's pathogens
all right we have to build a distinguish
between healthy bacteria and pathogens
on our plants and if we can't we're not
going to know what's safe and what's not
safe and the thing is is that when
regulators come in and try to regulate
us they really need to help them
understand what's important in the plant
because I guarantee you they are not
going to figure it out themselves okay
there you're gonna have to spoon-feed
them like like a slightly slow four year
old
well a couple of things I completely
agree with the Swami and in terms of
organic growing I grow organically in
Los Angeles here I use two things I use
BT which is a Mozilla's thuringiensis
which is used to naturally kill bug
worms and they are a plague here the
second thing I use is I use tanglefoot
which I put on the is the sticky
substance that put it on the stem if
that prevents crawlers from coming up
and now than that is just me going out
there looking at my plants and pulling
off anything that's got in an infection
let's say
you know by some sort of bug and just to
keep the population down I know that
there's always going to be some sort of
insect out there there's always going to
be grasshoppers or something else that
are you eating it but I'll just go out
there and pick off what I can and that
way there I know that whatever I'm
smoking is absolutely you know clean of
any pesticides or anything else and I
think that's the way it should be grown
and it leads into this market of indoor
growing where an awful lot of pendous
pesticides and fungicides and everything
else are used and one of the the main
things that should be done with this
the evolution of cannabis on the
development of strains is the
development of resistance names through
things like bus riders for the outdoor
grow and for how do you mildew for the
indoor crow is that sort of thing and
now that we're finally going to be able
to grow you know vast fields of this and
actually see what is it has a natural
resistance to it these things are going
to come about because so far they
haven't in that's due to the illegality
and and the inability to grow a massive
amount of plants and find those unique
plants that have a natural resistance
now I just want to one other thing and
that is I've been able to witness
something in that I know exactly what
the Afghani one looked like back in 1979
that came from coupled to a land race
and the Durbin poison came from Durbin
another land race and I recently
acquired a couple years ago a couple of
phenotypes of German poison which is
nothing like the Durbin poison that went
from me over to Amsterdam the one now is
a much heavier producer it still has the
early flowering quality to it it doesn't
have any of the smell that that mine had
and and most importantly and
disheartening to me is that it doesn't
have
the coloration and the stigmas that I
saw in that variety that that that
strain that strain had purple stigma
stigma so the little white hairs that
most you probably call pistols and or a
lavender lavender purple I've never seen
in any other strain and I was
disheartened to see that it wasn't in
this drain anymore and the other was at
Guinea one Afghani one I got from my
original source so it's about filial
generation 37 now and that also that had
red stigmas it had bred sting comes in
and had white stigmas and the three
females that I grew this year all had
white stigmas and when I asked her about
red singlet she said she she couldn't
remember seeing them so she lost that
quite a long time ago she also also lost
a lot of the flavor over the year and
that was pretty much a natural thing
because she wasn't a selective breed or
she just picked out a few females and a
few males and just let them go
so it was interesting to see what
happened to those things one from
selective breeding by Dutch breeders and
the other by just you know reading the
pollination
perhaps what I'm most interested in
seeing as we now enter
legalization also you know
standardization should be the next part
of that so now that we're able to grow
and cultivate under license we're not
fearful of someone coming in and raiding
the plants or taking things away from us
we can invest in infrastructure that
will allow us to produce in a much more
consistent reliable and standardized
fashion so that every single harvest
every single crop has the exact same can
I have a node and terpene profile as it
did the first time that you did it so we
can see consistently in the lab
currently that that is not the case it
is drifting around quite a bit it is
exceptionally difficult next to
impossible to create medicine if it's
not standardized under those types of
conditions and with capital coming in we
can invest in the right infrastructure
and put down greenhouse technologies
other types of sophisticated farming
technologies that exist in other
industries utilize those tools to become
very efficient effective at producing
standardized consistent product we'll be
able to take that cultivated product and
marry it towards other types of
technologies such as pharmaceutical
technologies delivery devices other
advanced processing methodologies and
really create the next wave of products
that will deliver much more beneficial
therapeutic effects at a consistent rate
across a wide range of ailments I think
we've all seen that cannabis can touch
many different types of ailments many
different types of people can benefit
but we never know which one we're
getting we never know which composition
is going to help us and when this age is
where we're going to now start to be
able to see I know exactly what I
started with I know how I handled it I
know how I put it in my product form at
the end and now I can deliver and
consistently deliver that type of
response for patients who are looking
for it and not only does that benefit
patients but it also benefits the adult
users who may not want to feel sleepy at
the concert right so they were going to
also want to pick their specific you
know product and product types and I
think we're just starting to see this
age come about and to me that's some of
the the most interesting aspects in
addition to different cannabinoids
showing up different ratios of
cannabinoids and different terpene
profiles we'll be able to capture that
and keep them consistently to me that's
some of the most exciting aspects of the
the future that we're all creating here
yeah that's a good point and I think
that the other thing too is is that
there's this kind of one-size-fits-all
where we were kind of fooled ourselves
into believing that every plant will
grow the same way every place you grow
it and the truth is is that one thing
that we've noticed around the world is
is that cannabis plants get very very
interesting when they get acclimated to
particular environment and what we're
seeing right now is is that I would say
and not to insult my friends up north
because they're the best cannabis is
grown in California right there but what
we're seeing right now is we're seeing
people trying to grow tropical strains
you know in the in the mountains of
Trinity alright and are trying to get
you know of basically strains that were
developed for the Afghani mountains and
grow them in Hawaii and the thing is the
plant will adjust but I think we have to
really look at what's a local string and
let some of these landraces have a
chance to re-emerge and I think that
that's going to I mean I think it's
gonna be really really fascinating in
California to see what happens in the
macadamia nut belt okay where you could
truly grow these late flowering time
Hayes's and some of the things that we
haven't seen they're really a long time
can I talk to that too it's a strange
Jeff there's the thing that you're
talking about is the Stan nation for
medical purposes and I applaud that 100%
but as we get now away from the strictly
we had to talk about it's always
medicine right we know it's medicine but
now we're also talking about the
inspirational market and that
inspirational market which will be
approved by Prop 64 that is going to be
where you have your fine human Sekar or
you have your your top shelf $80 bottle
of wine and those are going to be
artisanal grows that are going to be in
nature and they're going to have
variation they're going to have
fluctuations and if you think about wine
for example the same vineyard has the
same vines year after year in the same
soil but you don't expect 1979 to be the
same as 1984 from any wine strain right
now if we're growing from seeds why
would you expect her seeds to express
themselves the same way they did last
year when the climate is different and
in fact the seeds different even though
we know the strain is trying we're
trying to breathe true for the strain so
I think that there's also going to be a
market for that really high-end totally
unique
small-batch artisanal grown that is
going to be you know it's going to cost
you because it's going to cost that
farmer a lot of that time and effort to
make that and I guess that's where we're
positioning ourselves to put first
appearance medicine out there for people
but also the most unique kind of
spiritual inspirational high and that's
where I think there's going to be that
high-end market although you will be
developing if the answers on both sides
of this which is the u.s.
standardization when we need
standardization but we also need the
artistic expression that comes with
craft and the thing is is that wine
makers and beer makers have really taken
the lead in this in a commercial sense
and and cannabis breeders and growers
have done it in an underground sense for
a long time and having them be able to
step into the light and I mean I was
talking to Dave Watson a few weeks ago
and he was talking about yeah I'm gonna
grow seventy thousand hazen seeds out
and i'm gonna find twelve plants i
really like alright and i hear that
bitches may tomorrow that's what Luther
Burbank used to do grow a whole field it
takes me out I mean it's just I mean
like having a bee Dave Watson pick the
best 12 it's on a seventy thousand
that's me sounds like like that's the
world I want to live it so
yeah yeah that's a dream come true yeah
that's a sack come true so let's talk
about
technology and in what kind of
technologies you're kind of that we have
right now but also technologies that are
kind of emerging right now there's some
really interesting things out there
right now that I think are kind of
fascinating to me I think that
vaporizers today will be looked upon
like tube radios are to somebody who's
using a state-of-the-art laser projector
and that is but but at the same time
tubes have their place that ask any
audio file I think there's going to be
this interesting mix of of kind of new
and old technologies in service of this
plant and I think there are some really
interesting technologies emerging and if
anybody want to talk about some of the
ones that they find intriguing well
it'll it'll be a very interesting
marriage of hardware and software so
much like you've seen your iPhone evolve
you're gonna see electronic cigarettes
or other delivery devices evolve that
hardware is definitely going to evolve
and we're gonna make the concentrates
and the software that's kind of going
inside of them evolve along with it so
we're starting to see compositions that
are improved and people including
terpenes in different ways so that's a
vast improvement from what we had seen
before we're seeing very different
hardware technologies certainly a lot of
people gearing up towards making
exceptionally new ones that have very
different types of compositions in terms
of internal mechanisms of how they work
how fast they may turn on what they
deliver as opposed to when this first
started a number of years ago and I
think we may even see adaption of some
of the pharmaceutical delivery devices
also being utilized in this space so I'm
I I think that it is a pretty exciting
endeavor we're gonna see like you said
there's a lot of people that will say I
still trust the old stuff that was right
for me but we'll see a very rapid
evolution over the next two to three
years I believe in seeing very different
types of hardware come out and hopefully
there'll be improved for both
composition and safety we'll be able to
study them to say they're delivering
consistently because then I think you
can really roll on that product being
delivering the exact response every
single time that you wanted and we'll
also see other delivery technologies in
terms of patches oral consumption and a
lot of ways of very you know varying
what types of molecules are delivered to
me and when
so it's an interesting time because I
think what you're seeing is you're
seeing companies like I'm psyche coming
out of Israel right now that says they
can deliver like a cartridge that
delivers exactly the same microgram dose
of a cannabinoid terpenoid entourage to
the patient every time
when you ask it well how do you do that
well it's a secret processing technique
and
there's a lot of hype out there too but
I think what it is is it is that you
know I still haven't found a vaporizer
that can actually top the taste of my
technique with a pipe and so I want to
see that happening in vapor Isis I want
to see somebody be able to deliver a
terpene entourage in a way that's really
great because right now for me a lot of
these Terp tout concentrates in these ii
pens it's the difference between crystal
light and real lemonade okay where it
tastes like oh yeah yeah that tastes
about as much like grape juice as grape
kool-aid does and and what does it say
oh it's cush
so anyway but I also one thing about the
vape pens let's not forget that they are
landfill and the whole sort of you know
some of them are better than others but
most of those vape pens out there you
use them and you throw them away that's
just one more thing in the trash heap so
keep that in mind also now there are
other ways to vapor course with the
volcanoes and so on and so forth but you
know I'm such an old hippie I just like
to smoke my joints but the reason I like
to smoke my joints is actually I think
that the joint is the only way you get
everything and what I mean by that is
when you start out your joint it's at
room temperature and it's already off
gassing vows to organic terpenes and
you're taking those in it you can dry
hit and get a really delightful taste I
recommend that but now as you light it
and that cinder moves through what the
stuff at the end of the joint at your
mouth that goes from room temperature on
a continuous scale all the way up to
combustion so as the cinder moves
through you are actually getting
everything that's in that cannabis if
you're vaping you got a very limited
temperature range and TAC volatize is at
a different temperature than CBD and
every other compound has a slightly
different temperature at which it
vaporizes so if you're smoking a vape
you're getting two or three maybe a ten
degree range of thing but if you're
smoking a joint you're getting the whole
thing that's why
by the way by the way see that's what
happens when you go to the top of the
mountain and smoke the joint okay okay
so so the bottom line is that kind of
insight I guarantee you you won't get
that in a lab but you need to okay okay
well well in just kind of I think I
think that kind of speaks to the the
standardized experience versus unique
experience situation I think I think
there's a little something for everyone
that's coming in the future and I think
maybe a lot of these like these pens
that are more processed or the terpenes
are added back there you go you can have
your standardized experience you can buy
you know what you're gonna get every
time for those people seeking a new
experience every time a unique
experience chasing that perfect strain
that perfect taste then then you go with
the joint or some of these extracts that
are that are minimally processed that
that also provide a unique experience
and unique flavor the like the rosin
yeah yeah the way that cannabis was
growing that season is gonna also come
through in that extract and so I think
there's a little something for everyone
I think and then I think the infused
products absolutely need Standardization
I think if there's one thing you can all
agree on that if you're gonna eat an
edible should know exactly how many
milligrams that edible is going to
contain because it's gonna hit you hard
if you get it wrong and any what we see
is that's where the standard a yet
actually we have growers that come
through and test every batch with us and
they're growing the same strain and if
it's off point five percent one one girl
they're they're calling us up and asking
us to retest it they've got at that
standardized even outdoor growers or
even even the same strain across a few
different growers either there's a
couple percentage points variation where
we see that why this swings are with
edibles and there's so many edibles out
there or infused products but most of
the edibles where it's just there's
certain edible matrices that are almost
impossible to get homogeneous there's
there's you know add well we're you know
beef jerky for gonna infuse beef jerky
the the jerky itself isn't even the same
size and so I think I think where we
would we can all agree that we need to
see standardization and are these
eaten eaten PhD I still have an issue
with infused beef jerky but that's
another thing either I do think I bet
I'm also kind of the libertarian side of
me really wants to support the Roulette
class of edibles
you know you buy your ticket it takes a
ride you know
but but but seriously I do pay the
slimes out that the juice products is
important work yeah we call it becoming
a cookie casual tub
yeah so one more thing from Jim and
will we're gonna go to questions okay
just following up on what Swami said
the the Pens are fine for convenience
they're great for traveling that sort of
thing but my preferred method is smoking
a joint and not smoking a giant blunt
either I like to smoke a regular ol
little joint that I've been growing all
my life and what I've always thought is
that when you're smoking like a blunt
with an enormous amount of
grass in it and you're
dropping in on that and creating huge
amount of smoke you're really burning
this stuff you know you're not
vaporizing it at all because I've always
thought that as you draw on the joint
what you're really getting is what's
heated before that red-hot coal our
ember is burning this stuff so it's
really that heating process of slowly
drawing on the joint that gives you
everything that's really there it gives
you all those dirt beans that are
boiling off at a much lower temperature
than THC and so forth down the line so
that's why I smoke like that and that's
because I think that's where you get the
most flavor and absolutely the most
effect of what is in that plan and how
you roll the joint is key - yeah exactly
and I've seen him roll a joint with one
hand on the back of a speeding Ducati
motorcycle okay but but it's also really
important I mean the thing is is it I
mean nothing I've watched people like
Kyle kushman watch somebody incinerate
his creation with like taking the
lighter and going you know and it's it's
ways things where you just want to heat
you want to just kind of liberate this
this kind of incredible operatic on the
plant and so I couldn't agree more I
mean if there's one big takeaway today
an insight it's it's really take care of
your cannabis in how you're consuming
that is the evolution of
[Music]