[Music]
this is the doctored a verse which which
is about as nice as you gonna get as far
as an email rig it's totally portable
cordless you can tune in your
temperature really easily and as you see
it hits really smoothly
and has a lotto she's about to take a
hit of our grapefruit rosin which was
pressed from this grapefruit flower
no 100% solvent free from that flower
which is grown we're up north
[Music]
red as soon as it turns green it's ready
to go yeah definitely and you can choose
like as much as as much as you want as
far as like size of your of your inhale
and and combine that with your
temperature and really that customize
[Music]
and the bubbler is just killing me
definitely a fan of the doctor Denver
[Music]
that's like you don't need the blowtorch
you don't need to worry about even what
your temperature is the previous method
which still has some validity is the
blowtorch and your temperature gun so
you know exactly where you're getting
your your titanium nail at this is just
a standard rig that we converted and to
just your traditional you know rig
you know just three-stage percolator
okay so I guess that concentrates market
can be kind of
but you know split up and obviously like
dabbing but also yeah definitely
what are you guys seeing in the market
well a big part of what we settled on is
just like our own end user experience
with cut with concentrates and there is
a bigger push for kind of a response to
like solvents being used as a response
to like Dho going with solvent free and
so we you know I've been making that
product for a few years now and so I was
also had some insight and recognizing
that you could still get a good quality
product without having to did you
utilize any any sort of solvents or and
you're always gonna have people that are
diehard BHO fans or solvent ethanol fans
and that's fine because you can still
make good quality product it would those
with those methods ours is just really
making it simple kind of going back to
how it used to be just this is heat and
pressure and basically hashish and in
full spectrum which is another thing you
see across the board with like teachers
topicals pop on berkeley like you know
they're big big on full spectrum for all
all of the teachers and we definitely
respect them as a brand they're doing
the same thing that we're doing as far
as using just heat and pressure to
extract their hash oil and then using
that homogenizing that with their custom
blend of oils for their various products
so then what's great about it is once
you've dialed in your hash product you
can find out what your cannabinoid
ratios are and then just combine that
with you whatever carrier oil you're
working with and you can really get a
consistent product that's like
full-spectrum 100% quality every time
talk about
you know everybody thinks of DAP I mean
of Rossum presses is kind of like you're
doing small batch so how do you how do
you paint the vision of a manufacturing
facility that well really in in order to
get the quality it needs to be at that
scale it's it's really impossible to
completely upscale on the same way that
you could with with BHO or ethanol
machines just because of the physics of
it
so what it requires is a lot of labour
so this product is is born out of love
like well if you're gonna be involved in
making rod at Rossum you're you're gonna
want to be committed to doing things and
not necessarily the easy way it needs it
takes a lot of fine-tuning a lot of
back-and-forth each bag just by looking
at each bag that we packed full of
cannabis you know it each one's a little
bit different a little bit thicker a
little bit longer wider and it's amazing
what you can pull out of it and so that
affects how quickly you're gonna press
down you know what pressure you're gonna
start with end up with
well like what did what did he bitch to
you about recently and what did he bitch
about to you recently and like I was
frustrated about our excitedly well the
other day he wanted a little bit lighter
color out of the rosin so I had to do
some experimenting you know on the
temperature and also on the bag the
micron size of the bag and it you know
took a few hours about half the day but
I gave him the results that he wanted
I used a smaller micron bag and it
reduces your yield but it gives you a
little bit higher quality and lowered
the temperature just a little bit which
also can reduce the yield but it's all
it's a lot of you know experimenting and
each bag you know you drop down five
degrees it still doesn't give you the
effect you want you got a you know pack
another bag and try it again
so there's a lot if you really pay
attention to the variables of
temperature pressure and then you know
micro micron size time and then bag
geometry which is how big is it because
there's the pressure of your machine but
what's really hat what's where's the
pressure at the bag and so that is
directly related to your bag geometry so
once you dial in one you just gotta have
to keep pushing forward with you know
answering some of the other variables
but it's it's working as far as mass or
as far as manufacturing it's it's doable
and we're working off of one press and
we could definitely do a lot more yeah
it stands up eh oh it's like right here
end of the table to about oh the surface
of all the heat the actual heat plate is
it's only about you know twelve inches
by two and a half inches three inches
and the reason why you want that is so
I've worked with larger plates as well
like so if you imagine a really large
plate you can get a larger mass that you
are you know pressing but it's not gonna
press this evenly and then if you once
that oil starting to be
did you want it to get off those plates
as quickly as possible and cooled down
as quickly as possible that's exactly so
exactly so narrow plate you could you
get your bag packed up right to it all
of that squish is gonna come out and
then you can even collect it onto a cold
plate if you want something that's been
in the freezer exactly yeah yeah yep yep
and you there are presses out there that
are our square shape peer-pressured
makes a great press I love their press
and and I and that's what I use and the
reason why I like them more than
anything was their attention to their
plate sizes and not and really not
focusing on like more pressure means
more yield because that's not
necessarily true like there's a sweet
spot that you need to you need to find
him you can actually get great yield
great and maintain quality without you
know going like super excess of pressure
or super excess of heat because those
are the two typical ways that you
typically boost up you absolutely even
how fast the plate compresses so if
you're with flour you want a fast
compression when you're doing something
like kief or bubble hash something
that's a little bit more dense you want
to slow down that press you could
potentially make the bag explode or
cause it to heat like I'm heat unevenly
so it's so there's a lot of factors but
but once it's what's nice about it
though it's mechanical all its it's
simple and calm it's not complex it's
simple it's still mechanical process
it's easy to control your variables your
runs are fast and once you've once
you've figured out for this particular
strain or that or this technique he's
dialed in it's just to can go I mean
[Music]
two to three inches so when you guys are
doing this at scale like how many
precedents do you have in your visit or
how many of you envision having in your
facility I I'd say probably like five or
five to ten just really depending on
Broome I mean ultimately that's what it
really boils down to and just go in all
day 24/7 absolutely 24/7 easy so what
are like some when you guys are talking
to each other like innovations you want
to see something that I'd like to see is
something that I like that mean I think
peer pressure has got the plate size
down and and the right amount of tonnage
that they're using but I also appreciate
a hand app and press it would be nice to
see a good quality combination of the
two especially when you're exactly
especially when you're first learning to
press there's nothing that replaces like
that connection to feeling the bag and
and and really understanding physically
what's going on and and that actually as
you get more versed in the extraction
you can use that as a quick way to
diagnose of you know remedy or do some
troubleshooting is by just like alright
what is actually going on physically at
the bag that seems kind of silly but it
works
[Music]
in like five minutes
I am definitely interested in tinctures
one of the things that I really
appreciate about our rosin and our rosin
line is speaking you can also make you
know instead of having be edible or you
don't really know what your dough scene
is it's like having a nice one you know
a milliliter dropper with it at a dose
that I know where it's at and I also
know that that has come from like a
solvent free immunity and it's full full
spectrum that and I mean those actually
those are the two big things being rosin
and tinctures really taking rosin oh
that's really hot so live resin I mean
that's basically cryogenic technique
where you are making sure that the the
trichomes on their plant are frozen
right you know when you write at that
time before just before harvest where
the terpenes on the on your fresh plant
are so like just Turkey it they smell so
good and then you know you you you cut
you dry and you cure and it doesn't
quite have that same that impact and
that's because though all those terpenes
have volatilized
so that with the the live resin
processes and like fresh frozen because
they're taking care taking that plant
trimming it and then within hours
hopefully instantaneously getting it in
into a freezer
that's flash frozen and then that
preserves all those terpenes that's
really exciting you can use that same
flower to make rosin BHO any sort of x
extraction and you're gonna you're gonna
have a much wider terpene profile to
play with and you know a different
experience for the product because of
that absolutely yeah they're small
smaller the molecular weight
it seems like everything should or is
focused on kind of how do you keep as
much of the yes into that plan yeah
exactly right exactly
what innovations are you seeing there
and nothing losing none of the essence
of what was in the flower today I think
really fresh frozen is probably the
closest thing and just doing what we're
doing with with rosin is trying is
trying to create a product that is as
close to the flower as possible so like
if you were smell you know our flower
that's been pressed or the the rosin
that's been pressed from the flower they
have the same terpene profile the same
what do you guys see like what are the
first to go off the top of my head it
couldn't tell you but they I could tell
you they go start to come off around 170
Celsius and man it's not little blue but
I kept the top of my etiquette I can't
tell you but I but it's trying to do low
temp presses is really what's what is
gonna capture can keep all those between
one 70s in South this is in Celsius or
between 90 and 170 Celsius and so you're
gonna actually start to get terpenes
volatilizing much sooner than not at 170
Celsius but like at 70 degrees like even
you have room temperature and so trying
to make sure that you know you keep keep
as much as you can without you know we'd
still getting a product that's the
balance because you still have to have
yield you still have to have something
you have to get something you could you
could use all pressure and very very low
temperature and get you know capture the
most terpene profile but you're you're
gonna probably get 10th to 20th of what
you should if you you know kind of bump
up the temperature and find that happen
absolutely well exactly and you can also
do mechanical separations so we've been
able to do like low temp mechanical
separations and get THCA that's actually
something I'm really excited about and
it's it's really nice to be able to get
again thca
without having to use solvents and it's
it's a real straightforward process with
with rosin you're just you're doing a
mechanical separation through really
fine screens multiple runs and you're
collecting your turf terpenes that are
pouring off and you're you so you're
collecting that and your product is
actually what's on the inside which
would typically be your waste product
you know the chip the flour chip or the
keys chip that you throw away or recycle
this the actual product is THC a crystal
that's been the last stuff we got tested
was like ninety nine six all without so
all without solvents how can you tell
I'm actually his apprentice he really
I'm just learning the ropes but I think
I'm on my way to really learning the you
know the chemistry behind the planet
brain hurt because it got such a workout
well at first I didn't believe him that
each bag would be a different and each
one would take you know you have to keep
your eyes on it to an extreme early and
you got to know how it responds and how
it likes to be treated and it really is
an art rosin pressing and it's
it's taken my interest to a whole nother
level and I really love every second