[Music]
really boring really it's efficiencies
kind of all we talk about you know math
and numbers on how can we save a couple
pennies over here on energy versus using
big screens like if I had to boil down
what was said today is that uh membranes
which is a big filter that that was kind
of like the takeaway that I think will
be most valuable to the most amount of
people that was something that it's been
out there but it's been not as openly
talked about as it was today so that was
interesting I thought I saw the
hesitation and no his eyes saying it out
loud and then he went with it so it's
interesting it was immediately there and
he was just like all right oh yeah dread
pirate is here with some of this crc and
that stuff was incredible oh yeah I
think it was a dinner but uh oh look how
about that you got the good stuff
who is no with he was with Harry and Ken
and ace from beaker and wrench that was
a good one I like that one
dread pirate he's on the forum he's the
guy that first released the CRC tech on
the forum kind of like the first draft
of it with him in the end Oh fab guys
it's like a remediation of the
impurities that you don't necessarily
want or need to smoke a lot of them are
color compounds and other random things
you do tend to pull a little bit of some
of like the ethers or not eat there's uh
esters and and aldehydes and alcohols
which kind of changes the smell we still
got a really bright turkey smell from it
and all the mids but some of the lower
ones seem to sometimes tend to drag
behind in the column in the Sierra see I
definitely see RC stuff that looks
amazing and then tastes like trim you
know because it doesn't get rid but i've
also had I've also had some CR Sita I
think people aren't filtering enough and
I definitely dab some that had some
filtration media left in it davin on
yeah something that people need to like
make sure they're filtering that shit
you know that's my main thing I heard
that a Chas the a Chas bold did the same
thing
don't be shy I mean that's the future of
you know with great power with great
power comes great responsibility and
when we're starting to take these
chemistry routes that isn't you know
they're not it's not just you know
making some charas what is going on with
dead skin and shit
yeah it's returning returning a point
into actual you know trying to adopt
pharmaceutical science and as absurd as
homegrown pharmaceutical Sciences it's
what this one country that's something
else so what this industry has done for
the last seventy years means since
Prohibition we've had to find our own
ways about doing things and that right
there is the culmination of it it's you
know the ultimate fuck you - that's the
ethereal the ethereal who I guess really
whatever is trying that's that gets to a
personal level almost a spiritual level
but what this means this is what happens
when people you know are you could call
it entrepreneurship you could call it
capitalism but you know this is
innovation the fluid innovation in
progress I mean we're watching it happen
day by day and man it's just fascinating
to be able to be a part of it come to
work with a plant under while being
under immense oppression or you know
obstacles or just you know legalization
or whatnot sacrifice the potential for
your livelihood to even do science with
this plan in the first place kind of
comes to I guess like that accumulation
where it's like this is the best science
we could do and bama's you know it's
like next-level shit you know well this
is you know this is what happens when
people innovate for themselves and we're
not relying on massive corporations to
take our innovation you know by the
hills and do it for us because when you
get to a certain point I mean you just
can't I mean that was Dustin's talk you
can't beat the open source it's not
happening
you would smoke that blood starting
material credit to the Grover credit to
the processor it's all parts of the
whole
it takes excellence in every step
possible but the interesting thing is
really the potential that we have to do
I mean these same refinement techniques
will take the will take place in other
industries and other nutraceutical I
mean we talked about a lot of mycology
today and all these same refinement
techniques are going to come up sooner
or later
and it's cool if you can use cannabis
with it but I know with I'm sure I don't
know I'm sure the ball container
corporation is pretty happy with all of
their mason jar sales and I'm sure
there's some refineries out of Texas who
has see these new places popping up
they're capitalizing on it what kind of
technique thing a different industry
will learn from us you know compared to
you know
[Music]
just like you guys are doing cool crazy
shit that people do extraction that's
actually they do co2 they do co2
extraction and also I don't know they
they make like a distillate product
which has terpenes that they post inject
to like flavor their stuff it's it's
pretty phenomenal opportunity we run
like super high margin which allows us a
lot of flexibility to run R&amp;D on our
product - I think that that helps and
the type of person that's in cannabis in
the cannabis industry right now is not
the same type of person that may have
gone a more traditional route with a
less you know they're they're they're
not as willing to take risk right as the
typical cannabis person is because we've
been taking risk the whole fucking time
so you kind of have a different type of
person and that there's you know there's
pros and cons to each different side but
one of them is that we can have rapid
development and adaptation of new
technologies better than any other
industry we've that I've seen we can
scour the internet for obscure little
pieces of data and convert it into
something that's making billions of
dollars like what show me another
industry that's doing something like
that
this is like the first cannabis cannabis
snowman
that I've been to since I got a 10-year
federal prison sentence for a cannabis
conspiracy yeah so this so you know just
just being able to come back and see my
like I've known Boris for 20 years I've
known you know a bunch of these guys so
just to be able to come out and see
these guys now my homies 10 years later
like you know industry leaders and
leading the way and and they ain't got
nothing to worry about you know I mean
and it's cool and I feel like that's
amazing you know it's a beautiful thing
to see and you know it's definitely
something we need to pay reverence to
but we also need to realize there's
still plenty of people locked up because
of this bull should we do it every
single day