[Music]
you are at spannabis so one maybe talk
about like what you're seen in Europe
like if you're seeing any differences in
the European or specifically the
Barcelona market and then like NorCal
and then kind of trans you see yeah yeah
well it's a trip because I'm gonna go
back a little bit in time but I learned
from Europeans originally how to make
hash I learned from Mila back in the
early 2000s I traveled to Europe in
Amsterdam and learn from Mila and
nowadays me and Mila travel the world
teaching and Mila will say things like
how nicotine me about fresh frozen and
talk Europe about fresh frozen so you
know I think a lot of the American
market learned from Europe originally
we've now since given a lot of tips and
trends to the European market and we've
now just been trading a lot of tech back
and forth I've done live demonstrations
in Europe for over ten years now from
Amsterdam to now Barcelona and teaching
a lot of technique in that realm doing
live demonstrations but also receiving a
lot of information and learning every
single day that I go out there you know
the power system is different in Europe
than it is you know I say it's just even
converters for the harvest right freeze
dryers you know there's there's some
cool things happening in Europe cool
trends one of the coolest things that I
see is Europe has the opportunity to do
a lot more large-scale Fino hunting so
they're able to do pop a million seeds
in in Morocco in places like that phenol
hunt and Morocco and bring back those
keepers to Spain I've seen Fino hunts on
a larger scale than what I've seen in
the United States so I've seen a lot of
hash strings you know they're seeing
really cool numbers and terpene profiles
from the strains that they're Fino
hunting for making hash I want to big up
people like la colada
in Barcelona people like HQ slight over
there at the HQ lab people like la
sagrada farm turps army just crushing it
out there in the solvent list world and
it's really cool to see because they're
piping that whole mechanical separated
side of things the salt on the side a
lot more than the United States Europe
has grown up smoking hash so it's really
cool to see them bringing this quality
of hash that we're seeing this in the
United States that same high-end quality
of our live rosin things like that and
taking it to another level as well I'm
gonna mention lock a lotta again because
they've gotten even further than the US
with our rows and coins lock Lauda's now
laser etching their rosin coins with
logos and people's images so they made
me one with my essential extracts image
on it and so just some cool artistic
factions to the solid in this world out
there
now you mentioned solvent list do you do
you personally operate within so since
day one I've really promoted and stood
behind solvent list back in the early
2000s when we started making hash there
wasn't a lot of information out there on
hydrocarbons butane specifically and the
heavy metals and things left behind we
didn't have all the purge technology we
didn't even have closed loops back then
in the early 2000s so after you know 15
excuse me 15 years or so I've learned so
much when it comes to the hydrocarbon
side and solvent side of things that we
now are working on some products that
we're utilizing hydrocarbons and ethanol
and other chemical solvents because in
reality in a solvent las' lab that i've
been operating in for the last 10 to 15
years you know making water hash and dry
sieve and mechanical separated products
we've noticed that a lot of the strains
and a lot of the material I get are just
not viable in that mechanical world but
they may be extremely viable in the
hydrocarbon world we may actually be
able to pull a lot more of those viable
turf
and the oils via different chemical
solvents that pull different parts of
the plant basically so a good example
and this is an old-school example but I
like to use it blue dream in solvent
list that original cut clone only blue
dream yields maybe between 1 and 5
percent but when we run it via
hydrocarbons we're actually able to
retain a lot of those terpenes and we're
seeing 18 to 24 percent yields that same
strain so it's a viability thing and
it's also a quality thing you know when
we run it mechanically or solvent Leslee
we retain a lot more though that waxy
cuticle on the outside whereas the
hydrocarbons are rupturing it and
they're able to separate it a lot easier
I think it's a great thing because it's
created a market for that strain and
there's other strains now like that that
have a similar trichome structure so I
just used blue dream as an example I
know that there's a lot of hate these
days on blue dream it kind of got played
out you know like a lot of other things
in this world where people just over
consume it they liked it a lot in the
beginning it yields well for the
hydrocarbon side it yields well on the
flower side and then it's just kind of
overplayed out people sell it you know
and it just gets hyped out of the circle
basically so for your own personal
production process do you see a scenario
where maybe you do like a first press
solvent list to get like all the best
stuff and then take everything that's
left over and do a second there's
there's ways to create viability with
that yes for you know that's how we like
to test things once you find out that
the blue dream is not going to be good
and solving this we're not gonna run it
and solvent us however when we find a
strain like Mike MD oh gee that does
amazing in solvent lists say you know
I'm yielding over 28 30 percent each and
every time no matter who grows that
strain I run it I yield that much
there's still some by-product left in
that material that we've ran that you
can do other you know make other
works with for sure and why do you think
that yields more in the solvent listen
area you dream
it's a trichomes structure the chem do G
has a lot bigger of a trichome head a
thinner cuticle it breaks the head off a
lot easier on that chem do G compared to
breaking the head and the stocks and
some plant material on that blue dream
because the trichomes a lot more fragile
on the blue dream the chem d has just a
lot sturdier of a trichome head that
breaks off a lot easier plus the biggest
thing with it after scoping it and
running it and processing it to rosin
afterwards we've noticed that that chem
D and other strains you know similar in
nature and trichome structure have a
thinner waxy cuticle to the amount of
oils inside so the amount of oils inside
are a lot more 8090 percent oils
compared to about you know a 10% waxy
cuticle if not less to be completely
honest compared to something like blue
dream which almost has 80% wax and about
20% oil and in the center of it
it's just how that trichome grows and
there's other things that you can do to
affect that waxy cuticle not using as
many salts not not using as much sugar
in man process flushing better will
actually grow more oil compared to wax
so flushing that turning those sugars
into oils in that end process of the
flowering plant will definitely help
reduce your wax to oil ratio so as an
extraction artist you're definitely
reliant on cultivators who are some of
the cultivators that you love working
with yeah you know there's a lot and
I've operated out in Colorado for a long
time we worked with you know some close
family dank by Pank was one our main
producers in Colorado along with the 14
er the farm we had a few greenhouse
grows down in Pueblo that crushed out
for us as well
coming to the California market I've
looked at farm after farm I've done a
few collaborations there's a few out
there on the shelves right now as we
speak some of my favorite farms to run
fresh
and so far been Callie kosher that farm
is crushing out there greenhouses are
amazing the strains are proper and where
it is they're out in the Central Valley
out in that area yeah and yeah they're
they're really paying attention to
running strains that are good for hash
fielding finding those phenotypes and
growing them properly they're actually
kosher certified you know as we move
into a more regulated market we're able
to see more things of that nature
certifications clean green
certifications things of that nature and
I look for those certifications I want
people to be testing the soil I want
them to be testing their flour as much
as possible aside from the COAS that are
regulated to actually enter the market
so yeah proactivity is key for me and
what are some of the strains that
they're growing that you're sort of
currently excited about it yeah you know
we did some trials for the fresh frozen
of this for this hash cone this full
mount hash cone collaboration and I
really really really like the friddle's
forbidden fruit times skittles so that
one's going into play for this
collaboration I also really like this
lemon bean which is a lemon tree x OG
Eddy leppe it's one of the first lemon
strains that really has that lemon rind
that still produces insolvent lists
because after years and years of testing
the lemon Jie the lemon tree a lot of
these lemon strains out there just don't
yield for mechanical separations or
solvent 'less extractions
but this lemon bean did work so so you
mentioned fresh fruit and I feel like
fresh frozen kind of came on the scene a
couple of years ago and farmers you know
like I remember talking to Craig from
talking trees farms a good friend of
mine you know
what percent of my farm of that am I
going to allocate to fresh frozen it was
like okay
like a 25% and I would assume this year
based on how last year one he's gonna
he'll like it either more or less so
it's a big side of what we do is it
consulting on that you know helping
farmers go from doing dry drying they
actually you know one of the big selling
points for me coming in is I'm able to
take a whole dry room convert that into
a mom stable or another flowering room
so you're producing more stability in
your in your farm with a mom room or
producing higher numbers and bigger
margins if you're gonna turn a dry room
into another flowering room you're
cutting down on your staff and the
amount of employees that you don't know
coming into your facility via trim staff
etc because you're able to buck fresh
frozen plants Bigley from and freeze
them without having a trim staff sitting
there over a table trimming the material
so we can get rid of that cost and that
security issue
and yeah just freeing up the space
freeing up the cost going straight into
a freezer we're coming in with freezer
trucks able to pick up this fresh frozen
material I think it just helps the
fluidity of a floor of a farm turning
over well now let's talk about during
the equation what do you like more about
getting fresh frozen material versus
what like five years ago you probably
weren't getting anything fresh frozen
right
I've been running fresh frozen for about
ten years now okay works so let's talk
about ten years ago the day before you
ever first at your first fresh frozen to
the day after and like what was the mind
like holy shit this is game-changing the
oil and the terpene retention you know
when we're talking about dry material
that's been handled especially if we're
talking about trim and the bottom of the
bag and things like that a lot of the
trichome heads have already broken off
without me breaking them off and when
they are broken off with that type of
agitation in the bottom of a turkey bag
you're grabbing a lot more plant
material and you're grabbing a lot more
of the stuff that you don't want waxes
plant material things of that nature
when I get fresh frozen material I'm
able to really control that variable and
break off the trichome heads properly if
we can keep our environment cold the
water and ice mixture cold before that
fresh frozen material hits I'm able to
really just break off the trichome heads
and because they're frozen straight from
harvest it's retaining a lot more of
those air volatile turbines the terpenes
that just want to escape into the air
just naturally so because it's fresh
frozen we're able to retain a lot more
of those and just a quality control
thing the less hands on that material
the less it's been touched and agitated
the higher quality and product we can
retain so now to talk live resin live
resin compared to live rosin or just in
general I feel like that's sort of new
wish to the scene live resin really hit
the the commercial market at the same
time fresh frozen hit so about 10 years
yeah really around the finish line in
Colorado for you yeah like I think the
California market on concentrates was
Baja it was lagging Colorado it's crazy
to say that you know I'm I'm California
I'm from California I think that a lot
of Californians you know would probably
agree but be surprised you know that
that Colorado really pushed forward with
that concentrate market but in reality I
think one of the reasons we were in
Colorado able to push forward with the
concentrate market and create this
higher echelon of products is because we
came with regulation first Colorado was
the first to implement these new laws of
regulation recreational tightening down
on all the compliance side of things
and uh you know we were able to write
things down first in Colorado I moved
back to Colorado to operate essential
extracts in 2009 because Colorado was
the first place to allow me to pay taxes
on hashish California wouldn't let me
yet so Colorado really gave me the
opportunity to study and to write these
things down and to replicate our
processes so it's it's crazy to say but
I think that Colorado really stepped up
game when it came to concentrates and
did exceed California for a minute now
California is you know I'm pushing back
with the regulatory system that's coming
into place here new recreational
cannabis just keep pushing that Echelon
you know only the strong will survive
right now yeah well so this is this is
an interesting story we had first
started running fresh frozen when I was
working with a company called pink house
in Colorado and this is 2010
so almost 10 years ago is when we really
started running fresh rose in the
commercial market and it's funny because
this this gentleman and I'm not even
named his name of his face in his name
right now but kind of a negative person
in our industry kept coming at me being
like you don't know what you're doing
you're not running a live material and I
thought about it and this was you know
ten years ago - I'm like eleven - what's
this guy talking about he's a little
kooky but he might have something with
that term and so we actually pulled down
this Skywalker plants I think we had a
row of six lights of Skywalker where my
partner at pink house was like have at
it try it live try it fresh and so at
this point we didn't even freeze that
material this was straight bucking down
a whole plant shucking off the big
leaves and chucking off the buds into a
fresh frozen bucket and we were hand
paddling this bucket ten years ago and
we came out with this amazing live oil
as what we were calling it live solvent
less oil and it was a lot more oily than
the dry material running a lot more
terpene heavy just potent this stuff was
crazy the Skywalker back then was og
Mazhar it wasn't the Skywalker og that
we know today it was an older Skywalker
Fino that was Mazzara times blueberry
sorry I think I said oh gee
but Mazar times in mazar-i-sharif times
blueberry and had this Talat osis funk
to it and when we ran it live it was
even that much more intense the room
smelled like death in a good way and
from there we really started promoting
that term that live term because then we
started playing with freezing that
material and running it in our solvent
'less situation and we were doing
collaborations and working with friends
of ours in the industry one of those
friends and one of those companies back
then got together and a few of the heads
got together in the same room and I
might not be explaining the story how
they explained it this is exactly how I
remember it we were all at giddy-up slab
and it was kind bill and rye Pritchard
and a few of the other friends over
there at giddy up slab and we started
talking about how the psalmist guys were
doing this live material and they wanted
to try it fresh frozen live material in
the hydrocarbons set up and that's where
live rosin came from later we dubbed
live or sorry that's where live resin
came from later we dubbed the term live
rosin for fresh frozen hash that we then
pressed into rosin so live resin came
first before the term live rosin but the
idea of fresh frozen and running live
material actually came from the salt in
this world live resin is via hydrocarbon
butane extraction fresh frozen butane
extraction is live resin live rosin is
fresh frozen mechanical separation or
fresh frozen solvent list extraction so
live rosin we're running fresh frozen
material into live water hash and then
we press that water hash into rosin
that's live rosin and on the other side
of things they're using a closed loop
system
with jacketing and running at sub
temperatures here in California who are
some of the extraction artists that are
impressing you in 20 19 20 18 20 minutes
then there's a lot there's a lot of
really cool extract artists out there
just pushing the boundaries of what a
solvent lease extraction you know really
means I got friends like Rackham solvent
list that's crushing it and that
mechanically separated side soil grown
solving this is doing really good work
man there's so many like what are the
nuances of some of their technique like
I'm sure so you guys talk technique and
like how'd you like this is amazing like
what you do and they're like this is
what I did you're like holy shit that's
clever so what are some you know if
people are pushing the boundaries my
assumption is that's that's a technique
yeah you know on innovation compared to
making bubble hash in my uncle's hot
barn in Mendocino you know 20 years ago
in an uncontrolled environment
uncontrolled mid starting material we
were making kind of brown pliable
mildewy smelling bubble hash for years
and things have changed a lot since then
we've really promoted the controlled
environment aspect of making water hash
so people are using walk-in freezers and
it's one of the first things I promoted
on a John Doe radio show back in
2009-2010 was I make my hash in a
walk-in freezer so after taking a look
at all these different labs via
collaborations in California seeing the
different nuances and differences
between different extract artists you
know it's it's really cool to see what
we came from from making hash and a hot
barn to now all of these extraction
artists are working in walk-in freezers
and really really controlling their
environment which is cool to see and
just the slight differences are really
cool to see as well I promote creating
an ice water bath that you have full
temperature control before you even put
your material in there I've seen some of
these extract artists put their material
on the bottom of a bucket with ice in it
and then start adding room-temperature
water and
I think it's cool that I'm able to see
some these differences and come in and
you know change some of their SOPs and
learn from them as well so you know it's
really cool to see all these changes
happening in our industry and people
sharing freely because it's pushing the
boundaries of what we can do and it's
creating a higher echelon for the
products we're making out here so talk
about you just mentioned SOPs what are
some of the common things when you walk
into someone's operation that you know
if I talk to people who consult with
cultivators it's like they don't pick a
couple of things that they're noticing
yeah one of the things that I've been
trying to change as I go into facilities
is now that a lot of people have gone
that walk-in freezer route it's rad and
they're working the walk-in freezer and
they're retaining those terpenes and the
stability of the product but the second
they walk out of their walk-in freezer
oftentimes these walk-in freezers are
placed in cultivations and other
facilities that aren't completely
temperature humidity controlled
throughout the entire facility so I've
been coming in and helping people design
the actual flow of these laboratories
and controlling the temperature and
humidity in the entire square foot of
the building through the walkways etc
it's creating a lot more shelf stability
is what I'm seeing because when you go
from your walk-in cooler to a 75 degree
50% humidity and humidity environment
you're almost mitigating you know the
fact that you're using that control in
the walk-in freezer by coming out into
that environment so I've been helping
facilities with not only their launch
but they're built out at this point it's
one of the cool things that I've learned
just coming from a psychology background
and a hash making background I've now
done you know learn to design and Sketch
up and convert that into CAD and help
these companies come online with a
proper infrastructure and actually
building
[Music]