[Music]
that's the GMO right there you ready
smell it I just feel like it's only see
it on fake packaging kind of like how
Noah was saying he makes brass knuckles
I was like and I only see them on the
Instagram of people who are like you
know three more states east of me you
know talking about DHA and we're like
yeah we know that already but yeah it's
like blue hit like you could tell that
it's so surprising that it was so such a
knockoff that's because he's like so
sweet and innocent it doesn't know that
so people be out here who didn't like
literally anything in us and he's like
oh I make distillate for breath like
like it's not an actual source but you
know what now what I could do is get
some from him and flex so hard on the
whole internet
I am real I'm gonna come cat what room
is it do you know Pasadena cool in that
hallway I'll come catch you I want to
see her she's so sassy Oh perfect I just
like listening to her talk I like her
her attitude on stage do you want to dab
okay another one yeah nice yeah you guys
go in the events later this evening like
whatever yeah we just got our I'm sorry
to pop some of those seeds I saw that I
saw that I saw them in Portland talking
about like Auto flower seeds then I was
like you know I still keep a little grow
like just for my own hobby has been kind
of laborious I'm like maybe I should
just switch over to you know Auto flower
and just like have one room and just put
them in the little flower and then just
go from seed every time I just got some
crop King III think Clapton was I don't
know I are there a lot of people in the
auto flower game I guess some are better
than others and that's actually what I'm
interested
kind of exploring like everybody talks
about Mephisto so I want to see like I
want to grow it out myself and be like
it's pretty good yeah I mean what's
sweet about it um like because people
are if you like look in the like it's
like the autumn flower groups and stuff
like the people that are against like
aggressively angrily against it and it's
like you know you could just like grow a
plant and if it doesn't work out like
you just grow another plant like a
different plan you know like the
consequences of it not working out or
like pretty small unless you like just
plant 50 acres cuz you don't research
her yes of course please try whatever
you want
maybe the GMO or the peanut butter
brothers some diamonds oh yeah so I've
got they're basically all diamonds kind
of fundamentally because the terpene
contents higher so they just always
separate anyway but yeah I've got sour
Clementine over here this one's a
raspberry light key and then this one's
death by cookies which is Death Star and
cookies which is a weird combination
I love the jars yeah they actually hate
them no the opaque part is a requirement
for regulations and so yeah and so the
way the companies make the jars opaque
is they just paint a clear jar so inside
the jar you can see the imperfections of
the paint job on the outside of the jar
so it looks like there's black shit in
my hash because it's like a wrinkle in
the paint
behind the jar you know and so it's
maddening to package and you can't tell
if they're like is a thing in your hash
or not and then people take a picture
yeah so that is delicious so the paint
part is a typical but yeah so
super-clean so you know are you just
doing it yourself are you in with the
company yeah so I have a couple of
things going on but I started a partner
with Santo Gardens which is not a garden
at all mostly because I got involved and
so I turn to their grow rooms into
extraction space because I needed more
room so we are live resin only
processing company all we make is live
resin it's all filtered through
absorbance using that like all cozy or
CTA so um you know it's just that one
product and that one niche and we do the
best that we possibly can
and I got involved with them because
they were brand new to the market 2019
is a really interesting year to decide
to become a medical dispensary in Denver
CO or a medical myth in Denver Colorado
because the market is crazy saturated
with a lot of competitive low pricing
you know low quality on the inputs like
it's you know all of the premier brands
are running the exact same material so
it's really hard to have a like angle
over anyone else and what I needed was a
place to try out my experiments on
higher quality material because I'd just
been consulting for the previous 5 years
and under the pretense of consulting
people bring you in because things are
not going well because the material is
poor because the equipment is non
performing they don't call you and
they're like so things are going really
well our material is extremely
high-quality and we're just wondering
what we can do to get better like that's
never the higher yeah so I needed a
place to test some ideas and Santo
Gardens allowed me to come in the lab
and try out some weird stuff with their
freshmen so that's where I'm getting to
this so what it's often referred to as
color remediation I don't like that name
because color is in a compound and some
things that are colored aren't
contaminants and some things are so it's
a bad way to describe it but it's the
you know
the nomenclature of the day and the idea
there's we're using polar adsorbents to
remove polar compounds within our
extraction process and so with a
hydrocarbon as their solvent it's
extremely nonpolar most of our target
compounds like terpenes and cannabinoids
are nonpolar and so those adsorbents
disallow the things that we don't want
like moisture things that are soluble in
moisture heavy metals pesticides salts
sugars stuff that we don't want in our
final product and it allows everything
else through we don't know exactly what
the perfect ratio of like the ideal you
know hash oil really is but it you know
when you compare like the high-end
solvent list to the high-end solvent
made we have the same compounds we're
gonna see almost the same thca ratios in
your high-end versus mine we're gonna
see really high terpene ratios in your
high-end versus mine because it turns
out that if you do a really good job
extracting you get the but but like but
to be fair I mean Mary told me my first
Lite hydrocarbon right so much
respecting the IDS on fire by the way
it's very following and like yeah it's a
it's a yeah so I'm I'm partial to like
hydrocarbon extractions and it is
because the product it's the best
extraction methodology and of course
people out there would argue about
crying ethanol and co2 and even refining
to distil it but yeah good you know my
hydrocarbon processes do you get you all
the trip you get you all that you need
right that what you're looking at what
know or what's in the trichome head is
another way to put it like those
materials are the ones you want the
other ones need to be filtered out
coming through
exactly ya know it's so yeah it's just
this is a client this is like yeah
definitely a lot very happy just like I
mean like I've been growing for a while
my first step into like the legit campus
world it's like you know I like
transporting myself to Denver started
building that map and like it was just
awesome I was like first I don't use
type things and like first but like
going to a place like that
facility to buy and get checked out on
cannabis extraction equipment doubtfully
a first you know so super excited and
like now getting you know games
definitely leveled up like none of these
kinds of products were being discussed
back then people just weren't at that
level we were just happy for shadow you
know we're happy to have no residual
solvents right and and for a really long
time and even still now like what people
were always chasing with concentrates
was like consistencies and colors and so
like the idea of color remediation I
feel like is remediating or our attitude
towards color more than remediating the
product of color cuz when I make these
none of these are clear when I make them
I have absolutely clear th CA and then I
have slightly colored phenols I have you
know like there are compounds of colors
that are in my you know super Nate and
my mother liquor or whatever that other
solution you know whatever you want to
call it and it just happens to still
look really clear when I you know bring
it out by the gram but like I'm not
removing color so much it's just bring
you know using every resource I have to
make it a little bit better than before
and so like back when we met that's what
getting a closed loop was like that was
still you taking advantage of every
opportunity that you could and all the
technology that was available to make
the best thing that you could and at the
time probably the best advice I had was
like use propane that's more selective
but like we get yeah we get better
because we learn more and that's not
gonna stop so you know TBD till next
year this is really exciting because
people are finally is starting to
embrace some of this change and that's
something that's been really hard to do
for a long time because the market was
so competitive everything sold there was
no reason to get better cuz if you could
just get shatter you could get money in
Colorado I mean the whole dab market was
there before anywhere else an
appreciation for extracted products and
you're basically saying that like I mean
it's good to be the one who can say and
we decided our competitive advantage
would be best quality yeah exact are
competitive in is where the cheapest or
we're the fastest melody buzz yeah yeah
yeah else has thought of that ya know in
our industry is now's the time for like
the top shelf right I do it's it's fair
point lake in the beginning not so much
here in California but definitely in
Denver it's like safe access was like
such a boom you didn't have you just had
to put out product like just put out
product people would buy it was like I
felt like especially without coming that
we were selling into a void I didn't
have to try to innovate or try to raise
the game and now yeah and look look even
this device the peak it's like
normalizing yeah we couldn't articulate
it the consumer had no palate like so
even if you think the alcohol model when
we come out of prohibition most people
are still used to drinking soda and milk
they have no refined palate for spirits
or wine or beer and that impacts America
for a while you know we they had mixed
drinks it could be a sweet thing mixed
with alcohol but refined spirits good
wine take a while to get that palate
back in cannabis there's a few of us
that may have had it earlier on and
didn't even have access to high-end
stuff we're just happy for good flowers
and whatnot or extractions you might
make it home but now people are catching
up quick right into market in Colorado
California you're both seeing a slow
like finally sure sure I think every day
of dispensaries there's a higher demand
for quality and because we can talk
about it let's just start there the fact
that like you know brand ambassadors can
go out and articulate the value
proposition and the differentiation of
what you make your products and how you
make them and like science education
like it takes TLC to innovate right and
usually people like myself like we
talked about and get passionate about
how we make our products because we're
thinking and putting like energy into it
and like I think consumers resonate with
that they're like all that those dudes
are doing it real like there that's good
stuff and then like and then they taste
and everybody's palate is different and
and look I'm really psyched on
concentrates because this could like
these kinds of devices in this kind of
session could mitigate like the vape pen
craze that's going on and while I
appreciate the convenience
the pennants like I don't walk little
flash right you know right that's right
there's a little bit of ritual to it and
like while I appreciate the convenience
of a pen beyond just losing them all the
time
I don't know that that device will ever
be ready for primetime and most of these
are solids those pens are not really for
that I know the heated chamber but
they're also if they're done right
they're potent enough to be curated
right like stop we just walked in here
have a session and move on you know and
go for quality not everybody's gonna
think that way there are people that
walk around with six packs of paps you
know and there's gonna be concentrates
and pens for those people but yeah the
game is leveling up every year like next
year I mean the peak wasn't around last
year right next year it'll be something
else it'll be another dealer great
device or some new innovation in
technology you know obviously saucing
diamonds all those things you know that
have been coming out lately are amazing
yeah so it's a talked about and so two
markets the farmers you're working with
the dynamics between like what cultivars
are we smoking and then like are you
telling them what you want or are they
being like I have some hot news ship
that you guys definitely need to check
out I mean the market difference is
probably huge then between us cuz you
know one thing that I always like to
point out is that Colorado is famous for
good concentrates and bad weed so we're
doing our very best out there yeah I
mean that's probably a product of like
we have a lot more Sun grown and there's
a lot more farmers and so yeah we do get
good quality weed and people nerd out on
flowers concentrates definitely of
course have had a rise here our
relationship like you know this is not
it's all sorts from Sun grown and it all
goes back to to the farmer right so we
are trying to go for just as a value
proposition of farm-to-table handcrafted
product you know so yeah it's just no
one can poke any holes and
yeah it's hard again iodine look I'll be
honest and we would not be able to
effectuate the strategy had we not had
an already in another grand identity
like our core brand identity with our
topicals and our wellness suite we call
that the tip of the spear it's allowed
us to grow that marketplace and
dispensary get revenue and now take our
time I mean this is definitely a quality
over margin product it's hard to scale
it takes there's a labor to create these
high-end concentrates put them at a
price point that only so many people are
buying we're growing that marketplace
without here talking I try to dab as
many people out so that they can
understand them what it is to have great
low-temperature vaporization and whatnot
and I love smoking flower don't get me
wrong but when it comes it's like flower
because that's awesome and the tradition
and then after that I'm all low temp
favored ization it's like you can
harness everything all the flavors and
yumminess that you need that way you
know definitely so talk so you're
starting to talk about some of the farms
and like what what are you both asking
them what are they both asking do you
actually sorts me indoor so yeah so
everything that we source is indoor and
we only process fresh frozen our
facility which is also a little bit more
specific because yes yes same thing but
there's a lot of resistance to that from
a lot of farmers like it's hard to get
really high quality fresh frozen on a
consistent basis yeah so it's a limited
market you know for example with the
medical license all of those pounds and
plants are literally still associated to
individual humans and that you know that
market is shrinking and so then it
becomes harder to provide enough
cannabis for everyone let alone enough
cannabis for me to process and turn into
high quality concentrates and so you
know the amount of low quality material
that's available definitely is excessive
compared to the amount of you know high
quality material which makes it you know
restrictive marketplace we also only
purchase wholesale and sell wholesale
compared to where you're going you know
and working directly with a farm and
right back we handpick regardless of who
our supplier is some suppliers
we purchase only specific things from
them and we you know choose the best of
what they're growing in our opinion or
the stuff that's best for us for our
extraction because the way that you want
to grow cannabis and the types of
cannabis that are best for extraction
are not always the best for big fat
colas and you know nice easy to sell
high-end pounds and so and especially
with like solvent list as your
application that matters even more
because your yield is so much less
accessible when it's difficult compared
to my solvent you can you know dissolve
it easily and so it's not even just the
the quality of the material that we have
to go after but the like the type of
material itself because anything that's
too dense anything that is you know
those big giant like football colas um
you know is really not the best product
for us we're looking for surface area in
addition you know to having the you know
the incredible potency and the perfect
print you know turbulent flavor but it's
definitely same for us like you know we
send a truck out to the farm we have to
we test wash every strain where now that
we're in our second year we're second
set of cycles we do have certain crops
like the GMO being grown consistently by
the same farmer but it's intimate
relationship because with this solvent
list it's about trichome head size so
not everything is gonna wash well just
straight up and there's nothing we can
do about that so we need to find the
strains that wash well right now is by
eye even though there's a proposed
technology we're trying to develop where
we can take snapshots of the trichomes
and get a measurement and understand
scientifically the average trichrome
heads on this particular strain are this
and we'll get them at 90 or 120 and
it'll be perfect right now Brady does
that because he's a fucking magician I
mean there's still a little art I mean
I'm sure you could be there's a lot of
art still in this process I mean like
all good cutting-edge science we have
some good tool box like understandings
of the apparatus and the methodology of
what we're trying to do but we're trying
to push it right we're trying to find
the new and we're trying to make it
scalable of course right so you know how
if we can effectuate this photographic
way it'll allow others to go and it'll
allow us to maybe go through different
supply chains quicker in terms of
evaluating as opposed to test washing
every
which takes time but which is also fun
but yeah it's an intimate process and
now that we have some strings and we're
gonna standardize you know I've called
for four of them like I'll still let the
guys play because of course that's part
of the industry you always want to have
the new new and some inconsistent
product but business demands and
pressures are me to be like can we just
have like the same screen at the
dispensary all the time yes I guess but
you're like that's what you should want
different stuff and I do one and I am
look we're towing the line I hope that
at one point we'll be like a sneaker
company when we drop a strain on IG
people show up and it sells out and we
that happens a little bit we have some
fan following but that's the level of
quality of the product I don't think
that's too much to ask for quality but
we will put a consistent product we
thought about like putting a lower tier
product as a high-end brand that's
always a difficult choice to make to
like have a lower price point product to
suppose we're not there yet it's almost
like you have to be really big to offer
like yeah exactly or like a key chain
and Tiffany's or something like that
yeah you know something you can have a
little something you have a little
something but you can't have this you
know you only get this on the holidays
or something I actually don't believe I
don't believe in shiny things at all I
love spending money on the things I'm
passionate about and I appreciate people
are passionate about so it's not really
for me to say I definitely want Brady
here but I definitely know the garlic
cookies is one of them the THC bomb is
running in like 8% so of course there's
some economics around that oh man like
what washed well and had a good like
yummy profile and what we could
encourage farmers to you know do a few
hoop houses or some full term I built
out a lot of good climate control store
that a lot of fucking walk-in freezers
do you power power constraints for
walk-in freezers and yeah and we've also
you know especially well yeah yeah so we
have Webb freezer trucks right and they
don't really get frozen on the truck but
they definitely spacious yeah right and
the truck is definitely it's a freezer
but it's not like subs
so it's not gonna freeze the product but
it'll definitely start to mobilize it
and then by the time it gets to the lab
you know depending on how far in the
hill it is our whatever I immediately
gets so Brady you know it's like that
thing like the dense coal is like we're
wrestling and trying experiment if you
start to macerate them you open up cell
walls and that potentially is gonna
leach things that you don't want but at
the same time you want to have surface
area there exactly so we've been
experimenting with techniques we usually
only do smalls right so we partner with
the farmers they come through because it
again outdoor a little bit different
process even from the harvesting
perspective so they'll just take all the
tops and then they'll just be all the
smalls and we come literally the next
day so the plants have had those buns
have had a chance to like flesh out
again right and there you see they're
all and then we just stripped them and
how we macerate them is definitely
something the breeding watches carefully
because while we want surface area we
also have to be careful not to break the
plan up too much to let out certain
things that hands right now although if
I had to shout out pure pressure for
sure we use peer pressure presses and we
use peer pressure stainless steel
washing drums 50% because some people
still love a fucking trash can food save
trash can and we paddle by hand and we
do use peer pressure paddles we use
professor rosin bags so you know yeah I
mean again that's just that denver
connection those are my people the
equipment is good you know it's like
they're at least you're trying to scale
the solvent was there are other other
company other couple of companies out
there while we do a lot of humble
centric stuff pure pressure is
definitely one of the brands that we
work with it's not in Humboldt and there
are like sasquatches some rosin folks up
north that we could partner with but
right now we mostly use peer pressure
equipment and lots of hands and TLC that
has to be hits yeah that's people
literally like yeah and we and it's
definitely our team we used to let them
do it and it would show up in totes and
like Brady's a perfectionist I think
most extraction artists are
professionist like he takes these jars
and how does his team
wipe them out because they came from
China and if it leaves black on the foot
I'm just like I kind of get shocked by
the labor but you cannot argue quality
yeah exactly yeah like yeah he wants you
know he's got this guy clean blood
coming in he's like we're like we're
building clean rooms to make cash and
I'm like okay I get it I'm with it right
so yeah so we have to go and take the
product the right way and like wow you
know some of it believe it or not to
investors and whatnot and like if I to
people who may not understand I'm like
it's just for the ritual of it I will I
will articulate to the public and
document this process but this is not
crazy winemakers do it spirit makers do
it
craft people do this kind of thing to
create quality products it's on us as
business people our marketing people to
articulate that to the consumer and
people love that this is beyond grand
story of course we're taking all the
videos in the drug is gold exactly
people to see it yeah
but I would argue that it's still it's
still a part of the scientific process
because the fact that you go out and do
it puts accountability on you which is
really important to the scientific
process someone has to have been the one
who did the thing so you can report back
and know what happened so you just have
so much more data when you can go and be
there at the source you know like it's
really easy to be fooled when a grower
says I never spray anything if you never
go into their grow if you go into their
grow to harvest their stuff and there's
flying bugs in the air
you may have the answer and so like that
relationship is important for
transparency which is also important for
that scientific process so as artistic
as it might be I think it's still very
mathematical I think you could still
absolutely calculate the business
advantage that comes from that because
you won't end up making a poor decision
based on a lack of information if you
are more hands-on or at least you won't
be able to make that mistake twice
right because you'll have made it you'll
learn all the way through that problem
yeah and it's awesome because like we
see people like getting like some of the
younger members just getting more
knowledgeable and like yeah there's no
phoning in hash that's
other thing is our guys are incentivized
like unlike our other workers you if you
don't show up to this job whether it's
at the farm or while your hand paddling
you will lose quality you will lose
extraction arey and that's money I mean
I think it's all extractors right so
whoever is running your equipment
regardless of the methodology they have
to be in the game right even if it's you
if you think it's automated then you're
just making crude if you're trying to
make a quality product every like nuance
needs to pay attention if somebody is
not heart's not in it or they're not
some some way tied to the economics or
the other side that's right and not then
all of a sudden it's not a craft product
right if you were I mean if you were to
compare it to food it's like someone who
you know just makes Haribo gummy bears
and a factory there make the same thing
all day every single day it does not
matter what they think or feel about the
product that they're making but if you
take that to like someone who makes you
know confections and a bakery one day
they make maybe these little cupcakes
one day they make the little candy
decorations that go on the cupcakes the
next day they're making different icing
for all of the different other cakes
that they're gonna make them make the
next week and so the diversity of
products that they make is really what
makes them good at their job they might
make the same type of gummy bear that
someone who works in a factory makes but
those someone who works in a factory
can't come in and make a different type
of gummy bear also so it doesn't make me
a good extractor to make good hash out
of one thing one time like that just
happens what makes you good at it is to
be able to make good hash out of
everything that you take in and to be
able to repeat it all of the time with
wildly different material because even
when you're talking about like I've got
four that I really like those four
aren't coming in at the same bag size
that you're choosing they're not coming
in probably even with the same
temperature and pressing necessarily the
size of batch that you're gonna run at a
time might be different based on the way
that they yield like all of those
parameters make them individual products
every time I have a different strain
even if I get the same consistency out
of it like I'm still making something
totally new and so that's that's like
the expertise is that you need you need
versatility to be able to do this all
the time and you
can't phone in versatility you can phone
in a repetitive process but even when
you do the same thing it's not the same
the scaling comes in getting such a
large team to be able to be on the same
page all the time well talk to me about
one thing which is if the concept of
long-term aging of hash like a lot of
times cannabis has always been like it
needs to be consumed now like the best
time to consume it is immediately
whereas some stuff you can you know cure
it and age it for a long term and then
you could have concepts of like oh the
2015 year was amazing and these things
peak like 3 to 6 years out so anywhere
and then your batches become more
valuable yeah I mean that's more in
Frenchie's game I guess right and you
know cured hash is definitely not my
personal skill set but yeah there's
definitely yeah and that's you know so
that's an interesting one too you know I
think flowers are definitely perishable
you can immobilize them to a good end
but that's all you're doing it's like
terpenes or VOCs they want to go they're
gonna oxidize whether you smoke them or
not it's not like wine in that bottle
but definitely true Moroccan hash can
age and definitely gets older and more
CBN e'en more sleepy and but it has a
distinct taste aroma and you know that's
uh I can see I could see that and like
cigars in the future and like that's
what you put in it like a good like
Hanna gar like freshly rolled with like
old like you know 20 year old Moroccan
hash or something like that maybe we'll
get there I don't know I mean I'm sure
there are people that are passionate
about those products but yeah anyway I'm
fortunate have to start to bounce when
you guys dude I did promise we have a
tour of cannabis dispensaries to hit
before and get back here at one point so
I've got uh let's see
got some sour clam over here and then
raspberry Lachi and white cookies and
then you brought with car the cookies
mainly papaya wedding crashers these
last few events I've had a good time
just like posting up like this and just
like that's like Frenchie
French cheese heaven is like that's the
best way to spread the word though you
can't argue with this I have the best
picture like with Frenchie in the
background like wafting the cold and
that is a completely different smoke
smoking experience regularly this
definitely has I mean even again the
drawing the curing you know with our
something like this hash for use of
freeze drying I mean that's like
next-gen dry right it's not the same art
and curing but the freeze dried it has
its nuances to be sure well what are the
the freeze dryer like its pluses and
minuses versus above my paper honestly
it's like those kids have better I can
tell you a little bit about what's it
called sublimation or vacuum sublimation
whenever the type of a term for freeze
drying is and why it works but yeah the
nuances and the timing and look it's all
in the prep right so it becomes a hand
feel how they lay out so makes me out
you know as it comes out of the bags you
scoop it up and it looks like sand
basically you know the thickness that
that paddy is how it gets stacked in the
oven same thing with working of a coven
right it's like right now I feel like I
feel like I used to understand my back
of course like to Marie's point there's
numbers somewhere so and bring the
number back and then all of a sudden
that would bring like the cooks
experience back to front right because
in a way I guess what science data is
your recipe right you go back in like oh
these were the view of the variables
that I use and it worked perfectly right
so even things like testing just
different thicknesses and being like oh
yeah yeah I mean I mean I'm sure my
hidromis are just the way you pack your
columns way to get the materials
macerated all of it and it's wildly
different so I'm sitting on a panel the
other day with a guy from hammer mill
like that like grind shit to a pump and
I'm thinking oh right but there are
people out there especially on the side
like what a masturbation sawdust you see
a massive surface here you blasted right
they get dark as crude oil but then they
were finding it to distillate anyway so
just big eyes you know stress is the
hardest way to make distillate because
you have to do so much pose much like
prep like it's just you know it's the
longest road grease it the same you know
high purity product if you would just be
faster than the first silly all right
well I'll see you guys later
yeah we're gonna run in by some desert
weed it's funny they're like part of the
job