actually I think it will take a beer
[Laughter]
I'll smoke some of that J though I'll
tell you that we have a we have a bong
as well to pack I just actually had a
broken one of the broken joints we could
pass you know let's go for okay let's
also note that doesn't have well it's
what I'm saying like you're like so late
on that well you just went and didn't
let me finish speaking all right what
should you know which one that says is
OG okay so this is uh but it's called
specific og right no I mean here oh gee
yeah but I thought there's something
like right here so yeah one of the
friends that we that we produce inside
of our space is called the bud father
bud father is like fruity like you know
thematically correct branding so you
know when people like join as Instagram
page goes welcome to the family with two
glasses clinking you know like it's just
pretty ridiculous but the guy that oh
that's the the founder is an amazing guy
named Dan and it's one of the products
that were not only branding here but
we're pushing it out in other states for
him to you know basically that's kind of
our whole theme and where we work is we
do contract manufacturing so we'll bring
brands in we'll give them a an interest
on our license so that they can produce
and then we'll make all their products
for and package them distribute out to
this tourist firm so this is one of our
guys what he makes all kinds of products
check yeah does pre-roll shatter crumble
eight stars
yep I'm all prepackaged flour all in a
very don corleone in kind of a way okay
so you guys first of all where is your
facility Boyle Heights just Soto and
Olympic on the east side of our south
east side of downtown right by the Sears
buildings yeah 15,000 square feet yeah
our if you ever want to come shoot
something cool like our manufacturing
facility is probably something outside
of what most people get to see in the
space it's 5,000 square feet of
automated plant processing so you're
basically dumping in input on one end
and you're pumping out oil on the other
end and pretty much goes like that all
day long every day it's we we can do
about 5,000 pounds of processing a day
in that facility and we're building
another one in Compton that can do
40,000 pounds a day of him processing it
will be all him focused yeah yeah it's
gonna have a hemp license rather than a
cannabis it's done a microphone with
your facility you're processing for
joints for flour for oil for cartridges
for live resin rot like everything so
yeah the only thing we can't do we're a
type six manufacturer so those live
resin products and stuff things that
take like butane propane or some sort of
hydrocarbon extract like we don't mess
with those right now
I guess so hydrocarbon is basically the
only thing you don't do you do co2 you
do did you solve unless we can we have a
license for it just not in our
wheelhouse at the moment no one's asked
us to do it but we're totally equipped
to and we can do that we just don't make
any of those products right now like
we're both like purist at heart and we I
love like dry sift rosin I think it's
the best one of the best products on the
market solvent list products at least
supplement list is it's just really hard
to that's nice what do i I love bubble
it's how I cut my teeth about eight
years ago I was making bubble hash and
washing machines in my kitchen humble
talking trees farm well part of humble
are they in yeah smells great
yeah my beginnings was purely making
bubble so I had to side-by-side wash
machines and for cultivation Wow yeah so
I cultivated for a long time first
around I've been but I've been
cultivating for about twelve years I had
I have been up to this point I stopped
about four years well no I haven't
stopped actually we said one more I
forget about it sometimes it's shoved
away in a corner somewhere
yeah we're in Humboldt so I moved Arcada
I grown a little bit you know in
Southern California moved to Humboldt
went back to school for communications
journalism degree at Humboldt State and
as soon as I moved up there I was like
oh this is actually the the mecca of
everything about ten years ago I moved
to 11 years ago moved to Humboldt and
I'm like oh this is like the mecca of
everything and this is definitely what I
want to do with the rest of my life and
got roped in yeah did start about eight
years ago started doing bubble like I
said to to wash machines and a big
barrel and with with bubble bags and ice
ice hash and yeah but back then like you
could go people just drop off like
pounds and I mean 40 50 hundred yeah
back that nobody did like they were
happy if you came and got it off their
farm because they you know back then you
if you found trim on a farm it was the
same as fine
you know each one of those pounds of
trim counted as a pound of flour so you
get the jail time of like you know
whatever that weight was and so people
just give it to me for a trim with a
street value of hundred thousand dollars
right how they how they calculated it so
yeah after that I got into open blasting
I spent a summer on a farm outside of
Garberville just going through butane
cans everyday in glass PVC first time in
Michigan yeah in Humboldt like that you
just had access to that kind of stuff
like you know I had like four or five
different glass blowers and they would
make they made me a set of tubes like
the PVC is actually like that's what got
me away from cultivating and actually
got is like I was starting my first my
first personal grow in 2009 in Michigan
way they had legalized medicinal in 2008
I was doing my own grow and having a
hard time in a under about 2000 Watts
and a little tent and my dad had a buddy
that it was also a grower and he was my
first caregiver and he we went in and he
had cooked me pulled off a bunch of fan
leaves cooked him in the oven
blast them through PVC and and basically
melted this black tar onto a bowl and we
set there and smoked it and I'd gotten
higher than I've ever been
and THC and there's like well there's
something something to this yeah I and
I'm not very good at growing right now
so let's just so let's try it out and my
first you guys yeah we also own a piece
of that business but yeah we contract
manufacturer for them as well so like
one of the things we when we pick up
brands we take a bit of the equity yeah
it's been cool it's you know I spent
years of my life driving to places to
pick up trim to bring it back to our
facility to process with mixed results
and one I don't know when but like
someday one day we just decided like hey
let's just actually sit here as much as
possible how do we get people to bring
us the trim and then we do what we do
with it and then just give back the
results and they pay us to do that
and that kind of changed into our model
and then we found people who are into
like doing toll processing and contract
manufacturing that didn't have either
didn't have a license or didn't have
some part of the puzzle a big thing is a
like like we were talking about people
didn't realize the farmers didn't
realize the value of the trim
they were only selling their pounds and
they were selling their flour and then
they didn't realize the value now you're
getting more educated farmers that
realize the value of the the stuff they
were throwing away and they would much
rather be involved in the end product
and
you know the advantageous sources of
income that go through it instead of
just you know selling that trim they
would much rather get a hand in the
market of concentrates and start
producing a product that now you know
that's getting the Ally out of it yeah
Dominic so they down some products yeah
you're right that is like that that's
where the the conversation kind of
wrapped on we you know we came from
small farmer stock like you know people
that were doing less than an acre you
know like quarter acre or something like
in the same garden as they grew their
vegetables and everything else he
counted them out in the sticks and
humble and that was kind of like always
our our thing like you know where's the
value that we bring to those people and
we thought you know hey let's let's get
them to have some participation in the
downstream economic so like where these
products are going to like that's what
they're missing that's why farmers get
commoditized and stuck in these little
small boxes and yeah we've figured out a
way to we're like hey we charge a fee
but and and and hey no problem we'll
even sell this end product for you and
you get part of those economics down you
know after it's sold yeah I mean it's
basically monetizing your waste streams
and it it goes further it as the science
catch it catches up to the industry then
we're able to realize that there really
isn't too much waste and I mean we can
we can pull there now we're looking at
for our distillate a distillate residue
and there's people that are extremely
interested in that and making bio
plastics
and your biomass is I mean for one it
could be animal feed it could be burned
for energy with inside the plant the
these are just streams of value that was
considered waste that we used and used
to have to pay to get rid of and now
there's more and more companies that are
realizing the value of these products
and creating creating businesses around
relieving these waste streams
and also making valuable products out of
them well on that topic there's one
thing to recognize the economic value of
the fiber and all these other things
it's another thing to actually have the
infrastructure in place to currently do
something about it so you guys are about
to start processing hemp right yep
you're gonna have so much material
that's not going into the CVD
isolate so where are we today with for
example turning into plastic and the
fuel and to rope and clothing and I got
to go to a hemp show in NBC about eight
months ago and I was blown away
you know I I've been pushing to get into
that market
British up and be yeah Brit British
Columbia Canada at the University of
Vancouver and they you know those waste
streams exist
they haven't been scaled so for instance
there's a guy creating hempcrete you
know that is stronger than concrete
there's like there was a guy up there
that was making batteries out of hemp
and biochar there was obviously a bunch
of different fiber guys up there that
were doing everything from you know most
of the molding inside car doors now are
all hemp based you know there's a bunch
of really cool products but it hasn't
been scaled yet and this was in Canada I
think Canada is probably like five years
ahead of us as far as large-scale hemp
production goes
murder where the cultivation is
happening right like yeah I think you
know the oil industry would be an
analogy where you have certain you know
refining extraction
you know transportation distribution to
the refinery it really comes down to
logistics of moving material and I mean
if you could move if you could have a
mobile lab that comes to the farm get
stuff into crude and the oil the biomass
is it's the biggest taker of energy for
for moving around it's it's it's hefty
for what we're pulling out of it if you
can get those valuable space if you can
get those targeted molecules out in the
field then you don't have to worry about
other processing down the line you can
you can send your your waist down for
fiber processing or plastic processing
but if you can separate things closer
closer to the source it's gonna reduce
cost but as you get to these more
precious things say is say if you're
incinerating your biomass and you're
doing
graphene production like it takes
nothing to ship you know a gram of
potentially graphene rich material to
you know the other side of the world to
actually do research but it really it's
logistical II it's the big challenges
getting the target molecules mmm
processed early and then moving the
waste streams in a proper direction to
where you don't you're not processing
them in several different manufacturing
areas you want to do most of the stuff
at the field and then take the different
materials the waste streams out to the
the other processors and biomass is the
the biggest the the what's 10 per single
grain on it yeah they're you know going
from going from biomass as a whole to
crude you're cutting out ninety percent
of your weight if
more so that's the logistical
interestingly though right now which is
kind of follows along with what we've
been how our thought process works when
we make decisions up but the price point
on some of those bulk cannabinoids are
both testable quotas is still so good
that a lot of people aren't thinking
about that the logistics cost is really
like almost nothing compared to the to
the margin if if you're a single source
provider right you're a farm that's
going straight into your own a
manufacturing facility even if you have
to transport thousands of miles to a
facility the economics are so good right
now in this market that it doesn't play
a big role it's not it's not a cost
factor that you really like oh my god we
got to make sure it costs twenty six
hundred dollars to do a 40-foot
container on the back of a semi truck
and you can fit about twenty five
thousand pounds of material in the back
of that truck and so if you think you
know you're getting twenty kilos off of
every thousand pounds that's four
hundred and something kilos of finished
oil you get off that that twenty five
thousand pounds or more you know and
that that equals that twenty five
thousand pounds equals you know and in
revenue you know millions and millions
of dollars worth of CBD isolate or
full-spectrum distillate or something
like that so right now the people aren't
even thinking about that because it's
you know but we our whole thing is like
efficiency we reuse all our ethanol over
and over again and we clean it every
time and we've taken away some of the
heating and cooling elements of the
process to make make it cleaner and and
more efficient you know and I think in
the same way eventually like Noah said
like you know farmers want to grow
plants and cut those plants down it's in
that somewhere but with him specifically
cannabis too it's more complex you know
you're drying for days you want to dry
in a certain way to preserve your yield
and so I think some expertise or people
getting into that market of harvesting
separating stalk and stem for fiber
production from from flower
those are the things I think people are
looking at now for that take that hit in
two years from now when everybody their
sisters growing hemp and like it's just
a big commodity and yeah I could imagine
efficiencies are really gonna start
mattering I could imagine that you know
like feed corn was probably a challenge
in getting a getting good separated corn
without tons of husks and biomass so
that's you know low and low in
nutritional value and and those are the
things that we are starting to look at
now is the is just trying to reduce
those efficiencies because eventually
the the price for CBD is going to be is
you get more big players in the game
it's going to drop significantly so to
be that it should be like if it's
exactly to make it make it available to
everybody it should be it should be
available to anybody with a buck in
their pocket to get a little CBD in
their system and and it's that's the
thought the thought right now it's I
mean we haven't built it we haven't
built our own out and we haven't come
along a design right now we're playing
with we're playing within the confines
of what's what we've been given
here in the state of California you have
to have a physical address to be using
these solvents it's not that's not
really can transport like it's not easy
for a regular guy to transport you know
ten thousand gallons of ethanol in the
back of a tanker truck you know yeah
from one place down a dirt road to some
other place and and I think in the long
run when you start talking about
consumer goods specifically you know
cooking it up you know in your garage
while you're baking it in your oven
inside the house like that so that
probably is not going to happen for too
much longer you know if it's still
happening at all and so where you're
doing some processing could be an issue
you know like taking a non FDA certified
you know tractor-trailer and
doing that work on the field I don't
know if that works long term maybe it
does for obviously for him and a fiber
fiber but maybe for Pharma or
nutritional supplements out of it it
flies it is yes yeah we we really prefer
ethanol it's it's a renewable solvent we
it's extremely aggressive and it
I mean slightly is mmm significantly
less dangerous than dealing with butane
it's not as volatile as a solvent it's
not in general like yeah it's aggressive
as a salt but it might make you
aggressive yeah but it definitely is
it's not the easiest solvent to work
with and we've learned that yeah we've
learned a lot with being forced into the
the corner that we are with our six a
license we can only do non volatile
solvents and we were really lucky that
that ethanol was lumped into that group
if it wasn't we'd be dealing with a lot
of co2 and rosin presses but not be able
to do the industrial scale of
cannabinoid extraction that we do it
does take an aggressive solvent and with
the high pressure systems that co2 has
to use it there's very very low
throughput compared to what we can do
with ethanol safely each solvent and
like checkbox like different
capabilities or what they're good for
large scale volume is one of them yes
that's co2 I mean obviously bras and
presses you're doing like yeah six inch
that's cotton gin yeah so yeah but you
can get some of the best products ever
out of
you know solvent lists you know water
washes and then drive sifting and then
and then rosin and then our ERISA name
with separating th CA and and then also
tossing out your ear your rosin there
letting it stratify and like the BHO
guys too like that's a lot of work and
it makes the best extra extra action
might in my opinion but if we want to
get cannabinoids to everybody that's out
there that needs them there's not enough
rosin presses in the world either that
someone brings you or like if you ever
go to a retail shop and just say like
wow whatever these guys are doing I want
to learn what it is cuz this is crazy we
we we love rosin or the solvent list
rosin like hi we would go to you know
jungle boys has be like dry sift dry
sift rosin as well and it's in yeah
it's one of the best products ever if
it's a super craft product and we pay
the extra price for it I think all those
technologies have a specific user
function you know rot you know rosin
presses meet that criteria for people
who really want the best extract as far
as flavor as far as capturing the
essence of that specific fee know it for
sure it costs $100 1/2 gram or sometimes
you know 150 dollars out or a gram and
yeah it is the I would say it's the the
most top-shelf yeah teak product there
there's people now that are really
starting to do great things with with
hydrocarbons I mean they've been doing
great things with hydrocarbons but now
they've really learned how to refine and
I've seen a few people actually pulling
really strong terpene profiles from
hydrocarbon extracts colorless like yeah
there's a terpene profiles with
colorless oil like using hydrocarbons
and really good good flavor profiles
yeah I mean I mostly know I the for
terpenes that I was really impressed
with dr. Jack Hughes on Instagram he
he's really spent a lot of time at
preserving terpenes and and polling and
distilling terpenes out of crude
extracts to in keeping good profiles
he's just put so much time into that
over over a lot we met him he was one of
the first trade shows we did I actually
just found this business card more we
saw him at at Vegas Vegas as well but we
saw him at hemp con in San Bernardino
they were they jet he was in the Jenny
extracts booth that was him that was him
yeah yeah I can't believe that I knew
that my goodness but yeah I mean the
cool thing is we've watched a whole
bunch of people like level up over the
course of the last five years on
Instagram like so many people have gone
to a new level of their understanding of
how they want to interact with the plant
and and a lot of people have their own
little bubbles too they they they find
their their niche so breaking dabs on
Instagram is a he's really when the
short path distillation game came up he
put a lot of energy into just figuring
out all the the variables and how to
make great oil and and increase
throughputs
and writing it all down it's just so
huge in this industry for people to like
write it down create a a very specific
SOP and then so people can duplicate
that work exactly like that then it's
and verify the results you know so it
becomes a standard yes
he's a confessor he's a consultant that
that was very very generous and
everything that he's put online
eventually it right now he's worked
towards you know commoditizing ism in
some way but it's great it and but that
I don't know anybody that runs a short
path that doesn't you know tip their hat
to what he what he did for the industry
and and another another yes that his hot
condenser tech the braking dabs hot
condenser tech was absolutely a ground
breaker for the distillation of
cannabinoids because people started
realizing that they started selectively
selectively condensing things before it
was all you vaporize vaporize their
cannabinoids and everything that comes
up you condense it all and then you just
you don't want anything to bypass and
end up in your trash so he was the one
that realized that there will be things
that code is still and that there's ways
of increasing your condenser
temperatures to let them bypass your the
drop down for your your oil and they'll
continue as a vapor and then they'll get
deposited further down your path yeah
but not in your flask for targeted soil
so basically in distillation if I could
just like cut this down a laser this is
actually basically in distillation you
have a boiling flash you pour your your
crude oil into this boiling flask and as
it gets to specific temperatures it
fractions off by vaporizing different
compounds inside that boiling class so
there's THC CBD all your cannabinoids
all your terpenes depending on their
specific boiling point is when they
would fraction off of that main body of
oil
so what breaking dabs did was most
people just had a cold fluid running
through their condenser so once that
oil vapor would hit the condenser it
would this is just so for people who
don't know this stuff I just want to
like give them this this short story hit
that condenser and it would cool it to a
point where it would Ries elyda Phi
right and then and then it would it
would land on a there was a flask that
would come off of that path and this is
all done under very deep vacuum right
but you for cannabinoids specifically
correct me if I'm wrong they don't they
don't need to be so cold to read that
they're volatile in the sense they want
to go back their natural state is oil so
you don't have to bring the temperature
up or down so you've got a really little
bit of vapor pressure very low vapor
pressure is the better term for it
so this hot condenser tech allowed you
to pass more garbage and just really
collect a very much cleaner cannabinoid
fraction into your collection flask Kota
Stills like so yeah so like selectively
Rican dancing was something that people
started it that it it jogged something
in a lot of people's my brains and got
them thinking on another level and gray
wolf to like yeah of an open like there
was a feel for it a there's a couple
guys who are like awesome in this tech
community too because they have openly
like upset a lot of people but like kept
this small band of people in the
technology side side of cannabis or
specifically in processing kind of
hanging on to each other like we all
follow each other IG we see each other
at all these events there it's not a
huge group of people and so gray wolf
and he doesn't even he's not even on
Instagram which is yeah but he he's an
old codger that
but he's been designing closed loop
systems for well he he's an engineer and
the closed loop systems he basically
owes open source them on the internet so
people could so it would destroy the
ability to make patents around them so
then people could actually yeah make the
machines themselves so he open source
them very to just make sure that people
would be able to make closed-loop butane
designs and don't know if you're
familiar with connoisseur concentrates
the mr. extractor and it's a it's a
about to say something that might cause
drama there we you might uh there was a
big video series about how this company
had owned all these patents and they
tried to patent this stuff but it's
really they're not enforceable patents
and there's kind of Supercop kind of
they they got it and he was he's made a
pretty funny video series of him up and
this big know drew hey that's all i know
i'm as drew and with a couple of pretty
blondes and him in front of a desk
overseeing like la or something and he
talks about and he gives like a an
hour-long series about how he's he owns
all the patents he's gonna be the future
of the industry and it was like it was
pretty cringy yes it was a groaner yeah
the whole thing yeah and i believe that
he's actually the gray wolf has been
sued for some of the stuff that he put
out he's had to deal with no actually
skunk farm had gotten bought from
another company and there's some really
stuff going on around the open-sourcing
of that but people have attacked Great
Wolf for what he has tried open-source
and he's been like copied all over the
industry like if you see a closed-loop
butane extractor like something on it's
probably like taken from one of his
designs almost everything out there is
based on a terminator design the
Terminator was you know a bunch of try
clamp spools you put the material in the
small ones they have passive passive
ones that use high you could just put in
hot water and ice and recover your
butane but it started out with just a
small little turbinator series on scum
farm research comm and then eventually
he started showing an automated mark to
version that they worked on to where it
was all pneumatic valves and then they
and then they they brought it as a mark
three was the basic design that
everybody's been working that the early
design for the mini closed-loop to
everybody worked on these are
hydrocarbon closed-loop extraction
systems so just getting the oil off the
plant yeah so basically you have a
column you pack the the material in the
column you pass butane through the
column at the bottom it's all collected
with oil under vacuum and then you heat
that and you heat that bottom pot and
then you would pull all the solvent out
and then recover it with some type of
condenser or a pump that was the fun
days of using a peon HVAC recovery pumps
and then eventually it moved to TR 21
HVAC recovery pumps and then you had
companies come in like with the camera
over the name of the company but
see Emmy pol series of these little
stainless boxes for recovering like
mostly pubs like that was a that was the
first approved one I believe there's
that and then there's the new manic
Haskell's that were built around that as
well but these were these most the pumps
that were used for the first at least
five years four years we're doing it
we're all like the same kind of pumps
you would pump freon into your AC system
like that's the only thing that really
fit that marketplace and a lot of the
technology that you would use that would
be a lot safer was kind of like you had
to go through I was passive I mean a lot
of people you could just add heat and
add cooling and one slide trouble like
going to specific companies and saying
hey you know this is our company and
this is what we do and they wouldn't
even they wouldn't sell us anything
they've like no you don't fit the
criteria of people that we sell our
products to with like pharmaceutical
supplies you know like even inert you
know getting bee bees yeah yeah getting
butane and mass you know like all these
laminate yeah and trying to do it
legally you know so yeah as much as
possible anyways we order through a
mcmaster-carr which is one of the best
industrial tool or parts of the fire
though and we have we have an account
there but we're aware that there's other
people around that have had multiple
accounts suspended just because they
know that they work with the industry
and they can't end its
and like they can't get their next day
part because their know they shut off
their account because their cannabis
guys and I mean even a couple months ago
we did a we're trying to do one of those
whiteboard videos where it's like
drawing little character yet and we got
like a week into the process with this
company in Utah and then the guy called
the designer or the guy who was in the
video called me and said yeah so we're
really sorry but we're gonna have to
discontinue working with you guys and it
was like what do you mean he's like yeah
the owner went to your website like it
was like this bad thing like our
websites super professional and like you
know describes what we do
and he's like yeah he's just not into
cannabis and I'm just like wow alright
well I don't want to pay company funny
enough that guy was like I just say from
a personal standpoint I totally am into
what you guys yeah I also have this
little side business yeah super funny
but yeah it's still like a it's odd that
you know 33 states have some sort of
cannabis or hemp or CBD law in the books
right now it seems like it's moving
towards federal legalization sooner than
later so it's it's odd that like people
are still like it's the devil yeah and I
I still look for equipment I have to be
extremely when I'm sourcing equipment
especially through other countries I
have to be careful about what I'm
talking about and I just I don't I don't
tell them what kind of biomass or
anything like I only talk about
parameters or anything because I've
gotten so many times where people get
cold feet I don't get any more answering
from them but those are usually
large-scale suppliers when you have
people that are more research based
those are the people that are more
willing to play and they they they're
really curious but when there's these
large companies that really don't need
to need to go outside and do extra sales
like like any any news as bad news to
them like just keep it functioning as is
their goal give me like one or two other
people who you would consider like
innovators and kind of what their
innovation
was one Dustin powers
Dustin powers is known as future 4200
future 4200 calm and on Instagram he's
one of the biggest proponents of open
sourcing he's created a huge forum and
well it's actually a gang leader it's
called The Good Life gang and it's just
a way to open up different networking
opportunities they put on different
networking events in different different
cities we've done over here inhalation
extraction mostly extraction but some
cultivation as well and certainly move
like towards other other parts of it
again like hemp is becoming a big focus
on that stuff as well but it started
from this dude going around and like
paying consultants to teach teach them
something and getting the SOP for that
specific thing and then and then he just
loaded up his website is a treasure
trove of kind of the history of how
people have been extracting and it was
and now all these other people just
upload their as like you know he was
doing news doing his own extraction you
know he was just that he's a great
market kind of guy like well he worked
he worked for he worked at skunk farms
for a little while like so there there
was a connection there of this mentality
from like very wolf of opens you know
this dedication open source and then
like Dustin came out of that school of
thought it's for a little bit of
influence yeah and he he's actually
completely changed the like he the
website that he produced was something
that now it is the resource for all all
the cannabis extractors all the big
names and I'll now
lots of large-scale CBD companies and
you know big shiny china manufacturers
of equipment are all just getting in
there and I mean there's advertisement
going on personally but it's not an
advertised website he's not taking money
off of it it's just this just treasure
trove of people just talking about ideas
unedited unedited and like sure he
catches plenty of flack for the things
that he puts out and he tries to promote
businesses as he knows that they're
legitimate and if things don't work out
he has to take the brunt of those things
and by putting himself out there it's
just it's been a noble thing and how he
how he has given this information to so
many people and I'm like yes take a
beatin from time to time give me
something that you came across on that
site the past month that you forwarded
to him we were maybe Delta 10 oh yeah
Delta 10 stuff Delta time THC there's
now a huge thread regarding that and
don't live when we had a fun little fort
a little for a layman's background so
depending specifically the old
everybody's different and I'll all have
their own special ways of a festival but
depending on where or how the different
pieces of the molecule are laid out you
you know the difference between THC
delta 9 and T and C a is th EA has a
carbolic acid molecule on its tail and
no boxer group carboxyl group and in
another thing there's Delta 8 THC which
has gotten really popular with the water
clear trend
and people would you know they would
throw a bunch of carbon and some acids
and stuff into their boiling flask and
then they'd start distilling it and it's
coming out beautiful water clear they
sent test results are they testing the
labs and then it's you know like very
low percentage of Delta 9 THC eventually
we started they got standards for Delta
88 see then started quantifying that
there's more THC in this that there is
but then there's still a little missing
piece that like you'd see you know 60 to
70 80 percent cannabinoids and this
water clear stuff that you know it's all
cannabinoids and there's plenty of
isomers and stereo isomers of THC and
these are things that happen through
reaction their reactions that happen
through heating and the presence of
acids and bases and given the different
environmental things or what would spray
it on those so that that can actually be
a big indicator in what's happening into
the reactions as well so so good all
that distillation method we're like you
put stuff in a pot it boils at different
temperatures and all that well throw a
catalyst in that pot that you don't know
is there like you know people spray put
sulfur on their plants or people you
know certain things get sprayed on
plants and when we concentrate that
thing in a hot flask under vacuum where
fires and fire attack there's a whole
bunch of ways you could do that but to
go back to Delta 10 Delta 10 is simply
an unknown type of THC that until
recently was it is yes in different in
different ways they affect all three of
those can affect a single person
completely different so these are kind
of
noise that have been only recently
discovered no they've been discovered
but they're only being mass-produced yes
they yeah Mexico Manila and knows about
him and he has and we are just now mass
producing them because we have the
freedom of the market to start start
playing and then we also have the
competition in the market to try to make
the clearest most beautiful looking oil
which you know well it used to be Delta
8 th DW I mean I we can I know you I'm
saying historically historically when
they first started getting this
perfectly clear bottle of oil
it was Delta 8 and they would do this
refluxing carbon acids and but but but
yeah and that was it then they would use
a catalyst in the flask that they were
boiling in when we're talking about
people who appreciate the clerk that
clear net the c-terminus of it is that
the consumer is that an expert consumers
okay and what's your any not consumers
have been led to believe that their
clear the oil is well and and and that
clear could come from a lot of different
things it can be cut with another clear
oil that it makes you know just diffuses
what color is in there there's a lot of
things that can clarity is definitely an
indicator of purity though it's an
indicator but the a slight yellow amber
tint the these are little little atomic
level refractions that are happening
with chromophores that hold into the the
tail end of the molecule these these are
what are chromophore is uncle mela
these they're they're basically like
atomically small things that will
refract light at a different color so
you have so by breaking that bond you
you like that's when people distill with
certain things in the flask you
can break that at that chromophore bond
and it you can also break that bond by
through chromatography as well which
people eventually developed a method for
Delta 9 THC
does anyone clear water clear yeah and
that was just a method of taking a
single pass distillate and then passing
it through a series of usually magnesium
silicate or floor so actually and then
but different color remediating
absorbance that were also being used to
remediated pesticides and they still are
used to remediate pesticides and it just
happened that you make water clear
delta-9 after remediating pesticides
properly as sometimes depending on the
oil and what kind of colors and that and
yeah the condition and they're they're
they're prevalent in the same way that
THC is in canada like there is it kind
of like a is it a totally different
cannabinoid that is in very low
percentages in bars not so much on the
cultivar it's a reaction through
processing so you're not gonna have
those you're not gonna have a bunch of
delta 8 or delta 10 any in your flowers
you're gonna have it in it kind of a
crazy they're isomers correct and it was
the one thing that's what you're
capturing well if you because you're
right it's it's these little slices but
the only way that's possible is that
we've now created these massive machine
that will process a lot so we get bigger
trends you know we we see information
come out of plant material from farms
all over California grown differently
going different ways different yields
different strengths different compounds
or the makeup of the cannabinoids in
that specific strain like it's really
interesting we get to see a lot of those
so at the same time as we're narrowing
the focus and really like getting to
chop down into you know now we're we
just picked up a machine that will
separate out individual cannabinoids so
you can collect them individually
it's a centrifugal partitioning
chromatography this company called roto
Kron THC and ten are kind of like mine
like other cannabinoids that we've known
about it but haven't been able to
isolate so on the market are we gonna
eventually see like THC eight tinctures
and THC ten tinctures in the same way
that we see other kind of minor
cannabinoid
totally and we've been seeing mostly
we've been seeing a lot of THC eight
cart hay in cartridges and there is the
subsequent subsequently a decent amount
of delta 10 THC that's in there well no
they're just calling it it if you're
buying a card off the traditional market
you they're saying it's one thing but
who knows what really is in that
cartridge right so but because you can
take garbage oil and by attorney by
doing this process to convert it to
Delta eight clean it up to make it look
clear a lot of guys do that cuz I can
buy a really cheap oil get a little bit
of a fraction of that off and this
really nice-looking oil and then it's
just cheaper the way that it's produced
then I like water clear Delta nine it
takes extremely expensive absorbance and
a process to do it with the Delta eight
you throw some activated carbon in their
flask
if you distill right your you can get
water clear I mean there's a few other a
few other parameters to change but you
just dump a bunch of garbage in your
flask and then just mix it with your oil
and your oil is coming out nicely that
was what a bunch of people were doing to
fix their dark oil especially in the
early days when people really weren't
distilling very well their ads and
humbled for a I guess an extraction
company that will take your moldy flat
and so can you guys talk about like
while you may be able to clean moldy
flour is that I mean a lot of people I
mean moldy flour is like that's unless
the it depends on the mold and usually
it's gonna be botrytis or piano that
powdery mildew if it's something and
those don't leave behind any aflatoxins
they're gonna em so if it was something
like Aspergillus which is more of a
grain mold then that leaves behind
things like that can go into solution
molds those molds can all be filter
filtered out I had a point two micron
range and with proper distillation
methods they they won't they don't come
out but they they actually are usually
undetectable by by the time our oil is
crude not even before it's going through
most of the extra processing methods and
it still cannabinoids coming out its
long story short there are people that
that do do that kind of stuff we do it
but we thoroughly test our end products
just as a an education point because I
think when your average person here is
like someone's taking a moldy flour and
turning to concentrate you got if
someone made an amazing product like a
constant
what started as moldy flower either you
would have any problem smoking that well
do you think about the when you get a
hard cider do you think about a nice
apple or do you think about that rotten
apple that's fermenting I mean the end
product is actually the the rotten apple
we're pulling the actual non-biological
compounds out of it completely
separating it from the biomass so any of
the but we leave behind all the
biological compounds that all the DNA is
left back behind with biomass and that's
what our process does is to separate
target oils from biological compounds so
yes I would I I do smoke our product I
do smoke it if it if there is similarly
you know I guess I I smoke it yeah every
day yeah that idea you know going back
to where we started as we got into this
small farm kind of mentality and how can
we support this and make this turn this
into a business and that was one of the
things like we've actually got to you
know save a couple farms by them sending
us all their molding material and like
we extracting all the good stuff out of
it leaving behind all the all their
garbage and refining it and testing and
make sure it's you know okay to sell to
a consumer market and and then we sell
it knowing that we did like a really
good job and then that money goes back
to that farmer and it's cool that's
really cool and they live for another
season for it yeah
which is you know and then the day all
you can hope for right now just get to
the next one when you were first growing
in Michigan and you were first growing
up in Humble what were the genetics that
you came into that we were just like I
I'm from I'm from Michigan so yours is
gonna
like mine are gonna be wacky it names
the mines Williams wonder I was that was
my baby
I loved Williams wonder and well it
wasn't like just you know just a big fat
I don't know how true it is I was told
that Williams wonders like in an indoor
only strangers it has to be has to be
flatter under 12 12 and 12 and it won't
it won't start
outdoor fast enough and I mean I was in
Michigan it didn't matter but it was
like a super strong Lysol and just I it
was the but there was the it wasn't
leafy you had really big leaves and then
one day you'd walk in and all of your
plants would be hanging over because
they would just plump up at the same
time then you start have to like it was
just really fast really quick and like
low maintenance
I did that with super Silver Haze as
just a good strong thing that was gonna
reduce mol
deal with mold because I was you know a
new grower and get something to be mold
resistant I think for years I grew just
a few strains Platinum Girl Scout
cookies which was platinum OG a Girl
Scout cross that was bonkers just just
the most fire just well everybody was
just beautiful like and it was always
dense you get when you grew that
straight is like dropping little rocks
in your in your bucket when you're
trimming you know don't like I can't
just pop or like you know the oh geez
and stuff are a little bit lighter and
so I grew that Platinum cookie strain I
grew Tahoe OG I cut a Tahoe G Louie the
13th and OG 18 that's how we met yeah
oh yeah those are my three strains the
Tahoe Louie and and cookies which were
like you know I grew things that I knew
people like and I and I like myself and
those trains were all fucker like yep
you know pretty happy in because you had
a lot of hype I mean right I mean I I
think I really love Louie Intellivision
still two of my favorite strains the the
limonene in Tahoe was like so pronounced
like you just smell this like citrus
coming off that plant and like with that
fuel underneath those and they grew so
they grew perfectly warm cool and chunky
yeah and then the Louise had that
awesome crown and crown of yeah they
were really cool they purple out and
then really at that whole greenhouse
purple doubt well that was the girl of
the Platinum girl scale they would to
like yeah the Platinum would just you
know get a little cold at night and they
were just cope just turn into these you
think we're like shiny I believe like
the density of a baseball though yeah
man I'm going to transition to the joys
of regulation what what's one regulation
that affects us manufacturer the drives
you crazy
no smoking within 50 feet of the
building smoking marijuana on premises
yeah this the the shock of culture like
we yeah we we're old-school guys like we
like to work around our plants and smoke
them and so I don't know is that the one
that but I'm sure that you've got some
other stuff that's true you have you
struggled I have a really odd odd take
on on the regulations yeah I'm not gonna
like have an opinion about the taxes and
all that they're you know debilitating
and
but a lot of the other right regulations
specifically for manufacturing you know
that kind of circle around safety and
compliance and you know like I wanted to
get better at this so I get people
better product at the end of the day and
so like if if someone's pushing that
into the industry and like saying no if
it's going I mean we have like this some
of the toughest laws on pesticide
content yeah in the US we have but
beyond what the FDA would even say
there's some things that have happened
that do make some barriers to get into
it because you gotta try a lot harder to
get good product but they're super
important for like making the industry
real and like making consumers have you
know a good feeling about what the
people that are in the marketplace are
are bringing to the table and just like
anything else out there like all the
garbage food that's in the grocery store
all these different things like there's
you know sometimes regulations don't get
followed and people try to you know cut
corners and skirt them but like I think
that that spirit of like trying to get
better and having regulations in that
sense push you towards that goal line of
like offering the absolute best product
you can I'm cool with it everything else
past that you know taxation and like the
way they've rolled this out everything
like obviously I'm I'm in it so I have
issues like everybody else but I think a
lot some of that's overlooked is that is
that other work how do you guys I think
of LA and I think of per square foot
price you how'd you guys decided to set
up a manufacturing facility in LA versus
45 minutes north of LA where it's
probably much cheaper so a lot of things
happen we we met this guy about four
years ago his name was use owed
nishihara so
yeah a big dude he worked at that time
for one of the largest manufacturers of
flavored hookah tobacco did a hue they
just released this like huge 220,000
square foot
you know facility and then like you know
FDA came out like no no flavored tobacco
you're done and like that whole market
just went and then they came out with
pods and now they're all from their
fighting pods over over targeting you
know jewel pod jewel pod packs so that
but that's the FDA's got that coming
down in two years anyway so like de
charm clove cigarettes you know all
these different things they're like
those things are all done within two
years you won't see any flavored I think
they kept menthol yeah there be like
riots if like yeah right like exactly
how these Southern Belles like just
pissed off that's not good for anybody
but yeah the so all that regulation
where was I going with this
yeah oh so we met this dude he was bar
to this big company
he brought us down here on this kind of
like pre cunt and and we were so that
year we were on a hundred and sixty acre
farm him and I were running the farm and
we had Mendocino outside of Ukiah not
too far from Johnny stashes place
actually and so for a year we built ran
this farm it was supposed to be like
five guys it ended up being me and Noah
the entire year like the partner we had
was like how stuff things happening not
not good things happening with him and
it was really uncomfortable for at the
last six months but we just like stuck
it out there and we said okay where to
next and and I'd been feeling for a year
so like we did this trial run me and
Noah partnered
on this project built our own for our
first closed-loop system and a car was
designed that he did in a carport in the
middle of nowhere in Mendocino and I
mean slightly gray wolves design and so
I was like if I think this is where this
industry is going to be the most
interesting I think most I don't think
soccer moms gonna be sitting in their
car rolling up doobies you know in their
minivan I think they're gonna have a
little vape pen or they're gonna have a
little topical or they're gonna take a
little pill like everybody else does
that's not a weed head kind of kind of
person and I was like yeah I roll I roll
joints a lot yeah I me and my wife like
probably smoked a part of a J every
night if I'm like I have kids so I don't
smoke too like eight o'clock at night so
because I don't smoke all day like I
take couple puffs I'm like ready to go
to bed
in years past my favorite way it was
spliffs so a little too back on hash or
a little bit of tobacco constant
sunflower I went through a pretty long
period of just like chewing through
concentrates because we were making so
much we're smoking yeah we're doing
specifically we're this like rush
Labor's oh and then we were doing
contract manufacturing so people would
bring like a thousand we had thousand
different strains come through there
that were doing these small batch like
sauce it was most that it was all dabs
that it tastes really like crazy for
sure like lemon
and just don't Kansas yeah became like
Oh what does this taste like what does
this taste like yeah which is no good
yeah I would say now I just I'll smoke a
little bit of a joint I really even hit
Bacon's that much anymore
don't do the splits at all at very very
occasionally like usually when I'm
stoned during the day I'll smoke that's
that's my primary intake intake I think
I have a CBD heavy tincture and a THC
the CBD is actually like a full spectrum
from hemp and the THC is like a
two-to-one ratio of THC distillate to
mgt
so I I take those every night and then
I'll take a few drops for the CBD if you
drop registers of the CBD throughout the
day but the CBD just keeps anxiety
anxiety and I've lower back pain as well
but mostly anxiety down THC helps me
sleep I'm usually so excited about how
things went on with the workday I like I
love my factory and when I leave it I
I'm just thinking about the next thing
that I'm gonna build there and like I
it's hard to sleep I take a little as
I'm leaving work I take about a thousand
milligrams of THC and then by the time
I'm eating my dinner and everything it's
starting to kick in and letting me start
to slow down a little bit so I can wake
up and do it again that I mean like in
three four got three white a white film
evaporator
that I'm installing one massive 0.5 and
then 2.2 meters squared
wiped films I've got the surface area of
the of the cylinders is measured in
meters squared and 0.5 is like a massive
surface area to evaporate off of and
we're installing a falling film
evaporator busy be following film
evaporator hopefully this week when we
get in the last of the parts and firing
up the centrifugal partitioning
chromatography system we also have I've
got my chemists working on THC
remediation from CVD material and then
we're also working on converting CBD you
have to take it out of CBD oil to keep
it to keep it full spectrum to be able
to yes and then also converting CBD to
THC we're developing stages SOPs around
that and then trying to build equipment
to do that it's not commonly and people
do do it and it can be done yeah and I
think that's a big future of where
that's so lightly like a like maybe for
people currently are doing anything that
it's on such a small scale and it
doesn't actually work correctly so
you'll get like half isomers from half
your oil will be like that converted oil
some of it will be some in Frankenstein
a lot of it doesn't see molecules a lot
of its delta x and some delta 8 so doing
it correctly to where you get a
conversion from say Kinesis Delta 9 THC
is like is a consistent conversion to at
a very specific yield meaning like the
amount of material that gets converted
is like changing and so many different
like it's the industry shaking
revolutionized everything so you think
about those like tens of hundreds of
thousands of acres in Colombia and Chile
that grow ahead and imagine the
implications it makes for when when
places actually start legalizing THC
like it takes how many how long do grow
plant and then get to really relevant
because you can't grow a hemp farm and
then process and then convert it to
future weight not the future right now
the USDA just opined on that anything
any compound because of the farm bill
derive for my hemp plant is a legal
compound and because of the language in
the in the farm bill there needs no
other congressional approval like THC
from hemp and CBD from hemp are
perfectly legal compounds so that looks
like and I think if like the Senate
Majority Leader like Connell who's been
pushing him for a long time that is the
backdoor to legalization
that's why cannabis probably isn't legal
on a federal level he's a crafty old
geezer
he's like the guy in every single
scooby-doo show you know and he's like
oh well you've got me this time yeah
exactly
you dimed kids so if I understand
correctly you guys see a future where
the massive massive amounts of hemp
feels being grown can be converted to
THC which could end up in my vape
cartridge yeah and
actually people are now starting to grow
hemp for terpene profiles if you if
people are worried about flavors and you
know and can have an odd profiles
well flavor profiles can all be done
through breeding well you can eventually
isolate those and then you can isolate
the terpenes and then from there you
grow different cultivars for different
cannabinoids and then we start to
isolate these cannabinoids and then we
can form them into a concentrate that is
tailored with the right concentration
for cannabinoids with the flavor profile
that that's all natural it actually
doesn't mean anything all-natural yeah
it really means really no there's really
no definition to all-natural you can
it's yeah it's a market ideally I say
anything I mean what cannabis is well I
was I mean I was just saying all-natural
as like it was a really stupid thing for
me to say I didn't mean all that I met I
met cannabis derived or have derived so
yeah as terpenes coming from the plants
that's the word it's plant derived like
if you're not using cannabis terpenes I
think you take plant derived terpenes
and if they're not plant drive terpenes
there are oil based synthetic well no no
I know
plant derived terpenes is what people
say about non cannabis it's it's either
cannabis derive terpenes or its plant
derived terpenes it's just a way that
people skirt though the ground a lot of
different plants yes exactly so they
skirt around that and people say that
all the time so it's all the terpenes
out there are plant derived like that
you know and they're actually molecular
the same but that's the profiles like
the real thing is that it's terpene
profiles that are important these and
profiles on a cannabis are way way way
way more complex than five terpenes
they're like
and also there's then you're not taking
the there's flavonoids and esters that
don't come over and I've steam
distillation like flavonoids kind of get
the short stick talk about Madi noids
terpenes so give a plug to flavonoids
why do we care about flavonoids um they
they're I'm not completely versed on
their medical benefits but they are
heavier molecules that add flavor to the
profile of cannabis but because their
olfactory terpenes deals specifically
with your olfactory senses where
flavonoids deal with your tongue and
your taste yes and the molecule is way
heavier on the flavonoids so it's it it
does not get distilled out
yeah it's it's not part of the distilled
terpenes it's not part of a terpene
blend same thing with the esters as well
and these are things that that blend to
the entire smell profile we call it a
terpene profile but it's a it's a smell
or it's an experience profile yes
yeah and that's errs yes and well we
don't know what happens when you what
kind of reactions happen when you
combust all those different 180
different compounds I know but yeah on a
medical level like there's you know I
don't circling this way back this
conference that we're doing is like
focused exactly on that there's a lot of
fiction out there a lot of people have a
lot of really good ideas about what
cannabinoids do what different compounds
what you know full-spectrum single eye
slits you know a lot of people have some
good ideas
but there is not enough science that are
you know propping up these ideas or
smashing them to pieces and so like that
the conference we're doing is is really
focused on people who are actually doing
that research and finding some answers
can come out and you know talking
bringing it to the attention of the
people that are making the oil and and
you know this in the gray black and
newly white market and it's like there's
a disconnection between the cutting-edge
research and the people that are making
the medicine and once you start
connecting those people that is like I
think that there's a lot of great things
can happen you go back to like you know
you want to make the best product like
find out what's in what delivery method
is best for you know the doctors are
doing research on that cannabinoid or
that group of cannabinoids you know how
that goes intersectional your stomach
your lungs your but we've got a long way
to go in research and like connecting
the people that actually are passionate
about about it on the the site of making
the medicine is really important with
the people that are actually researching
and and providing that medicine and then
give me one patent that concerns you
it's a I wish I had been prepared for
that you want to go first I'll do the
medical one and you can do the patent on
it okay well the the medical one I
there's a sky UCLA and he's part of the
him and his research partners Eva Cooper
Jeff chin yeah yeah so Jeff Chanin's Eva
I watched a talk with him the other day
and he did it was a small you know takes
money to donate to the UCLA cannabis
Research Fund it's a great great place
to put some of that weed money don't
give them cash they won't
but they create pretext I don't know
actually that's a good question yeah
yeah so they they did a small study
where they gave someone five and I'm
gonna get the dosing off because I
didn't memorize it but it was like five
milligrams of oxycodone by itself and
they would measure from normal how much
pain or the analgesic effect of that
five milligrams on them five milligrams
of oxycodone really didn't do hardly
anything right there was no noticeable
change in there and their being able to
withstand pain then they gave them a
five milligram dose of THC and there was
a 20% increase in analgesic effect and
they can withstand 20% more pain then
they gave them five milligrams of
oxycodone and five milligrams of THC
together and it had an 80% increase in
pain management and at that low doses of
oxycodone like the kind of addiction
worries go away it doesn't but there's a
catalytic effect between the THC and the
oxycodone working together to give a
enormous boost in analgesic effect and
like we are sitting on top of the
biggest like heroin crisis for opioid
crisis whatever I call it ever and and
and most most of those addictions start
with over prescribing or overdosing to
get the analgesic effect that they need
because of some real pain that's going
on in their body and then they get
hooked you know the common story I got
in a car accident got prescribed vicodin
if I couldn't let the percocet percocet
led to this that it it and I open
prescription
yeah I'm chillin on the streets yeah so
that's a pretty common story so I think
studies like that which until I heard
that I'm like oh using cannabinoids with
with Pharma like I don't know if that's
good or bad
you know my my humble hippie side of me
would say that like probably bad but my
scientific mind says man like I want to
see like results with some studies like
that if you could like it reduces him
the amount I mean if if it if it
increases the efficacy yeah I don't I
don't care if it's you know like I don't
care who I'm dancing who it's dancing
with or what it's doing I care about if
it's decreasing the the need for that
other that other component yeah I mean I
guess there's a Puritan as a Puritan
like we it might not seem like it's the
best best bet but usually it's just like
try to take the find you know find out
for sure like I'm not that guy that goes
around saying cannabis absolutely can't
kill you a cannabis camp like you harm
you in any way like I don't know that
like I don't think so
I've definitely I should have been
harmed if it was a man who's gonna harm
me but I mean I did see you crawling
across it Oh about a hundred yards a
cannabis but then that's cuz he got he
got brave with the dabs no no I was lied
to by someone this this guy
I have 39th birthday I had he makes me a
39 in oil about you know this size it
was about that big and I think two grams
oil and I'm like back then I didn't
really smoke or all that much I was a
traditional guy and he's like yeah I'm
like I'm like that seems like a lot you
know I only spoke like a little bit of
this so far he's like I don't know it's
like pretty much the same and so it ends
up he just drops the the circle of the
nine into the dish I'm like all right
took the whole thing and mediate was
like oh that's
good that's not gonna be a good day and
tried to get out of his front door on
one side of the property was about a
hundred yards from my backdoor and I
made that crawl like across the pond up
a hill like barely couldn't see couldn't
barely move yeah yeah like terrible
vomited all over myself like it was just
the worst night I mean I don't see me
until the next day
and he was very arrested actually I
don't know if it was the next day or the
day after the next day yeah okay on the
hot seat with a hard question a patent
application or a fruit patent and
actually I'm gonna expand it that you're
either concerned by or like that's
totally clever and ingenious and they
deserve that cool
I don't as for I'm I don't seem much
many enforceable patents that really
that concerned me there's yeah there is
like there's always there's a million
ways to skin a cat
so technological patents are they're not
a big concern but the things that really
interest me are the the patents coming
out regarding like technological
advances regarding condensation of
ethanol that we use in our processes
which a guy that I know through
Instagram I've been he's been developing
he's from Yellowstone extractions has
been developing a method of instead of
using chillers to condense ethanol
vapors and falling film evaporator using
diffusion and pressure and then passing
that heat out just into the atmosphere
and really reducing the amount of energy
costs it's it was super innovative I've
been talking to the guy for
past year-and-a-half as he's been
developing this and he's just kind of
giving me a little breadcrumbs along the
trail to tell me what's going on and
finally here but released this
patent-pending technology that really is
it's awesome for the industrial scale
condensation of ethanol it's going to
reduce the amount of electricity that is
that I use for recovering ethanol
greatly yes yeah totally yeah I'm going
to buy his systems from him as a an
add-on to my system I tripled the
capacity of the yeah of a standard
evaporator and get it really well
like he it's sexy yeah and so he
obviously has a wish list of toys he
wants to play over there either one who
has to approve budgets yep we kind of
argue over it has been pretty easy you
know yeah there's better what's your
current favorite toy in my a membrane
ethanol recovery system that we
developed herself we've figured out a
way to recover ethanol everybody thought
that to separate ethanol from oil you
need to distill it and so there takes
that takes a decent amount of energy to
just it to vaporize ethanol and then
reconvince it so we have developed a
method to mechanically separate ethanol
from our from our crude stream with a
fraction of the energy so we use you
know less than 30 amps to recover one
50 gallons an hour when that would be an
average around 200 250 amps that 200 220
volts so our energy efficiency has gone
through the roof and it's a technology
that's going to actually open up the
ability for large-scale ethanol
extraction and using like using ethanol
potentially as a solvent for other
industries not just cannabinoids but
because it's been proven as a recovery
method and it has a it's it's a heavier
molecule that takes more energy it
hasn't been used much in extraction
industries but now the fact that it's
been proven to be able to separate be
separated in industrial scales there's
the potential it'll be used not just in
cannabis oil production but oil
production across several different
industries so this is kind of like how
the porn industry LED innovation and
digital media monetization we hope so
and cannabis is introducing new
techniques that is happening grassroots
[Music]
totally and and the this ridiculous
thing ridiculously cool thing about it
is that it's all like grassroots
oriented like we're were two guys who
you know started growing small-scale and
then just kind of grew grew grew in this
industry and like I think that's the
same for all the the tech guys in our
space like most of the innovation isn't
coming from from large females which
process these research firms like with
any large R&amp;D budgets it's coming from
people that are doing out of passion and
and necessity for me smokers yeah
straight up yeah