[Music]
can you talk more about the residual in
specific pesticides and it seems like
some growers have been surprised that
there
the test results are coming back as
having contamination from pesticides
when they weren't even using those
pesticides so talk about some of those
surprises and and why that's occurring
mostly when it comes to when it comes to
growers who get surprised at their of
their product was dirty a lot of them
are surprised that it's dirty because
they sprayed it early in its cycle and
so they're surprised that it didn't go
away it's it's typically not pesticides
that you see move downstream it's
fungicides and fungicides reason being
is that indoor cultivation doesn't
really generate using ultraviolet and
ultraviolet is what's needed to break
down some of these fungicides into a
more inert form and so when you can when
you apply something like Eagle 20 my
computer and all to an indoor grow in
any capacity meaning your mom ops or
always indoor
all of these situations we found create
reserve maybe up to five to seven years
to where the facility itself has
contaminated meaning that there's
particulate of like a boots are all
present in the space and pieces of it
break off and land on your cannabis and
so runes that we used prior that we're
having been used in years are coming up
hot and so any of these facilities that
were priorly used they're they're
registering hot because there's
contamination that won't break down for
most of the growers that are coming up
with problems now in concentrate for
them which is really where you see it
it's almost you know sixty eight percent
of the issues might have you turn off
and and and I would say probably these
forty the first percent of it's coming
from the mothers so what you have is you
have this incredible quantity of
nurseries that are using tools to give a
stellar appearance but that product
cannot be used in the concentrate
industry and so what we know is the
nursery is that I get borders all the
time to fill clients who have bought
products that have then blown dirty and
they can even test the clone and a clone
will not detect any levels so you can't
test the mom or test the clone it won't
come up in veg you have to literally
take that product and make it into a
super concentrate and accentuate it and
then you'll know if you can use it or
not and it makes it really difficult
because it's when you ever you receive
any cologne stock you have to actually
find out you know hey how was the mom's
been treated and who honestly wants to
tell you hey they cheated on the job
right or even you're saying even if they
and it turned out but the producer would
know the producer would know see the
bottom line is if the producers move in
stock that's dirty how did they get
forward then the producer so if you're
producing the material there is no way
you didn't know what was the input
material and and for us we're licensed
through the Department AG for spray
meaning the night we have a spray
license this is a you know I have a
degree in nursing practice this is like
actually nursery and what it does is it
lets us have a very now we're running
all organic spray methodologies but
every single thing we use is documented
and given to the AG department monthly
so everything we use how much we use
what's fragrance what intensity is more
patterns what we used it for I mean an
entire program is created to monitor all
of this there's no way you're you're not
aware what you're doing and everyone
says well a worker did it well what
worker is so inclined to kill the
businesses money without direction from
the leadership and so what I know is
that people who pick up the stock in a
way that it nursery could make the stake
is they get clonal material from someone
to start the mother process that's a
tough one because you basically have to
almost throw the plant that came out
flour some of it below it test it if
it's a zero you can run it you see the
project it's an extremely time-consuming
process that's why so much of the stock
that I sift in clonal forms
seed so I sift clones but I get them
from people like me that are organically
based meaning living soil biological
predation so this way what we know is
that the material used by me or anybody
else like me is shareable but if it's
coming from strangers I have no idea
what it is and so basically I have to
run it and then blow some of it to see
below mean and turn him into a
concentrate to see is a clean source but
if I go from seed then I can get around
that but the public doesn't want seed
they don't want differentiation they
want very similar products otherwise
Nike wouldn't be Nike gonna be sneakers
but its Nike so people want Nike and and
in the market you have to understand
that and that's where seed becomes
difficult because seed lets us sift for
progeny pulls out phenotype but it
doesn't allow us a stability yet and so
for a lot of individuals you know you've
got to make sure you understand where
you gather in the source stock from and
where you're producing it and if you're
inheriting old buildings were they used
previously and if these buildings we use
previously we gets into another problem
is now you have let's weigh abroad and
Russert might sly because they used to
be through it and Russert like that came
from all the other agricultural
industries prior any nursery is going to
have them and then now you have an
incredible concentration of russet might
being applied to Humble Trinity Mendel
or for the species annotation of star
thistle so they've used
might control in Canada for decades and
now they're using it heavily in our area
to control you know these these
unnatural plants where they calm
invasive species but the problem is it's
it'd be like if you went and sprayed for
a vase of species in Napa and you shot
out you know the lacewing or the or the
great borer or whatever the nasty
pathogen is for grape that's basically
what happened for us here and so the
Russert might became such a massive
issue because it holds dormant well and
when it comes out it's unlike anything
anybody seen no one knew how to identify
it and because it's microscopic in size
you can't see it moves too fast and if
you can tidy the damage or the silicon
module egg blamin then you really can't
pinpoint what it is but what we found
with russet light is really in
vegetative form as sulfur works
fantastic so either micronized sulfur is
dry or or or wettable sulfur sprayed wet
and it absolutely tears these things up
and
we can spray them out we can control and
then what we did for flower is where you
can't use sulfur as you get into
biological predation and by biological
predation is getting a hold you bug deal
up and what you're gonna do is you're
gonna work out a strategy of what bugs
to use and they're gonna be combinations
of juveniles and adults so the juveniles
can hatch over a twenty thirty day
period and come out sequentially and the
adults are already tree starved and so
when I had wrested mites at my farm this
year and so we they blew in they must
have blown over a mountainside how many
farms around me so they win more and
they can move four miles and they land
that on the bench and we saw some pirate
bugs and pirate bugs typically let you
know you have other bugs that are being
eaten by the pirate bugs because they
don't just colonize the example above
higher their yellow with a little black
dot on so they just named Oh pirate bugs
but they're in there it's just like if
you have ladybugs all over the place
odds are there must be a third somewhere
so when you when you look at predators
if you have a lot of wolves in your
neighborhood you probably have some deer
you have a lot of beer you probably have
trash there's they're going after
something and so predators let us find
prey easier than we see prey because
printers are always bigger so predators
let us see on bugs we can see the thing
we're looking for and then we can say
okay that's a sign and so my my farm
guys spent located the
the Pirates we did the ID found the
rustle and what we did was an aggressive
biological attack on where we went in
three times the normal pressure so if it
was to add you know a thousand sachets
we went up to 3,000 sachets and what it
did was it allowed me this incredible
ability to actually out fight the
infestation
so as the infestation was increasing I
was I was running at a much higher level
of predation so literally I just blasted
him right out so I might have only lost
you know maybe 3% of the total to
Russert damage and I would have lost you
know 40% so they will be talking radical
differences and we're not talking huge
money a normal application of bugs for
me would be about 3,500 it cost me 10
grand
- absolutely seal it and if I had
realized it and I should have known what
do I know from this lesson that next
year when I put the plants out we just
lay out all the beneficial sachets with
the crop the whole time and that way the
release is just continuous and we just
know that russets will come back and
that's how it is but as we control the
vegetative plants with sulfur so that
we're not having any issues we get them
into the garden organically boost them
up so that they're healthy add the
predation and now we have a biological
balance
and so that it's not the issue that
people thought it was but it is when you
don't know how to control it and most
people miss diagnose it terribly because
they see the browning of the pistols and
they think that the plan is prematurely
flowering they don't realize that it's
just straight diet and because they're
miss diagnosing it they don't have the
ability to actively fight it by the time
they really realize what they have
basically it's like having stage 4
cancer that's how much you can do at
this point it's it's aggressive so you
have to catch it when it's stage one you
got to get the freckle when it's
misshapen not not when it's a giant
tumor the size of a grapefruit and I
don't think people are familiar enough
with the real cultivation practices of
this type of thing because we're all
learning really new predation meaning
what we use new paths new pathogens one
of the things we're fighting and new
tools what can we what can and can't we
use so new and new and new creates
problems but if it's workable
[Music]