[Music]
everybody's always focused on the red
and the blue and later research has come
along and started to show that maybe
there's other wavelengths that are of
importance McCree was one of the first
people that usually is cited as the
wavelengths that we should be selecting
and part of the research that he ended
up doing was actually defining what par
was so it was defined as between 400
nanometers to 700 nanometers but most
people want to say that between the 500
to 600 which is the green spectrum is
not quite as beneficial because the
plant reflects a lot of that light and
we're finding that as we start looking
to that the the actual efficiency of the
plants through the green spectrum are
actually quite high specifically as we
get to the the amber wavelengths and so
the potential of actually using amber
for growing plants is exceedingly high
the Makri curve shows that that's a
possibility and then research that we've
been doing at McGill University is
actually shown that it's probably one of
the most beneficial wavelengths for
plant growth at least from a
photosynthetic standpoint if you're
after secondary compounds there's other
factors that are driving that but as a
base level photosynthesis then it's the
amber light that drug drives that if you
look at the work that Bruce Bugbee has
been doing which is on the emerson
effect so this is the impact of far red
as it starts to push into the infrared
possibilities we've typically saw that
in the Makri curve it kind of drops off
and it basically goes to zero there's no
good photosynthesis that seems to happen
with that but the work that he's been
doing has just been recently published
shows that if if you take a far red
wavelength of light and blend it with
other wavelengths of light and exactly
what the ratio is still has to be
debated it seems to have a beneficial
effect so it's almost you need to have
one photon a blue light with one photon
of far red will actually give you the
same result as two photons a blue of a
red light so it seems to result in the
same kind of effect on this one if we
provide just far red
there's no photosynthetic activity or
almost zero photosynthetic activity that
happens but the the potential of
actually blending different wavelengths
of light
so there are some growers that like to
say well I'm gonna give far red light
and has this beneficial impact to my
plant
you're giving a bit of infrared so
you're increasing your temperature but
you're not driving photosynthesis with
that but if you're blending it with
background sunlight or other wavelengths
of light so like a white LED amber LED
or some other kind of LED now you're
getting this benefit so the Emerson
effect is an additive effect but it is
not a standalone effect so the lighting
systems that are being made now are they
not truly effective do they not do they
have too much red and not enough other
colors or amber so there's an ongoing
debate between whether or not we should
be like a full spectrum very similar to
sunlight is the one option the other one
is saying that well maybe we need to
have a the proper ratio of red to blue
or have these other wavelengths in it
what we're finding in our lab is that
the certain wavelengths that seem to be
detrimental they don't seem to provide
much benefit from photosynthesis and
then outside of those ones so I'm
finding that this happens kind of right
but actually varies there's a bunch of
different places 680 is the easy one to
cite but as you start bringing in these
other wavelengths than having different
ratios of them actually have benefits to
them but I can't at this point I don't
think we've moved far enough to say that
we need one percent UV five percent blue
and then add all these things together
when we've added our wavelengths
together into one big group we actually
get a less photosynthetic active
productivity out of them than if we
would have done just single wavelengths
by themselves so how can growers take
this information and put it to practical
use what can they do can they use it to
in their purchasing decisions in in the
types of lights that they use how they
use them how can they use it practically
yes so I get that question a fair bit
about how should growers actually use
this and my normal reaction is that
typically HBS is still the preferred
choice it's a good choice and no girl
will actually do poorly with that metal
halides also a respectable choice I find
it a little bit weaker than the high
pressure sodium but still a respectable
choice the broad-spectrum fluorescent
lights that you get from white
these are also very strong and their
efficiency is now surpassing a lot of
these other ones so purely from an
efficacy efficiency standpoint it's an
easy one if you're wanting to start to
push up other compounds so if you're
after the THC the CBDs etc out of this
then there is starting to be a bit of
research and it's early stages but we're
showing that specific wavelengths
predominantly UV can actually push up
some of these effects if you ask me a
year from now I'll give you a more
in-depth answer but right now it's it's
still early stages but clearly people
are interested in developing those other
cannabinoids in compounds of Tory that's
the future isn't it so yeah of course so
within the cannabis market being able to
understand how each one of the compounds
is being impacted the challenge is that
ultimately they're part of a biological
pathway and so if we're shining one
wavelength we're probably stimulating a
certain pathway but we might be losing
other compounds so if you want to push
up your THC you might be dropping off
your CBD so so there's a lot of
interrelationship that's happening
between those that means there needs to
be a lot of testing done correct and so
they're very much cultivar dependent
location dependent and so and grow or
how the growers are growing the plants
also dependent so some growers will be
able to say well I don't need to do this
because I'm doing these other tests that
allow me to or other environmental
parameters that allow me to bring these
things up so they kind of play with each
other it is does any of this change in a
mixed light situation where it's like a
light depth situation where you've got
sunlight and real lights does that
affect this it does so within a green
house situation we typically pull out
the UV light and so then we're changing
a lot of the cabin oeid accumulation
from that standpoint so adding a bit of
UVA would actually be beneficial or
using a plastic covered greenhouse it
doesn't have the same impact so you
don't need to add the UV if you're doing
it indoors then you do have to play with
those two different parameters so what
one just comment what you were saying
about like the far red stuff like in
conjunction with other wavelengths it's
almost like the equivalent of the
entourage effect right so like CBD I
slit is not as effective as a full
spectrum
medicine in terms of being efficacious
so we know that there will be certain
wavelengths that will be beneficial
individually but there's also some cases
that if I add the wrong wavelength it
will be a detriment to the whole
environment talk to the entourage if I
can pull that wavelength out then I will
be beneficial so right now it is almost
you can't just say I'm gonna add another
wavelength and it's gonna be beneficial
it has to be more of a understanding
some are negative and some are positive
does that mean that the entourage of
fact that that it's being misused or
miss that people are referring it to
sometime at times and maybe not
providing it well the challenge with the
entourage is that it's used as a
catch-all to describe everything that we
don't understand and so because we know
just using it like if we say just THC
unto itself has these benefits but if we
do it as a medical trial we don't see it
so we're trying to explain something
because the science hasn't got to the
point that we can explain what's
happening so I won't say it's misused
it's just we're trying to interpret
farther than we have a true
understanding of at this point have you
done any research on kind of different
spectrum for different stages of plant
growth or for different cultivars yeah
so that one's a we know that there will
be stage effects on the plant so as
they're young seedling or if you're
going to be doing grafting or tissue
culture there's different wavelengths
you should be pushing for that as you're
starting this part such as so I'm after
a broad spectrum white early on not any
know UV and I'd say stay away from the
the far red initially as it starts to
push up now you're starting to get more
development of roots and you're wanting
to push into these other things you can
start bringing in more of these other
factors which has certain stressors and
other parts but then as you start going
to the full flowering events now you
that that's a ultimately a stress effect
that we're wanting to do so the
accumulation of the cabins and the
terpenes are purely a stress defense
mechanism and so we want to start to
stress the plant in some form at that
point and so higher levels of UV light
actually is beneficial possibly changing
the the 10
chair of the leaf so that be the afar
red or the near-infrared type places
will actually start to push these things
and so that becomes more of a grower
decision at that point what about for
people who are just running nurseries or
you know genetics or just clone
operations like a dark heart is all is
is this information relevant to them as
well so so usually if you're just
propagating it up to the veg stage then
it's just usually a broad spectrum white
usually covers most of what you need at
that point there's probably special
cases where they want a certain
coloration or leaf structure or
morphology
then you can start to play with those
but majority of people aren't after that
what about plants that are grown for
specific purposes like to make hash I
know or different products so is are the
light requirements different or so this
is it actually gets into a larger
question on this and I'm starting to see
there starts to be a bit of a
segregation so there's field based
production which is a very I would say
random is the right but it's a more
natural broad spectrum everything is
being provided to the plant but it also
provides a lot of variability so it's
like I'm drinking wine and so a 1992
wine is different than a 1993 wine kind
of perspective and so if you want the
consistent same level of production then
you have to be able to control all the
wavelengths in the full environment if
you're wanting to have that variability
then that and so for some cases of the
people who are the connoisseurs that'll
be after that variability because they
want the top end but the ones who are
after a consistent medicinal product
that's always providing the same level
of pain relief or whatever they're after
now we have to start to control that
more finely those sound like they're
they're almost two completely different
crops and almost completely different
industry they'll have to start to treat
them as totally different production
systems greenhouses in some cases for
very high precision of like the
secondary compounds not your primary CBD
or your THC will have to be even more
finely controlled at that point and so I
can see as we start pushing down and
understand what the the sub compounds
are in the cabinets that we're gonna
have to be exceedingly fine in how we
actually control the environment to
maintain that those medicinal properties
well somebody who's more on the adult
side doesn't need quite that resolution
and then if you're gonna be doing
extracts for where you're already
balancing them afterwards then it's you
don't have to be even so still do you
think that there will be production
processes that we'll be able to produce
cannabis that is like totally consistent
like a pack of cigarettes or yeah yeah
so it's so under full controlled
environment we find consistence as long
as you can maintain your genetic
stability through the system then you'll
be able to hold the same consistent
results genetic stability my
understanding is that the genetics sort
of degrade over time you know when
they're they're not allowed to express
themselves fully or changed so genetics
there's there's always a slight mutation
that looker and so but we see that
within like the brewery industry also so
with yeast we know that they're always
drifting slightly so if you take like a
company like Coors they spend a lot of
money trying to maintain their base seed
stock which is their yeast and so it's
going to be the large producers that
will be doing the coolers like coolers
like products will have to have that
same level of trying to maintain their
stability there might have to be some
back crossing to try to get it back
they'll be doing genetic sequencing to
maintain this and so trying to hold that
quality all the way through