you know what's happening with a little
bit with the farm bill and what the
expectation is there and you know we
just brought the whole CBD side of
having you know dual use there so I
think we're we're watching a lot of
people think that you know the farm bill
has solved all their problems and I
think we're gonna see just such a
massive new wave of CBD products coming
to market I think we're going to see
such a massive wave of new cultivators
coming to market especially in you know
Kentucky Tennessee North Carolina
Colorado this massive hemp farms come
out so all these people to think that
hems gonna or you know hemp derived
distillate nice leather against eight
thousand dollars a kilogram I think
you're sadly mistaken when they see how
much comes to market and how much is
gonna be available and I'm really
worried about all these guys have
created CBD brands recently that are
gonna go through you know really really
tough time with price compression unless
you have great brand equity but at this
point in time there's I can't think of a
single CBD company that really has that
much brand equity and then there's the
question of whether or not the FDA jumps
in and I think the FDA is a is certainly
looking a lot more closely at CBD than
they were previously because they're
thinking that everyone's jumping into it
now and if you make claims that don't
pass muster with with what they think is
acceptable expect that you're gonna get
a letter from the FDA at this point so
I'm really curious to see what happens
because everyone thinks well CBD is
legal now well well we'll say it's it's
legal to an extent but we'll see whether
or not it's legal to to sell with you no
no no additional oversight and I think
that oversights coming five years from
now like market size of hemp and hemp
derived product versus what led the
charge which was you know higher THC
cannabis yeah do you think kind of
industrial hemp just gonna be like an
800-pound gorilla compared to what
I think for CBD and potentially you know
surprisingly for other you know
lesser-known trace cannabinoids
yeah very likely yeah it's kind of rub
it on yours great point yeah I mean for
for all the hype we're getting right now
about hemp for for CBD I think
ultimately like hemp becomes a huge
industry of its own right for everything
else for plastics for building materials
as you said you know for clothing fur
you know if you think about all the
things that hemp is good for it and also
how quickly it grows how fast it can be
you know it doesn't it doesn't damage
the soil in fact it's a remediation
product so planting hemp makes your soil
better it's oftentimes planted after
you've depleted the soil exactly yeah
you know you think like Superfund sites
you know can you plant hemp they're
clean it up and still be able to use the
hemp for for other things outside of
human consumption there's there's so
many great reasons for him to become a
massive industry so I think that you
know the the cannabinoid side of hemp is
you know a small sliver of what I would
have totally idea and I think that's you
know it's the one thing that I think
we've been waiting for for a long time
and you think about the how hemp became
illegal and what a farce it was that you
know no one was told in Congress that
they're actually talking about hemp
because those called marijuana at the
time and that you know even people that
passed the bill were like wait wait a
second what do we just do we just mean
hemp illegal you know it would have been
a huge industry for the last hundred
years but for the fact that it was a
cloaked under you know some other name
that no one
[Music]