[Music]
the reality of of having this this
market that's already established and
trying to be regulated and finding
myself up against a wall this is I guess
what I'm what I'm getting is that on on
the one side I don't have you know the
the finances or the the business sense
that these large companies do and still
realizing I needed to go through with
this process and I needed to become
compliant and I needed to start going
down this this pathway several years ago
and seeing my friends and family and
community members that couldn't or
didn't want to do it kind of look at me
like I was crazy and and be so shocked
like that that I would do this process
and yet at the same time not fitting in
with the real players then the new
industry that comes in and says hey
we're gonna do a million square feet or
whatever and we have all the capital we
can lose money it's it's in our business
plan to lose money for three or five
years or whatever it takes and seeing
the like how how they don't understand
how a small operator would work or how
that could function and yet the small
operators in my life
acting somehow like I'm the man or
something for
for trying to keep my family my two
young children safe and and getting
caught kinda in this this paradigm where
need access to market but don't somebody
asked yesterday hear about my sales rap
like you know what sales rep or sales
reps how do they work for your company
it's like I don't have a sales rep I
don't just try and meet with
dispensaries or distributors when I can
yeah to try and get something going but
I am the lead farmer I am tied to my
farm that's what we do all day every day
and and the discussions we had yesterday
and yeah tied to your farming but it is
a family farm and I think that is what's
getting lost and we had the discussion a
little bit yesterday and really on but
have family farms like in all other
aspects of North America if you look
they've gone to commercial farms and
like this is an industry where there
still are a lot of true family farms and
it's how do we collectively get that
group together into market and I think
we're better together than individually
I think we talked a lot about different
sectors of the market and I think
there's a lot of operates there's a lot
of opportunity for all areas but the
area that you are in is this small batch
this craft properly dried properly cured
like product that right now isn't
necessarily being rewarded from a price
point but I think we'll be and we at GCI
and partnering like we're throats were
involved in both Canada and Switzerland
and are moving into California which we
think the Pacific Northwest from BC down
to California is the epicenter of
cannabis in the world and think the
triangle and thing this is the old world
to cannabis and that is a market that is
going to
as we move forward both globally and
rules and regulations coming down that
the world wants and is a treasure that
needs to be protected and the small
family farm such as yours and thrilled
to be partnered with Hezekiah and the
coop and bringing sort of marriage of
farmers capital and so that we can
compete and we can get these products
out to the world and allow more people
like yourself to come from the free
market over to the regulated market and
have a pathway and have collectively
have sales teams have market names so
things so we've got a team work so the
nature of this business by the laws and
the prohibition of input of force people
to be secretive and to be isolated and
working solo or with very few trusted
people one of the opportunities with
sort of the regulation and coming out of
the closet so to speak is that we can
work together sure like the probability
of us meeting 15 years ago probably
pretty pretty low you know and it's
fastly that we're both sitting here and
there's opportunities to move forward
and work together and it's sort of
bringing the marriage of capital and
good values and to build a product and
what we want and I think what you guys
won is in 10 years to have an industry
that we're proud of or at least a good
portion of the industry that we're proud
of and that carries on the values and
being able to provide for family provide
a good product be proud of what you're
putting into a jar what people are
smoking yeah and I think together we can
do that and it's not without difficulty
and I don't know I've found this whole
experience and Madeleine's has been
fantastic meeting great people and yeah
and the was the I think what we're
really looking for is people
distributors you know collective
bargaining groups that we trust to a
level that we can contain
you two just spend the majority of our
time farming yeah because it's the I can
kind of the elephant in the room or
whatever you want to say is that the
traditional market provided plenty of
shady shit goes on but if the if you had
the right people is that they did that
they allowed for these half-hour
transactions that took care of part of
the year yeah um and that allowed for
farming and what we're seeing is a
problem one problem with this new market
is five hour meeting about a five hour
meeting to talk about a net 30 that
turns into a net 60 that turns into a we
don't know it sat on the shelf and what
are you gonna do about it and I don't
know how intentional this is I'm not
gonna try and put it out there that it's
you know that they're trying to scam me
but I see with these these distributors
that some of them are just trying to
survive but the more established ones
know that I'm busy farming and sure I
have a business lawyer and I have a
defense attorney but do I really have
the time or effort there are finances to
work with them at the level that I would
need to to to draft that leather
letterhead to you know to go to court I
don't so instead I let it slide I mean
yeah and I think what we want and I want
to work with people and look there's
good people on all sides of the aspects
and there's bankers and people that are
assholes and screw people over and I'm
just sort of there's farmers that do as
well hell you know what I don't like it
so it's not but it's finding that group
of people that have a shared and common
vision and common goal that you trust
and you shouldn't need contracts shaking
your hand and looking in the eyes is how
this business has taken place for 30 or
40 years it should be how it should be
able to continue you should be able to
trust your partners
and that if something extraneous happens
on my end or your end when I come to you
realize that it wasn't intentional and
you believe believe that because there's
not this fear of their trying to take
advantage yeah we're all trying to do it
like yeah something like oh did was
there a mold issue for some reason that
no one could have thought of like a
crazy humidity event comes through
surely Menor you just trying to hide
product and that's not it's about trust
and its built-in and what with heads and
the coop is because it's the coops or
farmer owned and you're still like it's
not big business coming in and trying to
buy your farm and tell you how to do it
you still own your farm you have these B
but helping that path to market and
become that source that so you can farm
and create the best product and we do
the best job at getting that product
into jars and out to the market and
capital back to you so you can continue
to do your and that I think what I've
seen is people have different portions
of that business and everyone thinks
their portion is more important and
should take more money and are trying to
squeeze the other and everyone needs to
have a fair and living portion of that
pie and that's how we can grow it all
and let's grow the pie instead of trying
to take pieces of a smaller pie from
each other sure that's you know that I'm
kind of the belief that I I don't think
that mine is is my piece is the most
important it's you know that it's better
than someone else but the reality is
that I I do have this certain capital
investment because I'm also on the front
end or whatever on the first verse to in
in line for the creation of the product
that it is a hard pill to swallow when I
do basic math and I'm getting just great
down on numbers that I have to like kind
of calculate quickly in my head they're
like the the jar price the eighth price
and in these meetings and unlikeliness
try to get out a calculator and stuff
and it's like okay that's not a hundred
percent my world the the business
certainly isn't the business aspects of
this but I can I can do some basic math
and I can say don't don't
basically call me stupid when you sit
here and I'm I'm kind of asking for
whatever like a fifteen twenty percent
I'm hoping to get and meanwhile they're
saying they're only putting a hundred
percent markup on it and the math just
doesn't line up when I can see the
product on the shelf and say I know how
much all these taxes are yep so I I know
that that's not the only thing that's
causing this product to be so exorbitant
ly expensive that the majority of
consumers just don't feel that they can
afford it or they truly can't yeah
absolutely and I think what is lacking
in a lot of the industry and through the
coop and the model and doing this is
transparency and that's what we won and
I think it's a lot easier to understand
when everyone can see every aspect and
there's transparency to it of what the
markups are and there's a lot of people
with industry they're trying to hide
those pieces so they can take a bigger
group and it's it's about building trust
and building and hopefully this event in
meeting you yesterday and continue the
conversation over by the coffee earlier
on and that's led to us sitting here
with a microphone which is more awkward
but it is a continued development and
hope we have more discussions with
hezekiah and get you involved in
because I think we can succeed as a
group and market this region this plant
in a way that the there is consumers
that want this and it's just a matter of
being able to have a unified voice to
get there and a quality product and it
takes great people and visionaries and
you've taken the path from the free
market to the regulated market which is
a difficult one and we want to be there
to help make sure that that was the
right decision
yeah yes no and that that's not that's
the beauty of the code the coop model
and that's why you know I look forward
to I see it as a as a necessity for me
because it bridges this gap between
being the lone voice trying to make
enough of a wave or whatever you want to
say that that like that my product does
sell in sells in in a timely manner and
it actually works but at the same time
not having to go it alone yeah that they
and and and scale up because the other
option is to scale up to such a
magnitude that I don't don't need a
co-op that I just I have these um what
are the marketing agents or whatever
terms some of these distress throw
around and that the coops seems to be
that that beautiful middle ground of
having the voice but all but having the
voice without having to buy the voice
absolutely and everyone having multiple
skill sets and pieces if you do it I'll
grow it up and you're all yourself and
fully believe you could do that but
you're not the strongest at all the
aspects and what happens when you have
to do everything and you have these
different things you don't do anything
you do everything average instead of
doing what you're really good at well
and the great piece is if you get a
whole bunch of group of people that are
all good at pieces we can excel at all
of them and propel the entire group and
then that's that's the beautiful thing
right there
is is that if we could come come to
market strong in in that that collective
voice of of saying this this is this
beautiful marriage of a quality product
created in a sustainable fashion yeah
because I think ultimately when there is
some more some higher level of consumer
education that that is ultimately what
they want is a marriage of those two
things absolutely and I think
collectively if you have started with
ten farmers and a hundred farmers and
three hundred farmers and now it's
100,000 square feet of collective grow
to a million to 3 million all of a
sudden and all unified telling that
story and that education it's more
powerful and it's easier to get that
message out about what the product it is
than 300 people individually doing their
things and not unified doing it and it's
just look median like it's it's crazy
it's easy to get messages out but it's
also difficult like everyone's got an
Instagram but who follows what and it's
all over like media is so fragmented so
getting a voice and trying to educate is
much easier if we've got a whole group
doing it and it is I believe
fundamentally it's what people want they
just don't necessarily know how to get
that there's not a path in the regulated
market to get that reliably and
consistently and I think this marriage
and partnership between farmers keeping
community and I think one of the things
that was most important yesterday was
the collective model is a way to keep
families on their farm and family it's
not as you mentioned it's not just a
farm and it's not just family that
they're together and it's a combined
entity and this is the backbone of what
North America has been built on and
doing this and it's critical to keep
that part of
this alive because that's why people are
doing this like I know you absolutely
love the plant but you're doing this to
provide for your family and to make
their life better and to be able to do
that together with the thing you love is
fantastic
yeah well for me they're inextricably
linked so I I can't I can't just say one
or the other and this is kind of the the
quandary that I'm in where historically
we don't want to rock the boat yeah yeah
I know Hezekiah Izzie we had a talk last
night after that about this very thing
where it's the one part for me it's more
than that but he was kind of saying it's
the biggest one for him we're all a
sudden it's a big it's just a time to
shut up but we're like okay think of the
children we don't we don't want to push
that boundary yeah and I've been in that
same place whereas I all right we
already have enough things that we're
trying to try to push through it's it's
the one it's so taboo that if they they
want these certain regulations in place
you can't have kids anywhere near it
well we'll just do that yeah
but then at a certain point after enough
time energy and as a small farm of money
I've spent so much money to them why
can't I have some kind of a voice saying
it's just a plant no my children are not
going to be consuming the plant but
being near it is not going to hurt them
so why can't we have a little bit of
dialogue and education about the fact
that they don't need to be you know a
way from it to the point where I lower
my quality of life in terms of being a
family man yeah we're being you know a
person that that's with my family and
that my wife could have a little bit
more free time or time to work on her
parts of the project that
that the kids could be a little bit
closer to that that's absolutely and it
I think it's something once again as a
group and that's something at GCI
and working with emerald grown that we'd
like to take up and lead and we're
separated enough from not having a farm
that is being the voice and pushing it
it's not creating risk on our side right
because by not physically having the fan
like so can sort of create an insulation
a little bit to push this to try to get
these through it with the support of the
farmers but get this through and I think
that was one of the things that came out
of the sort of roundtable last night
that is critical and it's the passing on
of the family farm generationally and
learning is part of the process and if
this is a crop that doesn't allow that
then you end up with a disconnect at
some point because maybe not all your
children are gonna want to continue but
maybe one does and that's how the family
farm continues and it's through that
education process and if through
regulations which don't really make
sense because as we know the plants
their plants you can't magically get
high from being too close to the plant
you know the light it's so I I think
it's something that it's very and if
it's a one of the byproducts of pushing
this forward it'd be fantastic because
it's critical to the whole piece of
having this high quality product because
without family on a commercial scale you
just can't get the care and the end
product on a scale and I'm not gonna say
it's never gonna happen in a million
square feet and maybe they'll create
technology to do it I'm very skeptical
on that front and I think the consumer
is gonna want something different and
they want the old-world cannabis and
and talked about this Bordeaux burgundy
champagne region of cannabis and the
Pacific Northwest is that and this is
you've been a steward of that for many
years and the whole at Northern
California have been and it's a duty to
carry that forward and to continue that
and we're excited to be part of this
journey with you guys I am excited for
the for the future of being able to
continue to form at this point we were
kinda interested in survival mode yep
that I I care so much about producing
the product and all that goes with it
and for me the the family farm aspect of
it is so important because it's I got
neither or that happens real quick when
you take away the family either my
family life suffers because they are
farther away and I don't see them as
often or my my work suffers because I am
with them and I'm trying to commute in
to take care of it when I can eventually
and when we're able to bring that
together
I see how both my family life and my
work life go up enter at this this yes
higher place and I think the most
important thing is keeping that together
but second is this sort of marriage
between the coop finance farmers and all
of these pieces is the immediate goal is
obviously we won't have a great product
and we get it to market in a regulated
fashion but we need to move it quickly
that you're beyond just surviving like
it needs to hit a point where it's a
fair and equitable occupation doing it
and getting that piece and getting it so
that more people want to come from the
free market to the regulated market
because there is a path to better
quality of life better family less risk
all of those elements and
there's a path to the passion they've
had for their plants and things to get
to the market and it was shared and that
I see one of the biggest takeaways from
me this weekend is we need to help get
from survival to comfort happiness and
comfort and and obviously we want to
grow to like great success but we need
that first step over like it's got to be
and taking away that that option of an
either/or because there's a lot of
people that are sitting on that razor's
edge right now going back to the free
market because they can't do it right
and that's what we've got a chain like
these pioneers and these people that
have taken that first step we need to
support them and help so they can
continue this path yeah and so that it's
an easy decision not a either/or
decision and I think an extension of the
the whole family discussions you know
family something you know talking about
how close the children can be to the
grow or things like that but I think
there's a bigger issue here also when we
talk about family farm is that in the
corporate model they they can follow
these certain rules if though all the
water for the facility needs to come
from this certain area of well
specifically that's not hydrologically
connected to something else fine they
can do that and then they they go home
to their house wherever that is and they
live their normal life well on a family
farm it's not really like that and so as
an example I got a million gallon pond
in two Springs that provide all the
water that I could ever need
yep well we had to punch 160 foot well
well I we had water at 35 40 feet pay by
the foot you can do the math it's not
necessary but it's not hydrologically
connected
so I move out of this area of being as
heavily regulated okay and so that works
that's what they want for for cannabis
cultivation fine
they do they still want it metered and
I'll roll with that
well that wasn't good enough then they
started saying well what about for your
domestic use why can't you just use this
water for your domestic use and I I
think it's a poignant example of where
this regulations starting to really
creep in to the to our our everyday
living to earn oh my family already has
clean safe delicious drinking water yeah
and we're not using a lot of it we have
deeded access in a normal world that
would just be accepted but because of
the nature of this plant and it's
extreme regulation this point it allows
for this just this hyper regulation
where they start controlling aspects
that to me seem like they have nothing
to do with the actual plant itself and
yeah and I think and I think a lot of
the regulation takes place in vacuums
and don't understand the family farm
which is also part of the whole
education and getting the story out
right and showing the positive stories
around this not just the negative
stories because people see the news and
the free market black market whatever
want to call and people that are doing
the bus or what they're doing and a lot
of times some of that is involved with
other drugs like there's there's a
perception that is portrayed and what we
need to do is start changing that story
and tell the good stories and the pieces
so that it's seen as a for what it is as
a crop yeah I mean that's that's a big
that's a big distinction that I make and
you know these broad sweeping statements
but here's one is the
like a simple it's a to two parts split
in terms of free market traditional
market cultivators and then distributors
wouldn't you know people in in the
business is people where it's
potentially the only Cromley real cry
maybe jaywalking and speeding or
something but it's the only crime they
commit and otherwise are normal whatever
whatever that means yes like yeah that
everything else about them when you meet
them you buddy oh my god you could be
you know you're a normal person and then
the other side which is straight-up
criminal element yeah where they have
used money from human trafficking and
hard drug sales to finance these
large-scale illicit cannabis production
and distribution operations and that we
can make a distinction to the general
public
yeah and and say hey I know that these
people they haven't done everything
perfectly they've had to do what they
felt was necessary or what made their
business work but they're not bad people
absolutely and that's there is a real
distinction there and I think in
fairness like Canadian regulators
American regulators and the law makers
the unintended consequences of trying to
they want to remove the criminal element
from it but it's captured the pioneers
as well and the people that we're doing
it and pushing plant based medicine and
that have gotten us here yeah to that
like that have carried the mantle and
risk their Liberty their freedom in
order to do this and though that group
yourselves and these farmers people sort
of the ones that should be celebrated
and they shouldn't be caught up with the
regulations they're trying to elimate
eliminate the criminal element and I am
all for the criminal element
unfortunately not an end intended
consequences
the criminal element being removed I'm
very in favor of that but the unintended
consequences is unfortunately generally
it's organized crime they have lawyers
moving money doing things these simple
rules that they put in place and become
onerous for the guy that this is the
only thing that they've done wrong and
having jaywalk they don't have the
ability to get around it so it doesn't
these rules don't actually catch the
criminal element unfortunately and
that's sort of the unintended
consequence and they exceedingly punish
the people that are just trying to get
their to go the right way and that's
where I think telling the stories and
having the public realize that there is
a difference and these are family farms
like these are farmers this is not a
criminal enterprise yeah yeah and the
guy got three broad categories that I
put this into and Aldus you know the one
is is the business aspect of it and new
or newer people coming into this kind of
a lot of what we see here yeah is there
better at it oh shit yeah I've made my
business work but I have no business
background I you know I don't have an MD
MBA MBA or really care but that that's
great for them okay and they have this
this skill set and I I think there's
there's pieces of that for me to learn
on how to run a business that that works
to where I have good forecasting
abilities and good bookkeeping skills
and all that and so of course they they
have that in a way that we as farmers
for the most part don't and this set the
second one being the the science of it
and I feel like the big business they
can get that they may not personally
know how to grow the best product but
they can get enough people on the team
that know it that they can make that
work but it's
the history and the culture of it that
they seen it's kind of alludes them and
they don't see the importance of it and
that's that's the big one that we really
hope that we can kind of and that's the
most important part to me
and that's what can't get lost and if it
does get lost I don't see a future where
Northern Californian or British Columbia
Oregon the stewards of this plant for
the last 50 years can survive without
that culture because that is it's a
culture of the history the legacy and
it's the being able to grow this product
in a craft and a way that's critical to
the survival of this area and it's gonna
be a segment of the marketplace that
does it it's not the entire marketplace
and I think we talked earlier there's
lots of elements of this marketplace
there's new consumers that are gonna
come on women men that want a
replacement for alcohol and they want it
through a beverage or an edible and that
and that's where the science is going to
come in and onset times and offset times
but make a full spectrum like the plant
the time back to old-school old-growth
wines and the Cabernets and the
uniquenesses that come from the
different microclimates and that to
farms by the crow flies of quarter mile
can have totally different environments
and different products and there's going
to be there is a consumer that wants
that now and there always will be and we
need to make sure that we provide an
economic framework that it's sustainable
for the farmers to be able to grow that
and that we don't lose that and that
comes back to the family farm and
working together and I'm really excited
about this journey and it's been
fantastic meeting here this weekend and
look forward to many more conversations
for sure