[Music]
so the assumptions I want to start with
for this panel discussion is that indoor
agricultural facilities will use a lot
of power based on sole source lighting
as our main strategy so we're gonna talk
a little bit about how business models
and growing different growing systems
are going to revolve around that
assumption then we're gonna move to then
we're gonna also keep in mind that crops
being grown currently have limitations
that in terms of what price points we
can hit so as we look at how we're gonna
utilize energy and utilities light HVAC
we do have limitations we can't use as
much as we want to whenever we want to
because we may not be able to afford
what to sell what we're growing and then
finally there's a lot of talk when we're
dealing with indoor agriculture about
extremely niche crops but there is also
a lot of different indoor AG food
producing projects that are out there
and those niche markets will be quickly
saturated and we need to think about
what we're gonna be able to do in terms
of accessing broader market so based on
I want you to keep those assumptions in
mind as we go through the panel
discussion and with that I'm gonna start
by letting each panel member introduce
themselves and give a short presentation
on their company and their background
okay
we're gonna start with Sam from arrow
farms my name is Sam Schatz I'm a
managing director at arrow farms
so basically arrow farms we're
controlled environment agriculture we
been operating now vertical farm in
Newark for the last three and a half
years a commercial farm the company was
originally founded in 2004 actually out
of the Cornell School of Agriculture and
we were an OEM for much of the 2000s and
then we reformed the company in 2011
around owning and operating these farms
we built our kind of first model three
farm back in 2013 and built many
subsequent farms
since then it all in Newark as I
mentioned we went operating the
large-scale production facility now for
about three years the design for that
facility is about five years old we're
in the process right now of closing on
the funding of our next project which
will be in Virginia which will be you
know the next the next iteration of the
design we're very excited about that we
have been selling the retailers like
Whole Foods and Shop Rite Fresh Direct
and we've also brought in financing from
many different institutional types of
investors but just to summarize we've
we've managed to bring in about 200
million dollars of equity capital over
about four rounds of funding over the
last six years or so so I guess we can
go what I'll do is I'll talk next about
the technology which a very high level
here so we built in a number of
different spaces I'd like to show this
video because it you know if a picture
can speak a thousand words a video can
do much more than that I only have
another minute here I think but
basically this was one of the first
farms that we built it's three towers
this was actually an old paintball laser
tag facility that we converted to
growing food and we we actually operated
this and then this was the next farm we
built after that this is one that we're
actually still operating this is in also
in New York and now these towers are
about 36 feet high and they're growing
food year round using 95 percent less
water than field grown crops about 50
percent less fertilizer and the small
small fraction of the land and zero
pesticides so the product that we grow
doesn't need to be washed it can go
right into the package which obviously
skips a very big step because you don't
need to wash it you don't need to drive
those right into the package and it can
be sold to customers and we're currently
we're selling throughout the Northeast
about eight different SKUs as you can
see here we're
using LEDs latest in LED technology
everything that you see here arrow farms
is vertically integrated so we designed
engineered manufactured installed and
then we operate these farms and
continuously improve on not just the
engineering components but also on the
growing algorithms that we use nutrient
delivery and all of the kind of
supporting systems and harvesting
packaging seeding germination etc so
anyway I wanted to share that obviously
a lot of a lot of great things to
discuss on this panel I will say that
the the leafy green part of our business
is just one part of our business and
we're vertically integrated to go into
many different crops and so we're
actively pursuing many crops in addition
to what these systems are engineered for
so thank you good morning everyone my
name is Javed Abraham I'm a lead systems
design at Agra tech chure consulting a
grow texture is a tech agnostic new
york-based
agriculture consulting company we focus
in controlled environment agriculture
and we consult mostly on greenhouses and
vertical farms so we're not married to
one system type or the other we look at
each client's needs based on the
particular market that they're operating
in and the crop that they want to grow
and we help them to plan their business
for profitability and for a long-term
success we approach each project with a
triple bottom-line perspective looking
at the the social benefits of their
business the economic benefits as well
as the the environmental benefits so
there's really a lot that goes into
planning a controlled environment farm
you have to look at market pricing you
have to look at equipment availability
the crop you're growing and then design
around those parameters rather than the
other way around we see a lot of
companies and individuals trying to
basically force systems in places where
they don't necessarily work or trying to
produce crops in them that don't produce
a positive return on investment in that
particular
market and then that's basically setting
yourself up for failure so we try and
steer our clients away from that that
fate essentially and we have had the
opportunity to work on over a hundred
projects in 20 different countries in
the past four years and these services
range for from everything from market
research to farm design feasibility
studies as well as novel system due
diligence and it kind of investigations
into system efficacy there are really a
lot of factors that drive whether a
client will choose to go with one CA
system or another and as you can see on
that slide there's quite a few kind of
factors that we look at when we look at
these the way these systems operate in
these particular regions you know water
scarcity is a big driver these days and
we hear a lot about water use and
efficiency in these farms and you know
the difference between an evaporatively
cooled greenhouse and a completely
enclosed vertical farm a lot of that
difference comes to the water use of
those particular systems so in
California for example you would lose
more water through an evaporatively
cooled greenhouse than you would through
a completely enclosed vertical farm and
if water is really your pain point your
operation then we would look at how you
can manage those specific resources
based on the strains in your particular
region we are an interdisciplinary group
we are a healthy mix of agronomist
engineers policy experts and
sustainability experts and as I said
before we look at each client's
individual needs and we assess those
with a triple bottom line approach and
keeping sustainability in mind
good morning everyone my name is grant
vandenBosch despite the very long last
name and three consonants I am NOT Dutch
i I do have a Belgian Belgian heritage
so I guess it was meant for me to come
into this industry so before I briefly
touch on Who I am and who we are at fits
season my role as chief category officer
and in the in the spirit of the
conference set by Derek I just wanted to
very very briefly sound my personal
reason why we decided and I decided to
come to this conference you know I think
as we think about energy usage for for
food production specifically for leafy
greens and indoor environments as as we
all do up here this is this is a really
high cost driver for us so it's figuring
this out is a strategic competitive
advantage but when you look at the
mission of a lot of our companies it's
also one that's sustainability oriented
and and it's one with a higher purpose
so it can be a difficult conversation to
have when you think about the importance
of being able to be competitive on your
energy usage and it's it's not something
that I think I have the answers to or
maybe even we all appear on the stage
have the answers to but I think coming
together with this very diverse group is
how we can find the solution for how to
have the conversation to share best
practices so so that's why I'm here my
role at fifth season as chief category
officer is really to lead corporate
strategy marketing sales business
development and and broadline how we
think about our overall go to market
strategy so we we grow leafy greens and
herbs indoors in robotic vertical farms
we have human free grow rooms that are
connected to a highly automated
production process that operates much
closer to a smart manufacturing system
than it actually does a traditional farm
Chris asked me to come on here and talk
about crop types and the purpose for
some of the crop types this this map
here that you see I'm sure you all have
probably seen it before the reason why I
chose to continue to use it is because
it's still the driving factor for why
why our businesses are able to be
successful the fact that you know 86
percent of consumers are consuming leafy
greens that are
not from the state where or even a
locality from where they're they're
consuming them it is just forcing
consumers to settle for an experience
that quite honestly is now it's not
matching their beliefs when they walk up
to that category so it over the past
couple years is you think about the
wellness trend starting to infiltrate
just about every single decision of
people's lives retailers as as well as
consumers are looking at the leafy green
category with it with a new lens and so
there's there's a lot of demand driving
leafy greens and herbs broadly it's it's
not just from that that kind of very
focused focused group so a lot of us do
grow it for that for that as one of the
reasons amongst many others I you know I
think one of the other things I wanted
to quickly mention is that when Chris
set the assumptions for this this
conversation I think one of them is
really important to to come back on
which is you know the consumer can't pay
$100 you know per ounce
for for leafy greens it's just it's just
not going to happen so many of us here
do have to face the reality of a math
problem that most farms have struggled
with for for hundreds of years and so
thinking through everything from
production to output to grow science and
how everything comes together into a
system that allows you to to justify the
high capital expenditure for a lot of
these facilities is exactly what a lot
of us deal with when we think about just
trying to compete on shelf with with $2
a pound
you know big leaf flat cooking spinach
all right well with that I've got some
prepared questions for the group so we
can gotta get the conversation started I
want to do is start with Jive Eden and
since there
their company is more focused on helping
growers find ways to implement systems
what I want to do is is ask you the
question what type of growing systems
have you seen most people looking
towards and you know kind of give us an
idea of why they why and how they
determine the energy impact with those
systems so to answer your first question
I would say it depends on the scale of
investment or funding that they've
received so far and kind of what stage
at development they are a lot of kind of
categorized as beginners or people who
are just entering this industry for the
first time are often looking at smaller
pilot systems so container farm systems
are very popular for that that group but
then there are there's a constituency of
investors out there who are raising
higher amounts of capital and looking to
implement novel larger systems that
would go into a warehouse envelope so
you know these are companies like arrow
farms and you know plenty
Bowery companies of that sort so I would
say it's a it's a good mix between the
two and there's almost always there's an
immediate interest in going for a
vertical farm envelope and we always
stress that our clients should also
assess the the efficacy of going with a
greenhouse for that particular region
and we help them in kind of comparing
those two systems as far as energy use
you know yield output cost of
implementation as well as long-term
operational cost so there there are some
regions in which vertical farms will
work well consistently year-round and
then others where greenhouses can you
know produce a bit more cheaply they may
be a bit further from the metropolitan
area but you're still within local range
and I'm sorry what was your second
question
well let's jump let's take that and
develop that answer a little bit further
let's say if you look at clients that
you've had and compare small growers to
large growers and let's let's make the
assumption that they do want to go to
indoor farming what sort of limitations
do they have in even choosing equipment
for their for their project and let's
focus on the small grower sure yeah so
the limitations are often capital these
systems aren't you know cheap it's not
inexpensive to put LEDs over every
square foot of bed space that you have
and to run those LEDs every day
so I would say it's a lot of capital
limitations more than anything and then
there are some knowledge gaps as well
that we help fill as far as you know
what are the production parameters for
those particular crops how do you
package them how do you maintain a
consistency day to day in your output as
well as how do you comply with a lot of
the regulations that are out there and
bringing that product to market so one
more question for you on that is when I
was listening to one of the panel
discussions yesterday and they were they
were given an example of how a farm has
gone through a lot of different
generations of HVAC equipment my
experience has been that a lot of the
small farms inherit their HVAC equipment
if you're inherit in your experience if
you are inheriting an HVAC HVAC
equipment how does that play into the
choices that you might have sure that's
a that's a really good question
we have seen a lot of inherited
equipment in general HVAC also hydro
inherited hydroponic systems and
inherited irrigation systems etc but
when it comes to HVAC when it's
inherited it's probably not sized
correctly and when it's not sized
correctly you're either you have too
large of a system that'll kick on and
off too frequently and lower the
lifetime of the equipment or it doesn't
have properly sized dehumidification and
we find in general dehumidification is
often overlooked when it comes to
completely
you know enclosed systems like vertical
farms and humidity is one of the biggest
challenges that we face when you have
crops growing in a box they're
constantly transpiring and you have to
keep those humidity loads down in order
to keep paper pressure deficit in range
and to maintain consistent growth so
it's it's a challenge and usually when
equipment is inherited
you're not sizing correctly or you know
not using basically the right stuff so
the next question then be for grant so
grant first you didn't in your over you
didn't tell everybody how big your farm
was so first first thing I want to do is
set it up with you tell everybody like
how large the farm is that this season
is is getting prepared to open then next
how you guys determined what equipment
you were going to be using and what
priority you put to making those
determinations as you design your farm
yeah certainly thanks for asking me
Chris so I have a better model on a
slide in the panel that I'm on in about
30 minutes so so hopefully y'all don't
get too sick of me until then so the
farm that we just finished is sixty
thousand square feet it's in it's in
Pittsburgh it's in a historic town
called Braddock it's actually the town
with the last remaining operating steel
mill in Pittsburgh it's a really
interesting place so in that 60,000
square foot farm we have a 25,000 square
feet from a footprint standpoint of of
biodome space and then that translates
to 126 thousand square feet of growing
space so that's all of the arable space
if you will of all of our stacked
methodology or all of our stacked
systems so that that's that's due to the
level of density that we can get from
from some of the automation that we have
built into the the bio dome so so so
that's the size of the facility the the
initial we didn't enter this space from
a gross science standpoint we actually
entered this space from an automation
standpoint so many of us have have
Carnegie Mellon roots we were not a
spin-out from Carnegie
but we have it was kind of a dorm-room
project if you will to say okay how can
we use robotics to automate a growing
system and that started out as around
the size of this table and then over
over three three years we kept we kept
saying okay how do we how do we think
about moving the plants around the
system to get to to get to automated
workstations and then it was and then it
was it was really taking that
methodology and expanding upon that so
we used a hydroponic system we have fill
and drain trays and then those trays are
moved around the entire entire growing
operation via variety of connected
automation tools some some of it is
off-the-shelf that we've augmented with
with our own software and our own
hardware software hardware integration
and some of it is stuff that we've
proprietary fabricated for ourselves and
then Sam kind of the same question
towards you you know for you guys when
you looked at you know the crops you're
growing or as you're building your
business model we're did the HVAC
lighting conversation ranked in terms of
importance to you guys as something to
solve you know as a priority you know I
think early on we knew that you know
lighting and HVAC we're going to be big
priorities and I think you know
certainly they're they're very much
related obviously you know the the
efficiency of the LEDs there's a direct
impact on what HVAC systems you you're
putting in and and obviously all that's
a function of what you're growing and
how quickly it's growing and
transpiration rates and things like that
so it was very much a top top of mind I
think when we first set out we probably
underestimated like many what was going
to be needed from an HVAC standpoint
particularly on dehumidification you
know to looking back to 2013 2014 but
we've obviously been growing quite a bit
since then and our our next facility
which will be about 140,000 square feet
of floor space but probably the
production equivalent you know if you
take will have about two acres of actual
growing area that'll be the equivalent
roughly the equivalent Wondra acres of
farmland in terms of production volume
so that one that that facility in
particular we're taking a completely
different approach on the the kind of
the critical infrastructure side of
what's needed and then yesterday in a
panel discussion we heard that times of
the year in terms of the markets you
know what what you can potentially get
at market for your product
we heard that times of the year impacted
growing decisions how has how has those
how have those sorts of very very
variables impacted arrow farms as
growing decisions or crop selections
yeah I mean we you know our business
plan is to essentially be a price taker
in the market and that's something that
we're striving for so we want to be
growing at a cost structure that's
competitive with the field farms in
California and in doing so you know
really be in a position where we can
take the price that's given to us
obviously that's somewhat aspirational
in certain instances we have been doing
that in other instances it's been more
of a struggle but that is the goal and
that is I think the goal of this
industry in general is not just to
produce with less inputs but to produce
economically with less inputs than field
farming so so I think the kind of answer
is your question I mean we have seen
some seasonal variability in terms of
order volumes things like that but
generally you know since we're selling
into such a large market for for leafy
greens and in particular that hasn't
really affected us as much as it might
be affecting some of the larger growers
right now okay and then Javeed a crop
question for you in the majority of
projects we see around the country and
really around the world are focused on
leafy greens and culinary herbs can you
have any examples of other crops that
are doing well in a completely lit
environment sure
so strawberries are kind of the the next
big crop that a lot of CA growers are
looking to produce in vertical farms
specifically there's a company in New
Jersey called
we she farms
that is now growing strawberries and
distributing them to Michelin star
restaurants in New York City they cost
about $50 a pound there they're very
expensive
supposedly delicious they are served as
a plating in one of the you know
multiple courses that you'd receive at
this restaurant and as one of the plates
you get two of these strawberries
nothing else so you can see the kind of
markets that these products are getting
into especially on the on the culinary
herbs and niche crop side but we we
caution our clients about this these
markets because the size is limited and
you can over saturate those markets
pretty quickly and there are a lot of
big players in the Dutch Adric
agriculture industry that have focused
on these markets and are paying more
attention to it in the United States an
example of that is the New York City
microgreens market which is is largely
controlled by a Dutch microgreens
producer that produces very cheaply in a
greenhouse on Long Island so they they
compete with all of the smaller
microgreens producers in New York City
and it's hard to build a kind of a
capital raise around a market when you
have or a limited market size when you
have very big players get kind of
stepping into the ring with very low
cost of production and we've seen
investors shy away from those niche
markets for that reason and then this
question I'm gonna give to either grant
or Sam how have your decisions or the
decisions you've made around energy
purchases right how have your technology
partners played a role in that
whether it be I know grant you guys have
micro-grid partner I know you guys are
working with Dell and some other groups
like that have you really you know how
how much do you rely on those
relationships with the tech partners
versus how much of the stuff do you work
on in-house oh maybe go first and try
and try and keep it short so I mean the
the partnerships in this space are huge
so you especially when you think about
when you think about energy it
our largest cost items so when you when
you think about the great math problem
that's how we often talk about it
internally and externally it's all about
trying to make the economics work I
think Sam hit the nail on the head we
all want to be price takers in this
market that's the only way we're going
to be able to to really start to move
the needle in terms of the product that
comes out of out of California so the
the technical knowledge of how different
energy solutions can integrate within a
system is just not something that that
we have both had the time to do because
that would take us probably I don't know
20 years to build the perfect farm on
our own or its it and it's something
that when we we need to connect
information points across we need the
expertise of external partners so if
it's something such as such as our micro
grid where that allows us to take our
internal energy usage and how we plan
for energy usage on a daily basis based
on what's in the biodome and we look at
what's happening in the and from the
grid and we try to we try to manage and
do curtailment as best as possible or if
it's if it's trying to even take a step
back and look at okay having having
high-res high-resolution controls on our
breakers looking at high resolution data
analytics on on each of our panels and
trying to match that up with how our
HVAC is pulling pulling that together
and being able to bounce that off of
somebody who is an external partner and
say hey does this does this look right
for just just how I'm trying to
understand what the hell is going at
part of my language what's going on
that's huge because you know we're we're
a very small focused team we're trying
to get the highest quality plants out
and we really do rely on external
partners very heavily so I think
certainly we rely on external partners
for some things I would say though a
very high level like arrow farms were
where our own technology partner and
that we have a technology that we built
out obviously in conjunction with many
other players but we have a technology
that we're looking to deploy across the
globe and the site selection where you
actually deploy that technology can
solve a lot of the questions and
it's for the same reason why you have
farms in California you may have farms
that are located next to utilities where
you get a lower cost structure or have
certain infrastructure in place you know
there's a reason why farms are in
California and it's because they can
produce with a with a low cost structure
and that's a function of a lot of
different factors but now there's new
technology and those that new technology
is now going to be implemented across
the globe and that will be done in
conjunction with site-specific factors
and I think that can go a long way at
mitigating a lot of the costs so it's a
little bit of a different way to answer
and then one final question before we
open it up to the audience for for
questions I'm gonna put this house to
all three of you because it might be
slightly sensitive information are any
can any of you answer the question what
percentage of your cost of goods and
material does utilities makeup so
another way to ask that is how much on a
per pound basis what percentage is
utilities or whatever whatever metric
you are comfortable using or sharing
yeah I'll take a swing at trying to
answer that it kind of depends on the
crop because not all crops take the same
amount of usage and that if you as you
think about the everything going on in
the biodome you have a mix of crops
that's that's also gonna going to add
into something else from what we found
it's anywhere between thirty to fifty
percent in terms of what our cost is
javi do you have anything to add to that
yeah I would say it depends a lot on the
system type the crop definitely plays a
role in that but also I mean when we
when we look at a greenhouse that has no
supplemental lighting your your energy
use can be very very low and then your
labor will be the higher cost component
almost across the board we see labor as
the the biggest cost for these farms
utilities does hover around 30 to 50
percent usually but then that can grow
if you have a highly automated farm that
uses you know a lot of mechanization and
automation instead of that labor
component Sam do you want to add
anything or okay all right
with that being said I think we have now
have some time for some questions so
I'll turn it to the audience in an
earlier panel we talked about how the
energy consumption of a farm or facility
is not necessarily the greatest
contributor to the carbon impact it's
often the fuel mix and so I was just
curious if you could both were in all
three of you comment on what you've been
seeing in terms of your own facility the
mix between electrical consumption and
other whether that's natural gas
delivered fuels on-site thermal
renewable generators etc yeah from a so
I can't comment on the total carbon
impact we just finished the farm and
where we're literally firing it up to
have have crops on shelves in the next
30 days so that's something that we hope
to be able to share and be in be open
about very soon we do have natural gas
that comes into the micro grid too into
a standby dispatchable generator and
then we have salt we have solar on our
roof as well so you hope to offset that
how much that that will actually take
over time as we think about ramping up
to production we want to we want to
publish actuals once we have them so I
think micro grids are definitely a great
and I think there's a panel on those
later today a great opportunity for the
sector in certain instances particularly
where you have higher energy costs you
know I think there that the challenge is
you need something like 20 times the
square footage in terms of panels of
what you would need just for your
consumption during peak hours of the day
and then you need all the batteries and
everything else so it's it's huge you
know that would dramatically impact your
site selection right so now all of a
sudden you're you're looking for you
know two million square feet versus you
know a hundred thousand square feet
of space it dramatically changes that
assessment so it's a challenge but it's
not to say that it it can't be can't be
addressed I mean we we located
specifically our next farm will be in
Virginia specifically because it had a
reliable grid had reliable inputs for
natural gas and for electricity and also
that we felt the utility was making
efforts itself to diversify its
portfolio and to move into renewables so
you know it's a bit of a different
approach but you know certainly we want
to be partnering with utilities where we
have a like-minded view in terms of the
you know their carbon impact over over
the course of our of our farm operation
so you guys just sort of answer it
Jim Pantaleo Sam grant Javed thank you
so when we talk about either owning a
building or leasing a building it brings
a whole another question in with respect
to how much you can go off-grid maybe
this is a question for you Javed what
have you seen in terms of folks that
owned their buildings versus folks that
lease their buildings and the reason I
asked that is that I've been a part of
indoor farms where the buildings have
been owned and leased for the lease
building we wanted to put photovoltaics
up on the roof
we could totally find with the owner but
when we left they stayed so it didn't it
didn't really pan out with the other
building of course we owned it and we
could have done that but I'm just
curious what your what you know about
that thank you
sure well I think a lot of it comes down
to you know who owns the building and
what they're gonna allow you to do I
would say in the planning stage it's
really important to look at the zoning
in that particular area what that allows
for and if you are planning on using you
know micro grid or
you know other renewable energy tie-ins
that you have the space for that so it's
it's it's difficult to provide a concise
answer for that but I would say it
really just comes down to doing the due
diligence beforehand and making sure
that you can do those things before
you've invested either through a lease
or a purchase
thank you very much gentlemen
a Gorillaz just did a study and
obviously they do quite a bit of reports
I just wanted your comments on vertical
farming because the numbers in that
particular study seem to be fairly high
with regards to not being profitable in
the vertical sight and I know you just
mentioned something about labor as well
which I would expect with the cherry
pickers and all that trying to do you
know vertical farming is gonna be a big
challenge I'm just curious
Jessica do you have a consensus amongst
you of where do you think that's going
and how you may be able to make it more
efficient yes so I think every project
every farm is unique so I think there's
a lot of studies that are published in
this space
labor is often cited in them as as being
a large cost but there are so many
factors that go into this very complex
it's not even complicated it's beyond
that complex math problem I mean what's
the rent
what's the yield cycle what's the are
you doing one crop are you doing
multiple crops you know what is the HVAC
strategy there's all these factors that
come together so I think it's I think
the vertical farming space in particular
has has has struggled because a lot of
people are still trying to approach the
validation or the the proven economics
from a research standpoint without
really looking at kind of full
production assumptions what I what I
mean by that is is really looking at it
from a okay huh how do you balance all
of these different work in process
inventory inventory actuals and and also
what's happening from a market
from a marketing standpoint so I think
it's definitely here to stay as an
industry I think that there's enough
need for it I think that there's enough
factors for it labor is is a component
but it's just a component in a very very
complex problem and I think that's all
right it is very complex but you know
we've been operating now you know the
the vertical farm that I showed in the
video for about three years we just as I
mentioned that was designed about five
years ago when we designed that it was
to prove out certain KPIs and we as a
company have consistently hit those KPIs
and now feel confident that future
build-outs will get the unit economics
that we need so you know in short you
know obviously we didn't we this was so
new when we were setting out to do it
and still extremely new this this
industry is in its infancy we were kind
of triaging risk and we really built the
facility around I would say more like
flexibility because we didn't know
exactly what we needed we didn't know
exactly what automation was going to be
needed we didn't know exactly what you
know critical infrastructure was gonna
be needed so we built it around
flexibility so that we could hit the
KPIs that we needed to hit and you know
having de-risked you know essentially
the ability to scale these vertical
farms you know the economies of scale in
conjunction with those KPIs we feel you
know confident we're gonna be building a
much much larger you know improved
design of that you know in Virginia so I
think that that says something obviously
every technology is different
what profitability means is different to
different parties I mean there's a lot
of different ways to kind of look at it
but but you know I think I agree this
this industry is is unquestionably here
to stay there's a lot of tailwind I
think in the industry as well to kind of
keep driving we just talked about led
efficiency and efficacy there's a lot of
improvements that are kind of coming
down the pipe so and I just add one more
thing to that is that there are profit
vertical farms out there but what did
some what both all the answers up here
touch on a couple of things what is
profit that means a lot to different
people so what you'll see right now in
food production in the vertical farming
industry oftentimes the smaller farms
can turn a profit but they're usually
bootstrapped and profit his measured
maybe differently than somebody who's
out doing a large capital raise and
building a mega vertical farm so it's
variant that I think that that was a
great answer I'd like to see if Chevy
had anything else to add sure yeah what
we've seen a lot is entrepreneurs
building their businesses in kind of a
step function where they won't set out
with positive unit economics they'll
understand that they're going to be
operating at a negative margin for maybe
a couple of years and while they build
their brand and then basically take up
shelf space and then they can leverage
that shelf space for investment in
further rounds and provide their
investors with a roadmap of how they're
going to lower those unit economics and
achieve profitability in the future sure
yeah everybody's going after that
because it's kind of the low-hanging
fruit of the industry it's you know
microgreens smaller baby greens they
have lower light lighting requirements
compared to other crops so you can
manage those heat loads more affordably
and there's a lot of you know existing
standardized automation and Meccan it
mechanization systems that are often
borrowed from the Dutch horticulture
industry that are then used in this
industry to reduce that labor cost but
as the market expands into other higher
value crops we see the labor
become an issue again with things like
strawberries where you know if you're
not operating on a size of farm large
enough you can't use natural pollinators
you have to hand pollinate or you know
do some other method for pollination and
that becomes very cost
costly again so it depends on the crop
as well as the size of your operation
yeah dad one more thing to that at urban
AG news we we look at three variables
and there's a lot of inputs that go into
these three variables if you think
currently if you think about light
intensity you think about plant density
and you think about crop cycle and you
look at the variables that make up those
three are those three measurables you'll
find profit I um I was curious if you
could talk about the commissioning
process whether that you perform
yourself or whether that you had a
partner performed for your facilities
either when you were newly constructing
in your existing building and then Sam
if you have plans for commissioning for
your new facility yes so we we built new
everything was was built from the ground
up we laid the concrete pad everything
else so there's there's kind of HVAC
commissioning when you think about that
there's there's light turn on literally
so so that's all a lot of things is
packaging commissioning so some of that
stuff we've worked with partners where
we've bought technology off-the-shelf
but I mean from a full systems
integration standpoint I mean that's
really proprietary to us and I would I
would I think within this industry it's
pretty much proprietary to everybody
so it's really how you bring all of
these pieces together that that's that's
really the real challenge so we have a
full full kind of commissioning turn on
turn on plan with that that we are at
the tail end of now and so that was
something again back to Chris's earlier
point that was something that we worked
on with external parties so our
relationship with our utility has been
fantastic they've been really close
since we went from dorm room project to
visionary mega farm we included them
from day one so that was that planning
process we we worked hard out probably a
year and a half ago in terms of hey what
is this actual commissioning schedule
ramped up gonna look like and we saw
we've seen really big dividends
making sure that everything was was was
really just just well articulated and we
feel lucky that we we actually did that
piece successfully I mean I agree that
the commissioning is definitely
proprietary how you kind of integrate
all the systems I will say one thing
that that you should distress with these
types of systems is there's there's a
real estate component and then there's
the kind of improvements to that real
estate that needs to happen and then
there's the equipment itself and all of
that is a bit of a dance and the earlier
you have access to the building to
starting installing equipment the better
because it accelerates that time line so
I think from when we talk about like
permitting and early access and those
types of questions there really isn't a
playbook out there and we've had to work
directly you know with the permitting
offices and you know the relevant
parties to get into the building sooner
than maybe you normally would have and
you know I think establishing some sort
of a standard there would be a good
thing for the industry because hopefully
it'll be a good thing for the industry
but getting early access to get that
process going is important because
obviously these are expensive to build
out and the sooner you start growing and
selling food the better we have time for
one more question
yeah go ahead I think that's an
important point Sam that you just made
to around these two so there's a lot of
activity in the cannabis realm so when
you think about permitting when you
think about commissioning from that
standpoint you do have knowledge and
some utilities not certainly not all and
I think we've all been part of that
conversation here today over over the
past couple days a lot of our facilities
do have very proprietary controls so
when you think about panel boards where
those are placed how those are designed
how they're impacting certain production
systems all of that is just going to be
unique to really any type of inspector
so it's it's it's for these size farms
it's it's something that's new and so
for a lot of utilities and a lot of a
lot of inspectors new is just new means
time it means time to understand it
means time to become familiar so making
them a bit of our I mean literally since
the first time we got we got initial
even almost napkin drawings was was what
we tried to do because it's it's a
certainly a unique situation all right
with that I'd like to thank the
panelists and thank everybody for your
attention
[Applause]
[Music]