[Music]
oh damn
oh yeah
a little green hats
eat
i know some varieties they like have
that food
quality that just like we just kind of
want to like eat some of it you know
so you live where i live in kovalev
round valley and mendocino county oh all
right
yeah
just like a few ridges over
yeah but it took a while to get here it
took a while to get here
yeah all back country roads
yeah
so what it introduced us to the lineup
that you brought um so most of these are
velvet perps crosses velvet perps is a
strain that i've been developing for the
past like eight or nine years now
um
which came from a family
strain that we've been working with for
a while
it's a very purple
distinguished
bud that and
it definitely pops out if you if you
look at it and see there's there's not
much bud that looks
like it you know
so it definitely gives you that eye
appeal
and it's pretty crystally and
and it smells really good so
yeah
so most of these are just uh crosses
of the velvet perps so i've crossed uh
i used the velvet perps and crossed it
with all the other varieties that i've
been developing too so i've been
breeding for the past like eight or 12
years now
and what do you like about the velvet
perps that you want to experiment with
in a bunch of different directions
i've found that it's very disease
resistant and resilient to like frost
and it's pretty good vigorous plants so
they get pretty good size
when it's trimmed all down the pounds
are like you know
this big they're very dense buds and
weighty
and
so it makes for a good production plant
so that's why i wanted to cross it into
all my other ones to make them stronger
and
you know just have more of a
uh
seed stock you know and can the guy
standing next to you try it absolutely
yeah you want to try the velvet perps or
you want to try something else
what do you got that's kind of the most
uppity most uppity
uh
yeah
maybe a violet skywalker
the reason we crossed all these
varieties together with the velvet perps
is so we could have a velvet line so
because
we i found out that you know whenever we
have the velvet perps in a dispensary
it's
they always tell us that it's the like
number one seller that they've ever had
you know it flies off the shelf quicker
than anything else
it's a good problem to have yeah it's
it's it's a good problem
so yeah it's a lower thc it's around
like 17 to 18.
so
for overall it's a good for everybody
you know if you don't want to get so
super baked but at the same time it's a
it's a good overall like day smoke and
night smoke
so
yeah
so this is the
velvet skywalker skywalker goo crossed
with the velvet perps
it was awesome
and you're growing in
the earth not even in pot like all in
the earth uh raised beds that we
sheet mulch and uh use just local manure
and our own manure that we produce on
the farm
so everything's in the ground
full sun out of greenhouses no plastic
grown under it on them
or over them
so everything's as natural as we can do
to produce
these beautiful plants so we try to grow
as large as we can
so
most of them so as large as you can how
many are do you have a plant limiter or
a can
it's a canopy limit we have two five
thousand square foot
of gardens but you like to grow big
plants yeah we like big plants so one
plant will go we'll grow one plant in a
nine by nine
area and what's the philosophy behind
that because you don't do that
right i do you do grow as big as you can
okay
i mean that's pretty i we we've always
grown that way like just
um throughout regulations and uh you
know it's always been like oh only 25
plants so we've always just been trying
to maximize the biggest right yeah so
that's kind of where my question's going
which is now that you don't have that
like limit that you have to work around
are you growing it because you think
it's
the best plant or because it's like what
you've done for what i've done and what
i know and what i love to do i like to
see the full expression of each plant
you know
so
having them out there for three full
season
full uh
you know cycles of of the season you
know like spring
summer and fall you know the plant is in
taking all the information from the
cosmos from the soil
you know producing all this beautiful
medicine you know so that's what we
really try to do is um you know make
real medicine so
that everybody can
enjoy
and
get excited about you know that's what
it's about
so what are your initial expectations
me i'm super excited i love it
it's a quiet excitement
i'm gonna tell you the truth i i
actually haven't tried this this
cross yet i really i'm excited
all right yeah i mean these most of
these are all new to me too all right so
this is all like i mean i can only smoke
so much weed at a time so i haven't
really tried them all yet you know
i just busted these out for this little
conference here so you have your
personal joint roller next to
well when i'm going through a lot of
varieties what gets hard for me is when
i hit one that i love
and all of a sudden i just i want to
consume it
and i'm
damn you people that was beautiful yeah
no i see i see myself like going towards
a couple years back like at least trying
the things that that people are
hyping up or whatever and like hopefully
from a couple sources yeah yeah
i had a couple three purple ones come on
great yeah awesome i knew it was the
genetics not the temperature yeah it's
definitely like july
the the velvet perps the the genetics
came from uh a jagua line which is like
a
purple jasmine
goo afgoo
so the purple jasmine is very
dominant purple tree
smell like that real
like carrot top smell yeah
my native friends were going crazy about
it
oh
yeah it's awesome
um this velvet candy is one of my
favorites too i just this is a new one
candyland goo cross with the velvet
curves
that turned out really nice yeah yeah
i just like
the colors like popping out and the
crystals
well the crystals look so much more
against the purple background
right yeah it's like wow
i actually photographed some of them oh
i bet they're very uh photographer at
all right yeah they're very photogenic
so in terms of your
like predominantly where where do you
see all your sales coming from like is
it concentrated locally or is it like
like are you selling down in la and
um
[Music]
we're sending it right now to um local
uh
company that
bucks it trims it and then
uh
distributes it wherever we want so
we're gonna have like
uh companies that we work with already
you know and
you know wherever it goes it's fine with
us as long as uh
you know
they can
send it out but as long as they
reference like sun roots farm our name
on there we're good with that you know
we're not trying to like
fill jars that are at our farm or
anything
it's too much work
we sell wholesale and that's it like
after that we're work we're good
what are your thoughts and what you just
smoked
that's great
it's it's wonderful no i'm just kind of
taking it in because there's this common
thing that's going on
in
all this all these crosses that like
that i really like that i haven't seen
in a long time
the the jagua totally makes sense that
that's it's bringing in that flavor like
for whatever reason in my circle that
just hasn't been around in i don't know
a decade or something
and
so that's that's super fun
i love dragoo is a local
strain to kovalev
my brother and his friend noel actually
uh
collaborated and
produced that one like i don't know
probably 15 years ago now
and
throughout the years we've just been
breeding with certain phenotypes that
come out and selecting the ones that we
like
though we had this one seed stock that
each seed just came out totally
different like oh this one's a silver
goo this one's a strawberry this one's a
lemon all in the same
like cross but they had all these
different flavors it was yeah all the
expressions it was it was just like a
little
yeah it was amazing like those seeds
i wish i had some still i grew corn like
that this year someone gave me one year
of corn
okay i'll plant it
man it had
yellow corn white corn blue
[Music]
we grew some like red
flint corn this year it's really
beautiful corn oh yeah yeah yeah
this was a some heirloom strain i didn't
get the name of it
the main thing i was concerned is to go
work in my
normal climate yeah
this platinum velvet right here is
this is a one of my new favorite strains
that one just like
for the purple and then
it's got that you got those uh
almost like orange hairs and blue
let's see like in in there that is
like just the beach which the one we
were looking at was
that the one that just carried it all
the way through to the
the core
and what did you say the cross was on
this one this is a platinum diesel
crossed with the um velvet perps okay
what do you got going on
this is actually some lamb spread
that we uh
we got we've been
messing with it's like something i like
to delve into
more
uh as opposed to like kind of other
things that i
that i work with you know like
this that are a little bit more
you know
standard on the market it's cool to like
put something
out
uh
i don't know something that that's just
it's actually it's bringing
something much more unique to the market
and like
to see people actually consume something
like this that doesn't have the visual
appeal
of my other varieties and to like
to be like wow i wasn't expecting it to
be an actual experience that somehow
like that automatically it's gonna be
lesser than because it's not carrying
these these visual appeals like
you know so
something like
this that just fall
like i just think it falls a lot more
i don't want to even say more flat but
it's just like i've consumed so many
variations of product like that in the
last five or ten years
that like
it's hard for me to really differentiate
it as like a new experience even though
if it has a new name
um
and like and these are all varieties
that are just coming into my life from
different directions different popular
things that are being bred and like to
come across something that
has fallen out of
favor a little bit or as uh
you know not not in production or
circulation and be like oh my god this
truly is cool this actually has this
thing in some unique merit where all of
a sudden i want to
hold i'm not so i'm not so quick to just
like let it pass through my hands like
well every i think i feel like every
like variety even if it's not like what
you're saying as visually appealing it
definitely has its um benefits even if
it's you know it may not look so
you know
so
how do you get the public to appreciate
yeah right
when they're going after bag appeal
and jar appeal now right well yeah our
screen appeal or numbers i think yeah
number two testing
testing and like yeah when
those are hitting mid and high 20s
and this is not then that makes it
it's harder to get rid of
yeah or yeah even get people to
experience on a smaller level
versus yeah when i just give it away and
share it with people that i love i get i
get to have that interaction in a way
that bringing
another
new popular varietal the people in my
core center are bored
like
they're kind of like okay cool versus
when i like dabble into this other stuff
for my own enjoyment i see it around me
and like my
my group of people where they truly get
excited
you're like they like the stuff i like
yeah or just ideas
even if it turns out that like okay this
one isn't my perfect thing at least it
was cool getting there because it was
different
that's what i've been that's what i've
been having a lot of fun with recently
[Music]
and what new kind of like experiments
are you doing on the farm
like what are you playing with whether
it's like composting
this next year i'm actually going to do
some direct sewing like in february
just pop some seeds out there right
where i plant
just
what
of what i'm gonna grow they're like
white water you know something something
like this
oh yeah okay oh i see instead of like
starting them in the greenhouse and blah
blah blah transplanting i wanted to see
whichever ones survived because i mean
i usually don't clone
cloak them like if you're going to put
them outside outside outside in february
you're just going to let them
just let them do their thing because i
always like have volunteers coming up in
my garden and they do just fine you know
so if they're in the right place and i
you know given the right care
you know if it's going to be a crazy
storm i might go over there out there
and like cover them up with like a
little pot or something for the night
but you know i'm gonna
see how that um turns out because i feel
like
it might be a lot
better than doing all this extra work
transplanting
making soil to
start your seeds in you know all that so
just trying to um minimize
what is you know the impact and
the work because it's definitely a lot
to deal with
in the springtime philosophy and this
coming february is the first february
you're gonna do it
yeah i'm gonna try it that way
like in an ideal world just a whole
bunch of them like evenly spread out
around the property for like the yeah
i'll probably just like stick five or
six seeds right where i want you know a
plant and then pick the best one you
know
so i like that
and then there's the whole thing too
with the tapper in the whole root system
that it just never has that weird
experience like
it's it's going for it like from day one
you put it in a pot and it's always
gonna get root bound you know no matter
what it is so
unless you're like transplanting it when
before it needs to be transplanted
which can work but it can happen
yeah you're always disturbing the roots
you know
you transplant and then it has that
shock of being in new ground and being
outside so i just want to like
try to avoid all that does anyone know
any good bomb games we'll see how it
goes
yeah no totally
oh yeah
we got to do some
that's really interesting i want to
reach out to you again on like how
how the plant
seems like a trade-off right it's like
okay maybe it is going to be a little
bit rough in the beginning for the pen
but
it's well that'll make it more strong
yeah you know way so
yeah it'll make it more resilient to you
know everything else
i mean you're the strongest one
[Laughter]
so tina's gonna jump in okay
because i've noticed like everybody
keeps smelling
one thing
oh yeah everyone's been digging that
yeah
sounds good yeah the bernie mac bring
the bernie mac in
wow i want to smoke some of that one
i just love to
all the time
yeah
i mean this is is funny is like
even though i do i miss all kinds of
stuff this is one of the few events
and i feel like i'm going with the
commercial supermodels varietals
people actually have unique
well somebody's gonna appreciate these
if your chicks
kinda look like this like
my values too
it was very gratifying to open this and
see that yeah i was like hey come on
i had one last night and starting my day
again
[Music]
oh there was this
i mean there were several in here that i
was so excited about i'd like to see
which ones are yours and yours as well
because i didn't bring anything because
i'd travel across the board oh yeah man
i'm gonna come and check it out so why
don't you introduce these guys to what
you brought sure
this is um
bernie mac as label
and this is sapphire
so sapphire is a two to one
cbd to thc
um biovortex genetics
and um
you know i was just i'm just really into
colas right now
and just like so you can see
really kind of get a sense of the plant
right
and really
trying to draw
the um like the bud and the flower back
to the plant
yes
and so this grew we grew this in three
different environments and one of them
was in these deep google cultures one of
them was in a shallow google culture and
the other in boxes
and this is shallow google culture i can
tell by the structure because the
structures got like the the deep google
cultures ended up being kind of more
like big and fluffy
and
and big mamas you know
like really big expressive divas and
then the smaller
google culture medium-sized buds
medium-sized colas but a lot of some
girth
and then the boxes tighter smaller bugs
[Music]
there's lots of things to talk about but
would love impressions at you know any
point
and then this one
this is the bernie mac that's left which
is cool and i had done this oh let's see
there's a couple
crazy looking
buds
with sugar leaf
yeah that looks
[Laughter]
delicious and i wanted to leave this
once again i wanted to leave like all
the leaf on all the sugar leaf
so you could just kind of check out
beautiful the um yeah i like to see it
we still get to see what it looks like
check out the show i mean that's all
good yeah it's just
sugar
and if you can just feel the
remember last that we were talking about
trichomes and trichome development
and you can kind of feel like this is
definitely a greasy
yeah grease your trichomes
yes
you can break one off and just yeah and
it's got that nose that you get with the
grease
what do you call that one this is bernie
mac and the genetics um
of this are by capulator and this was
something that we picked up to do some
pheno hunting and this was absolutely
the the weakest it was the week they
were the weakest moms the weakest clones
when we transplanted them
they had transplant shock for two weeks
they were slow to come back
and there were several times when i
thought about pulling them out and
replacing them and then we just kept
going with them and going with them and
because we had this incredibly extended
like late summer
they suddenly came on in september
and we finished cutting the first week
of december
wow so they were it was like the rare
season for the late bloomer because we
just didn't have any weather yeah yeah
it was quite the season we started them
with the clones we cut the clones in
i want to say march
[Music]
no maybe later
i think it was april that we cut the
clones but
i was going to give up on them several
times and then she ended up being the
superstar the clone superstar of the
year
so i'm glad i didn't give up
awesome
and it had a really powerful had a
profound lesson about late bloomers
and you never know you never know
give them a
chance i had a similar experience that
it's like i haven't grown this but this
is just the regular mac and i hunted a
couple years ago and
last season and
this season it like you know definitely
struggled in in terms of speed of veg in
comparison to everyone else
but then when it started to flower
really worked out in our environment i
don't know at least where i'm at like it
just flowers really healthy and it just
came out for me and come on
what's your elevation 1200
to 1900 depending on where and how far
are you from the coast
we're in bloxburgs so i don't know
exactly and in miles but like
yeah something i think they were like 15
miles east of the 101 and the that would
be like probably about a miranda so i
don't know what that would be from there
out to the coast it's about 20 miles
from the 101. less a little less of the
crow flies
no it's 20 miles yeah yeah so you might
be about 40 miles
i guess
yeah how about you guys
um we live in the valley florikovalo
which is around 1400 feet
but the mountains go around like 7 000
above us so
we have our own little microclimate
there
and then your climate's probably
completely different yeah yeah
we have short seasons
so what's your elevation how far from
the the closest ocean right we're we're
eight hours inland like we're far from
ocean
not everybody where we live has good sun
like our places we get nice long days
and
i'm able to do uh
outdoor greek hoop houses
i'd like them that way
it's like how do you decide you know you
work with the environment right to
figure out how you're going to
throw every strain though it's a lot
like
yeah it's pretty
pretty important to find the right
strains that'll work
in our climate
so which ones work for you
um there's some
some ones out there
like um
there was one
my friend was working with
calling it white grizzly and that one
it just didn't have the
thc levels but it was a really reliable
it's not gonna get mold and
it's gonna finish
and then
people started breeding that one
with this other one called seaweed
and
that's not what
much nicer look
another better finisher
[Music]
i am rolling i think i'm rolling some of
this mac larry just put on the table
yeah i just pulled it out of that and
this is you this is you right yeah
yeah
and these are all sun roots
[Music]
yeah and we just uh
this color is incredible
we were talking about that earlier
i think i did some of this last year uh
josh and kelly gave me some seeds
and i was doing a light depth and
had all these crazy purples coming out
and i'm pretty sure
uh it was from you awesome velvet perps
maybe yeah did you smell that
yeah that's amazing
i'm curious about something when you see
trichomes falling off right
like
is that abundance is that um temperature
is that humidity
probably a little heat humidity
it was really
i mean i think it's one fact everything
you i'm not disagreeing with anything
but um the longer the competition stock
the more likely it is to break off
i would be interested like to say
uh since there's all kinds of different
glands and some
for our purposes are more valuable than
others on the same bud like is it for
all the same like so are there equal
percentages of those same different
types of of trichomes left on the bud as
on the
bag or glass or something interesting
like which ones which glands are most
prone to drop
and is that those ones happening is that
advantageous
like you're saying is it just because of
an abundance like i see it probably more
in in india like whatever what's it
called indicates like you know dense the
frosty buds most of what kind of sells
well for me and that's kind of like a
little discussion i've been having with
a couple of people and we were kind of
talking about this with something like
the lamb spread that just doesn't have
like
visually like nearly as much crystal or
frost as most of my other varieties but
it's way less likely to have stuff
shedding off on the bottom of the bag
it also doesn't get those high
numbers on tests but still has a an
effect that could be considered strong
so when we say strong and then we are
also talking about numbers meaning
strength
there's kind of an issue there so is
that leaf to calex ratio
right is that part of what's happening
yeah there's a there's a lot more leaf
in there than in like
one some other variety
that's like
or like this yeah or like that would
share way more parental lineage like way
more similar varieties than
that coming out of left field yeah that
looks more like a land race yeah
and all these have been poly hybrid
crosses with other poly hybrids like
yeah
and this one
uh
it's
that one and
this one are
yeah that's lovely
and that's more like what i
like i i personally like more like it's
if is this a heritage genetic no
no it's a more nuclear but it's it's
like more on that
i don't know like enough about terpenes
really speak but i guess like
humiliating when people talk about earth
like deep
earth cushy
flavors and this is just a different
pheno of that and i think it has a
little bit more i guess what they call
gas or whatever but
um
whoa
i like got your pickles and your relish
on there too
this keeps an afghani
nose to it
right and yeah like i i wouldn't consume
those all the time but i really like
having
something really strong in there and uh
i realized something kind of recently is
like a simple thing for me
in terms of describing like i don't care
what strain something is i think like
most people here but
one
one distinction i do like to make is i
like
really more
upberty uppity type of weed for the most
part
but then when it's not that i like it to
be this strong antithesis to that and
the wii that personally doesn't speak to
you that much is all this stuff in the
middle it's just kind of like murky
and
that's subjective but for me
and that's where i'm going back to this
kind of thing i've been talking and
thinking about a lot recently is my own
like personal hypocrisy
around producing so much product that
would fall into that very category
uh
it's it's pretty and it's not that it
isn't potent clearly by its tests it's
something
but
it's
for my personal consumption it's falling
flat in
in some area because it's not really
pulling me
strongly in in either direction that's
like that that's just something it's
like a mediocre meal
it fills you up you're like
i'm done i'm check box done with dinner
yeah but that's about it
well is it also like different
personalities
yeah right and so it's interesting
because this is like an adaptogen right
and it has so much to do with like
personally a two to one four to one
you know eight to one
sits pretty well with me during the day
and at night like 90 this is nighty
night for me
you know i like i can't really smoke
this during the day
[Music]
or actually this is just thc
yeah this is just hc but nighty night a
little bit before like not right before
bed because it's clarity and it's kind
of like but it's pretty heavy thc and so
pretty probably intense it's pretty
intense or if i have like you know a lot
of communications to do it's def like
conversations will go way too long
yeah
like if i'm just trying to stay to my
list and get down to brass tacks for the
day and get it done
if there's some creative time or time in
the garden go
and that's awesome right
but um it's also i've been thinking
about how much this is like this
resembles art
like flower with the intention that goes
into it and the personality and the
perspective
and it's like the synthesis of life
experience you know there's nobody who
does it exactly the same
you know and so is there a way to
so what's the criteria on
like
on taste
how do you account for taste or like
personal relationship with something you
know
it's like it's like to me it's more like
music or art or love than wine or beer
or
food or any you know
i find like just growing the plant
throughout the year you build a
relationship with it like each each time
you go out in the garden you're building
a relationship to it every time you
clean it out you know and you know make
check it for bugs you're building that
relationship so
um
yeah
i mean you remember plants from years
ago right oh yeah i remember every plant
in my garden for a long time
like that's a relationship yeah i can go
out in my garden and know what every
plant is like
or what like
back in previous years
i remember in that spot
and that was the one
and i think that's the one yeah what's
that spot going to do this year
and that's that's the beauty of like
starting seeds and
planting them with seeds because you
never know really what you're going to
get
so until you see the
expression of it and
that's what really
makes it special to me
when do you see the expression
when like when is there a true
i guess i guess that's kind of open
question but i
one thing that i'll say is like if i'm
working with things that are way out of
left field or something
then i see there's much earlier but it
gets tricky i think sometimes when i'm
working with 10 versions of the same
so i'm working on narrow gene pools and
we're trying to claim diversity and
variety out of what's really not but
that's what the market is is screening
for
like play playing um
playing along with that and so it's like
when i get to come across these truly
different flavors and i think there's
like something not even like because
it's the biggest amount of different
types of pot i looked at a gathering
like this but it's a way bigger spread
because people are pulling things
out of
i don't know out of their own collection
of their parents collection their
friends grandparents collection like
that's when you brought 12 drawers 12
different things and you you are pretty
much like all these crosses here is
there anything yeah that is center oh
except for this lemonhead i just
bought some seeds actually that last
year for like the first time
because i wanted a super lemony variety
that i could cross back and i crossed it
into the velvet perp so next year
we'll have some
it was just like some sea junkies or
something yeah
off the internet
um but i wanted to
broaden the gene pool and make something
more unique you know like a purple
super purple that has like a lemony
smell to it you know
there's there's nothing like that yet
so we'll see how what how it goes
what are you exciting
um
a bunch of
two to one crosses so like
we have this one called lunar bouquet
that's uh harley sue crossed with
roseberry
and so
it's got a nice like blueberry overtone
and it's also a bit earthy
and i want to cross that back into
higher thc to
really find a true one to one
is what i'm looking for
like searching for
and um but the right one to one
and um
and so there's some hunting to do around
that but that's the one that i'm most
excited about
how about you
well i'm just right in the transitioning
between indoor and outdoors so
like i'm really
trying to figure out what i'm gonna go
with
with this uh
you know the whole uh
legalization and all that up in canada
yeah that's part of uh
this trip is like research even like uh
trying to figure out
what to move forward with
my programs changing
like those those ones i mentioned
earlier like the jellyfish and the
seaweed
the ones that i've been
so you can destroy just anything yeah
it's really interesting to see what's
going to acclimate outside inside or
inside outside well yeah yeah like the
the light that's kind of like the
transition thing right so you see which
ones are hardy and which ones are uh
prone to mold they're milky
but yeah i'm uh
untapped you're hiring your feet
pardon me
[Laughter]
yeah so i'm uh
just on the
that adventure of uh
you know the transition of legalization
and
discovery discovering you know what's
going to work for for my uh
dream right to to
to uh
grow some fields of it
have you tried the root or alice up
there well that's what i've been looking
into too because
yeah i've i haven't not tried it but
i've been talking to folks about it
because i think that might be a real uh
wait yeah
yeah
what's that dan dan yeah oh okay
yeah i'll talk to him yeah yeah because
that's um
i mean
to fight the unpredictability of the
fall right like that would be a good
solution
[Music]
i mean i've been so stoked and see like
i feel like this has happened in all
kinds of
i don't know things that i i caught like
when they were new and
i don't know because it didn't catch me
at that time i didn't really go anywhere
with it meanwhile other people were
and
so like when rudor alice or when
you know people started pushing
autoflowers 10 or 15 years ago
maybe maybe longer but like it really
started to come on the forefront like
whatever mid late 2000s
and they just weren't
there for the most part at least what we
saw
and uh and now i'm seeing some product
that's pretty impressive well that's
yeah i think there's some breeding with
the root or alice right yeah yeah yeah
they're working but then the background
dance dance were looking good right fans
were looking good for rude or alice like
yeah hell yeah yeah so cool and he was
like saying that if you you can breed
you know he he
three or four years down the line we're
going to have a reuter alice velvet
perch so nice yeah
very cool yeah that's exciting very cool
folks i
was talking to got uh two crops this
year with three doraleous yeah because
they they planted their seeds
like
ten days two weeks before harvest
right next to the ones they're about to
harvest so then they had a protected
environment and
they said it worked out pretty good that
is like right there that's true
yeah so that's i know people doing a lot
more work
that's a great idea
[Laughter]
like so
like what's going on with the soil when
something like flowers are finishing
and then you're starting again i i agree
i like i kind of like i'm kind of of
that persuasion but that again like
but if this also works pretty well but
it's saving all these other ways there
just might be like such a place where
that trade-off makes sense
like how do you how are you getting two
crops a year like without light dipping
like what are you talking about and
that's what he told me he's doing i'm
like
whoa
if the genetics are there waiting
waiting waiting waiting yeah
he said the first crop was uh 60 days
and the second one was 70.
and he said it was
he did the math it was 20
more
overall harvest than a single crop of
bigfoots
yeah
really cool so i'm considering i'm
actually going to visit his farm when i
get back and uh no trellising invited me
for that yeah yeah yeah my big plan is i
have to like
cage them three times you know yeah so
i'll have like a little inner one and a
big outer one and then a net around that
just to keep them from falling over
that's how when i grew yours that's what
i was doing exactly yeah
i was like i took some pictures of my
top step of the step ladder doing some
pruning and tying up i'm like yeah
one of the cool things about growing in
terraces
there are spots where you can stand on a
terrace above another terrace and like
utilize that it's like a scaffolding
system yeah
well i live on a flat
valley so i can't do that you know that
must be terrible
there's so there's so much extra space
to use
it would be really wonderful if you guys
could come by on your way out tomorrow
there's going to be i think a few people
that might trickle down some three
parcels away
so like three parcels away from here
down island mountain road towards town
and to see like i mean it's it's
incredibly challenging like there are
these tiny little
terraces
with like steps
to all of our wider little roads um they
vary and it's all like none of it's
consistent like this county and the
state hate us
hate us i was gonna
ask you about that
yeah some something for sure when the
state came to my garden there and it's
like what do you do
well
and we've worked it all out and i made a
lot of concessions and
it went went through a lot of stuff but
like when i've seen pictures of your
garden it's like i was gonna ask you how
did that work with them well i spent a
lot of time explaining why i shouldn't
be taxed for interplanting
like for companion planting
and so the inspector was like well it's
part of the cannabis i mean it's part of
your garden and i was like
and i was like well just kind of
consider the return on
um on this you know
on these plants like on the on the
companions
like comfort i'm not going to sell this
country and i'm not going to sell this
caster and i'm not going to sell this
you know any of this amaranth
and so why am i being taxed on the
square footage for it
and so and then i started explaining
like the reason why it's so important
like for the for the soil health and for
the plant health and environmental
health and all of it and he by the end
of the inspection he was like okay it's
cool i get i think i get it
and it was just a beautiful education
piece really awesome
that's so great to hear
um and who what what agency was this
specifically well it was a
a county inspector working for the state
because the state isn't sending
inspectors out there they're using
county inspectors