[Music]
Casey we've been talking about you know
big AG Big Pharma and also the the
corporate reality you know a lot of us
have corporations but when we're
referring to the corporate entity we're
talking about you know mergers and and
and things that are much larger than
anything that we've dealt with as
farmers or as small business owners or
even as educators Casey could you talk a
little bit about the uneasy compromise
in this industry definitely you know my
farm is about an hour from here
born and raised on the mountain and in
2014 you know we're doing the farmers
markets we're doing the collective and
we find ourselves suddenly very public
and we've got the alphabet soup of
various media arriving on the farm you
know the first the first like
significant media interaction I ever did
was CNN and the story title was doping
the drought and it was essentially like
essentially like hey your teams down by
about nine runs there's nobody on base
you got two outs you want to swing the
bat or what and and you know so for us
at the time you know being food
producers being you know were farmers
market vegetable farmers CSA farmers and
small-scale cannabis very small-scale
cannabis you know we really felt that
there was this typification of cannabis
farming happening and happening in the
media that was was very wrong and so you
know it was a it was a very difficult
decision in terms of that whole going
public process but suddenly we found
ourselves like very much in the
limelight and still to this day you know
a big part of my social change agenda my
focus my goals is to be able to engage
in a in a conversation that reaches as
far out as possible to be able to speak
to the values that I hold and the
beliefs that I have around food
production around small farming around
regenerative practices and the difficult
part of that is that when you wade into
that center whether it's public policy
whether it's public media there's a lot
of compromising
parent to that and that is for me one of
the great you know philosophical and and
deeply personal questions is like where
you know where can the compromises be
where are the compromises can we accept
those compromises and it's an emotional
roller coaster you know there are times
where I'm like you know what fuck it I
quit and there are times where I see
something or you know where I received
feedback like you said this thing that
really touched me from so you know from
from Michigan from Illinois you know
from all over the country in this this
broader perspective and I think one of
the things that's very very important
for us as farmers is to is to recognize
that we all have different context and
we all have different reality under
which we find ourselves and we make
decisions accordingly and I think
there's a tendency with many social
movements in cannabis as a social
movement to end up in a place that's
very dogmatic and when we do that we
take away something that was possible
and for me you know a big part of my
focus is is local food security and food
systems and so I look at ways that I can
help to promote local food security and
and food sales for food farmers and that
was a big part of my initial foray into
public policy work was this idea that
food farming and cannabis farming here
on the north coast of often gone
hand-in-hand you know going to the
farmers markets and realizing after a
while like all these other old-timer
farmers are all totally grown weed to
like cuz I'm like hiding around the
corner smoking my joints and they're
like hey so you're gonna share or what
and that was a big realization for me
and that's part of what drove me into
the public policy conversation was
wanting to see food farmers have access
to the regulated cannabis market to see
it as see it continue as this support
tool that it has been for our
communities and so all of those things
are still what drive me and I look at
the landscape of the current cannabis
regulatory environment and the current
marketplace and it's very very difficult
and so in terms of being here in a
solutions oriented
effective you know is what I see are for
lack of better terminology organized
buyers and I see that we still do not
have not been able to achieve the role
of organized seller and how do we build
that out moving forward and this is one
of those points where you know for me
I'm very comfortable doing media
interactions I'm very comfortable
talking to the government I'm a terrible
businessman and so it's it's kind of one
of these like we each bring our
skillsets to this puzzle you know I sort
of have this an hour to my brain lives
in analogies of there's this puzzle and
we all got different pieces of it but
somebody took the box away so we're all
trying to figure out like what does this
puzzle look like where are the pieces
who are the pieces what pieces do we
need to still pull in and how do we
evolve into this arena in which as small
farmers we can be organized so that we
can negotiate with on a scale the
organized buyers because at this point
as a farmer you know for me I faced this
hard choice of like well you know I had
a business model that was a farmers
market business model we were doing the
collective it worked really well and now
I'm a wholesale farmer and I can choose
to either sell my product or not sell my
product and if I choose to not sell my
product to go out of business and get a
different job so all of those realities
pile up on us and and you know it's the
emotional rollercoaster at any given day
like I can totally do this
oh fuck and we're all in that at the
same time and like I think that's one of
the things that's really important about
these gatherings is that you know we're
all at different places on the emotional
roller coaster in any given day and the
gathering gives us the ability to
modulate and and go back forth to
continue to do the work so long story
short you know what I see looking at the
playing field is there are giants you
know we've talked about these huge
multinational corporations the publicly
funded marketplace there are giants
within our space which are massively
larger than us and then there's us and
you know I I wish I could say like I've
got the answer silver bullet and I don't
but it's it's the reality that we're all
facing and trying to figure out how to
navigate as very small players in a war
that is essentially based on corporate
and government super structures and so
one we're trying to find our places
within it and figure out how to navigate
it
but two we're trying to figure out how
to change it and there's the old saying
like don't change a paradigm build a new
one and the old one will cease to exist
and I definitely resonate that but for
me and in my role I've always been more
of a centrist and so it's been my job to
go and talk to policymakers and and
generally to be able to come to an
agreement yeah I see where you're at
this is where I'm at okay this is our
compromise in the center and so I think
it again comes down to each of us has
our own specific paths in our work that
we must do and where we are called to
fit into that puzzle we must find that
place and go forth and do so and so you
know one of the things that I've
struggled with a great deal from a
personal perspective is the judgment
that comes with and from this process in
which we're dealing with both ideology
we're dealing with business and we're
trying to figure out how to navigate
those things and and that for me is the
heaviest burden and the thing that is
the hardest about the process is that I
often don't feel like I have the right
answers but I feel like I have to
continue on the path to try to figure
them out and I think that's the the same
for all of us and so one of the things
that I really want to call in for our
community is is to remain supportive and
to hold space and understanding for each
of us for where we are and and be able
to come to a commonality around that and
continue to move forward because this
whole thing is is you know watching the
changes in the last five years has
really ripped us apart and in some ways
and I think if we are not able to create
space for people to be where they are
while we try to put together what we
want to be we're gonna have a really
tough time with it
what is with this whole process is that
public policy is always iterative and so
you know we started off with the very
vague SB 420 collective cooperative so
2016-2017 I'm part of a project that's
operating an agricultural cooperative
and that was you know it's great it's
Sunkist it's the organ value what is it
nevermind but there's there's a ton of
like big AG coops that you know Pacific
Coast producers controls 80% of fruit
packing and tomato packing in the
country and it from California and
they're cooperative farmer owned and so
you know we moved into this this
iteration of like yeah we're gonna do
cooperatives gonna be amazing and then
the state said well actually we made a
cooperative rule and you can only be
four acres in cultivation to be in the
quarter to have your cooperative can't
exceed that and so we've kind of gone
back to the drawing board in which well
okay can we do a c-corp that is you know
that has be core principles and
cooperative bylaws you know and so this
is very much the solution I hope to see
in us becoming an organized seller and
the hard thing about it for me is having
gone through three iterations of it like
I've come to realize like I want to join
it and follow in it and put energy
towards it I can't lead it and so that's
really again you know I said it in the
panel earlier today and I'm gonna call
it out again like those of us in this
community who have those business skills
to lead that type of project like we we
need you because that's that's the
biggest part of it is that it's farmers
we're pulling in a million directions
and when you start a cooperative it's a
whole nother layer of business you got
to do and as farmers were like man so
you know I think that this is the time
and opportunity for us to organize with
the limited resources that we have to
try to become an organized seller and I
think you know you have to be really
careful in that conversation I'm not
talking about violating antitrust laws
but that we be able to engage in
aggregation
grading if as small farmers we had
aggregation and grading so we could say
these facilities have this weed at this
grade that would change the marketplace
completely and that's something that
given the number of locally owned
businesses that we have now who have
facilities you know we're starting to
have the pieces on the board to be able
to do that and it just requires enough
leadership and impetus to be able to
draw those pieces together into
something cogent that's really the
difference between the big corporate
structure they have this you know bottom
line and the thing about our community
is that our line is bottomless we are
going to be forever trying to figure out
solutions and how we're going to be
putting medicine out to the people
because it's what it's what it is that
we inherently do we're here to do that
and as a collective we have to keep our
revenue streams rolling in a way that is
productive because when each farm is is
doing well financially then the entire
community is doing well financially and
I wanted to start to move into the idea
of creating revenue and revenue streams
as a collective and one thing that I
have thought about that that I think
could be very poignant and very
accessible to us right away is that many
many many of us have secondary products
that we produce on our farm whether we
produce chicken eggs whether we produce
gorgeous jewelry whether we produce
consulting services education whether we
are coming to your local zone an area as
a group I believe that we can take all
of these secondary products that we have
and put it on an international
marketplace that is a pure certified
marketplace that could be easily put up
that people could ship products from
their own location they could you know
go online to book their consulting and I
just think that I would like
put that on the front burner as a
discussion in moving forward for this
collective and start talking to the
people here in this room that are
absolute wizards at helping to create
something this is this could be
education forward education number one
and there's a lot of people in this room
who already have incredible successes
with multiple products as well as
secondary products outside of the
cannabis industry and forest and
Patricia you guys are really on top of
it with your secondary products and what
you offer from the community could you
talk a little bit about that and how you
can see that as something to move for in
the collective I love that this got
brought up because I do actually yeah I
love I wanted to bring this up before
that really on this international
marketplace we should be as part of
education and as part of what we are
allowed to do is be selling other
products such as tea blends and you know
using the diversity that you have on
your farm not just tea blends you can be
creating canned products and ferments
and all these different creations that
you do it doesn't even have to be with
food it can be some kind of blend or
some kind of wizard ear magic that you
truly embody and can put out there so
like on our farm we have a lot of
products that I sell mostly at one place
which is a little co-op in our town and
we hope to start extending it like the
tincture making and the herbal tea
blends and fermented food products from
our farm selves anything that we can get
creative with and that does lead in part
to the education because there's so many
people and times that I've heard from
city folk who I work with and I grew up
in the city so I have that kind of
connection where people just want to be
tapped into a different source of Metis
and it's not just about cannabis its
food as medicine there's herbs as
medicine there's earth medicine spirit
medicine there's all these different
facets of what we're doing on our farms
that connect us back and we can share
and put it out there as part of the
story that it's not just one little
portion it's all of it encompassed so
Kate and Bobby got it you all really are
doing a lot of multiple products in
cannabis and you're really diversifying
your brand you're creating more products
than I've seen a lot of other people
create and I'm seeing huge successes so
how can that help other farmers and
moving further into the industry and and
for the success of multiple products
okay so I'm a silversmith by trade I
haven't quite figured out the link for
between cannabis and plants and silver
smithing yet so that's kind of something
that remains very close to my heart but
very much on the back burner so we
primarily started out producing flowers
from there we moved into extracts we do
co2 because we were finding we needed
more revenue streams so currently we
produce a line of THC products in a
separate line of hemp CBD products the
reason for this is because the THC
products are not I have a hard time
distributing them our market is mostly
the end consumer we are in a few stores
we will be gaining momentum in 2020 we
just got product liability insurance
this process took us over six months and
it was just a whole lot of back and
forth and now we're like insured all
over the place like in case something
happens everybody can feel good about
knowing that our products have
insurances so with that being said we
have picked up a few new stories we
create a salve that's like our main
product actually every product we've
created has been
for his mother she is basically like our
guinea pig
she's always she has more ailments than
anyone can imagine so I've always been
making things and testing them out on
her we started with a sow that fixed her
sciatic nerve one of our other products
we make a elderberry medicated sleep
elixir this got her off sleep
medications this has gotten several
family members off of sleep medication
and then these people tell other people
so yes we should be mostly selling to
people with a medical card this is not
always possible so you know our products
are kind of expanding this way and I'm
able to make products CBD products and
sell those over the internet so we just
keep diversifying this is how we're
growing we do other things we have
vegetables for sale sometimes we're
working to open a farm stand on the
property this year so we can give people
an address to come to because meeting up
and delivering is just not really
fitting in our schedule so if you if you
can come to our farm and you know buy
our products from us and we can stop in
the middle of the day and sell them to
you like yes this is this is what we're
doing or ancient green farm yes
yep the products are all branded under
ancient green farm I do all the product
labeling and marketing so I do put my
art school degree to use you can have
the greatest product in the world but if
your label looks like shit you're really
not going to sell it
yeah this is something I will get to I
have a lot of ideas it comes down to
time I'm creating also a brand that's
really recognizable I'm I'm looking in
this room and I'm seeing incredible
recognizable brands and people that have
put out a lot of energy to to create a
brand that that people see and want to
have Steve and quani and you all have an
incredibly recognizable brand and I know
that it's the both of you and quani and
you're definitely a lot of the backbone
of this so I'd love for you all to talk
a little bit about how other companies
here in this room can put out a brand
that is really recognizable and that the
community is asking for its kind of its
kind of touches on which it caught me
off guard with earlier today but yeah
building a brand is extremely important
especially if you don't have a
storefront you gotta be able get your
product to market and if no one knows
you know my lavender versus you know Joe
blows lavender it's really hard for me
to to get in the store if they don't
want it so building a brand that people
can trust is been key for us so just to
give some an idea where we're at we were
in Nevada
we started off into that about five
years ago when this whole regulatory
system really kicked off and got really
stringent for us microbial testing was
what was just this this horrible thing
that no one could really get past it
even even the synthetic hydro guys are
having a hard time let alone indoor
no-till but again we stayed true to it
we adapted I think that's really
important in this industry right now is
just being have the ability to adapt to
some of these regulations and not being
so stuck in your ways but anyways so
yeah we we designed this trustworthy
brand we we're really able to connect
with the the local scene at a more
organic way versus trying to go big and
get billboards and TV ads and things
like that we would do simple things like
shirts and
that's in and something we did at the
beginning that was pretty cool that no
one really did was we would host little
gatherings like these at dispensaries
called know your farmer because a lot of
the people in Nevada in Las Vegas needed
education as to what cannabis was the
way we grow
so we these gatherings inviting the
community to these dispensaries and
teaching them about permaculture
teaching them our methods what we did to
be them pure clean green certified and
just growing clean cannabis was a key
thing to getting our brand out there and
just like still to this day I think 70%
of our consumers are still local so
getting the local communities involved
was a key thing to again dig our brand
out there and loyalty that I'm producing
a good crop you know a good crop with
good branding I heard someone say having
a good packaging is obviously key not to
to go there but yeah you really got to
address your product up to today's
market is extremely competitive but you
know also taking a consideration when
you're putting on the effort into
packaging make sure that you're also
still thinking more generally and how
can we minimal or keep our or our carbon
footprint and low as possible
at the same time make a statement but
yeah awesome and right now we we have
the the attention of more young people
that want to go into farming than ever
before all of a sudden now cannabis has
become this beautiful amazing catalyst
for young farmers to one out to want to
go out there and learn about planting
crops and and wanting to do it right
they know that there's problems within
the big AG model and they want to do it
correctly and you know there there's so
many problems and and hoops that we have
to jump through in order to become a
regulated cannabis seller but one thing
that we can do
when we first start our farms is we can
be producing food and there's a lot of
you here in this room that are producing
food and I know that that sometimes is
often the backbone of how we're able to
pay our mortgages and how we're able to
move you know paying for the paperwork
basically of becoming regulated in the
cannabis market so Daniel Stein I'd love
for you to talk for a minute about you
know producing food ok great
producing food on your farm that that
that's helping your family and not only
bring in fertility but it in the soil
but but fertility in your economics as
well yeah you know economically it was
it was kind of the opposite of what you
were just saying that the cannabis
supported getting our food farm and that
business model to a point where it was
actually a viable business I started
about 25 years ago food farming on a
little lettuce farm in Hawaii the same
lettuce farm that that Daniel of radical
herbs also farmed on a long time ago but
I was passionate about it and I loved it
but it didn't buy me any weed so I
started growing weed around the same
time and and noticed that that like
could supplement my income enough so
that I so that I could have that
lifestyle and now we've been doing a
commercial production food farm about an
hour west of here in braceland
for ten years and we started really
small with the space that we had doing a
lot of sprouts doing sunflower sprouts
and pea shoots and sauerkraut and things
like that that we could on a small scale
while also devoting the small amount of
area we had to to cannabis and and we've
expanded slowly trying to incorporate
what what we consider best practice is
the whole time and we've in the last
eight years we discovered no-till and
trying to implement a lot of these
regenerative practices on a production
scale of food far
and they're finding it the most
rewarding thing in the world like last
night I almost called Brassica in into
the circle there was a gentleman that
did and and every time we were talking
about potatoes which came up a lot I was
just like in the broccoli that goes on
top of them with some butter and cream
in because this time of year there's
like this is this testament to the soil
we've built and I've never seen anything
like it where the brassicas we grew up
in the summer when we were busy with our
kids and taking care of our house and
all this homestead stuff sat and start
trays in the in the greenhouse for such
a long time that they were almost dead
they looked all purple they were
nutrient deficient we put him in this
living soil out in the farm and and we
do about an acre of this kind of
production and we put him in and forgot
about them and then there was a drought
and I didn't have any water to water all
through the fall until it recently
rained and you know we have cauliflower
and broccoli heads that are the size of
my head and and cabbages and all this
food for us through the winter and we're
not doing it as much commercially
anymore but the the food and and the way
you get rewarded in the quality of your
cannabis from doing these practices is
the same for food so we have this market
we do two farmers markets and we feed a
lot of people that come to us first when
they come to the farmers market because
you can taste this quality you can taste
the medicine in food that's grown in
these systems and it's it's a natural
overlap and one of the challenges with
it right now in the California market is
I'd love to be selling cannabis to the
same people I'm selling food to because
they taste it they understand that and
then that naturally bridges across to
what's this other product you're growing
and how's that but we're working on
solutions for that do so by medicine
yeah so totally important I'm also Blair
oh Claire you all are also doing a lot
of secondary products as well as ethical
raising of livestock for meat and
vegetables would love to talk to you
about it too
hi everybody I'm Blair from radical
herbs and yeah totally
everything you said really resonates
about growing food and I think there's a
lot of farmers out there these days and
commodity farming and everything who
have to talk about having a second job
to fund their farm and I like to say we
get to farm to be able to farm and so I
think that's a beautiful gift that
cannabis has been able to give to us we
have a very diversified farm we raise
sheep cows chickens sheep for wool and
meat we have a variety of vegetables
that we grow and herbs as well we do our
little farmers market out in Koval oh
and sometimes we don't quite get there
right on time but we always have a line
at our booth and people are constantly
telling us that they're addicted to our
vegetables and I'm like me too so it's
people calling us when it's raining just
the other day because we didn't do
farmers market prepping for this and you
know just needing to get our their
vegetables that week so that's like such
a good feeling and I think that is in
cannabis we're disconnected in that way
with the way that the system is we're
not being able to be face to face with
the consumers and that I think that
there's a beautiful story to tell there
and a beautiful connection that in
contrast you can see like you know I
think we have a lot to gain and learn
from how just the organic vegetable
production is comparing you know
cage-free chickens versus pasture raised
chickens we have like amazing imagery
that we can use like you know sun-grown
versus indoor or like smart pots versus
in the ground like there's people see
that imagery I think it would easily
tell a story of like what we're doing
that's different and just like people
can taste that and what we're producing
they taste it in the vegetables and the
cannabis and the meat
a bunch of CSA stuff and that's sort of
a whole other commitment that you make
to your community in that could you tell
us about it yeah so you know I think one
of the things that's very important to
me in terms of this local food security
question is the fact that it inherently
builds community and so in this last few
years in this time of transition the
farmers market has been kind of one of
those anchor points for us we're like we
all get together and like sometimes
we're having the same conversation again
and again and it's did you hear what the
county did i Budda Budda Budda but it's
we're still coming together and you know
I think that for a lot of us cannabis
was the portal back to agriculture and
so as we walk through that portal we see
that it becomes this ever-expanding
bounty and you know farming is a huge
amount of work and Edie
you know Daniel Taylor and us are you
know we've kind of in this funny
mirror-image northern Mendo southern
humble and seeing you know you get to a
certain point and you see the holy shit
this is working and so we just you know
for instance we just got a plow and
rotary plow that I'm using to put in
swales and I'm gathering up seeds from
all over the garden it's like oh good I
can gather up two dozen three dozen four
dozen different species and put them in
the in the swales and so you see
biodiversity becomes self-replicating
and I think that those types of systems
create foundations on the farm for
diversity in crops and diversity in
value-added products and then from that
foundation how do you get it to the
consumer and so the CSA model has always
appealed to me a lot because there's no
choice involved it's whatever I
harvested that day that's what goes in
the CSA and so and and it can be
difficult from the consumer perspective
cuz it's exactly that you don't get a
choice so if you don't like eggplants
and I put eggplants in three weeks in a
row so but one of the things that I
really become fascinated by is this idea
of institutional CSA purchases and
weights working with a canvas company or
a hospital or a school district or you
know any place in which employees come
to every day if part of the employee
benefit or wellness program is a csa
purchase then it takes out that you know
for the for the average consumer buying
a csa you're always stacking up the
valuation of I paid twenty bucks for
this and I don't like eggplant so maybe
it's not so good for me but if it's part
of your employee benefit program then
you essentially don't have that
valuation and you say to yourself well
either I'm gonna eat it or not but I'm
gonna try to figure it out and and this
bag comes every week from the farmers
perspective I take all the stuff and I
drop it off I don't have to do
distribution I don't have to do billing
all I have to do is provide it and
that's a significant and packaging into
something that people can take home and
so that changes the dynamic dramatically
in terms of from my farm having to do a
bunch of individual accounts and
individual interactions and you know Bob
didn't make it to the farmers market
because he was busy bob went to work on
Friday and so when the thing was at work
when he left work on Friday then he can
take it home and so you know the CSA
model in terms of looking at systems
thinking how do we fit into this modern
bifurcated convenience driven society
with the types of products that we
produce and so that's something that is
to me very important and when you look
at value adds like right now in the in
the winter local the local food system
in the winter there's it's wide open
like there's not enough production and
there's all kind of value adds that can
be sold and so for instance like we do
salty Susie seasoning salts and we bag
up you know we dry out herbs all season
and then we mix them with salt and and
sell them in the winter and so there's
you know there's all kind of little
niche you know we used to do salad like
Dana said sauerkraut at market is
phenomenal and so essentially just
figuring out like these are the things
that I want to do for myself that I like
to consume
I bet other people would like to also
talking about all of these value-added
products is and and and the thread that
we have between all of our value-added
products and in something that we're
going to wrap up this session with and
and go to lunch is Holly you you you
were talking to me and I know a lot of
the work that you have and putting
forward is how do we achieve a higher
value-added product
by utilizing this stream of ethics that
we call regenerative at this time put it
on our packaging or how can we better
highlight that to help us out in in
gaining better revenue streams certainly
the certification your certification the
jump your certification mark the Sun in
earth mark these certification works
that are able to get out to a broader
audience helps to inform the consumer
however I think that Appalachians are
going to provide a broader framework for
the world helping to identify cannabis
that is produced in alignment with the
environment and at the same time to
protect our practices is this that
should I talk about Appalachians now is
that tomorrow okay so I I really believe
that Appalachians are going to be a the
bus framework for putting the
certifications and putting the farms
together in greening recognition very
easily for the consumer very easily at
the retail space I am sorry my expertise
is not in economics so I don't think I
have a lot to say about this other than
I think Appalachians are going to be a
very good tool for everybody consumer
and producer in to help us to elevate
the value of the primary and secondary
products we see it and with other
agricultural products that are produced
even in Appalachians even if they're not
produced by those methods but earn the
appellation so excellent thank you all
so much we're gonna wrap up this first
session here
amazing so much information