so I've got two panelists here who are
former colleagues of mine from the
marijuana policy
project uh starting with Aaron Smith the
executive director of the national
cannabis industry
Association Ain and I used to work
together at MPP he was the director of
our California policy and now he is very
busy um spearheading the uh organization
of the Cannabis industry at
ncia we've got Neil LaVine also a former
colleague we worked together on our
Arizona legalization campaign back when
we were just getting it off the ground
in 2014 Neil was our director of
initiative campaigns um a a major
Politico over here and now he's the
senior vice president of government
Affairs for Live Well last panelist here
is Adam Cohen with M hardine Adam is
both a dispensary owner as well as uh
one of the leaders of M hardine which is
a turnkey cultivation management company
in the industry so I'm going to pass
over to you all to fill in any blanks
I've left and then we'll get started
thanks Sarah um again I'm aarin Smith
co-founder executive director of the
national cannabis industry Association
uh we are uh just as any other industry
uh has we are the trade Association that
represents your business interests in
Washington DC uh we represent just about
1100 member businesses across the
country uh including uh about 300 last I
checked here in California uh we also
maintain a California affiliate
California Cannabis industry Association
that I hope uh all of you are involved
in as members as well um and I'm really
glad to be on this panel about the
federal conflict because the really
primary purpose of ncia is to make sure
that the industry has a seat at the
table in Washington DC to ultimately uh
take down the the barriers that that
Federal conflict poses to our businesses
uh and while we're not seeing uh those
of you who've been involved especially
in California for a long time may
remember the days where we were seeing
you know criminal uh justice actions
taken against medical cannabis
collectives throughout the state and the
the country on a regular basis while
fortunately that has has slowed way way
down uh there's other issues that uh in
some ways are more Insidious uh to to to
undermining the industry because of the
federal conflict primarily uh section
280e of the tax code uh which is a
little little known know to to most
people in this country but hopefully
very well known to those in this room uh
disallows any ordinary business
deductions Associated uh with the
trafficking quote unquote of cannabis
meaning your rents your marketing
payroll uh many of the the ordinary
expenses that any other business can
take for take for granted as an expense
uh can't in our industry and that has
many of our members facing 80 to even
90% effective tax rat rates as opposed
to 35% or so that that other comparable
businesses would face um the other big
issue that we're working on is resolving
the banking crisis so that businesses
can safely deposit their cash into uh a
depository institution into a bank not
have to run on a full you know some
operations are running entirely cash
only basis which is a public safety
nightmare uh and very costly to anybody
uh in the industry um we maintain a
full-time uh lobbying presence on the
hill working on these issues as well as
really the end goal which is ending
Federal prohibition removing cannabis
from the list of Controlled Substances
entirely and allowing states to regulate
in a model uh similar to
alcohol thanks Aaron Neil hi I'm Neil
living with live well in light and
health um Sarah and Aaron covered just
about everything so I'll be incredibly
brief because I would like to get to
some Q&amp;A and like to wrap up in time for
us all to watch the debate so uh I'll
just say this two two additions to what
Sarah said um live enlightened Health we
are a fully vertically integrated um uh
cannabis business uh right now we're
only in the state of Colorado we have 14
retail locations uh all on the east side
of the mountains and I am also a member
of the ncia board and agree with
everything anything that Aaron just
said Thank you Neil
Adam good afternoon my name is Adam
Cohen I'm one of the co-founders of m
hardine we are a turnkey commercial
cultivation company providing a range of
services to our clients including lenser
Support Facility design ramp up and then
the day-to-day operation of our client
facilities we also maintain our own
licenses in businesses and we provide
the same service for ourselves of course
we have clients in 10 states we've
produced over 130,000 pounds of finished
product to date uh we've been uh very
successful in uh thank you in uh working
with our clients in the uh competitive
application markets like Hawaii and
Maryland Etc uh Florida's another one in
addition to M hardine uh we also as
indicated we own our own cultivation
facilities and our own dispensaries sort
of in the family between all the
partners of M hardine
while we have 16 dispensaries operating
under four different brands in two
different
states uh now I I got into the industry
about four years ago I'm a lawyer by
trade a recovering attorney and I I came
by way of private equity and I was uh
doing investment both private and
institutional money and Luxury Resorts
and hotels around the Caribbean and
Latin America so you can imagine I
actually love that so I found this
opportunity to be so compelling the
first time I ever walked into a large
scale grow it was just a eureca moment
for me and I knew that uh and after
doing research I realized this is a
multi-billion dollar industry clear
clear macr Trends towards legalization
and acceptance and yet not a dollar of
institutional capital and why is that
well it's because of the conflict with
federal law and so for the last four
years I've been trying to navigate that
process um thankfully I'm still free uh
I have fewer concerns today about my
door getting kicked in but that was that
was always a concern and it still is for
for many people things are getting
better but we have a a very far way to
go
still that's great thank you Adam um my
name is Sarah hollyhead I'm a fundraiser
with the marijuana policy project I've
been with the organization since 2006
before there was much of an industry to
speak of so I've seen a lot of change in
the past 2 years I've been primarily
focused on raising money for our Arizona
legalization campaign and that's been
really fun for me the industry there is
pretty mature and um very actively
engaged in ending
prohibition so Aaron touched on these
the three biggest issues uh Federal
issues are 280e the tax issue banking
and I have donors all the time tell me
their check is going to be delayed
because their account got shut down so I
know it's real um and then the
Controlled Substances Act the need to
remove marijuana from it so I wonder if
one of you could jump in with which of
these you think is most pressing where
we're at on the issue and where we're
headed they're all pressing but
280e is uh our largest concern for sure
um
um the the history of how this all came
about um is that a lot of people don't
know and I actually wrote something
about this last week um that the United
States Supreme Court ruled that the
marijuana Tax Act of 1937 was
unconstitutional back in
1969 which led to the creation of the
Controlled Substances Act which was a
more constitutionally defensible
prohibition scheme than the one that
existed
the problem is that uh it was placed
into schedule one upon the creation by
the Nixon Administration temporarily
while they formed their handpick
commission uh to justify the science
behind making marijuana schedule one
controlled
substance the commission uh now referred
to as the Schaefer commission came back
and said marijuana should be
decriminalized but I guess at that point
uh the Nixon Administration did no
longer felt the need for scientific
justification and marijuana remains
skill one where it is to this day the
second thing that happened was in the'
70s an industrious drug dealer from
Minneapolis um uh took a bunch of
deductions for his business selling
cocaine and marijuana and he went to Tax
Court and successfully defended a
portion of those deductions so the
Congress responded with tax code IRS
code 280e in 1982 which said that you
cannot take standard deductions if you
are violating state or federal law in a
schedule one marijuana or schedule 2
cocaine controlled substance now we go
fast forward to 1996 where California
becomes the first state to opt out a
federal prohibition on the state level
in anyway uh under prop
215 and President Clinton who was just
reelected and wasn't going to face
another election asked Barry mcaffrey
his drugar the head of the ondcp to
craft a strategy to crush the new laws
and in that memo from December 20th 1996
the ondcp specifically all the stuff
that we saw happen for the last 20 years
are in that memo the raids everything
and they they spell out using 280e as a
weapon to crush the industry in the
Cradle so when you take a look at this
historically marijuana never should have
been the controlled substance act to
begin with that's number one and this is
on purpose it's not like the IRS
stumbled upon this code uh that was
there from 1982 and they're using it as
a weapon this was weaponized by the
Clinton Administration in
1996 as a as a Lynch pin in modern
Federal prohibition so what we need to
do is marijuana needs to be removed from
the control substance act entirely which
will take care of banking which will
take care of 28e in the interim uh we
we've heard from a lot of folks Ethan
was just here on this stage
uh I keep hearing from my friends in the
Cannabis legalization movement that a
lot of the philanthropists that have
historically funded the movement are
pulling back they're pulling they're
giving back so they're looking to us in
the industry to fill that Gap but we're
being kept small and poor on purpose
dealing with an effective tax rate of
upwards of 80% because we can't take any
standard business deductions based on
tax code
280e so this is it this is the Lynch pin
to to prohibition remove marijuana from
the controlled substance act entirely
like tobacco like alcohol where it was
never meant to be get rid of 280e and
then yeah we can end prohibition once
and for
all thank you
Neil I I want to shift and ask H how
does some of this tie into to what's
happening at the state level like like
what are we seeing happening at the
state level that could positively or
negatively impact these issues
well you know obviously we have a huge
election coming up on November 8th uh
that will has the potential if we
succeed in California and at least a
majority of the eight other states to
really reshape the debate around
marijuana um it's absolutely vital that
uh as an industry that we're supporting
those efforts at the state level because
uh there's a direct correlation between
the state policies and what's happening
in Congress you know members of Congress
are very timid they're they're already
probably 20 30 years behind public
opinion on this issue as it is uh they
tend to only really care about what's
happening in their districts and their
backyard and if you look at you know if
you look at this election you know right
now we have less than two dozen just
over 20 I think members of the House of
Representatives that represent the four
adult youth States uh and after if if we
pass all five this year this be what
over 100 that will be representing
states where marijuana is legal and
regulated uh not to mention uh 34 or so
of the house and a majority of the
Senate representing states that have
some form of regulated uh marijuana that
departs from federal law meaning medical
Canabis um so I think that that uh you
know we're already seeing the issue
being taken more and more seriously
after uh you know amendment 64 and i502
passed uh in 2012 uh we're going to see
another big flood of of interest uh in
this issue and resolving the federal
conflict uh because you know if you
think about like California here alone
in by 2020 if uh given passage of 64 uh
in November the the market here alone
could be upwards of $7 billion like the
size of the whole the whole country
right now and if we don't fix things
like Banking 28e and the bank banking
issue specifically is one that is very
uh kind of pressing for our opponents
and those who maybe don't really care
about whether our businesses succeed but
they want to resolve that because that's
$7 billion that's outside of the banking
system and and creating Public Safety
hazards and transparency issues so uh
that that alone I think is you know one
of the biggest things that we you know
and clearly is pressing because I think
that that's I think it's six weeks away
from tomorrow that we have uh this
election before us and um it's also
really critical that as industries
develop in new states that that the
industry be involved not not just
involved through the association of
course but involved in in local politics
involved with with their members of
Congress and meet you know meeting with
their members of Congress in the
districts attending fundraisers giving
money uh I know you know I know that
we're all asking for money but those
members of Congress who support our
issues deserve your support and as the
more States flip there will be more uh
you know what ncia is you know what we
do is we work to build coalitions and
move move the members of Congress kind
of along the ladder so you know the the
moderate opponents are now you'll now
seeing them come on board as you know
championing uh things like CBD access
and those are laws that we probably you
know largely ineffectual CBD laws but
they're pushing something those that
were just for medical are now moving
along and and supporting just a full
states rights approach to adult adult
use and we'll just I think we're going
to see that that uh
exponentially uh that pace increase
after November if if we're successful
and that's that's uh what's absolutely
important that we all know that this is
not inevitable because if the opposite
happens and California loses or a
majority of the other states uh go down
the narrative will change and especially
with California the headline will will
say you know public not ready for
marijuana legalization so get out and
vote and donate
money can thank you can I jump in real
quick uh one real world application on
the state level to Federal prohibition I
think is really uh and this I'm talking
about impact on people I see my friend
Sue sisly sitting in the front right
here
so a bunch of you probably know that
Congress through the appropriation
process was going to allow veterans to
go to the VA in states that have medical
marijuana laws and not be subject to
sanction for getting their medicine and
actually being transparent open and
working with the VA and that was killed
so because of the federal conflict
veterans with with conditions protected
under state law who are going through
the VA or are worried about the
retirement cannot go into medical
marijuana systems in Colorado uh where I
live PTSD Is Not An approved condition
it looks like the legislature is going
to move on that finally in 2017 knock on
wood hopefully but that's a real impact
and then when you get down into Aaron's
100% right on the policy impacts but the
real life impacts down the state level
with Federal prohibition it's just when
it when when when they get so toned deaf
that they're putting our veterans
retirement at risk and their health at
risk how can you not be disgusted with
the state of federal Prohibition in in
its
entirety and Adam I want to and and if I
may it's not just the veterans it's the
youth it's every everyone this we're not
creating a new market here this product
exists what we're doing is providing an
opportunity to test it regulate it and
tax it it's time for the federal
government to get its head out of its
ass and deal with this the right way we
and the public policy around the banking
in particular is just terrible I mean we
live in a different world financially
post 911 and the government strives for
transparency and accountability and yes
they yet they want to force this
multi-billion Dollar Cash Underground
Market which sets sets us up for all
kinds of problems from tax evasion money
laundering theft physical insecurity for
people who are transferring uh money
from one location to another it's just
terrible public
policy speaking of real world impacts
Adam I mean I want I'm interested in
knowing in your business dealings with
clients um how are they impacted by
Federal prohibition and how what steps
are you able to take to try to lessen
the risk lessen the impact on them are
you asking specifically like my clients
or my investors and the people I work
with yeah your investors any any of the
folks that you deal with through M
hardine or through any of your business
entities you know originally the way
that we structured the company now mind
you this is going back several years so
things were even more challenging
imagine trying to ask somebody to write
aill million dollar check for a
federally illegal business everyone's
very interested in the industry we hear
that we feel it every day but when push
comes to shove to write that check I
can't tell you how many calls I've had
you know the day of a closing where my
wife's not comfortable with this my
lawyer advised me not to do this so you
you really need to structure in a way
that protects your investors the way we
did that is we formed a separate um
intellectual property holding company
that would never touch the plant it
simply licensed the IP to the operating
company and kept a degree of separation
but it's it's not bulletproof um but
that's that's one thing that we've done
okay um so I'm curious what can can one
of you or several of you paint the
picture for me what does the end of
federal prohibition look like where are
we headed ideally and maybe actually
after the big
party yes
um well you know there's this is
actually a very important question we
could have several panel discussions on
this alone because there are a lot of
different I think there's eight
different legalization bills right now
pending in Congress um ranging from just
pure states rights where remove uh like
the Sanders bill and the Senate remove
cannabis from the CSA and just defer to
the states uh to a more uh alcohol
related model that has a federal excise
tax but still uh puts
marijuana uh regulation primarily under
the purview of the states and then
there's also move to to reschedule uh
marijuana rather than deschedule it and
put it in a two or three uh category and
and so in my in you know from an
industry perspective probably the worst
thing we could do is
rescheduling uh because that would
essentially create a whole you know
create a whole new Juris ition that
we're dealing with the FDA uh that you
know you're not going to get clinical
trials of you know raw cannabis strains
approved through the FDA and and even if
you did that those would only be
dispensed through pharmacies and pretty
much everybody in this in this room is
no longer in business except maybe a few
uh possibly that that might be able to
to navigate that um so what we what we
want to see is cannabis to be treated
more similarly to alcohol uh not not
under the purview of the FDA under the
purview of ATF ATF NC um that would also
allow still defer to the states uh so
that states can continue to experiment
with different regulatory models and uh
you know so that we can continue to have
this laboratory of democracy and and
frankly I think that's more
politically winnable uh than because it
would still allow states that are really
really backwards to maybe just have IAL
marijuana for a few more years and we're
not so as far as when it goes to you
know like I said most members of
Congress care about their district and
what's happening in their state so we
can go to somebody who represents you
know North Carolina and say well
actually this doesn't affect you until
your state legislature you know makes
makes a change um so there's a lot
there's also I think something that we
need to be really concerned about is
there are growing uh influencers in the
space that are starting to acknowledge
that you know marijuana prohibition
isn't working or maybe they're just
acknowledging that it's on its way out
anyway and that legalization is
inevitable and they are proposing models
that would not be good for the the
Cannabis industry and that would not be
good with P for patients or consumers
models like state run stores where
government employees would be tasked
with with selling marijuana and
marijuana users would have to get onto a
registry uh to in order to access sort
of like the uh the heroin model in the
UK um and those those forces are out
there uh one you know one of them is you
know botch is uh uh you know hired by
some of the State uh regul Regulators
throughout the country is pushing that
model uh and as this you know as this
issue heats up uh our our voice will be
Amplified but so will theirs and we
really as an industry need to unify to
make sure that that's not the direction
that we take that that that we take
reform because uh they're they're they
do have a seat at the table as it is and
it will uh they will continue to gain
influence yeah Erin um just piggybacking
on that I have been hearing more and
more about companies offering compliance
related solutions for the Cannabis
industry that um they feel have a strong
foothold in the marketplace because the
government is looking for all these um
trans parency mechanisms to make sure
that the Cannabis industry is compliant
and um but some of the ones I've heard
about so far are really scary sounding
and and along the lines of what you were
just talking about like um causing every
Canabis consumer at a dispensary to have
to show their driver's license and every
every transaction would therefore be
recorded um is that the direction that
we're headed in a complete lack of
privacy for all can abis
consumers well I I don't think that
that's necessary um I think I think what
you're getting at with some of the
compliance solutions that are that
you're seeing out there and not to talk
about any companies and specifically um
they're providing solutions for banks
because the banks are now under
direction from you know under the the
guidance from finsen in the Department
of Treasury and Department of Justice uh
they have guidance that basically says
you know what you can do business with
state legal into uh marijuana businesses
but oversight of the compliance their
compliance and their legality under
state law is your responsibility to
track that so of course banks are
extremely conservative institutions and
I don't think they should be put in that
position when you have a state license
hanging on the wall and regular state
inspections and such but that's the
current the current state and so some of
these Solutions are there to so that the
banks can have that level of comfort to
fill the Gap to fill the Gap so once we
address the banking issue we can kind of
do away with those concerns it sounds
like right okay it looks like you had
yeah I think it all it all runs together
right it and as these gentleman
indicated rescheduling is not a good
option and frankly I'm glad that the DEA
declined to do that in this this summer
because they think that the best they
would have done was to make it a a
schedule two and that would have done no
one any favor it just sort of
complicated the matter uh it needs to be
three or lower or completely removed
which is the most apprpriate and once
you do that you solve the banking almost
automatically I believe uh you'll start
to see institutional Capital come into
the industry in very significant ways uh
280e goes away we start to normalize so
this is really the Crux of the issue it
needs to be
descheduled so if you want to ask a
question please come up here to the
front corner where Susan is
standing okay so the question was
basically why are we talking about
regulating cannabis like alcohol rather
than like a medication that's not really
a federal question unfortunately because
we're not necessarily proposing um
Federal Regulations like alcohol like I
guess alcohol is regulated by the ATF
but not as granularly as it is at the
state level is that right right and I
and and you know a lot of it is about
like okay there what models already
exist what's politically possible and in
my mind what's it's it's going to be
much harder to create some you know
third regulatory regime that's that that
has never been invented before and get
that through Congress so it's really FDA
the pharmaceutical you know that
direction or something more similar to
alcohol and and I think that you know
that what's best for the industry is to
not try to shove this down into the
because this is also not a dangerous
pharmaceutical it shouldn't be treated
like oxycotton or or any you know it's
it's safer it's a safer substance than
most over-the-counter drugs for that
matter but but those are State she's
saying every city in the US has Public
Health departments again that's state
level and we're we're really talking
about Federal level policy here this
this should be taken out of the hands of
the federal government altogether the
best model that I've seen is just to
Simply create a safe Harbor for the
states that choose to regulate it allow
the states to do what they want to do
with it and a number of things are
accomplished there and one of the things
that we'll see now in a number of these
states they have very well developed
programs that are creating a lot of jobs
and a lot of tax revenue Colorado last
year generated twice the amount of tax
revenue for marijuana that they did for
alcohol $1 billion of direct marijuana
purchases last year Colorado is not just
going to fold that up they're going to
protect that system and all the states
presumably many of the states will want
to do the same thing the federal
government simply needs to back off and
allow the states to regulate it yeah
money makes the world go around it's an
incentive to to the point on the federal
level you know we do want it to be like
alcohol and that we want it removed from
the CSA entirely right and you know the
the we don't want to be in the FDA
system the FDA system if we go into re
open up research what does that actually
mean that means spend tens of millions
of dollars
to find something that you can replicate
that then gets rescheduled like Marinol
into schedule 3 I mean is that what we
want for whole plant marijuana I mean
the FDA system is not now can can
pharmaceutical companies derrive
cannabis-based medicine through the FDA
system that gets prescribed yes
absolutely but to take marijuana and put
it schedule two or even schedule three
and put it into the FDA system is not
where the plan is supposed to be in our
opinion it should be removed from the
CSA entirely though there is a role for
the FDA certainly when it comes to Pure
Pharma and the development of drugs that
are designed to uh address very specific
ailments and you want to go through the
clinical trials and the fa approval
process for that so I really see two
Divergent paths one being a pure Pharma
play and the other being everything else
the neutraceuticals the adult use soft
medical Etc right okay any other
questions from the audience please come
up here to Susan so you can use this the
the microphone thanks a lot uh really
appreciate your Insight um the question
I have is how do you as two physical
retailers feel about delivery and what
do you see as the future of kind of
delivery in Colorado or the other states
that you operate
in we both want to jump on that one
um that's interesting um you know as a
general policy as a company um we tend
to be pretty I think everybody in the
industry tends to be pretty adaptable
when it comes to local regulations right
so you know when it comes to to to
something like delivery that that's very
much a local issue as far as the history
uh delivery in Colorado I I I don't hear
anything about allowing delivery in
Colorado anytime soon and you know if we
were in a jurisdiction that allowed
delivery maybe we'd consider it we're
not so we haven't had that internal
discussion I don't know there there are
there there are bright obviously
delivery especially when you're dealing
with patients that could be a huge
benefit um the the the I I think that uh
as far as we're concerned um we there
there are certain things that we are
really really concerned about right we
are concerned about 280e we are
concerned about banking other stuff
where it's you know we're pretty
malleable with if the businesses in this
industry are pretty they're as tough and
as Hardy as the plan right so um when it
comes to local stuff like that we can
kind kind of go with the roll with the
punches uh but uh we haven't had to deal
with it we're only in Colorado so as a
company we don't even have a position on
that Nevada allows for delivery uh I I
look at it honestly as more of
a pain than anything good from from an
economic standpoint as the business
owner certainly you're providing a
valuable service for people who are
Indigent or somehow inconvenience or
simply can't go to a location to to buy
the product so there's certainly some
Public Service benefit to that but as a
business owner it's certainly not a um a
Big Driver of the business I'd like to
see drive-throughs I think that could be
interesting and social use clubs those
are those would be more important to me
than than focused on
delivery okay other questions can you go
back to your banking system with regards
to uh federal law uh you had basically
said that it's there's no federal
prohibition but the burden is so great
uh that banks are choosing not to can
you speak more to
that well there is federal prohibition
but there's there's guidance that was uh
released in 2014 by Department of
Treasury and Department of Justice
jointly that essentially outlined the
priorities of Jus of the justice
department in their enforcement against
state legal businesses which to be clear
all of them no matter how compliant they
are are committing felonies every time
they open their door uh but but the
Obama administrations you know had their
guidelines which were things that I
think everybody here can agree on no
diversion out of state no ties to you
know violent criminal Enterprises no
sales to miners uh ensuring you know
100% compliance with with all the state
guidelines and so but they they left
that burden to the banks at least the
way that it's been interpreted it was
it's sort of it's sort of vague actually
but the way that it's been interpreted
pretty much univ un Al is that it's up
to the banks to know their customer and
ensure that all of these guidelines are
being met so therefore a bank wouldn't
want to take a very conservative one
would would be would not want to take
the client uh unless they knew 100% that
client wasn't selling to miners so how
how does a bank do that without being in
the in the store um the way that you
know what we asked for you know that was
a step forward when we got that guidance
but it was a compromise to what we were
asking for which was that if a if a a
client could walk into a bank and
present a valid you know all of the
paperwork that they to show that they
have a license in their state and in
their local jurisdiction then the bank
would would treat them like any other
business but this again uh politics is
often about compromises and that's what
we got um there's other you know the
real solution is to carve out in the
statute uh Safe Harbor to banks that do
business with uh any state legal
marijuana operation and that would be an
amendment to the the bank secrecy act
and there's there's legislation pending
right now to do to do just that uh so
the guidance is really a Band-Aid and
then all of the other compliant software
and things that um that have kind of
popped up for banks to use or or part of
that
Band-Aid interestingly enough um I'm
we're fortunate all of our companies
including our dispensaries are fully
banked and we have open transparent and
good relationships with all of our banks
they know exactly what we do uh we have
audited financials for all of our
companies and we've been doing this for
a few years now and yet on the personal
side I bank with a big national bank and
they shut down all my accounts last week
so it's it's still I mean it's this is a
real issue it's not going away MPP also
has difficulty getting banking services
and we don't do anything illegal so it's
frustrating and we have banking too but
when we say banking there a huge we have
banking right we have check deposit
services that we pay in a norm amount of
money for we don't have commercial
banking services we can't get a loan you
know there there's so so we don't have
banking but yes some of the folks that
are able to establish a relationship
with their Banks and show that this is
who we are and we can be transparent
that yes we have access to banking
services but it's always a struggle and
then and and stuff always gets ripped
out and you'll have a you'll have a
vendor that's dealing with you that all
of a sudden will randomly call and say
we can't deal with you anymore cuz we
got shut down over here if we're dealing
with you um and so and personal banking
accounts being pulled and on and on and
on and on losing Payroll Services
Etc hi Jon Irvine um I was involved in
policy and child protection in the adult
entertainment industry and talking about
an industry that was legal and still
could not get banking accounts it was
make me you know five or six Banks
across the country that could you know
would work with them and then they they
would disappear and even as a Child
Protection Association in a 501c3 and
four they questioned our banking account
so even with it becoming legalized don't
you think that there's still going to be
that same issue and what can really be
done around that cuz we were you no when
I was in that industry it was not
something that was really being handled
very
well we could
remove we could remove cannabis from the
CSA entirely that could be that's what
could be done that's the
idea like Adam said this is all
related this is all related this all
part of the federal prohibition
scheme and there's one thing that you
can all do about this go
vote go vote and we continue to fight
the good fight we have made a tremendous
amount of progress over the last few
years I've seen a sea change from when I
got involved in the industry hopefully
we're at that Tipping Point Point uh but
as Aaron indicated it could go either
way if um a number or a majority or God
willing all of these referend to pass
this year there's no turning back if on
the other hand we have a setback and few
or none of these initiatives pass we we
set back quite a few
years the other thing you do is you can
uh contact your congressman and you can
contact your Senator um in Congressional
offices they have the 100 to1 rule for
every contact they receive they figure
it represents 100 people so contact your
congressmen if they contact if they are
good on this issue thank them if they're
not ask them why put on social whatever
they put you as put as a response either
praising them or shaming them this is
this has got to get done through the US
Congress the the good thing is I don't
think there's much to be gained
politically for most at the state or
federal level to be fighting cannabis as
much as they once were at least we're
talking about it now four or five years
ago there's very little discussion in
the halls of Congress about changing the
laws around cannabis although
unfortunately in two of our initiative
States it's the governor who's actually
spearheading the opposition effort
that's in Massachusetts and Arizona and
Neil was just telling me about Harry
Reid in Nevada coming out against our
initiative so unfortunately these folks
do still need to hear from their
constituents and hear that indeed they
are they're hardworking business people
they support a better approach to to how
we regulate
marijuana and for the record the the
governor the AG the mayor of Boston they
all came out against us in 2008 for DM
in Massachusetts and we got 63% of the
votes so awes more than Obama got you
know at at some 65% of the vote in
Massachusetts actually so you know at
some point you know the endorsement game
people I think are seeing through this
for what it is right especially when it
gets to those folks I think think you
know it's it's dog bites man for the
governor to say that they're against
legalizing marijuana right um but the
news is really the other way and that's
even getting less and less um but it's a
really good point though is that we have
this stubborn
misperception that the people are not
where they are and the politicians are
behind the people and that's the key
Point here and so you know we wouldn't
be where we are if it wasn't for direct
democracy and unfortunately at the state
level it's taken us almost as far as we
can go the California initiative is
enormous and it has to pass this
November but we are now positioning
ourselves we have to affect change on
the federal level it takes a lot of work
to unwind 70 years of
misinformation and and also add like
it's we've made a lot of progress if you
you know when we count noses in you know
in Congress like counting votes I I'm
pretty confident we have the votes for a
medical marijuana
law already as it stands I we've seen
rakar pass on you know more than one
year running um we we're only maybe half
a dozen votes away in the house from
some form of States you know support for
some form of states rights around
marijuana entirely um and a lot of what
we're up against now are are just the
general dysfunction of Congress and that
you know if you've been paying any
attention you know Congress hasn't done
anything uh this entire you know their
entire two years the in this session so
next year we have a really good
opportunity given success on the ballot
in November uh given that we're going to
be in the first year of a new
Administration whichever Administration
that ends up being uh we have a huge
opportunity to just as long as we don't
screw this up I think that we can see uh
280e reform banking reform and
ultimately uh the end of federal
marijuana prohibition uh across the
country thanks Aaron
so on the federal question on the on the
presidential election coming up um I've
heard a lot of people say that the Trump
and Clinton are very similar candidates
in terms of their stance on marijuana
which is essentially let the states kind
of do their thing but there is one area
where they differ significantly and that
is in who they plan to pick for AG
attorney general can you all speak to
what impact that may or may not have on
marijuana policy going forward I don't
think the candidates are the same
Hillary has come out and said that she
will pursue um rescheduling probably not
nearly as aggressively as we might like
to see but worst case we're going to
have status quo I can live with that
Trump's Wild Card nobody knows what he's
going to do or who he's going to appoint
I heard him give a speech in the last
week talking about the great scourge of
drugs on our nation's youth it's the
same old shit we've been hearing ing for
my entire lifetime so I I think that
that is uh the riskier of the the two
options one man's opinion at the risk of
offending any Republican friends in the
audience um I refuse to acknowledge
Trump as a normal candidate in any way
shape or form so you know he's running a
racist misogynistic campaign and he's
trying to bring fascism to America and I
reject him entirely so I won't I won't
even take the question there's no
there's nothing similar between them as
candidates yes thank
you um yeah he's he's just like such a a
wild card he has he has said some good
things on marijuana but he's also said
some really disastrous things he's too
too close to Chris Christie uh for me to
be comfortable with him uh so yeah
beware that's a danger right that he
points chrisy as AG yeah that's that's
what I'm really getting at the the
danger is we give them the nuke codes is
I'm sorry we give them the nuclear codes
that's the danger yeah to be honest I
don't know if if I you know how much
I'll be worried about marijuana uh in a
trump presidency given everything else
so but now I'm I'm steering away from
ncia scope I guess when I say that up
here you you may become a heavy
user well so in Arizona where I've been
doing a lot of work the Democratic party
is doing a lot of get out the vote work
right now because it's turning out to be
a swing state there are a lot of folks
in the state who are Republican but
there are also a lot who are very
dissatisfied with Trump as an option so
Hillary could end up saving the
marijuana vote in Arizona but this is a
real this is a very real question I mean
what what if the crazies get their way
and Trump H be gets elected um Chris
Christie has made it well known that he
is not um he doesn't see this issue the
way we do so that that's that's a real
concern
well regardless of who you want to vote
for president please go out and support
these referenda and the jurisdictions in
which you live and take your friends and
take your family this year is so
important for our
industry okay I have one last question
for you all um so I hate these
prognostication questions because they
assume some level of inevitability in
forward progress but I am going to ask
you to pregnant ostic a little bit um so
say we do pass one or more of our five
legalization initiatives in November so
those are California Arizona Nevada
Massachusetts and Maine so say
California passes who knows about the
others um all these municipalities in
California and and probably elsewhere
who raise as a as a reason for not
moving forward the federal conflict
excuse oh oh it's ferally illegal we
can't do anything because we would be
breaking federal
law what do we see happening you know
not just here in California but in
States like Louisiana who probably would
would throw out that excuse as a reason
for not passing better marijuana laws
what's
ahead well I mean we're always going to
hear that from some of the the you know
backwards jurisdictions and you know
places like California that's very
diverse you know you've got some parts
of the the state that are very red uh
and the answer is let's work on fixing
federal law and ending that conflict um
but also if you're working in those
jurisdictions you know what we what
we're seeing is and we've see in
Colorado Cal in California when you know
neighboring jurisdictions are regulating
cannabis cultivation and reaping the
sales ta or the tax benefits from that
uh and not seeing any increase in crime
the the usually their Neighbors start
coming around and and deciding that it's
time to to allow you know allow
cultivation or retail and so I think
that it's you know economically it makes
it just makes more sense uh for these
these uh jurisdictions to come on board
but I know that it's you know we've been
working on it here in California for 20
years now um but you know the answer is
yeah we got it that's another reason we
need to change federal law because a lot
of the local problems even if with you
know talking to your zoning commission
your your city council at the you know
very very local level are rooted in this
Federal conflict and that's why we we
can't lose sight of of the need to keep
pushing hard in
Congress this relates to your earlier
question actually right because
federally our entire industry is built
on a
memo and a restriction on da being able
to use funds to go after medical
providers so we need real change on the
federal level we've got to that point
Point if's Let's play that scenario out
and Chris Christie or whomever becomes
the AG and the head of
Justice uh the co memo is gone and that
Pro all that is a prosecutorial guidance
and it's over and now they're free to
begin the raids what does that look like
in Colorado where we have 29,000 badged
employees in the industry as of last
month what do you do what when when
you're going to go and start rounding
all the tens of thousands of people up
hundreds of thousands of people
throughout the country seizing all their
funds destroying those jobs crashing
local economies o o only after we're
done with the
immigrants the
wall so but no look that's that's a joke
but it's not a joke right that's that's
what we're dealing with today it's
insane so you know the the it it we need
real Federal reform and it really it all
comes down everyone you know everyone
says it's Pie in the Sky no there's no
appetite on the federal level right now
for real 280 reform there's no appetite
to remove marijuana from the control
Substances Act the very first political
campaign I was ever involved in with
Jesse vur for governor of Minnesota in
1998 there was no chance he could become
governor of Minnesota there was no
chance that rep that Donald Trump could
become the Republican nominee last year
there's no chance when in 2004 we went
to Vermont uh with Gary Johnson and the
governor of Vermont and the Speaker of
the House told us you will never ever
ever get a medical marijuana law passed
as long as we're in this position and
four months later we passed a medical
marijuana law that the governor let go
into law without his signature people
keep saying it's impossible you can't do
it you can't do it politically we have
to ask for what we need not what we
think we can
get and what we need is to remove
marijuana from the CSA
entirely and I guess that's where I was
headed with my question too is um state
level progress is crucial to to achieve
Federal level progress in fact that's
MP's whole strategy is to make progress
state by state by state and that builds
the support in Congress like Erin was
talking about earlier and that helps us
make that Federal level
change so I think I'm going to wrap it
up right there unless we have more
questions give you all a chance to hit
the bathroom before the debate question
oh one more
question just for you thanks so um would
an increase in state level product
liability lawsuits have an impact on the
fed's taste for
reform I'm not sure they're directly
connected to be honest with you as a
business owner I can tell you I worry
about that quite a bit uh but I'm not
sure that the state's seeing more
litigation around product safety or even
enhanced state regulations is going to
make a make too much of a
difference yeah I don't I don't think
that that's something that Congress is
is concerned about right now um I mean I
think what what what matters is that the
state regulations are effective and that
the the all of the the major actors in
the states are following the
regulations um and of you know sometimes
we get them obviously we get them wrong
sometimes and it takes you know time to
improve uh and work at the state level
but that isn't something that's that's
really being looked at uh that that you
know deeply as far as I can
tell