there's flavonoids and esters that don't
come over and have steam distillation
like flavonoids kind of get the short
stick talked about Maddie no it's
terpenes so give a plug to flavonoids
why do we care about flavonoids um they
there I'm not completely versed on their
medical benefits but they are heavier
molecules that add flavor to the profile
of cannabis mountains chirping Jets
Mallory terpenes deals specifically with
your olfactory senses where flavonoids
deal with your Thalia in their taste yes
and the molecule is way heavier on the
flavonoids so it's it it does not get
distilled out with yeah it's it's not
part of the distilled terpenes isn't
that part of a terpene blend same thing
with the esters as well and these are
things that that blend to the entire
smell profile we call it a terpene
profile but it's a it's a smell or it's
an experience profile yes yep and that's
ears yes and we don't know what happens
when you what kind of reactions happen
when you combust all those different 180
different compounds I know
[Laughter]
but yeah a medical level like there's
you know I don't circling this way back
this conference that we're doing is like
focused exactly on that there's a lot of
fiction out there a lot of people have a
lot of really good ideas about what
cannabinoids do what different compounds
what you know full-spectrum single eye
slits you know a lot of people have some
good ideas but there is not enough
science that are you know propping up
these ideas or smashing them to pieces
and so like that the conference we're
doing is is really focused on
people who are actually doing that
research and finding some answers can't
come out and you know talk and bring it
to the attention of the people that are
making the oil and and you know this in
the gray black and newly white market
and it's like there's a disconnection
between the cutting-edge research and
the people that are making the medicine
and once you start connecting those
people that is like I think that there's
a lot of great things can happen you go
back to like you know you want to make
the best product like find out what's in
what delivery method is best for you
know the doctors are doing research on
that cannabinoid or that group of
cannabinoids you know how that goes
intersection of your stomach your lungs
your but we've got a long way to go in
research and like connecting the people
that actually are passionate about about
it on the side of making the medicine is
really important with the people that
are actually researching and