[Music]
foreign
first time in L.A and we were like he
needs to experience the valley and uh
it's actually quite cool right now so
you're not experiencing Peak heat Valley
but uh
yeah no this is good so all right so we
have the flour mill sfv we have The Man
Behind The Flower Mill so you want to
give us uh some backstory on how this
all came about yeah well it's funny like
we were talking earlier it was 2019
canacon Detroit and I had met what are
who are now my partners that's
wow is that like a military uh age 47
twin rotors they used to uh they it was
an Army transport but now it's used for
putting out fires I used to work on
h-46s the C Knight which is a smaller
version
all right so so yeah it's 2019 I'm in
Detroit canacon I'm managing some grows
at the time and uh just kind of entering
into the Cannabis Market publicly and uh
I had met John and Aaron and Jason and
those are the actual guys that invented
it three Engineers that started off
making aftermarket automotive car parts
for Mazda Miatas and so they were
tinkering at the end after the work with
the machines they are okay
um not quite as heavy as maybe uh we are
but uh they definitely you know
appreciate the plant and you know
um well they're good great guys they're
engineers and so they tackled the issue
with the equipment that they had in the
back and it started off with a little
shark fin and that fin would just get
worn down all the way until it was
completely flat like this and it became
a Milling screen or a Milling plate like
I like to call it and that
is how we ended up with this
and as it went down we found that we
started off with just 10 flutes in our
rotor and now we have 20 because we were
getting pancakes so uh
you know we kept on designing and
Engineering it and at the time it was
Royal Health and the product was called
the crown and uh they had gotten two
prototypes out of 30. they had called me
back about a year later and said I don't
know if you'll remember me but we met
you at Detroit cannacon and I said it's
in my hand right now I've been waiting
for your call
flew out literally I think a week later
and made them a deal we became Partners
within about 10 days hiked Camelback
Mountain Barefoot together and the rest
is kind of History you know from then we
renamed it Flour Mill and worked on the
design and I kind of helped build the
company around a product and build a
brand within that and together we had
taken it to to this level and now we've
got five Partners total and it's me and
Q and Aaron and Jason and uh
that's
you know and John in Canada so we're all
over two guys in Arizona one in Canada
and in Detroit Chicago yeah
yeah without them none of this is
possible so I'm just the guy that gets
to do all the fun stuff out here and so
there are three sizes right so you wanna
there's actually two sizes we have the
mini Mill
which is pretty cool
so the magnets were a big part of it
we've got the standard size which is
another
version of the flower Mill that is all
built in and doesn't have any
interchangeable parts
except for this ring that you can put a
Keith catch into if you wanted to
this is the one that we like this is
personally what I use every day
most people really like the premium
version because you can customize it
and swap out these screens for different
sizes
and break it down any way that you want
while you're doing it for Backwoods or
for Vaping you might want to go a little
bit finer and some people some of the
professional rollers actually do a blend
of
two-thirds with a smaller one and one
third of the of the batch with a larger
one so that enables people to customize
it based on their cure based on what
they're going to be using the product
for does it have a smoother burn well
yeah it burns more evenly and
consistently and the difference is that
because of the way that it's being
processed you're no longer
grinding you're Milling so all the
trichomes and cannabinoids are still
stuck to the vegetable
so it it burns differently it lasts
longer
um it it gets you a little bit more
lifted and elevated because all the good
stuff is still attached to the
vegetables
um
completely breaks down so it's easy for
cleaning
I'm just the industrial design
the engineers those guys you know it's
just clean and tight yeah yep how did
you come up with the the actual part
that grinded what did you do the mill so
this is a rotor a rotor flutes yeah yeah
the flutes yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and
this was just uh that's a process yeah
that's it well it goes back to like
Milling food a Milling grains and and
all that stuff so this has been this
technology has been around a long time
we just haven't been applying it to the
to our industry yeah I recognize the
different size holes from meat grinders
yeah I've never seen a great Crossover
with food actually I don't mean to bring
up the word granny because this is a
meal
and uh for the patents we did get our
patent on this thing so that's why we've
been kind of quiet about coming out so
strong but you know now that we're
covered and protected because we know
this is probably the the way that you're
going to want to be processing your
cannabis personally uh going forward so
um
magnetic aspect is what separated us
from being able to get our patent when
we were denied and we had to appeal it
they were saying the pepper mill and a
lot of you're mentioning food and you
know kitchen utensils so this is really
close to a kitchen item and we had to
say well there's nothing quite like this
and so the magnets along with these is
really what enabled us to protect you
just holds it together right yeah
um so still that's really a cool part of
it the other thing is a quarter turn off
it's double threaded so look how quickly
you can separate the housing from the
base so most of them use 180 degrees and
you're spinning and spinning this is
double threaded so it's very easy to get
on and off that is something that I
think you just noticed after you start
using it for a while but it's it's meant
to be more efficient increase the
quality results the idea is to make a
more efficient process it's a lot faster
you can do 3.5 grams at one time and
probably less than five seconds so we
can do a demonstration like that and the
end result is lighter and fluffier and
it's easier to roll it's easier to
manipulate and play with but it's also
it comes alive which we can show on
video which is why this is so cool
because I'm doing this over the phone a
lot of the time or in places where I
can't do it with product and show you
and give you an actual demo and that's
where the magic happens so I think
equally as important you want to walk us
through the lineup of weed that you
brought yeah sure most important that's
one of the reasons we're here I guess
this is a Pillow Talk number one from
Tang Farms with Moscow seeds and
genetics and this is really very special
this is from afino hunt that we did down
in Oklahoma with Ben grieve and Aaron
and we are Partners in a new company
called analytics that smells unreal
photos yeah that it smells better than
anything else on the table at the moment
I'm not trying to insult anybody else's
bud so that's this is really nice which
we can sample a little bit later we have
uh the elevated genetics Tiki Tom
this is just another gray one
and these are the genetics that you know
there there are seeds
uh from Moscow usually
and then uh
there's this one some Raspberry Pi it's
not these are not my favorite sample
jars for this reason yeah but you can
get it raspberry pie is very good this
is actually one that
um is one of my personal favorites I
think this is this is going to be
absolutely phenomenal divulge the origin
of the genetics yes we do this is a
Moscow and tisky I actually sell a bunch
of their stuff right this one's Tiki
right or one of them is Tiki Moscow and
Tiki crosses yep
um what's the origin of tiki that's
another breeder he's another breeder out
of Michigan and mosque is out of Ohio so
those are Midwest so guys you're from
outside right yeah yeah yeah yeah
um so yeah uh then we got like some
Chris Moscow my other partner at Hill
Street genetics
um
and Hill Street companies this is the
Jamaican blue that I've smoked most
people down with but I've never sold any
of it so this is a really beautiful from
Lamb's bread from Jamaica from 40 years
ago we've brought up washed it back
cleaned it out and brought it back with
some there's some grape got in there
this is Superman ice cream so we've
created a new one that is just
phenomenal so that's a fun one maybe I
and I can smoke some yes yes we'll be
doing that and then we got some
strawberries you said that what you what
was the Rohan story
yeah well it was fun you know we heard
from Rohan and he had you know row had
contacted me and went down to Miami to
see him and we were able to actually
share the Jamaican blue and there were
some guys from Jamaica there and I think
Mike James is there and you you know
they're mentioning how you could taste
the tarwar and the and the red clay in
the soil which I thought was so cool you
know to to I've never been to Jamaica
and they said You're Nobody Until you
know in this industry until you've been
there so
um thank God I'm stampster damn and
Spain under my belt in the last couple
of months but I think Jamaica and all
these other places are next so it was
really cool to connect through the plant
um with that family and have such a
great experience with it so that was
pretty neat because of the and where we
connected uh with Lion order was really
on the fact that Jamaican blue coffee
you know the Jamaican Marley coffee they
they Mill it so their process for making
their coffee is very similar so we
connect it instantly on the flour mill
that's amazing and then genetics were
just a fun thing so we've actually taken
this Strawberry Cough
and mixed it with the Jamaican blue to
give Roe exactly what he was looking for
which is the blend of these two so
that'll be out soon
well that's up to him
[Laughter]
so we like to work with people like that
and you know there's a little bit of
spillover and other things but you know
well let's get to it all right
um but I thought you brought some
generous here too so yeah I I'm sorry
we're gonna smoke all this tomorrow so
I'm totally
all right to try what you brought with
you well here's some strawberry so this
is the difference I'm just going to lay
all these in here see that stem
yep we're gonna leave it there typically
you dick your hands and you'd mess it up
I'm gonna put uh
it doesn't get grounded in there does it
well it doesn't have to that's up to me
that's up to me I mean I don't think
they will use the word ground milled in
there
I gotta stop saying and ground don't
call it a grinder so look at those stems
are right there on top without the phone
oh my God then I didn't go all the way I
went most of the way then I just take my
finger take the stems out like that that
took like less than a half seconds oh
yes that's what I'm saying and that was
you know and then look at the end result
oh my God
there's the other stuff I have never
seen anything like this
burnt fewer calories yeah yeah
it is happier it's it's lighter fluffier
you can shape it you can see how it's a
little bit alive it looks perfectly
rolled down right now and what what
gradation of holes this one is our
standard and so we have all these
different ones and we can run some
through and change some different sizes
to to show you the difference and this
is just is this a standard no uh yeah it
is because that's the one that it comes
with naturally so when you change them
you unscrew the thing and then you put
the new one on yeah yep as of now we're
always looking to tweak things and make
it better
um all right you want me to roll one
that'd be great and then let's do the
Jamaican too just because this is we're
here together and you know um let me
just plug Cali High episode 61 it's
called Jamaica it's about the time I
went to Jamaica these so this these
genetics the the Lamb's Brad came from
Jamaica in 1980 one year before I was
born and these guys brought back that we
actually have the photos of the seeds in
the field on the mountain with the
plants and the whole thing and then it
was a couple guys working for the
military came back back and brought them
back and we've had them ever since so we
actually popped these seeds do we have
any filters here I have some in the
house I don't have any
let me run I'm a Midwest guy we smoke
like cigarette style joints with no
filters
um
since we've got a moment you know one of
the cool things about flour Mills that
we were able to approach people that I
don't think you otherwise would be able
to and we went with
um you know zigzag my father smoked
zigzag oranges my whole life so for me
they're iconic and legendary in their
own right my my childhood but uh to be
able to do a collaboration with zigzag
and have it be the first collab with
zigzag was really a beautiful thing this
is phenomenal so we made a new logo
together and this is a really cool thing
that you can see out they just got their
shipment so I know that they're selling
really well right now and then who else
were you excited to do a collaboration
with oh well of course future future
cannabis project this is one that you
can get to
yeah
tight and we just learned the Hawaiian
word for friend which is HOA
so we're all HOA here
let's do the blue
that was on the bottle cap
big a big way so again I want to put a
whole big Nug in there I'm trying to
keep that clean you know it's nice to
you see the stems there let's see what
we can do with this one
it's phenomenal here no not that one
that's strawberry soda right well you
want to do the Jamaican yeah well that's
okay
I don't mind yeah which one you want to
smoke first did you make it yes it's
very special this is something that I
want to experience with you guys
together
here let's make this easier on you
so normally we have Otis here who's like
the house professional roller and uh
it's nice to just have him yeah yeah
yeah do all the rolling our rollers will
be in town tomorrow you know we're um
set up for hollow flowers so we'll have
Hapa and Bruno Luxe rolls and
that's usually who it takes care of this
for me too
some of the best in the world I think
that's nice well done
well done look at shenzo it was speed
beautiful that was just I mean together
I think we make a good team absolutely
bro I'm looking for a job podcast
you can find Kelly High on the future
cannabis project though too so I'll show
you how it breaks apart so we can do one
that's smaller
they've added these washers in to the
premium because so many people are just
spinning these without product in it and
it's created some metal on metal issues
and so we're getting a lot of comments
about that but it's very small it's less
than one percent of people are actually
having an issue with it but so we've put
these extra rings in there just to kind
of help people that it's kind of like a
fidget people are really playing with
these often and they like it in their
hands it's uh
what's what's the feedback on kind of
like
what scenarios people I mean you
mentioned it before but kind of like I
love this size
hole for this purpose and that size for
that I was just in Europe with uh and I
ran into stores and pickle you know the
volcano and I I have a volcano I have a
couple of them I think that's a perfect
product for the smaller holes
the consistency and the mighty is really
good for that too but I think that you
know when you're vaping especially on
the go that it gives you
your your Smoky vaping more surface area
at once and it's all consistent so
there's not left with bigger chunks or
something like that that is trying to be
processed
[Music]
here in case you guys
I got some orange soda here which is
some of my personal favorites this is
really delicious this is all grown in
soil with with no uh
no nutrients no Toppers no teas just are
organic patent-pending soil
and uh
water
yes please
I think we should spark one of those up
yes that's true so why don't you uh
where's the oh wait sorry I missed it
it's okay
yeah it's fast
so that little stuff that was in here
again laying on top right there
that is phenomenal
because I spent half my time pulling out
these sounds before I even put it in my
grinder not associated with the mill wow
so look at the difference between these
two so that's the finer one right the
smaller holes
[Music]
so some people like to mix these
together
and also what is so cool about the flour
mill is that afterwards you can't help
the terpenes just they liven up they
wake up and so they don't get stuck to
the mill right you're not creating that
is probably grinding it together so yeah
I mean check the nose on that that you
wouldn't have thought you wouldn't have
got that same
hit out of the uh of the jar
true hey there
all right
I think we're all three-part Italian at
least here I got Italian and German
I'm Italian and Great Britain I'm one
one quarter Scottish 1 8 English and
Irish and half Italian
Sicilian and Greek and my
all right all right I know what this
tastes like salute yes Stevens
you said it was from Stefano DeStefano
yep
nicoletti here
nice
yeah
I have the lineage of that
so there's some
like something I haven't tasted in a
long time
[Music]
I heard Bob Marley's favorite strain was
called the cotton the cot yeah really
awesome cotton my son told me that
huh cat Corey is the guitar player from
third world okay all right do we have a
uh uh
in Austria
I have a portable weed maps one
um
[Laughter]
around but
maybe get a let me there's a little one
over here okay let me
I think that pillow talk because that's
um also the pillow talk was grown the
most amazing smell that I said okay yes
that is it pillow talk okay it wasn't
the Kiki was the pillow talk yeah
and chenzo what was your uh Lamb's bread
story my Lamb's red story okay so I went
to Jamaica in 75 the year after I
graduated high school because my brother
told me there was rastafines at smoked
weed there and that was kind of their
religion so I bought myself a ticket
after selling a bunch of Colombian and I
got in the grill
and met a Rastafarian named reford ward
he turned me on to reggae for the first
time also we were sitting in my Tenon of
Sands of uh in Negril Yacht Club under a
palm tree and
um he told me that
Lamb's bread is actually a technique you
cut off the uh the top eight inches of a
plant
right after it starts to Bud and stick
it back in the ground in Jamaica this
the muddy soil acts like
um well we would put our clones in and
it takes root and becomes an amazing
yeah and that's what they called Lamb's
bread
so years after that people came up with
a strand they called Lamb's red that
smells great what's this one this is the
pillow talk
that's uh Moscow and Tang farms and
House of Kush and all that oh Tang has
been and uh Ben and Aaron and Brent yep
and so we've created a new company
called analytics and we have that's a
whole nother conversation for another
day yeah
he's no longer with amazing Ben is with
us so it enables us to do things that he
wasn't otherwise able to do so I think
that it's going to be a lot of fun he
just got back from Oklahoma so Ben did
growing in soil he did the final hunt
yes so and Coco we've got down there I
think
um heated soil so this came from soil
and so he just did these um he had about
250 that he popped and this is one of
the best ones that we came back with so
let's uh give this again yeah great
cross contaminants
for Old Friends Orman
all right what was the second joint we
had rolled out it was still Jamaican I
never rolled one of the other ones yet
not either it was oh that's two two of
the same okay
it's Jiffy not as quickly as you can
Mill it
but to have fun party tricks while
you're rolling now oh yeah
that is so cool it makes it harder for
me to rip off yeah I didn't even know
that check this out too
oh that's cool oh wow I did not know
that it'll stick to your refrigerator it
doesn't stick to anything it's got a
nice relationship with things and people
because it's made with love yes there's
a lot you know we talked about that what
is the mission behind our company what
are we trying to be and what we're
trying to do here and after a couple of
weeks uh hammering it out in person uh
in Arizona we came up with we want to
make products that bring people joy we
want to make people happy want to
enhance your relationship with cannabis
make it easier better we run 34 pounds
through one of these without cleaning it
at one of the labs in Michigan shout out
to LIT labs and Mark and the boys over
there and Gene um you know they had a
Flour Mill yeah
I I love you know good industrial design
good engineering and
you know small business like you're
checking all my boxes like how many guys
are in the company five now and it's all
Partners so we're still doing this on
our own I handle all the sales Aaron
runs everything out of the shop and
headquarters in Arizona we brought on Q
and he's masterful at the back room and
getting oh nice all done
you're like uh
a maestro a maestro with a rolling paper
over there oh Chris and this was the
best roller he taught me how oh shit man
I should get a mic stand maybe uh but
yeah I know my brother Chris taught me
how to roll
when I was about 12.
maybe 13. I think we have something here
this this is probably one of my favorite
genetics that has not been just yet
discovered I would love your opinion on
it okay this is Pillow Talk phenohan uh
I thought it was the best smelling herb
these are actually moscases I don't even
know that that's so I can ask Rick uh
it's what cross yeah
but also to get back to Aaron and John
and Jason are the engineers those are
the guys that crank out all the cats all
the everything floral earthy and a
little bit fruity
but like uh underlying
what kind of fruit would that be
maybe uh somewhere this is where we need
to give give is like my voice in terms
of uh
I'm like it tastes good or like I'll be
like it tastes fruity but like he'll be
he'll wax poetic about right
the gagiers shout out to Gabe and we
wish he was here we're going to try to
do our best to describe this but it is
super smooth
it is not tasty
yeah
and it has many elements it's complex
right but it works together
yes they are and we care about it we pay
attention to our terpene profiles and
the caminoids and the blends of those
sometimes you have these high thcs and
that really takes away from helping your
pain receptors and actually getting the
full benefit of of the Entourage of the
entire plant when you're growing it
specifically for one cannabinoids and
there's hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds that you do and don't know
about well you're you're in some ways
overlapping the positive that you can
get so yeah that's very good what did
you think of the Formaggio
I only had a couple of hits but it
started this conversation off right yeah
you know that's good I feel very
comfortable those are growing over there
yeah
I I um I was so fortunate during the re
I tried to keep the strain alive during
the cold winter and I had two mothers
and I was like oh I'm gonna have better
take some cuttings so I took some
cuttings and then like a week later
the two mothers got powdery mildew and
I've never had because I had to I don't
have the right stuff and I was moving
the plants in and out the change of
temperature and the dampness because of
all the rain gave them powdery mildews
never had on a cannabis plant ever but
uh so I I chopped them down and threw
them away but taking the the Clones
too much four of which I kept which are
right there and
um before putting them out there I'm
keeping him in veg but I have a little
tray of clones right there which I
should probably put in in a few minutes
oh I see yeah yeah beautiful I'm trying
to keep my strain alive bro so how long
have you been gardening
um
well straight for about five years six
years now and I grew a successful crop
back in like 19.
four okay in in Morocco on Moraga Canyon
just east of the uh
405 where Gaspard gas bar de Portola was
led by a group of Chumash Indians in
1769.
it's called Bel Air now
so we could roll one of these up too and
then what we can do is see if it we
never know one of these this is the
strawberry this is delicious okay so we
rolled one of these yeah this is the
Jamaican oh wait then what's this joint
this is the that's another Jamaican from
the beginning right
Oh I thought you meant the one yeah why
don't we put it with what it because
we're gonna yep let's let's repeat the
name of this again
pillow talk
I'm gonna hear about that folks
and which state is that from Michigan
yeah
I went to boot camp in Great Lakes okay
yeah right on yeah that's Illinois
that is all connected
yeah well Great Lakes is a little city
north of Chicago oh I was thinking about
all the Great Lakes yeah the largest
freshwater Naval Training Center there
cool so we're a Red Wings fan in fact
the Raspberry Pi I was just with uh
Darren McCarty yeah and shout out to the
Red Wings and Darren McCarty
and uh he played in like the 90s he yeah
he's a legend and so we I went to a game
with like the Steve Eiserman yes that's
right that's right yeah they were good
so I'm an hockey player I used to play
yeah yeah was a tough day well they got
bertuzzi who was a former Wing so he
just got traded over there and he's
doing good
um so I was with uh McCarty and our
friends at ice buyer and we were in
Detroit and went to a game ran into him
got together the next night out in Hazel
Park and uh I brought some raspberry pie
and some flour Mills to say thank you
for the night before and we just clicked
and had a great time and I shared the
Raspberry Pi we shot a video of him
smoking it and uh
I'm smoking on this
brass Berry right here delicious rice
Berry don't forget the pier Berry
love you brother
you know raspberry pies rasp our ASP and
I think a lot of people say Raz
raspberry because of this industry is
probably part to blame because the
r-a-z-z and the flavors of gummies and
the different products right yeah so I'm
actually with Roe in Miami before this
meeting in Detroit and we're laughing so
hard about Raspberry Pi so when I tell
them the story while we're in Detroit I
telling Dairy during that story and he
goes rasp
berry pie my friend's recording it
um and now like a week later after that
there's a music a song made from that uh
smoking that joint Raspberry Pi from the
audio recording of the video and so it's
evolved in this thing and I think
raspberry prey it warrants that and
there's the Club remix yeah it is I got
a remix before I got here just before I
got to California
um so it's really you know it's cool to
be able to work with those people I love
music so you know you play uh no but um
Detroit Electronic you know Detroit you
know I mean come on Motown Electronic
Music Festival scene uh all that is you
know part of our blood beautiful
[Music]
so it's really cool that this this
industry and these products and the
genetics that we bring together can
cross over into the mainstream like
sports and you get to meet people that
you like and might want to work with and
so like being able to work with zigzag
or with
um you know former red wings and things
like that
I've wanted to do kind of like
like skateboarding content and surfing
content and music content and like
hockey like sports content
and uh it's just like let's smoke weed
and talk let's do it do it two minutes
in The Penalty Box no the sun bin yeah
let's talk uh about the cosmos with a
with an astronomer
like imagine
astronomy podcast nightly if you had a
Neil deGrasse yeah yeah like and uh just
got to smoke weed and ask him whatever
questions it will leave off the Tyson
because that's better for the the future
cannabis project Neil deGrasse
that's true I didn't even think about
that
yeah
he even has a name that works I do want
to shout out to something that I think
is really cool you know
um this is the uh strawberry strawberry
coffee this is the another organic no no
raspberry pie which is another Moscow
this is really good too cross yeah I
haven't been you know I only sit in my
backyard smoking my own weed mostly all
these Highs are different give me some
weed okay
but these this is freaking amazing
you're enjoying this yeah great yeah
this is always ready of really great
weed in a long time thank you probably
since the last time I was at Peter's uh
I was gonna say that's every Tuesday
night
now that's what I love about the event
oh my gosh like this I love the session
from everywhere shout out to the
sessions so many joints going around
Santa Monica well I guess that's West
L.A border of Santa Monica and you get
to a point where just everyone's so high
and like they're like shaking the joints
off like a pitcher shaking off a call
next time I'm bringing my melodica
somebody's gonna play the ball yeah well
you brought it and you never played it
oh that's right you could play it right
well I was DJing bro in case you didn't
remember you were terrible
wait a minute here
but because those turntables had shitty
needles on them they didn't want to give
us any of the good vinyl dude they gave
us stuff they didn't care about
scratching up
terrible music because peaky music I
mean some great albums I did the best
with what I had and and people enjoyed
it it wasn't that bad was it yeah it was
pretty bad but it was better than
nothing right
well it was also coming through terrible
speakers so we had like the double
whammy of the speakers sound okay you
had the high end
no mid and bass
what about the second time I DJ'd with
my phone oh yeah yeah I know that then
what one sweet now yeah yeah DJ from
your phone yeah
Motown and you know
if I DJ it's a commitment to like
getting back into it because I don't
want to like if I do it I'm gonna like
start spending time at home going
through music and I know it's like it's
like something that if you enjoy it it's
like an art and if you enjoy making art
why not make it good you know I enjoy it
I just have no time for it that's why I
throw the playlist together or I just
need other people to DJ what about
do you ever use like
turned or simulated turntable stuff with
like Reverb and so I had I I used I used
to use turntables and then I started
using Ableton and so I do you know like
so many people DJ with like the what is
it tractor and what's the other one
so you said it it's very strong right
what is it ta what would you guess as
the THC contents of that product
um not as high as I you would think from
the effect because of the terpenes it's
special it says 19 and yeah I've never I
don't walk around with coas I'm not
trying to prove a point uh you know with
those I know that what's amazing is I
would not sell in the dispensary Market
you can't get this yeah
the quality of the high it's not the the
number of percentage of THC it's you
know and it's yeah you're right it's a
Entourage of different terbians
yeah there's some DJ Short down in there
there's some grape guide I have the
whole lineage of it if you want to know
but um yeah that's a big thing you know
we say I like the line um
you know you can't really you wouldn't
pick out choose your dessert based on
the sugar content that's not how you go
find things that you like right or
you're alcohol based on the are you
drinking Everclear tonight
making oil with it right in fact we're
drinking oh yeah it's my her favorite
beer cheers here's to the flour mill and
the partnership thank you
thanks for your hospitality yes and our
partnership with the future cannabis
project project
you have the click Library
okay there we go
so
[Music]
yeah and you can get these you can buy
these absolutely how did you hear about
the farm out where was your first
interaction with it
we uh at the events uh someone was
bringing one so the FCP sessions and
it's cool because you see new stuff pop
up and it's like that's cool
and um
that was one of them where I immediately
I mean I reached out I think I reached
out to you right away right yeah what is
this
um did you that's a strawberry
strawberry yeah yeah you like that I do
like that that one but we haven't gotten
to the one you've been hyping up all
night uh no we didn't oh wait that was
the pillow pillow talk pillow for sure
yep yeah yeah
okay
yeah
it's it's hard after the it's hard after
the third hit folks do you actually
you know get there yeah
subscribe yeah and then like I have to
do all the production so I'm like super
hot and that's why I love this hey I
volunteered to edit it Anything Audio
Video I'll put it together I'll send it
to you okay but um
so I love being able to work with people
that this that gives us the ability
um because we're not a grinder not
everybody we don't have to do collabs
and Partnerships so we're very selective
about who we want to work with and we
pay attention to your history your
involvement who you are character is
important you know we come from bringing
morals ethics and values and business
Acumen to cannabis these things cost
more to make we're not trying to make
the prices High because we think they're
worth more and that you should pay more
it's because that quarter turn threading
right there that costs an extra oh it's
like almost two dollars just for that
extra double threading right yeah so
that adds up with the quality of the
magnets all this stuff and so you know
and we know what we've created so it's
important we you know what you've
created and how important and it is to
you so we appreciate it thank you for
having us and and doing a collab with us
well and thank you for being willing to
do it no I was totally excited and I
wanted to just to mention your logo
because I think it's the same logo I've
seen
lately for sure
in the past week no I'm going to say
within the decades this is one of the
coolest have you seen a cool one three
years ago today uh my basement wall was
covered in pictures of all flower Mo
logos what they could and wouldn't be
and this one was not on there yet this
is it right yeah okay so can we see this
over here I don't know do it on this one
on this one okay
like well you know what chick is his hat
out and his shirt yeah this shirt is so
cool we're gonna get close and yeah yeah
we just made some new sweatshirts
and that physique yeah Dad
yeah my daughters sing songs about my
fat belly in Chinese
How does it go
it's uh like tattoos uh or something
like fat belly
that's motivating isn't it yeah my kids
walk by and slap my belly and that's you
know always motivating
okay so let's uh
did we smoke everything nope nope that's
the orange the orange okay we have not
smoked the orange folks
we are going to smoking and it's
orange soda this is Chris wasco's stuff
so Chris Wasco lives in Michigan as well
and he's got just a beautiful history of
no he's um he's related he's he's got a
partner Andy and they got uh spot up in
Lapeer Michigan and Vassar a couple
licenses up there and Chris has put
together over with his family it was
like with his grandfather starting
fishing you know 30 years ago teaching
him how to make soil and so he's really
mastered the technique of living soil
and that's where I feel these terpenes
really come out and express themselves
he's gotten 4.2
um back on coas for terp profiles on
these uh it's just a very clean and he
he's a plant person turkey is really
high yeah no typically you're between
one and two percent I mean I think if
you're getting between two and three
you're doing really good and that's like
a nice place to be people are hitting
between three and four but they're using
a lot of things to Pump It Up
um we don't this is how would you do
like that's not even my thing I'm not
the the expert on that so I won't go
into it that's why we have Ben that's
why I got Ben as a partner yeah
um Ben grieve and Aaron and you know
we've we've got some
pretty solid people that that's what
they do what is it what were you saying
the number is 4.2 percent which is high
and that's great and it's from water and
dirt nothing else it's a hot and cold
mix
and uh I believe that's what you're
licked down I do yeah yeah that's
beautiful and you don't need a pen or a
thing you don't go Hey where's the poker
you're you're good this is beautiful
well let's give you take to dry on that
okay yeah see if you can taste those
terpenes right there
oh my God and it's soda so why we call
it soda it kind of fizzes on the side of
your mouth and you'll so the soda line
is what Chris has come up with and he's
there he's responsible for the Jamaican
blue and the lemon haze I have Lemon
Haze with me which is one of my personal
favorites
um
and uh so the combination of having
people that have dedicated their lives
to these plants and
we're able to kind of bring these out
into the mainstream
and there's
it has like a deep OG underneath the
orange somewhere down there
it seems like this is a this is this is
like really worth investing in yeah
and smoking
yeah so we license our genetics out
and um really so you just don't make
flour mill you know there's a company we
invested in houses more yeah so we're
Partners in House of Kush and you know
some of the newer genetics and designer
genetics that are coming out that are
people looking forward to stay ahead of
the curve but also with that have a
story and have a legacy and have
um you know balance between what we're
looking for today but we're not trying
to play these High T games and all that
stuff some of this stuff does test out
High the cream sodas are 32 this is
between 26 and 30 all day they yield
everything's been tested for commercial
viability
well
there you go if you need me to further
test out any I'll be here excellent
yeah now your opinion is valued oh yeah
these are amazing
and so they're all unique questions that
we get to do this all over again
tomorrow night good are you coming I'll
be there bro
um
so this leads me to think that Michigan
has the the kind like Cali like
California there is some serious Talent
you got heavyweight heads out there and
they're actually the ones that are
growing lion odor stuff in Michigan and
they've got some they started with their
sunshine and you got trick trick and
Willie J peso with their giraffe head
and Shout out also to riddles J.O with
his runts and Skittles um we've been
hanging out a lot the last year and I
really think his genetics are some of
the best he found Girl Scout cookies and
some of the originals that we all know
today under all these Brands so we are
able to work with some of these
kind of you know to me they're the
Godfathers of the genetics and there's
other people that just been gifted stuff
the right way and you know there's plant
people over people people and some of
these Growers you're not going to run
into them at a show you got to know them
or be introduced to them because you're
doing something different and I think it
comes down to the business side of
things uh if you can make enable people
to do what they're good at eliminate all
the marketing of the accounting and the
stuff that gives them headaches build a
team around them I think that's part of
what is making a difference is you know
we're not just here to sell shit we want
to help here's added circle like these
are things we know from having other
businesses in our lives before we got to
cannabis yeah that's a helpful it's
helpful to be a financial planner it's
helpful to have been a defense
contractor and sold weapons of the
government it's helpful to have right
teacher excellent 25 years
let's see I just came a better listener
avionics stagnation
um so you know I see people that have
talent in this in this space in this
industry but sometimes they're getting
wiped out by bigger people consuming
them or getting in the contracts or not
protecting themselves or following
through and and not doing what they say
they're going to do and collecting money
and you know I think there's a lot of
that going on so we're just trying to do
really good business I sleep well at
night we're not you know you have people
that do it for the money and people do
it because they love it
when you learn something well I love
this do well and you have the ability of
this I was 13 years old when I tasted my
first cannabis and it was to this day
I'll never forget it I remember that I
could see it in my head
um I was up on the hill behind my house
under the avocado tree with my older
brother and my friend who had gotten
high before me and they got me high and
I I could not stop laughing it was
no it's funny I think the person I spoke
with was Ben it was my mom's
friend's kid and we spoke I think uh out
of everybody I'm smoking he's the only
person that doesn't smoke weed that I've
smoked weed with my whole life was the
first person the first person never did
after that I don't think uh I turned a
bunch of high school friends on to weed
uh they smoked for the first time like I
smoked all through high school but they
smoked for the first time at graduation
at my house
and uh
and then two of them just became like
all day smoke like
shit just right there heavy Stoners Like
like every day for the past 30 years all
day true story we got caught in school I
started that and uh we got caught and
the police came at school and we were in
front of the lunchroom and Chris and uh
we got suspended for a week and our
parents put us together for an entire
week so we got high and played video
games and hung out and like we were all
alone our parents were at work and that
was our punishment in high school for
getting caught with weed was to spend a
week together and think about it yeah
you know it's just eighth grade wait
with like no parents around
got busted in the eighth grade the one
of the lay teachers saw smoking behind
the laundromat and told they had none
and the head nun that had me in class
and it was she had to go get the bell
rang she had to get the kids in I was up
against the blackboards the class was
talking to me and she comes in and she
goes nicoletti I thought I told you to
stand with your nose against a
Blackboard I'm like no sister you didn't
say that and then she you know she
slapped a few kids and me several times
during the year and
she went to slap me she goes Nicoletta
you have the Colossal God and she goes
to slap me and I had to grab her hand
and then she tried to slap me with her
other hand I grabbed that one I said
sorry sister I can't let you hit me
anymore and then you head-butted her
flashlight I had put their hands yeah
she started shaking and go stick you
know go out in the hallway I'm like okay
yeah don't stand up to me take my abuse
anyway
um my mom knew I smoked anyway so it
wasn't a big deal but uh yeah we used to
smoke on the lawn at North Hollywood
High in a big circle passing a water
pipe full of hash and like the vice
principals like over by my hoop house
right over there you know yeah
is it best going to festivals later and
seeing like your janitor teachers from
high school they're out smoking in
public and that's a fun one
72.
yeah
that was 10th grade
and the guy that was the hash connect
was lived above my avocado tree
live above your avocado to cool
so he also came with avocados
[Laughter]
fresh made tortilla chips straight from
the other oh yeah it was a house avocado
tree
when it had avocados they were really
good they didn't have them every year
yeah I'd like to have a good avocado
tree yeah you have to have a pollinator
around if it's a female I think it's a
female and male thing
it's in everything yeah
like uh
I think you graphed on certain
of a cut like because if if you have a
good uh if you eat a good avocado and
you plant that seed it's not going to be
the same no
so you need if if you nail down
something you like like Haas or whatever
that's like now from clones of parents
um and and then and then
um put on to like a different avocado's
root stuff like uh lemon tree like that
in the front
the the real lemon bearing part is
grafted onto some other Citrus or lemon
type with China yeah right Thorns like
like
um Prince Charm that sounds good I bet
those are amazing
yeah they are yeah lemons right you know
they're very sweet very sweet very cool
you'll go home with one tonight
I like that
have we sampled everything
well I think so okay yeah oh no we
didn't we didn't go for the uh
Tiki Tom let me smell if you could yeah
you choose
okay A little gassier what else what was
the other one oh the raspberry pie we
need to do that if we haven't we were
talking about yeah
come on now all right let's do this one
I think that's the one you were hypingo
yeah we haven't even smoked it yet yeah
there is no too high unless you like
are too high
this should take us somewhere
this has the most amazing automatic
removal of stems I've ever seen
that's a good one
uh all right here we go I can't believe
how this happens so I'm going on those
finer holes because a lot of
professional rollers and people that
will really want the smaller grain then
look at his hands
five seconds
it takes a little bit longer with the
um with the smaller holes and the more
coarse it is I mean you're basically one
turn that was probably six percent but
look at that
wow
um
yeah a regular grinder does it comes out
smelling nice like this kind of
I think it wakes up the flower and it It
prepares it for its purpose and that to
me is what's so special about this thing
the end result
it's fun to talk about all that and you
know the process is cool what it's doing
and how it's doing it but this is
just awesome
are you excited to smoke your next joint
I am very excited this this smells like
um could be the best one so far that's
awesome that makes me feel good
yeah because you don't know it's been
hyping up the most all night seriously
this one's and it's available we have it
nobody else has that it's a place it's
very whiny very white it like red winey
berry
like a
Chianti maybe or maybe more I could look
out the lineage it's fruity deep fruity
shenzo I think after you roll this we
should have one more beer
I think so and then call it a night
so the lineage on that Jamaican blue
uh it's an Indica dominant hybrid strain
created through Crossing an old favorite
DJ shorts original blueberry crossed
with Jamaican land race BX then crossed
with Superman ice cream which is Grape
God and it is your favorite and Infamous
Cataract Kush BX Jamaican blue Blends
floral notes with sweet tropical Citrus
flowers finishing with delicious Berry
tartness that will Linger on the tongue
the aroma consists of a citrus and
tropical floral overtone that is
slightly Berry and sweet
Jamaican blue experience has a nice
lifting effect that comes from its
Jamaican lineage that Fades into a
relaxing and slightly sedative
long lasting high coming from us Indica
ancestors you'll feel a euphoric
cerebral onset that will fill you with a
pure happiness Vibe pushing out any
negative or racy thoughts
a light tingly body high comes next
creeping up on you before you suddenly
take hold or pulling you on a state of
relaxation the 13 the terpene in
combination with this moderate THC level
which I said is about 19 percent
uh comes from some CBG as a bonus it
gives Jamaican blue on experience that
is entirely unique
yeah
I give out a lot of stuff that's high in
CBG yeah hoping that people play with it
we have CBG gummies lit labs are doing
those they're just pure CBG gummies
which is good I've been doing I have
like some dabs I'm doing dabbing like
like terp pens and just dabbing pure CBG
I have psoriatic arthritis how do you
get it pure just order the API you know
what's the effect instant and it's great
I feel pure CBG CBG
yeah
CBD in my gummies especially no I
haven't had any lately because I've been
just
making Edibles for my own stash but all
right let's light this thing up what is
it called raspberry raspberry pie don't
call it raspberry
so I can see how that one based on the
finer grind and why people like that
that's very much like a cigarette on the
end of it you know
the way that Lit Up is no I'm the actual
hot yeah like that was noticeable
because I don't use that one
we should just say where's Camera two
look at it on camera too the lighting of
that you might have to make a commercial
out of that so one of these got it
we can zoom in on the software
here here I can fix it
[Music]
filter
astray
just have to re-roll it a little bit
tighter
fit it in let's see where we cut in some
dubby music it's plain while chenza's
repairing fixing not only do I roll but
I repair everything
I stand by my work I will I will repair
it some raspberry pie
I have a song for it that we could I
could play actually yeah yeah right
let's just uh play the actual song while
we're smoking it oh here it is on my
phone right there this is the remix
though I like the first one better but
let's see
uh
what
okay that was great that's what I charge
for
all right here we
says someone downloaded the audio and
then put music through it yeah I want to
play the original one first because this
one's it's just Epic
oh you know what I should do hold on I
gotta show you the the video of
the moment right because that's even
cooler you can see how this evolved
naturally
okay this is the wrong size filter is
what it is but you know what it's gonna
be okay
just be careful yeah yeah and then we
have Sticky Lips because of all the
terpenes
and that last one was a very I call it
an Oiler
it was the orange one orange soda orange
soda that was yeah it was so dense
there we go
back here Aaron McCarty now I'm smoking
on this
brass
Berry right here delicious
all right remember seeing that
[Laughter]
right
so then
about a week later I'll wait for the
plane to fly over
[Music]
here he wants to come out
the phone's a little bit louder
[Music]
this is Marcus Christie in Michigan
I think I would probably grind my not in
such a fine way
the next one up
so yeah that's the original and then he
sent me the remix and I was like it was
very cool yeah so then he added some
poor shit yeah that's a so that came
from the night that was sharing so this
has already become just kind of a
legendary genetic for me it's been and
it's good
it is like a Raspberry Pi
experience
like crushed but very like
[Music]
my drive home tonight it's gonna be very
slow on the 405 I'll be like right hand
lane in the Prius going 50.
foreign
I had other phenotypes of the cross
between the Afghan land race and the um
OG some of them took after the Afghan
had Cedar like smelling big buds you
know donkey dick types but the one that
took after the OG had like nuggets you
know spaced nicely you know yeah are you
excited for the caterpillars this year I
already caught one at the base of one of
the plants out there it was there and
then I lifted up something that I was
looking for Phoenix you know bugs for
Phoenix we have a
a Leopard Gecko and it needs insects I
when I don't buy crickets or I'll find
them around here and it's been too cold
for crickets I have to sometimes I have
to get what's underneath the pots you
know I lift up a pot and there's pill
bugs or uh worms or stuff so yeah that's
a constant
battle Yeah so but I found oh um
caterpillar under there I killed it
um sorry Mr caterpillar may you be
reborn in a better existence next time
but I didn't want to take a chance in it
spreading I didn't know what it was and
didn't know so many of them
like I have a Jared
and I just drop them in there and
there's like
well you see 50 of them in there the net
is there because one year I was
completely devastated by caterpillars
you know I had grown some kind of
Hawaiians strain that
um
wasn't used to California Heat
and it was weak
in I don't know maybe I didn't cover it
so
it's cold
well why don't we wrap up okay but yes I
do agree with you it's uh it's chilly
it's a Brisk night in the valley
but these are the most amazing machines
for for getting your cannabis into a
a rule
she's never going back to Christ here's
the zigzag one this is really cool
Flour Mill we'll leave you with one
he's gonna be a Miller yeah I
you know I think
it's so amazing is the top of the
rotor yeah the rotor
those little flutes
that is me okay so you got it so it
doesn't do metal on metal friction yep
because of the
um
washers yeah yeah yeah they're working
you know it's it's you know when you
create things that are this it's
Innovative in a very saturated market
and you know you're going to take on all
kinds of stuff but yeah you know it's
I've had incredible success on it I
personally haven't had any issues I've
never seen anything
like transform that
butt into
drawing them not Grant okay milled yeah
it's a different Final End Result right
it's sold
yeah that's the whole point
I think it treats the product with
respect
your flower's happy or you're happier
yeah smells tastes better smells pure it
doesn't smell like it's gone through a
grinder yeah well Brent I hope your
first trip ever to the valley was
memorable yeah and that the next time
you're in the valley you'll be like I
remember the last time I was in the
valley that's right of course we're
happy to host you is that yeah thank you
thanks everyone peace ciao
I'm gonna drop the mic now definitely
don't drop them out
all right
[Music]