[Music]
my name is Michael Steinman's and I'm
one of the co-founders and CEOs of flow
Khanna and I'm here today to tell you
three things first I wanna start off and
tell you a little bit about flow kana in
our story then second I want to discuss
the incredible opportunity that
California has to really build a totally
unique different kind of cannabis
industry and even take that further into
agriculture at large and three I want to
talk a little bit about the capital
markets and especially China some of the
irregularities that that's causing in
our marketplace and in our industry so
to start off with flow Khanna simply
speaking we are a branded supply chain
company ok we take a different approach
than the traditional large scale big AG
model big farm model where instead of
growing our own cannabis we partner with
small farmers in the Emerald triangle
and only exclusively source sustainable
organic and kind of zero carbon emission
cannabis products at a high level we
have two components to our business we
have kind of the flow distribution arm
of things and the flow processing and
manufacturing side of things the flow
distribution very simple distribution
company we have three hubs across the
state in the Bay Area in LA and in San
Diego and the flow processing and
manufacturing side we're headquartered
in the heart of the Emerald triangle in
Mendocino and we have three separate
aggregation hubs strategically located
in the Emerald triangle where we source
the product from the farmers we in take
it we grade it we sorted we trim it and
then that product gets sent down to our
main processing facility to get
value-add process manufactured at scale
the main processing facility we have was
used to be home of the old Fetzer winery
so we bought the old abandoned winery
from the Fetzer's that's about a two
hundred thousand square feet facility
it used to be home of the third largest
winery in the US and we are repurposing
it to do a centralized cannabis campus
that brings all the pieces of the supply
chain under one
so lab testing distribution
manufacturing packaging all the services
of small farmer needs to really given
the ability to scale and to compete with
a larger forces coming at bay we are
have the good fortune of being the
number one flour brand of the state
which is kind of a not only a testament
to kind of our hard work and our
commitment to this industry but rather a
testament to the conscious consumers of
California that are really voting with
their wallets for brands that are more
ecologically minded environmentally
minded and sustainably focus to really
build a different kind of industry which
we most definitely need to do and I kind
of always say we're at a very fragile
state in the cannabis industry a time
where the fate of this industry and the
livelihood of so many is really at stake
and California has the incredible
opportunity to really build something
radically different and radically
amazing something that I don't think
even agriculture as a large has really
seen see prohibition has been really
devastating to mankind it's cost the
nation billions of dollars it's
destroyed communities separated families
disproportionately affected minorities
just to name a few of the bad things but
in California prohibition did leave us
one gift and that gift was that it gave
us a totally fragmented supply chain of
more than 53,000 cannabis farmers and
these cannabis farmers not only live
totally off-grid lives with solar panels
rain catchment totally fully diversified
farms with carrots and cabbage and
tomatoes and celery and cucumbers
it's a beautiful and inspiring ecosystem
and not only is it beautiful and
inspiring but they're literally the
largest supply chain of the world these
53,000 cannabis farmers produce about
eighty-five percent of the cannabis
that's consumed nationwide we are
powering the black market of the nation
from this state and this is a very very
unique agricultural model that instead
of having the traditional the number one
and number two players at the top that
command ninety ninety five percent of
the market share that whole market share
of eighty five percent is split among
53,000 cannabis farmers and this
beautiful gift and this incredible model
of agriculture is at a great threat
right
and it's a threat to being lost by the
wayside of the traditional big AG model
the same big AG model that has decimated
our planet for decades and is a single
largest contributor to all of the
climate crisis we are exhibiting mono
cropping which is a common practice in
big AG to make it easy and simple and
more efficient has totally made us lose
a lot of the biological diversity we
have in the fruits and vegetables we
consume today so II for example wheat
and corn we enjoy maybe one or two
varietals in a universe of hundreds of
varieties that we've already lost as
mankind imagine if that happened to
cannabis and the loss of these worlds is
fertile soils in the biodiversity pose a
mortal threat to our future survival
we are literally killing ourselves with
our food production models that we have
on our planet today see modern
agriculture has turned our food
production into a business and in order
to win in business you have to scale you
have to lower your cost and you have to
make more margin right so fundamentally
it's caused our food production to drive
to use more chemicals and pesticides and
take cut corners and really you know pay
people lower wages and produce it
cheaper and cheaper and cheaper I don't
know why but I feel like that's a
fundamentally flawed model to really
produce the food and products that we
consume and now we have an opportunity
to do it in cannabis with our medicine
and why would we go in on the same route
to produce the cheapest possible
cannabis from our perspective we want to
produce the best possible cannabis and
this is the mission of flow kaanum
C we believe that the future of
Agriculture is small fragmented
decentralized farmers working with
centralization and technology to reach
scale and these are and these are models
that literally exist in our world today
for example the largest taxi cab company
in the world
uber doesn't own a single vehicle the
largest hotel chain in the world
Airbnb doesn't own a single room I
believe that the largest supply chain of
cannabis doesn't have to come from one
source and one producer and one big AG
farm so as we look to build this new
agricultural industry
why do we want to do more of the old
let's learn from the past and let's
build something different and imagine
something new after all that's part of
the pioneering and adventurous spirit
that all Californians like us hold dear
so it's up to us the operators the
distributors the retailers a
manufacturer the other cultivators to
really work in synchrony in harmony and
use your dollars and use your time and
use your resources to invest in the
brands that are pushing the industry
forward and are trying to build a better
industry for all of us to enjoy the
opportunity is grand and responsive and
the responsibility is even grander and
that responsibility is most evident when
you go take a visit to Canada our
neighbors up north and you understand a
little bit of the industry that they are
trying to build and I'll tell you it is
the polar opposite of the industry that
we have here in California
Canada contributes about zero
agricultural products to the world yet
they're building the biggest production
facilities for cannabis in the world so
all of them have to be these massive
indoor facilities because of the rules
and the regulations they've got to be
GMP certified they have to be ISO
certified they literally have to use
full bodysuits to go in with a face mask
goggles a hairnet
gloves and booties I literally felt like
I was walking into a spaceship yet
instead I was walking into a farm you
know I couldn't help but think about my
home in Mendocino and the farmers that
we work with and really think about the
times where we are down in the ground
and playing with the little worms and
collecting the worm castings and getting
real dirt underneath your fingernails
real live dirt to create real live
high-quality products it's a very very
different industry it's an industry not
with farmers but with lab coats and
there's not a single agricultural
product in the world that's grown
indoors and I deeply feel that
California must lead the way in building
the cannabis industry that we deserve
[Applause]
I also learned that a lot of people out
there are trying to wrap a story around
empty jars and air literally and taking
it public these companies have no
long-term value and no sustain kind of
growth potential they're not really
thinking about the industry that we're
building not really thinking about the
value you can create or how many
communities you can empower and what
girl good you can do to the world
it's stim plea wrapping a story around a
public process and playing a little
fictitious game on a computer screen
around value and why are people rushing
to get an exit so quickly when we
haven't even begun the regulatory
process of this industry and I'm not
trying to dismiss the public process
after all capital is an incredibly
important component of raising any of
building any business and at falow
Connor we've raised probably as much
capital as any of the bigger players
here in California and we'll continue to
raise capital but not to build air but
to build a business of value to build a
difference that makes a difference to
the communities that we work with and to
really big bring more wholesome products
to the California cannabis industry at
large and see I grew up in Venezuela in
a third-world country and I learned
really early on that countries grow at
the pace that their capital markets
grown right you need capital to give it
to the entrepreneurs and the business
owners to create more value to create
more jobs to create more opportunities
and that's what helps economies develop
in like countries industries are the
same way we need those capital markets
we need those investors we need the
Canadian public process and we need it
to build the industry that we really
want to enjoy without them it would be
impossible for this industry to get off
its feet so in kind of closing remarks
and now opening up for questions I think
that as entrepreneurs in this room and a
lot of business owners that I see and a
lot of the cool brands that I see and a
lot of responsible operators that I see
let's remember that this gift that we
have to build our businesses it's
collectively building the industry
together and every single thing that we
do in every single day that we spend in
every resource and every dollar that we
put into this industry is building the
collective of the industry that over
time and over decades will soon
stabilize but it's in its very nascent
forms and that's the gift that we have
as entrepreneurs and business owners
right it's a gift to like take our
dreams
bring him and manifest them into reality
to shape and mold humanity to propel us
forward to build the dreams and the
things that we want to see in the world
so let's not forget that gift and let's
not forget that responsibility and we
must remember that in life what's truly
valuable is not what we get but it's
what we become it's not what we get out
of what we do that matters but it's who
we become in the process of getting what
we want that truly is valuable so what
industry are we trying to become what
companies are we trying to become and
what is California's place in the
grander market of the world and with
that said I just want to thank Susan one
more time because she's a very dear
friend of mine and I'm a very big fan of
this conference and I'm happy to open up
for questions because I think I have
more time to answer I think if that's
allowed Jaime Padilla I'm with United
Farm Workers it's the labor union of
Dolores Huerta and stace of Chavez I
found your message really encouraging
and what excites me most about cannabis
is the potential I see for the kind of
overflow of innovation and positive
change that can happen in agriculture
overall and and I particularly
interested in how you were talking about
tapping into that positive consumer
power to drive some of this change and
as you as you all think through that I'm
curious as to you know when you when you
talk about social responsibility and
sustainability the the labor piece of
that right and I did a lot of work in
the coffee industry where that there
there was so much focus on small farmers
folks forgot about the labor that went
into into coffee and I'm concerned about
that happening here and I'm curious how
you're factoring labor into into your
work on social responsibility so it's
two parts so once you first asked about
you know what are we doing to kind of
encourage positive consumers to kind of
engage in these types of products in
this type of Industry and to talk about
the forces of the labor
how important that is to building an
industry more or less okay so I'll start
off with a second actually we are one of
the largest employers in Mendocino so
we've been working with the county of
Mendocino and the CEO of the county very
regularly we've actually been talking to
a couple of the labor unions as well so
I'd be curious to get your card as we
kind of build this industry and I think
you're absolutely right I mean I think
agriculture as large as suffered from
kind of improper treatment to small
farmers and they're marginalized the
workers I came from Venezuela and I used
to work with actually coffee
cooperatives I'm not sure exactly where
your coffee cooperatives work but it's
much in the same way and I think right
now in cannabis it's it's a different
consciousness that these farmers have in
a different culture that people live in
Mendocino and it's very much about that
community right I think them at large
it's not never been maybe because the
profits have been so large has never
been about the bottom line it's really
been about how do they share this
product with their farmers with their
neighbors with the people that work at
their farm and I think that ethos we
have to preserve it and trying to keep
it forward as we keep on growing this
industry and secondly addressing to the
consumers and the cannabis market it's a
tough task right I think we live in a
very very noisy world right we live in
the attention economy right every brand
is struggling to get the consumers
attention and I really believe that the
best marketing is a marketing that comes
from the heart that comes from talking
about values and that's really what we
focused on at Flo Cara
yes we're like sustainable and we'll
organic and we have all we tick all
those boxes of like the fact driven kind
of behavior patterns but at the end of
the day consumers choose product because
of an emotional connection right they'll
pick up a brand or they'll read an
article or they see a clipping and
they'll connect either emotionally with
it or whether or not to that brand and I
think that's kind of how we focused on
building kind of our customer base is
always being true to what we believe and
kind of wearing our values kind of on
our sleeves you helped me understand
when you're dealing with that many
supply outputs how you maintain quality
control so I would say that in our kind
of our model you know we don't have a
large scale farm so we don't have all
the work and all the investments
required to get that off the ground but
on the flip side we work with so many
fragmented and separated farmers so what
we do have is a big farmer relations
team so the farmer relations team is
working with the farmers to work on
strain planning strain mapping so a lot
of the a lot of what we're seeing right
now is that you know I think that
industries naturally move towards you
know consistency and standardization and
Brandt and consumers at large look for
that in a brand that had the repeatable
experience so for us we have to work
very very closely with our farmers I
mean we have monthly meetings with them
we have quarterly retreats with them
we're always constantly reviewing what
they're producing what quality came out
of it we've developed a kind of a
grading system internally at flow Cana
between triple a flour double a flour
single a and single B which is the same
grading system that happens in any other
form of Agriculture whether you go into
the citrus industry or the coffee or the
cacao industry there's a universal
grading system so we've built that over
the last few years at flow Cana and then
we kind of open sourced it to a lot of
the coops in the region so they've been
able to give their input they've been
able to give their comments and then
we've then given that to kind of ice CFA
which is the International cannabis
farmers Association and they've been you
know they said this then have been
improved the grading system and have
taken a kind of unlife of itself got
input from the market from the
dispensary so we're really trying to
establish kind of standards in the
industry that we can all work with and
these are the same standards that happen
across all other industries so I would
say that kind of dealing with the supply
is about you know having a baseline
understanding of how we talk about the
product the grading and the sorting is a
key component and I would say the second
is just farmer relations and just being
really constantly involved with the
community and being very strategic that
the challenge with cannabis is you know
you're already picking the strains today
that you're planting in March they're
going to be harvested in SX Tober so you
have to have so much planning and really
have to predict what the market is gonna
want in the future so it's a it's a
tough task but it's one that we take on
every day really yeah
all right guys we'll enjoy the rest of
the conference
[Applause]
[Music]