[Music]
turn that light on in our Geeta
the greenhouse podcast where are we
sorry right we're looking over the
Newport Harbor
it's our beauty house
it's amazing here we are in the
greenhouse welcome cannabis turn you on
this porch every night like checking out
you know what I do a lot of work from
home so I prefer to just sit out here
during the day and crush people the
future this is what I like
dude this is a great place to try some
calls this is a good thing you can space
the other one I do like the other things
the other two overlooking the art
Newport I knew Peter cannabis yeah do
you know when I moved out to California
to pursue and get back in this industry
I moved into a tent real life is word
Freudian room in that house before I can
afford and you know humility is
undervalued the option who's it to be
able to I am grateful to God I
appreciate
I'm sorry so we're sitting at a table of
these shoes yeah so let's talk about
these four sections my sole shoes well
you know let's talk about the Industrial
Revolution yes yes great shoes are just
a start
I chose shoe because most people are
going to feel it or not you know I'll
make you a special shoe
so these are the first hand-woven hemp
shoe in North America so the ones you
have in front of you are
I made have like a canvas but the one
that I'm wearing this is actually very
first prototype you can see is a
hand-stitched and the unique thing about
the shoe is that every single pair is
one of them so the pattern will not line
up on a shoe and so I designed them like
that you've been rocking these sensor
well you know I mean you don't change
yeah it's kind of cool when you rate
your own shoes why would you wear
something else and there you know it's
not just about the shoes
it's about this industrial have
revolution that you are very much on the
forefront of like that's well you know
is this this got a start way back in the
day and can right we had a huge
marijuana legalization movement and
heavily as a human that had its abstract
nuts and it failed for several different
reasons the reason that I believe the
film is because the culture didn't
accept it as really a better replacement
many many textile rings basically
everything says a leather on your body
better more durable antimicrobial
antifungal hypoallergenic out a hip and
waterproof so and you think it's the
culture that didn't accept it or do you
think it's the powers-that-be that stood
to lose
so much they didn't allow the
infrastructure to really let me let me
answer that directly yeah culture
dictates everything we will if what we
will not accept we have to stand up
together and they could change it has
one right the problem and I see in the
country right now especially is that we
are so bifurcated we are so divisive
from our political stance let's come
together on a plan that you know hemp
industrial has hemp right is the gift
from God and it remediates the soil it
removes more co2 than a tree it produces
better fiber better paper our
Constitution is written on it so if you
can't get behind that heck that's
anti-american not free to grow hemp
though interesting not in our state you
know and we come from Texas we hail from
the great state of Texas as you know and
we are still not able to grow our own
hemp and what we're really nervous about
is that industrial hemp will push out
the medical and the CVD well I
this past 18 months or past year 2019 I
traveled to 68 cities and 19 countries
building a manifest of each individual
industrial or hemp CBD THC minor
cannabinoid markets and where the
culture and regulations and everything
was gonna be this is gonna shock you and
probably a lot of people that are
watching a podcast but the future of
cultivation of of hemp for a refined
cannabinoid production will in my
opinion cease to exist in the United
States in the next four years the
economic advantages of Labor rates that
are achievable in countries like
Colombia or Mexico for two examples in
the Western Hemisphere simply will
follow the commoditization that's taking
place in many agricultural products such
as fresh-cut flowers or sugarcane we
don't go into this country because the
difference between the longest and
shortest day in Colombia is 41 minutes
so the northern hemisphere simply can't
compete with that
many psycho ability is that for the
moral crops of hemp a year out door of
three maybe four to five
Negroes relentlessly and if you find it
relentless plan God thank God and if
with a climate control it and the
institutional type of capital that's
been invested in these countries because
they already recognize that it's only
going to go one way
you got a forecast for CBD isolates and
isolated molecule to be trading at a
hundred dollars a kilo in the future
just like sugar I mean you guys you got
to think about that three years ago we
were selling at eighteen five twelve
five that next year sixty five hundred
last year I'm selling it for fifteen
hundred bucks right now so just see BCD
Iceland and so industrials on the future
of the industry in the United States
is short-lived you and you turn on
institutions like Mexico which already
have you know agricultural producers
with 20 straight kilometers of
established greenhouse they can just
take okay well we'll call her out this
mile
amazing I mean I hear that and I totally
I see that but what what say you about
the smokeable hemp
that's really a that is a concern that
the smokeable hemp flour will be banned
hence you know kind of paving the way to
ban any smokeable flour of any sort in
Texas it's very strange and this is kind
of a land that we're living in so you
know the the the reason that the United
States has really lost this battle is
because we are so bifurcated our state
laws that say you know I'm going to do
this and I'm gonna do that in Texas
unfortunately is suffering from that
exact consequence when we launched the
state system in Washington they were bro
I mean we literally set up the track and
trace office in the welc be and so
unless Texas they shouldn't ban that
because there's
medicinal purposes and actually
smokeable hemp is probably the only sub
facet of the industry that will survive
in the United States because the
importation of hemp flour for smoking
purpose that will be refined to that
nature will not come from those
importing they'll get a refine into an
isolated or distillate or you know
easily ship container so right there's
something to be said for you know local
flower artisan flower yes you know their
marijuana flower that we love so much
you know because you put yourself into
growing the plant yeah it really is a
reflection of how much you can't no I
wouldn't spray flower coming out of
Mexican right right right like you know
right no no but you know the isolate you
know who fucking knows you cares this is
this is all sort of future thinking
right like this is what will what what
is stopping that from becoming that
reality like are there still any staff
gaps now that are like hurting him fully
coming online industrially so industrial
hemp let's classify the two here the
dust real hemp production cultivation of
hemp for industrial purposes versus
refined canister whether it be minors or
CBD industrial hemp will survive the
United States but the United States is
very far behind in building the key
linchpin which is the production or
never extraction I'm sorry the
processing facilities to make it into
fibers to make it into you know usable
textiles that we can develop and and and
replace cotton or replace infrastructure
it's a new yeah and and so there's a
couple different really forward-thinking
states that are taking like industrial
waste sites and they're planting
hairline and that's perfect for you know
put on your body instilling toxic waste
yeah
planet at Fukushima it takes radiation
of the ground Wow this is the best this
is here to save our world I'm telling
you this is it's here to free the people
it's here to reverse this negative
paradigm that we've been demonizing
plant-based medicines right it's here to
elevate our consciousness you know free
us from PTSD remove information our body
help us with our neurological diseases
the depriving of the endocannabinoid
States government's have done yeah it's
like ripped from think about it in the
United States the corporate agenda to
feed us food that makes us sick treat us
with a few of those ailments not cure
them feed us more medicines to treat the
symptoms of those medicines and
eventually we rot away and die you know
unless you're conscious of that make
your own choices
and that's what I want to inspire with
these shoes we are here to inspire the
embrace people to embrace industrialized
Hamady and revolutions coming your style
through comfort yes through a lifestyle
brand that's going to move into some
other categories of niche that that are
like you know accent pieces yes make
sense it does it makes perfect sense
there are accent pieces and they're more
than that I mean they're they're true
true pieces of self-expression
it's not just oh I'm loud I'm flashy
Here I am it's also you know that that I
care I've made a commitment to you know
this planet to making one plant based
decision right because even if you buy
them because you think they're fly as I
love them you're making that decision to
give the consumers a choice of four
charities from the Amazon to the ocean
to the United States of choices they can
donate a portion of each sale to Wow
they've mail is back the postcard tell
us what you want so real quick oh we
skipped over it but what is the
Instagram handle fly soul shoes
soul like your soul you gotta gotta have
a little fly soul decayed off you know
so not sol ESO shoes so back to the the
endocannabinoid system and the
deficiencies I'm seeing some studies
that are just coming out on migraines
ADHD things of this letters Alzheimer's
there now there now pointing to
endocannabinoid deficiencies as the
premise of these issues fun fun fact is
CBD or the cannabinoids themselves your
endocannabinoid system but the CBD
specifically is I believe the only thing
we found that can actually go in and
remove the plaque from the brain that
leads to Alzheimer's so getting back to
what a miracle it actually is this plant
is fucking amazing
yeah I mean it does so much for so many
people there's over a five percent
variance in its DNA content from plant
that is a broad range there's like a not
there's like a point three percent or
less darienne's between you and a
chimpanzee think about that for a minute
think about how long it's been around
genetically you know modified itself
yeah hmm that's why you know plant the
same genetic at sea level versus
eighteen hundred meters you could have a
completely different every microclimate
come out differently you know you can't
take genetics from Canada and plant in
Jamaica they think you can though a lot
of people fucking yeah well I've ruined
Jamaica
you just have to making gold let's talk
about that we were all in Jamaica yeah
we're you and Jamaica yeah
there's a sneaky little guy though you
gotta yeah I don't know where to find
them
yeah I know where to find them we're not
gonna let you go so let's talk about
Jamaica and what's happening there and
all of the new strains cropping up and
Canadian money flowing in and what the
fuck's going on well in 2015 bio track
where I was the CIO CFO of designed and
implemented the track and trace for the
University of West Indies and university
technology in Kingston and we passed and
wrote the law and Minister Paul well to
legalize the possession of cannabis on
the island up to two ounces we thought
they were on the fast track to becoming
a very successful country at that point
but Jamaica has a cultural hurdle to get
over by which there's a lot of greed in
there everybody wants it and the pride
of Jamaica has cost them the Opera is
you tender and really be because the
branding of Jamaica was you know come to
Jamaica get on our beaches it was
branded notion we went when we were
there once we welcome
I saw something slide down the slide
that I
oh yeah you know put your making hats on
still regulated their program to a
medical so in other words severe
tourists you have to go into a place and
fly to a doctor's say right you know
just forget I did my medical care ok
with it yeah of course Leo has her
medical card in Jamaica but um you know
the industry on over the past decade a
great friend of mine dr. Darryl Hudson
there's a world-renowned
PhD in this industry in Canada outside
of Toronto has been studying the
cannabinoid contents and THC levels of
Jamaican candidates for over a decade in
Jamaica they have a wellness retreat
in Jamaica as well psychedelic research
ayahuasca available and so over the past
decade
Jemaine Gould had a certain THC and
you'd find you you know in various areas
of that people have been introducing CBD
and hemp into the island and not
understanding and this is part of a
classic example of Jamaican arrogance
that is costing them everything is that
they've been smuggling it in planting it
and not pulling the mails and it's been
pollinating the entire island and so
there used to be no CBD on Jamaica no
CBD in there strands now it's a one run
off everywhere and as our lambs breath
went I mean is that what basically yeah
I think I mean it just diluted diluted
alluded to the you're on an island right
got it you know unless you're going
through your field and pulling your
nails right your that's not everybody
right that's not their way of I mean
their will but that was it so when we
were in Canada in Jamaica I don't know
if one geneticist panel of dr. Darryl
Hudson was on the panel said you know
and it was almost like very few yeah you
know after all these conferences that
was best because he came up he said
Jamaica is about combining all the we've
mastered and that's shipping out and he
doesn't understand
that's not what the industry is about
it's not about smashing your weed
together it's about refining our art of
what we can create to help people it's
not really about getting high
the secret is if you know everybody
likes this phone get high I love it but
it's really about what we can do to
change the planet and and help humanity
become this is a gateway drug to health
and happiness 100% because you can't not
think about the other decisions that you
make on a daily basis when you're stress
all those levels down and you're in
communion with a plant you start
thinking about things that are real well
literally aids with homeostasis right it
levels out every system in your body and
that I mean is a huge but even at a
societal level you see what we're doing
right now
have you ever super like you know
anybody like don't go fight Yeah right
right more you know you share kindness
you know you express ideas you know in
vulnerabilities you know in a space that
we you know oh my god this is life this
is being recorded
you know it's hardcore recorded and
we're doing something big with this
conversation right now
but yet I don't feel encumbered by you
know like fears of like looking like an
idiot with you guys you know because
we've shared this button together you
know so I encourage people to smoke on
the street you guys it yeah because I
want people to smell it I want people to
be familiar with their kids so
California now I'm you might already be
aware of this but very recently there's
only five if you have a doctor's
recommendation there's only five places
you can't smoke in the state of
California in public and it's I mean you
got to look at the pot brothers a lot
yeah
within like the best the but yeah
operating a boat is one of the places in
public that you can't smoke within
operating a boat yeah in a vehicle that
is operating and within so many feet of
a school and there's two others I would
use it but that's why I really have made
more of a transition away from the
regulated THC market here in California
and letting the dust settle I mean you
know I'm gonna give you some truth right
now the regulated market is surviving
because they're participating in both
sides and you know 80 percent of the
legal market in California is black
market probably yeah and no no in the
legal dispensary market yeah that is a
chain of custody which only legal
product tested product makes I did too
they're talking about are more robust
even existing in LA black market
dispensary right that they are selling
their access products they're producing
of their own facilities labeled in and
who just put it in the market and you
know listen can't really blame us to be
honest with you because not the taxation
system the state of California you know
I remember I was at in 2015 the first
Department of Taxation hearing on how to
design the track and trade system at
that point you know we try to give the
state an idea of listen you can't fort
the industry you have to give taxation
at various levels we had reconstructed
the taxation code for Washington because
they had learned this lesson alright and
you felt they were on board but as well
you know this was early this is 2015 so
right by the time it really got handed
down so many more influencers had come
in to try different techniques to really
get the state what they did is really
screwed themselves because
they were to actually provide the
industry especially in the beginning a
little less of a taxation or actually a
significantly less taxation and tax in a
different model associated with
production at various lifecycle changes
of the change of custody they would have
made a lot more money instead they have
made it literally or nearly impossible
and especially in LA is a tragic example
to make money in an illegal market it's
just you know why would I buy an eighth
of cannabis at $75 when I can go next
maps and for 25 1992 pricing yes 2020
okay so walk us through the track and
trace a little bit so for those that
don't understand what's been rolled out
or what what is you know up your sleeve
when it comes to that well in order to
provide a closed-loop economic system
for an agriculturally tract product you
need to make sure that there's no
illegal or listen inventory coming in
and out of right you need to make sure
that you're not having money laundering
taking place you need to make sure that
you're not delivering this regulated
commodity to people that shouldn't get
it like children and so really know what
that means is that you need to have
unlike any other agricultural product a
track and trace down to the gram for
cannabis so when Washington went live 37
country companies bid on the RFP for
track and trade software program for the
governmental regulatory system bio track
THC which is based in Fort Lauderdale
won that bid and during the
implementation of that we you know
learned a lot about you know what
taxation models were you know
you know how to not allow monopolization
or you know big corporate interest just
to own the whole market you know it was
the beginning of the industry so track
and trace is literally quintessentially
important for the opening of
international trade right so one day we
will have a federal legal system one day
we will be able to export California
branded cannabis because California
branded cannabis is the best in the
world but I'm saying this and it has a
premium all around the world give me
give me a little insight on how it's
even traceable down to the ground so
there's a couple different techniques to
do it that are implemented right now in
the United States rfid tagging radio
frequency identification is implemented
by bio tracks largest competitor and the
winner of the city California contract
called metric and that is a company
called Fran wall decor which really
developed the system to track cabbage
it's really inaccurate I wrote a paper
in 2016 of 16 different ways you can
sneak pounds out the back door right
they bungee when so when Colorado and
Washington went live bio track when
Washington metric won Colorado and you
know it's been a learning process for
both companies since and a battle of
who's gonna get the next state contract
California was a beast like no other
because it's the fifth largest economy
in the world you know sixty percent of
the cannabis in the world is grown here
it is might be an under estimate of and
so and it's huge
so trying to regulate an existing market
versus something that was coming on is
proving to be more comes from than
attract and trade system and anyone that
exists in my opinion really can handle
but metric has an rfid tagging system
the answer your question and you just
scan your RFID reader but in Colorado we
saw an example of an example of just
being in a box and scan the box and
you're growing eight rooms you're not
reporting and that's gonna happen with
the system so why why is cannabis why is
it a necessity to track to that level
because it's a gradual one regulated
drug right so it's like I mean if we
ditch that let's let's first off it
enables a government that tagged
something like let's get so we if we if
we drops down to schedule five as hemp
has what what game-changer is that do we
now get to consume lemon extract the
same as cannabis extract because it's no
longer Schedule one like is that there
is that there hook in the fish is that
Schedule one classification that's a
part of the book the other side of the
book is
[Music]
so that's the reason it's not a safety
issue it's not it there's no other play
that's what they're good
you know safety plays a part in it you
know if we're gonna give medicine to
people let's make sure it doesn't make
them sick I mean that makes sense right
I would like to smoke regularly tested
preferably outdoor but for hundreds of
years millions of people have smoked
cannabis grown in the hills by hippies
that don't wash their hands yeah without
my fact the industry when what we're
talking about earlier two thousand
twelve two thousand when the first money
really came in and we're starting we
started looking at this new horizon of
cannabis well you know you know pioneers
in the industry in Colorado like Norton
ablaze and lost audience of green
horizon and affordably of Mehta and
Massachusetts and they founded River
Rock in Colorado 2009 you know these
guys were I really like the heroes of
the industry Norton was recently in the
National Geographic about a struggle
about how you know for a legal
standpoint they attackin to attorneys
that you know believe so heavily in
plant medicine that you know they took a
you know everything they had to you know
really provide a legal evidence and
efficacy for undeniable fact this
medicine this makes you better
this is in Colorado Colorado in the US
and so did you know that's really what I
think that you know Colorado was really
the really
besides in California I mean they made a
medical in 98 but Colorado bites
beginning to track it and ready to do
that came to a level where now we can
tax it and now we can pay the IRS income
tax yeah now you have a federally
regulated system and eventually we'll be
able to export our cannabis right and
the United States will have a THC
Revolution right now but that has to be
trackable at each point of the process
right raw material extract the material
finished product because if there's a
recall you need to be able to find out
where it came from
yeah I guess that's the root of it right
yeah there's no there's a most advanced
system that I've come across after all
of the track and trade systems that I've
looked at from Switzerland sick-sick / -
you know what exists in the mind places
now is this some gold backbone
there's same guys that build QuickBooks
and and that's weak sort of - or -
they've come in with a real ERP that
gives you just a lifecycle dashboard
where it stands through the entire life
I love your passion is it's so like it's
hard not to just like get fired up being
around it and like like I think you you
um you've got such a an amazing depth
and knowledge for this and you're fired
up about it I would love to know what is
sort of your future like your ideal
future like what does it look like for
America and this and this hemp game in
this and really the kid the cannabis you
know revolution baby well I was working
for that law firm until my birthday in
August and I resigned to launch the shoe
company so I'm very focused on this my
sole shoes
since we don't take it white man should
be quite honest I don't serve that
company best as the CEO or even a
c-level executive I'm best as you know
being on the road and you explained that
my vibe it's so live spreader yeah
former executive vice president of Nike
for past 13 years to any twice gamma
unit CEO and I built a team of all my
friends in the cannabis industry so
we're a team of passionate people for it
and we're gonna make that happen but I
accepted the role as the global
expansion officer for green horizon
California we are building a million
square foot cultivation facility in
Coachella and launching a brand called
natural States and for CBD and hemp
products of many many different
categories in 23 countries in the next
24 months and so I'll be launching the
first beauty CDE health and wellness
woman facing line in Harrods in London
September quarter and edible line in
Japan and culturing each product by the
geography in this window can can I get
some of those edibles or do I gotta
import that the woman is really the
decision-maker what women are much
better leaders than we are we just had
this guy last week you know so it's like
it's so obvious you know and so the
sooner we can get out of male-dominated
society the better will be my opinion
so Hillary no Bernie
never loves that guy cannabis on
Instagram I got this I was a swimmer I
was a competitive swimmer I got his
jacket in sixth grade I got it big yeah
intention he was that smart as a
six-year-old and so this is si si an
injury school it's a yeah my mother was
a flight attendant for 42 years
and she would fly to commute to Chicago
to fly to China to fly back commute home
and then work a second child to pay for
me to go to this private school and so
my life goal is taking care and this
this this past January are you because
they believe shit
I drove every little possession across
the country moved her into the building
next door was that her official
retirement was she working up until you
you snatched her up
yeah so tell us about some speaking
engagements you have coming up or you
know things that are so green horizon is
the entry for the health of your family
to enter the industry nice tummy and is
our co-founder and so his daughter and I
are going to be touring certain
locations in Europe and Asia and South
America and Central America and the
United States really conveying the
message of how this plant can help oh
let her speak about her story but she's
written a book there's a New York Times
bestseller called bite me about her
battle with Lyme disease oh sweet but
we've developed a medicine involving
cannabinoids I was treating it that's
really like you're such a Renaissance
man
you know you are you're touching so many
pieces of this plant in these industries
you know I'm if you could pick one you
could just pick one thing what would it
be industrial hub and what well I can't
it just kind of dawned on me you know
last night when we were prepping for
this it's like oh wait a minute
it's my podcast I can ask whatever
yes because they're so curious you know
about you know people who are truly
changing this industry changing the way
we are conscious about hemp in this
plant and marijuana and fashion you know
I mean it's just it's a cooler way to be
I mean you know when you're in line with
though it's good for the whole and not
just yourself don't maybe a better idea
you know life is not about you it's
about altruism it's about loving the
common man and not expecting anything in
return
doing it for the love master hippie you
know yeah I practice plan Edison I
practice ayahuasca you know I get in
touch and talk to God as much as I
possibly can I live by God's justice and
hemp is God's justice man I'm telling
you right now do you think it's possible
to like what does the campaign have to
be how do we keep convincing people to
buy him um you know it starts in a
couple different levels I mean obviously
rocking these mother and putting on the
hemp
I hear you universe you know you got to
make it cool you know you got to make it
something you identify with somebody
looks down he's like damn and then then
you say wow it's made it a hemp they're
like okay you ever had the reaction to
these that do that they're not cool
don't not once not once I've seen the
reaction I walked around in a show once
that when it told me I just made it for
myself I found a little town in Mexico
and I make these with a family that's a
fifth-generation cobbler and this is my
very first pair I made and I was walking
around in it dude these are and I just
made it for myself it's a game changer
and I got stopped 27 times in one day
what are those shoes from I was like
maybe I should do something what what
how long my grandmother died in June 4th
and that's I was running on the beaches
of Tel Aviv serving the purpose of this
law firm that I had no interest in and I
couldn't get home take care of my mom I
said you know what I got to do this and
I said I'm gonna take the shoes I design
let's start a business
June 4th it's been a long time coming
tell you totally fulfilled all of my
preconceived notions mmm stories and you
know little things that I've seen in
social in here and there and you know
your name is Peter but I feel like you
know you're kind of a J Peterman figure
you're this man who you know on Seinfeld
and yes you're like this J Peterman
figure who is who's gone all over the
earth who is just he's altruistic he's
there for common man and he's there for
his fellow man and he wants to make the
world a better place and so he's
bringing back these beautiful shoes or
this event that you put between your
teeth and you feel that you know I'm
just like you're like the Explorer that
brings back little gifts for us yes I
gave up the direction of my life to God
when we started practicing ayahuasca and
it's been very ups and downs but I was
fortunate enough to serve the fortune
500 law firm of Zuber Lawler and be the
director of the hands
practice and when you move out of the
suitcase for 18 months and travel 25
days a month I mean awesome people you
realize that the things that people
value like cars and like you know
possessions and even real estate
probably don't matter it's a fallacy
even money is a fallacy my opinion it's
something that's been created by society
that really doesn't have truth what is
now you agree that there's value is the
only reason there is value yes you know
what the most powerful and valuable
currency there is it's your effect on
others with that you can change the
world and so money is the placation of
our weakness they do have the importance
of it in life
yeah is the vacation of our weakness
it's another shirt that's certain 13
today because you know we're talking
about veganism and we're talking about
you know how to live a more plant-based
life recently and you know we're weak
and we have to placate that by oh it's
my mom she's in a little more mom oh
this is great yes hi mom
hey mom I'm doing a podcast on my
balcony right now and you're on
speakerphone say hi I'm doing a podcast
on my balcony right now being filmed in
video and you're on speakerphone in
front of everybody right now say hi
hello hi and welcome to the green house
podcast how you doing tonight I'm I'm
living my best life I'm hanging out with
your son he's he's an angel he's an
angel from heaven that's my assessment
as a Texan we're talking about the
cannabis industry moving to Texas and
hoping that it happens sooner rather
than later
you're so wonderful um and take Tommy
for a walk it felt really good really
good doesn't work does it work No
hey she's got a you know she's living
her best life it sounds oh yeah how we
looking oh man we're great we're great I
wanted to do one thing before before we
move we move on in this phase is I would
love to know just the you know what tell
me about the shoes longevity does it
break apart I mean cuz all you hear
about is hampers stronger than
everything did and fuckin I'm telling
you like and I'm part of it I fucking
breathe it I know it but I have had I
have no practical knowledge of it so is
it like is it is it is it as badass as
people saying well it's if it really is
man it's waterproof so it repels things
its antifungal so it's not gonna get
stinky its antimicrobial so it's not
gonna have stopped growing off your feet
I found a company hand heel that is
making the soles at a hemp seed and so
I'm gonna try and make one the sole
planet hemp plant will come out
biodegradable but the future when you
wear it out you plant your shoes and a
hemp plant okay now how does how does he
how does this how does one make rubber
from said plant so they they make a they
take the hemp seed and they take
recycled PVC tubing and they melt it
down and tada
now what the the addition of the hemp
seed is my idea how long we'll get into
details I got a couple I got a couple of
you're gonna make improvements coming
the shoe that's
I just want to know when the ladies
comes out oh yeah slip-ons and these are
just my you know shoes you came to my
house and I had guys look at my shoes
much better than having my own pair I'm
actually like playing with your pairs I
actually put some on because I was gonna
wear them and then I remembered like oh
it's a podcast like my feet hey you know
what before we go though I really want
to thank you guys because what you're
doing is educating and spreading the
changing the way people receive this
message you have such a brave lots of
responsibility here because you're going
to have wide visibility you can have
people that didn't intentionally mean to
see your podcast see your podcast so
bring them people of value bring them
education
please don't accentuate the perpetuation
of the culture which demonizes the plant
or you know puts girls in bikinis and
thongs they love that that's all that
that's not what it's about
this is not about me you know I love
getting high and I love it I appreciate
all subscibers of it yeah but let's
raise our butt notches and achim using
sports cars let's raise our collective
and we're close to it we're close to it
and I feel like we were on those we're
all all of us at this table are on are
reaching for that light we are and we're
reaching out Department right now you
know thank you
we're in the light here literally thank
you so much for being on the podcast and
we look forward to having you back and
we look forward to checking in and and
keeping up with you this has been so so
informational and good luck with
everything you're doing thank you
I'm retired
[Music]