hey peter so we're in my kitchen
and we've got the the guys from grow
magazine
it's bear and pk nice to meet you guys
and then eric uh eric snug shots
and candid cush chris from candid kush
how's it going
what's up chris and then yours truly
and jordan is coming on in and jordan's
daughter is here haley
and her daughter who is a very adorable
one-year-old named aurora and
my wife and my daughter and
it's sunday morning family time
i love it say hi hi
how are you
i used to take baths like that
we just can't like amber my wife just
canned like 20 lugs of peaches or
something like that
oh wow so we made peaches
and we're we're also
um going through all these different
phenotypes uh freak show
super freak and there's there's jordan
who you spoke there he is
what's up man vape shifter i i'm in my
garage right now with like
horse flies flying around me and it's
like 100 and something degrees
we're skating the heat somehow up here
it's kind of perfect right now
yeah there's a little bit of um wildfire
going on
so oh wow
there's a little bit of smoke smoky haze
in the air
around us we have a hat a half canned
jar of peach jam on the table and i love
it you got you got
yeah you're uh this is all from the
garden you got some
some flowers some peaches you're
making some jam does everybody get to go
home with jam at the end of the day
that was my plan i still have to talk to
my wife about it though
so you grew up
a bunch of different uh
freak show plants and now
so so you've harvested so does that
imply you did a light depth
uh so
these um these different freak show
phenotypes this is an f7
f7 and uh
they're these are
are obviously seem very fresh and nice
so this was this like light yeah i just
got them and they're disturbing
right now they're beautiful some of them
the minute i was able to get it yeah so
i'm gonna cure it
later so these are these beautiful
uh freak show seeds
and they as as the plant is
they are very unique and
they often they remind me a lot of
korean
um i don't know if folks know but if
you've ever grown
cilantro and and had it uh
go to flower that yeah hold on
actually give me one second
because i got my uh zipper
you've got some coriander there so here
here are freak show seeds and we can
compare
so that people can see the
the likeness of the freakshow meat and
the coriander seed
because jordan tell me if you agree but
i also feel that they
that these freak show seeds are
more rounded than
cannabis seeds
you know and people always say to us
they're immature and they kind of get
upset
sometimes when they first get their
freak show seed packed
and and we've tried a number of times
to explain in fact jordan even made a
video that kind of shows
that yeah there's a but but they're
always like this no matter how
long we let them mature on the vine
there's no way that you can get them to
be
uh darker or you know to look
differently this will show us right
[Music]
one second
okay so what is that so these ones
still have the the very skin
shroud it's sort of a it's a paper thin
uh coating that that cannabis seeds have
that are
you know it's it's where the tiger
stripes often
are found on cannabis seeds and and
about freak show seeds that's different
is that that that coating
that gives them their unique look uh the
different tiger stride
patterns the model looks of all
different types of cannabis seeds
the thing about freak show is that that
that
shroud is actually thinner
and detached so it it is more readily
brushed off by the seed sorting process
and and it doesn't uh weaken the seed or
damage
the actual viability of the seed at all
but it does certainly make it look
different and i would say
more like coriander right
say hi sure we've got a few different
guests here today with us
it just happened especially
the nat pennington show was special
guest all right who
who's up first that's this is eric
eric what's up how's it going
good and you lit do you live in the bay
area or are you up in oregon
no i'm i'm up in bend oregon okay got it
yeah yeah
so so you guys are doing a photo shoot
for
uh what was it grow magazine
well we were it might grow magazine but
we're uh
ideally yeah we were doing i was doing
some uh
it was raspberry parfait
yeah there's the last one i did for
grove magazine
hey there we go so we're doing a stack
spin of uh some raspberry parfaits and
seeds
down inside like actually still in the
plant
so um should be super cool i
haven't processed it down yet but it was
like
shooting started at like nine or ten
o'clock at night it was shooting until
uh
about five in the morning
so it was an all night shoot and what
was the reason why you did it at night
uh well so it we did it at night so it
was uh not super hot
uh it had to go all night because it's
basically
it's i don't know the total of pictures
like
crunch numbers but it was probably like
8 000 pictures
um because we're doing it's a 360 so the
camera will move
0.5 degrees between each shot
and then uh at each stage it's basically
taking
uh 55 different pictures for this one
so i can stack it together and get more
depth out of uh out of the frame
and and what are you shooting on are you
shooting on like uh
like a cannon with a hundred millimeter
lens or what what's the rig
uh yeah this one is it's a canon 5d sr
so 50 megapixels uh shooting with the
the canon mpe
65 millimeter uh dedicated map
1x to 5x um and that one last night it
was at about two and a half x
were you taking the pictures out in the
field or or just
inside with like a perfect uh setup like
a controlled environment or
yeah controlled environment yeah we uh
we took over the uh the document storage
closet
uh here on the farm and
uh and set up the rig in there um so we
can
control the uh the wind any airflow
ideally any vibration um
and uh yeah so we take take the stock
out of the garden
put it in there so we control the
environment the lighting um
and control yeah try and control
everything
almost controlled it tickled bummer
so and you did i mean that that's the
the cover of grow magazine with freak
show on it
so talk about um like it's obviously a
unique and
interesting plant like talk about
freak show but also just talk about some
other
you know interesting plants you've come
across
in your journeys of macro photography
or photography in general because some
of this stuff's not macro but
yeah well i mean just i mean interesting
plants you've met
free show's the craziest looking as far
as leaf morphology goes
but when you get up close on freak show
it's still
just you know trichomes everywhere yes
but it's you know it's just a standard
cannabis plant when you get up close on
it it's just a different
shape um which is super fascinating to
me
um and then as far as like
weird weird unique interesting plants um
a lot of the purple stuff i've been
shooting lately with the
pinks inside the trichome heads super
fascinated by that
um it's kind of a rare trait that
doesn't really pop up too often
but uh that was on the uh the star pupil
i was shooting there and uh yeah just
anything super unique i'm like drawn
towards so i want to
want to shoot some more of uh the
freakshop you know
super tasty ones that we've been trying
over the weekend here
when you've done close-ups of the
trichomes is is it
different or is it just kind of similar
to other like at that close-up level
yeah well yeah we're going to catch all
of that we have
i have been hearing some stories of some
crazy trichome stuff that's going on on
the pre-shows uh
at shapeshifters farm but uh i haven't
shot him yet so that's that's gonna
happen this later this year but uh
as far as the macros of the freakshow
i've done so far the trichomes look
the same they're pretty much standard um
just normal normal looking strikes which
is pretty much standard across all
cannabis
it's just some have like longer stocks
or thicker stocks or
smaller heads bigger heads different
colors going on
i did recently photograph um a mac one
uh strain and um i found on this one
particular cut
a it's almost like a snailed eyed
trichome i have
no idea if this will come through if you
can see it
in the middle or not yeah yeah so you
see that one right in the middle
yeah it's like a snake tongue
yeah and then on the same exact plant
i found this other section this is gonna
be a little harder to see because it's a
little
bit darker yeah
um but there's just like this wild
looking trichome formation
and actually when you start looking
around more and more
into this frame there's like
you know double-headed ones next to
triple headed ones
next to real fat stocks
next to this other weird looking droopy
one down in the corner
and this was like very recent work um
not even published i just captured it
just a couple weeks ago actually
um so i have that cut drying
and then i'll revisit it um as
it's finished and see like what those
trek homes look like there
that's probably the weirdest thing i've
seen yeah that's definitely i've never
seen anything like that
like i've seen double headed trichomes
and double stock strike them but
that thing is a straight mutation
and like the the cola of the flower
also didn't look like normal
i i don't know really how to describe
did i show you pictures i don't have any
pictures of it with me
but it didn't have like the traditional
type of like uh
christmas tree cone top it was more like
weird sugary kind of swirly formations
and stuff on there so
weird pretty interesting stuff
when you talk i mean because i know like
you know
hash makers look for certain things in
the trichome
so what like
when you when you do a macro of kind of
a hashy
plant that's desirable to hash makers
kind of
what are you noticing that's different
than something that
maybe would be the opposite where
they're like that's not really what i'm
looking for
i mean so i i don't know i
i'm not a hashmaker i have a rudimentary
understanding
i mean i i don't know
i haven't noticed a ton of differences
like if you shoot a classically
hash strain versus a non-hash strain as
far as
like what the trichomes look like um
classic hashtags usually have like a lot
more trichomes
on them um and another thing a lot of
people
that i've heard search for is short
stocks
but as far as like just if you took a
two macros and one's a hash train and
one's not a hash strain
i don't think you'd be able to tell the
difference by looking at the
actual heads themselves but i don't know
that's an interesting one i i think
something that
uh probably is hard to sort of like
quantify about hash making
is how easily the
the stalks will break off and allow
the bulbous trichome head to
sort of detach because a lot of you know
what you
see in think of like the full metal hash
and the really light colored
hatch that's you know off uh
you know live live bubble hash basically
or
fresh frozen bubble hatch
those those are really not
a lot of stalk material it's really just
the head
that you're capturing and so i think
that's a factor
of like what makes a good uh
strain that sort of just dumps trichome
heads
is takes a good half strain there's
another thing
called the uh that started starting to
pop up recently
and another photographer schwall is the
one that kind of
spotted it but uh he calls it the weak
neck
trichome and if you try going from the
direct side you can kind of see the head
is like
up off of the stock a little bit and you
can see this like really it's like a one
cell
kind of attachment point you can just
clearly see it's just barely hanging on
yeah it's gonna snap off yeah with
little effort
ideally you want to snap it off but the
to be able to
see a trichome from exactly that angle
is really tough so if you
shoot a whole leaf and you've got
hundreds of trichomes
in the frame you know maybe
10 or 15 will be at that exact side
angle
or maybe potentially a little bit more
but
yeah and then also um
just like the thickness of the gland
it's a little i think
challenging to see like through pictures
but yeah you definitely notice like when
you break up different
um cultivars with if the weed feels like
sticky or greasy
or like more powdery and sandy yeah and
then
that ideal for right patch making
um if the head's more resilient it's
gonna survive the
process a lot but you don't want to be
too thick because then there'd be less
total cannabinoids within the gland like
the thickness of
that's like a conversation i've had with
extractors i've heard that conversation
too but i don't know if it's like i
literally heard it on a podcast driving
up here i don't know i didn't fully
agree with it because
it's there's so much resin and it's just
a small
so tiny yeah it's gonna be super thin i
don't think it's taking away
that much resin if the head's thicker
but then again i have no idea
danielson and mr miyagi debated the same
thing
so so peter i'm really glad that you you
know
caught us here on this very laid-back
casual uh meeting of the mines up here
at our anchor farm in eastern humble
um this is where humboldt seed company
really
you know got going and uh
it's it's awesome to have shapeshifter
who created the freak show strain here
and these amazing photographers
and then we've got the guys from grow
magazine
who are you know this is eric's
photography right here on on the cover
of the magazine and of course the
yeah the famous freakshow
but here are the guys just to give you
an idea of what we're up to
we've been oh that's just gorgeous
look at that look at that center fold
oh yeah we gotta anger
[Laughter]
pretty cool well it's it takes uh a
village
and and so guy here is is working on
some freak show right now
actually and this is the mountain the
mountain cabin
that is a humboldt seed company uh
kind of headquartered whatever
so so so is he getting that ready to
roll a bunch of joints that you guys are
gonna smoke or
what's he uh prepping for we're also
getting all of the seeds so here's
pk and it's basically it's a taste
go ahead you tell them it's a taste test
yeah um
i got all of them sitting here seeded
and i did a bunch of fingers light
seeded so
we could still taste it uh so it sends a
meal with the light seed
to it and we have it um and we're gonna
i've narrowed this down to these five
and
there you go that's our job today is you
know
i'm using these guys as guinea pigs
so so talk about kind of the subtle
differences between the five
uh you know the only major difference is
the terpenes and just the flavor
because i nailed down actually locked in
a whole bunch of other
qualities with freakshow um just nailing
the leaf morphology right off the get-go
you know i didn't expect anything to be
stable in other ways but
yeah i've gotten to the point in my
breeding where i'll go ahead
and uh try to nail two or three
qualities just in one reading but that's
why
i started out with 120 phoenix uh
recently and then i i doubled out my
choice of 30
and we've narrowed it down to five here
now so
uh there you go that's our job now is to
go outside and uh
spark it up so awesome nat nat
can can we can we uh can you lend your
your uh palette can you can you take a
whiff of one of those and tell me uh
i have to describe it i've been loving
like the number 29 it's one that i've
been really
digging uh i don't know if you can see
this but i've already kind of gave
them little preliminary judgments you
know when i was
first throwing them in the bag and uh
some of them didn't make the cut i'm
like well
i'm not interested in you and but yeah
these these last five
are gonna get uh kind of go on the
market limited maybe two right now
yeah well you know basically the i
the criteria of course
for uh freak show
you know it's most well known for its
amazing and very unique leaf
shape but what a lot of people don't
realize
is that there are some incredibly unique
uh and original tri um
turpins that that freaks
the freak show strain actually produces
very
unique terpenes and so
now we kind of feel like our next job
or you know is really getting
what we consider to be the most
powerful terp and the most pleasant
turpin
well so so what are some of the unique
terpenes because i know
jordan when we spoke the other day i
mean not not in freak show
but you were talking about something you
smoked a long time ago
that i believe was thai that had like a
distinct chocolate
smell to it that you know is just not
something you can find now
um so what what's kind of the unique
terpene profile i mean have you isolated
what that
terpene or those that combination of
terpenes are
that give it its uniqueness yeah i was
telling that a while ago
that um like this generation is where
i'm kind of pulling together all of the
flavors i mean
no one could really nail it down to one
and we don't want to do that anyway
because
everybody kind of likes a different goal
of things and
the honest truth on this is i i probably
have 50 different types of freak show
right now because
that's how i am and that's how i do it
and i don't want to limit myself or
bottleneck
things and and just the fact that freak
show has such an
unlimited like ability to morph just
so it's i mean i'm going in different
directions on
leaf morphologies what he's asking is
the flavors
okay the original which we also have
here the holy express
which is one of the parent stock the
other ones uh
the holy express was the original and i
have that here
and so this is like three generations
deep on a sesquiterpene line that i'm
looking at the kind that hangs in your
sinuses
as you're walking out the door and you
get busy because it's sativa and it got
you out of your chair and you're jamming
and you're like still smelling it in
your head well
to me that's one of the most rarest kind
of genes that's been getting knocked out
in the last you know 20 years of time
and you know there's still
really nice melon wheat out there
there's all kinds of
fairly tasty way but it all seems to be
getting kind of homogenous
well i'm going back to those ones that
remind me of the old days
when an old dude says man that takes me
right back to 1968 or something you know
what imported we that have that really
weird smell up the house too
it's all about the quote sativa the
narrow leaf drug tropical
has always been my bag and you know
everyone's like
you know against me like people almost
like hate sativa for all these years
it's really true but wow
[Laughter]
are are you in a room full of haters
right now
no no the times have changed and i don't
hate indicate anymore
yeah we're you know one thing peter
that's been really interesting
about having like the honor
of being the group that got to
you know sort of mass produced and
and come come forward with shapeshifters
wonderful creation has been
getting to kind of see how many
interesting different reactions
and one of the things that i
i started noticing was the people that
reacted kind of negatively and were
almost offended by
you know this totally different
cannabis that is still cannabis but it's
it's a hundred percent different
uh a lot of people that were i think
just
new to cannabis in general or at least
new to trying to grow
it um kind of thought to themselves
well you know these guys are out there
changing it before i even have a chance
to
and what they don't realize is we're not
changing anything we're just expanding
on
something and you know making it
more interesting and and kind of more
unique so
i think people that it seemed to be
consistent that like experienced
growers loved it and wanted to
try it as soon as they could and then
some of the people that were just
maybe growing their first plant were
like
why do you have to create something that
looks so different you know
like we just want it to look like a
normal pot leaf
people were actually like offended by it
and and
we i had to remind them that a this is
not
genetically modified uh ever
never it is modified by me well but
but not the traditional sense of genetic
modification where you're
not slicing genes so we're not
we're not splicing genes from
methodicals
we're not gene editing we're not uh
splicing genes or you know
we're not using crispr we're not using
any of that
technology this is just simply a natural
mutation that occurred
and and of course mutations are
responsible for
all evolution and so we wouldn't
be the human beings that we are today
without
many many millennia of of mutation
you know giving us an opposable thumb
and giving us all these like
advantages and potentially disadvantages
and then
letting you know natural selection uh
work that out and of course you know
this new and amazing kind of cannabis
is no threat like people don't need to
be threatened that all of a sudden all
cannabis is gonna look really weird
because
hold on are they threatened by wedding
cake
i i i would come at it from a totally
different direction
i think it it it looks like a
fern which from a plant
you know i'm not a an expert in plants
but i know the fern was kind of the link
but
it was like the first plant correct uh
and then all other plants you know the
fern's been around for
uh what 400 million years
um and and to me
that that this thing visually
looks like a connection not to something
weird and new and different
but literally to the past
that's why i'm saying i would look at it
inversely and say it's not this new
bastardized thing it's something that
again and it's it's visual but it it's a
reminder
of where plants came from in my mind
right and that and that's cool
i mean as i think and i'm sure maybe
i i could be a little bit off on this
but i think
even humans and and plants
we share like 75 of the same
dna and that's how of course
you know similar we we all are so i'm
sure that
yes freak show was related to a fern or
is in some
cosmic way but but the reality
is just to answer some of the basic
questions it
it is a natural occurrence the the freak
show strain
it's very different and it does have
what i would consider to be some really
unique
and unusual turbines would you guys
agree
and you know these guys trap you know
they
have photographed thousands of cannabis
strains and
uh you know so the turpins are really
unique and i think that there's a lot of
really
incredibly unique things and what i
really uh applaud
shapeshifter for
hit the fact that he did not discard
this unique plant
the fact that he was able to say
you know the fact that he saw the
potential of it
as he was developing it and
i mean i know i've i've been a breeder
here in
in humboldt for well over 20 years and
i've thrown away not
things like this but i've thrown away
things that didn't
fit the the normal criteria
that i expect you know our community to
to want and
and in retrospect
i you know probably threw away some
things that could have been amazing
but historically those anomalies were
scary in some sense
like i don't want to waste time or money
on that right well it's kind of a new
uh you know with the stigmas around
cannabis uh thankfully kind of melting
away
a lot recently it there is
more room for diversity and for more
experimentation and for more
research and you know amazingly the way
to get the diversity
back is going to be the line breed you
know in
all these separate directions uh
before it all gets so homogenized that
it's going to be super difficult to find
something unique and different
handedness and that's that's a lot of
how freakshow came about
is i was actually trying to nail a turd
you know like i said the sesquiterpene
uh the level that this one
some of the parents dog had i was like
okay i really need to nail that
and uh it turns out that right when i'm
right when i'm nailing what i was
looking for in the way of turrets i'm
trying to
fix this once and for all and it's gonna
have diversity
it's gonna have five flavors that range
from fruity to gas
to whatever uh but yet it was at that
point when i nailed it i'm like okay i'm
super interested in this kind of
that's i started seeing the anomalies in
it like the gator tooth
leaf was kind of the burst really
it caught my eye like crazy because i
remember seeing that
all the way back in the day when you
would get one seed out of the tie stick
and it was the waxy crazy
really dragon looking it was like dragon
tail and kind of i remember calling it
back in the day
real super skinny leaves with these
hooked uh serrations on them and when i
saw that i go holy shit
that's the thai weed in this we know
there's highways in it probably from the
big sir holy week
um and i i researched it also a
pineapple supposedly housed high
and uh so it turns out that the
origins of freak show are all related
already
and i think these things just happen
because i've been choosing for certain
uh for what i'm looking for all this
time
and there was always a lot of abnormal
abnormalities in it i mean
they've been there the whole time i
don't know why it crossed my mind like
okay
i'm just going to see where i can take
this just dedicate a little time
to go on go for the really crazy looking
weed so that it
it stands out and the plan
actually out did me um i eliminated the
regulatory genes completely
it's not just an indication it's a plant
that can
continue to mutate indefinitely you know
uh
and that's the interesting part for me
is now i can
zero in on one but like i said i have so
many different lines of it i've got bad
crosses of it
one thing i haven't done i have
outcrossed it um just for fun to
check it out and test dropped out and
there's no freaks in the first
f1 outcross on anything you thought then
people are going to be posting that
later going wow
no no freaks uh but i guess there are
some people that are saying they're
getting a certain percentage of freaks
out of that one
i'll cross it with whatever but uh in
general
what we want to see is for the whole
entire world to have pre-show where it's
mainstream
on the people that are against something
that cool huh
total corey ever when it's all backed up
like that it does look like cory
well you know i think we're all i i
would certainly hope
that we're all into having you know
cannabis become
more and more accessible you know but
and it's a medicine and people should be
able to
you know enjoy it and have it however
they want to have it it's a gosh
damn plant so what the hell i mean
it's we're all here for one reason or
another and definitely cannabis is here
for
i think a lot of good reasons but um
hey do you think that uh we should give
it a try and
and go on a little uh field trip
up up to the cultivation area and
and look at some at some freak show and
look at some different stuff
let's do it and then just jordan quickly
because your roots were in the santa
cruz area right
and so you you mentioned holy express
and i was like that must be some sort of
big sur holy weed kind of family tree
so basically the lineage is is
stuff that you grew up with right i mean
big sur holy weed uh
and then you said pineapple express
yeah the all of it in there is all
sativa or sativa dominant
and we'll just say sativa but yeah the
uh
i wasn't able to find out what uh
holy baba what was it uh banana
kush i'm sorry the banana kush had kind
of had it yet
and after what it really was it wasn't
so but that's the only
kind of broadleaf afghanistan line that
has in it but
see now i've done i've done a lot of
breeding where i'll bring in
you know some some afghanica but then
i'll just choose back
for the sativa phenotype so now
you end up with a 50 50 hybrid that no
one can tell
from a super solar haze it's just
uh it's just a matter of taking it in
the direction you're trying to do
and after years and years and years of
that i finally got to where
it's not so much guesswork anymore and
the family of
the seed bank i have i know real well
like the back of my hand i mean
i can almost predict the outcome on
anything i do
but yeah i'm i'm a line breathing tool i
don't want to go into a big round about
it but uh
you know i it's it's working the line
breeding thing
back crossing's good uh yeah i did take
this one for a back cross ride
um i wanted to take it more to the
pineapple express direction
because that was the one that had so
many generations of what i was looking
for in lawyers
did you grow up in humboldt or where did
you grow up
uh no i was born in new york and
grew up um spent time in philly
the then moved to humboldt when i was 18
years old so i
got a high tail uh that was in 1995
and voted yes on prop 215
with our our our guy dennis carone
um who became a friend later on
that was my my first vote was voting yes
on prop 215
1996. and uh the rest is history i never
really like left humble
after that aside from you know visiting
family and uh taking a few vacations
a few work trips things like that well
where where i was going with that was to
ask if you had any kind of historical
historical experience with kind of big
cert like the big sir holy weeds back in
the day
yeah we've grown big sir
for a long time we've had different
cuts of it and seeds of it come up here
and and big sur was uh on my way
i went and snuck into on my way to
humboldt we
we snuck into ethelon and like smoked
big sur holy weed uh in their hot tub
late in the middle of the night when we
were what was mojave was mojave in the
hot tub
i don't remember i you know i've since
met but i don't remember if he was in
the hot tub
that night it was a blur you know it was
a long time ago and lots of things
happened in hot tubs back then
you know so we've now
deseeded and twisted a bunch of these
selections
this one here is all i have to remember
is that i got number 53
and i hope it wins and like i said this
is
i said so you you have favorites already
53 is your favorite
oh no we're down to 67. we're starting
we're going to
start the smoke analysis the uh
and we'll do lab testing as well but but
we're
we've been here this has always been the
most reliable
we got to test each
yeah i like it and that is is this your
commercial way of uh
of separating seeds the the you get a
team of free labor to hand pick them out
no we when we do this
like really we're having a relaxed
laid-back
weekend where we're working on the freak
show strain and trying to
do some phenotypic uh
you know narrowing it down a little bit
so that we have
um a consistent turpin profile
um not that it's not all they're not all
great they're all
great but um you know so part of that
is uh you know the organic way
of selecting and working on phenotypes
is
smoking and checking out the flowers and
and preserving any seeds that might be
in it normally we have a seed sorting
machine
that we run it through and we've got our
seed
distribution laboratory out on the coast
so you guys are kind of really seeing
kind of the way that we've always done
it and our
a more rootsy way of of what we do here
at humboldt seed company and it's just
so happened that there's
a bunch of homies are in the house so
special uh moment i would say
so so just the last question before we
uh cut it off and regroup
uh jordan when i talked to him the other
day was talking about breeding indoors
will not produce as good seeds as
outdoors so can i get your
both your perspectives on that about
kind of
well you know outdoors
i i think everybody has their opinion
and um
i don't know if if that
uh
you'd have to ask him
so you well then you guys have a
different opinion right
well i i just think that you know
you get what you put into it and i i'm
sure that there are some amazing
uh indoor breeding facilities we have
indoor breeding facilities
and outdoor and you know i think that
selection is the most important thing
um and you know
so i do kind of feel like um
if you're only selecting
in one environment then that can be a
little bit flawed
but um you know
i tell them about the uh we breed in
both indoors and out
and grow up yeah that points up
so much stuff right away oh well i think
what jordan's
what he's referring to is just how
different
uh growing conditions because
if if anyone's familiar with the
grow-off competition
everyone starts with with one with a
clone of the exact same
plan it was they all end up with the
same bug the last two years
it was the last two years it was uh
that's why we do that cookies and
then the next year they chose caramel
cream from our strain
or from one of our strains and
both years the test results came back
like and i'm not trying to point anybody
fingers or call anybody
out but there was thc level
from the same exact cutting that went
from 15
thc all the way to 30 percent
and turpin results that went from
point seven percent all the way up to
five
point which is just almost a record
uh for turpins and so it just goes to
show
how one single clone
you know one clone propagated strain
can you know come out so differently in
in different locations and different
same mom growing yeah from it was it was
all from the same exact mom
but anyway let's go out to the field and
uh
and see how things go all right
we might if we lose wi-fi it just means
that we're gonna have to sign into the
other
wi-fi that we have to maintain for um
like metric purposes and things like
that
you you have a dead okay because it does
that need to be
up 100 or just when you're uploading
data
just when we're uploading data okay
so this is our kitchen garden here
some tomatoes coming in and
yeah i'm looking at my tomatoes uh
outside the garage right now
and this is our little trail you guys
coming
got some pretty sunflowers
so is is is everything
on your home property
yeah we have um we have a dude
like two different premise technically
premises and this is the residential
premise over here
and and there's no cannabis stuff over
here but then you
go across this magic line
oh that you even have a bridge
little foot bridge what do you think so
it's kind of a
little cloudy day so so so
so wait which number are you on what are
you smoking
one 67 and it's rolled with a fresh
tobacco leaves
oh sixty-five very nice so do you grow
do you grow tobacco at home yes sir i do
oh yeah there's almost nothing i don't
grow
uh you know really grow it all
matter of fact my air those are a lot
more important to me than freak show
to be honest i mean they're both super
interesting
you have no idea what i've done with
heirloom tomatoes
i'll mess around with any genetics you
know i used to do
hybrid uh wolves for many years and that
was interesting too
you know i had them up
wolves like like the
in the canine family yeah yeah
they were absolutely pure ones they came
from minnesota
and then i had one out of alaska and
then it was hybridizing them
uh with german shepherd because you know
you don't want to cross them with
huskies huskies aren't really a
real obedient dog at all so anyway i get
them up to 96
wolf big black beautiful wolves and
listen to every word you say very
trainable and all that stuff
look more like a wolf than a pier and uh
they had killed my favorite dog uh one
night and uh that kind of ended the
whole
breeding program wow let's go check out
the freak show chamber
this is we're starting to get into sort
of the
zone so so you're growing it on your
property too correct
yeah we've got um
this is this is our farm this is the
humboldt seed company anchor farm and
we've got
40 different breeding chambers here
that we each one
inside each one we create each different
strain
that we release and we've also got
a permitted farm and nursery down in
nevada county as well
so but this is our main anchor humboldt
farm and then we have a
distribution for the seeds that we call
the seed lab
and that's out in eureka but
um
and so so the idea here is is once you
guys
pick a winner of jordan's uh
the stuff that he brought over from his
property
you'd then pop those seeds and basically
create
seeds out of that that would then go to
market
yeah that's how we did the original
um freak show seeds that are in market
today
so here jordan and i are going to go in
uh inside one of these chambers here
where we breed the freak show
and all right so they're little they're
little hoop houses
got it yeah and i mean you know
we have our own special
sort of tricks that we've developed over
the years for
breeding different strains but i like
the use of
bamboo yeah
yeah i mean it's nature
and here's some freak show buds actually
cfc'd
i'm seeing the siege forming right there
and this is the feminized freak show
so the one of the interesting things
about
um the way freak show
develops the anthers
particularly on this like a sex reversed
one develop on the outside of the flower
but you know what people really want to
see are these beautiful
freak show buds starting to form up
isn't that just amazing
yeah so so
in this room it's all
females that have been pollinated with
a male that you selected or or
what kind of the set up in the room so
we've actually
fully reversed um
the sex of of this plant
or of of freak show and that's how you
make
uh feminized seeds so it just so happens
that we're in
a feminized breeding chamber right now
but we all
make regular freak show seeds
um but yeah here's this
is right here the this
bud is is absolutely 100
accepting pollen right now
and the pollinators
look like that
yeah so
you know this you're getting kind of a
really
sort of a inside look
at freak show we don't always
share exactly what this stuff looks like
but
you know breeding isn't always
as exactly as photo as growing
flour for smoke because you know
for one thing for seeds to be mature
you need to let the the flowers kind of
sit
and and the seeds will ripen inside the
flowers
for another month at least
beyond uh when you would harvest it for
for smoking right
and yeah and how freak show seeds are
extremely hard to
process because uh they're
pale the way they're pale so it's almost
impossible to tell
a hollow one from you know a good one
but it can be done you just go through
them one by one check them
right it looks like we're in like a
jurassic park
scene right now yeah
he's got a leaf here actually
so that's that's the uniqueness
well not to mention that and the turpins
are
incredibly unique yeah peter this is a
lot like the
the super freak and the fruity freak
ones that i'm i'm
breaking out right now uh going for a
much more
kind of simpler lacier
matter of fact the ones at my ranch are
quite a bit different than
this particular one but yeah
sorry in terms of the leaf structure
yeah exactly leaf morphology has gone in
a lot of kind of crazy directions and
you know that's what got me started
finding freaks in the first place but
you know i can't help myself now i'm
looking at the freaks of the freaks
and where it's you know really taking
off
and you know in another departure uh
you know in the way of leaf uh shape
and that's there is actually
correlations between
certain things that you can look at on
any cannabis plant
uh at any stage of the game aside from
smelling them and stuff uh
you know i did it as guesswork you know
we would find out later oh yeah the one
that you really love them skinny thai
leaves
uh that is the tasty one by god you know
so uh yeah come to notice
things like that correlations between
morphologies
and you know final outcomes
okay well it's really warm in here right
now and
yeah um
anyway there's some beautiful we go
yeah we could go show them the ones that
are in the fields
and and so in that room how many plants
are there
i'd have to look on metric there's quite
a few so we do
selection from quite a few plants
i would say my guess would be around 40
or so okay 50.
so here's just one of our phenohunt rows
and uh these are non-non-freak type
cannabis these are just our our normal
cannabis and we we like to grow
they're looking good we like to do
autoflowers kind of like out along the
edges
because it's sort of helps us build our
autoflower research
so here's some nice little cute little
autos that are just
popping out from behind these
hedgerows of plants
but anyway this is like a little tour
now you're starting to get
some of our breeding chambers are up
there
on this bigger flat you know i'm a
little hesitant to like
i didn't really clean up for this peter
it's nice autoflowers are doing their
thing right now
so that's we like that
it's a nice uh technique actually doing
autoflowers just right alongside
and is that just so you can kind of just
see how their experiment is just an
opportunity to let it
express itself and get some feedback on
it or is there another purpose
uh we get feedback on it we test some of
them
and then you know it it's also just like
you know it the more the merrier as far
as flower goes
um and so
but primarily the answer is it's for r d
all right so i'm moving up now to where
we have some
freaks growing out in veg
and uh jordan's on his way as well
let me just see this is um our blueberry
muffin
breeding chamber here
so these are pollinated here we go
okay so this is the blueberry muffin
yeah this is our blueberry muffin
breeding chamber
so this i don't know if folks can see
but that is
full of of our femme blueberry muffin
seeds
oh wow okay
so so so the see those seeds are already
feminized or do you have to treat them
so the way that people a lot of people
don't quite get it
the way that you make feminized seeds is
by altering the pollen
and the pollen comes from from a plant
that has
two x chromosomes which is just a
generally a female plant and so
because of that it uh
creates all female seeds
got it so so so one once you put the
seeds through the machine there
and and pull them all there there's no
more work to be done in terms of the
feminization process
that's right yeah it it happens
you treat the um
you treat the plant with uh
a silver with the female plant with
silver
until it releases um pollen which it
normally would not
release pollen so
when it releases pollen the pollen that
it releases is
all female pawn now
so these are just going to be full term
outdoor and they're just currently in
veg right
yeah these are just in veg right now and
and are these from feminized seeds are
these just regular seeds
i don't i think that some of them are um
we created both feminized and regular
freak show seeds last year
and you know we've keep track of
of our rating always at the base of the
plants
you can see this one was rated
nine and uh
that just has a good turpin the gs
stands for
to be honest it's not that technical it
stands for great smell
but you know hey we're keeping track and
we breed with our highest
rated ones so these are all nines and
tens
and from individual populations and they
were selected out of many many
um so you know many phenos or let's just
say
individuals in a population
phenotype is kind of a subjective word
if you ask me
you know one person's definition of a
different
phenotype can be very
different than someone else's definition
if you know what i mean you know
you know what what
well okay just for example someone might
call this freakshow
leaf shape a phenotype and
just say that is uh an
interesting phenotype of cannabis
but for jordan and i
we we go through and look at these
different freaks and and we think of
each one of these leaf shapes that's
different
and so on and so forth we think of those
as phenotypes as well
so um i that's why i just would say that
the word phenotype is subjective but
that's okay it's
it's meant to be subjective um they use
overall phenotype for that you know
overall phenotype includes everything
about the plant
yeah and then we have chemotype and then
looking at the genotype and
terp type even yeah terp profile is
another whole area of jeans
and i always tell people when you
combine
all of it together and you find that
plant that you really love
that we we call that one a dreamo type
yeah right i got the problem of i
kind of getting to where everything i
got i love it all
uh so that's why i have so many lines of
fruit show i could take it in any
direction
i want right now and i could do it in
you know one generation
i'm pretty damn happy now it's just a
matter of what flavor
do you like you know at this point it's
kind of a flat
five flavor uh variety because
it's gonna have the fives and i like it
that way
you know it's not right and and do you
guys have five different
joints going right now
all right yeah we got it here you guys
hold the camera you cue the banjo music
man
so what do you think these guys what's
the initial impression
team grow magazine is here at humboldt
seed company right
number 25 number 29
number 53 and number 50 at 67.
and like i said we're kind of all off
the clock right now peter we're doing
like a special
uh you know really laid back you know
we're working right now
ah yeah easy it's a hard job well
normally we'll have you know like
notepads
we could go down and look at the the
phenotype rating
sheets that we have as well yeah we're
gonna have a little vote
i you know i try to rain uh
rain these guys in sometimes but they
just they're big energy these are big
big
characters right this is pka say hi pk
hey how's it going
hey guys this is guy guys actually the
uh
producer the publisher grow man
i'm also the janitor
and where where are you guys based out
of are you guys up in oregon as well
yeah we're in a boiler room down in
eugene and we're not we're nodded
this is this is humboldt county right
here yeah of course
here i'll i'll show you the view over
the um klamath basin actually
you have to excuse me i'm not always
just walking through our breeding
facility but oh with that anyways so
all right this is uh
the scenery here in
northeast humboldt county
kind of uh an unusually um
day we were potentially gonna have some
thunderstorms today but they
seem to be holding off but
normally it's uh just
bright blue skies right now
right now that's that that's that looks
like a happy uh
happy spot it's a beautiful spot we have
a wonderful spot for breeding here we
have
uh 25 000 square feet
and we breed in all of it
or breed or do really intensive pheno
hunting like you see there
and um you know we were honored to be
able to
do freak show here but we have of course
you know
50 different genetics that we maintain
here
um each one of them has this individual
pollination chamber and um
it's a heck of a lot of work we rarely
take time out and
just so happen that um our interview
kind of a meeting a meeting of the minds
or a lot of people come here
to the farm today
you know sort of a special moment and
uh inspiration very cool
well let let's uh let's pick this up
i mean uh we should do stuff
like you get great reception so i'd love
to do stuff from the farm and like like
even like you know i'm just thinking
like off the top of my head like talk
through your
like your process of feminizing seeds
and like
different breeding topics where you
could teach people and
um well we try to we try to be really
really like
sharing and not you know have too many
trade secrets because we actually want
people to
try breeding themselves and we want
people to get into it
and you know we feel like the more
people understand about it the more
they'll understand how much
like work and yeah real effort
so so is that corn in the background
yeah that's our little sweet corn patch
that we do every year for
you know the the trim
not the crew but the seed harvest
team and sweet
guys talking about the sweet kron which
if anybody has ever gone through
southern oregon you see the big
company that does sweet kron it's like
they have corn and weed for sale that's
funny
we all like to you know no one wants to
get
fully sort of just known for
one thing as you know like the whole
i think one of the reasons why he
knew that freak show was special and to
try to work with it and keep it around
when it appeared for him is because he's
had so many
many years of experience you know he
knew
better than to just cast it aside like
you know i might have done that in my
early
days of breeding so right he's got
quite a few years on me and right always
really
you know we want to pay deference to
that
here at humboldt seed company because
there's so many that came before us and
even though i've been
here growing and breeding in humboldt
for
five years alma or is that
no more than that i guess but anyway um
i
still feel like i'm you know a beginner
in a lot of respects compared to
some of the folks whoa but anyway
peter it's been amazing and uh
i guess i'll sign off now all right and
i'll chill
check in soon what are we looking at
there
to be honest this is uh this is
forbidden fruit
got it which um
my cultivation manager here at the farm
just loves forbidden fruit and i like it
i'll give it up to forbidden fruit
all right