and now just wanting to touch on ethics
of extraction and sitting right next to
me we have Gil and Brandon and Frenchie
yeah he'll be back he'll be back it's
okay I'm gonna pass over the microphone
to you here okay that's great and and
both of you all grow as well as do
extraction and and also are very active
in the regenerative community so can you
put those together to us why it's
important one with the other yeah
definitely for sure yeah we wanted to
talk about like how regenerative
cannabis and farming ties into what hash
is all about and yes so we can kind of
like start it off maybe with like a
little bit of thinking how mother nature
kind of does it all without any of us
interrupting it and the plant falls
right back down to where it was once
grown right so I kind of always thought
that that's really important into
sustainability and creating a farm and
fertility and all this so when we farm
the hash that's what we're yeah that's
what we're farming so we're not really
farming for the flowers and that means
that as much as the biomass gets put
back down I mean it's it's amazing for
next year
so we put 99% of it back now and I think
that's a big part of the sustainability
in this small farm that can keep it
going type of thing because it's
definitely cost-effective and all those
things come into play and you know so
tying that into kind of like the whole
thing is like
it just keeps the flow going I think for
a small farm you know it's hard to do
all these and with the regulations and
stuff so I don't know it doesn't really
apply to everyone that they can really
do this
I know but that's just how we do it and
and we this you know we have the love
for hash like that so we don't really do
much and so it's a small scale thing
right yeah for sure yeah sorry I'm
struggling with things to say after like
just all the real professional people
that have licked talk today you know
over there and all that so it's just I
don't know I'm just a kind of a simple
guy but I do work with canvas physically
like most days of the week that's for
sure so uh but solving lists is really
popular right now I don't know if people
know that but or what state you're in
I'm in California and Trinity County and
I feel like California it's kind of
often said cannabis trends whether you
want to talk about legally or socially
or whatever but people talk about
adaptability as important currently and
that's what led me to solve and this is
just following Gandhian
seeing where it took me and I was just
trying to see what I really enjoyed
about it and what I didn't enjoy about
it and growing flower I'm sure you can
all understand like spend all this time
growing it and then drying it and
processing it as an art unto itself you
know just literally keeping that thing
so pristine I would lose sleep over it
you know what I mean making sure my dry
room was perfect and making sure my
trimmers weren't just like destroying
the weed you know what I mean
feeling pressures to use trim machines
all that over the years you know I've
done I've worked for other people I
farmed I've done a lot of different
situations on small-scale large-scale
but uh yeah personally for me that was
just stressful dealing with the actual
flower the longevity of it you know
sometimes you're forced to hold on to
product rapidly and some strains you
know it happens faster than others and I
think that's hard to say whether or not
that's gonna happen to you know before
you grow it you don't know so I think
totally all that that we preserve it
yeah and kind of like isolate that and
almost kind of think about it as like a
wine like we preserved it and aged that
year and it could even get better or
worse I mean it all depends but it's
definitely like capitalizing the year
and not letting it get worse innocence I
don't know and then yeah like we appeal
to that market and that market like ask
for it so we kind of like adjusted I
feel like to that thing and it's uh
we're constantly teaching them I feel
like to like it's a it's a huge like why
you should be enjoying hash over
anything else and man that's a struggle
I feel like because so many people just
have you know they're all they know
everything everyone knows everything
already so it's kind of like you know
nobody wants to hear it
Davis some some people don't but yeah I
think that's a I think that's a big part
of why what we do what we do and you
know really push on to not ingesting
chemicals because we really just like
care a lot about everyone and that's
like why we do and make what we make it
push out for the next person to find the
health in the cannabis you know so we
really grow it healthy and then make it
healthy and then it's like the highest
purity product that the plant can make I
feel like without any of the chemicals
of machinery
all the trades make sense just on
therapeutic level to me it's like you're
really meant like trying to use cannabis
or medicine to me sitting there and just
smoking flour and flour flour flour it's
hard to medicate where someone could
just take a small concentrated dab you
know and I mean I think it will always
go on value in a medical market where I
think that will inhaling for all the
times that we do out there I mean it's
not gonna be that good for us I feel
like we all know that but vaporizing
oils is like tremendously better so you
know I think that's a big part of it to
which we still like have to all kind of
grasp and we all love smoking joints I
don't think we're gonna stop that right
that's not gonna happen so but then
there was I guess the other half was we
wanted to talk about kind of finding
these hash plants because not every
plant of the cannabis plant is the hash
plant and the word hash plant is kind of
big I feel like so I kind of want to
like maybe touch on the word hash plant
and kind of put maybe it know do you
think it's I want to hear what you got
to say so I mean there is as much
difference in a cannabis regime as there
is in a flower the world plant adapt to
an abbot at but the wall plant adapt and
its defensive system even more so so if
you have a tropical plant with a lot of
insect life super green it has to
produce a resin that is really sticky
and protective if you take that plant
and you put it into the in Dooku's
mountain where it's there is no insect
life because life is only well there is
water it's super dusty that resin
which is Tiki is going to be covered in
dust and it's not gonna work anymore so
the more the plant created the moment
seeker to protect to to have less
excitation of of resin to protect itself
and you can recognize genetic just by
the regime I can even recognize
Parenthood like lining edge in the
breeding just by looking at the reason
it just because your culture is flower
my culture is a sheesh and
no you don't have the ice culture here
who I wanted to tell you you may have
you have the consulted killed you that
is copying the BHO industry it's vastly
different you know what I mean
well yeah yeah I do know you mean for
everyone to join it but I think it like
what I wanted to say and and touches so
like the texture of the resin like you
said you can't take an equator type of
plant and bring it to the mountains but
like we taught are we talking about the
mountain plants so they should we kind
of like fall into detail of what type of
resident are we talking because I feel
like there are residents that are closer
to the equator that fall into you know
you touch them they're oily right and I
think they fall into like the tincture
category what we make tinctures out of
the ones that are more like
water-soluble terpene like resident
plants do you find that it's like you
know what I'm talking about
that you are spraying your plant like
there is no tomorrow and wife the plant
can be nourished with the leaf it's not
made foods who the live and that you
play with your raised in a door so it's
like I don't know you go flower you
don't go hey Xion concentrate it's a new
game for you and it it has blown the
market away concentrate is the next big
seems in E and you see here in America
but you live in an island or
the rest of the world is smoking Ashish
is smoking solvent less and that your
market of tomorrow the market here in
America it's an extract market when when
you do what I do I collect a raise in
IDI I crush it into a mass there is a
chemical reaction that I'd turn into
that mass and that mass when it's older
it's greater than what the plant gave me
I'm like a winemaker and that process in
the world alcohol and you see wine it's
unique because if you take the juice
from the grape you can make many alcohol
SKU distillation but to make wine you
need everything harsh together to have
that chemical reaction happening and
making that transformation so it's
something that is unique and cannot
compete compared to any other extract
hear you use the word ash for everything
that is a concentrate so already when
you go in Europe and you save the world
ash and you mean an extract you're gonna
have to say American ash like you say
for Amit for football because we don't
speak the same language ask for us it's
millinium of culture it's very very very
dear and you just cannot appropriate a
world and use it for amazing projects
but who have nothing to do with us you
know what I mean is I
because because the world market is
coming and if we need if you want to
have an exchange between country we're
gonna need to speak the same language so
you cannot appropriate word that I've
millinium of culture - just because you
can yes you can but the value of it is
is what you know what I mean is like if
you really want to be all of that and
what other language that is meaningful
in a world trade well you need first to
respect tradition and an traditional
culture and then we need to be able to
to describe the type and profile of the
of a flower of the us take personally I
need I would need a wine maker that is a
smoker to get deep enough into a tapping
profile to to describe it because I go
maybe two three four level but you can
go twelve fifteen so it's like that
wine became popular because it's
pleasurable well cannabis even more so
and this is where we can appeal to the
people it's who the palate and here
furthermore so the world extracts the
world as people the world everything
that come after you go the plant
it's an appropriation of your walk from
it's different because my my education
was going into a producing country going
as far away deep into the producing
place to stay with the local to make my
own ass because I'm smoking only the
best and it's not for sale
when when you can when you can do that
there is so much you can do by yourself
when you create that entity in in those
places it has never been me making us
that makes us quality people wanted to
know where I want to to define the
quality I have so when I came here in
America
all those producing country the quality
of my ass was the lawn the climate and
the crucifer and it's long race when I
came here in the Emerald triangle
I had the lawn the climate the genetic
but behind the genetic that is afar
there is a breeder and then there is
actually a farmer here in producing
don't even when it's cultivated it's not
farming it's just to achieve ated so i
became like a winemaker I worked with
specific cultivar that I liked specially
and I need Vani out to provide me with
what I need to show off on AG and it's
not only me it's every extractor
everybody's that touch your plant should
give you credit because everything I am
I owe it to what was given to me here
and the same when I was in producing
country the problem is like you sell
yourself cheap while the value of making
a project in a metal triangle give you a
word opening because you recognized
worldwide for your quality and I love
you to death
but if you didn't deliver what I can
receive here I'm not sure I would go
through the old shit I'm going trying to
work with big money people and shit like
that guys you know what I mean it's like
there is something that is so unique
that you could become the Bordeaux and
the phones of the cannabis
because there is nowhere on the planet
where there is a generation of people
that had been growing genetic and the
genetic adapted so well you have the
diversity and you have an Easter with it
and on top of it you have a lot of story
to make it palatable to a market where
it's nice now to have to deal with out
loud and and people like that but when
you go genetic you give me purple pants
guys it's like I can get purple punch
from anybody from you I want the stuff
from Covello I want the stuff that you
keep in your in your cupboard stuff that
I'm the only one to put on the market
and you have the only one to go because
when you compete with the same genetic
with the indoor already your son gone
you have a handicap and then you're
walking with the same genetics and those
people it's like he doesn't even make
any sense you're following fashion and
when you follow a fashion you are behind
you need to bloody create the fashion
and you have a hell of a lot of genetic
to do it it's just like I don't know you
don't know your value it's crazy to see
everything you have and you don't use it
it's like you should own your genetic if
any extractor touch your stuff even if
it goes in the web pan when you buy with
a pen and I know that the guy has been
hunting is genetic in in a mile triangle
well I may look at it if I know that the
guy is doing the shit at in Salinas I
wouldn't be interested that we don't
even look at it it's like you have that
value but when you sell a product not
only it's under priced but on top of it
you don't get the credit for it it's
like yo you know what I mean is like we
owe you everything doesn't matter how
big I am I owe it to my farmer
it's like that quality that I get a
because you gave it to me and it's like
it's important to remember that and to
own it to own your name to own the
genetics that you breathe because that
what makes you so different and that
what you have a world reputation for
quality there is not that many place in
the world that have a world reputation
for quality I know another one
it's a remote valley in the mountain of
the Himalaya where I spent seven season
making chalice so if you don't use this
as a as a mean to create everything you
don't believe in yourself how can you
have people believing in you you don't
ask for shit you need vandalism
they're not gonna give it to you I'm
special because of my education and how
I came into the business and and my
future is always the origin of the
products that really counts is like if
the least qualities because it come from
somewhere and that somewhere is very
special you have that very special place
and you this is a brand your brand is in
healthy angle because you'll known
worldwide sun-grown you have a lot of
sanguine and I've said I've had someone
in many producing country well the
sanguinary multi-angle it's not quite
the same than anywhere on the planet and
I was just thinking what ties into that
too is talking about extracting resin
from plant and in certain zones and
areas you know it's meaningful that that
resin is is telling a story of the area
that it's grown in or maybe a story of
the environment or a story of of the
soil so you know that you all are
noticing a difference between indoor
resin and imaging is that vision Edie
it's a defensive system of the plant
it's a BB
rafi of its life and its own villain
Matt it's like the world story of the
plant is inside that resonate if you
know how to read it is that the
connection between the ash maker and the
thermal it's really important because I
can tell you stuff that you don't know
about when you've a breeder a summer and
ash maker like min Jean for example then
you have you have the knowledge of or
Zeus aspect of the of the plants and
maybe I was rescued Brandon and and you
know when you're growing and how are you
how are you searching for plants you
know we we appreciate you know that
knowledge the last couple years I've
been breeding for the certain type of
resin that is easier to work with with
water ash for simpler reasons because we
all use water hash mostly here in
America right but that's kind of like
what is that easier head and that's kind
of what I was going to say before was
this every plant has a different texture
to it you know a different Turkey and a
different smell and it carries a
different texture of that resin head of
that you know life so what heads what
plants are better to use than others
because I've had so many people call me
and tell me and cry to me that they're
losing yields or hash or plant they
could have just sold it as pounds but
they chose the fresh frozen and then
they get nothing in return
right
so that you use and the the world
environment you use it's like it's not
only he's a plant it's no precious make
sure but lets you get your environment
right you get everything else right then
it's up to the plant
I've been I you know I've got it up on
my farm we're all we're dialed in up
there right we do it right and and I've
seen you know hundreds of different
residents passed by my I've been washing
hash for eight years and growing for
fifteen almost so it's been a long
journey I think for my short life and
I've just been full-blown dedicated I've
got the blinders on I don't see anything
else that's why I didn't go legal I
didn't do this or that I don't care to
even spread myself out thin too much to
try to help out it like I focused on
this exact purpose and you know what at
least what only I could see me I haven't
went to the other countries I haven't
seen that type of resin of court I've
talked to some people we went to this
you know only to that extent of talking
but the hash that I'm looking for is
what I guess what America now is aiming
as what they're calling water hash ice
water extraction right and all that side
of things so I respect the the the
culture and the tradition though so much
like you know like I mean I want to go
to Indy I want to go to all these other
places I want to go and give thanks and
like just do whatever volunteer make a
freakin kilos for them you know so I I
feel that but then you know here we are
modernized we're 2019 about to be 2020
catch up with times a little bit as much
as I want to go backwards but here we
are and this ice water extraction when
you have everything dialed in or like
spice water separation
what is that head what is that resident
what is that texture so I've been down
the road I've seen the oily ones I like
to use those for tincture but we're not
here to talk about that as much as we
like to talk about the solvent less hash
so like I find it to be those fat but
like granule
Sandee heads right okay so we can agree
on it and that is right easy to do with
water right and I so is thank you so dry
you know try sieving as well it's nice
for me some you are you were born in
diversity guys I was born I had six
flavor okay so for me it's every plant
and more like a time every plant is
precious
it doesn't filter or difficult now I
just want to talk about me easiest know
though for a lot of people in here like
I said I got you know messages of people
crying and you know and I don't want to
be that guy always trying to explain I
you know here this is the time if you
like to talk about the easiest one let's
talk about the easy that might even put
it on a whole tier level where these
terpenes and these hashes get sold at a
lower price because they're you know
super freakin easy to make you know then
there's these harder ones the lower yes
maybe and being relevant in the market
is having diversity and there's a huge
want for a specific kind of hash and
there's also like a really beautiful
niche market for you know hand-rolled
traditional hashish making and i think
that it's important that we talk about
both both entities and and that's sort
of what we're talking about here and
respect them both and that's great
everybody smoked ass guys you know you
live on an island like the rest of the
world we smoked us and as for flour we
have an edge we are making quality and I
can even make quality in quantity so
it's like you have the gene
we have the technology to make the best
I fish in the world is like all the
people that teach me that I lived in the
found form for months years after year
they all drooling on my IGN asking me to
go back what I did which I will so it's
like you decide to produce you will if
you decide to produce only quantity you
will not develop that in the next year's
when what trade is coming because the
producing country from the moment the
news I can sell anything on a market
it's illegal but they know what we are
doing and they really knows that the
next few the future of the market it's
making quality that's why they want to
learn that why they want a new tool and
stuff like that and we should be is that
next you know valves that define
qualities like there is completely world
country that could decide to produce
only quality for the LED is doing it is
I you can dedicate yourself only to
quality and have an edge because nobody
care enough to do it we do
the regenerative like the science of
organic regenerative conference up in BC
in January I think it was Marcus man who
you know at scale is do it and you know
yeah so he had a technique and I forget
if it was him or somebody else or if
y'all are in the audience that just
wanted to bring it up as its are all of
it feels like a field test for plants
where it was like hey I'm gonna put this
in a jar with some I you know it anymore
like see ya kid what's that can you guys
share that because I think that's
relevant to a lot of what your tried to
share too and I get people kind of
crying I mean this is also that I want
to kind of like what you were finishing
saying no like I don't know it's it's
just pure level of like life with this
like hash is really meaningful I feel
like we have to get that like statement
across but but anyway yeah the jar tech
sorry it's just like you throw some
fresh frozen your nugs in a jar and
shake it with ice water and it's pretty
much like an ice water you know little
mini wash yeah so you can kind of see
what sits at the bottom of the jar which
is like great for field tests yeah I
mean so you can know whether or not you
should freeze that plant or not because
a lot of people yeah kind of jumped the
gun and totally shoot themselves in the
foot and lose a lot of product because
you look there is in heed to judge the
flowering cycle of the plant the
flowering cycle of the plant is a main
metabolism of the plant so hazing a de
Segundo he metabolize the plant produces
to protect itself it has nothing to do
with the main metabolize of the plant
the amount of the ray of resin formed
inside the resonate is totally dependent
on the peak of the flowering cycle
but since you cannot look inside there
is in head to see how much reason there
is it's not the color and it's not the
size that gonna tell you if your flower
is is ripe or not it's you look at the
flower when you go tomato or any other
project you don't look at the secondary
metabolites you don't you know what I
mean it's like you look at the flower so
for me as a ash maker
I really need to observe a scene ed
bursting like food from a tree it has to
be really really full of jewels and
sugar and there is a CDS window for that
and there is not that many people who
give me in that CDA's window when I walk
with a greenhouse everybody telling me
oh yeah we are versed in time so many
others do you do a year five six okay I
walk on it which people would you fall
because I cannot have a premature plant
and that's something I need to ask you I
can I can literally tell you to the day
how early or outlet you are obviously
okay and two weeks early I cannot you
cannot flower that test that 28 books on
THC and I have added like the greater
sugar trim from that I got a shitload of
like on earth like on ground but it's so
light that you saw it in the air he
doesn't fall that means that you can
have canopy no heed and there is no
reason that is still found inside the
resin head and the closer you come to
that three days peak window the more
reason is inside that resonate and swash
who washing my plum 12 time it's like a
resonate his neck like a foot there is
an obsession under the ground and that
abscission becomes smaller and smaller
and smaller the riper the the IDI
is and then it just fall when it's
really high when I learned that my take
is
to get the melt I need to shake the tree
just a tiny bit I have the high post and
then I shake a tiny bit more I have a
second dimension of ripeness and I shake
my t12 time if my first shake when I put
it on the resin edge there is no melt
whatsoever you are two weeks minimum too
early if I can if I put that if I use it
to press and my first temple bar is like
it all together there is no real hug but
like the reason is not using your seven
eight days too early and so on and so on
until there is at CDs window where the
twelve ball are just like bursting of
raising the shining that you see on my
ig it's not me polishing the temple
Birla it's literally oozing from it and
then when you pass that window my first
or second temple bird egg on the price
they're gonna make a temple ball kind of
shiny but when you open it it doesn't
have that elasticity that straight she
takes to it as kind of moist eNOS to do
it I know that the plant has been
arrested - too late and the more temple
ball I have that has that sexier
the later you it has been arrested so my
question is how come how can you have
cannabinoid formed inside the ground
without having the reason that old it in
its body because that's a fact I have
seen I have not been wrong in the next
five past five years on our earlier hour
later plant has been harvested so I'm
I'm quite sure that this is happening in
the raising long but I'm I I can't
complain it and III have
time explaining to people that it's
happening in the first place I agree
with what you've described it's just
kidnap acromion seems to be different in
the life cycle of the plant where there
is CBC it seems to be have greater
production earlier on and for ecological
reasons that I can't explain it will
shift to prefer other cannabinoids
specifically CBD and THC but I mean this
is you know if we got a grad student out
there that needs a project this is
another one of those things that ought
to be investigated I need to work with
somebody that is not on my literally
Green versa so I'm ready to work with
people like that but as long as they
grow they play my game is like the
relation I have with you it's pressures
at the personal level but at the
business level and unload and one person
dependent on you so the trust I have
from you the quality you're giving me
because it's me it's something that is
more precious than money it's out for me
to work with an auntie Jean that is not
gonna support that because if they don't
unfucked
you know what I mean and it's very
difficult on top of that to be able to
support you I need to
I need to help you put your flower on
the market and I need to help you bond
more than your bond that people
understand where it come from
and first its origin it first it to em
right the anger and then there is a
conte and then there is the thumb into
it but if you don't have extract her
with a brand name that use their brand
to promote your farm and the genetic
where it comes from
it's not good enough literally because
we use that and it's not it's not
happening in America because it's not
part of your culture but it's something
that you should ask for because it makes
extract we give more value to the end
product and co-promotion is always
better than single per single promotion
and because there is very few of you
that have a license on top of it you
have a pretty strong edge you have the
fire and there is not so many of you so
that's why there is not that many people
I can work with to make this and us and
in the extractor that is in my position
extractor or ash maker is in the same
position we are very dependent on you we
all you credit and that credit should be
shown on a fucking packaging not just
blah blah blah it should be on the
packaging on the front wizard-like
technically speaking my name shouldn't
fucking be on that clear on that box
because there is no winemaker that puts
his name on on a wine bottle
they don't fucking care you know what I
mean the value of their project it's
where it comes from it's not who made
the stuff the guy who made the stuff as
a as a privileged to be the one that
fucking blow you away and that all we
technically need it's to to give that
pleasure
the emphasis that we put on brand like
you need to be able to to walk it to on
you oxide using the people that you are
buying from you and that need your staff
is like you want my stuff okay I want my
name on your box otherwise you don't
have it and if you and if you keep it
longer it will become along the ice it
like that plants become the place where
we go it becomes a
when they got it yeah and it was really
quick actually that they accept the
first fallen and they put it on the
first indicator pairs and that maybe
some earlier to see about the next year
and they didn't first call in on the
fridge and then a couple generations
they had seized that will monetize and
grown mountains of Mendocino County so I
guess my question is how do we
acknowledge the source but then you
start asking the question what is the
source I mean how far back do we go do
we go about five thousand years just
because that was when it was written
but because before that five thousand
years nobody wrote you know so do we go
back yeah a couple billion years you
know that we'd be here now I just think
we'd be here now and appreciate you know
because it gives alumnus of long days
and the value of this country because
for the moment we go in Columbia to go
shit like Depp and stuff like that when
nobody's trying to find out this
phenotype and the beauty that there is
in Colombia every country we grow will
squatter you know man I mean it's like
we do the same shit everywhere we go and
there is no respect for the long grass
and agility at least here if we can show
that we created something and it became
local but there is a respectful for the
origin of the of the know it would be a
very good stuff because it's something
we really need
and uses its beyond beyond being a
chicken this is the basic and knowledge
amount of of what you made with with
what you receive from this country
it doesn't change that you have created
like beyond dream but you if you give
the awareness to the people that
everything you created the source is
coming from those people then there is
not cultural and world understanding on
actually how it all
antara look and how it all develop and
created what we have to offer now you
know what I mean there is a legal regime
for what you're talking about though
something called the Nagoya protocol for
biodiversity and I don't remember the
whole name for it but the goal was to
preserve biodiversity and also to give
credit to and even compensation to what
could otherwise be seen as kind of a
misappropriation of indigenous plants
indigenous medicines and that kind of
thing of course it should come as no
surprise that the US has not signed on
to the Nevada part but in Europe it's a
really big deal you have to if you have
a new drug they came from the Amazon
rainforest or if you have some folk
medicine that you've adapted and
commercialized you have to say you have
to demonstrate basically that it's not a
violation of the Nagoya protocol
everything look Rd we do a test IP
ginkgo we have to give money back from
the profits of that test to China
because China is where ginkgo comes from
when you have a more cosmopolitan plant
canvas there is no one country ownership
and this happens with a lot of our
really importantly this notes because
what do you take with you when he moved
your food and your medicine and this has
happened forever I mean even roses paper
on some of the evolutionary history of
cannabis that we can extract from
archaeological thing and you see like
this is a plant that's moved rapidly
with us and has changed dramatically to
its environment and then being a you
know sitting in the lens of genetics so
many of our plants that we use are so
evolutionarily like admits that it would
be hard to really place them in any one
region right because we don't keep our
Mexican landrace breathing in one little
pocket in our plants right in northern
India in another pocket we introduce
those plants to each other so it becomes
very different in this environment but
there is history there and the truth is
you don't have enough data to even
understand that because we have we don't
have global populations that we can pull
from and you know you need this original
global and you can still do that work
but it's very difficult
probably right but we don't have the
resources to really even answer those
questions with the maps that we hear in
this culture interact with right because
we have to reference to something right
we have to go to the source and look at
a lot of plants and the strength to
understand okay these are the allele
these are the versions of these genes
that come from this place relative to
you know this other place so it's a lot
of let's figure it out you know you
don't know we can go and really further
and I don't want to brush off basically
what Tina is saying because I think that
it's a really important point and in a
decision on where we got it we where we
want to go as far as ethics of breeding
and whether we're going to be public
domain or whether we're going to keep it
to our own domain or or or what we're
going to do so you know on that level