[Musique]
child wise reading lot avoue adventure
ce book 1 et oiseaux all about persian
lack of adventure burton staff&amp;line à jo
all my life as we used to travel oslisly
really want to do and then it's event in
the mood for the first time sommes h1ni
twilight testing and famous contre les
attentes et où visite sur when i was as
i think that what it for eighteen new
york solide un abou dhabi give up
smoking fort traveling geeks agathoise
et vouvry all the eye à coude à coude à
luis tu bats inside et d'interviews and
because in france ou à nawaz ses 20e
tous se moquent a choisi l'ironie
the whole thing the pressure was really
really do you want you have so much
pressure négative en you and you doing
something that make you feel so good eye
amener vers lui l'offre like that in my
life as we had never had to hell
business like that in my life the world
now when that of god has been bad
surtout travel et tui travel in h
culture qu'on trie les digues et demi un
e break y tient et toi style illégale du
style coup de vieux habits beau stand
petit mot ce lieu deal with the cops 1
il donc feel like the scope of the world
you feel là que bad boy et cela quitte
son étonnante légales petites sparta de
culture and has been faut rendre d'un
endroit vieux ressorts is like it was
the beat mark conforter wolf and in h
country you work with aux plantes
mousseline winter belghazouani dry and
cold and you can actually separate
sticky résine aide et new works with
bandol of dry flower saurai like the
connection with aux plantes is not
really seront and for me everything oise
résine in india et changeur each and the
little bettini albi comme spiritual et
l'accueil ou des disquettes evry smoked
web god and the cannabis planté suppose
to being born in
une drop of the élixir of life the fall
from the sky striebig dire m0 l'oit
style illegally niña bâtisse la quittes
give you that her that space of mind
where you don't have the negative très
cher en
au niveau 1 all my life i'm nhl soit un
guide all my life in one after they do
you want to smoke h trail top ait heurté
to work with it so wanna go travel in
this producing contraire a dit d'entrée
ligot at the fittest chine to learn the
trade awad a dit pas nice théâtre longue
jupe producing presse mais google a tous
moque
you need to make it yourself et si notre
force elle what you what are you ready
to start of the local sohail instead of
coming angels buying something staying
at best of your day à western dance with
her with the family and well you you're
not there to learn because you work in
their work space and you work with that
you and i want you can à l'équation
actualité caserne au google notebook se
bat audit nothing but did you do you do
l'homme zannini n'ya sachs h is that the
dry un une cure de raisin
then in india et big and different
because you're still the résine en opale
move your hand one the plant is live at
the peak over flowers in time soleil
avec pretty strong relais shon with her
with the plant based hier à ce match
avec coude appreciate the flowers
l'athabasca racing to call exact date
résine et toi style hall
baptisé icetouch de stands flower one à
came here to the two days and furious et
étaient meilleurs solide travelling
producing contrit people coude
appreciate bataille admet 2 h 29 dit
trulli kern bataille d'idées
what was in portante was awarded à go to
make that as that what the quality of
quality came from the place à gwangju
make it so that if you if you stay ne
valait a été à étendre aux fit or if you
go habs l'antenne tous des workouts à
lausanne où a lieu dans get the scene
génétique son get the scene réseau
alsace soit quality min show that lada
et médias
but in unis mashaal pradesh industria
but which vallée which ham lundi du go
to make it and that's the quality of the
résident et ce land de climate and the
genetic et never been in my my whole
life time it had never been the guys who
might ce one eye qui me heurte aux
states everything changes because you
like that the plant oise médicinales à
nice hayat nos adieux date de plantes
oise oise médicinales un haided the
scene d'un ennemi produit aussi
contribuer ou en de good stuff you go to
the producing pay as you go s 10 passes
possibles inside and you up with family
that you can't do do you cannot tout
misé family n'aimerait rien gold c'est
moins d'amis ou crise au family
in pakistani mine bien il n'est pas un
leurre or in marocco soa use emma rallye
cup subi un bol tout
to connect with
with the farm in one after work with
aficionado il soit style hollande et
west hill the climb matt busby hines se
cultivant il faut y voi breeder witcher
lot crédit talent sur given and then
it's not looking producing contre il à
les accueillir farmer that is dedicated
for six months
cette plante strife introducing contre
isaac of the ground zero le site sur in
the winning season and that they are
there so in my mind highway and became
en laye que le wine maker hannauer quiz
certaines cultivars d'attac groen une
certaine vineyards bones the value of
what have you it's not me mais qui n'y
est in the paint of origin and the
people's aid crié tu es 2e producteur
rock hour with its not me everything
that you si on agit it's not me it's un
expression of the quality that is gone
in et morale triangle wilson groen
plainte
so is it vastly différentes if you
putman chikhi farm in marocco à notre
gain de 12 cm quality inn à gaya totally
dépendantes
on ne fermera non le genetic there is
nothing more important in my life
john mayer my small farmers rising
because of the wise as cannes au doux et
nice et going back for all the odds
eighteen solide years of making h one
aka meilleur taux américains à wall
street in good with the tools bonne
forme in making a choisi just something
à was going every year to be able to
smoke good stuff not really passtime
something that was really importante
because à god has been initiés
to be free formant seynod montagny niña
en livestream format of making a choisi
hexagonaux things i hate ignore d'être
adaptée que new way from un fromage
but when i'm here to the states with
that vie jeunes avec sac thulliez
médecine à the web il m'a aidé a dit
kemal à kraft man and craft maniériste u
sing sing your life services de
production work with and there is to you
work crise sera in use to le supérieur
ayad play with two left and right in
with many families in different contrit
dalian au cloud hawass total 10 min
beaucoup de producteurs aux working with
hawass kolingba de pollen in outside
américain louvre résine elle travaille
comme aide un col paul and which is not
really à une foule tout
to define de producteurs you were kings
wyss so not only because i'm the
controversial henaini noites do not only
dit d'ailleurs heini two to prove maïs
half boudry holes eighteen eu un solide
travelling introducing compte y aille
avec sperian celui-là tabs tf1 iliad
never had en surf hors is lacking ashton
u-sing comprises et donc si vous résidez
replanter donc 6ème until the three two
times en kurde battait don't you the
world cup c'est john qui faisait mine
spécifique room for so long ce one you
ask me why do you do that because it
makes better days in which is trop ones
et press and you i'm with you press and
why do with it because it makes better
haschich de 2nd soeur it's in the fact
that they know and that has been prouve
en dessous de génération en génération
en génération 9 h make her body dont of
the sayans behind the just do that it's
so aïe aïe à de lot of quest one eye
care maniabilité douteuse sayans à une
forme isaf rca need to know what what is
it that ayem actu leasing trahi comme ce
trail comme it's already gone in itself
the plank kingdom produits ou somewhere
organic illustre iron and its basique
lise jeu toulouse à deux plantes used ou
manipulent est evry living 'mobile'
organismes fort reproduction you have to
say that the plant kingdom alpha vendre
million years of the evolution of over
there definitely aware un mot certaine
ni aveu saint sauves intelligence
because they literally rule the planet
through un expression of terpènes
dessous vendre sa zone qui ont tenté
produce the abbey nabeul tous concourir
the whole world
why they're not mo by some things that
un we know all au top singles bottes
strikes and bones haillan ce cas notre
figure out what the full potential of
the stone roses en campagne can be
because there is no al chemist can't
even visualise so much to play with 1,10
g the most toxiques to the most
beneficial campagne et reese en eau
planète
so ricon à préty widely used by the way
the plant kingdom of the reason i want
plant in for drugs and plant known that
produce cannabinoïdes
creighton art mostly seen as to into
catégorie you have the hell is here i
want that really lukla clinton airs
interprétés abrasives 1 0
une grand orgue rendu là entre un trail
konan dit ce grand du leur tritone that
produce 12 organique qu'en bande ont
misé cannabis plantes produce
cannabinoïdes on his de cannabinoïdes
plantes can buy ou synthétise the two
most common campan d'une molécule une
une plante kingdom terpènes en phénols
everything that you is that is green is
made of enough
entertain everything that semelle est
certaine wishbone cité racing terpènes
is highly toxique le phénol it's pretty
toxiques to you can get ready sic
overdose england
en phénols on y de cannabis plantes
can't take two toxique quand pendre and
make andreu de fif qui place note auxi
quan et d'esprit balasse so the de
cannabis plante a five taille peuvent
oft ricon she has to taille peuvent
herry et ghiwane they come street au
point de plans de gros on earth lives
airoldi apparente and then du ring the
grocer mossley under side of the up the
lives les rues de protection for games
predator b cazères pretty abrasives
verso abrasif that i give lot of people
problème - 0 trimming because it des
valeurs jay z est abrasive et y est nous
organise campan de plantes c'est crade
cause à titre de protection games
predator une certaine mais où il met by
helping hand pauline échoué en aux
prédateurs slideshow un one is really
danse sur le saut il protège le livre
from from des hydrophones animaux av
freetype aux gens du lac ricon the first
one house is really really tiny tiny
little trahi comme the ball boss one
vers thomas crown d'iam et or n 10 to
sell tiny little little stocks des dons
de produits aux cannabinoïdes we don't
really know what they
muse et watson à des producers en galice
help line de lolif then you have the
capital cecily 12 bigger résine ed the
look that their stock direct lit on
on ne livre il fut lui il fut look
horizontale there is actually ou small
stock tweet battu green it ou 6ème
horizontale vers seventy un dream iron
d'iam et heures seydou produce
cannabinoïdes and we don't really know
what other fonction des efforts de
plantes eynden you have the capital
stock everything will longue stocks et
de in the capital stock and one le stock
is the little smallwood samedi aux
heures et steve d'ifrane stage of the
growth zwan art produce cannabinoïdes
lot more than the cécile just because
that the dimensional
off the shelf chambord haitham plos le
conti wild and as you have to understand
that ricon arnott parts of the mind
métabolisme of the plant watts se plante
produced in the strikes and head accole
second de riz métabolite de plantes
produisent ou strike force one hits my
one and flowers times n pollination time
heals et reese l'auto sticky suivre
substance en hand flowers you know
you're gone de collecte lot more pollen
un you get lot more than normal mais
causes de plantes gosses banker not
getting pollen se produit ce mort
because it went to be chance d'être
saint-paulet ni secondes comme if you
keep eux mêmes ignorent gros ego even
crazy à because he knows et les eaux
mais lille ne roma dr not getting est
bonne série seconde à spect of the of
the production of of tribe phone series
de protection à spector
opda d'expression it's the defensive
system of the plant which trigger it so
you need climatique conditionne unit
unit tous très sûr plantes tu bien bolt
get that stage of production neuve aux
résines ou à nu en ville haute au bout
stock résine ricon next to each other in
the head art basique little things to
each other the land of the stock in the
corridor of her that is they qu'être
conditions basiques les soldates series
nothing that can offer the fool
sanctions 9e of the lives and it
protected from des ide région du ring on
it really got haine du ring cold light
from
franck decool burn in the olive so the
strong heures the climatique dit france
nightend et are the more you go into
cette seconde production neuve aux
résines and which you and i have you and
i work in indoor because you really want
to stabilize everything ils dénient tout
flip out your jays nitoo max de plantes
en de standing est little folder battu
denis twitter attentif à evionnaz mean
you just need to three great and there
is also actebis sommes sommes youtube
coûte 12 as tu n as un caillou bataille
des dosettes ese risoux et ou trigger
êtes défensif system of the of the plant
without having to tous très sit in door
one you do we know cities year one in
one de plantes its own grenot alsace
what it does the ways to rebuild the
sand hate you do not create your de
notre gros trail comme the plant
produits them to protect herself
or for pauline hession which is really
be different and you can enjoy the
maturité au vieux flower which is the
peak of the mind métabolise base
expression of the second de riz
métabolisme est has nothing to do you
can enjoy
something that the plant use to protect
itself to tell you are all right the
flowers is however that tree pic window
of perfectionne for ever is really
define zanon aux résines date is for
mini originelle sur you can enjoy the
maturité of the flower by the régime
but that maturité of the résine is gone
du dj find the bells apic flower saigon
high toulousain sort 11
ayad à dieu what was that ricon zen à
une idée tous nos atouts et corinne gone
in the strikes and go daddy dans nos
matches bob cannabinoïdes and all that
stuff soi ou alain existing il ne
savent-ils
un artisanat 10 so the plant simple
précurseur of terpènes newell's old boys
i'm à 12 213 9 transformations go
through the stock ils tordent innonder
belliot
of the plant je peux précurseur of
terpènes become terpènes j'sais pas si
une tout ça tu mènes secretary vésicules
there the band with phénol truth defeat
synthèse et acquéreurs et jazz the
binding of the two most common molécules
bad the magic bien illzach banding bail
au synthé this is crazy edf figure d' à
ôta ici que half dozen of the sands of
art from understanding the wall
transformation of old cannabinoïdes in à
une plante it's pretty hate corps battu
d'entrée lean it would stade je ne sai
ans bezouce transformation' unit eu un
destin de transformation stage only to
be able to how to manipulate you done it
your way to be aussi on this to be able
to you thank you just need the conclut
jeunes to be able to stop and go further
en ce jeu cannabinoïdes art forme egos
vous êtes membre n existe hors usa de
secretary quality that slowly slowly
slowly fils gap enders et juan become
smaller josaine jeu firth cannabinoïdes
that is that come from de synthèse et
sylvie jay z the first one and see by
jean luc sept saulx difficult to make
that you can't gros cannabinoïdes on y
est battu need the sea budget to start
with the am not figures it out how to
make the sea budget in lab zénith ou
teck lee from her from de plantes so
doing that the sea bijie il se force un
thèse il fugue of flowers la baisse
with l'auteur si vite j ai while there
is good shoes la tunsie d'un tweet
hénaff fort de transformer chez 1up si
dj &amp; him to see bizier qui est fier à
une subissiez all the other
cannabinoïdes to happen mais que dit
very very very vais lire her that up
lance t il à tibi estate et des freaks
anna et devais rire et le lot of people
who clem having a ici bidji et plantes
il ya eu can't get lot aille si vite j
ai il fut harvey three weeks or les
tweaks orly du god platiau vite un but
at the same time dong est we want gifu
extract 26 bis et because the sybille j
ai planté son horaire ce pretty good way
to to get ur civile gs d'austin crise du
dong états match n 1 and cost vite is
used by ghazi fait admis ils furent
farmer ilse gaillou en tuera three weeks
rieur en séries us letters of difference
in price et dabiri libe nous aurons bien
the plant give you all those
cannabinoïdes with carbox il à cit group
campagne attach tweets des esat et
bloque old psychoactives respecte of the
cannabinoïdes la date à ce langage web
et it's médecine deux animateurs which
cannabinoïdes sûrs playing with you need
to get off ça tu es tu bien bolt web
full psycho active power
ovide un you can do that soudé
carboxyliques shon zuid transforme that
carbox il hassidim to see you tube le
mojito à blaye de façon rigoureuse ends
à new richmond thoër there is another
transformation de cannabinoïdes in to
another level of cannabinoïdes its sa
transformation' is also une oxydation
nano dégradé shaun of the hoff de résine
qui se transforme échéant at the same
time he knew criait tu literally
différentes cannabinoïdes cb1 end si
bien dit ce morceau pour if i can make
more powerful chronique peine
médecine liquide alstom à musina spectre
wanyou smocks you don't want it so one
you when you smocks un chêne your price
it with the source of in the wall play
in to be able to get qui est si elle
note 6 billets 1 à 8 octobre au beau dit
ouanna one will be pressing de tout
notre know in this has changed lot into
my habilité -tout cris et modifiant
tâches entre dawson deeper watts high
what's the wild side
hi hi hi don't have the aikiu to
understand the sayans bezouce
transformation just newstele me
everything i can do pur siby 10 h
non because we know how to manipulate
the hit that even if ayabe son petit et
si oui ce maïs est midi à cannes get rid
of the sing off de chelsea mais quitte
si bienne all day long and sending
bending en jeu réussie aux cannabinoïdes
of the à deux plantes is doing well
because i can't you certaines level of
the ability to transform them and making
little big man là que d'un mais qui
acheminent avoisine producing contrer à
cannes produce 10.2 produce
psychoactives à demi finale et use mipe
les grandes biken match ben eager n'en
not only because of the diversité
cultivant à tuer ben eager but because
of that much fun knowledge of de
production working with d'euterpé sort
terpènes a really really really
importuns il fut think there is no body
would by any cannabinoïdes dérivatives
où ils ôtent poutine qu'ils n'osent
inside the box b et everywhere been
doing that for ever un éleveur un
éleveur à 200 mm
certaines des hold-up médecine 11h06
aromathérapie année terpènes médecine
basiques les sauts et oisiveté racing
that it never had any
football
in cannabis industrie un style de jeu
fédéral real areola that if i actu liste
10 terpènes profile of the boss tiugan
define the origin of that bost à une
promenade et mais de band of study even
when the study of games cannabis the
dude aussi en titane hippie states the
fact et assfam durini there is he is
earl seul ucan pick-up not really super
interest in fact deux animateurs de
direction à deux attitudes des oiseaux
wasting votre super nintendo singh
so and the bee gees aprutino au total
tous terpènes ils interpellent ils
interpellent limonène hills limonène
deux animateurs where i come from aïe
aïe soldate ya hockey limonène iso
limonène de limonade criaient date
spécifique résine et un titre little
more spéciale aux heures
tales from any other frutti your booty
touiza spécifique region of
cannabinoïdes in the scene what could
only aux orane et da2 terpènes profile
of the plan hygiénique
it's my love and drugs place certaine
anne ouloto faisait mieux continue
contre kanti faiza d'admin spécifique
entourage et fait exact spécifique power
that the plant is giving you cannot be
libye duplique été tuées certaines
nouvelles il dit va te territories and
the big pharma ou i never be able to how
to access the interest and into sépare
eating everything and loathing western
médecine which is free seconde chance de
faith of medecine bottes they will never
be able to lock dans exact pour word
atlantis vigne ou à ceux thérapeutique
médecin given the ability to to do it
off with that plantes without having to
toubib aux appels de fixe ferme big
pharma because we don't play il ne
s'aime une simple et grand déni mort ce
terreau peine literally module in the
wall experience that you're gonna have
and running out du ring use of the
western médecine richer deux animateurs
the region of cannabinoïdes aturine ges
dépendent england terpènes that you put
with that ratio of cannabinoïdes d'obo
l'expérience psychoactives and medicine
alice gonna be different and also the
terpènes at the ability to to maximize
absorption 9
aux cannabinoïdes ilkhan literally
passthrough au scellement brain and look
donne une insider
of the cell show with the power of
absorption de terpènes av
if you have produite à deux ans
malegoude ntes groupe i cannot be good
bigorre not only because it is not good
expérience big band of the power of the
auction and that work experience that
herpen give you with this cannabinoïdes
is not there so as hb make up when you
work with stream analyse level à wil chl
young du rythme du ring de set up where
il fit semelle bad horrifie deux intimes
l ue dont il vainement to work that
because they will be no power in that
médecine deux animateurs ao melty
elle narre before we take break duo lose
you the world
extraction sorte ice-watch méthodologie
n you have to understand that to make un
extraction you need to take element from
the inner core of baudier l'admin datuk
annexe trackball you can extract vol du
cannet extract tissus qu'ann extract
pétrole you can extract lot of stuff
musée mécanique alfort ce but to what we
do it cannot be une extraction because
they try conne arthro tube errance dire
ex crescence on ne plante des arts notes
parts of the plant la protubérance on de
plantes
so the world extraction and not apply to
de méthodologie à use it very simpl de
méthodologie à ucil things that seconde
partie ce gonna be all about driving
because it's all come to tatou hauteur
et jasmin d'aymane taha to use to make
it is your un amateur 1 d'un rectangle