[Musique]
the farmer une fois en dix matches mort
powers and you can imagine les et roule
because he has clause as my my childwood
et 3,2 secondes brood war the farmer
notons easiware gros in the food a de
fait de pipoles de where is king vers
life to bring them to boney et hino
citiez soderiz relation série zak ten
thousand years have seen the birth of
agriculture and place le wall
civilisation in western en date western
hémisphère et ce besoin de farm et there
is the lot more respecte understanding
for me there is not 2e producteur à nos
produits wanna know it comes from its
way it it from where i come from his et
saxo et ailleurs you know i'm in its par
top cow boys are here you don't have the
connection farming 12bis mécanique à
nice de place il ya et saisir tu
si la mise à profit une série s'intitule
mois nuit
le microphone ignorer d'un trail suggère
terroir even bordeaux bordeaux 10
d'intégristes before the world tricot
nison of the quality of the wild bunch
of the world tricot nison johan define
the play that actually produce the
amazing
project so force de longueur d'1 me my
problem was you can't we prove that
there is cannabis terroir bottines fax
we don't have to prove that there is
cannabis terroir in or call because the
world over know that you making quoi y
étiez neuer problème it should i find
your terroir and in french to define the
theory usa apply six ariane ce tweet one
of the saiyans sins of science and that
are ready to say and death in itself so
is like it's very compliqué tu es de
mateur to actually di finanza cli jeu
full potential date criaient tunick
naissent date is rich own eyes ou world
wild fund and quality
et là ils sont qu'au stade
you've been fait by the oldest glaciers
en de planet it's been really inhabitée
not so longue go yves dreux micro-climat
and you have known yann sommer tout
hôpitaux à the the rich naissent of the
wall cost is used and the core of the
heart of the cannabis industrie tsao
zone origone un homme bolt a selon gazon
the potential of diversité génétique n
awad a peut-être the genetic as tu eu
deux régions amina the hayemaker
highwood un trade &amp; space for any where
else in world ever abhinav ou 2 go back
to india fort ospel et piqué
[Musique]
yves in the heart à revel style
harvesting montagnes de l'himalaya et
not quite the sound and the streets of
the harvest et irina montana irish life
and death of kings 1 healthy that is
sometimes i don't really want to be in
middle of the harvest one it should be
the most amusé in time of the year in
producing contrit actualise because of
the people coming to review of the
police des isotopes stress and gun and
people and because they don't have it if
u akbar d'oiseaux 19e rallye cup
la vipère il accède à croquer tu donnes
because it has to be done here is so
much handicap elle est c
il y avait dans sa résidence de tourisme
osseuse mdf somme investor breathing
1ère bac 1 1 et le one would take
investor day the fucking money to get
the rise and then there is only for
android l'iphone that have been given
instead of california institute of
blinding lights for drugs lac finalise
sa laverie things et ce mec belief
expensive make believe it's like you
because if they don't want to give
proviso riz permite next year were taf
la calzone where to go to tu compagne
d'un guichet and if you have the most
hid us for drug et sont les hobbits
player il very en healthy because they
have the money to two brahim l'axé work
in this morning a dit dan sinko vite de
se lavent ifla que big boy work with the
small lab et miseront ni customer à nice
is not appui aux bottes
whatever a ni té i step out servette et
la regza de mean to black man like the
big boys mean to black mel young le
valais ce crazy if we keep fighting
between each other the going rogue a who
we know where is my dividing where
you're going and we've been divide et de
la queue
never ever seen se légaliser jeune amine
very specific position all my life
iceman et ignore une producing contrit
because avant et de baisses h tous motte
1 à waze ready to go through late to
make it one eye caméra at the beginning
with stella qu'avery other producing
contre il va monter du good stuff your
eyes inédites comme de hurt like the
center of de produits chine présente son
ipo à calgary
j'avais mal criant golfe note la quasi
any other producing comptriote dongo tu
veux farm nos cadors intel zen ze kiun
expliqué à yagg oise introduce you tube
tu veux pipolino m libre à triengen
jeanne cherhal ou kindle with her with
aficionado just because of my life my
travel people did caire la times ed h
myself butt et toi un crime portant la
taille mais dit what they really want to
know it were d'hidalgo to make that h
saut et deux animateurs hi fi de
montaigne of the reef je mentais ne
venait pas le manthey nos vignes à se
montaient nov pakistanais
is always atom z religieux botte à botte
résine is like the people who have been
smoking forte generation ni la
dédication toi tout beau tout extreme
two to have that habilité douce mokdad
review the quality so in india et firme
écureuils au chara s'il ne valait manali
atteindre 11,8 et not quite the scene
that is your day cannabis at its own
site
à 10h09 de parvati vallée so when
someone dias qu aux banques et aux
archives ont tous norwich vallée which
hamlet you used to make that has all my
life the value of the a choisi never me
et oise where i'm ready to one eye
camilla it was the same island in the
climate bottines producing contre is
mostly landresse haine et farming break
the ice rose 6 ha de reining season n
pattaya city john harvey stewart est
ailleurs et d accueillir breeder behind
the genetic and the farmers by the plant
véhi dedic était de farmer actually bien
in the plant and never seen date sous
forme y aille became lac hoan baker and
the value of might achieve the farmer a
work with which génétique i work with
any where the genetic is gone n that
osmosis between the long and climate the
genetic and art and the farmers of the
value of match sow my approche to the
market has always been very different am
la cocaïne mais coeur technically
speaking à i don't even like to have my
name on au packaging out by yahoo draps
zola qui noya l'industrie there is not
the name of the hayemaker en au
packaging because et 2 1 et 2
entreprises and quality watts représente
de quality in the place where is being
born and raised that that the quality of
any pro
doubt that is dégustative et origin of
the of the project always had the
frenchman ils se partagent ma culture à
was born and raised in that
environnement et where all the credit of
quality deux animateurs y fut russians
if you make bouzid you make any things
with en agriculture elles produisent
valliot viaur productif où elle se
produit comme from and where it's my so
et ce bide efront and because i'm holder
iyaz more than making h tout à toi 20 to
bear au levain tiny industrie high have
love you et à coups de stock producing h
for over ailleurs because a dit wang est
the three mile en tête fort fort baronne
et tous et 10.6 got to survive in
toulouse moss 1
entre dictée bol market series
ngô il le flou and making h huguette lot
of defeat level veut of quality so you
have to the girl with everything because
if you don't maximale that you can't
give enough money to your farmer and if
your farmer 2 and thrive uk cheap staff
so is that he always deux animateurs
what you do as the hayemaker deux
animateurs à ottawa où il ya une chose
on
on au quality we actually tout honneur
on au chef is like it all dépendant de
back to where farmer et cela guy ou de
razer pour ton equality
on ne cherche fifi coudes on y dit luis
quality trim botte de quality market is
not
il note protected is not mur tu remédier
aux critiques il on courait le so if lui
fut tel que short cuts and your stuff is
green and a century qui relie nos
problèmes at what has the flowers are
supposed to be on home accueille
honorait la mine and its chaîne 16h make
her right in middle and we need
excellence for the farmer oui ni
d'astrid et windows
harvest of perfection to be able to make
that this great h
ce we à total y dépeint d'un taux aux
dépens d'un protecteur
or markets or farmer avait zénith ou bi
olmos independent and markets that they
can't live without being prêcheur and so
you want this unis tout pilote
or of them active facilité thing la
licence so that we can't have à urt
level aux voeux aux voix de california
is known for because he also king la
botte quality under shelf a lieu dans ce
mot quality il dispense riz any more n
ok i'm picky bataille no other people
who have known that she was tested
joyeuse quite isatis producers bitch in
their not really super connaisseurs
rebaïne une sem dispenserait is more
expensive and it's not as good so is
like it's not working in the big boys
are not gonna make the quality and the
big boy et cela xénon bodin's 'vision
bio world markets à mme céline produites
tout people older than twenty one and my
packaging une capitale et heures et
sweat en date mc lean sketch alwan
drogue
aucun accès le sketch de luan drug
intelli'n everybody's adam céline
gasquet jo le guen drugs and its illégal
world wild douche et like that you know
est la mini cela qui sur le make believe
un naze longue à the plant is not and
steve jobs with me gave the ability to
really see what it is because it's the
world markets
un zeris big boy introducing contrit
that have been producing masse quantity
fort millénium y furent big boy and you
want to produce quantity à 8 go une
visite producing contre yb ifo really
going under because it's gonna be there
compétitionner hardcore ben jerry's
nobody en eau planète
dedic étaient tous quoi lithié la
gouaille france dedic et edwine the wolf
hacking contrit il se dédie qu'était to
quality heaven is not one only
everything that they do in french et des
digues étaient tous quality in italy's
sem ouailles california is not gonna be
the first que the office economic powers
in world yves california decide to
produce on y quality organique les chais
où avait eu lieu à venise in that your
world markets shoot chebl forfait king
long time
[Musique]
sow
ça sent la fin ou encore black francis
n'goran de prendre part à des programmes
à un graphe le trimestre
[Musique]
les causes because he it confuse people
that you have to quality or three
quality the guys gonna take the cheapest
and is gonna expect the beast mandato et
security totally confuse m un acte right
for little bit web to grey d'un et
oiseaux no no no no no no soyouz stack
et aux stocks because civ résine
moiserie introduced in tune in tous deux
au cornet sauvé
of the smoker through billette show
beach masculinité ou un smoking n'ont ni
flower before date nbi forget a dit
woods smaug
hbl chine de seventies then that their
crackdown fédéral and they were actually
event receiving weeds from brawn la des
stars tête ou gros et smoke flowers for
tout generation then be et choc il dit
and as choisi 3e civ draisine date
waziri introduced à trois ans un ex
tracts ou en dessous des blagues
solvants classés aux eua trying to two
de get foot in the door by me me king
api rest of the
of the abstract the name écoute pack
almost as much cannabinoïdes ses shoots
des definitely ou à paquin au lot more
terpènes spéciale inaugurale jays not
any more and the the produits toise
lives in july very little résidus et
narines cerner la vie baudis mockler
extra qui no name and that define the h
market in america is is only america the
rest of the world d'une note smoke and
breast résine doux notes poudrées résine
in fridge est ce qu il fait méthodologie
il se donne in every producing h
producing contrer fort millénium vers is
something solide bénéteau d'agouazi
would have 10 à pird longtime go there
is no méthodologie la can stand touati
five years and by putz a édifice not
really want someone who have told that
stoned so much time you can only thing
that you can do it better if you don't
understand
the traditional méthodologistes
l'exerice nos glaces maker la didone
going europe 1 se disent traditionnelle
et glace making el nazer blue line up
the master d'actifs them the technique
buzz et yves des atours i try to
reinvent technique
there is no pentu go leurs nervis things
you know bots you you need you to learn
about your trade and then you can carry
that there there in h industry's et donc
12 adrian 22ème but when you good faith
the rest of the world you go no need you
will go no need you speak the sign
language is you use h for every other
extract et 5 the use in the world
football for games awards little the
ball with you feat
you have to put american before that we
hollande au stade at its not football
that we play l one we talk to you may
have to heaven in vain tenait mme sow
that we don't you the world football
so that we get your confuse one wittock
bas de football
lieu des mini fouilles afssa elsa sont
ni one game
il faut aussi s'il ne connut new world
cannabis industries and you see you
posent tous est au standard en fort for
that industrie we need to find
terminologie zadi fine everything that
we do and i saw diversified ça exprime
portail for everybody point de st de
complexité au vite
ils doutaient série the sum of the beast
extracteur une qualité de l'eau devienne
date et respecte qui organique
the two 2 to 2 to swing series of the
bands nikos because i by using duten gf2
abily titou capture the move et natal
terpènes elle faisait produce produits
cathares à mézigue that have no résidus
et s'acquitte in the ultimate tools to
capture the most volts alter peine à
tout sépare et evry quand panda 2
plantes is giving you so annacone forme
de perfume industrie souayah veulent
l'atteindre et speed for it it's not
because d'iam stock in mind is he is
already sommeil for me to learn just
about haschich dati cela faisait 2
despite the fasciné shon est
l'attraction de la thaïlande
ahiafor extraction d'adn au rouet à
cannes dedic et time tweet lieu dans la
mine because it is another monsters
altig les heures
moubarak resterait en deux matches nuls
mais le bureau for h m
un compromis de france court que est
agrégée aux in the same as many faisait
réservé sur l'illusion à vrigne réduit à
chimoio pretty limité de l'opening to be
to have that one you play fils louis xi
beady eyes and because we have seen as i
see by week-end perdrizat ici be seen
with high kick civile we can put your
hands the loss of men semaine
cannabinoïdes à 2
of the specific traîne et illimité de
bata 200 âmes la castelle in you lie one
you make h
il na inona une résine in her in the
body un produit series matrix est crié
tu es paul houde cannabinoïdes terpènes
la kin one you need the skin to make the
one you can extract à alcool from the
sea and from the juice what you cannot
maigre wine hi-fi l'undaf the matrix est
crié tu es de dieu ça ne choque heures
so when you're going to the world of
d'extraction et à 20 expand shônen
domaine aux petits vers city that il
faut qu'ils violent date we don't have
one you make tradicionales h
ce lac it all ander de concentrer et
ombres et la botte
we are closer to the entourage effect en
dehors je mène gift of the plant bouton
play fille dix matches mort limited and
even gamme équine rosine because you do
rosinha extract bots you just with
mécanique alcée pas riche que nous
sommes christophe that we did all things
we could not even to use the go séries
[Musique]
et people in trees et follow me home
manager vous avez là
hachey team manager they don't really
care about extraction noise et 6h et
s'exerce à cette culture
elle n'a qu'à nous achèterons you see
her is the best of the best sont les
produits phares 0 en stage in very small
quanti tier 1 d'ici là que yves esnault
a donc mec est fou tennis in close to
all my top albums l'un en stop me if you
know who knows who ce symbole vols ar be
adored aminé zac au foehn et n'a failli
à vous aimons madame something like
nevers foot on ne serait alors la
key2key paulo rendent ici la xoom wi
aulas tard at least andreu tout andrade
g of use in gresini note un peu le bol
stripping on a zéro note chili tripping
on les écoute bint est resté de bail
rosine because it super simpl hénaff
vieux noranda milliken bécane connect
with that everything that is really like
duten propre et
ne si au tout est à nos l'extraction et
tout faraud et from de plants for them
to be connected y est
sow se dit vas y c'est super important
before they want jing jing jing jing
ning a innové polar machnaoui syfy a few
pout cellophane peppers ou en evry g le
dit cela et ce crazy tout u12 packaging
d'eau et hewitt à têtu district lusaka
is not possible to produits d ascq ce
match il
l'action seventh heaven three grameen
c'est d'avoir industries tai chi paria