[Music]
majority of our vape selection we start
with things that do pods Suzy we have
the PAX era pods we have a wide
selection of select brand vapes here as
you can see they're extremely popular
for us as we keep going through we have
things such as our disposables and more
cartridges different various battery
attachments and then we do have more
concentrates things like live resin
sauces shatters what-have-you
we've also included a few of our infused
pre-rolls in there too to keep things
separated from the ones that are just
flour only as we keep going forward this
way we'll have our flour cases here so
this will be things anywhere from pre
rolls that are solely flour as we
discussed earlier to prepackaged eith
there actually are some brands that do
half-ounce prepackaged
things of that nature as we continue on
we do have our edibles here so we
started along here with our baked goods
we have some rice krispies some crackers
some cookies
we've also thrown in some juices in
there as well really great for the
summertime as it starts to get hot now
as we continue forward we move into our
chocolate always a fan favorite can't
get enough of that the tears and the
Kiva's and we've carried forever have
always been quite reliable but it seems
that nug is really making waves right
now really coming through with some high
quality chocolates then we move forward
onto gummy candies here
things like Green Hornet's Kona Kamino
district edibles at a pier etc some of
which are brand-new and really killing
it some people have been around for
years and still just seeming to break
through forever being popular in the
industry then we move forward to our CBD
line so we have a bunch of different
things
we have the select CBD products the pro
canna CBD products Popham berkeley these
are really gonna be staples for us as
the CBD becomes more and more popular
with the you know it could be the older
generation but even the younger
generation everybody seems to really be
wanting to that CBD effect where they're
not getting high throughout the day but
they really can have a level of you know
serenity and peace pain-free whatever it
is that they're using the CBD for you
know we also have things that are I
wouldn't say novelty but things like
bath bombs or CBD water things that are
just extra fun and a little bit
different we even have some CBD lip balm
CBD tea bags just different things out
there that not everybody carries oh let
the Tok brand so there are some brands
that it's a lot easier to decide than
others um such like we like the plus
that one was this really simple one
because it it actually eliminated a need
to put them in the display case saving
us some room putting it on top so that
was more of a like saving space
situation same with the Sun say choose
the Ken doesn't they brought those over
where it says you know what do you want
to feel and it kind of gives more of an
explanation on their products the reason
for that one is because we have so many
questions about the products from ken
doesn't what is the calm do what is the
connect do what is the cruise do so that
gives them a second while they're
wandering around to really figure that
out without having to ask maybe they are
shy to ask them they don't want to to
seem stupid or whatever it is even
though there are no stupid questions
here you know you just never know so
that was kind of an easy one to fail
like yeah we should put that out there
and really help the customers figure
that one out
honey vape over there same as actually
those two same thing as the before with
the plus they're just saving space for
us our cases are kind of limited and we
have so much product so it was nice to
be able to put a couple of which on top
saving us some space inside so a lot of
brands fighting for not much space so
can you talk about the decision making
process so that really goes with what's
like I mean if you're already super
popular in your already you know helping
us out as far as you know we're selling
a lot of you then we're gonna give it a
little bit more space for sure someone
like nug their chocolates are definitely
really popular so we have all four of
them out on display even though we could
probably just put one or something like
that I'm saying with the Select brand as
you saw earlier they take up quite a bit
of space in our baby case but they are
by far our most popular selling vape
brand right now we are yeah so our
customers can't seem to get enough of it
so I definitely think that that's
something that really helps you know get
us get you in there yeah what's new
what's trending what's declining so
trending 100% this I get you said that I
could the first thing that came to mind
was raw garden so those are right over
here we have not only the the sauces and
live resins but we also have the vape
live cartridges and I would say the
cartridges are more so trending right
now than anything because it's their
newer product even though they only have
two products out right now people come
everywhere looking for specific strains
like if they release a new strain and
then they put it on their Instagram
people will come here and be like do you
have that one I saw it on their
Instagram or you know I heard that
they're gonna be releasing full gram
cartridges which is coming I think this
week um the second we heard about that
we could go ahead a made sure we got our
order in because people aren't come
specifically looking for that stuff the
social media thing is really doing it um
also as far as trending I would say plug
play that brand is really like making
waves and killing it right now something
that I didn't think that they would be
as popular when we first started
carrying them
so they're right over here plug play
they make its cartridges essentially but
they're using their own unique device so
kind of like the way that the PAX era or
the stays a bay had their own device
with their own little pod cartridges
the thing about plug play versus the
other brands is that their whole focus
is to be really strong like a DAB so you
get big hits big clouds and that sort of
thing but they taste great and people
are loving them so there have a very
limited menu just the pods and just the
battery and they don't have to too many
strains they have what's called the DNA
strains the daytime nighttime anytime or
they have yeah or they have the exotics
which are gonna be the fruity flavored
ones what's going on in the concentrated
space so in the concentrate space was
really popular well that's funny because
you and we were talking about what's
declining and so what's really declining
is you're not really seeing many people
asking for things like crumble or even
really shot or quite as much anymore
people are really looking for anything
that's gonna be super clean whether it
be live resin the you know distillate
syringes sauces but yeah those are more
popular for sure especially I would say
the sauces because they come with the
most flavor and you know you really get
a full spectrum high you get really you
know really good so people do appreciate
that yeah absolutely yeah absolutely I
would say that nowadays are gonna be
every once in a while you will get that
especially here because our demographic
isn't super young but yeah I would say
that we see that more than any other
shop but yeah it's not that likely
definitely though people are gonna feel
like they're becoming more connoisseurs
now with these high-end products coming
out because they don't want any of those
chemicals or things that they used to
people some people used to not care
about but as far as like terpenes go and
things like that the regular consumer is
far more knowledgeable than they used to
be and that's more so what they're
looking about is like the exotic strains
or something that tastes really good
versus that's something that's gonna get
them the most high so even
no you have an older demographic they
are coming in here saying I saw this on
Instagram beauty oh yeah absolutely
whether it be Instagram sometimes we've
maps or you know cuz there really isn't
a very much Facebook or anything like
that going on anymore Instagram seems to
be the head of social media currently
and yeah even with our demographic we're
still getting customers in here at that
point but you know I would say the
majority of it is 35 and above so a lot
of the working class parents adults just
people not age really you know and those
people are super tech savvy so talk
about you talk about we mess like is it
a love-hate relationship is it
definitely things that you we love about
we'd maps because with Whedon Matt you
know you very rarely get a first-time
customer who says that they found you
from something other than wheat mops
it's almost always gonna be that oh I
was in the area and I looked on weed
maps and you guys were there you know I
saw you guys when we messing you had a
coupon or you know you had the product
that I was looking for when I searched
it into weed but you know weed maps is
always great for that type of thing but
you know there are some things that that
happened and I wouldn't say this
necessarily weed maps fault because you
know sometimes you'll want to get a
product verified on weed maps but that
would be on the other companies and you
put it in hoping to you know get a
pending request to get it verified
almost like a celebrity would on
Instagram and then they go ahead and
confirm yes we do supply that product in
that store and they will confirm and
verify it so the waiting game I would
say is a lot even so with the coupons
you know you put in the coupon and then
you gotta wait for weed maps to approve
it and so that can take anywhere from 24
to 72 hours so it's a lot of just a
waiting game situation but besides that
weed Maps is so helpful
yeah you don't you know there's a couple
things here and they're like they have
illegal shops on it that's always not
fun for us you know cuz we try so hard
to do everything we can to be by the
books we're you know you know I
personally have not I'm not sure if
upper management has but it's definitely
something that you know we're not
appreciative of Prijedor
you know we we like to keep it with only
legal shops on the site for sure
and how many like when you go and search
on weed Maps how many illegal shops do
you see and you're kind of well you know
go and spend a lot of time searching for
that to be totally fair but you know
there was one that we didn't notice pop
up the other day this store and we went
on weed maps and lo and behold there
they were so it was old you know it just
it always happens it is what it is
that's why that's why I totally is love
and hate cuz like I said you don't
really get first-time customers who said
that they found you any other way I have
a question about the more discriminating
user with concentrates does that
attitude translate over to flower are
people more discriminating about their
Wow oh yeah absolutely so it's and it's
gonna fall into the same category the
people who are you gonna be just as much
of quanis ors about their concentrate
they're gonna be the same way with their
flower and you see more of a split I
think with the flower than you do with
the concentrate and I think it's just
solely because concentrates right now
especially people like raw garden are
able to deliver high quality at a decent
price whereas with flower it's still
really scattered you know what I mean
we're still able to get you know we have
twenty dollar eight but they might not
be quite as great qualities are $40
eighths so there's still a little bit of
a barrier with that but yeah I would say
that definitely we have people super
knowledgeable when they you know they
come in usually knowing what they're
looking for they usually are asking to
see THC percentages and things like that
which is something that you know years
before it was unheard of people never
even understood let alone knew what they
were talking about when it came to
things like that so it is really an
to see how much the consumers knowledge
has evolved so then next obvious
question is is that as you're paying
attention in this it has to influence
your decision about what you're gonna
stop maybe like in the last year have
you well it's kind of hard because it
we're always trying to find the best
quality at the best price because
there's always the taxes to filter in as
well so customers will come in hoping to
get you know a $35 eighth and
occasionally they still are unaware of
the fact that you know $35 ace is gonna
bounce them up to whatever it is $48
something like that so you know it's
about finding that balance majority of
the time because I mean we have art like
I said our most expensive eights are $40
but we don't have quite so so many of
them because of the fact that with tax
they're already gonna come out to about
like 50 something dollars $56 so yeah at
the end of the day it's always about
finding the best possible stuff at the
best possible yeah we concentrate how
many people come in for brand specific
product they're seeking a specific brand
with with concentrates I think more so
than flower 100% because people are used
to the concentrate world being being
branded already from the beginning it
was already kind of a branded situation
where as the flower market was always
based off the Sun Street you know back
in the day it was just grabbing out of a
giant jar and putting it into a
container for you whereas now it's
you're going by brand and that's
something that they're not oh yeah
absolutely it's so much opportunity yeah
so get get back to flowers so what what
is your thinking
indoor-outdoor top shelf mids like what
what is your app you're kind of an
affluent neighborhood so what do they
consider top shelf so I mean at this at
this shop I like I said our most
expensive are the $40 and those are our
legacy a legacy strain eighths those
ones I yeah and those ones I love those
those are really great those ones are
definitely gonna be the top right now
this is not what you would say it's like
it's like it's creeping northward place
yeah absolutely so I mean with that in
mind and I don't want to say they're the
top like they're the best stuff we have
it's just the most expensive definitely
at our highest price point the dank
republic our house brand those ones
range from $30 to $40 Nate so we have
all sorts of you know varieties whether
it be you know highest ones testing at
like 29% th theta down to I think we
have like a 17 or something like that
but that's kind of our range there and
we try to keep it that way because like
I said everybody is becoming kind of a
connoisseur now so they're gonna come in
what's your highest testing th the air
can I see that what's the THC percentage
on that what's going on with it one day
was it packaged and you know very
meticulous about what they're looking
for for sure those ones you have I mean
they're all indoor with those ones we
also carry a bunch of the outdoor strain
or outdoor grown brands like flow Cana
those ones are quite popular and those
ones are nice because they take from
different farms so people do like that
because they are getting a variety even
if it's you know similar strains like
once we had a Sour Diesel wheels at a
super Sour Diesel but becomes they came
from different farms they were super
different strains that was really
exciting for a lot of our customers for
sure what else do we carry we have the
Emerald family farms those are another
nice outdoor one from up north people
really do enjoy those and they work with
their sister company loyal so those ones
another one that people really enjoy of
the outdoor come the outdoor ground and
those ones usually go from anywhere for
like 20
$1 $25 on the 8th so super
reasonably-priced is the pressure of
price pressure downward like oh it's
always down like the pressure dam like
people want yeah it seems like right now
that's really what people are looking
for and like I said I really think it's
because of the tax situation because you
know we have a lot of the time people
are trying to you know bulk up and get
as much as they can but you know and
then they hear that it's gonna be like
$300 or something like oh no let's kind
of take it back or let's find something
else that we can do instead or you know
but that's why we always like to offer
things like our deals here like with our
house for in the dank Republic brand we
do have a deal where we offer it's on a
board actually I believe eight eight
eight eighths to the price of six so
things like that we always try to offer
so they still can get quite a bit for a
better deal talk about now let's go from
the consumer side to the the back end
dealing with distributors and the people
who will sell you it seems like supply
is tightening up meaning there's less
flour passing testing which means less
concentrate less flour less everything
which means prices would logically go up
so are you seeing an uptick in the
prices that whether it's a flour brand
or a concentrate brand or edible brand
you know I'm actually really not too
much to be honest with you I'm you know
it's a really wide range of price points
whereas whether it be the prepackaged
bud which is normally what you're seeing
but to be honest with you I'm not seeing
an increase that much unless it's
somebody who is really like really was
it really popular in the market but
usually somebody who's like really
popular they stuff like I don't have a
good word for it is hype but you know
what I mean they're just getting a lot
of whether it be social media or
whatever it is they're just getting a
huge following so they feel that they
can put their price point up super high
that's you know they're worth it even if
it might not necessarily be yeah but I
really am not seeing too much of that
people are really trying to be
competitive right now
kill us Oh God I couldn't even tell you
I want to say 50 so that means they are
in competition with without another word
yeah so they're really I mean really
competitive prices I feel like more so
than not it mm-hmm yeah I mean
everyone's fighting for shelf space
unless they happen to get an exclusive
on something yeah yeah in Flour what
kind of like is cookies all the raid
like what so much it was very popular up
north for quite a while I don't know if
it still is now but right right now in
this area I feel like everybody's super
satiated with Gorilla Glue we're seeing
so much glue everywhere back and forth
and I feel like everyone in LA is kind
of thick of it what's funny is that yeah
you really do
yeah yeah I was gonna say the the cookie
space I think has come and gone already
and I think that's where we're getting
to with Gorilla Glue now is the bear
where then did we grill legal and
everyone's sick of it we're starting to
pass us by here so where's the high well
as funny as that everybody always at
least in this area predominantly
everybody really was looking for the og
really heavy indicas and normally what
we're seeing to find is a lot more
hybrids not quite so so many of the
heavy indica strains so that's always I
always think that's kind of interesting
yeah because that's what people really
want though it's interesting to see that
there's not too much of it right now
what other like major trash
so I definitely think that just in
general the micro dosing in world as far
as edibles is really trending right now
because people are wanting to medicate
all day
without feeling slumped or maybe without
people other other people in their lives
knowing that they're high you know that
helps a lot so if I could show you
so micro dosing we have the petra's
those are two point five milligrams yeah
and those we just got we just got a
couple new flavors of those as well but
yeah the two point five milligrams
that's really nice we also have the dose
easements they're kind of like an orange
tic tac those again are only about two
milligrams per piece but in general
those type of things are really becoming
popular like I said because people can
use it throughout the day whether
they're you know at home at work maybe
just take the edge off of some stress
relief something like that without
feeling overwhelmingly high or anything
like that yeah those are very popular
but I mean edibles in general are
ranging from ten to five milligrams and
for not I don't want to say everybody
but for a lot of people five milligrams
is still pretty pretty micro dose now do
you deliver hopefully soon I'm not sure
about dates on that but we definitely
have talked about it now are you free to
talk a little bit of
like how many people you do a day or
what the range is or then to hundreds
but I'm not exactly sure on a specific
number that's still my right thing yeah
talk to me a little bit about my
favorite product pre-rolls
and what you're seeing stoppin and
pre-rolls becoming more and more popular
I think it's because of the convenience
factor about it everybody wants
something that's ready to go ready to
smoke right now also the fact that they
can just you know kind of keep it in
your pocket it's ready so we have things
like our house pre-roll packs these
little blacks foxes those ones I really
like as far as like what I was saying
earlier about just being able to throw
it in your pocket throw it in your purse
nothing will break you don't have to
worry about it and they're ready to go
for whatever it is to the beach to a
concert just life in general I really
enjoy those what's cool is that we also
have things like the canned essent
flight pack so if you already are
familiar with ken Desa and you've only
tried maybe one or two you haven't tried
the other ones that's a great way to go
because that includes one of every kind
of their joint so that's nice and that's
the whole thing too is I always talk
about how I really think that the
cannabis industry and the kind of craft
beer industry are super similar and you
know we're all doing things like that
you know where you could get a beer
flight same thing you can get a joint
flight so I really enjoy that kind of
about them also is there such a male
viewable product yeah they have infused
products infused with different ones you
can use a top flour and then also
they're all different sizes yes so if
you have like a really high to so you
can have a look
yeah and it's funny that you say that
because with our half gram $5 joints I
always refer to that as a personal size
joint because I feel like it's perfect
for just one person smoking by
themselves they're good to go and then
they can continue where other whereas
the $10 full gram joints you could
definitely share that with a friend and
something if you want to like
gender-wise or anything you there any
like you know things that you see like
our demographic oh they're definitely
are some things for short like so when
you're kind of in the like I want to say
like 30 to 50 mom category that's where
you're getting a lot of things like
convenience pre-rolls disposable vape
pens stuff like that also as far as that
same age range but with men I get a lot
more of just like the cartridges like
the one gram cartridges things like that
more into things that have to do with
like technology so lots of like the
batteries and the paws and things like
that if you're a mom is discretion also
oh yeah I would say so and I think
that's why the disposable pens are so
much more popular for that typical area
because they're small and skinny they
don't really look like anything they
don't smell and then as soon as you're
done you can throw away the evidence you
know what I mean so I think that's why
that becomes super popular same with the
pre-rolls as soon as you're done you can
just throw it you know it's oh it's gone
it's there's no evidence and then you
know as far as the older crowds go
whether it be male or female I think
it's really just about the buds or the
babes vapes have become very popular for
the older generation I think because a
lot of the flower that we're smoking
nowadays there's a lot stronger than
certain things that they were smoking
before and because of that the baked I
think are a nice kind of ease into it
and you can really control your high
better wear it with like one or two
puffs okay I feel like I can take a
little bit more or I need to cut back
whereas with your smoking just flowers
you might have gone too far without
noticing it