[Music]
how's it going I'm Sean a manager here
at HPC welcome I'm gonna give you a kind
of walkthrough on how everything's laid
out in the shop starting here there's
gonna be one of our edible sections 100
milligrams cap on all of our products
gummies chocolates cookies hard candies
kind of a variety of different types of
products going on here moving on we're
going to come into our cartridge section
we have full grams 1/2 grams multiple
different types of battery packs large
variety of different types of products
here I'm then moving on we have our
flower section we have everything from
top shelf to kind of budget shelf we
have we don't cater to one kind of
category of people we like to have
everyone shopping for whatever they kind
of need we also have a variety of
pre-rolls we have single pack pre-rolls
we have variety pack pre-rolls kind of
anything that anyone's looking for and
then moving along we're gonna have our
tincture our bombs our rubs anything for
pain that anyone's looking for over on
this side lastly we have our CBD section
so anyone who's not looking to feel the
THC effects we have the CBD side here to
where you can get the medical benefits
without feeling the high effectiveness
is that it because isn't it illegal to
do hemp-based CBD out of a dispensary so
is that just lotia it's just lower THC
correct alright so it has THC it's just
not very correct okay I was like
hopefully he's not incriminating himself
right now like we're doing some
completely illegal shit no not at all
lastly we're gonna have our concentrates
these are the dabba Bowl if you will
products we have everything from crumble
wax shatter sauces we just got in some
moon rocks that have been really popular
so any of the old-school smokers that
like the hash we have that also inside
temple balls temple balls powder hash
everything kind of included there so
let's start there what hash brands are
you carrying so we have and what do you
like to smoke for the hash I like our
biscotti company here got a nice powder
hash here very good for topping off your
bowls you can smoke it by yourself by
itself if you like this is one of my
favorite companies for the hash and
where are they based out of biscotti
I believe they're located out of LA area
okay so it's probably like indoor crash
correct and then we do have a few more
concentrates more of our top tier stuff
in the fridge over there some of the
products need to stay on at a cooler
temperature to preserve their turf 7/10
lab some of the raw Gardens product
serving the shop over there and so
that's like a lot of the live resin
stuff is that stuff popping off the
shelves that is one of our top sellers
in the whole shop so give me a category
what's what's like the category that's
exploding so it top three is going to be
flour then concentrates then cartridges
sometimes cartridges outwait
concentrates sometimes concentrate away
the cartridges the kind of very is kind
of week by week and and how long have
you guys been open for we've been open
about a year and a half April 20th was
our grand opening last year so just over
a year and a half okay so those are
Trenton what's declining as far as a
product like category is kind of like
like if something's increasing something
else has to be decreasing right yeah
kinda I mean I would say if anything
it'd be saw really less fast some of the
teams
some of the tinctures maybe stuff like
that that people haven't been I guess
pleased with the way that they worked
out I would say something like that
would be the most decreased but again
the tinkers is not a one-size-fits-all
everyone has a different type of ratio
that they kind of need to to fulfill the
benefits that they're looking for so
talking about you guys have a lot of
product on the shelves and then there
are other shops where it's like very
minimalist so kind of what's the
decision-making process of how to layout
the shop so here at HPC one of our huge
I think advantages we like to have a
large variety of product we want to
overwhelm the customer we feel that our
bud tenders have a very good knowledge
so that the overwhelming feeling can
calm down once it's explained to them
and they can feel comfortable with any
any kind of purchase that they got going
on so you intentionally overwhelmed them
and then you throw them the life raft
exactly exactly in terms of an educator
and again back to the one size fits all
there's so many different types of flour
different types of cartridges different
types of concentrates it's everyone
needs a different type either indica
hybrid or sativa so we like to have a
huge variety so they can try multiple
different types and find out exactly
what works best for them as well as what
they enjoy them so we like to have that
huge variety we always like bringing on
new different products so that when they
come in one week maybe the next week
they're gonna have something that they
haven't seen before and we can offer it
to them as a good substitute or an even
better product and they try it so what's
an example of a newish product that you
that you like and your so we just
started carrying the moon rocks so a
moon rock is going to be a nugget flower
it's going to be soaked in an oil and
then it's going to be rolled in Keef so
this is something that will burn for a
very long time it is not going to be
just a one-hit kind of deal it's it's
going to keep on lasting for you
this is like brandis's this is by a
chieftain we'll shout out here from
caviar they have a sativa hybrid or
indica option for you so you have all of
your bases covered with what the moon
rocks so are you in charge of onboarding
brands like are you kind of them I'm
part of the decision maker I'm part of
the purchasing team I kind of do a lot
around here I've met I have many hats if
you will so talk about what it's been
like as one of the few dispensaries in
all event or a county just getting
overwhelmed with brands that want to get
on your show so that is an interview
must be a popular guy its shelf space is
an issue as you can see everything is
full we have grown out of our space if
you will but one thing that we kind of
look at numbers make sure that if there
is something that might not be moving
quite as quick we will kind of
substitute something that we want to try
to get in that might move a little bit
better back to we always want to have
something new on the shelf for people to
kind of check out and just give them a
variety of awesome new products what's
kind of your mix of like small scrappy
upstart brands and the big light like
are you carrying candy I see like forea
canned s like Papa and Bart are you
carrying Condesa
so we have some of the canned essent
pre-rolls we don't have their flour
currently in stock we have we used to
have their flour in the shop they they
sold pretty well the pre-rolls
definitely are a killer hit so we
decided to kind of stick to what was
really really well working for our shops
give me a really small brand that you
want to show some love let's see here
any product category I would say
we'll start with these guys here that
I've been pretty popular moving him
pretty quick these are the doctor Rob's
pre rely I know him well and these guys
have done a really good job in our shop
it's it's a five pack of Cree rolls
that's a very affordable price
these guys are killer for on the go each
pre roll is individually wrapped so once
you open the box only the one joint that
you open up individually is exactly so
that's really smart on their point I
think so so if you were to get into the
mind of the consumer like you've kind of
articulated some reasons why you think
this is resonating like the price point
the fact that when you open it it's not
like you don't need to smoke them all
immediately correct correct again
there's some of the companies with their
packs once you open up the pack it's all
getting their doubt you better smoke
them all fairly quickly or they're gonna
get dried out they're gonna kind of wear
down on you that they did a really good
job on how they pack their their
products right okay so if we move can
you talk about kind of the flour mix
between like your consumer do they love
their indoor do they love their outdoor
do they love I would say our top sellers
are our kind of outdoor budget shelf if
you will products I mean we have a very
affordable price range on our products
anywhere from 20 to 80 for an eighth
like I said we cover all categories if
you're a connoisseur and you want the
top shelf connected alien labs
cookies brands we got it for you we have
the budget shelf also if your don't have
the money to kind of spend that much we
move you got you all covered here so our
budget shelf does a lot of movement
which implies you have a budget
conscious consumer
exactly one more consumer that
appreciated sangra exactly the exact and
it's like I can't believe this stuff so
cheap it's amazing yes and honestly most
of the flower there is actually decent
it's it's not something that you're
gonna come in and shake your head to and
pass there's a lot of really good
strains in that in that budget shelf
there for you what what's your typical
like typical retail the mark-up is a
hundred percent are you guys doing like
if you buy something for a ten are you
selling it for twenty you selling it for
thirty its we don't markup anywhere near
as much as the other shops around here
we would rather sell more product than
sit on products and have it make us our
money we want everyone that comes into
the shop to be benefited by the price
that's our main focus if we'd rather you
not drive out to LA we want you to come
here so we'll have the most affordable
prices for everybody and how many shots
are in for 20 I believe currently there
is five there is another one opening us
up soon kind of down the street from us
so I think there'll be six in total and
420 me and you might set sense you're
kind of an oasis in the middle of a
cannabis desert like you probably get
people driving from 30 miles away
I mean Ventura County has been becoming
more and more of a destination for lots
of different people from all over the
world we're only ten 15 minute drive
down Victoria so we're we're one of the
closest if not the closest if we got
people coming from Santa Barbara we have
people coming from Woodland Hills
there's a lot we have a lot of foot
traffic around here we can see up to 700
people on a weekend during the week we
average probably around 500 people so we
we see a lot of people daily here what
what's been the reaction of people who
are taking kind of high dose edibles or
whatever when they know like max out of
milligrams yeah
so the edibles have changed over the
past few years here with with the cap
being at 100 milligrams I know that a
few years ago you can get a thousand
milligram
type of edible everyone has their own
dose I know people that can have 3,000
milligrams in a day and I know people
that can take 5 milligrams and feel a
little woozy
so we have the capped at 100 milligrams
so if you don't have the highest
tolerance it's perfect to get a 100
milligram bag you can dose yourself out
as needed to either help with your sleep
help with your pain or to get through
your day but like are you getting
complaints from like the cancer patients
who are like we we have ridiculous we do
get a lot of people that are upset with
the new ways as you will see I kind of
agree with them it's not it's not the
the best when you used to buy that
thousand milligram bar and you can eat
half of it and feel as good as you need
it to you would have to buy a few more
bags in this case now to get up to that
milligram a lot of chocolate correct but
I think that because of certain people
were not necessarily overdosing but
feeling too too high off of those types
of products is why they decided to drop
it down to the hundred milligram cap we
go check out the fridge yeah let's go
[Music]
and yes quickly since we just passed the
like the pods and the 510 thread stuff
are like pods like what are what's the
good what's kind of the reaction to pods
one feet like versus the open source
kind of 510 threads the proprietary
packs pods like with their own unique
battery got it versus the 510 thread
traditional beep I would say that most
people go for the 510 the C cell based
batteries I like it I have all types of
batteries there are certain strains that
I like more for the tax pen there's some
that I like more for the 510 it's
honestly I just go down to basically the
screen itself in the oil that's in the
product I don't care what battery is
used for if I got to get a new battery
and I like that that pod I'm gonna get
it so show me what you're currently
smoking so currently right now this is
the Fisher Pinsky's pod door cartridge
here the jell-o gelato on this is one of
my favorites from them if not my
favorite it is a very potent a very
tasty clean smooth cartridge and is it
like a co2 extraction or this is going
to be a full spectrum of co2 basically
there so that's what you're hitting
right now correct and that's just a
straight-up 510 thread is not like a pax
yeah I just see cell-based any any
battery with a button that cartridge
will work for all right let's go check
out the fridge
so here we got our fridge we have some
of our chocolates the Kiva bars in there
we have some drinks sodas we have some
of the concentrates that need to be kept
at that cooler temperature to preserve
the Terps some people might not realize
that if you have your concentrates in a
warmer temperature it is kind of just
going to degrade the quality slightly as
far as your flavor and your experience
so for those people we like to keep them
at a very cool temperature so that when
they get home they are going to enjoy it
just as it left the manufacturer there
[Music]
my favorites are gonna be the 710 labs
products they just do a phenomenal job
on my brand on either the live resins
their batters their water hash some
people don't like to smoke anything
that's been extracted with the solvent
so they have their water hash that it's
gonna be solvent list to give you a
really good clean smoke and that's
that's actually some of my favorite the
water hash also there it's just a super
tasty very potent type of a hi there
what's the what's the highest selling
brand you have right now like what brand
is cred just in any category what brands
crushing it I would say like where
people are literally coming and asking
for it
mostly back over to that budget flower
we have a company called house weed they
offer a very affordable flower every
single day well that's going to be our
top seller so it's been are they selling
by the ounce it's by the eight all right
correct yep so yeah like I said daily
people from 9 a.m. to 9 p.m. people in
here looking for that flower if we're
out of it they're a little bit upset but
we get it weekly so they might have to
wait it there's and where's that groan
you know that is going to be up north
kind of Emerald triangle kind of area up
there so basically they're hitting like
the budget conscious person would like
quality at a good at a reasonable price
correct that's correct and and that's
starting to resonate where people are
coming in and specifically asking for
them correct I mean there's some of the
budget flower that can be up into the
higher 20% and there's some of the
top-shelf that can be maybe around 23%
I'd say the main difference is it's
going to be just that smoothness that
tastes that you get for more that
top-shelf flower not necessarily the
high is what everybody goes for some
people really enjoy the terpenes the
flavor that they get from the flower
that's usually why you go for a
top-shelf type of product in my opinion
that's my experience with it but there's
some of the budget stuff that can have a
really high potency that if you just had
a bad day you want to get really high
and and take care of your it kind of
worries there so what some of your
favorite top-shelf flower right now I
would say we have the connected flower
the gushers is a really good strain so
connect it's indoor correct correct yeah
that's that's going to be one of my
favorite strains by far cookies has a
really good line also for their indoor
flower they have a really good strain
line up and I see collective they're
from up north they do a really good job
on their product also is that also that
mezzanine door ah yes
so excite your your indoor yes I've been
in the industry for about 12 years so
I'm consider myself a slightly
connoisseur if you will I do like my top
shelf flower for sure top shelf indoor
correct correct
some people who grow up in humbles and
Trinity in Mendocino may have a
different definition of what to cut it
up that is actually that is true I mean
you guys are super busy it surprised me
as a little shop on a third floor of a
sort of strip mall complex like I said
today's Friday we're gonna see between
six and seven hundred people today our
staff is amazing they they don't rush
anyone out of here we always like to
cater to everybody we don't want to sell
anything to anyone that they're not
going to enjoy I always tell the bud
tenders if you don't like it do not
recommend it offer them something that
you that you really enjoy so they come
back and they have a conversation aid
what you offered me was amazing I want
to try something like that if you have
anything else that you've tried that you
like we're here for the patients we want
everyone to feel taken care of and in
wanting to come back for their next for
the next day and kind of at any one time
I see Henry's and absolute if you kind
of peek at like two two vendors at a
time given the limited space correct
will peak up at 3:00 believe it or not
we can get three tables set up here with
different peds going Wednesdays through
Saturdays are the days that we have PA D
is just going all day everyone likes
usually between eleven and seven will
kind of break it up like 11:00 to 2:00
and then one from like two to five so
you'll change the brands in an hour
Brett are they all fighting to get those
slots like yes
we daily get companies contacting us
trying to get in here for a PhD we
booked out are they paid to do it are
they no no we we want them here as much
as they want to be here is that when
they're here their product moves quicker
which means we can get another order in
and get the product movement as quick as
possible
I would say that it benefits us as much
as it benefits them I agree so yeah so I
imagine I mean because it's it seems
like you know they're a ton of brands
fighting for limited retail space like
what what are the like are there any
brands that stand out in terms of
supporting you guys as a vendor I mean
definitely Henry is original they've
kind of been here from the beginning
with us they they're here from they're
supposed to be here from 11:00 to 2:00
every Friday they offer a BOGO deal when
you buy their products they also offer a
BOGO deal even if you don't buy their
product they will give you one of their
products which is one of the only
companies that does that so when I walk
out of here Rick is it Rick or rich rich
will hook me up with some Henry's with
in it with any purchase and I have got a
gun we love HPCC this is top of the
shelf a store in the state we love
coming here every Friday 11:00 to 2:00
and thank you for the partnership dad
right I'm one of the fathers of the
founders yes you retired school teacher
my son Rocco asked me to do demos hit
some shops because I live in Santa
Barbara it was like do you want to smoke
weed and you're like I've been doing
that for 40 years so yeah they they show
a lot of support
like I said 11:00 to 2:00 but don't be
surprised if you see Richard here till
3:00 or 4:00 sometimes we sometimes we
have to kick them out the relentless
he's an animal
yes he doesn't want to stay retired no
right cool so I need peanut gallery
questions or Lance is usually so
talkative what so talk to me I don't
know people like media analytics or
headset thought i/o or
new frontier data you know some of the
companies aggregate data on sales and
trends dispensaries but typically it
seems like 50% of the sales are flour
50% err we'll just call all concentrate
okay are you starting to see a pivotal
ship or you guys I mean you have a great
flower selection but you also have a
pretty good concentrate selection too I
would say like I said I think I
mentioned earlier kind of teeters there
are certain days where concentrates are
the number one seller and most of the
time though it's the flower there are a
lot of people that haven't quite
experienced or ventured off to the kind
of concentrate or cartridge side yet
that is growing and growing no daily a
lot of people come in they want to try a
cartridge they want to know kind of what
the hype is about it's actually very
convenient as far as the smell as far as
what you have to take with you you don't
need to bring a pipe and a lighter and
your me
you can just take your battery with your
cartridge and you're good to go
so it's it is very very growing very
fast with the concentrates like what
percentage of people obviously have
people who smoke concentrates coming in
to buy it but like when somebody has
never done it before and is like how the
hell would I even smoke this like are
you selling a lot of those people are
you introducing a lot of people to
concentrate it so for the most part I'll
start them with kind of something on
that hash side or the crumble side
that's something that you can very
easily top your bowl off with I can kind
of put a little bit on top of your we
don't need to buy any additional
hardware correct correct it's definitely
more for the connoisseurs and a brick or
your pumpka exactly exactly that would
again I would say that's kind of more
for the connoisseur that likes that
the high of just that concentrates more
than combining it with their flour just
a top off something like that or
canister exactly cancer and then for the
older demographic since we know the
fastest growing is really like the 50
and up are you seeing that more are so
attracted to the edibles tinctures the
topicals the transdermal yes I mean
we'll see the 18 year old kid that just
got his card wants to come experience a
shop and we'll see the 80 year old
grandma that comes in here that has hit
problems and needs a good rub or a good
salt to help out with their pain every
day we'll see a mixture of everything
there I'm gonna help you out we're gonna
redo that where you're not gonna say
that with their medical part all right
that's got it that's perfect a zero with
eighteen year old with a medical card is
only accepted in our shop here right
tell us about that so a lot of people
don't know what happened with kind of
segue into 64 for prop 215 so how did
the physician the medical patient so for
us here in every city kind of has their
own I guess way they want to go about it
we don't have a tax exemption for
medical or recreational we have the same
price for everybody the main difference
is going to be it ADA's equal
opportunity with its tax rate correct so
you have your medical card the main
benefit you can get more of a quantity
leave us up to eight ounces of flour you
can get with your medical card if your
just recreational you can get up to only
one else so if you do find yourself
needing more than just that ounce you're
more than welcome to go to a doctor and
get your card so that you can get more
for yourself and you and your team what
I tell me about your do you dream of
metric
night Marinette metric metric has been
quite a challenge here it is not the
most fun thing to go through at all it
is very necessary though if we want to
stay in business so we're we are close
to being on top of metric it's been
about two weeks now that we've been
converting over to metric it's not been
fun but it's something that we know
weeks work at so since mid-september yep
you guys have been taking metric very
seriously correct
erratic oh I would say bye-bye another
two weeks our shop will be fully metric
integrated and fully compliant with all
of the new regulations so let's say Mori
Ajax of the BCC is watching this video
is there anything is there anything you
would like to say that is kind of
frustratingly ridiculous
as you um deal with metric or so it's
it's very tedious work that needs to get
done in order to have everything in
place into their standards I'm not
really trying to complain its I
definitely feel like there's some steps
that can be possibly altered or shifted
around to make it a little bit more
beneficial for the actual shop here so
that we're not not necessarily wasting
time but we're still moving along in a
timely fashion as opposed to having to
stay working late hours trying to get
everything in place that was very
diplomatic
very gentle is is there talk to me about
kind of the consumers reaction to the
tax rate when they see that do your
taxes show up as one line item or like
multiple line items on their phones we
I like to say we absorb most of the
taxes that are shop here what you see
tax wise is the local city taxes on your
receipt your only it is what in eight
point seven five eight seven five in
Port Hueneme so that is the only tax
rate that you will see on your receipt
that is only what we charge you again
we're here for the for the customers we
want them to feel we don't want them to
feel like they paid too much for what
they bought so we we only charge them
that local city taxes on our on our
products so just talk trade samples and
you know yeah so before metric is
actually fairly easy for a vendor to
come by and you know give us samples of
their products so that we can try and
see if the price point the the quality
is going to work out in our shop dealing
with metric now it's been a lot more
tedious of an effort to get the product
in here we have to create its own
manifest just to get the product into
the shop which means on the vendor side
they have to create the manifest for us
we have to accept it we have to put it
into our system so it's not a quick and
easy come on by drop it off process we
have to schedule appointments and stuff
like that for just to get a sample of a
product so we can see if it's gonna work
out in our shop or not and if you try
that sample doesn't the vendor
technically have to pay what the sales
tax collected on that product would have
been correct correct so it's definitely
a little bit more pricey of a of a
process now so so the small brands you
deal with how are they handling that
because that's a big expense for a small
brand that's not well-funded you know
it's a it's actually pretty tough for
them I know that they have to like I
said kind of eat a little bit of their
of their profits there just to get us in
the shop but for the most part any of
the vendors that are in our shop have
noticed an increase in their sales after
the fact so it is somewhat of a risk but
it usually pays off in the end for them
no matter what
basically with knowledgeable about time
correct correct