[Music]
all the aspects of cannabis cultures so
first of all we're gonna start off with
Dale Shaffer I'll introduce him I've had
the honor of representing him very
briefly and he has been a martyr of the
war on cannabis in the sense that he did
time in federal prison for standing up
for his beliefs about the righteousness
of cannabis and refusing to plead guilty
to something that should not be a crime
so can you give us a little bit of
background on how you know what inspired
you to become a lawyer we're gonna start
like way back I wanted to be a physician
okay okay so I was on the track to be a
medical doctor I went in the military
learned medicine was on my way there and
my friend said you don't be a doctor
it's gonna get crazy and so I taught
high school did antique furniture and a
friend of mine went to law school I went
oh there's an idea and when I started it
I was still in the practice so I went
right from law school into medical
malpractice work because I was working
in medicine and I talked the language
and I had patients every day that moved
me into the law and as you know Molly my
ex-wife is a medical doctor yeah and she
got breast cancer and we both smoked pot
it wasn't like a big secret knurl family
knew all about it
but now it was serious and I want we
just passed a law so I wanted to do this
the right way and the cops showed up and
into who we were and they asked her to
do recommendations so they knew the
right people were and we started doing
that everything's cool until you give it
to the wrong person and she told my met
a cop you're not a doctor gotta go to
die and then that brings us into the
light of Barry McCafferty and the
Clinton administration and then
time let's rewind back in time a little
bit to your first experience with
cannabis you know yeah I was in high
school it was junior year and a buddy of
mine had to be something he said this is
Acapulco gold well cool and from there
it was all history because I went oh
it's like those guys that are
colour-blind put the glasses on you go
is this what it really looks like and
where did you go to high school I went
to high school in just north of
Sacramento if you know who Rush Limbaugh
is he used to make fun of our hometown
real Linda it was started right there
it's like all the trailer-trash out
there yeah why okay yeah that's where I
grew up you know did you use where you
have frequent cannabis user daily daily
from then on even in the military we
figured it out how you managed to use
cannabis in the military well the MPs
and the guys that did the drug test were
partying buddies of mine so when you had
a drug test he wrote the number of the
bottle on the palm of your hand and you
showed it to your buddy and it was a
negative test and when they were
checking the gates the MPS ago six is
hot so we went to five or whatever that
we just we we party with the guys who
would do this stuff to get you in
trouble so you didn't get in trouble so
you had the hustle was we figured it out
yeah
you're like hacking the system basically
I I first got to know you through Tony
boney theorem Tony Serra he tried my
case
yeah and he's everybody's rock star we
love the guy and I got to meet you there
what was it that brought you to Tony
it was cannabis actually like Tony Serra
was speaking at Stanford Law School and
most of the speakers at Stanford Law
School were super boring like Antonin
Scalia or some corporate lawyer he made
a lot of money for corporations and to
me that was not interesting but when
Tony Sarah came he was the most animated
and the most alive of all the speakers
who had ever gone to Stanford Law School
and watching that made me think like and
I was pretty young I was like I think
twenty-one years old and you know in law
school as a first year student I didn't
have like the wealth to like take a leap
year or whatever they call it like the
year to go to Europe I didn't I couldn't
afford it had to go straight from
college straight to law school and so I
was kind of burned out but locally I had
discovered cannabis while I was in
undergrad and so when I was in law
school I didn't have a connection and
this guy Tony Serra shows up and he has
long hair and he's talking about
cannabis and so I figured he had a
connection and so after his speech all
the law students were asking him like
hey mr. Serra can we apply to work with
you over the summer and Tony psyche and
yeah I don't really do it that way you
know you got to come to my office and
then we asked him a question do you ever
get high after 7 p.m. and he said what
time is it oh it's 7:30
all right he's like this this is over we
gotta go get high so we went to a law
school dorm and this was after the for
the Supreme Court justice who was denied
his Supreme Court seat and rightfully so
cannabis the Saturday night massacre and
all that good stuff yeah yeah and so
nobody wanted to go with Tony Serra to
get high except like a few you know kind
of counterculture rebels from the law
school and so we went to the law school
dorm we got super high with Tony Serra
and then to me that was like pretty
entertaining like you know like I
decided that my clients would be human
beings not corporations and so I got a
job with a federal public defender then
I got a job with a civil rights law firm
and then when I graduated law school I
didn't have a job and Tony Serra was
doing the bare Lincoln case for free pro
bono and so I knew Tony Sara he's my
friend and he's like come on you know
come work on this case you know we got a
house we can put you up come work on the
case and so back then I you know I've
supported myself by selling cannabis
so I would saw cannabis on the weekend
all right
I would sell cannabis on the weekends
and you know I had to arrange all my
deals to during on the weekends and then
during the deal during the week we'd go
up to Mendocino County to Redwood Valley
is where we live and then we would go to
court in Ukiah every morning so we wake
up at 5:00 a.m. be at the courthouse by
like 8:00 a.m. you know court would
start around 8:15 and it was three
months of like super exciting experience
and after Tony got Bear Lincoln
acquitted and I was kind of working on
the case like doing a lot of juror
investigation but I was working more on
like the gag order they put a gag order
on Tony and I'm Bear Lincoln and so he
took the gag order all the way up to the
Cal Supreme Court and you know it was
awesome like we would have like Native
American supporters would fish salmon
and they would like cook it for us like
every evening so we'd be eating well
we'd be like defending Bear Lincoln all
day and then at night like people would
feed us like fresh salmon that had been
caught the week before and you know I
think like the local winery free wines
would like give us a hook-up on you know
cheap wine and so like it was like a
very nice convivial Envivio attitude
working on the defense team you know
trying to save somebody's life and we
were successful and so after that I was
hooked on trial law and working you know
like righteous cases like with Tony and
I did that for 12 years at pier 5
eventually moved my practice to a Sonoma
County I just got sick of driving from
like living in Berkeley driving to 506
Broadway which is Broadway in Kearny
right in the middle of North Beach you
know and then going to port every day
and so most of my cases were in
Mendocino and so I just moved closer to
Mendocino County but I don't want to
live in the county where I was defending
all the cases so I moved to Sonoma
County where there was very few cases
there's a ton of cases in Mendocino that
I was defending and then there's a
to Mendocino County like two years after
I moved there and so then I had a ton of
cases in Sonoma County and then that
pretty much continued until prop
64 successfully passed and then a lot of
the cases just went away becoming like
misdemeanors or infractions or getting
outright dismissed but you know the way
up meeting Tony Tony has been really
instrumental in my life like he's you
know what I know for me the pivot from
being an insurance defense lawyer to
setting up these businesses was it was a
difficult dive and you came from the
criminal side coming back on the same
thing I know I didn't pay enough
attention in law school to corporate and
business law and contracts done it all
but I didn't really want to do it right
and all of a sudden now you have to how
was how was that for you coming from the
courtroom to building businesses and
anticipating problems well it was it was
not something I've been trained and
luckily like in October or this year the
continuing education of the bar set up a
program called the basics of / business
law and so I went there and I saw Paul
Gallegos there and he was doing the same
thing I was like brushing up on the
basics and so they basically taught us
all about like contract law real estate
leases you know licensing agreements
like everything which I found really
helpful it kind of like rounded me out
and I was thankful that such a resource
was available at the right time in my
career then I could avail myself of it
but definitely like it's been a vertical
learning curve since I graduated law
school I feel fortunate that I've been
able to utilize like maybe a little bit
more than 10% of my brain just like
there's so much to learn that you're
always like having to learn in the
cannabis law world for a while I was
kind of like resting in my laurels like
right before prop 64 I've been doing
cannabis defense for so long and I was
so good at it that it's almost like oh
yeah I've followed the moon and then
I'll do my prelim and you know set up my
our motion and what you know they it was
almost like automatic but then the law
changed until now I had to like you know
learn all about administrative law the
administrative rulemaking process
regulations you know that eventually
there's gonna be like disciplinary
process for all these licensees that
becomes activated they haven't yet
activated it because they hadn't come up
with an appellate framework what what I
find curious and I want to get your take
on this I see the next one to two grow
seasons as furiously getting more supply
chain members and then as the supply
chain matures the enforcement is going
to come along which brings the local
permit being jerked or find the state
doing it and do you see yourself doing
that and if so how are you anticipating
you're gonna help your clients maneuver
through that as it as it comes towards
them what's your plan to get them ready
to handle that next phase of enforcement
well probably compliance and like you
know really buckling down and I'm paying
attention performing audits you know
like vesting somebody with
responsibilities in the organization for
making sure that compliance happens and
periodic reviews take place because I
think a lot of the problems with
compliance can be that it can be dialed
in but then the regulations change and
they're constantly evolving right now
and so when the regulation is to change
and somebody has a dial then it just
means that they're outdated and I think
that's what we're seeing a lot but the
regulators right now are super what they
call in the instructional mode they're
very forgiving and so I haven't seen
much enforcement and on the criminal
side
nobody's getting busted except people at
the airport and on you know the
administrative enforcement side nobody's
really getting busted unlicensed
cannabis operators are just competing
with you know the
regulated market the people's free
market is some college it's alive and
well in California and because of the
tax burden it's pushing a lot of the
more sophisticated consumers who are
traditionally patients from this over
taxed over regulated system into the
legacy free people's market and so I
think the black market is gonna continue
to be an issue until it becomes
federally legal there is some
encouraging noise coming from Washington
which means that we could see some like
you know reform faster than any of us
may have expected maybe by 2020 maybe
Trump will be smart enough to say as a
you know presidential re-election gambit
to get the turnout that he will legalize
cannabis or maybe the Democrats will be
smarter than Trump and they'll
outmaneuver him on that issue but
somebody's gonna take the lead on that
issue and claim it as a victory I know
and you understand it's about my case
that they'll sit on information for a
long time and it could come back and
haunt you yeah are you how concerned are
you in this preliminary phase we're just
checking a box and giving you some
leeway to clean it up at what point do
you see that turning into you know
you're not learning you're not really
staying on QA and QC and have your
controls in place we're gonna spank you
where do you see that coming along not
for a while I think right now like the
part of the latest BCC rags in the
Disciplinary realm talk about like a
notice to cure I think or a notice to
rectify I forgot what it's called
there's like some language about like
fix the problem you know so right now
they're in the edging in educating
people about the problem and giving them
a chance to fix it and I think the ones
to ignore repeated opportunities to cure
the deficiency are the ones who are
gonna see enforcement and certainly like
the ones who don't even bother getting a
permit or the mustard gas the
enforcement just because the locals are
they want to see their money you know
there's like a anew
I think an assembly bill that allows
local jurisdictions to start fining
unlicensed cannabis operators and one
for legal colleagues recently reached
out to me saying like hey I have a
client and this is like an unprecedented
issue like they're going after the
landlord for something the tenant did
impress no and this is all based on a
new law which allows the local
jurisdiction to really go hard after the
landlord and you know they're basically
like they don't want to play
whack-a-mole they're going after the
landlord so every time they hit it
they're nuking that hole and the mole
can either in yeah I I had a recent
referral for the first similar things
the landlord wasn't notified a number of
tenants got popped in a row and he ended
up with a three or four hundred thousand
dollar lien and his property and he's
like I didn't get told that so a friend
of mine is fighting those due process
notice types of issues right now and
what I've experienced with some of this
local permitting and basically land you
stuff ain't about having to chicken in
your backyard okay because you couldn't
afford a lawyer to fight that this one's
gonna bring in top-flight firms and some
of those lines that we all ask which
sides are going to turn out will get
appellate decisions on will you remember
or following after two 15 when mower
comes out and you go oh what's that mean
and everyone was like what does that
mean it's another answer there was a
recent decision down south of the trial
level about over prohibitive
restrictions on the six plans yes okay
tell me what you think about that and do
you think the appellate courts gonna
help us without well I think in that
case the appellate court did strike down
like you know
restrictions as unreasonable
restrictions on the word reasonable is
like the stuff that innumerable legal
opinions are made of because it's sort
of your thumb and so because the law is
phrased in terms of reasonableness in it
it really it really opens up you know
like a lot of discretion in enforcement
and so I think in places like Fresno
we're gonna see like maybe them backing
off after the legislative loss but in
neighboring counties they may not get
the message and they may still play
silly and if this is the kind of impact
litigation that requires like several
victories in a row so that all the
counties yeah not just one district is
that an opinion yeah once they started
seeing a trend and they started seeing
everybody's paying attorney fees then I
start serving them in their pocketbook
where it hurts and really that's how you
make systemic change using strategic
litigation I I what I'd like to have
your thoughts on the delivery across the
entire state and the 26200 local control
fight how do you think that's going to
turn out well I think right now the
fight has been lost by this
sheriff's and the cities but they might
take it to court claiming that the
regulations are inconsistent with the
state law and with prop 64 and local
control and their mandate I don't really
think that ultimately they're gonna win
it's almost like tilting at windmills
because the ones that do allow bass are
just gonna be like serving the
unregulated delivery services which are
still advertising on weed maps I think a
bigger issue is like weed maps
continuing to advertise all of these
unlicensed delivery services I wish that
regulators would just create like a Wii
Maps license category and stop this
charade
right and give everybody a license if
that's the way they're gonna allow it to
continue playing out and make everybody
kind of be on a more even playing field
and you know but I also understand that
you know local control and local control
is required I'm a I anticipate that
maybe we'll see like a local
jurisdiction start handing out like
virtually unlimited number of delivery
licenses you know as long as they have
an office in that jurisdiction and maybe
they have other locations for the rest
of the operation I don't know like it
gets a little dicey with that but there
is no delivery rate radius I know their
regulations well de facto $5,000 in
profitability will limit you some that's
right but this last round of elections
there were 30-plus ballot initiatives
out there and the vast majority one how
do you see that in the next cycle if you
think this is an open more places up to
this is the business let's regulate
let's do resource management or do you
think the ideologues are going to hang
on for a while longer no I think that
the ideologues
their most compelling argument was this
is untested this is new we don't want to
be the guinea pigs that was their
strongest argument which carried the day
back when they were opposing it but I
think now that's not a very compelling
argument once all the tax revenue starts
coming in and the figures come in
they're gonna have to basically change
their approach and their approach is
probably going to be something more
about like you know we got to be
compatible with local community uses and
really try to like put people in the box
and the least desirable development area
for cannabis and so that may happen in
like some of these Bank counties it also
gets complicated with him you know some
counties may choose to become hemp
counties not cannabis counties and
there's the issue of like cross
pollination that's my next question the
we've had some overt threats already
from the hemp people we're just gonna
super pollinate all your cents amia yeah
and my first thought in
was they let her RICO case go through on
smell yeah okay we went to the jury the
jury said no but the the principle was
if there's a damaging impact on your
neighbor's property ie you pollinate my
stuff and ruin it do you think Rico
could be a way to intervene if someone
really wants to weaponize pollen they
could in a way you know and it's
interesting to see how like the federal
court would rule like a may prioritize
hemp over schedule one cannabis just
because cannabis is illegal and hemp is
now legal thanks to the have farm bill
and so that's an interesting question
and remains to be decided that could be
like a very strategically wise option
that some of these Bank counties could
take and for that reason I have no
hesitation talking about it because you
know just because it's strategically
wise I'll never implement it they'll
yeah they're you know more likely to do
something different but hemp is really
gonna change the game and we might see
cannabis all over California it just
depends on this is traditional cannabis
or is it you know less than 0.3%
industrial hemp you know type cannabis
what I read part of that farm bill which
seemed to specifically take the rezoned
extraction from him yes out of Skid it's
no longer scheduled that's and people
are talking about concentrating like you
know maybe if you're taking like
smidgens of THC maybe all those smidgens
the THC can be like concentrated to make
federally legal concentrates well but if
you understand this is a soil remediate
er and a soil extractor one of the
concerns we've talked about you
accumulate if I'm gonna do CBD
concentrates and you grow
the seed producing phenotypes and just
have them so the chemo type is heavy in
CBD and grow it on less physical space
so it has less opportunity to suck crap
out of the ground hmm
now I don't know if that's actually
going to play out because California
specifically said unless it comes to the
cannabis supply chain you can't put CBD
in any finger it's an adulterated
substance and that's right and I have
yet to see an interstate transport
transportation permit to bring extracted
CBD legally across the state lines there
everybody that contacts me but I asked
him where's your federal permits you get
crickets yeah but at some point they're
going to have to call a truce because
it's everywhere where where do you think
that line is going to be drawn between
the nutritional supplements and trying
to over-regulate cannabis like it's
vicodin on a bush where do you where do
you see that well I think now like the
you know with the farm bill FDA is their
only impediment to you know CBD really
like being in all the products that we
see in the mass market and so you're
right CBD has to attain maximum market
penetration and it's here to stay I
don't think it's just going to be banned
overnight people don't care about his
status it never did get make it made
illegal I guess it could be prosecuted
under the analogue Act that's some sort
of analog controlled substance but
there's really no political will to do
any of that so I think FDA enforcement
has been way chill compared to the DEA
and so if they're the ones who are
worrying about it they seem to be far
more willing to adapt whereas you know I
think some of the CBD companies they're
gonna start lobbying you know because
it's just got to be too profitable for
them not to how like the full
mantich i don't think they have 280e as
an issue right like if you have I don't
know if it's not a declared illegal
substance your tax system
there's no Twitty I mean doesn't get to
make tax policy well that is an
incredible competitive advantage to us
camper versus say the regulated cannabis
market what I see coming is taking
cannabis and jumping the hoops and
comparing it to other comparable
industries and say this isn't fair
how do you see that fight playing out
over the next one to two years one to
two years like there's that's a major
priority with a lot of the national
advocacy organizations and so they are
getting far more sophisticated there's
changes with a new Congress and so I
don't want to prejudge the new Congress
but it seems like they are very
motivated to like make changes that have
not been made by the previous do-nothing
Congress so with a Democratic majority
in Congress I'm very hopeful that we'll
see tremendous changes yeah well one
issue that is continuing up in the air
right now is the white labeling yeah
intellectual property rights who's the
manager he's just a financial interest
tell me how you see any lines that we
can understand around that that you
could advise where do you see that
playing out sure there was like a lot of
guidance in the final statement of
reasons that the Bureau of cannabis
controlled issued and they basically
said anybody who exert control over a
licensee is considered an owner and so
the BCC reg
they have a definition of owner that is
very different than what lawyers or
regular people think of when they hear
the word owner normally ownership means
that you have some sort of interest and
that you own whatever the property is
well according to the BCC you don't have
to have any ownership interests in order
to be an owner you could be an owner by
the mere fact that you are basically
like directing or managing or
controlling the cannabis business and
that creates an issue for intellectual
property brand owners you know that's
different than a BCC owner just somebody
who owns rights and intellectual
property and the issue is if they're
going to sell their intellectual
property or assign rights to the
intellectual property great they sold it
it's off their hands they can sell it to
the licensee but if they want to license
their brand basically rent the
intellectual property they have to
maintain control over it so it's not a
naked license which is in trademark law
naked licenses when you try to license a
brand or a mark but you don't exert any
quality control over how the market is
used and therefore you're basically
surrendering control and when you
surrender control it becomes public
domain and you no longer have
protectable rights in the market and so
basically because of the requirement of
not giving up control to avoid giving a
naked license
a lot of brand owners are now have to
exert control over licensees meaning
they have to register as owners under
five zero zero three of the proposed
regulation that really expands in my
view what most people understood to be
an owner they thought like an owner
somebody may be like you know the plant
manager could be an owner even though
they don't have an actual ownership
interest there there
but somebody who is just basically you
know directing and you know the
specifications and the way that the
product will be built but they're not
there on an everyday basis they may be
considered an owner so the advice I'm
going to give my clients is and the BCC
said this isn't in the regulations final
statement of reasons is the BCC will
give you guidance come to us and we'll
tell you so I think the safe thing is to
ask better safe than sorry and basically
say you know the control we exert is
limited but it is some sort of control
can you consider this an owner and I
think the BCC basically wants to know
anybody who is playing the game yeah if
you got to play the game you got to wear
a Jersey you got to be on a team if you
don't want to wear a Jersey get off the
field it's basically what the BCC is
saying well and the marketing of
products exists yes and this dropped
into it and they just went to work
marketing yes and so we have these weird
sets of control rules that are
incompatible with the real legal world
of IP yes and I we don't have an answer
yet but I have some clients who have
salaried Plus employees who get a piece
of the sales and stuff like that
cheering because you know that's like a
modern compensation trend it is I take
the business those are those are
financial interested people and they
have to be declared of course but
they're getting more than 20 percent now
their owners are not a new rests the how
far up they're gonna swim for an
individual let's say that a brand is
owned by another corporation oh good
question
so my pick is they want to know
everybody their note no more of this
hiding behind some some site door that's
a regulation the regulations are quite
explicit about exactly what you're
talking about that they will be no more
corporate layering it's what they call
it it says having you know a shell
corporation owned by a shell corporation
owned by another shell corporation owned
by numerous shell corporations
now the Bureau of cannabis control to
make sure that nobody who shouldn't have
a ownership interest in a laboratory has
one they want to get back to individuals
so like whenever an owner is a corporate
entity either a corporation or you know
LLC limited liability corporation or
even a partnership or some sort of like
legal entity that is not a natural
person they're gonna go to see who owns
that entity until only natural persons
are left and they don't call them
natural persons and the regulations that
call them individuals which is kind of
goofy and I guess individual you know
that bring that brings to mind that
goofy prop 215 case about people versus
Peron where it said a caregiver is an
individual who assumes primary
responsibility for the health safety or
housing of the patient and therefore a
cannabis club is not and cannot be a
caregiver yeah but that word individual
in the regulations you know is it's kind
of basically I I think it's okay for
them I want transparency and to see who
is pulling the strings because
corporations always act through their
officers and directors and their
employees and so it is good to see who
is behind this and if people you know
are ashamed to be in the cannabis
industry then they shouldn't be in it if
people shouldn't be in the cannabis
industry for whatever reason maybe
they're like a convicted fraudster then
that should be disclosed and they should
not be allowed in the industry it's bad
enough the way it is now with you know
the checks and you know the regulators
are not really enforcing any of the
agreements you know there's licensees
getting burned left and right on deals
court gone wrong and I'm not seeing one
of the regulations that says you have to
satisfy all court judgments you know
and there should be what let me ask you
about the metrics to buy products I'm
having a lot of discussions with people
drafting contracts with me and for me so
if I go to court and you don't pay
because she said they didn't give they
didn't deliver what you what she
contracted for and I asked you well then
what did you contract for and you use
terms like it was top-shelf okay and you
and I know that we're taught to break
things into their component parts what's
the metrics if your value is its
terpenes and it's cold process what does
that mean if you want a certain
cannabinoid chemo type profile what does
that mean water content have you are you
having discussions with attorneys
drafting these agreements on dialing in
these terms yes you want to have a level
of granularity in the terms like you
know for example if you're gonna do a
distribution agreement and somebody's
gonna be granting territorial rights
it's better to be granular if you are a
distributor and not give exclusive
rights for the whole state of California
to a distributor who can only
effectively destroy
maybe in the Bay Area but does not have
any market penetration in LA or San
Diego or Fresno or Bakersfield or
Sacramento or anywhere else in the state
and what you're talking about it's like
specifying the product and you know just
calling the product marijuana you know
ideally you would be specifying like
you're saying all of the desirable
characteristics that you want we haven't
seen that level of granularity as a
standard practice yet but we will in the
future because there's gonna be like in
more accurate testing available and I
think a lot of these criteria that
you're discussing are going to be key
into testing you know like the moisture
content and the terpenoid and the
cannabinoid you know that's a great
point well in writing conditions into
contracts that if it isn't a it's gonna
be B and we're gonna price to be at this
and here it's great and if it's not be
at C and rather than have to go hire us
at our reasonable rates to figure this
out in court I'm trying to teach people
do it now and in when you're like we're
hugging and kissing figure out how
you're gonna disagree okay absolutely
yeah the best time I figure out the
break-up is you know maybe before you're
hugging and kissing you know it's like
before you sign the contract yeah and
it's many times like a prenup but it's
good for people to think about like what
happens because if they have
expectations that they don't want a
breakup to happen and it's gonna be a
very painful breakup many times that
will help them a dear to their
obligations and not be so cavalier about
I always encourage my clients to put it
in writing and be very definite about
the terms and the more you think about
the terms like the more granular it can
get is it a good idea to have a template
that gives the client the whole range of
possibilities and all the points of
negotiation absolutely you know I think
you're doing them a service instead of
charging them on a per contract basis to
come up with a master contract and teach
them you know what the points of
negotiation are and then they can kind
of figure that out on their own and put
that in the contract many times it's
always good for them to have it reviewed
you know so I always tell my clients
like you know you can go ahead and write
your contract but if you want to run it
by me you know it's gonna cost a lot
less money because it's an edit it's not
writing from scratch and that way you
have like a second pair of eyes on it
and it's always good to like you know
have somebody else look at it myself
with my own work I always have somebody
look at it and I always sleep on it if I
have a chance to look at it with fresh
eyes I see a round of cannibalism in
some of the legacy people right now who
just aren't paying for the products
they're receiving they're spending money
on other things and not paying the
suppliers there I see a huge mess oh
there's a lot to be fixed somehow I call
it cannibalism because the industry team
is circular firing squad or eat itself
up tell me what you see coming with that
well I think you make a very good point
that you know a lot of people are like
robbing Peter to pay Paul and by that I
mean it's usually distribution companies
who are getting fronted all this product
and they're making promises that once it
sells will pay you and then these poor
farmers are waiting and waiting and
waiting and they're not getting paid and
there's always a new excuse and so I am
I have heard many stories like what your
man
you know because right now I think
there's no standard terms in the
industry there's no industry standard
anything and so it hasn't really been
defined there's definitely going to be
the very ethical distribution companies
very ethical cultivators manufacturers
retailers who probably will set like
best practices that will just thrive and
be successful business models that
everybody will imitate but for now that
has not yet emerged and there's a lot of
like business models that are basically
underwritten by venture capitalists who
are burning money and giving them seven
years runway to make stupid decisions
and many companies have that you know
kind of long runway and so we're seeing
a lot of distortions in the market
because very inefficient operations are
gaining market share and they're not
producing any money they're like losing
money you know faster than they can gain
it but then they're able to claim that
they're making tens of millions of
dollars in revenues while omitting the
inconvenient fact that they're losing
far more than well they're being enabled
to be inefficient yes there was a recent
laboratory problem in Sacramento yeah
where it looks like there was at least
fraudulent activity maybe criminal
activity and now the lab director said
that he had been you know keeping it
from the owner and from everybody else
actly which kind of almost points a
gross
you know negligence on the part of well
others the phrase they had was Pennywise
and pound-foolish because they had no
one watching him
doing it but my question is this may be
the first time or an insurance company
says no we're gonna deny a claim because
it was our liabilities based on criminal
activity are you seeing any holes in the
insurance industry for the supply chain
that you have to contract or bridge
around you or do you see that everything
is now covered by a an insurance policy
of some type
well there's insurance companies that
will sell insurance for pretty much
every need whether or not they actually
pay on these claims or claim that the
exclusions you know are triggered and
that they don't have to pay the claim is
a totally different question I happen to
know an insurance executive who
basically tells me that a lot of times
when they're writing the exclusions
they're trying to make it so that
they're paying minimal claims you know
that they can litigate all of these
non-payment of claims against the bad
faith insurance denial lawsuit so I
think insurance companies are pretty
slick in what they do like they I
haven't heard too many cases of
insurance companies paying claims you
know and making good on the coverage
they're making a killing everybody has
to get insurance these days I was an
insurance defense lawyer so I've had
these discussions about reserving money
and I know how they play the game but
I've also had some discussions with
attorneys who are coverage counsel who
specialized in review things that tell
me that these these non admitted
carriers are playing fast and loose and
you're going to have a hard time doing
anything
if they really deny and dump and run on
you sure because they're not like
writing their exclusions carefully
enough or they're making implied
representations you know that are
contrary they're probably doing all
sorts of sketchy things you know telling
people like hey I'm this was perfect
insurance for your business well I I
have been involved in some bad phase
cases where the people that were selling
the policies were making representations
and when they got to come anyway I don't
think so yeah and I see a lot of that
coming
shann I'm my curiosity who peaked when
the first big claim gets denied and a
company takes a nosedive and fails and
they have a bad faith case because the
appellate courts have lots of precedents
for bad faith but they recently last
year allowed cannabis specific contracts
remember when they yeah I'm into those
rule may be 1150 so now you can write a
cannabis specific California contract
sure - when Lloyd's of London is writing
it they're right not writing it for
California so I see some definitional
problems that will get some denials and
you're right they will fight that and
pay a claim because it's cheaper to keep
taking the money in yep
do you see any other holes or problems
in the insurance coverage besides
they're just not cannabis specific I
mean cannabis events you know like also
like there's
probably got once all the product
liability claims start coming in product
liability insurance it's got skyrocket
oh yes you know there's probably gonna
be a lot of like denials based on that I
mean I think there's like a few lawyers
who specialized in insurance law and
they're gonna have a lot of work in the
next few years because there's gonna be
like increasingly more insurance
companies they're gonna start insuring
cannabis activity and that inevitably
leads to claims and litigation over
claims I mean like you're saying like
this whole Lab thing like you know would
that be covered by the insurance they
probably have some sort of exclusion
about like ultra various activity and
they're gonna say this guy was not
acting within the scope of his duties
you know or maybe they were saying the
owners or whoever the named insured is
was negligent and in breach of policy it
already
Omar oh they didn't have someone
watching him oh they said oh yeah and
when he admitted to defrauding and
official or falsifying an official
statement that carries criminal
sanctions and I would deny it it's like
being drunk and get into an accident and
kill somebody just shot easy drive away
don't say nothing yeah yeah yeah a party
he's sunk their ship yeah did they have
a lawyer no obviously well if they did
you just have to wonder was your wait
yes let them go out and do
well yes many lawyers sided potted
plants and yeah well it's part of the
pivot into this industry to understand
who you're dealing with here mm-hmm
I had been to the lab and walked around
and you know ask some questions about if
I had to defend you for what you're
doing there how do you do that he taking
pictures keeping track and keeping
records and they didn't really have a
lot of answers because I'm a trial
lawyer you just got sued somebody died
how do I defend you and prove that it
wasn't you that killed him yeah that's a
really good point those are discussions
we show that there was a new provision
added into events for a 500 dollars to
change a premise moderate to modify a
premise and I was talking to Susan's
Soros this morning about that and she
goes what's this here for a deal why do
they add a 500 hours to change the to
modify a premise and I for event and I I
don't have an answer do you have any I
didn't we went back and looked to the
statement of reasons we couldn't find
anything in there about it
would be that they're trying to
discourage people from last-minute
modifications because like so many of
these event applications they submit an
initial application that is bare-bones
and then at the last second they're
submitting all these like new change of
premises and new list of vendors and new
list of participants and you know this
is before like all the new recs kick in
requiring like responsibility by the
event organizer and babysitting of all
the every other licensees at the event
and making sure there's no unlicensed
sales - making sure that the 21 and over
area remains 21 and over and cannot be
seen
you know from outside and all of those
requirements but I think the main reason
they put that in I think is you know
it's all speculative because well and we
don't have the AOL telling us we're
gonna let this do or not let it through
either and that comes January you think
oh yeah
ideally they would give everybody a
Christmas present maybe not they may be
like generating I'm hoping is an issue
that is important to me would be the
cultivation regulations I challenged the
definition of light deprivation as mixed
light and I said and I submit a very
detailed you know opposition and
strenuous objections saying that mixed
light according to the statute required
supplemental artificial lighting and
that light deprivation artificial
darkness is not supplemental artificial
lighting you know it may be an
artificial manipulation of the light
period the photo period but that's not
what the legislature was talking about
when it came up with three categories so
really light that should be outdoors and
you know the in the eyesore the initial
statement of reasons I think CDFA said
well because you could get multiple
harbors using light up then we really
believe that it should be classified as
mixed light and I'm thinking if you
could get multiple harvests in the
considers increased regulation
regulatory oversight just give him extra
inspections you don't need to redefine
I know a lot of outdoor growers who if
they were allowed to use like that it
would really mean the difference between
barely scraping by and making a decent
living not a great living not you know
the olden days but definitely not barely
scraping about and so it's an important
issue that I have
just kind of like pursued and I know you
know nobody's gonna pay me to write
about that cuz it's really not you know
the poor farmers who need that can't
afford a lawyer to evolve in their
behalf so I did it as a citizen it was
like my you know pro bono contribution I
had an issue with no new CoA without
remediation if it turns out the labs
wrong
yes I've I have my armaments on that
testing it shows that I've got this or
that's not there and all of a sudden he
shows up and I can't get a new co a
without remediation and there's nothing
to remediate and sometimes so the lab
will readily admit we're wrong you know
we it did not pass testing there's no
CoA but under the previous
interpretations they couldn't do
anything about it and so I don't know
what is the latest draft of the regs at
December and draft say there there's a
remediation plan and when I asked Laurie
this at a meeting so if I tell you I've
got R&amp;D testing all along the line that
this batch was clean and now it comes
out dirty can I submit that on the plan
and get a new retest and I didn't know
language change that I'm aware of
so I don't know I would I would still do
it I submitted a remediation plan that I
want a new Seaway because they're wrong
and I can prove it sure and I think that
I could probably get one yeah there
needs to be like some error correction
and maybe they should give like I would
like to see a regulation that gets the
regulator's some discretion you know
just to like correct everybody yeah the
old common law I don't have a word for
but it's the right thing to do and I
don't know what that would be maybe I
was just like an error correction
regulation you know they have the power
to like make it make it right and
effectuate things well it it can kill
let's say a cultivator has his entire
harvest in something fails a CoA and you
know I started testing from day one and
it's clean I can't get paid and I'm
gonna go bankrupt and you won't give me
a retest until he fix it there's nothing
wrong with it
yeah and that's the concern I always had
a big person or a big corporation
moving a lot of biomass they could
probably set on something for a minute
if these smaller people can't absolutely
I agree with you um I'm very interested
in organizing up in El Dorado where I'm
doing work these small cannabis
cooperative associations nice and so I
have if you have an idea about this they
exempt antitrust for the coke that
associates itself but it's got a limit
on four acres but if four or five of
them come together
I've been started asking questions
where's the antitrust line for them
yeah combination of cooperatives I think
they don't have any antitrust protection
the co-operative itself has none of a
choice protection there's no limit on
the size of the cooperative is there
there's a four acre cap oh well then I
think these cannabis cooperatives need
to start lobbying to lift that four acre
cap for a Cure cap is is ridiculously
low considering that some of these
santabarbara licensees own far more than
four acres you know with cumulative
permits I think it makes sense to like
change it so that these cooperative
associations could have maybe forty
acres which is not really that much when
you think about it you know that's the
traditional forty acres and a meal which
is enough to like support one family it
wasn't all that much well there are
regions I know mindo and and Casey
O'Neil I've talked to him Hezekiah was
working in that same area to organize
them and we're gonna take the templates
over across the valley but we want to
work in these mountainous production
areas cooperatively and I don't think we
have an answer yet as to how far you can
go to try and sell in bulk without
getting accused
manipulate a market in a combination and
restraint of trade so that interesting
is roll it out yeah that is very
interesting that has been Syrah
enforcement by the Attorney General when
it comes to that you know just like
there has been Syrah enforcement by
attorney general when it came to all the
medical cannabis collectives or
cooperatives and they made a switch from
not-for-profit to for-profit entities
and many times did it without taking
about of the membership or following any
of the rules required of cooperatives
and the Attorney General was absent in
the enforcement of the law in tirely I
haven't seen any indication that the
AG's gonna step in and start saying hey
there's you know somebody trying to
corner the weed market and make a
killing but I'm sure somebody can and
would because cornering the market is as
old you know it's just like rocket motor
coordination you know one yeah and until
somebody like you know I'm happy that I
think my curse expressly says that there
shall not be restraints on trade and
combinations which tend to diminish
competition that's really important then
it's in there in the statute because
there is a appreciable risk
unfortunately there's nobody in charge
of it I don't see like an enforcement
unit within the bureau cannabis control
focused on antitrust or you know
anti-competitive yes and there probably
is some anti-competitive actions not
that I'm aware of but there's gotta be
you know it's just a the natural flow of
capitalism when it's completely
you know unregulated somebody's gotta
try to take advantage well we all have a
hustle some of us have a license to
wrestle you know yeah well II and of
course cannabis it tends to attract
people with a high risk tolerance and
who are usually not gonna be like
scrupulous adherence of regulatory
regimes and so you know put those
together and the scofflaws some people
call that the black market the free
peoples market and I like the latter
better
it's lazy fair capitalism yes and we had
that with you know prop 215 and Senate
bill 420 and everything up until my
first you know people who blame prop 64
for ruining the party but it was really
ruined by the legislature and my curse s
predecessor Merkerson orma merci merci
merci
that was a boil on your but we couldn't
say that too much how is money being
moves between operators now I mean de
facto how's that being done I think a
lot of it remains cash which is you
should eventually take it to the tax
collector you know
there's some banking I have a few
clients we have like you know these
marijuana banking accounts and they play
exorbitant fees for but it makes things
a lot easier but that really
disadvantages the smaller operators I
don't see a viable banking solution that
is readily available for the smaller
operators at this juncture usually they
have to be you know almost big enough to
own a bank to get a bank account and
regulated cannabis industry well and I
know you and I believe that we want to
encourage the smaller craft operators
and the corporate people coming in have
the better business acumen and the more
money yeah you know my heart's not
really into it it's not that I don't
have clients like that but you they have
to agree with my ethos in business
before I take them on as a client sure
and one of the one of my big issues
right now is recycling everything out of
this industry and putting in sustainable
practices I'm trying to figure out the
cultivation waste and the minimum
composted don't just throw it into a
landfill somewhere but the the biomass
the post extraction biomass is in
regulatory hell in the public resources
recycling environment right now what
happens well the compost it's being
stacked in warehouses right now because
it's off gassing that's got if it's a
volatile extraction it's off gassing and
the bureau of toxic substance control
did a test where they put fish in a
barrel of water and they put the stuff
in and it's supposed to test at what
level to the toxic well apparently they
suffocated the fish and no oxygen
basically is toxic okay so now we have
declarations of at least especially
handled waste and if it's hazardous it
really gets ugly if it's toxic it's got
to be trucked to Utah you got
transportation permit so it hit a brick
wall
he's like a ticking time bomb for a lot
of these companies well and one of the
discussions we had with the
environmentalist who are the on the boot
the group was on the ground is they said
go ask him about eucalyptus leaves post
extraction what do they do with that ice
and she goes just hang on to this
because when they get released stupid
and you go okay but you just dump post
extract a eucalyptus biomass where what
do you do with it that's some of the
juxtapositions we're gonna have to make
between what they make us do sure and
the other side you don't care or you go
to Walmart and right there's the liquor
aisle and right there's the kids toys
the children I'll ask you first what was
the biggest surprise at 2018 how
ill-prepared the industry was for phase
2 testing it was a mate it was a major
fail on a lot of businesses that they
didn't anticipate and the the
unregulated market was still trying to
push invert product in and move it
through and and they just got caught
with a bunch of product in places where
now it's worthless in this system and
now you got to sneak it back out and
they expose themselves to problems and I
thought somebody just was not awake
thinking about what was going to happen
when you not have to test for all this
stuff and your products worthless so I
was a bit surprised at how naive they
were
and okay what were you most surprised
about in 2018
I wasn't expecting all these extinction
events which we might be seeing another
one you know with phase three testing
starting January 1st or December 31st
technically but like you said that July
this location of the market was super
disruptive you know we thought like by
now by you know what December 15th 2018
so regulations would have been permanent
I don't think anybody expected us to be
still operating under emergency
regulations with high uncertainty about
what the final form of the final
permanent regulations will take it's
completely indeterminate and this level
of uncertainty it's not something I
anticipated I thought it would be pretty
figured out by now I also thought that
track and trace would be in place by now
and that's just turned out to be like
some sort of bad joke that nobody wants
to think about I you know I don't know
what accountability needs to be had but
this whole track and trace has been a
complete snafu and needs to be revisited
because it's obviously not operational
and we were promised operation ality
like a long time ago so I didn't really
expect that we'd still be operating
under emergency regs and the tracking
trace would not be operational you know
I don't see I don't see a cure Marilyn
went live and it immediately crashed and
Maryland the state is like a corner of
one part of LA County like you guys are
killing me you're gonna turn it on it's
gonna crash and now what there's no plan
B the paper receipts are a recipe for
fraud and apparently there's a bunch of
techies in the Bay Area who saw this
crash coming and there is a plan B that
they're waiting for for tracking place
to flame out it entirely I have some
some tech geek friends of mine who the
same thing it's like they see something
coming we got some plans here yeah
but I'm so IT challenged like Oh tell me
I went over my head
you know how it works out exactly
hopefully somebody will come up with a
solution because this track and trace is
just gonna like the I've bigger than a
regulatory burden just like a tech
headache that nobody needs you remember
the DMV system they kept spending
millions they finally just burned it at
what point do you burn it and move on
and then who gets sued for incompetence
for letting them get a contract for this
I don't know it's government procurement
right yes giraffe was started out as a
horse and sent to the legislature right
so I guess let me ask you what
predictions will you make for 2019 that
people who are not willing to accept
that this system exists are going to die
yeah you keep asking why just go find
another job yeah so and if you really
get the program like George Carlin said
you'd be suddenly just taking notes how
crazy yeah it's really crazy but you
didn't do it right
we lost 60% of our cultivators because
they couldn't finish the loop up they
started temporary and just threw their
hands up so we don't have enough of the
market that's got to rebuild itself and
the people who are just not going to get
it are gonna die they're circling the
drain they don't know it they're
circling the drain right now like in the
regulated market you mean yeah yeah oh
yeah this is not a game yeah you got to
play by the rules
oh no that's not going away the black
market black market is still strong and
independent in parallel but yeah we're
talking about the regulated market he's
talking about like a lot of the I don't
know the operators who are just kind of
like they're they they'd still think
they can thread water is going to be
okay no you're gonna sink and die you
better hire people that know what
they're doing
and you go in your lane grow good pot
let somebody run the business good a
compliance person quality control
Quality Assurance has to be there or
you're just being stupid that's stupid
some people aren't educated well it's
just it's like okay then you know what
meas your lawyer I'm firing myself
goodbye you're not listening
so I guess my prediction would be
there's probably gonna be increased
enforcement after the collective and
cooperative defense expires January 9th
and we'll see like I don't know what you
know type of enforcement we'll see maybe
all the unlicensed feed Maps
dispensaries
maybe we maps itself will become subject
to enforcement i I've had an ongoing
discussion about that because of my
experience that aiding abetting and
conspiracy to violate the federal law is
a real thing when you have unlicensed
outside our federal protection firm
Rohrabacher
you're playing some games here and
there's people watching yeah and they
they were poking Laurie you can't do
anything to me I've represent enough
cops to know that I didn't get you today
but I know who you are I think that
kinda explains 503 to they said there's
a lot of well-known unlicensed batteries
yeah there's another one that was
playing fast and loose where's that
platform everybody knew what they were
doing there was pictures I was looking
at yes you are delivering and you got
stock in your warehouse so stop it I
always found that finally kind of
announcing prejudice when I would hear
like you know these tech companies say
we're a tech platform I'm like really I
never I was never taught about that in
law school the tech platform exception
to every law
yeah don't you know it's in the
universal convention at The Hague don't
you no but see people that are that's
naive or they're there dude my other
prediction will be like for cannabis
events now with a B 2020 coming in
they're not gonna be justice Fairgrounds
you know the weird guys see big events
probably at first but eventually they're
gonna be medium-sized and smaller events
and these these are no longer prop 215
areas these are just like straight-up
adult eats and consumption and sales we
used to have to sneak our pot into
concerts you can buy liquor there okay
my kids play in bands and my nephew does
too it's like you need a venue you can
go there and really let them sneak their
whiskey in but let them get their
cannabis and consume it and let's let's
open some concerts back up or we can
they don't have to be Woodstock but
small to medium venues can put on decent
music events have cannabis consumption
or deliver it there so you follow all
the directions give them a place to do
it he'll have a sports bar or something
if you can't make money it's like if the
government can't make money to
whorehouse you got no business doing it
you can do this because people want
cannabis they can consume where they go
it just sounds like booze I mean like
the way the event breaks read like
temporary
[Music]
for these temporary cannabis events the
delivery only retailers can also retail
that event so if you had a delivery
service you can be selling set up a
booth at an abandoned course get an
organizer license and set up your own
event and then direct-to-consumer
retailing without having to get one of
those super expensive storefront
dispensary licenses I we tried to rent a
hall to put on an event and for 50 bucks
I could get a liquor license I could get
a liquor license for fifty dollars
there's like 80 different types you can
get but oh the children we can't let you
have this so eventually they'll catch up
with the reality what people want to do
but today today
you
[Music]