other you know other stuff that's much
more artistic but that was kind of the
beginning for a lot of people i knew
especially the guys that came out
sawgrass shop back in
you know 93-94
yeah i wish i wish i could say i had
such an artistic beginning
but far from it it was more
how do i disrupt the whole world with a
gravity bomb
[Music]
turns out not everybody wants to smoke
out of a gravity bong but uh
it still does pretty well you'd be
surprised
hi sarah hi guys
i still sell a lot of gravitrons
[Laughter]
it does well surprisingly well i mean
it's still like a good
four or five percent of the catalog five
percent of sales
it's uh it's strong i mean that's that's
that's an outlier
right you know the the gravity bond or
the gravitron and the spoon are
are the major outliers for us um
but yeah been a long journey
how's 420 science sarah
um we're doing pretty good
um so guys in just a minute uh
yeah i don't know if you know a future
canvas project but uh peter cerveri is
gonna try to um
come in he's gonna live audio this thing
into future canvas project for youtube
live
so dave i think we're probably expecting
one or two others that might pop in
again
if you and sarah see folks in the
industry that you guys want to pull up
on stage as well
you know as you know i try to do a
sunday night show i try to find a
different topic every week and i try to
dig into it with people that
understand that part of the industry so
we've covered everything from policy and
legislation
to horticultural lighting to um
uh canvas investing so every week we
just dig into a different part sometimes
it gets super nerdy like last week we
did um
you know ip and trademarks but this week
we figured we'd make it a little bit
more light and uh bring in some people
have been working in the glass industry
for a long time
yeah for me it's part of you know part
of how i got my start in the industry
back in like 1993 i guess
when i really started um carrying around
gun cases on dead tour with uh with a
bunch of glass in them and
starting to work with guys like jason
harris and with bob snodgrass and
bob batrom and and uh cameron and a
whole bunch of other early kind of guys
that you know really for me was a really
fun way to go around and make some money
in the lot both the same time you know
being able to collect pieces along the
way so
over the last couple of years you and i
have gotten to know each other i know
you've got one of the coolest gloss
companies out there
with uh with graphs sarah you and i
unfortunately have not met i've heard a
lot about you and heard great things
so i'm really excited to have you on
this panel tonight and as i said as
other people you know come in
we're certainly going to invite some
people up so dave you know
how did you get started in glasgow okay
give me some roots especially as you
come out of texas which isn't exactly
what people think of as you know kind of
like
a hotbed of cannabis culture and you
know i know that's changing
but um but you know how did you get your
start in the industry and how did you
get involved in the glass industry
um i uh well first of all thanks for
having us
and i've really enjoyed this uh ask me
anything sick
session that you do on sundays so highly
encourage everyone to spread the word
it's fantastic every week
i i came
up as i just i really just wanted to
make a gravity bomb
and it was a it was just kind of an
experiment
of you know can i make something that is
you know that you know that is mark you
know uh viable in market
um and at the time the only gravity bong
that was out there was the g
bub and i don't know who ended up like
producing those i think
they were coming out of phoenix and i
can't remember who what shop was doing
it but the original designer was ham i
think
and but it was a 300 you know
bong sized gravity bong and it was
really cleverly designed
but it was just too expensive so i set
out to make a commercially viable
you know accessible all glass gravity
bomb
and um that's a really long story but
you know flash flashing forward it took
me a few months to you know to figure
out that
the best way to do it was to get a vase
from michaels and you know cut the
bottom off of a
wine bottle and then put a grommet and a
12 millimeter down stem with a nine
millimeter bullet to it
um and then flash forward to
you know now making these and selling
them in austin
i had to figure out how to make those
bowls cheaper so the
downstem in the bowl would ended up
being the biggest cause cost of my
you know assembly and um and so they
met freddy which is home blown glass
um sarah what's fred's last name do we
know
uh fred shorsh i believe is his last
name
well i don't know he's freddy from
emblem that's right just ready it
doesn't matter he's just ready
and freddie's been around since you know
the snogwrites days for sure
and freddie's been making he was just a
he was kind of a
at the time just a a pole shop right he
was making you know just
gorgeous glass slides so like nine
millimeter 12 millimeter slides that
um out of a shop in arizona phoenix
and um and so i would just take all his
rejects
he would sell me all his rejects for 50
cents and
um and so i would you know marching
around austin selling them kind of it
uh you know in shops around town and
then also like acl fest et cetera
and um and then freddie said hey you
really
you really should come to the champs
trade show which is
you know the at the time apparently the
biggest trade show
you know for bongs that there was in
and um and i and so i show up
with a 12 with 12 gravitrons and a
and a banner and the yeah and that was
it
i literally had it had a notebook like a
little like spiral notebook
and i sat down at the table put my
banner you know
duct taped my banner to the front of the
table off in the corner
the table cost me five hundred dollars
and
um and i put my bonds out and
sure enough people start coming up and
and saying okay i like it i'll place an
order
in which case i go okay great and they
say
okay do you want to write it down and of
course i just
i had no idea what to expect and you
know it turns out the champ show and
freddie
really kind of like open the door to you
know at that trade show i i
on boarded like 300 head shops and came
home that summer realizing oh shit i'm
gonna have to figure this out
so um so yeah i had a i had a product
um flash forward a few more years it was
like
you know i had 800 stores that i was
servicing
um so i should say that
um i met matt and gary also a for 420
science
at that first trade show and we became
fast friends and worked together
really ever since um but you know
flashing forward a few more years you
know i realized that you know
the world i wasn't going to disrupt the
entire cannabis industry with a
gravity bomb even though i still stand
by my word that it's the most efficient
way to
consume flour smokable flour
but despite that people want variety of
consumption
and so i set out to make a whole bunch
of different skus and now we sell
about 300 different top line
pipes mostly glass pipes only a couple
of vapes vape skews
that's awesome super cool to hear kind
of the progression of just
how a rod started and just you know how
progression uh has allowed you just to
build a massive company since then it's
got now 300 skus
sarah how about you how did you get
started and kind of where are you right
now
in the process i'd love to hear more
about your story
um so i started working at 420 science
in 2007
because i needed a job i was an interior
designer in phoenix and the housing
market was crashing
and i knew matt and gary i was really
good friends with them
and their founding story is very similar
to dave and involves freddie
telling them well
actually gary worked at this place that
did like printing
and was you know used to print these
pint glasses for freddy's home brew that
he always brought to champs
and gary was like oh you should put this
logo
on these little stash jars and sell them
you know as
stash jars for your weed and freddy was
like no but you could do that
and so that's what they did
and uh it took off and flash forward a
couple years to when i needed a job i
was like the second person they hired
and uh i started out just doing like
data entry
you know bookkeeping and then i started
answering the phones
and then i was like pretty good at sales
and that's
kind of how i came up in the company all
the way up to um
i'm our visionary now i've been here
i've been with them a really long time
i've we've gone through lots of
different stuff we went from selling
stash jars to
um what was our first thing we added the
420 scope
and uh and then res block was
which is a resin preventer for water
pipes and
um back in 2013
we were like okay it kind of feels safe
enough we'll we'll put some pipes up and
see what happens
and i'm sorry been growing really fast
since then
hi jason aloha how you doing
i have a horrible connection i'm in utah
in the mountains right now
jason i've got the uh the same problem
i'm actually in south lake tahoe so
yeah you're sounding okay we can
actually hear you all right and uh
believe it or not it's probably the
first time you and i have spoken over 20
years
i used to uh as one of your first
accounts i think back in 1997 or 98 from
utah when i lived in salt lake city utah
so
when uh when dave and i were trying to
put in this room together you know i
said i'd love to get jason harrison here
but i don't think i've spoken to you
probably since you know right around
2000.
so uh nice to see you again or hear you
again and thanks for joining us right on
well
i i appreciate the invite so much bro
for sure i'm down in eagle point utah
right now
and um you know it's really really
powder
steep and deep all day long so much fun
nice so hey uh dave and sarah just going
through and
giving us you've given us their uh their
background so uh
you know i'd love to hear yours because
obviously you go back a bit deeper
i think you're one of the first guys i
knew that had a lathe and the first
person i was putting out production
tubes
back i want to say starting in like
1996-97
so yeah i'd love to hear you know kind
of where you started and uh
and what's happened since
right on right on well i mean you know
you know where i started you know it's
kind of ungrateful deadlot
and um it's been a wild ride bro for
sure you know i i've i'm into the whole
production thing
uh that's how i do my my artwork and um
it's uh you know it's been it's grown
exponentially over the years i think
you know in our in our heyday been
between 99 and 2003 we were doing 4
million a year in sales and
70 employees so it was it was pretty big
and it's 30.
and then now um you know i'm in vegas i
have i'm in the arts district we have a
really cool
studio and uh you know it's a small
family operation now it's not some
megalith uh you know corporate
thing but um you know it's where where
i've come from and where i'm at now and
and i hope that anybody coming to vegas
uh stops by the studio and i'll give you
a personal tour
you know it's a really cool zone and
it's a real creative zone and happy to
be
kind of pumping artwork into the general
public i mean that's that's the game
here
is making people happy when you first
started
uh who taught you i mean i know back
then it was like you know snodgrass shop
was pretty much the only game in town in
the early years and i was just saying
before you jumped on that like
for me when i had like you know cameron
and bob bathroom and uh and like
uh dog paw dave dave willis you know
like teaching me like you know
giving me a lot of pieces to bring out
on tour those are the guys i looked as
kind of like the
grandfathers or godfathers of the
industry but uh i know you came out
right around that same time
like from the same kind of crew um you
know what what gave you that start and
you know who first taught you how to
blow before you even got your first
yeah i mean you know just some of the
names that you mentioned are some some
people that i definitely
are are very good you know my peers
and uh people that have i've been you
know in their circles
since the beginning and uh you know it
was when i remember bob bathroom before
he was blowing glass neighbor bob
you know i remember dave willis before
he started blowing glass and then he
you know he started learning with bob
for me uh and dave went on now he's one
of the
on the board of the glass art society so
he's incredible
incredible
incredible talents come out of all this
where i started
i was an art major at the u of o and um
i met
bob on grateful dead tour earlier and
ended up going over to his house and
maybe 91
and just watching uh and what was going
on the whole family scene over there bob
himself was a
a a guru of an individual you know
really enlightening inspirational
he was he's a what a wizard would be you
know in the old days
he is that now and and and i'm blessed
enough to have you know experienced his
his greatness and been in his you know
in his circle and um
i'm number seven in bob's lineage of
teaching people so i was just happening
to be there in the right day
right time and um got inspired from him
and it was more about it was more about
creating something that seemed to change
color the more you used it
it was something that that enlightened
people they would smoke this thing and
they would get high and make cool
decisions and
you know make make positive change in
the world and being part of that is what
i wanted to be you know i mean this is
the coolest shit i've ever seen these
dreadlock guys with these fats
bobstock pipes that you know respected
this guy so much i mean that's
that was what i wanted you know for a
lack of a
family or tribalism or or you know
religious
or something like that in my life that's
what that's what filled that vacuum for
me being part of that
yeah i remember for me like one of the
happiest days of my life is when marie
looked me over and decided she's gonna
give me an account
and uh and that was the time i was like
sweet like all right
i'm i'm in stock shops going to allow me
to take their glass out on tour and
allow me to uh
to start selling pieces and then
obviously i was very good friends with
jennifer stroll and jen was dating
cameron at the time
so cameron took a liking as well and
that was just a really
lucky you know sort of happenstance for
me around like 1994.
so uh you know yeah cameron cameron
cameron taught me my first
uh how to make my first bong and so that
changed my world and um
you know my my history and being part of
this pipe thing is so
you know fulfilled and so you know just
cool and
and i'm so blessed to be a part of it
and so now
the the now in this whole pipe we call
it a piper movement
at least that's what i call it um you
know similar to a um
uh abstraction art or um or realist
or something like this this is a this is
an actual art movement that's going on
that we've been part of and now what
we're doing is
we are bringing light to the fact that
this is this stuff that we make is art
and it and it holds a value the problem
with what we make is that when we make
it
it sells so quickly and it goes into the
stoner circle sometimes it breaks
these invaluable pieces uh don't get to
be
seen and shared like like like we need
them and so right now
um it's about bringing eyes on the art
movement and creating a value that that
is is well deserved and so to do that
you know we we have to document the
pieces whether it's to be a picture
or whether it be in video and so to do
that now
we have made a tv show and it's about to
come out to the world in the next couple
of months
and it's called operation pipe dreamers
so it's a six episode series
um 12 pipe makers the best in the world
we brought them out to vegas and we've
had a showdown
and we did three on three on three and
we on the enough winter of each of those
four heats
went on to a finals and the winner of
the finals took home ten thousand
dollars in cash
and a custom operation pipe dreamers
leather jacket
and you can follow our exploits at the
moment on operation drip pipe dreamers
on instagram
nice so dave you made reference to
champs earlier you know
yeah man uh dave when you made reference
to champs earlier
like for me that was the first time that
someone came up with a trade show that
uh
that was truly just about the glass
industry was the first time you attended
champs and kind of like what was your
first thoughts when you uh when you went
were you there for one of the earliest
ones
and uh you know how have you watched it
progress
well first off i want to say that you
know jason
has been an absolute inspiration to a
lot of people in the industry and
myself included i mean at
even early on i recognize the importance
of branding and i think
that you know underrated jbd is like
really
the first brand in pipes right like
people don't talk about it yes
you you made you made a lot of art as
beautiful stuff
but you built a brand and like there was
it's just that
like we don't you know yes i know it's
like a you know it's very uh
cliche these days like everybody's
building a brand but you know
this is something i talk a lot a lot
about in cannabis period is that like we
are
the there are lots of people with lots
of money that are coming in and building
a cannabis brand well
you know there were cannabis brands
before cannabis became legal and
there is uh you know and you were really
like i think that's the most amazing
flag you can put in the ground to say i
was the first real cannabis brand
um so dave that's pretty cool
right right now right now that's uh my
my biggest pitch
is that is that i spent a lot of time in
in holland in the very beginning of all
this in the early 90s
i blew glass on this on the you know
varmint over there for a while
and i i came back and and in 95 is when
i actually incorporated the business
so you know at those times i was getting
flown around by the guys back in the
east coast holding the diesel
that whole diesel crew the chem dog guys
all them they would fly me back and pay
me per gram ten dollars a gram for my
glass
and so that right there was a a it's
my street you know cred it's it's saying
you know look that's an example of any
of the biggest guys in the cannabis
business i was dealing with them all
throughout and now they're all owners of
fucking grows and dispensaries and
licensed up and
driving the lambos and it's really cool
to see and so for me
i'm network my networks go so deep and
so vast through this whole
path that i've taken that i'm i'm
exploiting that by
going up to humble getting the boys to
fill up the jars with
fire resin and i'm selling it in
california it's jerome baker's cannabis
collection
i'll be in sacramento this weekend at um
let me see where i'm gonna be i'm gonna
be at
a dispensary blowing glass and i'm gonna
be doing that all summer long
and um i'm gonna you know i have on my
instagram my tour schedule as i go and
it's
again it's i'm doing koalas on
bloomfield street in sacramento this
weekend on saturday
i do on april 20th um uh grass
grass city and then on the 24th in tahoe
and just after that i'm going to do
reading oh the 27th of this month i do
reading so i'm going on the road
showing off the brand blowing glass in
front of the dispensaries and giving
away
tons of glass to the to the people that
make a difference the fans
the connoisseurs the bud tenders um the
shot colors
and so i'm trying to you know show that
hey look
this is like a jack daniels of the space
it is a a name that
you know i i got arrested for um you
know you know i've i've done
i've done my my time and i feel like
i try to try to make a positive impact
with whatever we're doing
so you know it's just about karma but i
was just trying to keep keep things
straight a lot of people like when they
first deal with me they're like you know
can i you know and i'm like you know
dude you can call anybody
in the fucking whole bit in space and
see if i've ripped them off or if i
fuck them or whatever you know and so i
couldn't have gotten here for 30 years
right now
by by doing those kind of things in this
in the space so i feel like i've done
the time i've stayed the course
and now it's time that we all kind of
unite i mean we have such power amongst
us there's so many of us you know from
420 science to the different
you know people growing to the different
laboratories and we have such an
industry here that we need to kind of
unite and and have some some heads and
and get
get get business done now
so hey you just uh i mean you open the
door a little bit on this jason
you know obviously i don't think a lot
of people out there in the audience and
uh we're live streaming as well tonight
on to uh onto the youtube live with
future canvas projects so it'll be
thousands of people that you know are
kind of listening over the next couple
days
but there's a lot of people that have no
idea what happened with operation pipe
dreams
and uh and just like how detrimental
that was to the early days of
the glass industry and just kind of how
many people got caught up in it whether
it was you or whether it was shea from
seedless or whether it was tommy chong
but you know can you give just a quick
description and if you don't if you
don't want to talk about until they
understand but if
you're willing and going through what
happened and what kind of a bullshit
attractant deal the other side's put
down on
on people in the glass industry
yeah you know i love talking about it
it's it's my voice what's
what's giving me a voice in the modern
cannabis flow right now and so
you know when i was like i told you i
was doing 4 million a year in 99
and and by 2003 you know we were
cranking and in 2003 it was february
23rd
um the the we got arrested they came to
my house they
they you know tied me up they they you
know they
it was the dea the postal service the
secret service i mean all kinds of weird
you know investigational people were on
this thing
and in the end uh you know i went to
jail there in eugene oregon and i was
looking at the jail i was looking at the
tv through the chicken wire in the jail
cell and i seen john ashcroft on tv
talking about that he got you know the
biggest paraphernalia dealers in the u.s
and so that was my um you know sign that
this is something much bigger than just
them arresting me for manufacturing drug
paraphernalia it was called operation
pipe dreams it was a two-year
investigation on 55 of us we all got
arrested
and tommy chong was one of the 55 he's
the only one that did the whole year
in prison and that was because you know
he
has a voice in you know today's modern
e.t or you know e-entertainment society
so they didn't
wanted me to make an example of us they
used the justice system to make a
political statement
so now uh you know they took my
jeromebaker.com website away from me
and now uh years later i've bought it
back in an auction so i have my
my domain that was seized by the feds i
have that back
um and i have um you know they told me
i'm never allowed to make bongs again
and i made the largest bong in the world
last year
in 2018 24 feet tall glass bong
with an elevator to the top of it you
know and
this is my big fuck you to the whole
scene you know the whole telling me i
can't make art the way i want to make
art
and what it comes down to is are the
pieces that we're making are are
devices and these devices are actually
changing the fundamental
thought and character of society right
now i mean just think
if we legalize this in russia where are
we all
at you know what i mean and so so my
plight
my my vision is that we we are part of
this legalization movement
it's something that we all dreamed about
in high school and we are the changers
we are the makers right now and if we
can fucking
do this we're going to change the whole
world in a really positive
way right now um stop this shit stop the
wars
who else was there who else who else who
else went down in
five dreams i mean i know it was you
know chong it
was the chongongs and uh you know 55
north who else was there
it was shea from seabus company yeah
shay from siblings
shay from stevens is a i mean you know
main player there and
yeah north chris caught up to you wasn't
he
no chris chris slid through that one my
partner at the time was syed matation he
was the only non-owner of all the
businesses that got arrested so
he was one of the 55 but there's a lot
of them there you can look up operation
pipe dreamers on wikipedia
um and and again we're coming out with a
tv show that's going to tell you this
story
we're going to drop it on you all and
we're going to drop it on you know
everyday society
that hey we're making pipes these
fucking things take a long time to make
and there's more to it you know there's
a back story our tv show
that is different than all the others in
that it builds the character
all these 12 people that we brought to
the space
were very carefully picked and we had
you know
very we wanted to represent our piper
movement
the right way and so we're really proud
to you know to show this thing off and
i'm
and this is going to answer a lot of the
general public's questions about
you know what's going on but i do want
to tell you all that
not only is it still illegal the same
exact fucking laws are in place right
now where they can come arrest me for
doing the same shit
that also cannabis is illegal on a
federal level
they can be arrest anybody they want if
they wanted to
including us for over here uh
consciously
uh you know you know making plans and
and figuring out how to do illegal shit
so the quicker we can all realize that
we're just still operating as gangsters
the quicker we can bring this thing to
light and and get this thing in the
banks
and um we can all kind of
you know get the reward of this whole
life that we've done and worked so hard
for i think it's time you know what i
mean
so hey i think it's uh really
interesting that you talked about kind
of you know who got caught up in this i
always think back to that chinese
proverb of you know you never know what
good news or bad news is and
bill murray talks about in the bill
murray stories that you know
someone like gets hurt and all of a
sudden the other one's like oh it's
terrible and it turns out then because
they were hurt they didn't go somewhere
where they would have gotten caught in a
fire whatever the other story is but
you know from the perspective of tommy
chong you know i think a lot of people
forget that he ended up spending the
whole year but he also got
jordan belfort as a cellmate which ended
up being the uh the catalyst to bring us
the wolf of wall street
and all the other things that followed
from that so you know it's so much
hilarious that
tommy ended up being the uh the catalyst
for uh for you know another just
terrific story
really out of this whole thing uh a
thousand percent a thousand percent
i'm really on board with you on that
making lemonade from lemons
and uh and and this story of mine
and bringing that uh um positivity out
of the negativity um is told in a movie
that we did with leafly
so leafly the um you know the weed app
they
do a leafly dot tv and we did a movie on
there called redemption bong
and it tells the story of the arrests
and the hardships um but it tells also
the story of what positive can come out
of it and how to to be positive
and i think everybody especially in this
time needs to make sure that they
if they're if they're not good at
thinking positive you know try to and
try to help your friends and try to help
others
um just be you know be positive in this
time that we're in you can you we're
going to get through it and
that's that's you know and that's what
i'm pitching in this operation pipe
dreamers
is everybody if you don't know how to
you can blow glass at home
and make marbles and beads and be
successful and make money and feel good
about yourself
so you know we are able to bring that
light and use our voice
same as any other celebrity or rock star
or whatever you can you can choose to
use your your status and and create
positive change
and uh you know if those around you that
you surround yourself with are doing
that it makes it easier for you too
you know jason i i i really appreciate
the work you've done
and like i said definitely trailblazer
and i've talked about this a lot
in you know throughout my career
whenever i get the chance to talk to the
art the more artistic side of this
industry and
yeah the frustrating part for me as
someone who has collected by
over the years is that we can't we're
not going to build
a real art you know a real art category
until someone builds a legitimate
secondary market for it
and you know yeah it's easy for me to
just you know sit on the sidelines and
say someone should do this
i i'm busy and as much as i love to go
build a secondary market
you know we're not we're just not going
to build value in the category without
that
and um you know i just think it's an
interesting topic that has been
missing from functional you know pipe or
the the entire time
yeah absolutely and there is a secondary
market being
you know uh throttling right now and i
think that um
that there's there's just a lot of um a
lot of momentum
in it right now and i i think that we're
gonna be all good clear
the the pieces you know we're selling
pieces for 50 and 100 000
and they're pipes and bongs and people
are interested in them
i'm working with tommy right now we're
doing a piece that
he wants to sell for over a million
dollars so we're loading it with stones
and crystals and
gold and you know we're gonna put some
holy water in and hopefully talk
elon into buying it and send it to the
fucking space and even
put some more light on this thing so
when i when i was talking about
secondary marks it really when
what i mean is that is that people need
to be like collectors need a platform
to sell their pipes and there needs to
be a third party you know you need
the similar platforms typically will
appraise
these pieces etc that's kind of like the
robust secondary market
and i was hoping that lucan uh you know
salt would be here
unfortunately he had another he had uh
he couldn't make it but you know this is
something he's invested in
glass grab you know need some work it's
a decent app but you know it
kind of fulfills some of this um but
uh you know i just wanted to be clear
about what what would actually like
allow these pipes to actually appreciate
in value
truly well one of the things that helps
us right
now is um you know some of the big
players in the
in the artistic scene uh have to embrace
what we're doing
and so to do that um we're you know this
tv stuff that's going on
you guys all saw the show blown away
that just came out that brings
light on the glass itself and now with
our show coming out we are
involving the pilschuck glass school
which is an incredible
resource for all glass artists we're
also involving uh the
corning museum of glass they've taken in
their first
pipe about a year and a half ago into
the museum collection
so that brings legitimacy to what we're
doing by involving them in the tv show
now that we're doing uh you know
and we're gonna give a residency to one
of the artists and
just just bringing light from those
giant collectors and the bigger eyes on
on just you know that that kind of a
thing i think that it
that we need to morph it and there needs
to be people that that bring these two
worlds together
so that that that is part of what we're
doing and it's all about
creating value in the space like i said
that one bong that i make that goes to
one dude and he breaks it in the fire or
whatever
then it never gets seen uh so some of
these pieces need to
need to be you know legacy and and
and documented and things like that
that's how we do that's why we're doing
so much video and photo and
stuff like that of all the pieces coming
out because it documents it it brings
historical
value to it i think we're just too early
for that idea dave
story of my life
[Laughter]
so you know dave coming into class like
right after uh operation pipe dreams
you know you weren't too far behind that
i've got to ask were you either a
masochist or did you just basically look
at saying
there's no way they're holding this
thing down there's no way we're going to
stop
the other progression that's going to
happen and artists should never be
punished
you know i know you've come out from a
little bit different perspective as far
as you know creating grav as a brand and
creating something that uh isn't you
know necessarily hand blown but
you know bringing glass to the masses uh
you know what was your catalyst to say
okay like
i've heard the stories i'm still getting
involved in this and
no one can tell me what to do with
paraphernalia
um yeah no it's it was o4 i didn't get
into this actually until
uh april though four and you know
i was just it was 24 at the time so i
didn't really know any better it was
more
of a hey you know i'm nobody you know
when you're the size that
jason was at the time then you know
you're you're going to get noticed i
knew i could fly under the radar long
enough to
not matter to anybody um you know but of
course i called the
you know the uh you know the lawyers
that were prosecuted
or defending um paraphernalia cases
across the country
and you know the advice was you know
find another job
and it's it's it was illegal you know
technically today
you know just you know for everyone's
edification um
you know the federal paraphernalia act
has a
has an exemption for states that have
asso that have legalized the substance
associated with paraphernalia so
technically in california and colorado
and washington or all of the legal
markets including the medical markets
a bong is legal federally legal
um so you know they in fact they're
you with you on that i gotta argue with
you on that it's in this in this
scenario right now i haven't seen
anything came from
any you know um federal laws
that that that are any different than
the ones that were incorporated in 1991
by federal judge
william rehnquist designating that that
what we make is a bong
and that it's only to be used for
cannabis consumption
even though it is legal in these states
um
it's not on a federal level and what i
would do in section e
in section e of that law it specifically
says that there is an exemption for
states that legalize the substance
associated with a paraphernalia
and we challenge that yeah i mean i mean
i'm i mean i'm more than interested in
understanding it and also i mean just
fyi i have a license
to create cannabis paraphernalia they
actually call it drug paraphernalia
in the city of las vegas so i have a
license to do that
but what i'm being told at the moment is
the feds trump
everything and i haven't seen you know
any kind of federal anything that's that
that allows cannabis and if it does that
means that we can go to the bank with it
currently i just got shut off of paypal
the other day before about a week before
that they shot me off of shopify for the
umpteenth time for selling glass
cbd is allowed to be sold but glass is
not um you know i mean i'm i'm pretty up
on the laws right now i'd love to talk
in another
scenario where you can kind of get me
updated on what you know
um i know there's a couple specialty
lawyers out there that deal in the
car you know the paraphernalia scenario
but you know
just be aware you know i got arrested on
federal rap
and it's nothing of that law that i know
has changed yeah and
i'd love to understand if there has been
change but to be clear there's no in the
clear here
right like i'm not like let's all go
make bongs
um but the but the fact is that there
you know there is a little bit of light
in the tunnel but it doesn't change the
fact that like
these these laws you know the fact that
there is a pair of nail on the books
is going to be along like there there
will be federally
you know descheduled or decriminalized
cannabis before that paraphernalia
law you know gets gets uh you know falls
off
um and uh and so i mean yeah that's
that's kind of a fight that i've been
fighting since
uh 2010 when ncia was created and
you know we started drafting the
amendment 64 in colorado because it was
really important to get
the the language into the law that
explicitly says that paraphernalia
in this state is legal because if it
didn't say that
then federally the you know they'd be
able to continue to
to go after vanilla um and you know and
since then you know
most states ninety percent of them that
have published
laws have uh have followed suit and
added a peripheral piece of
paraphernalia
language in there um because of that
work the ncia did
um back in 2010 it was a big deal
yeah i mean believe me i i always think
i'm thinking myself as that frog
that you know i'm standing on the frying
pan and um
you know just wondering when it's going
to burn me basically
so you know i mean even to this day like
i said i'm still getting shut down left
and right
for selling bongs and so um
you know it's just about right now about
navigating the space and staying
positive
yeah i think that's the absurdity of
some of these laws that are still in the
books is crazy
you know as someone that came out of the
hydro industry for quite a few years
you know how to deal with the same
things you guys deal with where for
years it was like you know it's on a
bong it's a water pipe
you know anyone that came into my stores
for a long time the uh the mantra was
oh no we're here for tomatoes and
peppers you know we're not here for
cannabis growing
which obviously is just you know
completely fictitious when i hit a point
the word bong you know we we think now
oh we're all good
you know and we can say it now and i and
i've thought that for the past 12 years
i've been full throttle hashtagging the
word bong
cannabis blah blah blah and now what
i've realized
is that uh what i've realized is that
um i had to go back recently and scrub
every single post i've ever done
screw up every single invoice i'm
writing on my quickbooks programs
scrub it all and change my word around
the tube
not not put the word pipe i'm in
everything and then dave i'm sure you're
pretty versed in all this your
business i mean swamps mine i'm sure
your volume of sales
um are much higher than mine on a on a
yearly
and so i know that you you know you have
uh you know
knowledge of this space but my you know
i thought
i did too i just recently just realized
why i was getting hemmed up so much
and so it's you know just being
connected to these hashtags and these
algorithms that
that blocked me out and so recently i'm
just kind of
going back scrubbing everything and just
trying to paper it up nicely as i go
forward
soft disney style sell some t-shirts
bring light to the brand
and then hopefully i can sell the glass
on the back end
so sarah 420 sciences what are you guys
doing these days to uh
to make sure you're staying compliant to
make sure that you know you're putting
out really cool art that uh the people
are seeing
like what is the uh like when you guys
internally sit around and try to figure
out how to grow the business
you know what do you think about as far
as all these different concerns and then
what do you think about as far as how to
generate
new interest in just glass in general
oh geez that's a big question um i mean
we still keep it super clean very safe
you know like as jason was talking about
it's
i try to learn from all those that came
before me
and understand what
what we're doing still does skirt a lot
of laws
even though it might feel safe most of
the time
there we're you know we're always
looking over our shoulder i guess right
um
what are we doing i mean we got kicked
off instagram
we yeah right now we're totally d
platformed almost we got deleted from
youtube
we got kicked off instagram over and
over again just grab your hashtags
scrub your hashtag yeah remember what
i'm telling you right now it's something
that i've just learned
it's frustrating um
but yeah we love partnering with artists
um
on branded merchandise paying them a
royalty
and um bringing them into like this
to into a new market right and so like
doing
um collaborations with rolling trays and
stash jars
and grinders and stuff like that and
um that's been one of my favorite things
one of gary's favorite things is
you know making friends with these guys
and making money together
like we love it um
i don't know if that answers your
question but yeah no it does it's
really helpful so you know let's talk
about you know between all this talk
about the art these days and
obviously you know the industry that is
still massive when i say the instrument
in the glass industry
i remember the one year the hydroponics
industry and champs were actually had a
um
a show at the same time in vegas we
ended up just dropping the curtain and
sharing the uh sharing the space 9000
2009 it was such a fun weekend was like
two different parts of the industry that
were
you know facing from the same challenge
just all came together it was
awesome but um you know from the
artistic side
like i i don't get to see nearly as much
as i used to you know previously
but who out there is just crushing like
who's putting out like the best head
pieces like who's playing stuff when you
guys see it and you go to shows or
you're subjecting friends that are
blowers
who you looking at right now and just
going like that guys this bird that gal
is putting out a straight fire
i'm looking at tammy baller i'm looking
at hakisaki i'm looking at lace face i'm
looking at you sheen
i'm looking at puntington some of the
some of the
the the g's in the industry that are
that are pushing the
the artwork to it next level there's a
lot of young kids out there for sure
um but but you know these guys have
spent their life now putting this thing
together
and uh you know they're creating some
really interesting stuff
you got earl jr you're down in texas
you got salt i mean some some of the
bigger
you know bigger names that are that are
the game changers uh you know
dina wins win star glass you know this
chick is awesome
and uh you know these guys are creating
really you know monumental masterpieces
northern waters i love their stuff
that's like
in my collection they're like a husband
and wife duo
up in portland
is uh is portland like is the uh oregon
area still kind of driving
uh the glass industry or is that largely
just you know dropped off and gone all
over the country at this point
i mean for the early days it's pretty
much all about you know um
from from portland down to eugene just
south of there and all the people i saw
that were coming up in the early days
it was either from northern california
to maybe like portland in general
but where where are the hot spots now
i'd say
i'd say philly and denver i mean you
know or yeah
the dream labs and and evergreen and
um you know and the philly contingent or
just i mean
these guys i just crush more yeah i mean
it's just
yeah these guys are just unreal elbow
joe p
uh nate myers those guys um
you know snick job you know they're
they're just still uh
they're still on top of their game you
know and kind of like reinventing i mean
like i
just appreciate these guys that are
having to like
just learn how to promote like for the
first time like
glassblowers like jason are learning how
to do
a lot more self-promotion in a world
that's changed from
you know just pedaling over to the head
shop right
it's uh it's pretty wild
yeah i think there's some guys in japan
too that are really kind of game
changers they put a lot of different
eyes on what we're doing and um kind of
created a whole new
little world out of you know this this
pointillism stuff that they do and it
just takes weeks to make a little
pendant or something you know and they
put all this time in it
and it's kind of that whisker and uh
you know what painting with the whisker
in the glass jar kind of a
thing you know where they they have to
think it out and take this meticulous
process oriented steps and
they they really did some cool stuff
with the flame working movement and i
also go
always go back to bob bob's still you
know one of the most imaginative people
in the space
and anybody whether it's elbow or you
know slinger or anybody that's around
him
um picks that up and kind of energizes
off that so
you know you have to always watch what
bob and bob's team's doing the camerons
the
steve stotts and the the the different
guys and that whole crew there's
there's just some really really
imaginative stuff and in the end for me
it's changing color the more you smoke
it and you know a lot of these guys that
that are going now um you know have a
little bit different view and different
site on it
so that everybody's everybody's you know
unique
take on it you know combined make this
whole movement happen and it's really
really cool to watch
and what's the hot thing now i mean like
i remember the different periods where
like underwaters were really hot for a
while and like
all sorts of like different like you
know like people were adding in you know
different metals for a long time that
other people weren't using
like right now all right yeah
i'm about to tell you something dave i'm
gonna give it up right now and the
hottest
newest most fucking epic shit going on
is out of germany
it's a guy named hans iddick glass house
fair time
i'm watching him on torch talk and you
can see he's created something
in this borosilicate that's never ever
been done before
and he's selling it to us and it's a
it's a technique
it's a it's a it's it's a groundbreaking
thing where we can put
full photos inside of the glass and it's
in the borah silica glass we've been
able to do it with soft glass in the
past but not with borah silicon so he's
created a
a powder technique that he's put the
powders on the papers and we can
apply it onto the glass and and that's
the technique that i'm using now for the
whole new i'm i'm i'm
doing all of the new tommy chong bongs
and so we have a whole program coming
out with this photo realism stuff on the
glass and it's super cool
super fun but again it's hans tig and
it's very
class house fair time w e r t
i and he's all over torch talk showing
off this new tech
and i'm even hearing like people are
calling him like what are you doing you
know how are you doing this
and it's just one of those cool new new
news things that is going on and it's
fun to watch
so dave are you still collecting other
people's pieces i mean i know like uh
this past summer
you and i are talking about the gold
snob grass stuff and i sent you a
picture of like a little hammer that i
had
and i actually just tracked down where
my uh my old sherlock was which is a
cameron sherlock and pop badger marbles
on it which is
still like one of the sickest pieces
i've ever had um
but uh are you still collecting yourself
i mean you still like look at other
people's stuff and go hey i definitely
need to get my hands on that or sarah
are you collecting other people's stuff
like
how do you guys think about the industry
i mean for me i i definitely think to
your aftermarket uh discussion earlier
there's definitely gonna be you know
pieces of art that uh that 20 years 30
years from now people are going to look
back on though those things are
absolutely priceless
especially because as you know uh jason
alluded to earlier so many of the best
pieces out there in this world have
gotten broken in the last 30 years
that uh it's tragic that some of the
best ones out there just are gone
forever
so you know what are you guys thinking
about as far as collaboration
a lot of good bombs go to heaven no
doubt no doubt
but how do you guys think about the
collecting game or is that you know
something that you don't even think
about and just think the next amazing
piece will be created next month so
so what do i worry about are you
actually out there actively collecting
pieces
oh i always actively collect i'm i'm not
uh you know
so one hitters changed my whole business
back in 2007 i was like underwater with
gravitrons you know about to shut the
whole thing down and then
started making tasters and uh you know
trying to turn everything around and so
my uh my mantra for the last 10 years
has been to
um to try to get a one e from everybody
that
i can possibly from every artist that i
have ever admired
so uh you know jason jason passing this
to you yeah this is my mission yeah
right
right now right now being in vegas you
know the the
the what you want to do is you want to
have a 20 000
dab rig that matches your shoes and your
sunglasses that day
okay and you want to have a nice fat
louis vuitton bag for it
that's what's going on with the whole
collector world right now is
they go out and it's an expression of
them if they roll in with the
ducky you know i mean you like look at
this guy like oh look he's at the rubber
ducky and
the good concentrates it shows kind of
them who they are
and that's like the collector base they
have the cool shoes that match it
um and they have you know it's like a
whole thing
so so that's kind of what i
see as the collector's thing right now
that's what's hot
i love that my personal collection i
just have pieces that i
that i love when i see them i buy them i
mean the only
real like heady pieces i have
are maybe not even really that heady
like i have a jag
that ufo spaceship thing we bought back
in like 2012.
um i have an early like j mass piece
that i really loved
when i saw it a couple down neck pieces
but nothing like crate i wouldn't
consider myself a collector i would
consider like i buy beautiful pieces
when i see them and i can afford them
i i love i love sarah's collection i
actually want to hear rob
answer this this this uh his own
question oh and i have that carmen loser
bon
what did that piece that has a carmen
loser like head in it
and and then she clapped with that other
guy
that's my favorite piece that i'd keep
gary is oh jeff heath i have a
i have a bob snodgrass
dragon uh steamroller from that
sign from 98 and bob i feel it's the one
of the coup d'etats of the whole fucking
glass
you know collective collectible stuff
and i recommend
anybody when you see the bob stuff out
if it's bob's stuff you know his pieces
you definitely buy them for your car we
definitely have a bob snodgrass bubbler
too
yeah i keep i keep one bob sitting
around i still have a dave willis with
uh with the original dog paw stamp on it
because dave was like the first guy
used to let me stay his place in a
petroleum back in the day jason i'm sure
you remember that house up on the bluff
overlooking the toll river
uh by the mouth from the toll so i was
like you know the first place i used to
go up there
absolutely yeah yeah so i always keep
one of his pieces around i keep a bob
around i keep a
as i said a camera piece that the
bathroom did the marbles on
and uh believe it or not for years and
now i've lost it but i'm sure i can find
who has it but uh one of your one of
your original tubes jason from like 1997
i had for over 20 years so it's still
it's still around i don't think it's
been broken
i think it's sitting right now in um the
south shore of boston
at a buddy of mines place but that was a
piece that you know i carried
me absolutely everywhere for 20 plus
years and loved it still love it
i will i will also work that inspired
you
yeah i was super fired up i i that piece
meant another uh tube that i used to be
able to stick you stuck into a wood
block and turned it 90 degrees and it
locked
and that piece was amazing to uh to
carry around as well and i used to
whenever i had friends over it always
make sure i had two tubes so i wouldn't
be the person that was packing bowls and
not passing
and uh make sure someone else you know
to just you know make sure i was cordial
making sure that the other person would
have a pack ripper
waiting for them as well at all times
but i usually uh i usually keep
your tube as the one that was mine and
uh past the other wood block once it's
more of a novelty to the others
but uh but i wish i still had a glass
collection i wish that you know
i wish i had a lot of the stuff that was
offered to me back you know in the late
90s where a lot of it wasn't even pipes
it was a lot of people coming out of the
stock grass shop they were making really
creative things
that were you know non-pipes that were
just great artwork that uh you know
starting off with marbles and starting
off with jars and then progressing from
there just to really really unique stuff
sure that's part of the magic of the
whole collectibility is like the bitcoin
thing you don't want to miss out
you know definitely definitely and as i
said you know i've lost
largely kind of migrated away from being
involved in that part of the industry
you know that was kind of where i got my
start in the early 90s as far as you
know bringing stuff out on tour
that you guys are producing um so hey
real quick
i just want to let everyone in the
audience know and people are you know
listening on youtube as well
on the future canvas project that uh our
subject tonight is you know glass
blowing in the glass um
just the glass industry in general we've
got dave daley from grab we've got uh
jason harris from jerome baker designs
and sarah todd from uh from 20 science
we are going to open up the room a
little bit some questions so
eric who is a massachusetts uh person
who's up here on stage and has been
involved in massachusetts campus for
years
uh derek do you have any questions for
anyone on the panel or you just want to
say hello what's going on
i do have a general question for glass
and i'm not sure if
this is uh the right room for it but
in massachusetts the testing delays are
between like 45 and 50 days and it's
resulting in
like a deterioration in some of the
quality of the cannabis that by the time
it gets sold on the stores
and you know i don't think the mylar
bags are great for it
and some of the chinese glasses like
porous and
uh i american glass seems to be
too expensive but do you have any
suggestions
or recommendations uh or anything that
we can do to kind of help it
besides putting like nitro in there or
something
done a decent amount of testing why
besides putting nitro in there
why do you not want to put nice row in
there well i that was just one
suggestion that one person threw out
there and i didn't know if that's the
only option
or i mean i don't have anything against
it i was just wondering if there's any
any recommendations or what people think
about this
yeah i would seal it in a borosilicate
uh
uh some sort of blue silica canisters
with ground joint lids on you can
you know put your nitro in there so it
sits and holds for your time but maybe
maybe putting nitro in
might be bad for it when you pop it back
open for testing i'm not sure
i do know if you figure it out you give
me specs on it let me quote your job
because i make everything in glass
including all the biggest rigs in vegas
for oil
and all the you know they bring all the
shit to fix they
want fix for their big oil rigs and i
could do it all so you just make sure
that if you do come up with something
let me know and let me let me make your
sample for sure great
thank you very much i appreciate it
ross how you doing today what's going on
i'm good man how are you
jason what's up man
ross what's going on brother good bro
how are you
awesome are you down in florida yeah i'm
still down here still down here
uh excellent yeah i'm just gonna touch
it ross is a big collector by the way
and and ross had a uh way back in the
day he had some bongs get stolen
and when they got stolen he was one of
the first guys that i know that got the
insurance
claim off the thing and since then we've
came up with the american class
you know uh certification guild and
that's online it's connected to my
website and you can all now certify your
glass and document it so that if it does
get stolen you can get your insurance
claim
processed and it's been a very important
part of
creating uh this collectible art glass
as an asset
in your you know whatever financial
portfolio you have as an artistic work
yeah jason was instrumental i mean i've
been a huge collector since the early
days in the
back yeah about 13 years ago most of my
collection was stolen all
you know original jerome bakers chong
bongs
and i reached out to jason i said hey
man you know let's let's see if we can
do this
you know file actual police report and
not call it drug paraphernalia you know
or anything they're trying to label it
let's call it
art which it is um and successful in
miami of getting them to actually
accept the police report and then file
an insurance claim
crazy enough with usaa and with chase
help we actually got them to pay out on
some stuff
you know i've i've also been and what
what they called an
expert witness in paraphernalia and i've
been called into court a couple times
now
and i have to sit up there on the stage
and you know tell tell everybody in the
courtroom about
you know paraphernalia and what it is
and the value and what it holds
and um and it's been very you know very
interesting seeing it climb through the
ranks as it has and
like i said ross was one of the first
that we got that claim with and
really cool cool fact
yes that's awesome but um
you know i wanted to touch base you know
kind of on that secondary market you
guys were talking about you know
there is a big underground collector's
market you know and
you know we don't really have a platform
other than you know these facebook
groups you know which there's several of
you know jason created
you know his jerome baker one a lot of
people are coming in and popping
you know old pieces in uh we see even
broken stuff pop
up which you know are salvageable you
know there's people out there who are
doing repairs on stuff you know jonathan
kilmann you know one of the original
chong artists is doing a lot of great
repairs on stuff i've sent him stuff
he's done a great job
um you know there's the chong groups you
know there's maca of course you know for
coins and milli
um but you know we've talked about it a
lot over the years from me and the other
collectors where can we actually go and
find
all these pieces that people bought you
know in the 90s the
early 2000s you know before you know
operation pipe dreams
where are they now you know every couple
weeks some will pop up in these groups
hey i found this in a closet
this was in the basement but um you know
having a place where we can actually
trade it
all we have right now are these facebook
groups and
um yeah stuff pops up
i want you all to definitely check out
agc
guild.org so that's agc
guilt.org
and that has a place that you can
document your pieces and get some sort
of
you know like i said just just a a
fulfillment of
of of being you know the peace that it
is because it is breakable and things do
happen
and it should be protected in a certain
way
so uh i mean invite stefan to speak now
who
that's in this picture right now which
i'm guessing is probably circa you know
mid to late 90s and uh another old dead
fan so
stefan what's going on oh hey rob thanks
for inviting me up thanks all you guys
this has been
this has been really great it's uh
touched on so many cool memories from
the old days
uh my best friend used to live in bob
and marie's uh backyard there in glen
glendale glenwood what's it called there
uh in oregon is fixing some old bus
that we lived in on tour for a while and
he got me to commission the piece that's
in my picture
which uh bob made me in the winner of
89.90
i think he brought it to me actually at
the start of spring tour
uh in like atlanta or someplace in 90.
anyway this thing was all over tour
got broken at some point bob fixed it
even better than it was so
so many things you guys were talking
about and then it was lost for more than
20 years
and it just recently came back
that's awesome yeah i remember i
remember bringing a piece to bob that
was uh
like jason was referring to earlier it
was a steamroller at the time was the
biggest steamroller bobbin ever produced
it was about
almost two feet long it was an absolute
monstrosity i remember smuggling
into shows in seattle in 1994 and how we
got it through security i've got
no idea but we pulled that thing out on
the floor like literally every single
person in like 50 yards is like holy
shit what's that
and i remember when that thing got
cracked and bringing it back and we're
like is there anything that can be done
with this thing
it's the fact you've got one that
actually you know made it and uh
survived
i always think about like how many pipes
got broken in people's laps getting out
of their cars
and just like that being like this like
the number one way of like uh of pipes
getting destroyed
because rad you've got one that's like
survived and has been battle tested like
that
yeah i was still bombed when some random
i mean i smoked this thing with hundreds
of people on tour it was just some
random guy
and uh i think he was drunk and broke a
leg off and man i was
i was flipping out then i talked to bob
and
bob was like oh man all all i need is
cash glass and the gas
and i'll fix it right up for you and he
actually made it better so
wicked cool hey to both you and
ross you know the
[Music]
this this secondary market concept is i
can't stress the importance of it like
you know the collectors are going to be
the ones that drive the demand and
the artists are going to be the ones
that bless it so
you know if you have it's those that
have that you're the artist
that are going to be able to drive that
opportunity the most right if the
artists are willing to
put credence to their work to you know
to verify their work
and then you know which which would
inevitably give way to a platform
that would um you know that would
support you know
appraisals and you know and truly
secondary sales
then then you have an immediate platform
um
but you have to centralize it and the
only way to centralize it is to get all
the artists to agree
hey this is the place where i'm going to
send people this is where i'm going to
be
verifying my work and then
the people come out of the woodwork
so how do you go about um getting
certification on things that are
probably like 15 20 25 years old dave
you know is there an authentication
process i mean a lot of the artists
like jason i gotta ask you like do you
remember every piece you ever made
you gotta hope the artist wasn't too
stoned i mean i can tell i've had this
conversation with with salt
multiple times and he promises he
remembers every single
product he ever made and i believe that
yeah i know i know every piece i've ever
made i know every piece i've ever made
every piece my team's ever made every
piece with my
name on it ever made and and and
like i said there's there's i think i
think most of these guys do especially
from the old times you're going to be
able to tell especially if you can
get the the direct you know sign off
from the artist if it's real or not
and um you know again you know check out
what i told you
agc agc.agcguild.org and that that has
that
direct connection to the artist and also
facebook does as well
if you get documentation and you connect
with the artist i mean i mean nowadays
it's kind of like so different because
of the social media when we started
there was no internet
you know and so so now you can go
directly to the artist and avoid the
gallery and so that kind of
is a big deal and um you know
some artists deal direct with the public
some artists
to send everything through stores and
galleries and shows
and um but you can connect directly with
the artist you can get a certification
from an artist and as long as you have
documentation like that that's the first
step
signatures are great on the pieces um
and when you when you see that
that your favorite glass makers come
into town or has a shirt
go somewhere you can go bring your
pieces to them and have them sign it
document that with a picture and
understand that you're
you know creating legacy with the pieces
that you have it's like famous guitars
or anything else it needs to be
somehow documented so when it goes into
the pawn shop
you know you have all this certification
blah blah blah wrapped around it i mean
it's pretty logical so you know that's
that should be taken care of
i'll say about the memory thing bob sure
as fact remember this piece when
you know it reappeared after 20 some
years and
he was telling me stuff i didn't even
remember about how he made it and when
and everything
that's a snotty yeah
yeah it's something for me and the
winner of 89.90
i uh and and everybody everybody who has
the bob pieces must know
you have to know that that bob is
getting channeled and this is from bob's
mouth is that
the pieces that he's making are being
channeled through something and this
portal pops him out of his hands
and that's your key to the spaceship
when this thing comes down and lands
you're gonna be able to
get in with that into the door um so
make sure you have your
piece on you at all times yeah man and
my favorite part of like bob's story is
you know the connection to the culture
as someone that was raised by dead heads
that grew up listening to the music
and you know saw the surviving members
as much as i could
up until you know the recent um project
but
i've always connected cannabis and the
grateful dead but to
learn the backstory of bob you know
pulling up to lie
blowing glass bringing pieces to sell
you know it kind of being really like
the first resounding like
you know um artist in the scene and like
especially in terms of like using fume
and really killing it in that regard
um and being someone that loves few
artists myself
people like makabi and you know even
like what banjo does
and uh you know all these different
dudes that are just killing it right now
um you know they're all inspired by bob
and it's really cool
to still have basically the godfather of
like
the sea and that's connected to my
favorite band and the whole world
still around creating it's like i just
feel lucky to be around at this
time basically yeah i mean we are
blessed
especially to to know it and acknowledge
it and be part of it it's um
it's gonna go you know it's gonna it's
changed the world
it's changed the glass medium i mean
it's such a cool important part of
legalization of cannabis and
you know it's really cool and bob is you
know the pinnacle of the wizardry of
this whole thing for sure
yeah i remember going to barter fair in
1995 with bob
and like getting to spend you know two
days of barter fair when like you know
harvest was just coming down in southern
oregon and northern california
and literally just watching him get
absolutely mobbed by everyone that's
just like willing to trade whatever they
just brought down
it's really any pieces that bob had on
hand and between him and the rest of the
shop there was probably like three or
four hundred pieces they brought to
barter fair
and that used to be such a cool festival
or even called a festival just
like such a cool gathering of artisans
that would show up there and all the
glass blowers getting together like
right when harvest was
sitting at the same time like between
that and country fair i always thought
were like the two most fun things in
oregon
specifically because of like all the
artisans that would be there like
presenting stuff and just kind of the
vibe that was going along with that
it's a little magic though yeah yeah
bruce barter
is the best bro that's for sure hey i
just want to thank you guys for having
me in the
in the clubhouse tonight i really
appreciate the uh
the um the momentum that everybody's
going at right now
and i appreciate um and honor you guys
for um
being you know doing this you know
especially guys like dave
um that have pushed the envelope to the
maximum
you know thing right now so um you know
i appreciate being a part of you guys
i'm gonna have to sign off to cook
dinner for the kids they're all starting
to scream right now
hey jason one final question before we
let you go though what's next for uh
for jbd like what what what should we
expect to see and then we'll let you
sign off with uh with that
okay cool so right now like i said i'm
doing a new tommy chong bong
and um we're working hand in hand with
tommy and his family on like
daily right now in a design stage uh so
that's about to drop we're gonna do a
a soft launch on uh on april 20th and
then we're gonna
kind of build it out from there and just
in terms of jerome baker i'm just kind
of slow and steady i only have my small
family crew in there i'm making my
product in vegas
everybody's welcome to stop by you can
hit me on instagram message me i run the
insta
so you you can you can say hey i'm
coming on this day
and uh you know the jerome baker thing
is is where it's at man
jerome i know i named it after jerry
jerome is jerry garcia
and baker is getting baked and so i have
you know uh a really big play
um that i'm working on to try to try to
shine for some grateful dead people
and um you know we're all there man
we're all just we're all there because
we're not all there right
and um and you know i welcome all you
guys to stop by and visit me and kind of
get eyes on the prize right there what's
going on you can follow me on instagram
jerome underscore baker and
kind of put my daily life on there and
just show what's going on in the glass
and cannabis
listen man so much respect so much uh
thanks for
having uh you come up tonight and taking
part of your sunday with us
um but uh amazing work for the last 20
almost 30 years now man so thank you so
much for everything you've done for all
of us
absolutely bro there's anything i could
do for you in the future just keep me
tuned in thanks sarah for inviting me in
here i appreciate you guys
reaching out to me absolutely thanks
jason
hey dave what's going on mr grav aloha
what
what's next for uh what's next for grab
man which we expect to see i know you've
got a lot of cool stuff kicking around
yeah um what can you share
i don't know i was thinking about
throwing the whole catalog in the
garbage
[Music]
[Laughter]
classic
no i uh grav is
um you know my my entire singular focus
as you know rob and i have discussed
you know recently is is on single-use
cannabis consumption so
you know we're really focused on our
glass joint project in california
we're going to start rolling that out to
the rest of the country
and you know that's that's really
exciting work it's not a perfect product
i'm the first to admit that but
i'm really bullish on single-use
cannabis consumption specifically in
glass
so i think that you know grav has the
right to win in that category so
laser focus there second is you know
just
is you know literally throwing half the
catalog in trash i think it's
you know old it's got it needs a lot of
a lot of refreshing and so we are
in the trenches of working out what
makes sense and what doesn't in the
future
um you know cannabis is moving fast and
you know there's a lot of um
you know it's going to continue to move
faster and you know
in uh and i think that there's going to
be massive movement on a federal level
in the next
you know year if not several years um
which is just going to push got it it's
going to push headshots into a weird
place potentially
um and so you know i just i think about
that a lot and i think about where
um where the glass game is going to go
all of these artists that are kind of in
the middle tier that are not
you know jason harris dronebaker they're
not
salt you know that's that's going to be
really tough it's going to be tough to
survive um so
you know what's next for grab i think
that we just you know look i'm gonna do
the same thing i've been doing
for the last 17 years and keep my head
down
and keep you know every turn i think
that there's not something you know
i'm going to get bored and i just don't
so before i invite megan or adam to
speak here in just a second
you want to plug what you're doing with
uh with your glass joints as well
because it's such a novel concept and
there's very few people out there that
are really doing it and
you've done a really nice launch of the
california market you want to talk about
what you're doing with glass joints and
single serving there
yeah so for the for those of you that
don't know what a glass joint is it's
because we've made up the term it
doesn't actually exist
it's a iteration of the glass blunt
which is a slider which is
you know effectively a tube that is
loaded with flour and then
another tube that would that slides into
the interior of that tube that has a
restriction
in it that prevents the flower from
sucking into your mouth
and then you smoke it not dissimilar to
a real joint
but as you light it and you burn it down
you
push the ash out with the tube that's in
the inside
um so it like a push pop
yeah exactly exactly like a push pop so
you know if you smoke it the right way
you get a really even cherry that stays
lit the whole time
as long as you're pushing out the ash if
you try to suck it all down you know you
end up losing the the
the the cherry and it's a less than
ideal experience
so it takes a little bit of tweaking and
it's you know more of a you know
uh you know middle middle tier smoker uh
from a
experienced level to uh to really get it
but um
you know and that's what we're seeing in
market in california is that you know
it's getting adopted and stick and
sticking with about 20
of people to try it and i think we're
losing a lot of people that just want to
refill it because the biggest heavy
lifting that we have to do is convince
people to throw away their glass
so you know i'm the kind of the jerome
baker you know jason's antithesis of
what he's talking about he's
he wants to make art that lives forever
and i'm trying to make shit that people
throw away
um so i i don't uh and i think that
there's always gonna be a place for
the for the high end i believe that you
know that the artistic side of it is
as important or more than you know the
the throwaway shit that i'm trying to
pull off so
you know to be clear for everybody in
the room you know
this is in support of not uh in
uh you know not in combat of the
the art market
megan how you doing tonight
hey rob this is megan speaking i'm doing
really good thanks for having me up as a
speaker
of course anything you want to ask dave
or sarah
yeah i don't have any questions at this
moment um
i wanted to say hi to jason before he
hopped off because we've connected
at a couple events in hawaii
but i'm here to listen i love glass and
i love
art so smoking so thank you for hosting
of course i'm sorry i knew he was trying
to duck out i saw you raising your hand
raised he said he was going to leave so
i saw your hand and adam pop up i'm
guessing adam might have the uh the same
thing i just want to say hi to jason
before he bounced
but um but yeah anything you like and
should we please jump back in
adam how are you doing tonight
uh thank you rob i'm doing great i'm in
california and
there's a bit of snow so if the
satellite's not making it all the way
through apologies
and i'm not sure if you touched on this
but just the idea of
um autographing or a way to sign
the pieces um someone i heard about
infrared scanning and attaching or
minting a token associated with that
in a way that the art piece is both
authenticated
but if there is an increase in value of
the token
or the piece or any transfers there's a
way to pay royalties
to both the artist and possibly the
initial investor
but i just wanted to offer that as an
idea and just pay love and respect for
all the uh
builders of these sacred pipes thank you
right on uh sarah are you hearing
anything about that are you hearing
about the digital authentication or any
sort of infrared authentication
what are you seeing right now i haven't
but that is a great idea
it sounds like nfts i love it
i was thinking the same thing that's
like this sounds perfect for nft
um yeah that's that's crazy
that uh the people are thinking about
that right i'm surprised it hasn't been
done already to
create some sort of authentication again
there are certain artists that obviously
had like their own like very unique mark
that you could always tell whose piece
it was based on just
a certain thing they did anyone that
looked at they say oh that's so and so
it's just by um
just kind of knowing what their style
was but uh but actually truly
authenticating it i think would be
really interesting if they could find a
way to do it
um hey to dave and sarah question for
you guys like um
on the side of like sort of the nexus
between the um
the industry especially the artisans on
the um
on the extract side you know obviously
like the whole game with dab rigs
changed so completely once you know
dabbing came out
that you know are you are there people
that you guys work with or that you know
that
help you think about what you want to do
next simply because of what they're
coming out with
you know back when for like shatter and
butter and wax and diamonds first hit
the market
you know it completely changed the game
about how people were thinking about
what they needed whether it was you know
at the time like titanium nails or
crystal
and other mediums to to you know start
consuming
but i've got i think there's like a real
closeness between the real artisans on
the uh
on the extraction side and the glass
people themselves so
how do you guys look at that game
sarah do you want to take this oh man i
don't know
i'm not sure i just have to say hi adam
i just realized i
who you are i met you back at the
emerald cup like a couple years ago
i'm so happy to say see you
i'm just realizing who you were and that
was so awesome
are you and was it gary yeah
yeah and that was we were having a
little snack
and uh do it yeah shared a little bit
i remember that very well yeah it was
very cool meeting you both
and um yeah nice to meet you again here
in this digital space
ditto sorry to totally sidetrack that
conversation i just looked at his
profile and i was like oh my god
no yeah and i've been learning i've been
learning so much
from these younger artists who are
minting coin
and building things in three-dimensional
space which
the art is almost a representation of
the value that someone's trying to
put on or transfer or pay respect to the
artist
so the art is almost secondary but i
like how it applies
to physical art one
one of one creations that
and just what i've kind of picked up is
you can mint a token or
two tokens one for the artist one for
the
buyer and even just the tokens
themselves can increase in value
with no transfer of the uh
physical tool um so i just think it's so
neat
and uh you guys are very cool and um you
know there's apps that
trigger the iphone to do infrared uh
three-dimensional scans
uh iradar or there's radars in the name
but on the
anyway i think these things are becoming
accessible where the artists can
maintain their
um you know kind of earn more
i don't know what it is but it seems
cool and i'm done thank you
sarah it was so cool thanks for the
support at the cup
and that was very fun
so sarah dave and jason before they left
like what's next for 420 science like
what should we uh what should we expect
to see and what do you have on deck
oh my gosh i mean really just
the last thing that dave said to sorry
to be boring but we're just going to
keep building what we have
and double down on what is working and
be thankful for everything that we have
and that we continue to grow
sarah's being very modest for the for
the audience that 420 science has become
by far the biggest head shot that's ever
existed
by my calculations oh and i love that i
mean come on
it's not a bold it's not a bold
statement to say that 420 science is now
literally the biggest headshot that's
ever been in the history of the industry
and have been able to overcome a lot of
challenges that others were not able to
by very very thin hair
like we i mean look i have amazing
partners
and we have an incredible team well you
deserve it
so spencer uh first of all let me
compliment you on having a great picture
in your profile i love seeing
bright white furry um roots like that
so whatever you're doing keep doing it
but uh what's going on tonight
i'm i'm sure spencer can hear so if you
can't spencer you're out you're on if
you have any questions for dave or
sarah before you up before i wrap this
one up all right i'm not sure if spencer
can hear us
uh peter you've been in the audience
from future canvas project here for a
little bit
uh anything that you want to say i know
that uh yeah you cover all sorts of
different parts of the industry so i
know if you any questions on this
topic before we jumped out yeah
just quickly kind of the um
you know let's talk china and kind of
disruption and kind like i kind of view
the market as
your kind of generic pieces that used to
be made in america are obviously moving
to china
so you know that stuff's moving abroad
and kind of the market for american-made
glass is kind of more in the bespoke
kind of artist side of the equation so
can you
and and from what i understand like
there were
glass artists who kind of went and
trained people in china on how to do
certain things and techniques um
and so i i guess can you guys just kind
of talk about the
you know china part of the equation
i think we could talk for several hours
about this dave what do you think
my favorite topic
well um well first of all
let's talk about the last thing you said
and dispel the first
myth that we go to china and teach them
anything
there is the there is more
you know how do i say this um
ingenuity and glassblowing in china
than any glassblower i've ever seen here
primarily
because what china has done
over the past 50 years as
bomax left america i mean this all the
chinese glass market got built
when big borosilicate
um namely bomex which was also
um i'm drawing a blank
there's not i mean corning as well took
a lot of their manufacturing over to
over to asia
and um and built in an immense glass
bowling industry
you know the the the glassblowing
industry in china is
you know there's there's cities the size
of
texas that are just glass it's unreal
and um and so the
there's there's just more access to
material and skilled labor in asia than
there ever will be in the us from a you
know borosilicate
glassblowing standpoint um
so you know the you know
the the artists that built the pipe
industry
you know are absolutely the pioneers in
this and that's the big story here but
the you know but the the talent pool
is certainly not here um
and and it's just it's too hard right
like everybody you know
the it's the victim of their own of
their own making and
in a way that everybody wants to be an
artist everybody wants to be
yuchin everybody wants to be banjo and
you know there is no industry in you
know in the us
whether it's you know even if you're
trying to build it in you know southern
california with
you know an immigrant workforce you know
that's impossible
too you know it's just it's that's
that's failed as well
um so um you know if you want to get to
scale
as as as we have right like i didn't go
to china to get my products
cheaper i went to china because i
couldn't make it here just absolutely
could not do it it was impossible and so
i went to china and made it there so
um you know we still are you know
have an immense amount of innovation
that happens in the u.s
and you know six thousand square feet of
glassblowing facility that is
state-of-the-art and um and incredible
but you know there's just absolutely
zero chance that we could service this
industry the way that we do
domestically i will also say like we
still
have very strong sales with our american
glass
and there is absolutely an appetite and
a
production to fill it here in the us
it's the customer preference price but
there's so many factors that go into
this
well i was going to ask you about that i
mean sarah from like you know running a
huge head shop
like how much of what you guys have is
just production and how much of it is
you know truly artisan
you know do you guys look at saying okay
fifty percent of what we're gonna sell
is just gonna be your standards
production pieces or is it like 75
when you go into like just trying to
think about um you know what you're
going to move every
month what's kind of the ratio and how
much of it do you like to keep as far as
like the really high-end artists inside
of the industry
um you know up until now we've had a
hard time ever
selling huddys we've tried over and over
and
our customer base just doesn't support
it
i mean we will still try again because
we fucking love it
um as far as like a split you know when
we're look what we're when we're buying
what we're looking for
is consistency and
wherever your product is produced as
long as you can sell me hundreds of
those
consistently over years that that's what
i'm looking for
um and there's there are american shops
that can do that
and they kick ass with us and they're
you know people
are producing overseas that do that and
they kick ass with us
but we definitely we're always looking
to add
american glassblowers or whoever they
are
it's really at the end of the day is up
to what me and gary like and what we
think will sell and what
you know will continue to be supported
by our customer base
that makes sense uh danish how you doing
tonight
hey rob thanks for the opportunity so i
run a distribution company called medusa
and we actually distribute a lot of
grav and i just jumped in on the china
topic because
i think ultimately like brands matter
more than anything else uh in this space
just like anything else
just like any other space i guess i
should say um i think what sarah said is
exactly right
like one thing that grav has done and we
distribute
a fair amount of grav um that that seems
really
basic but a lot of the americans still
haven't caught up to it is putting
things in a box and putting a barcode on
it
right like you'd be surprised like you
can't run an
operation at our scale without boxes and
barcodes it's very very difficult
and so like to like we have a lot of
american glass companies that try to um
get distributed through us and the first
thing we always ask is like
what's like where are you on the
timeline of putting things in a box and
putting a barcode on it
and you'd be surprised at how many
conversations stop right there
um and so i think a lot of the american
glass people they don't have scale in
mind and i don't think they want to be
that big which is okay which is cool
um but you're not going to be like a
grav-sized company unless you think
about things like
barcodes um and so it's it there's a lot
of that and also like if you think about
companies like empire
that are i think blowing a lot of stuff
in america still like they just can't do
the volume that the market
requires um and so i think it's more
than just the price point i think
a lot of it is just like super basic
stuff that the american companies just
haven't gotten around to yet well
danish first of all thank you so much i
didn't i didn't drill into your
to your profile yet but uh yeah medusa's
well-known around grav and we love you
guys so thanks for the support
um but it's it you can take it a step
further
on the box thing first you have to be
able to make a simple repeatable product
to sarah's point right you have to make
it the same
size every time so it fits in the same
box every time
it stop the conversation stops even
before you get to a box
because it's it's so hard every single
glass pipe
everywhere for everyone's notification
again is hand blown
right whether it's made by someone in
you know in
in austin texas or in tibet
can you hear me yeah go ahead sorry i
thought for some reason maybe my phone
wasn't working but please go ahead
um so so yeah i mean it's a really good
point right like this has been
you know since since the the moment that
that
i actually started making more than just
the gravitron i was like
oh this there's a big problem in glass
if you go to this champs trade show that
rob brought up earlier
that you go to you know booth by booth
by booth and they have
four thousand skus per booth
there's like here's a bong with a tree
perk that has eight
eight arms in it here's a bong with a
tree perk that has 10 arms in it
and there's a cost difference and
there's a logo difference
and there's a color difference and so
now all of a sudden in two skews you
have
12 missions and it's it makes it makes a
it makes a catalog impossible to build
um you know so i'm kind of giving away
the big secret right now like
hey if you want to build a glass company
make it simple
yeah i mean we say we say to people all
the time right and i'm not trying to
like
you know take grabs business but i'm
just like look at grav
right like why aren't you guys doing
more of what they're doing and sometimes
we'll like bring in american glass
brands and
we'll have to bring in 100 pieces take
professional pictures of them from every
angle it takes it's like a huge
onboarding thing um and then they'll
just decide to never make the piece
again
right so we're like okay well how many
times are we going to do this
before we just can't take you guys
seriously because the stores that we
distribute to the shops and the
dispensaries
that we distribute to it they're like
hey uh are you guys gonna always be out
of stock of that one piece that sold
really well
and then we have to go up the chain and
and be like hey are you guys ever gonna
make the most
popular thing you guys ever made again
and they're like ah
i'm not sure if we're ever gonna do that
one again and it's just maddening right
so like
to a certain extent like um what dave
said is exactly right like
you have to have consistency if you want
stores to carry your stuff because they
want to
reorder the thing the thing
of the picture that i'm showing to
everyone
i don't want to take more of those
pictures
exactly
well listen guys uh i want to say thank
you so much
uh again the club that we're on has
asked me anything about cannabis
every sunday night we try to cover a
different topic we try to get in depth
from the people that
really have the best stories to share on
that specific topic
so next week it might be soil science or
it might be back to the nerdy
legal question again on d8 and um
and work in progress hemp oil and kind
of what the dea is trying to do with
that
i haven't decided you know depending on
who which guests i can get for next week
but we'll cover one of those two uh i do
definitely want to say thank you so much
uh to dave daley from grav and to sarah
todd from 420 sciences and absolutely to
uh jason harris as well had to jump a
little bit earlier
from jerome baker designs i want to say
thank you to peter cerveri who as always
uh is hosting these uh
as a simulcast on his channel on youtube
called the future cannabis project
so please check peter out and what he
does he's got some amazing content
on his youtube channel and uh thank you
to everyone else that contributed stefan
and adam and all the others that came up
to speak uh thank you so much and we'll
keep doing this on sunday nights
uh it's really fun for me to do them
it's always great when i've got guests
that really understand what it is we're
talking about
far more than i ever could so thank you
dave thank you sarah
amazing having you guys on tonight thank
you
thanks rob all right everyone have a
great sunday night and we'll catch you
next
sunday night for asking anything about
cannabis have a great night
you