[Music]
we is are here today just to kind of
discuss what we're seeing in the way of
what's happening in canvas-based
business and you know what we're seeing
in the way of valuations and M&amp;A
activity they're happening in canvas so
Jay what do you what do you see me now
what are your clients telling you what
kind of the bigger challenges you're
seeing from your client base Thanks um
so we're seeing a ton things are moving
super quickly and kind of in different
paces across the state so Los Angeles is
still kind of this laggard in terms of
getting people like really licensed but
then we see I think yesterday or two
days ago in San Francisco some of the
big marquee dispensaries are sold for
nine fingers like maybe 120 million
dollars one of the challenges I think my
clients face all the time is they see
big marquee transactions like that they
see in the news that somebody is sold
for 120 million dollars and they think
there need to redo what they're doing
they need to revisit a term sheet they
need to hold the phone on some deal
that's in progress we can't see all most
deals getting disrupted when they see
other good deals you've kind of seen the
ripple effects of some of these big
transactions yeah largest seeing a lot
of the same things the problem that
we're watching right now is the lot of
these transactions aren't being done as
cash transactions most of the buyers are
offering it's it's usually publicly
traded companies they're coming and
they're offering what are called 2080
deals for 20 percent in cash and 80
percent in stock in the stock then has
some sort of lockup period attached to
it oftentimes over multiples of years
and then often times you know you've got
no ability to to mitigate a sort of
downside risk on that stock component so
what's been you know difficult for for
the clients I've had is as they take a
look at the offers are being made to
them follow the cash offer over here in
the cash offer let's let's call it a
twenty million dollar offer and then the
other side they've got a an offer that
looks like it's a fifty million dollar
offer but really it's ten million in
cash in forty million in downstream
stock
so it you know you don't know what's
gonna happen to the 40 million dollar
stock component to it in many ways the
20 million dollars a better deal but
they start thinking we're worth 50 and
more importantly if one else around them
thinks they're worth 50 yeah if you had
somebody come to you in that situation
everybody's seen these Canadian
businesses just their valuations just
kind of go bananas and I used to work in
Silicon Valley where we're kind of used
to seeing things go bananas and then
come back to sanity how would you tell
somebody to think about the value of the
stock that they're being offered right
like it doesn't when we talk to them
about it and first of all we're not sure
for you know completely in bubble
territory or whether we've already
reached like to a whole territory at
this point so you know in many ways I
look at a lot of these valuations and I
think they aren't defensible I mean you
look at like where can be until rare and
it's not just a multiple to earnings
it's you know they're trading at 300
times revenue which is you know a number
that we didn't even see in tech or
telecom so it's almost impossible to
give these guys the the belief that this
thing's gonna stay is as high as it is
but right now because you've got you
know a lot of out of industry Wall
Street capital pouring into some of the
Canadian banks to fund these things
because they see the Canadian market as
being the safest place to invest they're
starting to feel some comfort there
which means it's validating these other
market caps and other people are coming
out or getting the same thing the
problem is that when the blue sky ends
and in fundamentals start kicking in
there's absolutely no way they can
sustain even if they continue to acquire
other people's balance sheets which is
you know as we're talking about earlier
what they're doing right now so when I
speak to clients about this you know
what I try to advise them is don't look
at the stock component if you are going
to look at it you know think about from
the perspective of all right how do i
medicate that stock component against
any downside risk like how do i you know
put a recalc in there so that you know
should I come off restriction the shares
have lost you know eighty percent of
their value between the time of the
acquisition happen in the time that they
actually become freely tradable for me
how do I say to the the purchaser you
know look we need to put something in
there that says should you lose X
personas value we want to have a
recalculation that brings us back up to
the total consideration that we were
promised in the first place yeah and I
think I see we see folks trying to
negotiate things like collars trying to
negotiate some kind of you know you say
it's going to be 50 million dollars in
stock well it needs to be
twenty forty and sixty that it needs to
have some grounding I think we see a lot
of the Canadian buyers really just
interested in that because they know
that their shares are crazily valued and
they really want all that risk to kind
of be on the seller they want the
dispensary other small company to kind
of live with that I think that I try and
tell clients sometimes if you had ten
million dollars would you buy ten
million dollars of canopy stock or ten
million dollars of whatever
Canadian company stock and usually they
think no if they had ten million dollars
that's not what they would do with it
and canopies great this isn't about
canopy but I feel like the when they
think about it that way they it becomes
real dollars right and at first we just
say I'll give you twenty million dollars
in stock and ten milligrams in cash it
seems like infinite but when you ask
them what do you want to invest in this
business they think twice
I go step past that and ask them you
know if you had that same money would
you buy yourself at this valuation yeah
do you really think that your business
is worth that much when you see these
other evaluations when you know I often
hear this like so and so just got bought
for 50 million that's crazy and you're
like yeah that's that's crazy you know
it's so you can't say that's crazy and
then I expect to have that as well
because the two things are in congruous
you know you need to make sure that
they're thinking about from the
perspective you know fundamentally what
are you worth and what's defensible
especially when you're thinking that a
lot of the transactions they're
comparing to are the ones have a public
stock component to it but when they're
raising capital they're still raising
capital with with private money it's
there is no stock component so you have
to say okay you know even if this other
company breezed at X and you know
because there it was an acquisition
where they actually were bought was
stock if you're out there trying to
raise ten million in growth capital and
you're trying to do a devaluation you
can't peg your valuation against their
valuation simply because it's a it's an
apples and oranges situation so if
somebody came to you and said you know
there's an offer to sell but there's
also an opportunity to grow the business
for a couple of more years would your
answer vary if they were a retailer or
manufacturer or
the distributor or do you think either
one of them should kind of make the same
sorts of decisions I would further
categorize away past that and say what
mark are you in you know what state are
you located in you know if it's an
oligopoly state like in New York or in
New Jersey or Connecticut where you've
got you know a golden ticket and you
know you can grow the business and very
likely the state's not going to you know
create some sort of an environment with
with new entrants in the marketplace and
everyone that's already in it has a
really strong Lobby to protect market
share there I'd certainly encourage them
to continue to grow rather than try it
sell right now but in a state you know
like California where you know that
let's say you know Los Angeles is a comp
set it's going to go from 135 pre ICO
companies to significantly more over the
next couple of years yeah if someone's
offering to buy you for you know
ridiculous valuation right now I would
say go ahead and sell it make sure you
don't sign a non-compete and turn around
and do it again as soon as you get the
chance to get a new license because you
know the markets are completely
different yeah and I think that when you
look at based on the Oh retailer versus
processor versus cultivator again it
completely depends you know if I were if
I were an indoor warehouse right now in
LA and someone offered me money I'd sell
in a heartbeat because the whole markets
moving towards mix like green house you
know there's there's no reason to be an
indoor grower anymore and most states
that have indoor growers you know
ultimately they're it's a failing
business model so you know how do you
actually be the lowest cost producer at
the highest quality and if you're not
that then you know you're largely
wasting your time long term and if you
got near-term exit take it yeah I think
we see I used to work up north I still
do working north a kind of switch
between both but it seems like the
cultivators are the ones who are first
being I don't want to say driven out but
being having the most difficulty
surviving having the most difficulty
adapting having the most difficulty
finding a place for themselves as things
move forward and it seems like the ones
who are almost newest to cannabis the
ones who are starting new businesses
sometimes almost have an advantage
because they're not trying to bring an
old business in they're just starting
something from scratch
does that does it make sense it doesn't
I think the California again
is unique because as we went through
this transition of illicit or gray
market to legal you had thousands upon
thousands of growers that existed
already in the state that the state was
encouraging you know hey get legal will
give you the opportunity to come into
the light you didn't have that with you
know to an extent with retailers but
certainly not with processors it's a
relatively new industry distributors is
you know very new industry but with the
cultivators there were so many of them
so while you have you know all the
northern counties you know Mendocino
Humboldt Trinity and then the whole
Grass Valley region all those guys were
we're dealing with you know okay do we
want to make the determination of stop
having an addressable market of the rest
of the United States on the illicit
market to having an addressable market
of just California yeah they had to make
that decision of do we want to do we
want to come in and they're all largely
cottage industry growers they weren't
you know large-scale commercial growers
they are now seeing Salinas Monterey
Carpinteria you know in the desert so is
much much different so ya mean to to
your point are those guys having a tough
time surviving yeah they're a really
tough time because now they dealing with
each other and a much smaller
addressable market of just the state of
California they're also dealing with all
these mega corporations that are coming
in and building these massive news
facilities yeah I think I see sometimes
they're almost there's a cultural
challenge sometimes I see too there are
folks who and it's not just cultivators
but folks who have been kind of steeped
in a kind of ploy stirred or or remote
whatever the word is of industry for a
while and now we do have private money
now we do have mature investors now we
do have sophisticated people who want to
do real estate transactions that are
kind of just novel to a lot of these
folks there's a deal I'm working on now
and the buyer and the seller very much
want to do the deal but they're just
almost like socially incompatible right
the buyer wants to communicate through
the attorneys that the seller thinks
that's impersonal and waste too much
money on legal fees the seller wants to
call the CEO of the buyer often and
schedule big conference calls which is
totally fine way to do it except the
buyer thinks that's nice and the whole
thing it seems like it might
collapse because they're just too
incompatible yeah yeah the business is
compatible but the styles of these two
guys is not compatible at this point
yeah I see a ton of that and a lot of
its based on sophistication of the of
the level of business they've done and
oftentimes the buyers at this point are
sophisticated guys they're coming in
with real capital they're looking at
these businesses in a very traditional
way they're they're looking at you know
what their revenues are currently what
their what their ebody is what their
what their growth curve is they're
thinking about this from the standpoint
of when I make an investment you know
what do I think this looks like five
years downstream is there a cash on cash
component to it you know what's my
horizon what's you know what's the debt
service can these guys actually cashflow
hard enough to service the debt yeah
the sellers are looking at from the
standpoint if I used to grow weed and
buy it for you know make it for a dollar
and sell it for two and a handshake was
my bond yeah
it's so for them you know going through
all these you know questions like when I
tell people to put a date a room
together I often get this blank stare if
you know what's the day to room and when
you go through and you know put the due
diligence checklist in front of they go
we don't do any of this stuff you know
yeah you don't think you do but the
person that's actually gonna be writing
that checks or sure does and you know
put it together now because ultimately
you're gonna have to anyway and rather
do it with me first and then do it with
the buyer that goes you know I'm not
interesting so these guys have no idea
what they're doing yeah I feel like it's
one of the the things they just kind of
have to like hold their nose and like
jump is the process of selling your
company is slow and difficult and
unpleasant and expensive and there's no
there's no escape from any of those four
things um you can do it with friendly
people you can plan ahead but it's just
gonna be difficult and slow because
that's what someone who's gonna write a
check for millions of dollars is gonna
insist we go through in order to get the
check and it's hard to like you said
there's a lot of folks who are used to I
grew it for one I sold it for two and
then I went to Costa Rica for six months
right which is awesome it's just not
really the next step and the problem is
and now you're starting to get the Nona
sophisticate investors our command but
they've already come in and those guys
are already thinking about the next link
in the in the evolution of the company
which is they want their exit you know
these guys aren't buying for
you know altruistic reasons they're
buying because they want to make money
yeah so if they come in you know two
years ago or three years ago when these
first real deals really started you know
happening in California and you start
seeing people poor you know not not sort
of money that was buried in ceramic
vessels in your backyard on the hill but
actually you know coming in from you
know reputable sources around Los
Angeles or San Francisco
those guys are already thinking of
cabinet in this deal for three years and
now I want to sell to the GTI's or the
the canopy's or the aurora's or you know
you name the the multi-state operator in
the US or the LP up in Canada and
they're thinking about what their exits
going to be and so they're doing things
properly already on the sale side so
when you've got the guys that are still
resisting it that are saying you don't
know if I want to go through all this
they're not only at a deficit you know
to to what their knowledge base should
be with a buyer but they're at an
amazing deficit to the people that have
already gone through the process once
and are now you know that further long
in their in their lifecycle yeah I feel
there's kind of the so we know nobody
likes other regulations we know nobody
likes kind of the cost of vendors and
the cost of people like me but on the
other hand everybody was great will come
out of the darkness will kind of have
like a real w2 it'll and it's almost
like the two things have to go together
people wanted legalization without all
the legalities yeah maybe that was maybe
that's a really obvious comment it is
well it's one that shouldn't be lost and
I see like comments and MJ business all
the time or in you know when you see
like LA Times articles or Samsung or
Chronicle articles you see the comment
section that comes after the article
inevitably it's like you know look at
what the announcement of Gavin Newsom
now sending you know federal enforcement
up to the northern counties to try to
enforce illegal cultivations and
everyone's like you know this guy that
can't believe he's doing this I thought
he's Pro cannabis yeah he's Pro legal
cannabis he's not probe elicit anything
you know so he you guys were given a
couple of years period I'm first of all
I'm the biggest supporter of you know
illicit farmers you know over the last
thirty years you're gonna find but a
certain point you know when you realize
that this is disrupting a market that
they're trying to get off the ground
they're doing it in a way that everyone
asks for them to do it yeah there's got
to be some some give-and-take there so
it's you know I would I prefer not to
see sort of the years of camp come
in humboldt Mendocino sure I don't want
to see helicopters landing on people's
properties but at the same time I also
don't want to see illicit growers taking
em you know the ability to do have a
good business away from guys that are
following every bit of letter of the law
so it's it's a tough it's a tough
situation there but eventually you are
gonna see the the people that were
non-sophisticated unwilling to to change
they're just gonna end up going out of
business yeah and I think sometimes I
use the word almost unsophisticated
incorrectly I do sometimes because I
think sometimes they're they're super
sophisticated they just want to stay out
of the legal market I mean it's not easy
it's not easy being a criminal and they
prefer yeah sure but the point
well-taken
living outside the law requires honesty
it requires being good at what you do it
requires not burning people and all the
things that you expect to see in real
business actually it happens in a much
more profound way on the on the illicit
side or the the outlaw side of it and I
think that the people that all of us in
this room probably dealt with for years
and years it was because you know we're
still sitting here because you didn't
burn anyone or do anything really stupid
and I think that you know acting that
way for years is probably the mantra
that you should have as a as a business
owner in general and you realize the
real criminals and the real dirtbags out
there are the guys on the legal side
that are coming in trying to figure out
ways to create term sheets that
completely and totally rape you
so it requires guys like Jay and I to
sit there and go dad don't sign that
like they absolutely not so the believe
me want to say I'm absolutely
sympathetic to the outlaw it's just a
question of how do you bring the outlaw
and into the legal market without you
know getting absolutely destroyed in the
process and right now I think that's a
business-wise it's a really tough thing
to advise people on doing because they
only know a certain way and that certain
way was based 100% on honesty and trust
yeah and the returns in you know non
reported transactions can be really good
you know we have this client who said
something once like I just want to go
back to the time when I could grow four
three months a year and surf in Costa
Rica for nine
and we thought like that would be
awesome but that's not yes please
yeah like that that was never a
sustainable that wasn't gonna work but
but it did for thirty-plus you yeah yeah
right dad so you know when you have
something that's been working that long
and that's pretty good yeah do that if I
could yeah yeah I mean look it's the
fact that matters that we are going
through a crazy transition right now in
the state of California and when I you
know the analogy I always used is kind
of in a relay race for you're passing
the baton and right now we're in the
space that's you know 50 yards of the
baton pass and you know you're on the
the the gray market or prop 215 side on
the you know perform early and now
you're moving into the post 64 you know
new life in California cannabis and
surviving this baton pass Lane it's
gonna be exceptionally difficult now
having said that the illicit market in
the near term until all 50 states are
legalizing the United States and you're
able to cross state lines we're never
gonna see the the illicit market go away
and I think there's a lot of people in
the northern counties and a lot of
people even probably than ten blocks of
here that are perfectly pleased to stay
in the market they've always been in
into your point as far as profit
motivation the the return profile is
still significantly better to operate on
that side there's just a much higher
risk profile as well so you know where
do you want to where do you want to live
you know I think for most people now
they're weighing that option they're
having to think about seriously but at
the same time as they're making that
decision from a business standpoint
which is really I think we're here
discussing it yeah how do you how do you
think about it no way that's gonna be
meaningful so that eventually you're not
spending three months on the beach in
Costa Rica you're spending all your time
on the beach in Costa Rica because you
had a meaningful sale you don't allowed
you to walk away from a great business
that you built up and said I made the
transition from you know from I wouldn't
say dark to light but great alight
successfully yeah I think that's a
conversation we have a lot with clients
who it never they never really thought
what they were what was gonna happen to
the business in the end and most small
businesses are either sold or closed
right and I hear clients often say like
when we do our IPO and I want to like
gently lien
and be like almost no business does an
IPO even if you're fantastic spectacular
probably not gonna happen
especially for a cannabis business right
um they're coming for you J so getting
you know kind of starting those
conversations were in reality you were
probably always going to sell this
business you were gonna sell it to
someone you know you were gonna pass it
on to someone or you were gonna sell it
to a stranger I'm hoping that you would
get some great outcome right for this
business it's been your life and your
sweat and your blood and your tears and
you told me a few minutes ago that you
have a sign that your mother wrote
outside your farm that was discouraging
people's horses from pooping on your
farm and she's had this sign for like
six years this is your life like this
business is your life it's called dew
point there's the horses nearby are very
kind right she's not yeah so I think we
talk a lot and that was a long aside I'm
sorry we talk a lot with clients about
kind of getting them comfortable with
the idea of it might be a great idea for
you to transition away from this this
might be the best chance you have to
right move on to its next yeah I think
that's something that shouldn't be lost
on most people anyone that started a
small business when you go into it you
know you think about how great the
business can't do and how you can build
this thing but after about your five or
six or seven you start to realize that
this thing is is you it's a marriage
it's a complete tether on everything
else you do it limits your ability if
you find a better opportunity you're
like what do I do with the one I already
have
you know I'm stuck with the Saints in
many ways of business as an anchor and
then you're stuck with it so when you
think about an exit you know it's it's
rare that a business is cash flowing so
well that you know you're like look I'm
perfectly happy just to keep this thing
going and for a long time that's what
Northern California cannabis was you
know it's like as much as we can make
we're know as much as we can grow on the
risk that we're willing to take doing it
you know it's I don't know anyone to
date that's ever so lar ever thrown away
a pound of weed you know it's it's it's
going to find a home unless it's unless
it's completely molded out or some other
thing even then I'm there's shady guys
when you see clients who are really
attached to some business if they've
been going forever how do you as it's
often the case some people in the
business want to sell yeah some people
in business don't want to sell right how
do you how do you have those
conversations with them where I mean
because my instinct is to encourage them
to probably take the good offer
take the reasonable offer because it's
here I I did it with a client yesterday
okay and then in the client yesterday
you know there are three different term
sheets around the table for them yeah by
three decent companies you know all of
them were qualified suitors yeah
they got an offer you know yesterday
that was the the third turn of a term
sheet and you know we got the call like
what do you think and our answer is you
know look you guys have been waiting for
this for a while this this is one that
no I can you live with but it's one
that's got great upside potential it's
got mitigated downside risk yeah what
else you waiting for
you know if you are serious about
selling this company take the offer this
is it especially that's gonna integrate
you into a company where you think that
corporate culture is one that largely
coincides with who you are as people and
you think you can integrate it and
easily the thing I discourage feel from
doing is being acquired by a company
where the culture corporate culture is
just not a fit and you're you know
moving into a group you want nothing to
do with ultimately and they go oh well
it's only a two-year lockup or I've
gotta stay with the company well that
could be the most miserable two years of
your life you know so it's we try to
encourage the a if there's one buy or
one seller that is on the team that
really wants to sell there's another one
that doesn't have that conversation
internally first make sure that whenever
you go out with a forward facing look to
the outside world you're doing it with
consistency yeah if there is one person
that doesn't you know want to it then
you figure out a way to offer to sell to
them first or you know a way to do
something else that allows the the needs
of the different people within the
within the company to match yeah I think
that if they're tyent's can go into
these conversations thinking someday I
will do something next right this isn't
the last thing I'm ever gonna do this is
the thing I'm doing right now it can
kind of facilitate either
other people coming in you tell your
partners or just not the this is my
member like Gollum in Lord of the Rings
like this is mine like I feel like it it
will wither if it's kind of concrete
like that I also think that a liquidity
event even one that might not be the one
that you're hoping for but you know if
you had a company that's doing you know
call it three million dollars in
top-line revenue and someone offers you
five times revenue and also there's a
fifteen million dollar offer on the
table and you've only got you know 1/2
million dollars of debt to knock out and
you've got a couple other equity
investors that own 20% of your business
if you end up walking away from this
think post-tax with six or seven million
dollars in your pocket I hate to break
it to most people that's life-changing
money yeah and if you want to go out
there now and make investments yourself
into other spaces and start peppering
the market with companies that you like
with check sizes of 150 to 250 K you
know also now you can you know spread
that couple million bucks still keep two
or three million in your pocket and
you've put three or four million back to
work in the space yeah hoping you get
another exit on one of 15 companies
you're putting in and chances are based
on the climate
you'll get one yeah so it's you know for
people that are like oh I'm holding out
for the 50 million dollar payday yeah
sure if you've got a business that's
that's that dynamic and in that
exceptional great but if you're you know
creating a product that you know another
vape cart you know okay you probably
want to take the 15 million bucks yeah
one thing we were talking about earlier
was the idea that so when you're being
paid with stock it's you're really
making a second bet right like the first
bet was that I can build a company I can
do this I can put this money in its
going to succeed
the second bet is they can build a
company they can do it better right they
can do it with my with everything I've
done and it's this hum yeah it's I feel
like that's one scenario where I'm
always encouraging folks to be really on
the one hand I'm I try and encourage
them to find a transaction that works
but I think I'm also really cool on
accepting paper from Canadian companies
which is just so such a gamble at this
point
I'll look in the camera okay don't do it
it's I'm not saying don't do it a
hundred percent but a lot of these
companies like they they have almost no
liquidity and they trade you know ten
thousand shares a day so and you're
about to be given millions of shares of
paper so it's like okay if you've had
that paper anything off restriction
there's no if there's no buyer on the
other side of the trade then what do you
really have you know if you actually
start putting these shares out in the
market you're gonna crater the share
price of the company anyway so if you're
gonna do it make sure it's a company
that really has you know the ability to
to let you have your ultimate exit if
not you're probably better off you know
continue to build your company if you're
good at building the company then keep
going and someone else will come along
later yeah so the question I have for
you that came on the same idea is yeah
as as we're watching progression happen
on a federal basis in definitely
watching progression happens
state-by-state and I don't think there's
a person in this room that doesn't think
the federal legality is not going to
happen you know not probably not in this
administration but certainly you know in
the next if it if it goes you know the
way of a Democratic Senate and a
Democratic president at that point you
know what do you think about the
California market as an export market in
the long term because for me I'm
watching a lot of consolidation right
now happened in California but
ultimately California always powered
American cannabis do you think that day
comes back and do you think it's
worthwhile telling people to hold out
until a the capital markets open up in
the US and B when California becomes the
epicenter again of American cannabis so
I mean I think I've heard people like
Lori Ajax say and one of these days
we're going to become an exporter and
it's probably true eventually I'm
reluctant for any of my clients to hold
out for that just because there's
probably going to be ten things that
happen between now and then that might
impact how things actually look you know
someday we'll probably have I used to
smoke a pack of cigarettes every day I
think the tobacco was grown in North
Carolina at that point I have no idea
where it's grown today but it's probably
not cheapest to do at North Carolina
anymore um cannabis commercial
recreational cannabis probably become
just like any other commodity Sunday and
for maybe I have a lot of times up north
who
to become like high-end vineyards right
they're gonna have a very specialized
product the appellation theory of the
humble crow normandeau grown and I'm
sure for some of them that'll work
I think the question is like for how
many of them could it work so I guess I
think federal legalization will probably
happen but not soon enough to impact
anyone today what do you do you think
it's would you if someone came in to you
and said I'm gonna wait until I can sell
my product in 50 states so that I really
have a market could you tell they're
crazy it depends on the toes of the
client yeah I'm looking at some of the
companies are being built in California
right now and you know you look at the
announcement made yesterday that Gotham
green put 125 million to work into flow
Cana and you know and do I think that
you know we 125 million dollars in the
revenue that Mikey Steinmetz is putting
out of the the Fetzer facility up north
that he's got the ability to to weather
a storm for a period of time yeah 125 is
a decent investment by any other
industry standards it's a tiny
investment but it's you know for canvas
is big a company like that or a company
and you know like I don't know some of
the other mega you know as groups are
being put together that that are looking
at California is a consolidation play
yeah you know do I think that for them
you know companies that are raising
capital at north of three or four
hundred million dollars in as a
valuation
I would I would think those guys would
probably want to weather the storm
because I think that in several years
time you know I don't think that this is
a something that goes on forever and
while I agree with you that in the
meantime you know do we see like the the
the country of Colombia become an export
market or do we see like Macedonia
become an export market to Europe or you
know are there new places they're gonna
pop open sure but I always think there I
think there's always gonna be the need
for high in flour and there's always
gonna be producers that are specialized
for high in flour yeah I think that the
part that we commoditized is is you know
the extraction side of it where people
are gonna grow just a blast yeah so I've
got a fine
technology that it thinks and I think
it's compelling but they have a
basically like a new gummy processing
technology that is fantastic and it's
their goal to basically make that
platform you mean you could you could do
the up title in 50 states and then
at the last minute put in cannabis from
that state right there's no reason the
first nine tenths of the gummy needs to
contain cannabis they are a company and
I think some of them if there are
manufacturing techniques if there are
some new recipes that could come around
and really I mean I think sorry
roundabout way of saying I think some
products could become national even
before we have I think they are I mean I
think you're looking at some of the the
branded products out there and the race
right now is to create you know brand
equity in branded products but a lot of
those are licensing deals for that you
know they'll be created in California
they're licensed to five or six other
states on the expectation that when
legalization happens they've already
built the brand equity and then they can
you know move in with 3pl facilities and
in five different locations think about
licensing so in the past four or five
months there's been a ton of excitement
in California about how much contract
manufacturing people can do right and
today's the final regulations people can
do a good amount those rules 904 is that
right I think it's 50 30 to the the
white labeling yeah yeah people so
there's some hopes to jump in when
people can do it but I wonder when you
see folks come to you who want to
assemble you know portfolio brands yeah
right a portfolio of iconic brands and
then just license the heck out of them
is that something that you think is
there is there a future that business or
is that kind of trying to do it like
under almost yeah I think there's a I
think there's definitely a future of it
for it if you're talking about a
california-based company if you're
talking about a Connecticut based
company I don't think you were large
enough addressable market in your home
market to to really want to be able to
do it that way but if you're talking
about you know when I think about the
market we're sitting right now it's the
largest canvas market in the world I
mean if you think that there's 39
million people in California and 20 21
million of those people live from LA
County down to the Mexican border across
five counties in the space that you know
geographically is about the size of
Rhode Island you know you're talking
about a market that is just
significantly more
than any other market that's out there
that's that's Colorado Washington Oregon
Alaska and Arizona combined you know in
in one market so if you think about from
the standpoint of aggregating brands and
only working just the SoCal market and
using that as your as your jumping off
point then yeah I mean I think just that
alone is worth it and then you can think
about licensing but if you're talking a
small adjustable market that's where
you're launching like a Minnesota based
you know like aggregation of brands
company it doesn't make any sense to me
I think another maybe one thing I should
have said was so if I were a company and
I wanted to get the rights to make
Marley and meatloaf and Guns N'Roses and
I said I was going to be the license and
company to have the music all of the
music the type today we're still today
there's a ton of products say there's a
ton of inconsistency at dispensaries
right today there's still kind of the on
the retail side the markets still really
do you think the brands that are gonna
be are the ones that have you know the
Grateful Dead label on them and that's
what's gonna allow them to kind of
become something or it's just gonna be
like a better product no III don't and
the the private equity firm that I
founded Akal years ago we did the Willie
Nelson transaction okay we led the
series and Willie yes you really thought
about yeah we actually were working very
closely with the Grateful Dead and the
Garcia band estate as well at the time
you know we were looking really
seriously at do we bring it Grateful
Dead canvas Brandon market and was right
when Marley was being done by privateer
and is right around the same time that
you're watching you know snoop work with
Casa Verde so you know everyone was
thinking about the standpoint of you
know do you need a marquee sort of an
endorser to do it and the thing I kept
hearing that was consistent across
everyone is well the advertising
equivalency of having these people out
there having the name out there because
you know if there's restrictions in
advertising and marketing can you make
up for those restrictions by actually
having you know Willie Nelson every
single tour stop wearing a welder's
reserve hat or having you know Snoop
Dogg talking about the fact he's got
some deals live well in Colorado and
that that was gonna you know drive
business but but ultimately you know you
look at the wine industry and you know
while you might have a couple of wine
it's not coolest name that drives the
other sales it's the underlying product
itself
okay and I think with cannabis you know
it's I think right now what's becoming
hotter are specific genetics are still
hot and then specific growers that are
putting those genetics out so if you
know you really trust you know whatever
whatever the underlying brand is like
I'm here today with a group called
Palomar and in Palomar puts out some of
the best you know craft cannabis product
in the country and I don't think people
are gonna buy it because he they had a
celebrity endorsement they're gonna buy
it because you know the grower for
Palomar is one of the best guys and then
in the state of California okay so then
what made Willie Nelson's likeness
compelling to you I voted against it
only person on the investment committee
that said no okay okay what was
compelling to me was was the fact that
there's an icon that's recognizable even
in states that are illegal especially
the American South you know Texas
Louisiana Tennessee like all the you
know country music states that anyone
that smoked cannabis down there be like
oh man I got rye well his wheat because
there's there's certain part of it that
everyone's gonna try it once because
it's Willie's weed but will they try it
the second time or the third time I
think that brand quality has to hold the
day and as you said there's
inconsistency and if you hire six
different growers in six different
markets to grow that same brand even if
you're putting out the same genetically
if everyone's doing like an OG Kush yeah
unless you're growing in the exact same
growing conditions with the exact same
media with the exact same nutrients the
exact same relative humidity and soon
it's going to be a different product and
I don't like true branding perspective I
don't think there's any brand equity and
something that you can't say is
consistent yeah
[Music]
you point are you guys like trying to
raise money
friends and family investors those that
couldn't hear it in the audience what
she is saying is that her farm in her
land up north is her life
so just because she has something that
people might want to purchase doesn't
mean that she wants to sell and I think
there's a lot of people that feel it
well I applaud that so that's that's
great and that means that you know
you're happy building this thing because
it's it's what you want to do long-term
which is awesome so Cheers
and I don't know if the same is true
like I know the specific guys are over
here as well or a pretty decent size
distribution company they have offices
kind of all over the the California
north and south I know they've done a
pretty good job picking up quite a few
brands so I don't know if the same is
true for those guys but China navigating
the regulations trying to figure out how
to get into the market how to get into
the market legally how to build
partnerships that are scalable has been
you know a big part of what we've been
trying to do and then on the fundraising
side there's obviously like a lot of
interest and a lot of money but again
finding those partners that can bring
value as well as those partners that are
strategically aligned to the type of
growth that you want to have and kind of
keeping this especially as I guess
Outsiders to the industry is not those
that have been in the gray market one of
the things that's been important to us
though has been actually working with
small farmers and we have an established
relationship with a licensed farm in
medicine oh it's a big part of it but
some of the pushback we've actually
gotten from some investors as well as as
well as some manufacturers that we've
talked about partnering with has been oh
like you don't need to do that like
we've got this stuff that's grown in
this warehouse and you should just roll
forward with this it's much cheaper and
it's much easier and like we can make
that happen much quicker so finding
those partners that are have that value
alignment has been a little more
difficult for us but something that
we're working on and what's your product
oh yes of the product drew Martin
is a line of botanically infused
freerolls
so cannabis with a specific blends of
botanicals that have been formulated by
by drew Martin himself herbalist that
sounds compelling yeah I do think that's
a good point that your name is Andrew as
well is that right thanks Andrew I think
it's a good point that as you're getting
off the ground there's a lot of people
that want to tell you how you should
build your business and why you should
build your business that way and I think
that you know if in most other
businesses you don't have that much
outside influence here you know as
people are getting in the it's amazing
to me that every time I go to a cannabis
convention seventy percent of the people
in that room were like oh this brand new
industry and I started laughing I go
that look I started this industry twenty
eight years ago and I was new that
mostly goes I was a kid and like being
taught by guys there were twenty thirty
years older than me really so it's like
you know four people say it's a new
industry to know the industry has always
been here
legality is new were you were you living
out here now in the summertime but uh
living living in Salt Lake City Utah and
then spending most the time well I'm
grateful that tour was sort of bouncing
around having fun it was awesome yeah
better than Costa Rica Jorge lot spike
my product is called cookie crack it's a
fantastic edible cookie and it actually
came from a cookie that we have been
marketing for years without cannabis
with crack no but now we've infused it
with cannabis before it was just a fun
dessert okay cookie that actually cuz
like both are scheduled one so I don't
you know yeah yeah that's true and you
know trying to get into the the legal
part of the market if I can be so you
know blunt it seems there's different
ways and what I'm interested in and my
questions about is this a shared
facility that they just enacted
I think late last year and they did
something with it earlier this year
which for somebody like me would be
perfect do you have any advice on that
or any information so if you can find
someone who's looking like to open up
one of the shared facilities I think
it's pretty relatively easy to get one
of the what does it take C s as an S
which is yeah it's very easy to get it
you have to find a you know somebody
with an N or you know m6 m7 yeah type
license and I don't know how they can
get into a but from what I understand
like the commercial kitchen that you
know several people can go in there but
they can't go in there at the same time
right so in essence you rent time I get
a s license or permit and you kind of
piggyback into them and I think I've
seen folks in like entrepreneurs in
Oakland who are trying to basically buy
a big space right and then like
basically rent it out it's like yeah so
I guess if you are you in a larger area
you know city no adventurer County ok so
there's very little that they're
carrying up there Thousand Oaks to be
specific okay um I think they've got one
Testing Center and one medical I mean I
think if you looked in a place where
there were just more right here might be
good I've also heard that Huntington
Beach there's a couple of cities there
and I've contacted the the the state
about it and they said there's a
directory they're working on they just
haven't put it out there yet because
which I think would be very helpful
towed myself and a lot of people I think
BCC has the list but to see DPH have a
list on its website
that's the one that they're saying that
they do yeah they have all the ones that
have permanent and temporary license or
annual and temporary license but they
don't have a specific directory for
shared facilities okay and I don't
okay right right well I've talked
directly with them and the gentleman
Billy I think it was his name I've been
communicating an email with him from the
from the California Department and he
was saying it's something they're
working on and then they're real close
to publishing the question yes it's a
viable way to go with the business yeah
exact or a white label understand those
facilities that do that that already
have on but then you kind of if you and
your license as well
yeah then they've got their license both
entities are licensed right do you have
any other suggestions on how one you
know other than going getting a building
buying the building and then applying in
you know where the licenses are still
available
I think the barriers to entry are super
high and I think for a manufacturer yeah
you you need to find a place yeah where
you can do it and then you need the
equipment the kind of shared space idea
though I mean you can drop your cost of
acquisition by a time it sounds like you
just need to find other folks who are
close enough to you which like you're
saying it shouldn't there are other
people in your shoes right you know who
want to do this as well I know I know
people who are German Cokely and I know
people were trying to do it in San
Francisco it's something that California
astronomy because obviously everybody
knows they didn't have the revenue they
thought they'd have in fact they had
less revenue with the recreational than
they did the year before with just
medical yeah and it's the restrictions I
mean they're just you know from seed to
sale is almost impossible you know my
background is manufacturing apparel and
I know how complicated everything yes
with regulations and everything like
that so it's so hard to track I would
imagine so I believe they're trying to
you know kind of open it up a little bit
I think they say that they want micro
businesses in there
they want to do something like the beer
industry has where it's just not the
Budweiser's coming in there and
controlling the market you know what
you'll get the growth of different types
strains different flavors different you
know different vehicles of how to
consume it so good luck thank you
so I think it's got the design I think
we ran out of time so Jay thank you so
much those really enjoyed it thanks to a
future cannabis project for for putting
on these vats that's super cool really
nice that there's a group in LA that's
actually doing this and get people
together in the industry
[Music]
you