[Music]
we're gonna go into discussion about
some issues on formation and go into the
a little bit company culture and then
the fundraise process for for who in a
in Amanda when you guys first started
forming your companies when when do you
think it was necessary to first engage a
lawyer and like the kind of lawyers that
you thought were necessary along the way
I know for companies for example to
touch the plant you know they make them
everything oh I need to get my my
license first and we go get our
regulatory 'el you know attorney and
then I regulatory might end up saying
you know I can do everything for you but
they might have the corporate expertise
so we sometimes have clients that come
over to us with that issue and said that
it might be interesting to see so what
your perspective is on when lawyers
became relevant okay I won't tell you
why did I want tell you it may not be
what you want to do so I met my lawyer
over oysters at UH and Tomales Bay at a
friend's birthday party yiii lawyer and
wanted to get into the space and wanted
to help and so he actually formed a lot
of our documentation in the early days
then we got into Y Combinator my
O'Connor inna has a whole legal
department thankfully he didn't mess
anything up and they validate it and it
worked out pretty well but I kind of
hacked I had as well in the industry was
leveraging the legal of my counterparts
or my partners which has helped bridge
some gaps here and there where you can
see a lot of different documentation and
compare notes and then you can bring it
to a lawyer and kind of like understand
how to formulate your own those are you
know some ways I've been able to
navigate legal but any of your raising
financing you know it's really important
to get your structure right otherwise
you may be at the finish line and can't
cross
um I mean granted I'm a lawyer so I
probably started earlier as soon as
money was being spent that was you know
something other than just our time I
think once the check was written over
like two grand
we should probably sort this out but I
didn't pick the right lawyer the first
try that's for sure and I made plenty of
decisions that were bad decisions that
you know you would think as a lawyer but
lawyers aren't entrepreneurs I've
learned that through and through so you
know as we go through these questions
tonight I am going to share a lot of
screw-ups because I in the very
beginning when I wanted to start this
business I went to an event called
Denver startup week and it's like the
largest free entrepreneurial event in
the world over ten thousand people a
year plus show up and the best panel I
went to was called founder fuck-ups and
these now successful founders got on
stage and told everything they screwed
up and I like notes on things not to do
and hopefully I can also tell you some
lessons and things not to do now that
said we're doing really well it's okay
to make mistakes you just have to not
repeat them and if you can have people
tell you about mistakes that they made
and you can avoid those ones that's one
less mistake to make one thing I would
say is it's a piggyback on what Amanda
said is and maybe atriums different but
don't let lawyers run your business you
know that's a big that's a big one if I
did everything lawyers time we started
ArcView in 2010 right so if I did
everything lawyers told me to do for the
last you know in nine years we wouldn't
we wouldn't be here right so you know
you got to look at the risk factors you
got to look at what what you're doing
and understand what's that what's that
risk when you take take different
actions but you know particularly
because so many things can cost so much
now if you're able to read and maybe
this is what atrium is working on is if
you can lower the cost to be able to do
a lot of those things you can you can
protect yourself even more so and for
lower cost which gives you the ability
to protect yourself more
we're working on it and I hope for for
the clients that are in the crowd that
that we're doing a pretty good job so
far so I think the next thing I want to
sort of discuss is a little bit more
technical but also an important point
with respect to when you go to form your
company it's obviously a little bit
different for you know if you're in the
business of touching the plant versus
just sort of a tech company operating in
the space I just wanted to hear your
thoughts on you know from an investor's
perspective what you liked if you're
investing in a company that touches the
plants sort of like the the entity
structure that you like to see for
example a holding company that holds a
wholly owned subsidiary that holds the
license and operating entity that's in
California and sort of your opinions on
sort of what you think works best under
the current regulatory scheme I can
speak to it a little bit
basically it really depends on the state
and also there our elements to where
that a lot of investors can get kind of
thrown off by a little bit because
you'll see a company come that has like
multiple LLC's in order to accomplish
certain things with 280e rules that
they're you know looking to avoid you
know looking to to be tax efficient with
with LLC's and stuff and you'll see
investors just be like whoa that just
looks weird they're used to seeing a
Delaware see corporate different
companies trying different things and
being innovative it's very tough as an
investor to know you know what's okay
what's not okay how that all works and
so that's where law firms come in really
handy on both sides to really understand
that are at ArcView specifically we even
though we bring investors and
entrepreneurs together we're not the
ones in the deals that touch the plant
at least so far we haven't placed any
capital there so we've stayed in the
ancillary side when it comes to us
placing capital but we certainly see a
wide range of
of setups but I would not call myself an
expert on that that's why I'm on this
panel with these guys the thing I would
say when it comes to formation and
entity type is that you don't need to
necessarily plan to be one entity type
your entire life if you are planning to
go and raise on day one certainly there
are things that make more sense than
others but you know I have a cousin
that's a top VC down the valley does not
touch family deals but his advice to me
was I take money from early-stage
startups for a living and as your cousin
I'm going to tell you to bootstrap as
far as you can humanly bootstrap and in
doing so a different entity type made
sense for me in the early days we were
an LLC and we were able to take
advantage of partnership taxation and
when you're taking on losses and
bootstrapping it's a really good
structure and so it you really have to
not get set on one type once we went to
take on serious capital yes we convert
it into a Delaware C Corp but I have no
regrets about forming the way we did
because it made sense and once you make
a corporation election you can't go back
from that so easily so you know there's
no need to you have to look at what your
situation is and where you're going and
not be dead set on day one and one thing
I did for those in there I know Troi
touched on this idea of 280e if if
you're unaware as to what that is it's
basically something in the tax code that
says that if you you know traffic and
illegal drugs you don't get the benefit
of certain tax deductions and so if
you're in the cannabis business you have
to work around that and so for a lot of
businesses in the cannabis industry it
means you don't get the benefit of your
general administrative deductions and so
you come up with these more complex
corporate structures to be able to work
around that and one other thing I wanted
to piggyback on what Amanda's saying and
yes the you know in the traditional text
sense the and you guys feel free to
correct me if I'm wrong if you you see
the you know Delaware company and it's
great for taking VC investments but for
touch the plant businesses it's not
always the best because for example
cannabis is illegal in Delaware
so as a result if you hip holding the
court there that creates a lot of
problems so you need to think about you
can't just go on coolly go and you know
use their Delaware and corporation Docs
if you're gonna be applying for a
license in California because that
changes sort of you know the place
you're gonna be in and the morale that
story is simply you this is where you
call your attorney make sure you have an
attorney that's versed in these things
and discuss what you're trying to
accomplish
because right we're tech company and
many of you guys are plant touching
companies and so you have different
needs and that's we're trying to you
know I wish I could give you guys the
answers to everything tonight but these
are one of the why you have to talk to
your attorneys yeah I can speak to to
corporate structures meadow la reunión
where seek Delaware c-corporation
we don't touch the plant we have four
founders everyone's an equal shareholder
we have an option pool that is dedicated
to hiring talent as well as providing
advisory shares how I paid for my
initial lawyer hoister guy Doug who's
awesome was initially advisory chairs so
that can come into play if you with a
you know having a seat work my wife
Crete has an edible company she's a
c-corp in California for exactly the
same reason that you said we didn't want
a licensed entity in Delaware in case of
any issues you know she's a solo founder
but as an option pool and is taking
capital through a safe vehicle it's
kinda what we use as a convertible
without an expiration date without terms
and you know payback periods it's what
YC continually uses which I recommend
but it might not be the best for you
it's just an easy way of getting capital
without having to convert that equity
initially ya know those are really good
insights who and for all of you who
haven't heard of his wife's company it's
called Melos and you should 100% try
them they're fantastic so I think
another big step along a formation
highway is dealing with banking I know
it's gotten a lot easier but I know
Amanda had some really great stories
about it and you know great to hear from
you as well
on sort of any roadblocks you've you've
hit in that space and or just like how
you got banking services from from the
get-go oh so well as the former bank
regulator I can't really lie to bankers
about what I do I'm like the absolute
perfect target for you know I know your
costumer investigation what do you mean
you didn't know you had to tell your
banker you're a former bank regulator I
couldn't really lie so I'm day one you
know there was challenges with that but
I basically had to use my entire network
of banking attorneys and whatnot to find
a bank that would take us and we're
ancillary but we found one thankfully
and we've been with them for many years
but they're like most banks that want to
deal with people like us not a ginormous
bank and as such they don't have their
own merchant services so merchant
services have been really challenging
for us over the years denials and then
having merchant services no problem for
two and a half years now when you're
bootstrapping a company and you pay
payroll off of revenue and come February
first Intuit calls you and they're like
hey based on who you take money from
we're cutting you off and we're not
decrypting any of the information oh and
not to mention your lawyer so of course
you're not keeping this stuff on your
personal servers you're making sure it
gets entered directly into the encrypted
system let's just say I had 97 accounts
outstanding at that point of customers
who I didn't have payment information
for and I had to make payroll this is
not for the faint of heart this is hard
stuff and that could have ended my
company could and did any company that
was bootstrapped on it I got scrappy and
I took on some consulting projects and I
also had a team that knew what we were
getting into all along so I was very
transparent with them but I made thirty
thousand dollars of consulting money
show up in about seven days and I paid
payroll and I called everybody I knew
and got a million rejections everyone's
like oh yeah well you're an Slayer we'll
be able to get you a bank account it was
all around the Jeff Sessions scares at
the time
eventually I got it done and I never
thought I would jump up and down for a
6.9% hate and then eventually we found
one at 5.9 and now we're back into the
twos but to say the least save as much
money his you humanly can it's not the
in case fund it's the when fund and
again it's not for the faint of heart
but we survived that one too yeah
getting it back in count is difficult if
you're a licensed entity I'm just I
think what we've also seen is all the
structures where there's a holding
company so you know that's kind of my
advice it's more about creating a
holding company that manages the payroll
or expenses for businesses that you know
that allows you a little bit more
distance from it
and that's where you kind of run a lot
of your your your payroll and expenses
so if you go the route of just saying
what you do you're gonna get denied just
Sam the biggest advice I would have on
this is to have multiple bank accounts I
got caught once not having another bank
account lined up and I'll never have
that happen again we almost weren't able
to make payroll and it was really it was
one of those things where they're like
we're gonna send you the money they're
gonna kick us they're kicking us out and
they're gonna send us the money but we
if we take it out by this day we can
actually have it to be able to open up
the other account otherwise you'd have
to wait like 15 days or something for
this cheque to come to then goes but I
had like a lot of bills during that time
I was like oh no I can't not pay people
so but we got right under the wire and
now you look back you laugh at a so we
got through it you know those were the
good old days or whatever right but no
don't have multiple bank accounts even
when the bank says oh yeah no it's
totally cool we're allowed to work with
cannabis companies every bank we've ever
been in has told well except for one has
told us that they're totally cool with
cannabis
because we're ancillary but the way
these banks work is they've got their
regulatory Department and a lot of times
it doesn't go all the way up there or
somebody from the regulatory department
does give ok but then a banking
regulator comes in and starts giving
them a hard time and then they have to
go back on their word and so this is
happens like a domino and so have
multiple accounts so when one Falls you
got another one and then when that one
Falls you get a new one
right it's getting easier it's you know
I think it's you can get a bank account
now but it takes work and sometimes it's
not always the best banks and sometimes
they want to charge you a lot of money
to bank with them which usually goes the
other way around in banking but not
anymore not with cannabis so there's
these different pieces of it but it's a
lot better than it was a few years ago
and I have a good sense that banking
will get resolved very very shortly I'm
hopeful too when when we went down to
that six point nine and that five point
nine and down to twos we still run
certain transactions and swallow the
extra fees and run things in that six
point nine in that five point nine every
month because we still need those guys
to be there in case we lose one of the
other ones also we changed our name
corporate wise like we we don't need to
have kin in our name and neither do you
you don't need green Verde virtus any
iteration of bloom Farms flowers
whatever and you know we have multiple
reasons why we changed our name to regs
technology but our company and our
project are very much kin of eggs and
we're very transparent with our bank and
her bank thankfully has always been on
our side so they opened us the regs
technology account the data probably
haven't they they they're VPS were
trying to get us merchant services as
well so just keep those things out of
your name to make yourself and your life
less painful sweet I think that was
tremendously helpful for everybody so
let's move on to sort of structuring the
founding team how like what
recommendations would you have into
of from you know the investors
perspective as to what you like to see
in terms of the equity split leaving
room for you know future VC money to
maybe come in to making sure your
founder team is founding team is
everybody's properly incentivized maybe
on similar terms nobody feels slighted
for example I don't sure you want to
start first yeah I mean it really
depends on what at what stage you're
investing into a company and also every
company is totally different in terms of
the incentives and and and things like
that I would say I mean this kind of
gets a little bit into value what you
can't talk about yeah we can talk about
valuation cuz that's really important we
wait on that a little later but I mean
yeah let's just assume you know seed
stage companies right really early maybe
just starting to go through the
licensing process at the beginning
founding team just kind of well I mean
in terms of what what what I would look
for in a founding team or like
structures I think I think that's
helpful
okay and then maybe just the proper
vesting at a minimum that you like to
see all right oh got it right yeah one
of the mistakes a lot of people make is
they get a group of four people and they
split up all the equity and then they go
out to the and then like what four
people stays together
for I mean like it's really rare and
really rare and very few people actually
think to do to actually have everybody
vest or to think about what happens if
somebody doesn't work out or if one
person put some more energy than the
other so that's that's super important
and one of the key reasons to be talking
to a lawyer early on as well to have
that so that's one thing to be really
that's probably the biggest thing I'll
leave I'll leave that one ever would I
know you had some stuff to comment on
this when we were talking before this
panel just said no founder equity yeah
so it's myself and three other
co-founders in a meadow there's four of
us we split up equity equally I think
that was important we all vested at the
same time as well we left enough for
investors that were not issued and we
had an option pool I think one thing
that we've done
is you know when we made the decision to
do this you're really getting into
marriage I think I don't know if
someone's gonna leave maybe but you know
we kind of committed that we're gonna do
this thing all the way through and I
think when you you kind of commit to
that you have to be able to think if
you're gonna be with this person how
they complement you how do they make the
product better or the team better we
ended up creating a set of values as
well to pull from and kind of like help
direct the the moral compass of the
company I think that's quite important
and then you know once you formulate
your founding team
it is like marriage you do need to check
in you can't just let them go off and
kind of gallivanting around it's about
checking in we do it every week we have
a founders meeting every week at the
same time if we miss it that dates the
scheduled the next day and that's where
we talk about what's again what's
happening what well what could be better
and bring up any other things that you
know could bubble up if it left too long
unattended one another you another story
I know you had a good story that you
wanted founder mess-ups so when I
started this and I was co-founding with
a you know an attorney who'd been a
mentor of mine so of course you know I
looked up to him and I had trusted him
and had 20 years of practice on me so
when the attorney we used suggested
vesting periods and he convinced me why
we didn't need them you know that was
mistake number one so I had a co-founder
that you know he had maybe five percent
less than me and you know it started
with okay well I'm the older attorney
who knows how to do stuff I'll I'll turn
the need be layaway is hard you try and
eventually I did everything and he did
nothing and then he got a day job that
doubled his day job salary and I was
left with an extremely toxic cap table I
did everything myself and I had a guy
that owned nearly 40% of the company and
I was pretty much done fundable I
eventually was able to raise a
convertible note to buy him out and I I
mean by far and away if all the
negotiations I've done
the entirety of this company it was the
one with this man that led to more
yelling fights screaming matches
painfulness and threats that I've ever I
mean I basically had to threaten at one
point I'll burn it down and build it
again if you don't take this money and
go away I got it done
spare yourself sounds like moral the
story is make sure everybody testing
periods for everyone okay I think we got
it I think to wrap up sort of the whole
formation discussion so we can move into
fine fundraising which I think everybody
is probably really interested about any
big sort of regulatory blockers that you
ran into outside of baking obviously
just when you're starting your company
and and how you worked around that when
we can't came out of YC our product was
really around like an uber for wheat
meadow would really facilitate
deliveries between delivery operators
and consumers and as we started moving
forward in the regulatory process it
wasn't clear to us whether delivery
would survive we advocated for it we
created trade groups around it we you
know fought at a local level to issue
licensing and all that but we had to
make a decision on seeing what license
types would survive and that was an
evolution into retail point of sale and
I think as you look at your business
models the regulations are so important
because any model can be written out or
written in to the regs thankfully we did
get a type 9 license and delivery exist
today unfortunately 67% of the state
didn't have any local laws and it was
prohibited and now we have another set
of regulations as perhaps allowing
statewide delivery and so I think
overall it's if you're not reading the
regs and reading the playbook and
understanding how this is going to come
down the pipeline then you know you may
find yourself in an obsolete business
model come the next session and you know
the way I get around that or help get up
that curve is really surround yourself
with great people
you know obviously joint trade
organizations they they really helped I
mean they advocate but they keep you in
the loop you can't help but go to a
meeting and just start talking about
regs it's what we do it's what we do you
don't like it in the wrong industry but
yeah I think that's really important to
think about in in 2011 I think it was we
had just started me and Steve DeAngelo
went into business for to start ArcView
and he was our first investor and
everything was going great we were high
on this idea of Obama had come out and
said they was gonna allow states to to
to do their own thing and the Attorney
General was in favor everything was
wonderful and then all of a sudden he
changed his mind and had this company
that was bringing investors and
entrepreneurs together and doing all of
this great stuff and all of a sudden in
like mid 2011 nobody wanted to do
business at all like people didn't want
to come to our events anymore
and it was still early enough so there
wasn't enough momentum really to like
kind of be like yeah whatever and like
like what happened a few few months ago
but it was so small at that time that it
really did cut it off and so believe it
or not I wound up we had no money but I
was so committed to it that I kept at it
and had to decide whether I wanted a
social life or a home and I decided a
social life and I lived in my car and in
friends couches for about six or seven
months during that time so that was one
regulatory hurdle we ran into and found
our way through thank you those are some
really good insights so one actually
last topic before we move into fundraise
is that a joint yes I've never been on a
panel with a joint this is a shortage
this is amazing
imagine I'm excited any Lea's left-hand
side so I go first it's all about
community at the end of the day it's not
I am NOT gonna be stoned while I'm on
this I don't want it to be like a bad
after-school special I'm good it's a
banana breath from a Humboldt farm
called Debbie that's result this is
Davey's friend's farm right yeah yeah
nice thanks Davey so I've actually never
I've never been high while on a panel
ever before well then maybe I should try
and eat right now now we're not not with
a bunch of lawyers you kidding me I'm a
lawyer and I did it so I think that kind
of all right let's move on to better
things like fundraising all right all
right so I figured we would start with
three series eight companies so maybe
you know you've gone you form your
company founding teams together maybe
done your first key hires issued some
equity and maybe you've gone through a
licensing process or you're in the
middle of a licensing process what what
does that order of operations look like
in terms of I shouldn't say order of
operations but what would be the the
preferred financing vehicle that you
guys generally see for seed stage
companies I know we get founders that
come in the door and like oh I want to
do a price round because it's so much
cleaner on my cap table but you know
sometimes the only raising like 500k and
transaction costs might not be worth it
it's really hard to value a company in
those early days is very very hard to do
it so that's why we see a lot of
convertible notes and safes in in those
areas and then also you know for if
you're pre-license and this really
depends on the state a little different
in California but if there's a chance
you're not going to get your license
it's really hard to raise money
that's that's changed a little bit with
what's happening in the in Canada with
the with the markets going crazy cuz now
with the way that they're buying these
these companies up there are now
investors who are like alright I'll take
I'll take a swing on on the chance of
getting a license in ways that they
haven't before because of that arbitrage
opportunity there but yeah that's what I
would say unless that's how no III
completely agree and I know you know I'm
and I know you've done convertible notes
who saves convertible notes from from
your perspective of your seed stage
company I mean even if you're raising a
few million dollars does it really make
sense to a price around at that point or
from simplicity as like a founder would
would you prefer to it depends I mean
can I give him more lawyerly answer but
I mean we're I mean it depends on who
you are and what your appetite is for
certain things like I had done
convertible debt and I converted that
and were pretty close to closing our
Series A and we did price it I didn't
want to operate with debt but there's a
lot of benefits to operating with debt
and and simultaneously ended up taking
on a I was swor going into it that I was
gonna not take any debt in this round
but I ended up taking a line of credit
to I was like okay so there's so many
pros and cons to it it's really just
depends on you as a company and what
you're trying to accomplish in your
appetite for different things yeah I'm a
huge fan of the safe you know not gonna
lie I think it really helps bring down
the cost of compliance but bring down
the cost of getting a lawyer to review
documents it standardizes everything for
everybody right no investors trying to
put their stake in the ground and saying
giving you specific terms and dictating
what you need to do or anything like
that we raised over two and a half
million dollars on safes we have over 40
different investors we didn't have a
discount but you could provide a
discount basically people that get in
early he can be discount on the round
you can price it pricing it as
evaluation which Troy's talking about
that's a little bit more of a dance but
in the early days it's more art than
science so make sure your narrative is
very compelling if you need more
information about creating a compelling
narrative Justin Kahn of founder of
atrium has a great blog post on it it is
what sells the dream and it what is what
sells
you know the investors in to get it one
thing though to be cognizant of on safes
you can do a Most Favoured Nation so
early people there is no valuation
whatever valuation comes down the pipe
that's the first one that they get
whichever best terms so you could do
that as well
and then I think you know you can go
pretty long on safes but you have to be
very cognizant on dilution and what
happens when that equity when that safe
converts to equity and why be mean by
that is you have an assistant pool of
equity that you sold in in that note and
that safe and when your equity converts
that whole piece shifts into the cap
table and the percentage is that you
thought you owned get diluted down
because now people are getting the
equity that they have paid you know for
via that safe model and if you're not
careful you can over sell your company
on safes and an equity conversion comes
and everyone looks around and doesn't
have as much as they owned before and it
can get pretty demoralizing and so quick
primer then for those who don't know the
difference between is safe and a
convertible note a safe is on its on his
face is very similar to a convertible
note but the really the big difference
is safes don't have interest or maturity
date and there are a little bit more
bare bones on you know some more low
early jargon terms but yeah so I think
it's super quick you can get money
quickly money fast I guess all right
well one thing that they were talking
about is dilutions and company
valuations I know some pitch book data
came out I don't I don't know people
sort of follow pitch book but Troy and I
were actually talking about this before
the panel and
and so the average pre-money valuation
of a tech company was around I believe
eight million pre-money and then average
you know size of a seed round was about
two million so then that brings us your
post money roughly to about ten million
so in the cannabis space are we seeing
something similar I know you mentioned
there's a difference between it founders
think you know it's a premium versus a
discount and you know let's hear more I
think that we're not seeing that at
least with at least with you know you
might see that with limited licenses and
stuff and some of the some of the states
are if you know you're in a town where
that only has a few licenses or
something like that then you can start
to see really high valuations early on
but for everybody else and everything
I've seen coming through we are not
seeing eight million dollar pre-money
seed rounds even even as things have
started to go up I mean this is just a
much more nascent industry and then
there's the big question as to whether
or not cannabis gets a premium or
whether it gets a discount if you're an
entrepreneur it definitely has a premium
right definitely
right this is the hottest industry in
the world it's growing at 27% compound
annual growth rate look at it 66% public
support this stuff is changing get on
the bandwagon we're gonna win right now
if you're an investor if you're an
investor it's really it's it's it's
often the other perspective where people
are saying well this is you know this is
the the the funding ecosystem isn't
there you know we don't we don't we're
not seeing the the funding ecosystem
fill its fill itself out who's gonna be
the the next round of funding on this
what are all the risks of the regulatory
risks I mean a regulator wakes up one
day and decides you know they're not
gonna allow delivery what happens these
are kinds we they can point to thousands
of examples all across the country of
examples where entire businesses were
wiped out from a regulatory change
including ancillary businesses and so
there's a lot of pressure from investors
to say look there's a lot of ways to
make money
and so if I'm coming into the cannabis
sector do I want to pay a premium or or
a or a discount because of the added
risks associated with that I do think
that that story is changing I think
we're seeing that change a little bit in
the last few months like literally like
since like you know two three months ago
I think we're starting to see that
narrative change and I think there are
more investors willing to pay a premium
but the the bar for how good a company
needs to be in order to get that and
what their path needs to be is changed
as well because if you go back six
months or even a year there are very few
people who would say that they thought
federal prohibition was gonna end in the
next two years very few people now there
is almost a consensus starting to brew
that by 2020 we will see very very
meaningful federal reform that will in
effect be legalization and that has
changed the trajectory of most companies
in terms of what your path is in a in a
world where where all the big dogs are
here and every major company that has a
solution is gonna want to be in the
space are you a builder you'll buy there
they're gonna they're gonna they're
gonna they just gonna build it
themselves or they gonna buy you and are
you gonna be far enough along when that
happens in order for you to be in the
mix for that buyout
or if to be able to compete with them
etc so the whole calculus has really
changed in the last three to four months
and we're starting to see some of that
premium in conjunction with that so and
I think that's that's great I think one
other question I want to get to you
before we wrap up that I think there's a
lot of first-time founders here is just
you're in the cannabis space a lot of
the best pool is obviously seemingly
smaller one how do you identify
investors how do you approach them you
talk to them in sort of what's that
order of operations to getting that
first term sheet or dollar in the door
it's friends and family money or more
formal you know feces that are active in
the space it wants to take this one
first we were fortunate to go through Y
Combinator and so we pitched at demo day
and we got introduced to 600 investors
but before that my first pictures at
ArcView and props to to ArcView for
setting that up which ended up we didn't
raise money there this is Vegas 2014 and
but I got introduced to my mentors Emily
from Emily Morgan for poseidon asset
management who eventually invested later
but I think it was really about putting
yourself out there and meeting different
people being present not just like lobby
conning you can't just go to every
conference like got to build your
business what you don't blog econ like
don't buy a ticket to the event just
hang out the lobby everyone else we're
outside in the smoke circle just bring
some good if I see you outside work for
you but don't spend your precious
diamond oh there are ways the hack
that's you but anyway so that's one area
you go you speak with people you know
people like Justin over there that just
came he's looking at invest in you
should hit him up I'm not sure why he's
investing in but I know he's an investor
and then the other area is looking
online AngelList
is a really good area of seeing who's
invested in other companies CrunchBase
is also pretty good most of the time
you're gonna get funds but if you drill
down you can see kind of who's
participated or what other deals they've
participated in you can you can really
see the whole history of what someone's
doing and then you have the idea
syndicates so if you have like the
ability of getting people together they
can form a syndicate invest in you
and now all the crowdfunding so you
could do you know something on seed
invest or we funder I'm not sure if
they're doing cannabis so republic o
some of these platforms that allow you
to have your friends and family your
neighbors all put in money too but you
need to have
of the narrative the narrative super
important and you need to have a big
dream especially you're doing like VC
money if you're doing VC money you have
to understand that their economics is a
hit out of the Grand Slam ballpark you
know they want big returns if you're
pitching angels if you're pitching
smaller funds they may not have those
high aspirational value targets and
that's why it's as you're researching
the investor you want to research the
sector that they're investing in the
stage that they're investing in and
their typical cheque sizes and as you
have more of these conversations you can
start layer in your pipeline and do the
dance because raising money is a dance
it's like your spot shows birds and the
peacocking thing like one dances over
here and one dances over there it's
totally like that you need to reject
confidence and the ability of executing
on your vision but you need to also be
humble enough to understand that they
could help you you know move forward and
have enough friends that you pitched
along the way so that your narrative and
the way you explain it and the questions
that come up you're ready to just spit
off of everything you should know
everything if you don't you're going to
get back to them and you do and I'll
just add everywhere you go it's
networking be it the conference be it on
the stage of ArcView you never know when
those people are going to come back in
and around of your life and I flat out
I've been told no many times and it's it
I just say no for now that's K okay
sucks in a bit but big fun we just
closed was a flat no in May and now
they're big yes so one thing to know is
that keep them updated on your progress
and keep them updated when new things
come about because somebody who's in
know today or know in may might be a yes
in December and you know a lot of people
are going to be a no forever but
continue to meet new people and come
back around to the ones that weren't
interested with those who are interested
because let's be frank cumin or
or definitely you know bandwagon in
general and so once somebody takes
interest that they respect they might
start to take interest too and so be
cognizant wherever you are you never
know it might be on the chairlift in
Aspen and it could be you'd be amazed
where you'll meet your investors and
I've definitely you know one of our
investors we met on your small event in
New York when you're doing the local
town one so it can be anywhere talk to
everyone in anyone thanks you want to
finish this up sure sure well I think
with raising money for cannabis
companies there's a bit of a signal
verse verse noise issue which is that
everybody wants to talk about weed
everybody it seems you know if you're
talking to somebody like everybody will
take a meeting but being able to figure
out who will actually write a check is
another project altogether and for
people who've raised money in other for
other businesses it's like you know
we're just getting somebody to like take
a look at your whatever right is like
hard to do and then this everybody will
take a look at it and then and then when
you're when you're with investors that
are specific to cannabis one of the
biggest mistakes I see people do that
you know somebody who's a dedicated
cannabis investor they've made plenty of
bets in the cannabis sector and then
they're looking at you and then the
first thing that entrepreneurs will do
will start going through the growth
charts of like how the markets gonna
gonna grow and all this kind of stuff
it's like don't waste your time on they
already in they're already in talk about
your solution talk about your team talk
about you know so you got an arc your
your perspective differently but I think
that a lot of people put a lot of
attention into their pitch and of course
at ArcView that's the whole idea right
it's a pigeon so people put so much
attention into their pitch and the pitch
is a very small piece of the puzzle it's
it is important but it's also about
follow up follow up follow up because
life starts
and people see lots of things that they
like you gotta figure out how to keep
people interested over the long haul and
that means you got to develop a
relationship so many I see a lot of
entrepreneurs that are just sort of like
constantly pitching like they oh you're
an investor oh let me tell you about
mother you know like and it's just like
whoa whoa whoa whoa human I mean hello
okay like and I one thing I always want
to remind people is that this is a peer
it's a it is a peer-to-peer relationship
and some entrepreneurs go out there and
it's like it's like a scene out of like
Oliver they're like you know and then
and then and then and then some
investors are like the opposite they're
like walking or like you know like like
got their suspenders and like you know
they're like they look down on on on
folks or like pepper them with like
really big questions or whatever and
then are sitting back kind of like oh
they have all the cards that's not how
it is it's just not how it is any deal
that happens is gonna happen because
there's an even trade because that
investor needs you that investor needs
and and a company that they can get
behind that can help make them money and
also in a lot of cases is more than
money it's about making it's about them
feeling like they're having an impact
and a bunch of other things that come
with why somebody backs particularly a
seed or early-stage company often has to
do with a lot more than the tangibles of
money a lot of intangibles and so
realizing that this is a peer
relationship and how would you speak to
appear that you wanted to build a
long-term relationship with you would
act in a way that was confident and
assertive and would you would ask
questions you would ask questions of
them what are you into what do you what
do you do what do you do besides
investing in cannabis right I mean
there's a whole host of other things
because when you work with an investor
it's a long-term
thing it's not just about getting that
investment it's about building and being
able to enlist their support over time
as well so that's what I would say about
that thank you
I think we are out of time in terms of
additional questions but are there any
questions from the crowd that we didn't
answer take 5 minutes or so the question
was which bank which bank actually I say
don't even know at this point my CFO
handles it my banks in Colorado there
called Alpine but they don't touch plant
touching so only ancillary in everything
I've been able to get at least a half a
dozen ancillary providers in there but
you also have to you can't just go in
and say I hear you do this you got to
find so many banks there to make
introductions relationships are key but
it's also a Colorado bank so not quite
as relevant here we're a Colorado
company yeah we're ancillary to so it's
it's a different
silent partners investors what what's
your analysis on taking on people for
operating agreements and licensing
agreements so it's not it's not like
white labeling but you know you're
having a management firm or real estate
firm and then the second thing would be
how exactly does it benefit a company by
dividing your different operating
agreements since a different cup your
different operating arms is different
companies how does that how do you how
do you gain advantage through the tax
system exactly everybody's looking at me
but I don't I don't have an answer to
any of that I have that's what I have
lawyers for are you asking specifics of
280e
issues right now yeah and then also
there's there's there's that and then
there's also there's the tax piece but
then there's also the question about the
licensing and the creating operating
agreements I think this is called the
time when when you really want to go
call a lawyer and ask them these kinds
of questions yeah that's right first
ones free one thing though to keep it
cognizant about the white label in the
licensing in the regs 5032 and the
proposed regs that now are now post
commented updated oal regs in the gray
zone there is regulation that doesn't
allow non licensed entities to work with
licensed entities to do white labeling
so if that's kind of the the route that
you want to go it may or may not exist
in 30 days yeah just wait don't hurt
your brain regard so I was just
questioningly talking to Jeff Jones in
class about the Delaware account so I'm
actually interested in probably
cooperating but why didn't you or how
did he go with the Delaware account with
you as far as it being an LLC C and like
how can I protect myself best in that
process
yeah so the the software side of the
business which is my side in our
household is Delaware's C Corp
traditional pretty much you know how you
would see it and most my wife is a
California C Corp you know one thing
that you you want to do I mean I guess
it's like how you divvy up your equity
right like if you're granting it all to
yourself you should fill out an IAT 3 B
or 83 B that allows you to if you do
sell and not to pay that much taxes on
it and I guess like it really depends on
your business and like how your business
partners are and how you're structuring
it but if you're trying to go for
investment and you're trying to get
founders and you're trying to get equity
and ability of to do advisory shares um
the C Corp I don't know many other
groups are doing it but see yeah I mean
also yeah from from a liability
perspective LLC versus C Corp is in
theory gonna you know provide for I do
the the shelter from personal liability
just on a you know just an operating
standpoint like if you know you got sued
for running your business but if we're
talking on a cannabis level it's a
little bit different because you know
cannabis is not legal in Delaware so you
know you can't form like a Delaware
corporation to apply for your for
example cultivation permit in California
so in that instance you need to be
looking at alternative structures and
generally what you know we have our
clients dues they're either gonna see we
do have some where they will have the
form a Delaware company that's a holding
company for another company that is
formed in California to apply for the
license and so for example you'll take
your investments through the holding
company level but you're actually
operate your cannabis business in this
subsidiary feel free to reach out and we
can provide you a little further
resources that you can read up on this
so my question is regarding fundraising
did you ever tap into other communities
that you belong in
it's being a cannabis entrepreneur so
you know for me I'm a queer woman of
color and so I'm trying to tap into
networks where they're trying to support
you know entrepreneurs in that kind of
community and if you did you know what
were some of those I definitely you know
when I first did art you actually I
honestly hadn't had much experience
pitching and thankfully my pitch is much
better now but I when I first moved here
to San Francisco I tried to find all the
interesting pitch events and one of the
best ones I went to was a female
founders pitching female funders and it
was it was super valuable thankfully I
mean helps to win so I have lots of nice
things to say but honestly those were
funds that were very conventional VC
funds not canvas focused and our tech is
gonna scale outside a cannabis but today
we make all our revenue in cannabis so
that definitely is limiting but it was
great because I got relationships out of
that with urban innovation fund and
Bessemer and they both check in on me
quite regularly and so they might not be
our investor today but I've got I knew I
was gonna run up against an issue with
the rest of our financing based on
something our leader had put in there
that I couldn't really fight him on and
so I was able to call them and say hey
how do you suggest I frame this when I
go to do the next part in and they both
answered me and maybe we'll use them
down line but I really the female events
are good if nothing more for mentorship
and the introductions that come through
that yeah I would also say that I'm
looking at like you know college you
know alma mater is all alumni networks
these sorts of things especially because
cannabis is exciting you know for a lot
of people I think there's a lot of
circles that you can kind of tap into
and there's a certain novelty factor
about this that people be like oh yeah
let's let's check that out
and then I know through through our few
about a year ago now we started the
women's investor network within our
command mentorship and camaraderie
within the group
where we have a lot of women investors
who are specifically interested in
backing women founders so that's
something that's been been happening a
lot as well
someone encouraged that the common
wisdom is that when times become hard
people tend to gravitate a little more
towards their vices a lot of people
think that a recession is on the way
curious to hear your opinion on whether
you think that a current entrepreneur in
the space looking to raise say a series
a should maybe try to accelerate their
fundraising process in anticipation of
an coming recession or if you kind of
think that even with the oncoming
recession there won't be a tightening of
the capital markets in this space yeah
money money is very finicky right get it
one you can't is a good good motto right
I mean not too much don't raise too much
but but usually what I find is is is
invest is companies raise too late and
not enough right it's usually not the
other way around
so I would say that the other thing I
would say is that when the economy goes
down it's not good for us because it
means people have less money they're a
little more protective but it's also in
a lot of ways we're a little bit
recession proof too because if if other
things are going down this becomes one
of the few places where you see the CAG
or the compound annual growth rates
still being really strong I don't think
it has too much to do with people
clinging to their vices I mean this that
that particular thing I think is maybe
after everything's legal everywhere and
you've got a something going on like
that that it would have that but the the
the factor of new states legalizing is a
far more of a push from from that from
that side of things so that would be on
saying yeah I just wanted to answer
Nancy's question who I have it
investors are everywhere they have
different meetings and groups to
there's a lot conferences I chose to go
in my startup community so a launch
festival is something that you know
we've been a part of that we've gone to
runway was another group in the cannabis
space that had something you know
lesbians who tech there's a whole nother
group in there usually investors are
going to those spaces and trying to
figure out who to invest in so jump
around you can meet new people
everywhere and this space is interesting
enough that a lot of people may may
consider it as far as the recession
question I think it's a founder this
feels very like dot-com II but also like
you know 2008-2009 when he had a little
bit it's not like that dire so I don't
see that happening but I do think when
you feel recession coming in then as a
founder you have three ways to really
sort of bulletproof it one sure you can
go raise money but more importantly like
cut your costs figure out where yours
not don't need to be spending money and
then figure out how to make some money
right sometimes the best cure of four
founders not to go pitch twenty people
is to go sell or pitch twenty potential
partners that way it gives you traction
it gives you you know money the bank
gives you product feedback to see if
you're resonating and if your pitch is
resonating you don't want to be in a
situation where you need to raise
because like investors you can smell it
they just smell it and they know you
need it and if you do that you lose a
little bit of leverage and you're
negotiating but if you're like I don't
need you I got my business we're running
you know we're strong team we've cut our
costs and we'll be profitable later you
know I think the the biggest thing that
we've learned is it's not about the
first one out of the gate it's one of
the last you won't be one of the last
ones standing and by making sure you
constantly have a runway right whether
it's three months six months ideally 12
to 24 I think that gives you enough
longevity in this thing to ride out the
three six-month interim waves
then you you're gonna be there but if
you ramp up costs if you ramp up hiring
and you know you're not going to be able
to hit your growth targets then you're
gonna be in a situation that just is a
downward spiral I think that was a very
good note to end on
[Music]