I'd like everyone to meet the mayor of
Avalon she's got a
question and first of all you know you
can all come to Catalina free on your
birthday on Catalina Express right here
at along Long Beach so come join
us I some of you might have heard me
yday we're on Avalon we have all the we
all have the coast guard regulations the
federal regulations that keep
transportation of cannabis to Catalina
against the law so going forward we're
really going to have to look at
cultivation local
locally um however my first question is
because 89% of our island is in a
Conservancy so they're concerned about
keeping everything indigenous and
natural even though there is some Loco
weed that does grow somewhere on the
island but question is when you grow
outdoors does it move with the wind and
could it go elsewhere and grow elsewhere
or is it because there's no seeds or
however you do it that's not a problem
that's my first
question Kyle this yeah um cannabis uh
pollen of any variety has been known to
cross oceans okay so uh yeah but uh
luckily there's something called the
species barrier so uh cannabis pollen
can't enter species with any of their
conserved plants or natural plants that
they're worried about so unless they're
unless they're cultivating cannabis out
there I don't think they have anything
to worry about okay so then my question
would
be so now it appear and maybe this is
something to talk individually about so
now truly we're going to need to
cultivate test and process and
everything right there on the island
because you can't take it back and forth
even to testing agencies so I guess the
question would be to someone what would
be a model and how much because the city
of avalin owns no land it's only owned
by a couple of different people there
one being the conservative with 89 and
one being the Wrigley family so I guess
the question is how could
we what kind of space and what are we
looking at to set up something that we
have 4200 people and a million visitors
a year so I'm wondering how we do the
calculation to figure out what our needs
would be and how
we get through this that's a lot of
metrics to go
through but um but you know what I would
suggest is is that you get your city
council to open to be extremely open to
the commercialization of cannabis um
because there's going to be a a lot of
tax revenue coming in um and B then
there's also the per personal the
benefits that you can reap in your own
Community by allowing these businesses
to set up so uh it's probably worth
forming a committee it's not that
complicated I mean you're not going to
it's like uh like the solar grid you
know you're going to grow too much weed
you can probably find someplace else to
pump it into um I would I would just
seriously suggest that the council
seriously embrace the commercialization
well well I guess my question will be
then though if some of you are out there
and can help figure out what this little
design would be that would be helpful
because because we don't have the
expertise locally of course yeah no I
would say you know if you have the data
on population you know you have the
demographics of the tourist you can make
some pretty good assumptions and guesses
what the production level would probably
be and then you could design around that
well one of the problems that they have
is there's no space so they need a
solution that they can grow as much as
possible in a tiny little space yeah I
definitely don't see like a 10 story
building being built nowal on to
cultivate but no that would be really
cool there you go a nice 10 20 story
building built out just for cultivation
I'm down with that you're down call me
what's up guys my name is Nick with
booms farm so I do living soil and
genetic consultation we've talked before
one of the topics is IPM integrated Pest
Management what's your view on crop
rotation versus the monoculture model
which is like corn and other food
production crop because I see cannabis
going that direction we do 350 acres in
Colorado and it's kind of we do okay
organically but it's becoming
increasingly hard for clients that are
having they can't use chemicals no
pesticides so now it's all biological
controls so I want to see what your
thoughts are on
that um I think tissue culture is a good
answer to maybe uh spraying nasty
fungicides and I I know you biological
controls only go so far but I I think
you know as we advance the tissue
culture and if if if there if it becomes
cost effective enough and we could put
out a really sterile crop every Harvest
uh or a sterile set of genetics from a
lab that then has you know a limited
exposure uh I I think that would be a
good start I think it's a tough tough
question to answer in general
though the thing is we are working with
genetic that was born in a desertic
place and on top of it most of the
cultiva that are used here come from the
from the Kush country like it's arid
montain so it's a plant that here
receive a
lot more water that is necessary and too
much food so that plant not only she has
problem to acclimate but you're pushing
her limit and then she become weak there
I have never seen PM or all the problem
you have here in any producing
country and those plant goes through
really harsher much much harsher
condition than here
so I think the solution would be to try
to step back a little bit and try to
work around the cultiv around the the
genetic more
than trying to adapt that genetic too
fast to to what we want her to
do yeah I agree I absolutely agree it's
you you have to uh realize that what
we're we're trying to make this plant
jump through hoops and basically because
of
prohibition you know so you know if you
weren't risking going to jail for 10
years you wouldn't be worrying about
getting as many grams per square inch as
you possibly could um so like frie if we
step back and we forget that we're not
looking for those helicopters overhead
anymore you know then we can focus a
little more on the language of the plant
and just uh accommodate her a little bit
yes hi guys you all know me uh just a
couple comments on on uh some of the
things that was said uh one was about
the LEDs and the
LEDs they have their place in growing
marijuana but growing flowers is a
little bit difficult with them they have
the same problem that fluorescents have
and that is that they're linear so they
don't have the penetration that a point
source of light has so you just don't
have the the depth of canopy that you do
with your uh hpss or whatever I was
going to say that David earlier I didn't
think that they can they I don't I don't
think they can create a high-intensity
LED simply because of the way it's made
it would be too damn hot they would burn
up right but on the other hand I've
grown with LEDs but I've used them uh to
produce small uh quite small uh seed
crops in a closet uh one of the benefits
of course they don't produce the heat
because they're more efficient you know
making light rather than Heat the other
thing is
that and this is something that
particularly grates me there is no such
thing as kaix to Lea racio all right
there is none it's bra to Leaf ratio CU
nobody in this room has ever seen a
female cix because it doesn't exist
official Smackdown by B Frank accepted
all right just to explain this very
quickly if you take a seed you'll notice
that it has spots usually or something
sort of camouflage on it if you look
really closely you'll notice that that's
contained in a translucent Veil that
covers about 60 to 90% of the seed and
you can rub those spots right off the
seed uh well within that Veil there are
presumptive cells that would become a
kaix if it ever evolved in cannabis
there are also cells that would produce
a the Corolla if it evolved now the
Corolla for you that don't know are like
the Fancy Petals you see on flowers you
would buy uh the KX would be the little
brown cup that's holding those uh those
uh petals uh well those evolve to
attract pollinators animals insects that
sort of thing cannabis is wind
pollinated it never had an incentive for
those cells to develop into anything and
so they remain just a few cells within
uh this thin veil and this Kix to to
Leaf de KX ratio has bugged me for so
long I can't tell you because it's so
much apart I am so glad I gave you an
opportunity to speak out the other one
is that they call the two hairs that
stick up that are the pollen catches
they call them pistols and those are
Stig SAS there's only one pistol per
flower and the pistol is the entire uh
sexual organ of the plant which is just
those two stigmas and little oval inside
that will become a seed of his poed
that's all I have to say than
question away from the speaker that was
an amazing educational moment
there so if we're looking at the future
of cultivation can we just talk a little
bit more about uh energy use because it
is not a very green um situation Oregon
right now has a new standard coming up
called clean green it's their
alternative to organic because frankly
if you have a bunch of pesticide
regulations well if you use organic soil
you'll be triggering those um pretty
pretty regularly so in California
specifically and indoor specifically
even more the energy grid
wow yeah I go I just just I once heard I
once heard that uh 2% of all the
electricity generated in California goes
to cannabis
production so I don't know if that's low
or high or if it's even correct I I I
just I'm qualifying that I
just we've got we've we've got Betty ye
in the audience do you know the number
no okay Rec stud that came out 2014 %
of% of all United
States okay so now I can't have
hamburgers because of cow farts and I
can't smoke my marijuana because it's
coal no I'm just you know I I'm using
humor it's it's a it's a very valid
point and we have to become cleaner if
not through
LEDs
um I mean I can't solve the energy
crisis I don't have any great ideas Mel
Frank do you have any great ideas about
the energy
crisis well come on up
here you know I okay I've listened to uh
uh some of the PBS on uh prop 64 and one
you get people there who have one aspect
of of growing like one of the issues is
the amount of electricity that's being
used and I've seen two studies one was
1% one was 3% but in any event they're
looking at this the wrong way because
they're looking at it as it exists now
with all these underground hidden indor
grows and there are not going to be that
many of them all right they're going to
start to disappear because people can
come out and natural light so they're
using the the the wrong uh data to try
to project at what it's going to be it's
going to be much less than than they
think it really is
yes very
good all how you doing uh question
relating to LEDs what do you guys think
of
lec's I I don't have much experience
with lec's yet so I can't really comment
on LEC I don't even know what it is can
somebody please educate me
it's like a Ceramics oh okay I didn't
know they were called lec's I just knew
they were called Ceramics yeah yeah I I
we have we've done actually Mel has done
some testing with LC's recently I think
he could probably comment on it but me
personally no I don't have any data on
the lec's versus MHS or
LEDs I don't either other than just some
anecdotal from people who have told me
that it Veges really well but it doesn't
flower very well
time really no I I the for people who
don't know they're called ceramic bulbs
and uh they're generally right now
generating are using 3155 Watts the par
value out of there in other words the
usable light by the plant is is very
high uh in fact I've seen one of these
315 not one actually I've seen many of
them but one single 3155 watt light over
a 4x8 standard tray uh be ble to veg out
the entire tray which was amazing
because when you would look at both ends
of that tray they seem appear to be
almost in the dark and yet we got great
growth across the entire thing so I
think now the ones that people who were
selling them are talking about having
six of these per 4x8 tray and of course
you would have amazing growth but just
from what I've seen so far and I haven't
done it with full flowering yet is I
think three or four which would cut your
electrical use from standard uh uh HPS
is where you would use two 1,000 wat for
a 4x8 tray uh by almost a half and these
are also some of the things that going
to change the amount of electricity
that's used as more efficient ways of
using the energy that that you need to
grow these plants and the ceramic bulbs
I think are one of
those any other
questions no we're good okay thank you
so much you guys really appreciate it
thank you everybody thanks suan for a
great event