[Music]
we're talking about the future of
cannabis cultivation my name is Alex
Campbell I'm going to be the moderator
today and I'm going to start by
introducing our panel uh KY kushman who
is a multiple uh Cup winner and
specializes in Banning
oranic or cultivation Frenchie canoli
who is a legend in the hash
game and he was going to talk about
something very near and dear to my heart
but we'll get to that in a second and
David Holmes clay n who has overseen
several cultivation facilities in Nevada
in Arizona and also here in California
and I'm going to start with my thoughts
on the future of of canvas cultivation
and then we'll turn it over to Kyle
first to talk about his background what
he thinks I say the future of cannabis
cultivation the price is going down per
pound on a wholesale level that's the
only organizing principle I would
operate from but Kyle take it away sure
that's all sure that's all you want to
say it's going to go down that's a fair
bet but that's a good thing uh because
cannabis is medicine and even beyond
that it's the safest Recreation
intoxicant known to man and it should be
cheap and available for anybody who
wants to use it um the future of
cannabis cultivation it's really awesome
to be able to talk about that topic just
think about that we're not we're not
thinking about the past or how we're
going to get there we're actually you
know it's kind of like this boat we're
not going anywhere we've already arrived
you know and um we're it's really it
really feels really good I'm not saying
that uh any fight is over and if you
guys were lucky enough to listen to
Ethan nlman yesterday he gave an amazing
a really really inspiring speech and you
know the legalization of cannabis isn't
just about any one thing it's not just
about being able to get high or being
able to cure your illness it's not just
about the
economy you know and when we do legalize
cannabis hopefully we'll continue to
fight for the people who are in jail for
having a tiny little bit of cocaine or a
tiny little bit of any intoxicating
substance that they decided to use and
not lose their freedoms and tie them up
in jail forever so
um the future of cannabis is is is
freaking bright man it's it's a hybrid
of everything it's a hybrid of indoor
and outdoor and um uh um uh light
deprivation using all seasons and um you
know it's a big wide open uh space for
entrepreneurial uh enterprising people
young and old who have a passion um for
this plant or for for the
industry but you think the price is
going
down you answer the
question because I can't I keep losing
these Consulting gigs because I start
with that I'm like price is going down
and they don't hire me I don't get
it yeah it the the the price is going to
go down for a lot of reasons it's going
to go down because of the supply it's
going to go down because better
practices it's going to go down because
it should go down because people
shouldn't have to pay $25 for a gram of
marijuana that's smoked up in a joint
here
[Applause]
here and with that let's move on to
Frenchie
canoli and you don't have to answer my
question oh actually but I want to talk
to you about
Terr uh but it's all go together
basically it's not a question of price
it's for the moment you are facing a
choice every producing country in the
world produce
quantity and not quality you could be
the first
ever producing country producing only
quality and I'm not talking on only
about us small small farmers I'm talking
about the wall industry in California
it's a huge choice that you have in
front of you it's a huge Edge on the
market so before thinking that price are
going to go down yeah price are going to
go down if you don't produce quality but
price are not going to go down if you
produce quality because the world is
open very soon to a World Market if if
legalization happen here in California
and in a few other states there is
country like Morocco there is many
country around the world that produce
vast quantity of cannabis derivative
that won't absolutely to be legal too so
it's like it's not only a choice that
you make in this small Market of
California and and the US it's a a world
choice that you're making like the wine
industry did in the 18th century after
13,000 years of mass production black
market and any things you could add to
the wine to make it his lifetime longer
they decided to go to Quality to Quality
because they had no choice they were
facing
competition and in a history book you
have literally a blueprint how to not
only protect your farmer but that their
land is so valuable because it's not the
price of the land anymore it's what the
LA produce something so unique that it's
a brand worldwide and that's called an
appellation controller you have
everything every part here in many
different places of California where
there is everything to create what the
wine industry
created 60 years ago so it's your choice
it's like do you want to make a lot of
money short time and to be just one of
the other Mass producing cannabis
country in the world or do you want to
be the reference to the world of
cannabis in the future like the the wine
IND the street looking at Bordeaux and
France so I I think I lost my mic lost
hello I figured out the answer to your
question it is that price is going to
both go up and go
down and Frenchie is
extremely smart in this area and to
expand on his thought what's going to
happen is is that cheap grade marijuana
is going to get cheaper and high-grade
marijuana is going to become more valued
so that's what came to me by listening
to French
I'll respond to that after we let David
talk check okay you guys can hear
me U Can you guys hear me pretty good
all right so you know I was thinking
about the future of cannabis cultivation
and I realized it was a difficult
question to answer how it's going to
turn out so I decided to think about all
the different cultivation types that
currently exist and the products that
they currently create and how maybe
those products would evolve and those
types of cultivation would evolve with
the types of uh canvas they produce so
I'm just going to do it a little more
analytically and kind of my style um so
if we start at you know the top indoor
cultivation currently indoor cultivation
produces in terms of retail value the
highest value flowers and the trim that
comes from indoor currently produces the
highest uh retail value extract I'm not
saying it's necessarily better than
Greenhouse or sungrown but in our retail
Market it produces a higher retail value
the indoor cultivation does uh pretty
much in all of its offshoots uh when you
move down to the greenhouse product the
greenhouse is definitely getting better
and it's becoming a competitor of indoor
and currently the a lot of the
greenhouse flow goes to
um you know the dispensary retail Market
it I think it still has less of a retail
value uh in dispens reason I'm just
talking about my experience in Los
Angeles um but this is what I've
realized and the extract that comes from
the greenhouse is also a competitive
indoor so I think indoor and Greenhouse
are competitors and they're going to be
competing for specific products I think
the sun grown is a
different entity it's a different Beast
altoe and the product it creates is
unique and I think the future of of of
sun grown is probably going to be the
largest segment of the market and I
think as the greenhouse and indoor uh
compete with each other that connoisseur
Market that you guys are talking about
is going to fight its way out now I'm
not saying there isn't a connoisseur
sungrown Market I think that's a
separate connoisseur Market people that
like indoor or Greenhouse
flow probably aren't going to be the
people that are going to transition to
sunr I think they're separate separate
uh customers but um um in terms of the
evolution as greenhouse and indoor fight
it out and Greenhouse becomes Hightech
and could do a lot of the things that
the indoor flower could do I think that
at some point indoor may lose the battle
because of the cost associated with it
um now there are a couple of things I
think indoor could do to stay in the
game and one is data data collection
data analysis if you look uh at at like
an indoor grow it has so much control
there's tons of variables that you could
analyze you could control I'm talking
the temperature humidity VPD Daily Light
integral dis alled doxygen content of
your nutrient Reservoir um you can look
at the tpin I mean these are all things
you could do in any of the types of
cultivation but in an indoor the type of
control you have gives you an advantage
to go the far the pharmace tical route
which I I I think in any of the classes
the indoor gives you the most control to
to produce a pharmaceutical clean room
type flower that the others can't and I
think that's the only saving grace of
the indoor in the long long run I I
still think it has legs for many years
but anyway yes the price will go down
but okay it's G to that's all that's
what I was really on average it
will um I have a specific question
question I'll start with Kyle I've never
grown indoor with LED lights have you
ever grown with neither have I if any of
you grown with LED
okay does it work because it seems to be
the
future it is a
future uh it is the future because it
save electricity and because LED
industry has not been improved for over
80 years it's so economic nobody wanted
to give some that they could not sell
and resell on a very regular basis it's
not been touched
until like until we came into play and I
I play around with one of the first
really good LED and yeah because you can
pretty much copy and get close to to the
Spectrum you
want and it's all about mimicking as
close as possible the the sun Spectrum
so yeah to a point in the future it's
going to make a lot of difference for
them Indo because it's so cost effective
let me just ask you a follow-up question
about mimicking the sun indoors do you
as part of your cultivation technique do
you also reduce the amount of sunlight
hours as the cycle goes on yes yes I do
so you move from say 18 186 to
177 so forth down until 1014 at the end
yeah don't follow it as as strict as
that you know maybe 20 to 18 to 16 to 12
and then at the end you know maybe the
last two weeks dropping it to 10 or 11
to 10 and then also the amount of light
intensity I think is important because
you know in the if you're trying to
mimic outdoor as the season goes on
October November you're not getting as
much total light so I I like to try to
replicate that as much as possible by
lowering the amount of light intensity
also and then what about about yield
with
LED um you know I have some some
experiments we did build like a like a
400 square foot LED experimental room
and the uh quality is always really good
I I think the only issue with LED in my
opinion was the inconsistency it's hard
to get a really uniform light across the
the canopy with LED and I think that's
really because do you have to put them
really close together you got to put
them yeah you got to put them close
together I mean if there's a way that
they can create a higher intensity
enough LED that you could get that
distance to make a really even light
spread I think there's a big future for
Led but I think there there still is a
big future in uh in you know vegging in
the veg stage and also in cloning and
you know also in supplemental lighting
and Greenhouse potentially so I think
LEDs have a big future in in a lot of
the different cultivation
types you mentioned something about
medical sort of being the in preferred
for indoor which I I can see just on a
personal level if you given the choice
would you rather smoke a joint that's
all sungrown or outdoor or would you
rather smoke a joint that's indoor and
I'll ask each of you that question I'll
start with you
first um you know it that's a that's a
very tough question I've had great great
sungrown uh flower rolled into a joint
um but I would say I'm a little biased
cuz I'm an indoor grower well just a
little so uh currently yeah my favorite
if I were going to put any flour I could
choose it would be my indoor flour into
a joint to smoke it just because of the
cleanliness and and uh the I mean the
cultivation rooms that I run are pretty
much like clean rooms and I I like that
stability you know about it but so let
me just are you growing in Rockwell are
you growing in potting soil and half
Coco you're going rock wol rock see I've
never been able to get good purple out
of rock
wool so got to just crank the temps down
the last yeah I know the temps but that
doesn't always do it I find the light
cycle actually has more to do it than
the temperatures but Frenchie outdoor
indoor take a stand uh outdoor all day
right it's like when when you're dealing
with a living organism that is aware of
his habitat and everything that is there
that
literally control every mobile being in
the air and underground the plant call
every microb underground to break her
food for the food to be available at the
right time she call she call every
insect every Predator she she can do
everything she Rule and that power you
cannot duplicate it you be by becoming
the master in a grow room it's not the
same plant that you're working with
that's why it's very difficult to grow
outdoor a strain that has been breeded
indoor and vice versa in the Thousand
Year if we had more 100 years or so or
200 years
of Prohibition that plant would become
very so away from what we know that it
could become a subsp is like we've been
thinking that sativa and Inda it's like
she's so adaptive but it's another
creation all together there is no way
you can give me what Gan is growing in
his garden that plant that is been
breeded in that Garden is so powerful
it's so unique that the neighbor cannot
do it there is no way you can you can
get that because the plant is exuding
all terpe and all all our life it's
according to her habitat so you're
getting something that is super unique
in itself but we can't literally compare
it's really a question of choice
literally yeah no I I agree the uh the
the the breeding that has been done the
last 10 years for indoor plants makes
them unique you take an indoor OG
outside it's it's a lot more difficult
to grow it so I agree with you yeah well
David you're lucky you went first
because I don't know why or how anyone
would want to contradict anything that
Frenchie just
said so I'm going to use comedy to
deflect my nervousness on my
answer um but I I I I do have a few
opinions on it and um I also prefer to
to smoke indoor flow for the following
reasons um
it has to do with kaix to Leaf ratio now
Frenchie everything Frenchie said I have
to I have to say is is absolutely true
because you're dealing with a
living I'm not going to say sensient but
a you're live you're dealing with a
living organism and no matter how great
a grower you are it's not plugged into
the Earth it's not feeling any of the
magnetic energy vibration from the earth
so it's not and then to go beyond that
it's a completely different animal I
like to say indoor and outdoor weed is a
completely different animal because no
matter how many how much I like to mimic
nature or how much my Mantra or my ethos
is to mimic nature how many times I
change that timer how many times I
change the bulbs and try to blend the
lighting it doesn't matter it's not the
same as what how the plant evolved to
have the sun rise and set every day at a
different time and have the Sun travel
through the sky and
so o to Frenchie
because he he speaks the truth um but I
like smoking indoor flower because of
the kaix to Leaf ratio so outdoor plants
are naturally going to grow more Leaf
because the light intensity is lower the
plant wants to capture more Rays so it
grows more Leaf okay so outdoor bud is
almost always
going to have a low a higher Leaf to Kix
ratio as opposed to indoor not always
absolutely not always almost always okay
but so if you take that outdoor weed and
you clean it properly and you remove all
of the leaf material that I personally
don't want to
smoke now you're talking about something
truly special that you have there when
you're talking about the resin glands
that Frenchie works with okay I'm not
talking about smoking a flower from a
stick that came from a stalk outside
there is a difference between that
flower and the indoor flower but there
is also a profound
difference between the resin glands of
the
two thank you for that I'm
outdoor I mean you I know you guys make
your living on indoor so we'll just
leave it at that and
personally when I smoke a joint and I
it's from Mother Earth it has a I I
don't know I can get more canabo out of
you know I that's just my personal I I
need to say also that you know we're all
a product of our environment you know
and where I come from upstate New York
and there was literally a a proverb in
Upstate New York for The Growers and it
went like this you needed to have five
plants for every one you wanted to keep
when you grew Outdoors you needed one
for mother nature you needed one for the
pl the animals you needed one for the
cops you needed one for the thieves and
then you got to keep the fifth one and I
personally didn't like those odds so I
went indoors there you go product of our
environment you know so I got good at
what I do but I also think I would love
to grow outdoors Under the Sun I would I
I I personally grow in dirt okay because
I don't feel like unless I get dirt
under my nails I'm not farming it's not
farming it's cultivating but it's not
farming so no disrespect at all I'm
just alliterating well I think a big
part of the outdoor versus indoor is
also the marketplace and the largest
Marketplace is Los Angeles and the
dispensaries in Los Angeles they want
well manicured Frosty pretty Buds and
the stuff that comes from outdoor
doesn't always look like that and I
think as consumers get more educated we
might see more outdoor cannabis yeah but
if you think that they are the one who
educ ated the public to the indoor it's
like most people have never smoked
outdoor here you judge a flower on
appearance when the whole experience is
all gustatory I just don't get
it so it's like it's all a question of
Education put some flower on the table
and you don't say anybody what it is and
you have everybody smoke I'd like to see
the result I I would to it's the pallet
you're right it is the pallet but the
average across the board the average
outdoor bud when you just roll it and
smoke it the way is is going to contain
more Leaf matter and that leaf makes it
harsh on the back of the throat so more
people choose the indoor
Bud where for the people who do Harvest
before the Cales are totally formed
because I know personally a bunch of
grower their their outdoor are sold as
Indo in very very high hand dispensaries
and that's all the dispensaries that
I've been keeping the indoor as the
uniqueness of it because that's where
the best market and the best profit are
now we are just starting to talk about
the the sun grown but we are far from it
because most people have not ever smoked
one but if you give them the choice they
would go for on indoor while you don't
have ever choose tested the outdoor so
it's mostly a question of Education the
market you educate the market whichever
way you want when you're the one who run
the show it's like the dispensaries have
been running the show and deciding the
deciding basically quality and standard
and what goes on the menu who should
create the standard it's the grower that
should create the standard the grower
and the lab for the moment we
cannot we cannot really speak of quality
because we do not have quity
standard fair enough thank you I'd like
to move on to another topic really
quickly you guys are three esteemed
Growers and a lot of people in this room
may not grow canas or think you're
getting started in growing cannabis I'd
like each of you if you could give one
piece of advice to beginning grower
starting with David what what if you
could just give one person one piece of
advice about growing cannabis what would
it be um I would say first read a lot of
books make sure that you realize that
it's a very complicated process takes
many many many years of hard work to
master and it's not just like a get-rich
scheme you know you know a lot of people
think getting into the industry I'm
going to grow a lot of pot I'm going to
sell make a lot of money well it's not
that easy um also I would say
um make sure that you you know depending
on where you are I mean we're in
California we're close to you know
hopefully getting over the hump but you
know there's still issues with uh you
know cops kicking indoors it's still
happening in California to this day so
check out your local law and read a lot
those are my two bits of
advice
Kyle
um simply start small
uh because observation is key and um if
you're overwhelmed trying to learn
systems you know how the HVAC works and
you know where you should where the
vents for the uh dehumidifier should be
as opposed to the exhaust for the AC and
if you're trying to learn all these
systems then you're not going to have
time to focus on the plan so if you're
really getting started just start small
and um and like I like to say learn the
language of the plan it's all
observation you look at the plan
and it will tell you whether what you're
doing is a positive or A negative effect
and then you get the confidence and then
you can go bigger and you can
concentrate on learning
more
Frenchie uh me I'm actually not a
grower but I I am like a wine maker I
receive the Bounty of the grower and
what you want is to wait for the peak of
the flowering cycle you want perfect
ripeness that's
my you wait you
don't of
time friend she's absolutely correct the
amount of time that you put in
cultivating those plants how many times
you had to water them how many times you
had to transplant them and prune them
and prop them up and give love to them
and you're going to pull it in a week
early because you're going to be Hasty
or you're going to hang it up and you're
going to dry it really quickly because
you're hasty
absolutely not this man is not going to
appre appreciate working with material
like that trust
me Agreed
100% maybe me for ash maker you really
receive the final expression of the
plant the world magical process of trans
transformation of the bounding of two
molecules that you find in Spade in a
plant kingdom happen in that little
resin head so for me I don't make
quality I receive quality I'm like a
wine maker or a chef I'm depending on my
Farmer to receive that quality that's
why for me to to protect them and to
make people realize how important they
are to to this industry there is no
industry without those people but more
than this here in California you have
something that is called the terar you
wanted to ask me about it that's what I
was going to ask you about next the ter
it's something when if you don't go as
deep as a wine maker the ter it's the
uniqueness and the power of the land the
land is so powerful that
every plant on the planet was born only
in one place and then they adapted to to
other it has so much in it that it
literally give makes the plant the plant
is made from the water it receive from
the ground and the sun of the Ray it's
like it makes everything and here in
many places you have the geology that
make the soil very special you have
microclimat by the Android you have the
genetic that is became heirloom there is
all the all the genetic that is around
the world the land race they were born
in one place and move from that place to
wherever they are now in before becoming
L race they were heirloom a plant that
is adapted to our new habit but didn't
become something
totally adapted to it if I can explain
it like that this is unique there is no
other place in a planet with that type
of
cannabis cultiva potential it's
literally a National Treasure and if we
have something that we really need to do
it's to protect Z pooket Emerald
Triangle verac Cruz semity there is a
bunch of little pocket like this because
if we protect them and we can make the
world understand that there is a
cannabis Tero we can have appellation
control so that nobody in the world can
use a world Mand doino nobody in the
world can use umol like you cannot use
champagne you can use a metodology you
can use Spectrum in your lump that mimic
or or
special climate you can you can make
soil that mimic the soil you will have
but you will never be able to do what we
do and this is this is what what is the
the core foundation of the wine industry
it's a multibillion dollar industry it
started in one little city in front and
in front of you you can do that so it's
not only make making money in the
industry but do you want to become the
bord of the of the Cannabis industry
that the world world has a reference to
you that all standard of quality are
made by our grower and our lab that's
what we want because Beyond making money
it's qualities that will set us apart
it's being the standard of everything
that will really bring
Financial Freedom but for a generation
after generation it's not only for you
today it's for all the generation that
come
and and I and I want to add that um
there is actually a language written
into prop 64 uh called the Appalachia
rule I don't know why it's called that
but that's I believe I'm stating it
right and they're creating um brands for
Sonoma for meno for humbold that uh you
know will not be able to be infringed on
in other parts of the world so that
these communities that have created
these valuable um not Commodities but
um what what's the word I'm looking for
Brands
orual you know these things will be kept
in on in the home front you know and and
so yes on
64 I second that um da David I know that
you U managed several large scale
cultivation projects and I think
something people are afraid of is big
marijuana but I think it's inevitable
given the money that's behind everything
can you talk a little bit about the
future of cannabis cultivation as it
relates to large scale projects and
where where the difficulties are in
large scale projects well you know for
sure the difficulty in the large scale
is to produce the quality uh that you
know a smaller scale cultivator kid
produce and you know personally I I
wouldn't want a 30,000 foot facility you
know to produce quality I I think it's
very difficult to do on that scale um
it's also difficult when you have
investors that don't want you to run
strains out to 90 days or 80 days so I I
I think that you know The Connoisseur
Growers the the cultivators that focus
on really high quality don't have to
worry about those 30,000 foot facilities
producing quality like they
produce as long as they you know do all
the things that they do the the care
they put into the plants um and you know
the things that that uh an investor
wouldn't think about you know they're
thinking B like every large scale
cultivation facility that I've been a
part of has an invest has investors that
has specific bottom line they're trying
to meet and they're not necessarily
going after quality so I would say it's
going to be difficult for them to hit
the quality of the smaller scale right I
think one thing that gets lost in the
Cannabis cultivation future is you can
look at the alcohol industry in terms of
craft beer 10 years ago it was Budweiser
and Miller and now Budweiser and Miller
are buying every Craft brewery they can
I think there's room in the Cannabis
industry for the smaller cultivators who
have who have a better product and maybe
a unique product and and and so I'm
excited about all the different strains
we're hopefully going to get to see when
prop 64
passes Kyle have you have you worked on
any large scale projects
in uh few just recently gotten uh you
know out of the garage and um you know
uh uh the the rental house type
situation into the uh you know warehouse
space and uh fortunate to grow you know
with uh some legal
dispensaries um yeah I have some
definitely have some commercial
experience but what do you think the the
biggest what's the biggest issue for
large scale do you think it's the
quality
issue well I'm about to tackle that and
fortunately um for me I think that it's
all about the people that you hire to
work with you and
um yeah there's a bottom line um but I'm
not concerned with that and uh I'm more
concerned with uh creating jobs for for
people that want to be in the industry
and so I'm going to stay away from
machine trimming and I'm going to bring
in
dozens dozens and dozens of hand
trimmers that I'm going to personally
train on how how to trim and I'm going
to train the trim manager and the trim
manager is going to be responsible for
making sure that that quality level
stays up you know um and you know it's a
it's still in the dream phase a little
bit are you a naked flower guy excuse me
are you a naked flower guy I'm not
exactly sure what you cut all the leaves
off the flowers uh well absolutely for
for sale commercially you want that bud
to look as you just want to smoke the
meat of the flour you want the fet Manan
you want to give a little spread on that
when you're trimming so that the leaf
stem pops out and you take the point of
the scissors and you take every little
Leaf stem out so that when you're done
you have a a bud that has a unique shape
to it because it hasn't been haircut bud
I call it it when they just hold it and
just go up around the sides you just
carefully remove each leaf and you have
to constantly move the scissors in the
buds and it's it's laborious but you
know there are people that do it really
really well I lived in mesino for about
four or five years and I met uh troops
of Housewives who made a really good
living going from from place to place
they they they would come to my house
and I would call them up and I'd let
them know a couple days ahead of time
because as you know when you're getting
ready to trim might be tomorrow might be
the next day you're not exactly sure so
if you really want to do this properly
you got these people waiting they come
over they do their business now
unfortunately there was a high incidence
of carpal tunnel syndrome so we're going
to need a trimmer Union so that we can
get them health
benefits okay all right
can can you tell us a little bit about
the line of of you're creating the
veganics can you talk a little bit about
that because I'm not familiar with it
and I'm not sure sure um vegan Matrix is
a veganic plant nutrient line that's uh
complete you don't have to buy I've been
growing with solely vegan Matrix
products and uh beneficial organisms for
I I've stopped losing track I think it's
about six years now I think we're going
on six
years so
um I still get really good compliments
from everybody about my weed so I think
I'm on the right track and um basically
it's just a it's it's a line of
nutrients that I can be proud of because
you can pour it down the drain uh you
can inest it it's 100% safe and
non-toxic for all living things um it's
between 95 and 100% natural and organic
and that's there's a line of products so
um some of them we need to leave a
little bit of room for uh minerals to
make sure that it was strong and
performed properly um but I have a
personal belief that if everything in
the world was made from less than 5%
chemicals I don't think we would have
any big uproar about the overuse misuse
or abuse of chemicals so um yeah it
creates extremely clean medicine and one
of our uh biggest claim to fames other
than uh tpine profiles that are uh
certain Labs have said they've found a
higher number of profile uh Tarpin than
they've ever found and any other samples
is the heavy metal
count um our most recent testing uh we
did some heavy metal testing and sent it
to uh a Laboratories that have done
thousands of cannabis tests and
initially they got zeros everything came
back zeros and of course they said you
know there's no such thing as zero you
can't have any Trace amount of heavy
metals it's present in water peaches so
they actually recalibrated the machines
to from parts per million to parts per
billion and they found that our produce
R ranked from between 300 to 600 parts
per billion of the heavy metals arsenic
cadmium Mercury and lead and to me
that's virtually undetectable if you
have to recalibrate your machines that
are not used for anything else um and
you can have up to uh 100 parts per
million in an organic
Peach um I think that we're creating
really pure medicine and I think that
that's really important it may it it may
not be matter at all to the average user
but to the portion of the population who
actually have uh imuno efficiency
diseases or autism which is believed to
be linked to heavy metals um or Crohn's
disease or any kinds of diseases where
the slightest bit of contaminants can
really ruin your day I've had people
come to me and just say my migraines
every I've gone all over LA and and gone
to dozens of dispensaries and until I
found veganic medicine I couldn't smoke
weed without having a migraine and this
person is extremely hyper sensitive and
not not of the normal but so I I like to
say if you're going to call it medicine
you better make sure it's actually good
for
you so before we turn over to the the
floor to questions I'm going to ask each
of you if there's anything else you'd
like to talk about the future of
cannabis cultivation start with you
David is there anything that you want to
add to our conversation um I think I
covered as much as I remembered so I
think I'm good I I'll wait for questions
let's hear from David he's doing a great
job thank you thank you C Frenchie
anything you want to add before we
we I could add a lot it's
always we'll get your microphone working
before the end I promise him and Donald
Trump yeah something's wrong with
Frenchie's microphone they were Donald
Trump was saying his microphone phon
didn't work sorry it it's like it's what
the type of quality Cal is talking it's
the type of quality I need to be able to
work and to be able to receive that I
need to be able to protect my grower and
if I really if we really work together
it's a long way because even the wine
industry didn't want to tackle
appellation control appellation control
give you
a lot
of not lot of space everything has to to
be local it's very strent reg regulation
and it's literally what we actually need
and we are stepping into history but we
don't even know what we have to offer
the world there is most of the genetic
that is up North is not known by
99% of the people here in California and
even less in the world there is a
treasure D Trove to discover and use as
a a standard of quality for the rest of
the planet there is no way that you can
bring any strain and tell everybody that
that strain is so miraculous when there
is no standard to compare to and this is
a something that is massively important
for us to do because everybody is
looking at us in California and at the
US in general and we have really
everything to uh to create it here in
the South we you don't really have that
relation with a with a grower I have
but and being a French also give me that
step back of the of the world situation
you are really at a time in a history
where not only cannabis will change the
face of medicine but to create the
standard in one industry and it's a
professional of that industry that set
the
standard it does it has never happen in
in any industry but the
wine so it would be really important for
us to start working on this before we
start thinking about making money
because we don't even know exactly what
treasure TR and how much we have in our
hand to share with the world
literally any last thoughts Kyle before
we open it up for questions I was lost
in Frenchie's thoughts there I like his
world
I want to live in French I want to live
in Frenchies world I want live in
Frenchies I don't think you get platinum
Emoji cookies there but that's
okay um what was the
question if you had anything you wanted
to add before we opened up the Florida
questions pot is
great I don't care if you call it
marijuana I don't care if you call it
weed pot I don't care what you call it
um marijuana is good for the world and
um legalization is a step towards World
Peace well said
[Applause]
[Music]