[Music]
here we are we're in this new age where
we're all focused on adult use we're all
focused on licensing we're all focused
on getting property and getting
ourselves together so that we have a
business going forward what seems to be
happening is that medical has kind of
lost a little bit of oomph and people
have sort of forgotten about it except
for the couple the sort of the small
group of people that really want to
focus only on medical and that's
wonderful and we're gonna hear from some
of them but as a general rule around
this industry I mean it really seems
like everyone's focusing on adult use
and I understand there's there's good
money potentially attached to that um
but we can't forget that at the end of
the day this was about our patients and
this is about helping people and this
was about the technology that's
happening and the developments that are
happening on the medical side and so I
really want to shine a light on that
tonight let me introduce them to you rob
Rosen heck right here on the end is the
founder of Lourdes Jones is anybody in
the room familiar with the brand Lourdes
Jones if you're not there you go if
you're not you definitely should be they
have incredible product we're gonna
learn about it tonight
they have incredible packaging which we
will also talk about tonight and I'm
just really really spectacular and Rob's
just an excellent guy full of so much
knowledge so I'm so excited to have you
thank you rob this man here dr. Jeff
chin do you go by doctor all right Jeff
Chen is a remarkable man as well he's
incredibly knowledgeable as it comes to
medical cannabis he has a group called
the UCLA cannabinoid affinity group
which I want to hear a little bit more
about and one of the reasons that I've
asked Jeff to be a part of this is
because when I first heard him speak I
realized that here was a man who could
take what is pretty scientific and kind
of can get a little confusing if you're
really not up to speed on on the science
of cannabis and you could break it down
into really digestible bits that the
average person can understand and I find
that very exciting and so thank you
thank you Jeff for being here too
thank you for having me absolutely so I
think the first thing I want to do is
just give them each a minute to talk
about themselves and their in what they
do and why this is important to them so
one Rob why don't you start with us I
grew up in New York on the East Coast
and I moved to California in 2000 and
became a medical marijuana patient I'd
always been a cannabis user and a
cannabis enthusiast so when I arrived in
California I was fascinated that you
could become a medical marijuana patient
and use cannabis legally and you know I
my knowledge of cannabis at that time
was extremely limited
you know it's smoked cannabis and I knew
what that did but I didn't know what an
edible was I didn't know what a topical
was I didn't know what sativa was I
didn't know what THC or CBD were those
were all new concepts and
you know I would go to the dispensary
and I would try products and it was a
little bit like Russian roulette you
might have this incredible experience
with something and you might have this
really terrible experience with
something how many people here had a
terrible experience with something yeah
so my background I've done a lot of
different things in my career but I was
a chemistry major and I also went to art
school and I ran a marketing agency and
we worked with food companies and
personal care companies and about four
years ago we decided we wanted to create
a cannabis brand that would address all
of the things that we didn't see in the
marketplace we wanted something that was
high-end quality transparent safe we
wanted to explain to people what they
were getting when I do it do you mystify
cannabis and make it user friendly and
something that you could aspire to there
were lots of people who were catering to
the STONER stereotypes and you know
associated with Bob Marley and Jerry
Garcia and all that stuff and that
stuff's great and those people who play
it played a critical role in the
legalization movement but there was a
lot of that already out there and there
wasn't stuff that would maybe appeal to
a soccer mom or somebody who would shop
at Whole Foods or people who cared about
the quality of ingredients and wanted to
understand what they were consuming and
so that was the idea behind Lourdes
Jones excellent thank you that's good
Jeff any one tell us a little bit about
you yeah sure so I I grew up born and
raised in Los Angeles and about four
years ago I was a medical student UCLA
when I saw the CNN documentary by Sanjay
Gupta and you know I my mind was kind of
opened to how cannabinoids might be
useful in epilepsy and what was really
profound for me was me having grown up
in a progressive state like California
that had medical marijuana since 1995
being a medical student at a progressive
institution like UCLA and if you ask me
the uses of cannabis I would have said
you know pain sleep that's about it and
the more I dug the more I'm
hovering really interesting properties
the anti-tumor properties
anti-inflammatory antioxidant so now I'm
going around UCLA talking to anybody
they'll listen to me
being like why are we doing research
with this why don't you care about this
and other medical students physicians
had kind of the same reaction again
maybe it's useful for pain and sleep
they didn't really know about all the
other layers so that's when I knew that
by the time that the average citizen or
the average scientist or doctor by the
time they learned about this organically
it might not be for decades and that's
when I kind of dedicated myself to the
cause it was white also around this time
that I entered the MBA portion I was
part of a dual degree undie MBA program
at UCLA basically you're trying to Train
physicians to run hospitals I'm using my
training now to accelerate cannabis
research thank you and earlier this year
I got a little bit of seed money from
UCLA I created the cannabinoid affinity
group which is a blue sleeo NIH's
interest group who here was that our we
had a symposium at 4:20 on UCLA I think
there's a few of us they were here you
were here ok so that's so we started off
with that and when we got enough
traction and interest from that this
actually happened about two months ago
we got a quarter million dollars from
UCLA to start the UCLA cannabis research
initiative which I'm the director of so
that's going to be something going
forward yeah and the idea is to be one
of the world's leading research centers
focused on cannabis so we're still in
our infancy right now our website looks
horrible it's a splash page don't judge
us for it but you know we're getting our
stuff together but my whole hypothesis
or the hypothesis that I want to test
through rigorous research is the idea
that cannabis could be a safe cheap
effective treatment for a variety of
ailments and at the end of the day I
think this conversation extends far
beyond cannabis and that you know
cannabis you could call it instead of
calling it a gateway drug I think it you
could call it a gateway herb for how it
changes the way that we look at and
utilize certain compounds that can be
found in food or plants that might not
be useful to be commercialized by a
pharmaceutical company because it's
unpatentable and
you know from from a profit standpoint
it's not very viable but cannabis is 100
to 1000 times larger of a market in
America than gingko biloba or echinacea
or tumeric so for once
there actually is enough money in this
pool that we can siphon away a little
bit that we can actually do research
that's never been done I'm not saying
that these other herbal products don't
have uses that's just there's never been
research money for it now or interest
but for cannabis there is it's a hundred
to a thousand times larger than the
market for any other botanical that's my
interest in this that's why I think it's
profound and I'm dedicating my career
for the foreseeable future for this so
that's great yes that's certainly worth
giving in my hand this is not I'm just
curious are you going to try to apply
for any of the tax revenue that's going
to come in from you know Alma yeah
definitely so there's ten million
dollars a year to the UC system to study
that impacts of legalization now that's
pretty broad you could be studying
criminal justice you could be crowing
studying the economic impacts hopefully
a part of that question will also be the
health benefit specifically the
therapeutic uses I'm not I imagine from
a priority standpoint most of that money
is going to go towards criminal justice
youth studying the youth to see if
they're using more economic stuff I
don't think a lot of that ten million
it's gonna go towards a therapeutic use
of cannabis so at the end of the day
we're looking at other ways that we can
get money for this type of work
well I'm correct I think it's saying
that UC San Diego was the officially
designated school that was going to get
two million dollars a year from the tax
revenue comes in from the adult use act
and UC Irvine just decided to create a
research program and I think they're
trying to apply for a portion of a
portion of that money so so you see all
these behind you on this so to speak
yeah oh yeah this was they gave us the
money to do this this is an official
program I actually moved into my office
a few weeks ago this is an official
program we haven't done any sort of
press release press launch yet so you'll
be still via that that'll come a few
months down the road I'm really the way
that I approach this is at my heart I'm
an entrepreneur and I don't want to
sleep approach it the way that an
academic or a lifelong researcher might
approach
I'm really trying to think how do we
make this sexy how do we get people to
care how do we get people to donate to
this research how do we get people to
support it so it's kind of a different
philosophy that I'm taking then UC San
Diego might or UC Irvine oh that's great
and certainly keep us posted because we
are here to help so okay let's start
with Rob Rob you and I've talked a
little bit about health and wellness as
it relates to medical I personally can
say for myself that cannabis use for me
has been almost exclusively for wellness
I'd love to talk to you a little bit of
talk to you about that a little bit and
and see how you feel that that connects
to the medical side of things I actually
had a pseudo little mini argument on one
of the talk shows that I did but while I
was on the campaign about whether or not
cannabis is medicine or whether it's
wellness and of course for me I go with
the wellness part but of course it's
medicine as well and the guy I was
talking to was like no it's only
medicine and I was like well it's it's
medicine to me and it's wellness what do
you think what's your take on all of
that so our view is that it's all a
continuum so these terms medicine
wellness adult use recreational use
getting high it being a you for ian's
Sacrament you know these are all words
so if you look back at the history of
cannabis you know cannabis was first
used about 10,000 years ago to create
rope and then about 8,000 years ago it
was developed into textiles and then
about 6,000 years ago it was first
turned into paper and about 4,000 years
ago it was first used as a medicine okay
but I mean the just to jumping around a
bit but the word medicine is you might
have tried this on your colleague
you know court you know cannabis is a
Schedule one narcotic under the
controlled substance act and one of the
things that defines something's that's a
Schedule one narcotic is that it has no
medical value so legally
technically in the United States it's
not a medicine so again
those words are arbitrary they're just
labels that we put onto things about
4000 years ago the Chinese first used
cannabis as a medicine and then it moved
into Persia and it moved into India and
proliferated around the world and for
centuries for centuries cannabis was
used in virtually every culture across
the world as a raw material for
industrial use to make rope and textiles
and paper and it was used as a medicine
and it was used as a euphoria
so what is it historically it's been all
those things the way you use it
engenders a label so when we're talking
about medical versus adult use and I'm
gonna try to stay away from the word
recreation all I might come out of my
mouth a little bit but I think I feel
like we've been talking about this a
while and adult use just feels a little
bit better to me but either way we're
talking about vertical versus adult use
little get your products your products
for example where do you call it where
do you put them again personally I would
connect our products to the way someone
uses them we're you know we're also
brand marketers we're experts on
consumer behavior so just
philosophically as a marketer I don't
want to tell someone how to use anything
I want to help them use whatever it is
they're buying for the best use in their
life just generally so somebody who uses
inedible to go see a concert because
it's gonna expand accentuate enhance
their experience that's recreational or
adult use or they're using it as a you
for ian's but somebody who you know
unfortunately has you know neurological
disease or AIDS or cancer or neuropathy
or autoimmune disease or goes to the gym
and has sore muscles they're using it
for some kind of medical effect wellness
health and wellness is another just term
so it's really a gradation as far as I'm
concerned if you you know pull a muscle
at the gym and you use a cannabis and
fuse topical to relieve it you know you
can go to the soup pharmacy and buy
ibuprofen for that it's an
over-the-counter remedy you know you
have nutriceuticals and dietary
supplements what are those you know so
these are just terms somebody who is
sick who uses it for pain relief or to
relieve their nausea or to help them
sleep or to stimulate their appetite if
they can't eat it sounds like a medicine
to me so we try to educate consumers
about the many uses for cannabis helped
them make smart choices choose good
products that are you know well
manufactured with quality ingredients
for the particular need they have we we
want to educate consumers and patients
and we don't we don't really see it as
it's this or that Jeff from your
perspective how do we or should we be
looking at medical products and adult
use products differently should we
expect something different from medical
products than we are said that we should
from adult use products going forward
yeah it's a it's a really good question
and you know looking at other states
where the products are sold alongside
each other in the same stores I wonder
and I'm not I'm not sure about this but
I wonder if often you're basically
taking the same products and it's just
all marketing and branding and
positioning whether to put a more
aesthetically appealing label on it that
it might be more medical versus not and
then the other layer that I often think
about is there's lots of companies who
create formulations that they kind of
try to target at different medical
conditions and again I wonder how much
of that is just the branding and the
packaging and that the actual
formulation itself isn't very different
the way and this this is where you know
I'm not super familiar in this part of
the policy but his weight it correct me
if I'm wrong but the way I understand in
California is they're likely going to be
sold side by side but if you're
purchasing medical products you don't
pay you don't pay the 10% Board of
Equalization tax but everybody will pay
the 15% exactly right and so going back
to original question you know I think
there's always going to be people who
will position their products for medical
and whether or not it is actually a
better product is you know that's gonna
be a completely different black box that
we need to answer I guess related to
that then is what makes what would make
a product more medical than recreational
certainly the delivery route is gonna
determine a lot of that
so obviously combustion fire like not a
good thing there's carcinogens there's
all sorts of stuff you're exposing to
you know vaporization traditionally
isn't seen as a medical delivery route
at least in you know Western medicine
that could change for cannabis and
that's because cannabinoids are poorly
absorbed and there's a lot of
variability in how they're absorbed
there's enter user variability so
between different people who we assume
should absorb it roughly the same rates
you see differences depending on whether
what you've just eaten before after
that's gonna affect how you absorb it
and so I suspect this is why for Marinol
you had a lot of people who did not find
it had very adverse reactions to it it's
because between human subjects between
patients one dose that might work for
somebody if you somebody else on that
dose it might be too much or depending
on if they just for instance had a meal
and they took it they're gonna absorb
more verses on an empty stomach
and now suddenly what dosage used to
work for them now suddenly making them
you know - it's too much for them so I
suspect that's a part of it and to help
you kind of conceptualize this GW
Pharmaceuticals when they created
sativex which is the one to one THC to
CBD product there's a reason that they
do an oral mucosal spray there's a
reason you
Spray it in the back EMF and they didn't
just put it in a pill form that's cuz
they quickly realized that if you're in
Doorly ingesting cannabinoids it's
really hard to predict how much is
absorbed and how quickly it's absorbed
again it varies in between people and it
varies on what else is with it so if you
think about edible products how you
create the edible product is going to
dramatically affect how quickly absorb
and how much you absorb so if you start
thinking about from that standpoint it's
not you can't really just transition
recreational products over to medical
because depending on the complexes that
cannabinoids sit in whether it's a brown
and versus a lollipop versus the
beverage even though it's the same I
think even though it's the same you know
even though you're only administering
maybe 10 milligrams of THC if it's in a
beverage versus a cookie versus the
lollipop they're gonna have dramatic
differences and how quickly and how much
they absorb so from that standpoint you
definitely are going to have to create a
dichotomy with how you think about these
products hello oh there we go is that is
that something that you are gonna be
spending time researching I would I
would like that to be a focus of our
research but as many of you know we are
precluded from using any cannabis
products in our research that doesn't
come from the federal government so
theoretically actually you just gave me
a really good idea so one thing that we
could do is we could get cannabis from
the federal government and then get
approval to prepare it differently in
two different formats of beverage versus
an edible and then administer that to
subjects in our study and that way that
data would actually have more we call it
external validity it would have more
real world relevance to what's happening
in the cannabis sector because a lot of
the official cannabis research on
America it's been done with rolled
cigarettes of cannabis of potency that's
maybe five to seven percent potency they
haven't been doing controlled studies on
dabs or
extracts or edibles or anything else
really aside from rolled cigarettes and
some studies where they did vaporization
that used like a lily of volcanoes done
at UC San Diego
they used a volcano and they showed that
vaporization was a legitimate way to use
the cannabis so that was actually a
pretty cool study that was actually you
know I've got that got approved and was
done at UC San Diego
with federal well so interestingly the
the so the federal government does not
fund therapeutic research the money that
UC San Diego has been using actually
came from California so what's been
funding the research at UC San Diego for
the last 15 years was money from the
state of California that was earmarked
for cannabis research they actually just
ran out of that money a year ago and
luckily now they have a pipeline of two
million dollar after prop C form to prop
64 they have a pipeline of 2 million
dollars a year to keep doing what
they're doing so they're studying things
like driving impairment what's how do
you measure driving impairment and you
know obviously you don't want people on
the road that are stoned out of their
minds but you also don't want to give
people DUIs who are using it for
legitimate medical use and just they
have a high tolerance so that's actually
a very complicated question and it looks
like the answer is some sort of an a
driving simulator an app that you give
somebody on the roadside because blood
levels saliva levels they don't
correlate with actual impairment very
interesting very interesting
um that's probably something we could
talk about all day but Rob I want to
talk to you a little bit about
anti-anxiety meds we've talked a little
bit about this and something that you
feel is pretty close to your heart
there's something some studies that
cannabis is maybe starting to be able to
replace some of the anti-anxiety meds
can you tell us a little bit more about
that and what your thoughts are on it
sure everybody's anxious you know it's a
human condition you know we could get
you know Jeff can do studies you know
double-blind placebo-controlled studies
but most people if they smoke a joint
they just empirically know it alleviates
anxiety
so talking about taking away til bottles
that are yeah so we we have where the
Lord Jones brand but we operate a
collective called Hollywood Hills
wellness we have hundreds and hundreds
of members and we have dozens and dozens
and if not more members who have the
very similar experience they suffer
chronic anxiety they've taken every SSRI
imaginable they have adverse side
effects and something has led them to
cannabis a friend relative just trial
and error and these are not people who
use a lot of cannabis recreationally or
for adult use or to get high they're
actually most of them quite reluctant
and sheepish about trying cannabis and
they come to us they join the collective
and we give them different varieties of
cannabinoids and universally they report
that they've been transformed reborn I'm
my new self all of those things you kind
of read about when prozac was first
introduced that and more
dozens of testimonials of people who
said I've thrown my pills away and I use
cannabis and I feel better there are
fewer side effects and it's more natural
and that's been our experience and you
know we didn't really know where we were
going when we decided to enter the
cannabis industry it was formal
collective we we had a pretty pedestrian
view of we're gonna we're gonna help
people get high and we're gonna make
better products and we're gonna label
them that was kind of where we started
we had no idea about anxiety as an issue
we had no idea about pain relief as an
issue we you know we can tell you all
kinds of stories that we learn from our
patients every week you know we with
this woman was given one of our topicals
as a gag gift by one of her friends
there was a joke at a dinner party and
gave it to her and
every night before she would go to bed
she'd used some hand cream to make her
skin soft so she put our bottle on her
bedside table and started to use our
lotion instead of whatever she was using
and she noticed after two weeks her
nails her cuticles stopped chipping and
they were stronger I don't even know if
she realized she had weak nails and she
used up the bottle and then two weeks
after later her nail started to chip
again and she called us and we this was
something I mean I don't know if you've
studied this Jeff but we didn't we had
no idea like its cuticle health it
strengthens nails and we started to tell
people about it and it would that
happens time and again we have friends
who are stylist to the celebrities and
one of the women who works in our office
hates wearing high heels and went to a
wedding and she took our lotion and
rubbed it on her heels before she went
to the wedding but she came back and she
said look I put this on my feet before I
went to the wedding and I didn't have
any pain in my high heels I'm crippled
when I come home from a wedding and so
we we gave it we started to give it to
the stylist and we were written up in
billboard and Hollywood Reporter and and
our lotion was used at the Golden Globes
and the Oscars for all the celebrities
feet so we're learning you know the
point is people like Jeff you know we
need to understand the true potential of
cannabis as a medicine because we don't
know what it does we'd be expecting a
Lord Jones football any day now
he'll bomb for sure so so so on that
note I think you know there's there's a
lot of amazing anecdotal evidence out
there and that actually helped
scientists know what to focus in on so
if not for the parents who had started
using CBD for the epileptic children you
know the researchers would have never
gotten on board and actually the people
of GW Pharmaceuticals CBD for epilepsy
was not in their product pipeline as of
like 2011
and it was really they started getting
some emails from parents we're like you
guys developed this THC CBD drug called
Sativex for multiple sclerosis why
aren't you doing CBD for epilepsy
haven't you seen the videos like what
videos and so this is a pharma company
who was informed by the anecdotal
evidence of patients so I think the
anecdotal evidence is valuable I think
there needs to be a way like a
centralized way that we can collect all
of this anecdotal evidence and really be
able to if if this if the number of
participants in this study is large
enough that we can start teasing apart
the signal from the noise so you know it
looks like a sense Ichi was partnered
with Stanford they were able to
distribute a survey to about a thousand
cannabis patients to gather their
responses my I think how do we get a
hundred thousand respondents to fill out
a survey and help us understand what
their what it's useful for so then we
can take what limited resources we have
and hone in on those use cases okay now
there is a caveat to all of this and the
caveat is that there is such a thing as
the placebo effect it's a real thing and
this is so you guys understand this for
cannabis the placebo effect is actually
higher than it would be for something
else and that's because going into it
cannabis already has this reputation so
going in expectations are already more
heightened than if I just gave you
something I said it's a Chinese herb try
it but because I tell you it's cannabis
you ready have this preconceived notion
that's gonna make the placebo effect
stronger the other thing is when you
take cannabis you actually feel
different because it's psycho at well at
least for THC its psychoactive and you
feel different that's gonna enhance the
placebo effect more than if I gave you a
sugar pill told you was gonna help you
but you didn't feel very different
afterwards but no I think I'm still my
sleep still pretty bad or my pain still
Birdie bad but with cannabis because you
feel the psycho activity that's gonna
hence the placebo effect even more so
that's justice K that we should take
everything with the grain of salt but I
think the anecdotal data is very
valuable and then on the on the topic of
being a substitute for pharmaceutical
drugs we see this in the literature so
there was a study came out recently that
showed about a two hundred million
dollar reduction in annual Medicare
spending because baby boomers are
starting to use cannabis and they'd
attributed this directly to cannabis
and then the other question then at
least for the issue of anxiety which you
guys in benzos you know we do also hear
anecdotally that some people smoke
cannabis and they have increased anxiety
and paranoia and I suspect that
obviously has something to do with
dosage right so maybe it'll load for
instance a low dosage THC is
anti-anxiety properties at a high dosage
it is pro anxiety properties and this
leads me to my next point which is that
more is not necessarily better and this
is true for a lot of things that's
especially true for cannabis and to give
you an example so CBD is an
anti-inflammatory but there are my
studies that show if you give if you
give a little bit of C if you give too
little CBD it's not going to have good
anti-inflammatory properties if you give
immediate moderate dose it's gonna have
too much CBD the anti-inflammatory
properties go away so there's a sweet
spot and so how do we find that sweet
spot that's part of what hopefully our
research can show as well but so more is
not necessarily better and that's that's
you know something that's very you know
counterintuitive to the American Way of
doing things but for cannabinoids it's
also very true and more is not
necessarily better that's actually very
interesting right because especially for
people who build up tolerance you just
you might want to continue to take more
and more and more but actually it's not
gonna really do anything for you well
and also you know your body's make
endocannabinoids but when you flood your
body with external cannabinoids your
body is going to decrease the amount of
endogenous cannabinoids that it's making
right it has a feedback system it knows
it basically says here's the level of
cannabinoids I want to be at and when
I'm here I bring it back up but if you
flood the body with external
cannabinoids like heavy daily
cannabinoids your body's gonna say oh
there's plenty of cannabinoids out there
I'm not gonna I'm not gonna make as much
as my own and it's also going to
decrease the amount of cannabinoid
receptors out there because it's saying
these cannabinoid receptors are being
over stimulated I'm actually going to
decrease the amount of receptors out
there and now you're talking about a
very Kondo cannabinoid system is very
complex now you start thinking about
what what are all the unintended side
effects and consequences so another
reason why more
is not necessarily better it's really
interesting right yeah I would say
that's give us a round of applause for
that let's talk about consistency thank
you let's talk about consistency and and
from both of your perspectives do we
need to be looking at consistency on the
medical side anything different then
we're looking at consistency with adult
use product or should you know cuz we
know that there's going to be pretty
stringent testing you know criteria and
regulations how do we look forward into
the consistency issue because I know
that for years that's been one of the
biggest problems right because it's
still a plant the end of the day it's
still a plant so it can't be exactly the
same every time right that's the
difference between a pharmaceutical and
a nutraceutical in this case so what do
you either review we don't you want to
go first maybe Jeff or about consistency
yeah sure so you know at first glance
like obviously yes medical needs to be
more consistent you have someone who is
reliant on this for their pain relief
for their sleep and minor and
fluctuations in their products suddenly
they're you know they went and bought
this item a few weeks later they went
back but the same item from the same
manufacturer and now suddenly they have
to take more or it's not benefitting
their sleep as much and it's because
you're dealing with the plant the plant
is messy even the same clone the same
genetics right slightly different
environmental conditions are gonna
change what's going on with it even if
you standardize to just THC right
there's like hundreds of other compounds
in there and the other point that I want
to make is that even though these other
compounds might not be particularly
abundant these cannabinoids are distinct
molecules so you might need ten
milligrams of THC to have a certain
physiologic effect but for this other
random cannabinoid X maybe only need
point one milligrams for it to exert its
anti-inflammatory properties or its
anti-pain properties so just because
these other constituents in cannabis are
present in very minor quantities does
not mean that they're insignificant so
yeah even if you standardize to THC or
standardized as CBD there's still
there's all these terpenes there's all
these other cannabinoids what do they do
then it gets even more complicated
Clayton when you start thinking of them
having interactions with one another and
the way that they can have interactions
within with one another is is a term
called allosteric regulation which is
where let's say I have a cannabinoid
receptor here you know I might have this
other cannabinoid that might not
directly bind to it but it's gonna
affect how this receptor binds to THC or
it'll affect how this receptor binds to
CBD so then you start looking at all the
permutations of all these combinations
it gets mind boggling which is why it's
so hard to develop pharmaceutical drugs
out of botanicals so you know at the end
of the day I would say that yes we need
stricter standards for medical I'm not
sure how to get there though you know
without being a multi-billion dollar
pharmaceutical company that like GW
Pharmaceuticals they make their drugs
out of the plant they grow the plant in
the UK but they grow it under incredibly
sterile incredibly rigorous conditions
and that's how they can get the plant to
be 99.9 percent consistent each time
then when they throw it into their
extractor with the same settings you can
get something that is pretty close to
consistent the other area that you guys
might want to look towards the future in
in understanding how this might shape
out in America is look at Canada so when
Canada first legalized medical they
didn't let you just start willy-nilly
growing these people had to put in tens
of millions of dollars into
state-of-the-art sterile rigorously
controlled growing environments to be
able to produce the plants the same
every single batch how is that going to
look if the federal government because
we think it's gonna be stepwise right
they'll legalize medical federally than
recreational if the feds legalized
medical are they gonna make you put in
that same infrastructure the same 30
million dollars to get a grow facility
up so for you guys to think long term as
to how this is going to shape up maybe
look towards Canada that might be a
model that we adopt here in the US you
know part of part of this whole topic of
medical --too and separating it out from
adult uses in the packaging and that's
something that you're really familiar
with and I'm kind of curious to see what
you think first of all the question one
question that's been brought up which is
are you listing all your ingredients
in your not just your cannabinoids right
how are people doing that cuz we're
saying oh this is this is gonna be great
for you it's healthy but then you start
looking at the rest of the ingredients
and it's really crap right so the one
question would be about packaging and
and really being very transparent with
your packaging and the other part would
be is are we going to continue to
probably have a lot of white label
product that people just buy and then
repackage and slap a brand on it and put
it out in the store how were we how can
we distinguish between all that those
are really good and complicated
questions and I think they're even
broader which is you know how is the
marijuana industry going to evolve in
the u.s. its larger than just labeling
packaging medical versus adult use you
know I I spend a bunch of time thinking
about the future of of cannabis as a
product in the US you know will it be
taken over by pharmaceutical companies
the pharmaceutical Lobby is the most
powerful lobby except possibly the
petroleum Lobby in the world you know if
it's determined to be a medicine all
again I think all these things are
totally arbitrary if it's determined to
be a medicine why shouldn't the
pharmaceutical companies take it over if
is it a dietary supplement is it a
nutraceutical is it like alcohol is it a
is it a vice that should be controlled
by the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and
Firearms and cannabis you know what is
it is it a consumer product should it be
you know will will Procter and Gamble
and General Mills take over the can I
mean these are big questions you know
I'm sorry I didn't really answer your
question but I think the questions you
brought up are really complicated you
know yes I believe everything should be
labeled should things be you know we
just passed a regulation in California
saying that you can't spray THC on to
you know there are a bunch of companies
that just go and they buy
bulk crappy candy made with corn syrup
and artificial flavor and colors and
then they spray it and I was I was you
know I our company weighed in in
Sacramento and and but that was not a
good way to manufacture cannabis
products but you know white labeling
yeah I mean you know you have one
company that makes edibles and then six
other companies slap a label on it how
do we feel about that I I don't have the
answers to that you know we're trying to
control our means of production create
something that's super high quality
disclose the ingredients create great
relationships with our customers that's
we're kind of old-fashioned that way in
our approach but you're bringing up a
lot of questions about you know what is
cannabis and how should it be regulated
and in Canada they do treat it like a
medicine and and the manufacturing is
pharmaceutical grade and when you go
into a grow house it looks more like a
biotech lab than a cultivation Center
there's lots of benefits to that I think
as far as safety goes there's not a lot
of consumer choice up there
they don't have edibles and topicals yet
they only have flour so I don't I don't
know the answers to all these questions
but they're really important questions
we just did chime in for a sec you know
in terms of the labeling and and
ingredients and whatnot that's more
something that will be handled at the
regulatory level so it's almost out of
our hands as to how that'll be handled
it'll likely be mandated they've to list
all ingredients the white labeling
aspect it happened so much in just
everyday life that it's bound to happen
I'm sure everyday you go to the grocery
store you're you might move you in on
the same day you might buy two different
things that literally are just the same
cereal that got white labeled like
everything you buy a Trader Joe's is
white labeled yeah everything at Trader
Joe's is white labeled they go to
companies ago I like this and I put
their label on it so that's you can
expect it to happen in cannabis on the
issue of again looking towards the
future maybe there's
few things that you might want to use as
food for thought so there are certain
naturally occurring things that
currently are sold as nutraceuticals
that also have a pharmaceutical version
so for instance you can go buy fish oil
as a nutraceutical or food supplement
you can also get prescription strength
like omega fatty acids that are
synthetically created that are much more
expensive and are arguably more pure but
they're out there's some people that are
was going to buy the fish oil and
there's some people that want to go
after the whatever is the pure version
in terms of cost it might be more
expensive to make something that's like
that medical grade but if insurance
reimburses for it that's also gonna
change behavior right you might believe
in that you might desire and believe in
the natural form but hey if your
insurance is suddenly paying for one and
not the other like okay maybe I'll let
my doctor prescribe and I'll pick it up
at the pharmacy and to be to be clear
the pharmaceutical industry in the
United States is no different than the
consumer packaged goods industry when it
comes to consumer marketing if you watch
you know MSNBC at night it's all
wall-to-wall ads that was something that
was illegal a generation ago and now you
know generation ago you would go to your
doctor and the dot year you'd consult
with your doctor and your doctor would
say you need this medicine and you'd say
what does it do and they'd say it's
gonna help you with this and they
prescribe it now you you watch
television and you go to your doctor say
oh shit I need viagra you know or I need
you know a vilify or whatever you know
you know so there's a lot of
merchandising and marketing in the
pharmaceutical world to which just again
just makes it more complex I had brought
up a question to both of you earlier
before we got here
being the were in West Hollywood who was
on the forefront in the 80s of the
hiv/aids syndromes shall we say and
medical marijuana was a really big help
do either of you have any thoughts on
that or any just contribution to that
whole that whole story and how you know
because that's still a treatment
right it's medical cannabis is still a
treatment for HIV do you see any
development happening in that area do
you see any kind of forward movement or
are we still stuck
so hiv/aids and and cancer too in our
experience our patients use it not so
much to treat HIV AIDS and cancer but to
mitigate the side effects of the
treatments of HIV and cancer so you know
both cancer and AIDS medication the
antiviral drugs they do a bunch of
things they cause people to become sick
lose their appetite become nauseous some
people have problems sleeping and
obviously they're create great pain and
discomfort so cannabis can help
alleviate most of those symptoms that's
why most people that come to us are
using it now there's a whole lot of
noise out there about cancer cannabis
kills cancer and I did read something
recently about that that some of the
cannabinoids may actually attack the
AIDS virus in some way where you know
I'm never gonna tell somebody who has
cancer cannabis is gonna cure cancer
there's no medical proof for that but I
think there is enough you know if where
there's smoke there's fire it's
certainly I'll throw this over to Jeff I
need to really scientifically
investigate that stuff yes on the topic
of cannabis and HIV or AIDS
you know Marinol synthetic THC is FDA
approved for anorexia which is weight
loss but specifically anorexia
associated with AIDS right so that's
kind of the first thing that happened in
the late 80s or the 90s they believe
there have also been studies actually
done also again at UC San Diego they've
done a great job looking specifically at
cannabis for neuropathic pain nerve pain
from patients with AIDS and it looks
positive for that as well so you know
all these things coalescing now then
there's the other question is that
cannabinoids are anti-inflammatories
right which is great if you have an
maybe if you have an autoimmune
condition theoretically it might be able
to help that but anti-inflammatories
also suppress your immune system and so
in that sense we actually had they did a
study on this I think at UC San
Francisco because the concern was if you
have AIDS and you're using cannabis
maybe to gain weight or to help with
your nausea but the cannabis is
suppressing your immune system even more
so right the AIDS virus is suppressing
your immune system is killing all your
white blood cells and then the cannabis
being an anti-inflammatory does it
additionally immunosuppressed you and
make you susceptible to all these
infections are you in aids you don't die
from the AIDS virus you die from
infections and it looked like the study
that did that show that it did not
measurably increase your risk for
infections so even though cannabis was
an anti-inflammatory people who have
AIDS it wasn't further suppressing their
immune systems which is a good thing so
and you added a last point about oh like
cancer yeah yeah I mean cannabinoids
have anti-tumor properties they've only
been done in animal studies but they've
been done across a wide variety of
cancer cell types brain lung colon skin
and many others and the mechanisms are
multifactorial right so we know that
they have direct
cancer killing properties through a
process called apoptosis so when your
cells become at least let me rephrase in
animal studies when cells become
cancerous they actually increase the
expression of cannabinoid receptors
generally and when cannabinoids activate
these cannabinoid receptors actually
triggers the cancer cell to kill itself
so can't still commit suicide it's a
process called apoptosis so cannabinoids
do that cannabinoids also prevent can
inhibit the cancer cells from getting
food so cancer cells need to nourish
themselves especially if they're growing
fast so they send out chemicals that
tell your blood vessels to come to the
cancer cell right because the cancer
cell is hungry it needs to feed and
cannabinoids seem to also cut off that
process it prevents blood cells from
getting to the cancer cells and lastly
cancer cells need to spread and it
appears that cannabinoids
are also able to inhibit the spreading
of the cancer cells this process called
metastasis
okay so through all these mechanisms
cannabinoids are able to do that good
news is so bad news it's a limpid any
animal studies good news they just did
the first human study the results came
out it was a combination of THC and CBD
for glioblastoma multiforme like the
most dangerous deadly form of brain
cancer and this was a placebo randomized
control trial and the cannabinoids had a
significant survival benefit so it was
yeah yeah so the people that got the
cannabinoids 83 percent of them had
survival at one year the group that
didn't get it
53 percent were alive at one year so
significant very preliminary study very
small study only about 10 people in each
treatment arm the other caveat I want to
add missus and then we'll wrap this up
not all cancer cells Express cannabinoid
receptors and so if your cancer cells
aren't expressing cannabinoid receptors
and you're hitting them cannabinoids
you're not really gonna do much what you
might do is you might suppress their
immune system and our immune system also
helps keep cancers in check
so now you can see where this gets very
complicated very fast and this is
another instance where more is not
necessarily better so just a caveat to
keep in mind going forward so I'm gonna
wrap this part up and then we're gonna
take some questions but I just want to
ask a simple question to both of you
cuz I bet that everybody in this room if
you're in the cannabis industry you've
gotten this question from someone you
know which is I'm sick fill in the blank
or my husband wife daughter friends etc
is sick with something fill in the blank
what do I do
so we're talking about cancer we're
talking about fibromyalgia we're talking
about you know epilepsy and the chronic
pains where do I go what do i do do I
just go get a paper Iser and call it a
day do I you know what is it what do you
as individuals and as people in the
industry recommend and say to people
that come up to you because that I know
it happens to me all the time
what do you respond to that Rob you bet
you could ask that a lot you're a
product guy so you know that's a tricky
thing because I'm not
dr. but we also we provide access to
cannabis so it's a weird role we call
ourselves
lay practitioners the first thing we
wanted you know we'll rely on what has
helped patients that we've worked with
but the big question we want to know is
is this something that's going to be
treated with a topical or an ingestible
is this something that's systemic or is
it something that's local and sometimes
will will offer a combination of the two
so like migraines and menstrual pain are
two things too where we might use a
combination of an adjustable and a
topical but you know there's a lot of
trial and error and what we do and we
are basing what we do on anecdotal
evidence as practitioners we're not
doctors and then also if there's any
question at all if we don't feel real
comfortable okay we have lots of
patients who use it this way we'll tell
them to go see a doctor I mean we're not
going to go out on a limb and offer
medical advice yeah it's I don't know if
I can really comment very much on this I
get asked all the time and at the end of
the day I don't really even know what to
tell them because there's so many
questions it's will it work for that
condition what dosage do you take what
delivery format then they like started
asking about what brand do I use like
how do I know what's how do I even know
what's in this brand are there
pesticides of this fertilizer so
unfortunately often I can't really tell
them much at all I wish I had better I
wish I had a better response for them
but there's really not much I can tell
them at all generally what I say is
don't replace it with what you're the
kind of traditional established Western
medicine is giving you don't replace it
it's easy to get caught up in you know
the the miraculous stories that we hear
and and you know but I I would never
recommend as a first-line treatment I
would say if you're using Western
medicine
and you're using these prescription
pills and you're not getting relief then
at that point if you want to consider
adding cannabis on top just understand
the risks and the benefits and use it as
what we call an adjunct an add-on to see
if it can kind of enhance your overall
response and that's kind of what I tell
them and it's yeah I know it's a tough
question because we none of us really
have answers but we are kind of
considered the experts right now these
days cuz there really aren't a lot so
you know it is interesting to just talk
about it and say what do you say what do
you do I mean I find for myself when I
get the call which I do all the time
unfortunately a lot of what my time is
spent is just talking to them just just
talking just listening talking maybe
suggesting hey you maybe want to go take
a look at some of these things they
might help you they might not I can't
guarantee anything but it's just almost
like having some information seems to
give them a little bit of peace and I
think that that's you know ultimately
what we can be doing right now is saying
well we can't guarantee anything but
here's some things you could look at
here's some things you should research
here's some things you can possibly try
and maybe they'll help they've helped
other people do you know feel better
here so there's a chance that it might
help you feel better too but there's a
chance it might not so you know it but I
think that as sort of just almost like
as a as an ear to just bend I think
that's where I found myself so so let's
first of all thank Jeff Chen Rob Rosen
heck it's been incredible incredible
thank you guys so much if there's any
questions out there it's kind of hard to
see but yeah alright we're gonna send
one of these mics around well what do
you guys come or anybody here Peter grab
one of these microphones this guy thank
you so much I'm a California attorney
who's been concerned about the future of
medical and when you look at Washington
where it's essentially folded you look
at Colorado where adult use market just
utterly outstripping medical I don't
know that there's an answer to this
question I don't
this questions really for anyone in the
room who's got any good ideas whether at
the local level or the state level
anything that you think can be done to
protect medical and keep it alive
assuming you recognize it as something
that could be under threat okay I can
talk to you about from a state
perspective we'll start there
so prop 215 which is our medical
marijuana laws here in California it
would take a constitutional amendment to
undo prop 215 it's one of the reasons
that prop 64 did not go down that path
because it was going to be extremely
complicated to undo it
so rather than undo it they folded in
some protections into prop 64 for
medical and but then subsequently all
that's moved into now SB 94 and our
regulations so how it's all gonna
ultimately shake out I don't think
anybody knows at this point but as of
right now this time our medical is still
protected in California it it's hard to
say how that will go down but the thing
that happened in Washington was that
because the tax difference was so huge
there was no incentive for people to go
to to adult use so nobody was opening up
adult youth shops and so everyone just
stayed in the medical and they went no
no no so they kind of shut medical
folded it into adult use purely because
everybody was trying to avoid the taxes
I think we have a better system here we
learned from that as well but at this
point medical is here to stay for the
time being I cannot predict what will
happen in five years from now but I
think we're safe for a little while
because of the fact that it would take a
constitutional amendment to undo prop
215 that's about what I can contribute
you guys all right I mean if you look at
someone you were saying how you know the
economic interests people tend to jump
to adult use but if you look at the size
of the healthcare sector in America or
the size of the pharmaceutical industry
in America and you compare it to the
size of the wine and beer market
you can see that there's a lot more
money in pharma than there is in selling
like alcohol
now I'm not again not trying to say that
cannabis is alcohol I know a lot of
people don't like that comparison but I
would make the argument that from an
economic standpoint there might actually
even be more money
servicing medical users than there is in
selling to an adult use market because
at the end of the day an adult use
market you're battling over marketing
who's who's got the sexier brand who's
got better distribution but in medical
if you come up with a formulation that
actually works for a certain condition
you've cracked the code on the terpenes
and cannabinoids you just stumbled
across a billion-dollar formulation
right so potentially maybe it's helping
people realize that there is a ton of
money in medical is just you maybe have
to be more patient and when the money is
going to be made whereas with adult use
you can kind of jump in now start
building your brand but for medical
really do putting that fixed cost R&amp;D
development in the beginning maybe not
being super propyl in the beginning but
it's really the back end is is going
under that and actually there's a path
going forward now for medical products
derived from plants to get FDA approved
you might want to look this up if you're
remotely interested it's called the
botanical drug category under the FDA
it's only been around for the last four
years only two drugs have made it
through that FDA botanical drug category
one is a green tea extract for genital
warts called Berggren the other is a
Chinese herb for menstrual hot flashes
both of them are plants you extract the
plant put it in a pill and the FDA will
give you clearance you can't patent the
formula but you can have you're the only
one that's allowed to say that this
formula was FDA approved for general
warts or hot flashes and that's a
billion-dollar drug if you can come
across that formula and you can stumble
look upon it and now what's even better
and one last point I want to make about
this what's even better is a pharma
company has to spend a lot of time and
money undergoing clinical trials for
their stuff but right now in cannabis if
you think you have a formula it works
you kind of just sell it to people
without having to spend a hundred
million dollars on FDA
go trials so you can already kind of be
testing your formula in a sense without
having to spend all that money so that's
another thing that could be valuable
going forward that's great any other
questions okay just a comment to your
question which is the in my mind part of
the the gap between what to fill in that
gap is really looking at education so
and what I mean by education isn't
patient education but career technical
ed so if you go through the State Board
of Education and create a certified
training that is career tech ed
post-secondary on something around
cannabis and bud tending or whatever
it's going to be so that you have people
who are actually trained to be able to
be those kinds of patient advocates then
that's going to fill in a piece of the
market that's missing because right now
one of the issues is if you're
especially if you're older or if you've
never consumed cannabis in any way and
you walk into well I'm an Oregon so we
can walk in right so for a wreck and we
walk in what you're gonna get is people
who can't answer it used to be that you
could ask a question and your bud tender
at the dispensary would be able to say
well this is a flower you know or this
is a strain that's known for this or
this is a product that's good for this
and now you've just got a bunch of young
you know generally young people that
don't really know anything that are not
able to give good information so I think
a big piece is creating through and
California has a really open State Board
of Education in terms of things that
they'll approve creating some kind of
mechanism to get people in that so that
would be that's one of the things I've
been emailed I have a question that's
been kind of burning for a long time
around medical product in adult use
around labeling and this piece of so I
go in and I see a tincture and
I say you know I'm in this in the same
place that has a tincture topical and a
flower so the flower I can the person
can say to me it's this strain it's got
this percentage it's been lab tested and
it's got this percentage of THC and this
percentage of CBD data but my teacher
doesn't tell me what strain it is maybe
it says it's a hybrid maybe it says it's
sativa maybe it says it's indica my
edible maybe it says any of that but I
know for myself medically that a lot of
what works for me is strain specific so
I'm just curious your thoughts on how do
we get more of the products that
especially as we're going into adult use
how do we get doesn't in your opinion
doesn't matter for topicals and tincture
tincture is to say this is a strain or
is it it doesn't matter because it's all
shake or it doesn't matter because it's
all leaf for sure
so streams when you're talking about a
strain first of all there's a lot of
string confusion because there's a lot
of people who just call they make up
names or they'll take whatever they have
and call it blue dream or whatever but
when you talk about a strain and best
practices are employed and you're
actually getting that strain the strain
represents a collection of cannabinoids
and turkeys and so you know this strain
gives me this desired effect because it
has this much THC this much CBD these
terpenes this profile and it assuming
it's consistent you're gonna have this
consistent experience as soon as you
extract cannabis oil or some kind of
concentrate from the plant you've
disrupted its properties
and you've disrupted his properties
based on how it was primarily how it was
extracted how much heat how much
pressure and what kind of solvent is
used so you could take the exact same
flower and extract it ten different ways
and get ten totally different
cannabinoid profiles and
terpene profiles in the extract that you
got from the same flower so that creates
one complication there so if I told you
I'm selling you loose blue dream as its
train that you're gonna smoke and then I
tell you here's a cookie that has blue
dream extract in it it's really going to
be dependent on how it was extracted so
what you really eventful and can more
consumer awareness so they understand oh
you know what I like a strain that's
high in cbn with lemon een because
that's immutable regardless of what the
plant source is so you know the only way
to really kind of predict the desired
effect of a topical or anything anything
that's a manufacturer product made from
concentrate is to understand which
cannabinoids and which combination and
terpenes and potencies are left in the
final product it's it's chemistry so
it's not an easy answer but just just to
add to that I complete with grief
everything you said I think then we're
gonna move away from strain names and
move towards hard numbers like here
here's the ratio that I like of these
certain terpenes are cannabinoids or
even if we settle if you find that a
specific formulation works for you then
maybe that's the one that you're gonna
go after and I think what's gonna happen
is companies will create ten different
formulations and if they can
consistently make each one of those ten
formulations they don't really need to
say that this formulation is going to
produce euphoria versus creativity
versus sedation they just have to show
that this is formula a and we make it
consistently and our users will
eventually self a sort to find the ones
that they like and that's them if you
can crack that formula you're gonna sell
a lot even the same strain you know
first off like you said the strain aims
are all messed up everyone's just making
it up I wouldn't trust anything the odds
that blue dream in this store is
actually a related to the blue juve
another story it's very slim but even
the same strain the same
nedick's batch to batch they're gonna be
totally different like you even
mentioned with the sugar leaves
depending on where you are in the plant
the ratio is gonna be completely
different you know depending on whether
using sugar leaves there's this trim or
says no vs. flower at the top versus
flower on the bottom right and so if
you're saying I locked in to this
particular formulation from this strain
it's you're not gonna be able to find
that consistency so it's going to go
likely to the derivatives the extracts
and then really honing in on if you can
consistently produce a formula that has
the same amount of these 10 cannabinoids
and these 10 terpenes we're getting
pretty close to something that's
consistent and then people will
naturally self a sort to what they like
and what works for them cranky I so
that's great I am going to I know we
have lots of questions these guys are
gonna stick around so but I'm gonna wrap
this part of it and we're gonna finish
off this event and and these guys will
hang out so you come ask questions but I
really just want to thank you both
because this has been so wonderful to
talk about this these guys are great so
please come up afterwards and talk to
them
[Music]