I forgot you had my full bio so it's
grimacing a little up here I gotta
shorten that thing great well so I'm
really excited to be here today
Oren get deep into some science I'll
leave a ton of time at the end for
question and answers I'm sure you guys
will have a lot so let's get started in
the game of cannabinoids great alright
so first brief Alan wouldn't be talking
about today so we'll compare how how do
we utilize the plant to produce
cannabinoids how can we utilize other
formats whether using chemical synthesis
and beakers or we kinetically
programming bacteria to produce
cannabinoids we'll talk a bit about the
cost because that's gonna be a huge
driver of who's gonna win this this game
of cannabinoids I will talk about some
of the potential effectiveness efficacy
effectiveness is it going to be the same
it's gonna be different depending on
where you source your cannabinoids from
and we'll talk about some of the the
regulatory landscape which is probably
the most complicated part of this that
we need to tease through so let's get
started I'll first just briefly overview
what how the plant produces cannabinoids
so here's what a plant does right so
it's taking carbon dioxide out of the
atmosphere and it's fixing that carbon
and building sugar is what it's doing
right and once it's built that sugar it
can then take that sugar and shrimp and
and transform it into a variety of other
compounds so what the cannabis plant
does is it takes carbon dioxide to form
sugar and so from sugar and through a
series of steps which I will just kind
of abbreviate it'll take that sugar
converted a compound a then convert a
compound C then D then e then F and then
eventually it's turned into a
cannabinoid dozens of steps later as
outlined in this diagram right here
don't worry about the details literally
don't there's so many enzymatic pathways
and intermediate compounds but just know
that eventually that sugar through a
series of steps eight abcdefg z is made
into CB g and CB g is the precursor to
many Kanab
the way you can remember that is the the
it's the og it's the original
cannabinoid that then is made into THC
CBD etc okay and the reason this becomes
important is when we start talking about
how you can make bacteria produce
cannabinoids you've got to figure out
where in this sequence of steps can I
utilize the bacteria to produce to do
those steps and also keep in mind that
this is not happening in a vacuum so the
cell in the plant or any cell for that
matter it's like a little city and parts
of that cell are dedicated to producing
energy so it's like look at the local
coal plant producing energy for the
entire cell other parts of the cell are
factories they're producing certain
things in the case of certain cannabis
cells they're producing cannabinoids
right but there's also parts of the city
that are use for defense or for all of
this stuff so it's a very complicated
landscape and so but what if there's a
way that we could just take the
factories making cannabinoids and take
advantage of that one piece in the cell
and I'll talk more about that down the
road the other thing about cannabinoid
production and the cannabis plant I'm
sure as you all realize is it is not
optimized throughout the entire growth
phase of the cannabis plant you really
only get robust cannabis production or
cannabinoid production in a very
specific part of the cannabis plant
right the the floral parts and only in
unfertilized female flower so it's not
optimal that means you're kind of
wasting all this time in the plant phase
where it's not producing the real
compound you're interested in so how do
we optimize that and furthermore it's
only stored in this one small part of
the plant and the trichrome that's not
stored throughout the plant so now not
only are you limited to this kind of
time cycle of the plant you're really
only limited to a certain portion of the
plant and the reason cannabinoids are
stored in Tri Chrome's is number one
they're fat soluble so that they can't
really exist in the aqueous Lea no leaf
parts of the cannabis plant and they're
actually toxic to the plant that's why
they're stored in these protective
little bulbous orbs okay all right this
will all become more important in a
second now when you try to do an
extraction from the cannabis plant you
have
to spend a lot of time and energy to get
rid of all the other unwanted compounds
so when you do an initial extraction of
the cannabis plant you're basically
pulling things based on their chemical
properties so yes you pull cannabinoids
but at the same time you're gonna pull a
bunch of other stuff from the plant
because that other stuff has similar
properties chemical properties to the
cannabinoids and so you're in a pole
chlorophyll are gonna pull plant lipids
and waxes you're gonna pull other
cannabinoids you're gonna pull
flavonoids and all this junk and then
you have to go through all of these
steps to get rid of all of that extra
junk and that's gonna create a lot of
cost so how efficient is it when we use
the plant and we're just interested in a
handful of compounds we just spend all
this time and energy getting rid of all
the other stuff that came along for the
ride in the initial extraction so how do
we optimize for that okay so that's
putting that aside for a second let's
talk about some of the chemical are the
synthetic processes the non cannabis
plant processes that you can make
cannabinoids so there's chemical
synthesis where you're building things
in beakers you're not using living
systems
then there's cellular biosynthesis where
you're genetically engineering cells to
produce cannabinoids then there's
cell-free biosynthesis where you don't
even need the cell you don't need the
whole city I just want the one factory
in that city that makes cannabinoids how
do i harness that and I'll walk you
through each one of these ok so chemical
synthesis you have you know beakers you
don't have any living organisms and
you're just basically building one
molecular building block at a time
you're rebuilding your cannabinoid but
cannabinoid is a pretty complicated
molecule and so for all intents and
purposes chemical synthesis might not be
the most cost efficient way to do this
also it's not the most sustainable
because all of the reagents you have to
use at each step of your chemical
synthesis these are things that you
can't dispose of very readily and
furthermore this can be very inefficient
so when you're trying to each step of
this process you end up actually
creating a lot of similar but non
identical compounds so then you still
have to go through filtration and
separation and all of this stuff
so for the rest of this talk I'm not
going to talk about this too much
because I don't think this is the future
of cannabinoid production from both a
cost standpoint a sustainability
standpoint what gets much more
interesting is biosynthesis so the same
way that the cannabis plant takes sugar
walks it through a series of steps to
produce a cannabinoid we could engineer
a cell that exists in a bioreactor and
that cell can also take a sugar and walk
it through those same steps and output a
cannabinoid and then I don't have to
deal with growing this plant and all of
this stuff okay now before I talk more
about this let's talk about the history
of cellular biosynthesis there we go
so prior to the 1960s the way that we
treated diabetics was that we would take
animal pancreas mainly Pig pancreas we
grind it up and we'd extract the insulin
out of the pancreas and then we go
through a very complicated series of
steps of extraction and purification not
too different than what we do with
cannabis to produce roughly purified
insulin but it wasn't very pure it
wasn't very consistent you would give it
to patients and sometimes you would
create sometimes lethal reactions to it
because batch to batch it was different
the porcine pancreas is just like
cannabis plants are different batch to
batch and you really only wanted one
molecule that insulin but all this extra
stuff came along for the ride when you
did your extraction so you'd spend all
this time purifying all that other stuff
out so in the 60s they figured out a
better way to do this and it was
Genentech and this is what made them a
billion-dollar company so they said okay
let's figure out what is the actual DNA
strand in the human pancreas cell that's
responsible for insulin production let's
take out that piece of DNA and let's
stick it in a bacteria and then when we
boot up the bacteria lo and behold it
starts producing insulin so they
basically took a
one way to think about this is they took
they took the code they took the code
that codes for if there's like computer
software code they took the code that
codes for insulin out of the human cell
put it into a different you know
computer and then booted up that
computer and that computer is now
reading that code and doing what that
code is instructing and that's how we
got insulin and so then we never needed
to use animal pancreas again so this was
in this is 50 years ago so this is not
new technology biosynthesis bio
synthetic production of compounds all
right now let's take this one step
further and so these are some of the
companies that have popped up to try and
do this there's a lot of companies
working in this space next one next one
okay so what you know in theory this
sounds simple but I think there's a lot
of nuances in how companies are gonna go
about doing this
so first what type of microorganism
they're gonna use is gonna be bacteria
is it going to be a fungi is it going to
be algae and each back each type of
microorganism has its own peculiarities
what food you need to feed it
what type of trick does it grow well at
things like that how easy is it to
insert your DNA into that microorganism
what yeah exactly well input and output
so are you feeding it sugar and that
organism has been genetically engineered
to take sugar all the way down to
cannabinoid through dozens of steps or
are you feeding it an intermediary
compound so rather than feeding it a and
having a transform it to Z are you
feeding it like Q and it can take it to
Z then you have to go spend time and
energy creating q right ideally you'd be
able to give it sugar and take it all
the way through but that's gonna be very
tough because of all the steps involved
so it might be that you create a
moderately expensive intermediate
compound and then have the cell take it
all the way through than the last one
and then you know do these cells keep
all the contents
of them or can you engineer them to then
you know kick out the cannabinoids once
they're done because then it's even
easier to for you to get a hold of it
it's just floating in the aqueous
material you don't have to lyse the
cells burst the cells open and get the
compound of interest okay take it a step
further
remember the analogy I said about the
city so in the previous example we're
saying why don't we rebuild an entire
cellular city with its own life-support
system its own hospitals and Gardens and
roads and all this stuff and cannabinoid
factories or what if we just take
advantage of the one cannabinoid Factory
in the city and ditch the city and so
that's what one of our faculty at UCLA
has been working on so again
traditionally so instead of building the
city he just focuses on now it's working
it's called cell free biosynthesis he
just takes the enzymes the cellular
factories for cannabinoids puts those in
a bioreactor
and he's theoretically able to produce
cannabinoids this is still really really
early proof of concept stuff it's gonna
be years before it's it will know if
it's viable at scale but people are
working on this and again the advantages
are now you no longer have to deal with
the cells so not only we so we've jumped
from plant to you know bacteria and
bioreactor but that bacteria is still
fickle it produces waste products right
it needs and you need to feed it sugar
to keep it alive it produces all sorts
of other stuff
now with let's get rid of the cell let's
just have the factory and then it's just
super it only produces one thing and
there's no waste products it only
produces cannabinoids you don't really
need to feed it sugar to keep it alive
and so based off that he's created a
spin-out company in design all right so
to sum it up what are the kind of
advantages and disadvantages of this
approach so first off you and you Accu
can actually argue that this is more
environmentally sustainable than growing
the cannabis plant you don't need lots
of arable land you don't need lots of
water you don't need fertilizer you
don't need to spend all this time and
energy to grow the plant to only extract
out a small portion of it and then
purify that it could be potentially
cheaper I'll talk more about that later
it's a lot easier to scale so if I have
a hundred acre cannabis farm and I want
to 10x my output how quickly can I go
from a hundred acre cannabis farm to a
thousand acre cannabis farm that might
take me a couple years to ramp up that
capacity but if you're growing enough of
your synthetic creatures in a 10 liter
bioreactor the you can scale in a couple
months I just buy ten other bioreactors
and I stick it in a room and I'm ready
to go so it's a lot more scalable
potentially more consistent again my
cells are just producing the one thing
that I want I don't worry about dozens
hundreds of compounds that the cannabis
plants producing and it's more
continuous it's not like I have harvest
to harvest every month I could be
growing cells for a couple days at a
time and getting cannabinoids out of it
what are the downsides huge upfront Rd
cost right massive upfront R&amp;D costs and
there's regulatory issues how is this
regulated under medical marijuana laws
is it regulated under like where does
this even fall are you would you be
latest allowed to sell this over the
counter marketing issues consumers
clearly would be weirded out if you know
your vitamin was brought to you by some
bug in a bioreactor and what about all
the other potentially beneficial
compounds in the cannabis plant the
so-called entourage effect will you be
able to recreate that and I'll talk
about more on that issue later okay
let's talk about the cost considerations
because that's probably one of the
biggest advantages of this technology so
these are some these are some prices of
commonly used over-the-counter compounds
you can buy that are produced by
microorganisms and it looks pretty cheap
ten to fifty dollars a kilo for this is
basically fish oil penicillin and a
commonly used vitamin these are
microorganisms that they're using to
produce these so you look at the cost
and you're like holy shit for a kilo
that's really cheap right so clearly
this process over the last 50 years that
we've been you know designing these
bacteria or microorganisms is we can get
the price down pretty low
all right now let's talk about betta
carry off Lane right it's a terpene
found in the cannabis plants also found
in things like black pepper you can buy
naturally derived relatively pure beta
carry off lane depending on how much
quantity you can buy anywhere from 20 to
150 bucks a kilo
you can also buy synthetic beta carry
awfully NAND it's cheaper however that
took the fact that synthetic beta carry
awfully exists and is cheaper than the
naturally derived carrot beta carry off
Lane it did not completely take down
demand for natural beta carefully and
that's because the makers of herbal
products or fragrance companies they a
lot of them self you know affirm that
they only want a source for natural
products so the the the appearance of a
cheaper synthetic source did not just
end the discussion even though these are
commodities these are fungible things
the the beta carotene is going to do the
exact same thing whether its derive
synthetically or naturally okay whatever
so let's talk about let's compare CBD
versus what bio synthetic CBD might look
like the reason I choose CBD derive from
hemp is that's probably what the cost of
THC would also look like if marijuana
cannabis were allowed to be grown you
know outdoor 10,000 acres at a time so
whatever price point that we can kind of
theoretically arrive at for CBD that is
what and a what THC will look like to
once it's grown at scale outdoors as you
kind of see happening countries like
Colombia and stuff and so what you find
is that you could get the price down
from anywhere from tens of dollars to
hundreds of dollars per kilo of
substantially pure CBD derived from hemp
grown at scale how did I arrive at that
number if you look at opium opioids so a
lot of the opioids that we still use in
the pharmaceutical sector are actually
derived from opium plants grown in
places like India and then they go and
they extract out the active compounds
purify it and put into a pharmaceutical
pill and that those opium products they
sell
even though they're naturally plant
arrived they sell for you knows tens of
tens of dollars per kilo maybe a hundred
dollars per kilo and that's when they're
grown at large scale and you have a full
supply chain to back it up so again
approaching that price point it would
look very similar to what we see with
opium on the biosynthetic side you're
also gonna get in that range that's
because you can look at many other bio
synthetic compounds that are sold in the
nutraceutical sector that approached
that similar price point that have
similar chemical structures to
cannabinoids but now keep in mind this
is you know I'm not gonna pigeonhole
myself and give you a narrow estimate
cuz then in a few years I'll look bad if
it's wrong right so just don't don't
ever predict anything in public it's
what somebody taught me so I'm giving
you a huge range here but I want you to
see that it's comparable right and that
there's a good chance that you know bio
synthetic could be five times cheaper
maybe more right depending on where in
this range it falls now if you're
talking about deriving it deriving
cannabinoids from the plant clearly CBD
is going to be the first cannabinoid to
reach an incredibly low cost because of
wide scale hemp then it'll be followed
by THC eventually as for the other minor
cannabinoid I don't know if we'll ever
get to that point just because the
current supply of cannabis genetics you
don't have plants that are 25 percent
THC V or CBD or all of this so for the
minor cannabinoids I don't it's probably
not going to get to this price point
scan hoping to be significantly higher
and so for the minor cannabinoids I
think it's highly likely that bio
synthetic will be kind of the reigning
way to produce the minor cannabinoids
and that's because it's gonna cost the
same whether you're trying to produce
THC V or THC in terms of the bio
synthetic realm it's just what you're
changing is that you're slightly
modifying the DNA sequence that you're
putting into the cells depending on what
cannabinoid you want to produce so if if
you're talking about just pure
individual cannabinoids and the bio
synthetic process can trump the plant
derived on cost alone is it is it game
over right these are
things are commodities they're identical
and if you look at traditional economics
whenever you have commodity pricing and
you know the price points go down to
where nobody's making any profit and so
is that the case well I think I think
there's another possibility we haven't
explored yet that's gonna give it's
gonna give the plant some kanabrocki get
it rocky come on so I think the plant
the plant has still got a shot the plant
still got a shot I'll tell you why okay
so here's why you we can get what we
haven't gotten very creative with ways
to grow the plant or ways to change the
the metabolism of the plant and how it
produces these cannabinoids so there's
one company trait Biosciences and what
they have or what they're working on
figuring out they've already filed some
patents but what they are trying to get
the cannabis plant to attach a sugar
molecule to the cannabinoids that it
produces by attaching a simple sugar
molecule to the cannabinoids they
suddenly become water-soluble that has
many implications so first off you're
gonna get higher yields and that's
because now that the cannabinoids are
water-soluble they can exist throughout
the plant they're not just stuck in the
Tri Chrome's on outside of the plant
extraction becomes a lot easier to
remember what I said extractions
expensive because you're trying to grab
for the cannabinoids but you end up
grabbing all the other things that have
similar chemical properties the fats the
lipids other cannabinoids flavonoids etc
if you have one cannabinoid in your
entire plant that's water soluble you
you don't even need to use like ethanol
and stuff you could you do water
extraction right
and lastly potentially ease of
formulation if the cannabinoids already
water-soluble they'll mix better into
beverages they might even absorb it'll
they probably will absorb better as well
into your body okay and so the other
really interesting kind of game-changing
piece oh and this is the company trade
Biosciences and so another really
interesting implication of this is that
because you're no longer beholden to the
Tri Chrome's
you also no longer beholden to the
flowering of the cannabis plant so you
could theoretically yeah
could we just take the plant and veg it
and you could just veg it all day all
day you're just vegging the cannabis
plant it grows up a couple you just cut
it down it grows up you cut it down it
grows up you credit down how many years
have have you had maybe mother plants
last for years years you don't have to
worry about you know nursery clone take
it to flower then the whole thing dies
and I do it all over again you just have
one room that every couple weeks you
harvest and you never need to throw it
into flower you don't need light
deprivation you'd have to deal with any
of that it's because the cannabinoids
are being abundantly produced throughout
the plant again now whether they can
actually scale this technology is one
thing but they've they've managed to do
it at small-scale and file some patents
around it okay let's talk about the
effectiveness of all of this so again
whether it's synthetic or its natural
it's gonna do the same thing okay the
real question is what else is actually
in the plant so CBD is a good example
where you hear people say CBD CBD from
cannabis isn't as effective as CBD from
hemp but the CBD is the same it's gonna
do the same thing the real question is
what else is accompanying the CBD if
you're if you're talking about a hemp
product it's not gonna have a lot of THC
right and so let's talk about that this
notion of of whole plant and so this is
a study where they gave my Speer CBD and
they measured inflammation the higher
the bars are the more inflammation there
is so what they found was at a low dose
of CBD you still had a lot of
inflammation at this middle dose of CBD
you lowered inflammation as you increase
the dose again the inflammation returned
right so this is not good there's a very
narrow window of efficacy so if you're
dosing a patient that's not good that
was done with pure CBD then they did the
exact same study with a high CBD extract
and they matched it so that both mice
got the same amount of CBD but this
group got all the other stuff that came
along for the ride with
whole plant extract and what they found
was that the more you gave of that
extract that you had a nice reduction
and inflammation without that rebound at
the end so again what's going on here
we're not quite sure what compounds in
the extract are responsible for this
arguably superior dose response curve we
don't know okay that's the mystery that
we got to tease apart here's another
study where they took breast cancer
cells in a petri dish and they applied
THC pure THC to one and they applied a
high THC extract to the other and what
they what they found was that yes the
pure THC was able to inhibit some key
cell cancer cell growth but the high THC
cannabis extract at the same level of
THC was able to have significantly more
anti-cancer effect and again is it of
the dozens or hundreds of other
compounds present in the cannabis
extract which ones responsible for this
increased effect is it two of them is it
twenty of them is it two hundred you
know that's what we're trying to figure
out right now as a scientific community
alright last thing regulatory
considerations and I'll open up for Q&amp;A
so there's a big mess right now over
marketing of food products like people
throw out terms you know artificial
ingredients all natural all this stuff a
lot of those labels aren't well
regulated right now like the FDA doesn't
have an official definition of what is
actually all-natural
however despite that despite there being
unclear regulation the FTC the Federal
Trade Commission has independently gone
after companies and sued them because
they made an all-natural claim that was
interpreted as deceiving the consumer so
now you start talking about if you were
if you were able to derive cannabinoids
from other sources would you ever be
able to claim your product was
all-natural no artificial ingredients
that right what does that landscape look
like and also people have gone around
lawyers will go around filing
class-action lawsuits against companies
that inappropriately label as well so
it's not just the government cracking
down its individual groups of lawyers
who will organize class-action lawsuits
against companies and so you're saying
you know over half of consumers are
motivated to purchase by the all-natural
claim that
not going away anytime soon and and soon
in the next couple years the FDA will
finally define what it actually means to
be all-natural on a product label so
then we'll actually have some strict
rules and guidance frito-lay recently
pulled the all-natural claims on their
products waiting until the FDA
officially puts in its ruling so again
the the companies are taking notice of
this and I think a couple years ago
Subway dropped all artificial
ingredients from their food including
synthetically made versions of naturally
occurring compounds so they went with
these slightly more expensive natural
produced compounds so again this is a
trend that's not going away all right so
last thing to think about is depending
on where you source your cannabinoids it
might impact where you're able to sell
it okay so if you are deriving CBD from
cannabis you'll be able to sell it into
the cannabis space that's clear but if
you and when I say cannabis I mean
marijuana cannabis not hemp right if
you're driving CBD from cannabis you
probably won't be able to sell it into
the nutraceutical space right
it's highly likely that the cannabis
anything produced in the cannabis
ecosystem is going to stay sold in a
highly regulated system and it's
possible you'll be able to sell it into
the pharmaceutical sector in a very
regimented fashion and that's what GW
pharmaceutical does they grow cannabis
in the UK they extract out the CBD
purify it drop it in some oil and sell
it as epidural I was recently FDA
approved so that's a possible viable
path what if you're deriving your CBD
from hemp okay so probably you're not
going to be able to sell it into the
cannabis space and that's because the
cannabis industry has its own kind of
protectionist measures that they can
take you probably will be able to sell
it depending on which government
jurisdiction you're in and to the
nutraceutical sector and you probably
will be able to sell it into the
pharmaceutical sector and you are seeing
pharma companies that are getting ready
to source hemp derived purified CBD for
drug trials but this is this is clearly
probably not going to happen because you
have all of these cannabis businesses
we paid all this money taxes now you're
gonna let hem cvd be sold you know and
mixed into cannabis products that
doesn't seem fair right it's gonna drop
that's gonna put downward price pressure
on us and now for the last one by a cent
that exceed e where does this fall let's
play a game actually all right what do
we think are they gonna sell it into the
cannabis space yeah or day no probably
not for same reason self protectionist
measures there's jobs at stake right so
now that all these states have dropped
it like are we gonna suddenly replace
all these jobs on these farms now that
we're gonna allow this stuff what about
the nutraceutical sector what do you
guys think ene it's question mark right
there's other examples of bio
synthetically made products that do
exist in nature but made by bacteria
that are sold in vitamins and
supplements that is exist right so it's
possible depending on how regulators
decide to allow it what about bio
synthetic CBD for the pharmaceutical
sector that's probably the most relevant
use case and these guys want really
really really purified product right so
that probably makes the most sense so
key takeaways and we'll wrap it up the
bio synthetic route is going to be
cheaper most likely but the one area
where it might be comparable is maybe
hemp derived CBD because just you could
grow that so large-scale and
industrialize it but for all the other
cannabinoids bio synthetic is probably
gonna win on cost especially for the
minor cannabinoids there is clear
evidence of an entourage effect and that
and therefore you might not get that if
you're just producing one single
compound of bio synthetic ly consumer
perception of what your compound is
clearly is important today it will
continue to be important going forward
and now there are regulations coming in
to actually define what is all-natural
how is that going to impact that and the
source of where your cannabinoid is
likely going to impact your permissible
sales channels so as you can see there's
a lot of considerations at play as to
what the future of cannabinoid
production you can leave that there will
look like so in terms of wrapping this
up in the game of cannabinoids is it you
know is it more like you know a civil
war where like the u.s. Civil War we
just lined up troops on each side and
you just
like hit at each other all day long till
one side gives up right you're just
competing on cost who can who get what's
the race to the bottom I don't think
it's like that
I think this game is more like game of
drones yes right where it's like there's
a lot there's like subterfuge and you
have like spies and like they have an
army of like Knights but you have like
dragons and there's like magic and
that's and that's because there's so
many factors at play cost is one
consideration we talked about cost we
talked about effectiveness we talked
about consumer perception we talked
about regulatory permissible pathways
for sales so that is how I see the game
of cannabinoids and I'll open it up for
Q&amp;A
so hand in the back of first and then
excellent talk very thought-provoking
any idea about how you see this being
given to patients is it going to be
patch oral and can you comment a little
bit about formulations and
bioavailability great question so IIIi
think oral is probably not going to be a
great way to deliver cannabinoids for a
very medical purpose and that's just
because the the rate of the absorption
so variable and so erratic and so that's
where things like some sort of a or some
sort of sublingual delivery or OA
mucosal delivery could be interesting
transdermal could be a very interesting
route that's very standardized and
stable and it's interesting I actually
think there's a role for inhalation in
some form
definitely not combustion but maybe some
form of vapor vaporization or some form
of aerosolization that's because it's
just a very consistent quick easy way to
deliver cannabinoids but I think in
terms of oral just like take some
cannabis extract put in a pill I don't
think it's ever going to be what I'm
what a medical product would be
recognized as just because it's too it's
too inconsistent in its effect
Thanks thank you questions about CVD
products and label claims versus maybe
drug claims of delivery and efficacy and
maybe onset and in your opinion is that
a safer way for a company to you know
kind of Trent like go through their
operations as opposed to what happened
like key relief recently where they had
to rescind a lot of their claims on CBD
in hemp and I think you know that has a
lot to do with the PC services you were
saying yeah so the reason you can't make
any claims on CBD is because it's it's
an FDA approved pharmaceutical drug and
so you know you can't make any sort of
you can make wellness I mean this is
true of any nutraceutical you can make
like wellness claims so rather than like
treats your insomnia it's like for a
good night's rest right that's kind of
how you have to phrase stuff so yeah so
so and yeah so the short answer is
disease claimed no it's not gonna be
possible
it won't be possible for THC either
because THC has been FDA approved since
1986 in the form of Marinol 50 yeah
uh-huh yeah so you have to stay away
from disease claims unless you're
willing to go down the pharmaceutical
drug development pipeline oh
drug delivery claim drug onset claim
that's interesting that is a little
better you have a little more leeway
there like for quicker onset use our
dissolvable tablets that is do you have
a little more leeway there because
you're not making a disease claim
something different so excellent talk
but i think it's interesting that you
were looking for a single winner when
you clearly defined in your talk three
different channels to sell it so I can
see a world where there's three winners
but and I can see more than that because
as you said the abundance of certain
cannabinoids and other compounds in the
plant is different and so you're right
you so can you see a world where there's
there are winners that are different in
each of the commercial channels and how
much do you think the government so for
example for the pharmaceutical Channel
how much do you think the
da's perception of these compounds
influences things because as a drug
developer I'll let you know that my
paperwork is significantly less
complicated if I use a synthetic homolog
of something yeah so to answer your
first question clear like clearly you
could you could very quickly be like
alright anything derived from cannabis
is gonna float around in the cannabis
industry anything derived from hemp will
just go to nutraceutical and then all
the synthetic stuff goes pharmaceutical
but like I said there's a ton of
crosstalk you have pharma companies who
are willing and ready to source
synthetic a hemp derived CBD and that's
and GW Pharmaceuticals the one company
that has an fda-approved CBD they grow
the cannabis plant themselves and they
create extracts from it so there's tons
of crosstalk so I think it would be a
bit too it wouldn't do it full justice
to just do with those three lanes now in
terms of what you said about perception
yeah it makes it a lot more difficult
when you're trying to go to the FDA and
say hey you know approve my drug I
guarantee you it's gonna be consistent
batch to batch for the next 50 years oh
and by the way I like derive it from a
plant and I take it through all these
purification and extraction processes
that's there that's kind of foreign to
them and they have a lot more scrutiny
over those processes they want to make
sure you're growing the plant identical
each time and that you can reliably
reproduce that so it does add
considerable difficulty can you speak to
the various CBD formulations and how
they'll work with food products so can
you can you clarify the question a
little more well the government seems to
be at odds about whether it's going to
allow CBD into food products and it's
going back and forth so I'm just
wondering if these various CBD
formulations Morello I see yeah so the
only the only shot of you selling CBD
into the as a food product a.k.a dietary
ingredient is if it's derived from hemp
that's the only basis you have any
ground to stand on period don't even
talk about anything outside that's not
going to be allowed the FDA actually is
perfectly correct when they say you
cannot sell CBD in food
and that's because as soon as CBD
entered clinical trials with GW they
created basically a moratorium and
that's why you can't sell this stuff and
the food product it's a pharmaceutical
drug GW staked its kind of flagpole on
it so it's it's it's actually very clear
that that's not the case now because the
FDA is under so much political pressure
from all of the folks who backed hemp as
a way to revitalize rural communities
predominantly Republican rural
communities that's why the FDA is now
willing to make a concession because of
this intense political pressure on them
to allow CBD so that the hemp farmers
can actually grow a valuable crop this
is nothing to do with you know them it's
all economic development of these rural
communities that's the driving factor
behind these conversations right now in
terms of the formulations for the food
products yeah it's really it's the hemp
derived stuff that's gonna be there you
I mean going forward here's likely
what's gonna happen is the FDA will come
in and say okay here's the maximum
amount of CBD you can put into a pill or
a bottle
it cannot be overly purified beyond this
percentage so keeping it more of a hemp
extract as opposed to a pure CBD which
that's clearly a pharmaceutical drug and
maybe you have to go through these
testing labs that we've done some we've
given them a license to certify that
your CBD product is accurate I suspect
that's somewhere where the FDA might
fall in the coming months and years as
they figure out the regulation we have
one more question okay great
presentation Thanks
question is have you seen any studies
that you know they're talking about
reintroducing terpenes and the entourage
effect have you seen any studies that
deal with the increased or decreased
efficacy of of terpenes when they're
reintroduced versus naturally occurring
short answer no and that's only because
we have been there's literally I could
count on one hand the number of studies
that have compared
pure cannabinoid to cannabis extract
head-to-head so we don't even really
know if the entourage effect if it's
like how real it is or like when it
actually occurs and we don't even we
remotely understand and start comparing
you know a
ahem extract versus one that was like
fractionated and then reconstituted into
a specific combination we're not we're
not there yet I will say though DeeDee
Murray out of Israel has done some
studies where he takes a whole extract
cannabis extract and he'll sequentially
break it into chunks and what he's
trying to do is to arrive at the minimum
amount of compounds from that full
extract that recreate the full extracts
effects and in one particular cancer
cell line he was looking at he found
that it came down to four it was four
ingredients that he isolated that when
combined could recreate the whole plant
extract but that's for these cancer cell
lines maybe for other disorders you need
less maybe you need more so I was just
curious if you know of any
pharmaceutical companies growing
cannabis so that it will have a higher
amount of minor cannabinoids you were
talking about that may be the future
yeah so it's not so much pharmaceutical
companies to my knowledge there's only
like one pharmaceutical company growing
cannabis its GW I think all the
pharmaceutical companies now are just
gonna work with and purchase their
cannabinoids from cannabis companies
predominately right now Canadian
cannabis companies because they're
creating kind of like the cleanest most
pharmaceutical grade stuff in terms of
your question which was minor
cannabinoids yes it's not so much pharma
companies it's all these cannabis
genetic companies breeders they're all
scrambling to get these rare genetics
that have high amounts of these minor
cannabinoids and it's because you know
what does this see what is a kilo of CBD
isolate sell for right now five thousand
dollars
what is a kilo CBG isolate sell for
right now or THC V a hundred grand fifty
to a hundred grand
right it's that much more valuable
because it's so rare so yeah so it's
really the breeder is the plant breeders
in genetic genetics guys right now are
scrambling to find those genetics they
realize how valuable it is okay
all right great thank you guys