hey my name is cody and i want to give
you guys
my version of a garden tour we're about
45 minutes south of chicago in the
midwest
and i just want to share some views i'm
not trying to show off i don't pretend
to be any kind of authority
i don't think any kind of growing style
like i don't think my style is better
than any other
i just want to show what works for me at
least what's working this season
where i am and uh i don't know hopefully
somebody out there needs to see this
i know maybe a couple years ago i wasn't
so sure that this
style would work where we are so
i'd like to see a video like this so
i do want to say thank you to future
cannabis project you guys are an
outstanding resource
the content you provide the speakers the
conversations they're bar none
especially when everybody's stuck
indoors so thank you so much for
allowing me to contribute
and i just really appreciate it
all right now one thing that's always
been fascinating to me it's always
been important is genetics
and selections and who's making those
selections
so i've always been interested in
breeding
everybody's lines that i choose to grow
they all seem to have very big heart
they put it forward with passion they
want to help people
and those are things that i personally
align with so that's what i choose to
grow
i also have been hobby breeding for a
couple years now
and then actually rizzo aka reached out
when he saw a male i selected
and i got to collaborate with him so we
have some stuff in testing
but yeah it's such a blast i don't don't
know how to explain how exciting it is
when something you make
gets uh grown by a friend that is in
need
um yeah hopefully hopefully more good
things to come from that
if you see i've got different sized
plants here
part of that is going to be when they
were transplanted
a lot of these smaller ones here
specifically are for the breeding
projects i have going
they are cuttings that have been tried
and true
and um like this season i found a really
nice
royal wedding mail right here we have
two royal wedding females
both from seeds so they are sisters and
royal wedding is from emerald mountain
legacy
if you don't know who they are please go
look them up
they're doing fantastic out here now i
am dry farming
and when i say that i just mean i do not
have irrigation and i am not watering
i did give them three solo cups of water
when i transplanted
and i also inoculated with mycorrhizae
and also used some super worm frass but
i'm not convinced those two steps are
entirely necessary
however they do seem to be happy they
might be
best looking plants in the garden now
you tell me
definitely very very happy cannot wait
to see how it goes
i plan on doing some fresh frozen help
friend and his family
what else can i say you know this one
got knocked down
and the cage sort of ripped open the
stem there
now i took curry powder made a paste
with some water
and put that inside where it was split
and it seemed to heal right over it's
just anti-bacterial anti-pathogenic
and that's something i picked up from
rising moon farms
if you don't follow rising moon go check
him out
and he's also a breeder he's a grows
hemp he grows
cannabis let's see what else
this is mother's milk
from bodhi it's going to be napoli og
crossed
appalachia
we have sour dub
this is gorilla glue rest in peace josie
strawberry banana og
this is nor kale dositos
and a paradise circus
just let her do her own thing
this is the mountain cut of tropicana
cookies
i can touch briefly on what i did for
ipm this season
i leaned heavily on last coast plant
therapy with weekly
applications and once the pistols
went from lashes to more like palms
as my friend would say i stopped
spraying
and started to lean on these green lace
swing
eggs that are on these hangers here well
they were
and yeah
very minimal you will see some pests you
will see some damage
this plant
it's one that i really like looking at
it's really pretty it seems to be just
soaking up the sun
but this plant is black lime reserve
across the chem 91 death star
i got these as a seed at the organic
regenerative conference
from buckwheat and that dude is an
amazing artist
he's a breeder he's a grower
check him out go on ig
underscore understood buckwheat and look
for
green triangle thanks so much thanks
again
this tent does not have much going on
i'm not really sure what happened this
is gmo on the back
and right away i was going to lean
heavily in this tent this is what was
going to be my main thing
and immediately could tell something was
wrong
i let it go i sprayed with plant therapy
just kind of want to see what would
happen here
someone can chime in tell me what is the
deal
i appreciate it right here we have
another
gorilla glue looks like it's
starting to show seeds here nice
okay this plant
is a sister it's another
royal wedding
but it has a totally different leaf
morphology
kind of likes to emphasize the middle
three
and she's definitely the furthest along
for flower starting to really smell just
really nice
we had a day of clouds and a little bit
of rain
and then last night it rained so they're
all
looking pretty happy right now
here we have another paradise circus
some of these big ones were actually mom
they weren't my mom's i should say
i had power outage for four days and
decided to do a round of cuttings and
put these bigger ones outside i thought
it'd be easier to take care of the
smaller ones
so far so good
sour dub
this one's interesting this is a bag
seed
and it's going to be valley girl valley
girl is
sfv og cross faceoff lg i believe
and so far so good
always check the lowers and everything
and so far
nothing to write home about
don't see any signs of
unhappiness but maybe i got lucky maybe
it just isn't unhappy yet
those things can sure hide
here i have two different
panama pupils that's mass medical
strains
we gave out some freebies last year my
friends
split the pack and gave me half and so
far so good
this one is obviously tighter
flower structure looks more like what i
see pupil pictures look like
so maybe it'll turn purple as we get
cooler here
and this one has more of a maybe a
cherry sort of a smell kind of a hemp
smell
it's also very pretty really like the
also really like how the leaves will
track the sun if you come in the evening
it'll be just drooped down like it needs
water
if you come in the morning it's angled
totally sideways same with the evening
and sort of middle of the day like this
it's just all over so that's very cool
to watch then you know what guys i think
that brings us to
what i might be the most excited about i
don't know i'm just super stoked i'm
really glad i get to talk about it
so this
is unreal to me this is a test line
that i was very fortunate to be sent
and it is cashmere 22
across to a pure vintage afghani
how cool is that what do you guys think
genetics from middle east
growing illinois
in this dry soil like i said it just
rained but this soil really is
it's dry
and also another one i'm super excited
about is this
i wonder if you could guess from the tag
we got
b triangle pu i guess
it's going to be black triangle cross
purple unicorn f3
again how awesome i mean i give thanks
this
is just too cool thank you so much to
bodhi
and his family for sending this test
line
both test lines
i mean i've heard nothing but good
things about black triangle and nothing
but good things about purple unicorn
have not gotten a try either
so man i'm not trying to show off but
i do feel very fortunate
all right to wrap this up i'd like to
say thank you thank you to peter from
future cannabis project
thank you to leighton morrison and
joshua rutherford
putting on the organic conference it
wasn't for you i'd probably still be
playing with
dwc buckets somewhere and i want to say
thank you kevin jodry
i want to say thank you to hedy medy
farms thanks again to buckwheat
thanks again to rizzo ak thank you to ak
bean brains
i say thank you to dragonfly earth
medicine i want to say thank you to
shango los and heavy days
uh there's so many more i am
so sorry if i forgot you but really i
give
thanks it's all gratitude and i hope you
enjoyed this
if you'd like to follow me you can go on
instagram
th e underscore i l underscore
g a n j i e r
and once again thank you so much for
checking this out