[Music]
we just watched a panel on tissue
culture and one of the very last
comments was that in like three to five
years breeding will be done at a
molecular level like other plants and
that the role of the current breeder who
basically breeds actual plants won't
really exist so I think there is gonna
be a lot of people that you know
breeders breeders now I mean it's a lot
of people say they're breeders a lot of
pollen chuckers you know a little pollen
chucking is going on people just
backyard breeding not doing any
selection I think those type of people
yeah they're they're gonna be done but I
feel like the actual breeders they did
the real ones right now they're relevant
will still be relevant in five years I
think they have that potential it's you
know it's kind of like they're gonna
work beside my vision is they'll work
side by side with the guys that are
doing molecular to help you know
understand and develop the SOPs kind of
drive drive the breeding because I feel
like it's a kind of swore thing you know
maybe I'll be proven wrong but I really
I really you know being a breeder I sure
hope I'm still relevant five years yeah
I mean I agree I think instead of
working with plants you'll be working
with scientists sure but you'll still be
relevant in the same way you're relevant
and turn like with plants you're still
the one to say we we bred it we grew it
out I approve that's good shit yeah like
that scientist dude or the business guy
in that well in me I won't be the one to
make that decision I'm probably not
going to be breeding the high THC or the
minor cannabinoid you know breeding
projects that some people will be able
to do with molecular processes you know
the caste 9 and CRISPR and stuff like
that yeah that's that's not my expertise
but working with those people and
helping them understand the plant I feel
like
they're stuffed it's gonna work
synergistically I feel like a lot of
people were afraid of crisper and cast 9
and the kind of direction that that's
going in you know these people GMO
they're freaked out about genetically
modifying stuff but I feel like they're
they've been doing in hops they've been
doing it a lot of things and I'm really
interested to kind of see what it drinks
talk about the man who just passed and
his contribution what he means to you
and his legacy as a breeder so it's
funny because his impact was so great
and I feel like most people can't even
really comprehend how big of an impact
nevels contributions were it took me an
actual date or right opposed about
Instagram because I really want to think
about you know all the stuff all the
work he's done and you know the
development of haze strains you know
solely responsible for a lot of it
Neville haze super Silver Haze the
development with green house was super
Silver Haze I mean that's dream its
impact he changed generations you know
and he affected you know on a large
scale more than anybody else in the
industry anything else that anybody's
done like his contributions are greater
you know and we may so he's like the
what is it the jingis con is like his
DNA is attacked because he had sex with
so many she's like a genius kind of
canopy on Europe especially you know and
I feel like people in the states don't
really have an appreciation for Hays and
most people that have seen it haven't
seen it ground properly they like over
in Europe if you've been able to spend
time in Europe in you know Amsterdam the
Netherlands in Spain in Italy even like
you'll see haze or you'll see haze
isolator or hashes and you know growing
properly is some of the most amazing you
know amazing strains on the earth it's a
but it's funny because haze is a
particular thing that not everybody
agrees with because our bodies are so
unique it's something like my wife is
not a huge haze fan although she's big
and it's like if she'll smoke a little
bit of haze so she can
the house stuff like that well yeah and
then other people it's like too much for
them so it's really interesting the
direction it's gone and I feel like we
have guys like short Brooks and Mojave
and karma and these guys are gonna kind
of continue with the breeding I mean
I've done breeding with super silver and
would like to get so especially after
Neville's passing we'd like to get some
more genetics back into like the mix as
well but yeah so I believe shorts doing
a huge breeding project on Hayes
specifically isolating some phenotypes
they're doing a huge Dino hunts down in
Arizona like if you reflect on him was
he like a mentor yeah I think I think
were you friends with him too you know
but I felt his impacts you know and I I
just I've appreciated the boys
impressive lineage you know and yeah
it's it's one thing that's you know it's
affected you know I feel like chem dog
also is another strain that was a bad
seed by the way
haze was actually developed I feel like
there's a handful of real breeders out
there that have really bred the plant
and worked with the plant and improve
the genetics over time Neville's one of
them Simon from serious seeds actually
took from like p1 landraces
he started with two land races created
real F ones most people think like f1 is
something we see every day but it's what
we're seeing these f1 poly hybrids that
have really complex genetics in them you
know and a lot of over breeding then
with specific strains like og and
cookies now it's kind of what's
happening I think the interesting thing
back over in Europe especially in the
Netherlands is there was a time where
haze just dominated everything people
found it they fell in love with it and
it went from these really long flowering
Hayes's to amnesia but it was still haze
for a long time it's interesting to kind
of see like the fragmentation globally
of cannabis like what people appreciate
like you're saying in Europe they
appreciate things that here people just
it's
subjective it's just like real Moroccan
hash or red Lebanon like the red
Lebanese or you know any of these
different hashes like we don't
appreciate them in the States we don't
really have access to them like they do
in here but uh you know our standards
are very different and what we think of
as quality is so different and that's
one thing that makes Canada so beautiful
is it's so subjective just like food
food wine beer it's so subjective to the
actual individuals that there's almost
something for everybody
ya know my my introduction to hash was I
lived in France for two years the first
year was in high school when I was 16 so
I was like by myself no family you're
drinking and then like you're not
smoking weed you're smoking spliff
Moroccan hash with yeah tobacco and as
someone who smokes weed that shit
knocked me out like I couldn't handle it
I don't normally smoke tobacco but just
everything everything well the other
thing is like there is never any weed
around no you're talking about like
stuff they're growing and a breeze or
have grown and appreciate in Europe and
in my head I'm like where was it all cuz
coffee shops coffee
you know Spain it was available in Spain
but it was really people were in the
shadows for a long time until the last
five years when people started opening
coffee got coffee shops with social
clubs in Spain you know it's it's really
and it's funny because the quality has
just progressed so much in Spain whereas
Amsterdam is kind of stagnating it's
regressed well it really hasn't grown I
feel like I went to Amsterdam for the
first time in five years and when I went
back it was almost exactly the same
coffee shop same layout all my
restaurants pretty much we're still
there so really interesting red light
was a lot smaller I'm still thinking
about like being 16 and then
yeah it was probably think mostly was
mixing the tobacco yeah so I smoked
chili I don't smoke tobacco at all so my
friend was diagnosed with esophageal
cancer last year and so I quit tobacco
completely no once you know just no
tobacco I don't you know I don't need it
and it doesn't really give me joy and if
it's bad for me why would I consume it
so cigar is nice yeah why so I have a
humidor that has 500 cigars but if
you're not smart idea every time people
come over my house I give them cigars
but I quit smoking and then I go to
Europe and my friends like you want
smoke kill them and I'm like well I
don't smoke tobacco but fuck it let's
let's do it it's you know and it's
basically sterile to a degree the
tobacco that goes in there it's just a
you know it's like a little basket to
put the hash in when you're smoking it
but it still gets you really high like
that's some of the most high I've ever
in my life is from smoking chilling with
friends my whole point like I went from
like so I went in high school and then
again in college and it was like you're
like I smoked a lot of weed and then you
go there and and we would go I'd go out
with my French friends and before we go
into a club we'd smoke yeah and I'd be
like you know what I'm just gonna hang
out in the car you guys go in the club
like I couldn't move and they're like
all right dude you're sure you're cool
in the car like see you later and be
like now I'm good yeah it's a trip but
most of those guys can't hang with us
pure smokers right so like they're like
they'll take a hit at the pier there and
that's it for the day well yeah and I
really appreciate I get to smoke to 20
year old Moroccan when I was in Spain
yeah Martin barrows clubs so this brings
me to the Frenchy comment of hash gets
better with age so and go and go I don't
it's a 20 year old house
we smoked 20 year-old Moroccan it was
held by a Moroccan that was there and
it tasted good it tasted fair it didn't
have a lot of flavor I feel like it
loses something you know like I feel
like it just like wine wine has an
expiration date where it goes over and
they even red wine so it was smooth but
there wasn't a lot to it it wasn't like
that
I like that fresh creamy especially that
creamy smoke that you get from really
good hash but since the sample size was
one you'd almost need like a hundred
different sort of hashes to be stored
for twenty years and then to see if some
of them like because like with red wine
some peek seven years later seven to ten
somewhere like tell you can the lipid
content there are so many different
things like you're looking at lipids the
tract the terpenes that are in there
terpenes will help degrade it depending
on what type of terpenes are in there
but you know I think the sweet point
that I know the cat's point is two years
I smoked some two-year-old Moroccan hash
that was probably the best hash I've
ever smoked no and right up there with
in strength-wise right up there with the
best Isolators that I've smoked but but
so to Frenchie's point that's huge
because that means that here's a product
within the cat the broad cannabis
product sweet yeah that actually gets
better with age yeah and Frenchy creates
a boutique product it's like you just
don't see it it's a it's a it's it's a
lost art there's people definitely that
are trying to carry it out but it's like
glittery but trees another one of those
things how many peopie debauchery but
how many people do you know that they
know how to breakdown animal well it's
also I think one of the interesting
things I learned about butchery is like
in the u.s. supermarket we have all
these generic cuts but there's like
innovation and cuts right and like we we
only gravitate to like five six
different cuts that it's like finally
understanding that there are more cuts
than the ones I always see in the
grocery store yeah and that they're
actually pretty cool I'm good
when everywhere you go in the world the
cuts are different like being at you go
over to Europe they're completely
different from over here and then
they're called different things and the
way they section is
a little bit differently but you know I
totally forget why we were on the top
again it's that Girl Scout cookies but
uh no so we were talking about it
because French connote Frenchie yeah
it's a dying art it's something that
will be preserved by some but only a
handful you know it's like these people
are stewards of the lost art of - making
what so I mean he's doing his courses so
do you feel like in those court like he
spent what I love about his story is the
way I understand it is here's this crazy
old French dude who spent 40 years like
a hummingbird going to every hash
producing region of the world and
learning each of their respective hash
making total methodologies and then
which none of them do like Moroccans
aren't hanging out in Thailand you're
right he's like the one guy in the world
who's actually done that and now can
synthesize like what do you like it's
it's like an MMA fighter who's fluent
and like wrestling my Thai kick boxing
Wing Chun in the quality of his stuff I
mean the price of it speaks for itself
you know if you're looking at buying it
on the on the rec market in California
that you know it's you know it's tans up
there right with the best like live
resin extraction bubble you know there's
only these things in the quality it's
just amazing all right so you so talk
about the things in the non flour
category that you're smoking unlike in
oh I got some live rosin is my new
favorite well you know it's just puff Co
yeah yeah give a little plug will give a
little plug
maybe they'll hook me up with one of
these someday so this is live Rosco so I
get some know this is actually a butane
that has the diamond separated a little
bit this is live rosin right here I
talked to John Mackay nice John Mackay
good friend really nice guy work with
him yeah so we were taught I was asking
it like when I was asking him about how
much fresh frozen material he's now
doing
but he was talking about a new process
he has which I don't know he's talked to
you as he talks so so you know so John
and I flew up to Oregon with a bunch of
other people with the company I work
with Newbridge they flew us up there and
they John gave a president oh you're
working with new because he's with me
but yeah I'm we're doing you are all
right so I got the same company we're
the same company yeah Jonathan all right
we're good guys so it's funny cuz so
Newbridge is like this this team of like
top industry elite people we got it
Silas his name's always weren't a dank
on Instagram but Silas is in my opinion
one of the top cultivators in the world
it's the guy who started the company no
he is not guy so he is the cultivator I
do genetics Eric Tran is the guy who
started the company eric is also
industry elite very business minded
super professional and super calculating
it's a great guy to have on your side
yeah yeah he said you actually respect
the guys who started the company I do
okay so yeah we're not thinking of like
all the big like yeah companies and it's
like all these finance guys and they
roll up a bunch of other companies and
so he's a black market guy like he came
from the black Eric Eric Eric came well
we all did yeah except John I came from
one in that company but a lot of the
companies that's like dudes who came
from Goldman snags we came from wherever
yeah no and I think that's one thing
that kind of separates us apart from
some of these other big companies that's
an industry people industry people we're
on it the same we were in the shadows
together you know and especially you
know Oakland was kind of an innovative
place in its own in its own right
Oakland kind of was a boundary-pushing
community the Oaksterdam you know we
kind of paved the way for legalization
you know it's pretty impressive what's
going on over there but with Newbridge
Newbridge is kind of pushing boundaries
especially with putting together like
these superstar teams right so we got a
lady who really knows what she's doing
her name's B B Scott she runs the
she's part of the team so what she does
is she runs the nursery's she does
large-scale you know nursery production
and she's all about better where she has
roots in Oakland that's coming out and
she has the Bay cloner II and the Bay
clownery is in Santa Rosa 12,000 square
foot facility that should be ready later
this year where I'll be working with her
she's absolutely amazing and she how
long has she been running a nursery for
she's been I think around 10 years I've
been working and then you know with
cultivation and nursery but her clones
are by far like the best clones I've
seen so she understands the process and
she doesn't skip steps and I love her
was it Voltron where like all the
individual robots came together as one
big robot yeah and we're gonna create
one badass boutique branding right
that's two that's the metaphor or
analogy I'm painting yeah and I feel
like yeah and Eric is really basically
Eric's like I'm doping this skill set
yeah
you guys bring green and genetic so you
got the nursery skills you got to
whatever yeah okay so that's what the
company is all about and so you're all
like everyone has equity and everyone is
exactly like Eric's the guy who started
it but you're all really good what Eric
is yeah he is uh he's the decision-maker
the cheerleader the shows are like our
loud seeds under that umbrella so well I
can't really talk about that right now
so loud see it yeah you say loud ceases
going with another direction they were
we're working it out with the company
called next Green Wave the acquiring of
loud teeth so loud seeds may go with
them we'll see okay well that's big so
that means that the company your baby
yeah they sell to someone else
yes but it's it's funny because I have a
the ganja farmer seed company I have
green light genetics dr. farmer seed
companies with Marlon Asher it's our
little collaboration that we're actually
doing through Newbridge are going to
have a new seed company coming out
called
ganja farmer seed company with Marlon so
some stuff you're doing with and through
Newbridge some stuff you're doing
separately right I do
I do consulting like for cultivo so I
did genetic consulting for them yeah
I've been in talks with several other
companies abroad and here for genetic
consulting so I so talk about give me
like a genetic consulting like example
or case study like you watch so Columbia
so Columbia is interesting you know
getting genetics down there fee no
hunting potentially I think there's
there's big talks of fee no hunting and
getting specific cultivars and stuff
that works within their climates I also
do why are you still learning what works
well there I think they are still
learning I haven't been down there so
I've because at some point you'll need
to like be like this is the shit that
will grow well here yeah first in your
perfect growing and so so we've been
talking about Auto flowers in Columbia
and people are like why would you bring
out a flowers down to Columbia I also
breed out a flowers that's one of the
things I do right now which is unique in
the US right it is unique in the US but
it's starting to become more popular
especially for large scale cultivation
it's very like Europe is bigger and
autoflowering than the US or like
history historically if it was a
complete like I mean in France and
you'll see people grow it like dime
France but like in Barcelona there's
people in in their apartments that have
Auto flowers just you know their porches
outside where you can look up and you
see their autofocus so the typical
grower in America does not grow auto
Farsi will go buy feminized or they'll
go buy regular but the last thing most
people do but it is catching up I mean I
think you can see statistically through
some of the seed banks that are selling
the auto flower seeds like ISO these
guys are starting to sell more auto
flower seeds and some of these companies
that make auto flower seeds in Europe
you know they'd be 50% of their sales in
Auto flour 50 percent in feminized no
regular so what's are you so me I'm
doing for large large scale for Ag so
that's auto flower I feel like is the
future for certain scenarios I don't
think it's right for everybody but I
think in in the given circumstance where
your problems with mold and mildew if
you have to tarp in specific times a
year Auto flowers are ideal
so if like October or like September
October or super-moist sure you want to
come early you want to come early yeah
okay well ah no flowers can also if you
start them in May you can do two seasons
trip yeah I think there's people that
are afraid of autumn flowers they think
they're shit I think for biomass they
are one of the most ideal situations
especially if they're stabilized or
there's very little phenotypical
variation so what's he smoking oh wait
so yeah we're talking about one point we
were talking about live rosin so Silas
is the one in Sarnia really turned me on
to live rods and especially in the last
like six months I always run an egg so
trichome heavy extracts that's the
company he works with but he grows some
of the best best cannabis I've seen on
the planet where does he grow he's gonna
be growing for Newbridge so Silas
no-till organic living soil absolutely
amazing super super greasy pot like the
cannabis the flower is so greasy it's
ridiculous like next level but where so
where was he growing so I believe he was
going on a medical side over he's in
California in California oh yeah in like
Mendocino or no I think more towards the
desert
so in the terpene profiles so so Silas
but the thing is is like bee and Silas
and I we we all connect on this one
level right where we all agree on GMO is
amazing now I think there's a lot of
people out there I don't know GMO
cookies if you're familiar with a garlic
cookies it's a chem D times thin Nate
Girl Scouts and it has a very specific
terpene profile that they that he gets
from the chem dee not from the cookies
the cookies add some back notes to it
but it is just one of the it smells like
dirty armpits
it smells like going to a Grateful Dead
show on a hot day that's how I feel
about the smell it's like a cheese
fountain not not cheese no no more like
more of like a fuck I think you can kind
of smell it with this this right here
it's it almost burns your nose a little
bit right but it's
that yeah that's good right but it also
yeah and I was like good armpit yeah but
yeah so I feel like it's an acquired
taste
it's it's a something that most new
smokers don't appreciate you know it's
like it's cat piss is another one where
like just the name turns people off
they're like I want to smoke no Kappas
we haven't seen campus in a while like
the real one but that was like super
ammonia it's a nl5 haze yeah it was
ammonia but the thing is is the the cat
pissed that we had 20 years ago you
would have 1/10 of a gram in your pocket
and you Andy scrambling around your room
trying to find it cuz it smelled so
strong sure there's no weed I know that
if you have 1/10 of a gram right now
tenth of a gram that it's gonna smell
your whole room up to where you start
panicking because your parents are gonna
find it right so yeah it's funny and I
think that's the big the big step that
people were gonna do next I mean I feel
like my buddy John that's up and then
though he's doing it I'm trying to do it
we're trying to go to these landrace
varieties and incorporate them back in
or at least closer to Landry's I feel
like the stuff that's going on with all
the wedding cakes and all the the
sherbert crosses and all these new
things they're great and people love
them but what we need is genetic
diversity back into the cannabis it's
just it's the one thing that's missing
and it's the one thing that over time it
causes genetic depression what's and
does that come from something becoming
super popular in the market wanting it
and then everyone thinking they need to
cross with it to call it come up with
their own version of it oh yeah that's
exactly what it is and so what happens
is we either are putting OGIS or cookies
and bringing everything it seems like
everybody's doing that it's like ok so
you just put it oh gee on another Oh
Jean you got a new oh gee well it
doesn't work like that
and then like Joan Rivers shoulder-pads
it goes out of style as the 80s come to
a close right and well and then the
thing is is so many people are like I
only like cookies or I only like og and
I have a very like open palette I like
all that I like good cannabis
doesn't matter whether it's a haze or
whether it's Sour Diesel whether it's OG
or whether it's cookies if it's good if
it's grown properly you like your
cannabis tapas a little bit of
everything I do and I like having that
variety it's like over in Amsterdam when
I was over there last time we ended up
in Spain and I got some really good
gorilla glue and the gorilla goo was
phenomenal where I wanted to smoke it in
the morning and it was just such a
strong smoke that I decided to switch
over to Liberty haze and herb walking to
the park we had an amazing time
switching over and it's like the only
difference is really the terpenes right
but absolutely going back to haze
absolutely amazing but part of the
problem that they had was they basically
loved hay so much that was all they had
over there for a long time - there was
not a lot of diversity I mean I think
since he was bringing some stuff in
there bringing some Durbin's and they're
bringing some other unique things in but
people were like I want haze dr.
Grinspoon 26 weeks okay well as you
evaluate kind of Europe generically in
the US right what trends are you seeing
well I see things like history repeating
itself here well start with Europe
because you're saying she's was there
jamm what is there Jim now there Jim is
American strains they want so they wanna
explore skittles okay they love skittles
over there and you know how can you I
have skittles in my bag I got both
extract and I got flour and I love
skittles skittles is any we grew it
what's that who grew it
so the skittles that I have in my bag
was one of my my friends here in his
little little small growth but the
extract it came from a local place
around here maybe in Vegas yeah it's
it's some California stuff I got so but
but it's like skittles skittles sherbert
people are wanting they want high trippy
and profiles and they want unique and
that's good yeah I think over in Europe
and in the states we're looking for that
there's still a little bit behind us so
we kind of set the trend and then they
try to scoop it up like the California
more than any
it's a trip yeah I feel like what so so
it's interested like I think of us
chocolate versus European chocolate yeah
the Europeans are a little more
sophisticated and have what I consider a
better palate for things like chocolate
with cannabis like I feel like here
everyone wanted the highest THC so like
that there's the the appreciation of
sort of the full bouquet and body of
what you're smoking like a wine or
whatever is I mean you do you appreciate
it but your average person but did your
average European have a better
appreciate like 5 10 20 years ago a
better appreciation for hash yeah that's
true perhaps you know they have our
appreciation for hash on another level
we don't see that in the States we have
appreciation for extract but not like
that old school house and that
old-school hash is kind of like smoking
a cigar it's got real nuances that if
you don't smoke ash all the time it all
just tastes the same
you know same thing with the cigar you
don't smoke a cigar you pick one up it
just tastes like a fucking cigar but
back to the you know and it's funny
because I had a conversation with Lance
I think a little bit about reference
points you know going through life with
all the inbreeding I'm a chef as well
and so the more things you taste the
more reference points you have the more
you understand something and it's so
real interesting and I feel like I
breathe I try to breathe my reference
points I try to cook and understand
cultures by reference points than by
having a broad number of reference yeah
and I'm constantly smelling jars so like
this I'm constantly smelling these
flavor profiles to see kind of what
would well would potentially go together
you know and then you mix and match I do
some weird stuff we roll joints together
of two strains and see if they taste
good as it looks
yeah a lot of those fun too and and
sometimes one sometimes it's not so the
you're all right the Europeans are like
wanting an American sadly wanting
American stuff the thing is is so you
look at what it takes to Colton
and sell in Amsterdam compared to
California it's very difficult the
systems that you like from a regulatory
standpoint yeah I mean from a regulatory
standpoint just from a person wanting to
acquire good cannabis the process it
goes through in California and the
process it goes through to get it to
that same quality standard in Astra you
rarely see that a triple plus that you
have in California in Amsterdam it's
it's rare but it's also humid and cold
and really really freakin cold and it's
also illegal to grow there so people are
basically you know they don't put people
in jail but there's take all your stuff
and they'll find you
so it's illegal to grow there whereas
California people still have rooms in
their houses and you know the standards
are higher it's funny though that the
people that were growing that mediocre
stuff five years ago that we're making
money they're not making money anymore
so so what about in the u.s. like are
you seeing because one of the things for
example Kevin Jody talks about is like
you know different markets have
different wants right like the East you
know I grew up selling in the East Coast
oh yeah so you grew up in Rhode Island
right Austin Austin right I went to
brown yeah so so you guys like Sour
Diesel and chem dawg
yeah pretty much exclusively like Sour
Diesel like me going to New York when I
was younger it was like the Sour Diesel
was the best like people didn't give a
shit about any OG nothing else our
Diesel was the one and you're paying 60
to 100 dollars an eighth straight up for
that stuff so what are you seeing so
what do you seen either generically in
the u.s. now so like where the trends
going so it used to be just like yeah it
five years ago it was cookies oh gee
basically Sour Diesel we had maybe some
perps but it not specific right and that
was the black market the white market is
wedding cake lava cake birthday cake and
all these trends right and the thing is
is like we were breeding very stable
genetics
you know before 2012 we focused on like
stabilizing genetics releasing f4 is
releasing f5 not releasing f2
like that was kind of against what we
believed in at the time but nowadays
people want F once and that's it and so
they want the latest and greatest in
three months down the road they want
something they kick that one of the
curve and they like now I want this and
it's because the white market
[Music]