[Music]
I've been growing since I was 16 years
old so it's been 12 years now and well I
mean my dad taught me how to grow from
the beginning and since then things have
changed a lot but I guess he just taught
me the techniques and Mura taught me to
respect the land and that we want to you
know increase or better the property and
better our home instead of just using it
up and using it for our business it's
more for you know I guess he just taught
me to respect where we're from and where
we live my farm is called Elysian Fields
and I live on a fifty acre piece of
property that we grow all seeds right
now from that have been developed by our
neighbors who are old-school growers so
they all grow really well and they're a
lot there's a lot of pineapple and what
we're growing I don't know if that
particular trait works really well where
we are or what the deal is with that but
we grow mostly I think fruitier stuff
more on the sativa side for me works
better the more indica has the fat buds
and we get especially in the fall we get
more of a coastal fog and that can
create mold and bud rot so for us more
of more on the sativa side of things
works a lot better so we grow a
pineapple OG something called pineapple
OG that's been developed by one of our
neighbors and then we also grow a sour
pineapple also developed by a neighbor
and I think at our farm we're growing
mostly sour pineapple and there's
actually a few different phenotypes of
that one there's a purple one and then
there's a more on the indica side and
more on the sativa side and my favorite
one is the more it's a TV one come out
really frosty really good smell good
yield
pretty much mostly but we're trying now
to Fino hunt and find our favorite ones
and we've been taking cuttings of all of
our favorite plants and just keep our
own genetics going but knowing the
biggest one of the biggest issues for us
right now is testing and knowing that
we're getting a clean start so there's
been you know people have used gnarly
chemicals on their clones and that will
that can last in the plant for a really
long time like generations so we have
been taking cuttings of our own and
we're trying to save our own genetics
and make sure that we have a really
clean start so we know everything that
happens to the plant throughout its
whole life my favorite strain I don't
smoke that much so I would have to say
right now Ringo's gift is my favorite
because it's a high CBD describe the
growth are you growing in the ground are
you growing in pots or native so we're
doing a mix this year we got a tractor I
got my first loan ever and got a tractor
and we ripped the native soil first and
then we put out mounds of organic
composted
this guy out in Chico makes worm casting
compost and we're just put out mounds of
that on top of the native soil and we
only used about a hundred gallons per
plant and usually we'd have like 200 to
400 gallon pots so we're just using 100
gallons per plant and then it they
especially because they're from seed
they have a tap root that goes down and
they're able to just keep on going
through the native soil and they're
responding really well to that
we actually had a 500 a few 500-gallon
ones last year - yeah so not pots just
mounts so we ripped the ground and then
we put laid mounds out on top of that so
the plants can just keep on growing and
you know they're about seven feet on
center and we used to be more like ten
feet on center because we wanted to have
the biggest plant possible because we
were only allowed 25 and now we're
allowed a square footage so we have like
a hundred and a hundred and seventy
probably at our house and that's not
even filling up the whole square footage
of what we're allowed but yeah we're
moving more towards building our own
soils and we want to have we're planning
on getting a compost pile like a big
load of manure put down so we can build
a compost pile of our own soil and cuz
that's a whole nother thing buying soil
you don't know what's in there you don't
know there could be stuff that comes in
through the plant and then that'll show
up in testing at the end so we're trying
to just get to a point where we know
exactly what's happening to plant the
whole life so we're there's no surprises
so what are some of the issues with
growing in the ground versus like you
grew it one way in the pots for a long
time tell me about the experience of now
growing
well so actually I've had one patch for
five years or so that was in the ground
holes that I dug out in the ground they
were like five feet across and it was a
great spot for a long time and then I
thought I had russets one year cuz one
plant just died and it just like dried
up at the end I thought it would just
finish out but it just dried up and died
and then the next year I noticed in more
plants and it wasn't rust it's what it
turned out to be was some sort of soil
borne fungus maybe Fusarium or something
like that so it was just killing plants
so that can be an issue and if you have
once you have that it's really difficult
to get rid of it like we talked to an
agronomist and they said just don't grow
there anymore so that can be one of the
issues rodents is an issue they if even
if they don't eat the roots they just
tunnel through and can affect them those
are the two biggest issues I would say
well it hasn't happened yet we use a lot
of teas mostly like we haven't really
been feeding much we don't use any
bottled nutrients anymore we're doing
all compost teas and maybe some
micronized feedings but that's it
we actually just bought a five or a four
hundred gallon tank that we can just put
in the bed of our truck and we have a
pump that we can attach to a generator
just plug in so we can move it from
patch to patch because we have we have
two different farms and at our house we
have two different garden sites in one
farm
is it the collective model or is it
different no so their main thing is
distribution and so they they came up to
Mendocino County and met some farmers up
there and realized that they wanted to
be kind of part of that or promote that
so they have been working with sun-grown
farmers that are all organic and they
have been there the only distribution
that I've worked with that has been
really consistent and has been promoting
us as the farmers who've been here
forever you know trying to make our way
so they do they do a lot of wholesale
right now but they have jars and when
they put your product in a jar they say
where it was grown and then they put a
tag on it with your farm name and
explain a little bit like just a little
blurb about your farm so they the
biggest branding is flow camp and then
your
yeah so for me it's a model that makes
sense as a small farmer how am I
supposed to go out and brand myself when
I'm trying to grow the best product I
can't I don't have time I work all day
long from sunup to sundown or even past
sundown sometimes I'm working on my farm
trying to grow cannabis so I can't I
don't have the time I also don't have
the funds to go out and brand myself as
an individual farm I also don't have the
product there's not I don't have enough
to if I had a huge demand to make it
make sense it to me it just doesn't
really make sense so having this the
double I think what is the white label
branding is that what it's called yeah
that makes sense
[Music]