[Music]
yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
let's start by smoking your flower
however you prefer to smoke it no guess
I guess that would be rolling a joint
right that would and Andy we actually
left the papers and the crutches over
there and you had one job to do that one
job to do got the ashtray clean though
as the funniest we've been smoking
cannabis all morning and preparation of
smoking cannabis all afternoon my hands
just be shameful no no I love I love
tools and utensils that I have had such
a collection of different papers pipes
and bongs when I worked at the dive shop
I used to make bongs and pipes out of
old scuba equipment because I'd sit in
this shed all day long waiting to fill
scuba tanks for the Puerto Rican lobster
fishermen on st. Croix and I'd be out
there all day long just sitting there
smoking joints and and working on scuba
equipment and when I'd have leftover
parts I'd see how to make a smoking tour
yeah hey get the regulator weed see ya
they put the regulator all back together
and have three Springs and a screw
laughter yeah they were extra parts I
think we've already got some of the
Durban ready to go ground up this is one
of our favorites Durban poison is what
people think of when they think of a
sativa
this one's video it's originally from
Durban South Africa and it has been
grown in our family and friends of
cultivators for well over 20 years it's
one of my absolute favorite this smell
is phenomenal well this is what like
when Mel Frank talks about like I missed
that original Durban poison I can't get
it again
this is the 2017 Durban is well yeah
this is one of those things when you
talk to old school smokers and you open
a jar of this you can just see the smile
on their face their eyes melt and
they're just like all happy memories
when people think of that happy giggly
stuff they used to get way back in the
day we always light up a spliff of of
the Durban and you know people it brings
back memories
I am the terpene Turpin allene so what
gives it that classic Durban smell to
love that unmistakable Durban and this
is an early Durban so it's got a little
bit of a shorter flowering period but
it's we've been growing it in Sonoma
County for a long time and we're really
trying to develop our own appellation
entire wah so we're gonna see how this
varies from everybody else like what
French wines made their way to Sonoma
wines we have we love Sonoma County
lines
kiona wives give me some favorite so
where did where we live up in Sebastopol
we love Mary Edwards
she's an old-school winemaker you know
one of the top in the country male or
female does a solid piano ours and Sam
you don't belong to it is but my
favorite whites it I drink right now
it's amazing but I prefer red the Pinot
Noir made a nice fruit drip and Sonoma
County peed on the water I mean she just
crushes it and then Martinelli right
down the street is Helen Turley's cuz
she don't winemaker there and she does
high-alcohol Zinfandel it's just really
like same thing old school female
winemakers is it or just crying right
now it's amazing like the cannabis
industry you know so many of the
important people in the county right now
are women
yeah like Shannon Cameron's wife our CEO
is just paving the way for regulations
licenses and stuff
well you guys are smoking we she's
reading through all the regulations and
yeah and she's on the hemp advisory
board for Sonoma County and she's also
one of the founders of the women's
cannabis Business Development she is
just a rock star I've never seen anybody
be able to just grab a hold of a project
and this is something you know with all
the administrative shit that I have no
interest in dealing with oh she's a lot
of Sun regulation yes she's four years
and all of it all of it and managing the
farm and Harmon smoke and build out of
construction and every little detail
there is we're in the position we are
because of Shannon's attention to detail
and just being a rock star animal and
everything she does and she spent 20
years as a project manager in telecom
and running massive projects and we've
built a restaurant together and ran that
together we've rebuilt a sail boat
together and sailed that down the coast
and lived on it for almost two years
together and she's just amazing person
to work with you know it's a I have to
keep up you know she really makes me it
pushes me to Jody to well we just have
such there's no way you can do this
alone there is no way that anybody who
was a small farmer and producer in the
beginning there's no way anybody can do
this without a team and without a family
and that's why this is community we're
all trying to rally together to survive
this and it takes Jody and Andy and and
everybody else on our team we have
fantastic people that you know we have
to hire the best the brightest and the
smartest to run with things that we
never imagined we'd have to deal with I
just wanted to be a farmer and keeps
valedictorian so the Durbin that you
said has been like between family and
friends for like 20-something years is
that kind of like the hero cultivar of
your life if you had to pick one that
you want Fiddler's greens to be known
for that's a tricky question because we
do different things for our Durban
flower for our heritage you know one of
those classic heirloom strains we
absolutely want to be known for the
Durban especially to carry on the
tradition there are some great people
who started this before us and it's it's
a real honor to continue to be growing
this because you know we weren't first
by any stretch of the imagination and we
just want to show respect to the people
who got us here and brought us here so
can you talk about any of them and what
they taught you the people that taught
us the people who taught me to cultivate
this is the primary strain we grew and I
started out you know lugging dirt and
trimming and washing pots and being the
grunt laborer for these guys and yeah
all of us all of us learned you know
working for these guys and you know they
they were just really neat people who
are travelers and we met we all met in
the Caribbean overtime and we run into
each other everywhere we go in the world
I was not a part of that these guys have
a couple of years on me believe it or
not but I mean I am in it now the hands
in the dirt part well
metaphorically what I can say yeah and
there's amazing people that are still
trying to survive you know the the new
regulation era and you know we just want
to make sure that everybody survives
that we're trying to make sure that the
people who started this and got us here
with this that they get recognition and
you know that they are given a place to
carry on in this industry because it's
been so drastic you know the the
regulations that it's difficult to
survive I yeah I just went about that OC
normal meeting where the guy
he started off talking about those
growing practices but the rest was
talking about the laws and what they're
trying to do and and essentially how
they're trying to survive and there's
you can see kind of difference between
them the LBC a but they both do separate
cool things ago BCA they have like a
guarantee hire process essentially we're
like anyone who like they want to like
set up something where they have like a
they want people through a program and
they kind of get certified and it's not
an official certification is no actual
but essentially you recognize than
anywhere throughout Long Beach any club
they're prepared are you next to those
systems in place to to protect the
community and to give people you know
more incentive because when you're
bringing things to a city council
meeting you know you need to have
positive approach to beyond just we got
to keep doing that we got to keep going
to the City Council meetings we got to
go to the Board of Supervisors meetings
we got a call and right because these
regulations aren't the end-all be-all
it's the camels nose under the tent we
got to keep showing up about a keep
fighting we've got to change the
regulations so that they make sense
you know most of these people that wrote
the regulations have no idea what we do
they have no idea how the cannabis
business operates and they're they're
writing rules blind but every time that
we contact them and we try to work with
them we're getting good reception
they're listening they're trying and so
we need to you know yeah we need the
angry activism but we also need to meet
people where their understanding is and
guide them along into the right way and
we're pioneers for a reason you know
it's if it was easy everybody would be
doing it so we never answered your
question yeah you were asking what we
would want to be known for but the other
one that we would want to be known for
is our ACDC
we're seven the tincture here but the
ACDC is a high CBD flower it stands for
alternative cannabinoid dietary
consumption the alternative cannabinoid
refers to CBD versus THC and the dietary
consumption meant that it was indicated
to be taken orally or
ingested as a whole flower and the ac/dc
is traditionally a fairly difficult
plant to grow it's pretty spindly and it
flops around but we've been growing it
for many years now and it really likes
where we are in Sonoma County we've
gotten it too you know the it's really
thriving and we're hoping the longer we
grow is a it's amazing that is what when
you have something like that are you
still trying to kind of gently breed it
in a direction or you like this is
perfect as is now I just need to get it
consistently like where every flowering
plant is like pretty much the same you
trying to take care of the soil
differently better every year also at
the plant you find out where it thrives
in an ecosystem and then try to foster
that ecosystem but your true but that's
addressing this iteration of that plant
are you are you like I'm happy with
where ac/dc is are you trying to breed
it in some sort of direction to express
itself slightly differently I don't
think we're there yet we're still you
know everybody's still learning on this
and this is a new form that we're
regenerating four years ago it was
almost a used-car lot there was a 12
jump cars everywhere the place was
destroyed that it was nasty and so we've
been rehabilitating and cleaning up this
place but it was the one place that we
found that we could get permitted to
cultivate on and so we're rehabbing this
farm we're working on the soil we had
this golden Ridge soil which was
basically inert so we've been working
with compost and to get it to a point
where you felt comfortable plants
because you plants in the soil right
yeah so what you need to do from
junkyard to feeling confident about
planting that in the soil we're lucky
that in the space that we cleared for
cultivation was a little bit of ways
from where most of the junk cars were it
was where our parking is and things like
that that there is a bunch of junk cars
that got hauled away and when we'd stick
a shovel in the ground we'd find a box
of forks or it was odd restaurant things
or a radiator little hotel room service
salt and pepper shaker
and we found them forever while we were
cleaning all that out and we basically
accumulated all the junk but where our
cultivation space is which were only
allowed 10,000 square feet it's fairly
fresh and there wasn't much anything
else but it's this golden rich soil
which basically has nothing in it and so
we've been working with Google culture
and we're slowly working ourselves
towards the North no-till and a
closed-loop system but every year we
plant cover crops and then we chop and
drop we add compost we create our own
compost what what cover crops are you
growing for what kind of minerals or
nutrients like I'm not sure on that the
minerals and nutrients that we're
specifically trying to work on
unfortunately that's one of the things
that's tough about what we're doing now
is I don't get to spend time on the farm
anymore I had the guys that I learned
from the guys that I look up to as
cultivators are now in charge of our
cultivation team and so the only way I
get to follow up oh yeah everybody on
earth yeah yeah some of our all of our
cultivators I really look up to man they
know so much more than I do and it's
gone so much further than where we
started we'll talk about some of the
things would you were asking what we
just did with the ac/dc two years ago
went through through the ground we grew
them the best we could and they tested a
20 to 1 CBD THC then they all went and
took classes on bio dynamics
permaculture and they dug Google beds
you know with dead oak boughs compost
grass clippings put the plants on top of
that with earthworm tubes and create
living soil so less water more about
that I was working together and the next
year it tested a 30 to 1 CBD to THC so
that's a way that they've all been
working together trying to figure out
the new practices try to build this soil
so that each year the plants are
hopefully a better example of themselves
yeah I'm actually wondering if we keep
going how long it'll take to I think we
said this before get if you keep growing
a strain in the same place over and over
and over again and take it back to seed
or regenerate it so it gets that memory
of that place how long before we create
it back to another
landrace in a new place what Durbin
there it is what I assume you have like
mothers on site and you're doing your
own clippings like you're not buying
from nurseries so like you're
essentially your own breeder and nursery
yeah we have our own nursery committee
in order for us to keep everything we've
had trouble finding people that we
wanted to work with that we felt could
do things as well as we could and so
because of that we do our own nursery we
do our own manufacture we do our own
processing we do our own distribution
and we do everything education first and
so everybody and everybody our team
whether you're a cultivator or whether
you work in processing we all go around
and do each other's jobs so we all know
what each other has to deal with these
guys went up and spent their time
working on the farm and they've also
spent time working on the manufacturing
production line yeah grass is always
greener on the other side of the fence
in this world I like all the sudden
traffic is sounding funny guys were
digging holes out their last three years
in a row the hottest days of the year
have been when we're going in the ground
yeah I wait the Tuesday after meadowland
yes I was driving from I was driving
like past Santa Cruz and Salinas
sunlight it was like a hundred and ten
was brutal they're all digging holes
like no no I have stuff to do inside
well so what does that do to the plan
yeah we've been hurting the plants off
for quite a while so they've been
outdoors and the plants really I mean
that's the terroir that's the
appellation that's what we're gonna get
naturally because we're so as yeah we're
so closing to the coast so we're gonna
have hot days we're gonna have cold
nights we're gonna have fog and that's
just what we produce and that's what's
gonna affect the planet it's gonna show
different expressions based on how that
plant lives we have high winds up there
or in the Petaluma windgap and so the
Durban the Durban and the ACDC bow
seem to really love it's a harsher
condition and we go full term too so
we're not trying to rush you know a
finish we let the plants go and that's
you know we won the girl off last year
and that was white Tahoe cookies and we
put it in these Google beds and did
compost teas and pretty much just let
the plant you know tell us what it
needed and we pretty much left it all so
these ladies are not hos plants it takes
you got to listen to him you really got
to watch them pay attention and we're
learning as we go all the time I mean we
make anybody who's been a cultivator has
made mistakes
you know the lesson is just not to make
the same mistakes twice or learn to
notice ahead of time and then setting up
your system so you don't have to you
know plant lots of beneficial plants get
beneficial insects create a very bio
diverse area because if you haven't so
you're mixing cannabis and you said
cover oh yeah all sorts of different
yeah we're gonna do clovers over to you
know different heights right hmm I love
using cosmos they're beautiful flower
sunflowers I love those cat nips a great
one to have as a companion plant and of
course with the traditional herbs we do
basil and thyme and rosemary and do you
know why like what's I mean obviously
some attract the right insects push off
the wrong and others when they die they
have good nutrients yeah we're learning
as we go and we're just trying to create
a lot of biodiversity out there along
the fence line we're planning the three
sisters we're doing corn squash and
beans the corn you know does a good job
of screening aphids and then we also
just we like the the biodiversity of it
we also plant our food and vegetables
around there too we do gardens we're
trying to create a Clos lucé this system
and it's it's a lot of fun so take the
ac/dc so its expression of itself as
flower which is here but then also
you're you're pushing it in different
directions meaning from flower to
tincture from flower to so other types
of products so talk about how a specific
cultivar sort of
expresses itself as its extracted well
we don't really do an extraction the
most important thing is what we do is a
long slow cure you can grow the best
flower in the world but if you rush it
out the door it's not gonna have time to
mature you know you can do things like
you can fresh freeze it and that's gonna
retain the brightness that freshness
it's like a young tequila that hasn't
been aged it's you know very zingy and
poppy and green and you can flash freeze
it and then you can extract from that
and you're gonna get some wonderful live
resin or or you know some of this gonna
be very bright but as cannabis is like
wine if you it's almost the opposite of
what you do that's the opposite of what
we do is we want a long slow cure so we
dry it very slowly in specific humidity
and temperature conditions lots of air
flow and what we want plant to do is
slowly allow the the chlorophyll and
things like that to degrade and the the
terpenes to express themselves fully and
oxidize just a little bit and that's
gonna continue to change and grow and
grow in depth and especially if you cure
it long enough to where it becomes
stable and you seal it off you can get
great expression of terpenes it'll
change over the years we had at ang cush
that we aged for three years that was
just velvety and wonderful we have some
Durban I mean we just smoked two
different harvested Durban and you could
tell that it gets that richer more full
flavor yeah so what you're saying about
how we show the expression of the ACDC
you use the word extraction and we don't
do an extraction which is what makes
this different from a lot of it's just
how we are how pillars is different than
there's the cure and then there's like
the slow decarboxylation right that's
right it's gonna oxidize oxidize a
little bit but we don't want it to D
karbalaa because a lot of like our ACDC
in our tincture lines we work with rock
and AB annoyed so we want to cure it so
that it's got that the the it expresses
the right terpenes and changes just
enough but then we infuse it into
organic olive oil so we we want to have
CBD a and THC a and C B G a and the
acidic cannabinoids
one line of our tinctures and then we do
decarboxylate for the other line because
all of the different cannabinoids and
terpenoids system differently between
raw CITIC and decarboxylated randomly
are you sourcing the olive oil from like
California from Greece from are you
learning about that part - we're like we
have a preference for we are really
looking for local producers and we're
trying to talk we're in talks with a
couple different local hala voya
producers but one of the scary things is
we have to go through a lot of lab
testing process because of the testing
we have to do for our final products if
any of the ingredients along the way and
olive oil is your canvas can be cleaned
but you fail because your olive oil now
which is scary you know and a handmade
you know boutique product like that no
that's cool so it seems like they're
kind of like craft NorCal all those
farmers that's what we're looking for
that's and matching them with your fine
craft cameras we made all right so the
bong has thrown Durban this is 2018 how
is the ac/dc smoked well we're gonna do
that next right yeah yeah it's delicious
and that's you said this version was now
thirty to one where you originally were
24 to 1 yeah anything that's gonna keep
going like at some point it's gonna be
like all right this is maxed out on CBD
as I can and I think we want to have the
full like the the CBD is just one part
of the plant it's a single no well so
that kind of guess my question is like
you're gonna lose something else if you
keep pushing the CBD it's like when
people push THC as far as it can go
other people are now pushing CBD is for
it this one goes to 11 it's like that
may not be the best though no it's not
something we're intentionally trying to
do what we're doing is trying to create
a great living soil and in that we're
gonna create the environment where the
plants gonna want to grow so we're not
doing specific anything specific to
alter the plant we just have been
working with the same genetics and class
when you pick which ones to turn into
moms you are kind of selecting for
something right so what in for example
the ACDC in the last round of selection
do you kind of like I like this
characteristic that this plant has
versus all the other ones we've been
pretty consistent with for several years
growing this strain of ac/dc and we've
got it pretty well stabilized and so
generally it's just with the vigor of
the plant that we look at and we refresh
our mothers quite frequently this year
we're flowering out a bunch of the
mothers and we're also using it for our
grow six big ones we're gonna we're
trying to encourage anybody who wants to
grow their six plants to grow six plants
and then share with somebody that can't
grow or can't afford it or zoned out
that way we're just trying to teach
everybody to grow it at so you know get
your hands in it right are you doing any
tissue culture we are looking into that
where it's interesting we're all
researching and reading books well
that's that's one of those things we
have to research everything we're doing
this is just a you know gone yeah we're
back in school non-stop if we're not
reading articles we're sharing articles
we're going to lectures we go to
community groups we go to medical
lectures to listen to the doctors and
the research tell us what's actually
happening when we ingest cannabis we go
and listen to these amazing cultivators
and old school people who've been doing
it for generations and we're trying to
learn from everybody and I love it that
we get to do this out in the open now
that we get to talk to everybody because
for years we had to do this and then you
know unless you knew somebody nobody was
going to share with you how they were
growing you know I walked around for
years with a copy of Jorge with duct
tape over the cover so I can read it in
public I know thirty to one CBD to THC
right out of the garden it's amazing
just infuse into all of us about so
what's our next cultivar and let's
compare these two
all right yeah so let's do it let's do
the silver og the silver og I'll let you
break this out and we're gonna use the
Firefly to vaporizer and then we have
then Firefly 2 plus so I didn't tell us
about the 2 and the 2 plus these are a
great little vaporizer you could do both
flower and concentrate or hash in it and
I've been learning how to use this it's
kind of fun there's a bit of a learning
curve with all of them but this one's
convection about the flower yeah so this
is um silver og from Spring Creek Azhar
Vanna White our friends le drew this on
Cassidy Rose actually won third place in
the Emerald cup in 2017 this is indica
style like you like you read about let's
say every time we smoke this it's
exactly what you're looking for at the
end of the night when you don't want to
do anything anymore
sit down please I just want to sit on
the beach and watch the awesome let's go
do that I'm like the dirt me where I
want to get up and clean my freaking
house yeah like that you know at I'm at
a place for both I mean this is 26% and
what Selleck does is he's done Korean
no-tell so 10-year living cell and he
and his wife have been working on they
see they feed this swirl I don't feed
the plant and it's amazing like going in
this place their farm is unbelievable
it's just 1% biodynamic you know they're
totally off the grid up there they're
growing amazing cannabis and a beautiful
light depth you know he's a welder so
he's built you know their barns out of
containers and all these amazing
structures in a place and they live in
an amazing year up there stay to
delicious cannabis so we're lucky enough
to have them in our portfolio and
represent someone who's doing things the
right way you know beyond organic beyond
biodynamic just the way I'm supposed to
be protecting from the Sun to the ground
and doing it exactly the way it's
supposed to be introducing the right
bugs the right ecosystem around it it's
it's the farmers one of the coolest
sponsor events it was really cool
have you guys ever done big lines of
code
I don't understand the question okay
what's Jodi like after one coca-cola
this is or or a cup of coffe is waking
up in the I know so Gunder what you
would be like if you did not smoke weed
and you took something like coffee no I
don't know we don't I don't think we
want to see that I thought I was in
violence today to get to here yeah
[Laughter]
promised him when he came to work with
this whole time was you can have
infinity we had so this is the Firefly -
yeah and so and the - plus I've got this
one set for temperature it has an app
that you put on your phone so you can
control the temperature with it and go
I'm just to change the temperature
because I love flower and vaping flower
you really get to taste the terpenes and
you get to text taste the complexity of
the flower without getting the
combustion in there and you can also do
concentrates and hash out of this and
you can change the temperature for you
know if you want to do the higher
temperature for the hash around 480 is
what I like and then I do a lower one
for the flower so what do you do for the
flower temperature what I'm trying to
run what I have it on here for I think
280 I think - it no no 420 420 that's
right talk about when you this is what I
like is that this is flower you group
right are not sorry this is but imagine
this for the flower you grew when years
smoking the joint of that versus this I
know you touched on some of the
differences but like what do you do you
like it as much in a different way it's
like I like red and white wine I don't
like all one all the time or all the
other ones so like do you like vaping
your own flower sometimes oh I do
absolutely I love to vape my own flower
I like to vape other flowers too - you
got a smoke and vape it I you know I
used to smoke and I use cannabis to stop
smoking tobacco yeah but I still enjoy
the combustion and you can detect
different things when you combust the
flower you watch the way it burns you
listen to the way it burns you smell it
you see how the ashes you see how the
the ash holds together to see when will
one the quality of the roll but to the
quality of the flour to hold a nice long
ash that turns and white and you can
smell if somebody didn't you know if it
was grown indoors and they used Newt if
it wasn't flesh properly or if there was
something on the flower and then the
same thing with the vape but you get
more of that it's more herbal let's see
you don't get the combustion with you so
you don't have you know the hot ash and
you know it's got a good mouthfeel it's
like you know really getting the bouquet
a glass of wine before you take it yeah
I view you at the end of the day of
smoking as like if a horse start like
god it's it slips on a table like
remember in a bachelor party you guys
see the movie back to the part yeah
where the donkey starts eating all like
the tranquilizers like rug
that's the movie text yeah so what all
right so there's a new one on the market
though yeah this is they call it the
Firefly palace and they change the air
flow through it
this one is nice but I feel like you
have to draw a little hard on it you
have to pull a little more firmly with
it and this one Jody and I have been
using this one for the last three days
and we've been testing and sampling some
of Frenchie cannolis hash out of it and
it is can we do that out of this one
absolutely right absolutely and so so
Jody what are our thoughts on the
difference between the two this is the
first time I've used this one we've
worked on getting this one dialed in so
I've been smoking out of that one
I see you've never used the older one
and this is the friend she had yeah this
is somewhat French assassin strawberry
banana with that metal lens when we got
to do the hookah there that was amazing
from whose farm you know Oh flower it is
so this is this so frenchie did that
with his flower yes okay with flour it
is farm flour
yeah that's great you just touch the
sides and the bowl heats up there and
just take a nice easy pull on it oh man
that tastes so good that's what's that
tasting like for you
they've it's that perfect hash flavor
you know it's just a little bit floral
you can just taste its Hashashin I think
our hash oisin is the the terpene that
they're equated it to but beta was a
beta Kari awfully and I'm no beta mercy
in beta Mersin when it's aged in hash it
converts to a terpene hash machine which
gives the cannabis are the hash that
hash flavor
gotten the Spring Creek Silver Logie
mm-hmm yeah and this is Gia's give the
bold stir what you cassette vaporizing
hookah in Neverland we go elastic
chopping out in it twice a day and you
just sit around
it was unbelievable TV Sharon said you
won yeah Jody won the hook yeah yeah
Bell is Frenchie's apprentice I wanted
to have and I wish I had done it I
wanted to have her and Frenchy sit down
together master apprentice and just talk
about like driving us respective like
what she learned from this guy over the
course of she found him for what two
years five that's five years five years
apprentice I mean there are like do you
know anybody who's like I've been this
person's of princes for five years and I
got three more to go
oh if that I mean that's that's one of
these things is cannabis is like sailing
you know there's no end to the rabbit
holes of learning to go down you can get
into the soil microbiome or you can get
into the curing or the hash making or
the product making or now into the
distribution or the manufacturer the
processing the actual physically running
the business there's just so many things
that you could go down the rabbit holes
but to see a relationship like that with
you know getting to learn from somebody
and she's a mazing cash maker - well
didn't she spend this past year like
growing like I'm gonna learn to grow -
we just looked on yeah yeah she went
earlier now yeah in a repertory smoke
session to prep for the smoke session
yeah we had that was growls yeah was
amazing I think she made a lot of that
hash we smoked at Meadowlands from her
own yeah yeah that about a Steve all
this fun they took good it's a good care
of us not they're just playing along and
she's like in 10 years I'm gonna be yeah
I yeah that she's I see that absolutely
why not finally so what was this one oh
the flower of the this is the Firefly -
no no no which flower did oh is this one
yeah seekin Zelig success Spring Creek
Farm silver oh gee this is the ash and
that's - yeah so you just touch the
buttons on the side and you'll see it
flash green three times and once it
stays solid green keep touching the
buttons and just inhale for 10 20
seconds
yeah we gotta make sure it's still green
we've been Oakland yesterday it's seven
it was alright wait so there's two pads
on the side pinch those two pads and
then it'll flash three times I'm gonna
stay scream like that keep holding the
buttons there's stuff in there right
yeah
cuz it's still right that should be let
me see if we need add some more yeah
let's put smaller give you a fresh we
got like eat more think he wanted to do
like each one on every device we have to
taste every one of these have another
one like no dude like we're gonna try
them all like we've just walked in I was
I was extra fire though you believe that
54 for 20 we have any questions for the
future for yourself you know some of the
stuff that be bugging you you've seen
from the inside because you know you're
dealing with taxes you're dealing with
the crazy rates from the state your deal
ideally this goes federally legal as
soon as possible and we can start
getting people in other states medicine
from places that do it the best outdoor
California Oregon Washington Colorado we
have so much cannabis here we have so
much knowledge from all this out
so economy you have two totally
different routes who are a site for the
same thing so the massive Santa Barbara
growers who are growing way too much
pretty California are like we need
global we need national / global markets
and the craft growers who could like LA
shops you don't want our amazing Sun
grow and outdoor regenerative cannabis
well fuck you cuz everybody else know
that's that we're gonna sell it to the
rest of the world yeah it's gonna be a
global market I mean there's gonna be
places like the Virgin Islands they're
gonna be able to grow you know their
strains that are special to there and
you know it
we don't want to homogenize the world we
want everybody to have their own unique
little space of it we just need to treat
up my shirt sharing with everybody it
grows on trees you know
what yeah when we get our medicine o
people in the rest of the country I mean
like we're five percent of the world's
population it takes 70 percent of the
pills they're like now you
xanax mean wait on ambien zoloft prozac
taking advil every morning I mean no
that is the silver Oh Jean all right
this one I'm still figuring out I feel
like we should have some Star Wars wait
actually you know it's we'll put the
Mentos in this one
no good
this is the aspirin tree this test farm
was so unbelievable it's just like it is
like everything in pergurt you get a
hint it was one yeah the first time we
tried this when we were on the beach and
we just basically sat down I like you I
[Laughter]
know cuz the ac/dc will help balance
that out that's high more enjoyable for
everybody in the restaurant some of the
great things about CBD is like that's
the grinder slash joint filler yes this
is a fun thing yeah it's got two
different attachments on it so you can
either put the side with the syringe
function so you can go right into a
rolling paper or blunt or a cone and
then you can put the little cap in it
and fill that up and put it into your
vape or loaded into something else or
your paper this is the fun thing I think
he did I think he did yeah that's a
great I love cannabis toys yeah it's
funny you build up so many collections
like and then when you move you wind up
done yeah this goes with the ghost so
the ghost vaporizer they use these
little crucibles their little pots
to put the yeah I guess we caught a pot
put the lid on it and this yeah I need
this one
so like when the travel yeah yeah yeah
for the night yeah the morning this got
them heft to it to it is just solves a
piece of hardware
yeah it's a solid as it looks alright
you think we're ready to go there
hit the button the back wait for it to
buzz in there we go try the ghost either
still a fun - what if they have up north
oh here
press and hold that back button until it
vibrates once keep holding it and inhale
cool yeah it feels like a hand grid this
button
yeah the one in the back yeah press and
hold it and wait for it to vibrate once
and then keep all the yeah this is the
Mendo breath I feel like you have to
crank up the heat a little bit yeah
cuz I have one at home a nice guy fix it
up and I was like okay how do you like
switch the temperatures and they
explained it to me and oh here you go
yeah oh you want me to do it oh yeah so
I have to remember we're just
experimenting with yeah it was like you
hit the front three times to do
something right having my phone over
there I pulled up the user manuals yeah
[Music]
like you know I could join this from you
via your app on your phone though right
well I'm glad you the 302nd OHS yeah
that's just talks about the battery oh
yeah why should I get super high dude
how long does it take and go alright so
for the temperature set it for dry herb
we should be two flashing amber LEDs as
the default heat sitting setting to
increase vapor intensity select one of
the higher presets for lighter vapor
reduced to low indicated by one amber
LED the concentrated preset is indicated
by three flashing L red LEDs and should
not be used for herbs
back to my bong wait it's a three
passion if it's green flashing that's
giving the battery indication it says
press and hold the mode button to
display battery level release then press
and hold again to display the current
heat setting Cameron I'm loving your
focus right now I'm admiring it wow this
is the first time I go down there cuz I
was all misty out before we don't wanna
go that high Oh damnit I think we had it
but I went to concentrate focus alright
we need you now we've got it all right
we're on herb hi
how do you go into that mode where you
change the temperature alright so you
press and hold this mode button once and
then release press and hold again and
then the second time it will show the
heat level and then you click on it to
cycle through and with the three amber
lights it's the high setting for herb
and so I think we should set our phasers
for high we're on three clicks to start
it one push here yeah I could taste it
didn't get much vapor yeah I smell you
have to keep cranking it up so wait for
the long buzz go the champion of the
hookah
fantasy yeah it tastes it tastes good
you're not seeing a cloud but what was
that somebody told us if you see a big
cloud it's like spinning your beer out
no as we were told that it's what I was
told is you breathe it in naturally and
you breathe it out naturally and that's
gonna maximize the amount of
cannabinoids you're getting out of the
smoke holding it yes just creating a
when I use that at home I never see
vapor but then I'm always like I'm
really high right now so it's definitely
worth
don't really say very same thing nut
tastes great
I suppose say oh think maybe it's so
good that just shows it here air coming
up
it's just buzzing now it's going crazy
yeah it's going crazy
[Laughter]
yeah it's guy it does seem to have been
effective certainly but wait a minute I
got to go back to my roots this is what
I carry with me everywhere man I think
that was the first thing I ever smoked
out of I've been six grand or something
that and a profile of the pro I would
always bend the poker and you could
never get it back into its holder if you
didn't clean everyone so what you do
yeah yeah dugouts are the best I've
carried one of these for over 20 years
I carry my ball wherever I go really big
pockets yes you do
this thing's pretty nifty all right what
are we smoking under the battery the
baddie is Durban we've been it's been in
and out of the lineup tonight we have
some gg4 it's delicious
all right so what do we have if we go
down the line what do we have
Vanna White take it away
these moltke from Yolo right for my guys
out there mm-hmm
so yes we have a GG for and I'm endo
breath from our friends in yellow County
two three four it's great indica style
so this gets you nice nice body high
it's only 16% so it doesn't make you
stupid so you can still get up and go do
things cuz I don't particularly care
about any Kara sativa so I try to keep
doing everything in my life for me no
matter what I'm smoking the meadow
brothers a little more sativa style
though a little higher THC as well great
uplifting makes you want to go them now
and do things yeah and then we smoke the
Silver Creek og from Spring Creek og
Spring Creek from silver flower for
rosin yeah
just for fun yeah I've never done
anything on a commercial scale we're
learning we're talking to some people we
would love to do something 100 meter
hash is what we call it all the farms
that we work with in all the farms that
are out there that grow and specialize
in their own strain we would love to see
all of them make the top shelf hash from
all of their flour and call it the
hundred meter hash that's what we call
it's the hash that never makes it 100
meters off the farm you know that's
something that's that specialty craft
right there that's something that's
gonna set each area apart is you know
just like you hear Frenchie talk about
the hash maker's he's met that they
don't care about the strain they care
about what valley it was grown in what
altitude it was grown in what were the
weather condition where it was grown and
that determined the quality and the care
of the aging and the the processing of
the plant how much care you take through
it and how you
Russia that's gonna make a lot of really
special places popped forward and the
people that really learn the craft well
it's funny I asked Frenchy is like la
creme right that what he considers to be
the best out of like a hundred pound
batch does he keep it for himself still
or does he put is he like I really want
this just for me but I have to put it
into the market and I think he's the
firm's own self yeah yeah I get that
that's my head's - for the year then
like president gave me other seven or
eight times but yeah because it sounds
like he eats a ton back Oh baby's gonna
take the best stuff off of the best of
the best
mm-hmm after but that's great I used
when I was in Amsterdam I used to put
hash in my coffee every morning and
that's how I would start the day sounds
delicious how is amazing a hippie
speedball have we missed anything with
blue cheese
we did blue cheese we have blue cheese
I'm gonna do you oh yeah we didn't use
your your very yeah okay we don't really
have anything specific we have white
buffalo we put that in there I don't
know can you put one uh yeah the puff
dough is badass I never did a bunch of
dabs because I hate the friggin torch I
[Applause]
know and I was sure that I was gonna
make some serious Bobby harm of myself
cuz that's just how things end you know
for ya yeah the torch does that for me
too but that's part of the nice things
about you know that's the way the
vaporizers is the vaporizers you can do
good hash or concentrates and vape it
not have to have the blowtorch that's
why the putco peak is so badass no
freakin torch well that one's still the
strawberry banana you will start with
that one
well done both all right so that's what
we did on in Firefly 2 plus yeah so this
will be a different experience than that
for sure
yeah so just a little bit in there this
thing's awesome you push it twice and
heats up for 20 seconds and then after
20 seconds it'll go green and then you
can started pulling it like a Bonnie
that's how simple that dab is I got a
blowtorch I'm shit fuckin Charlie butane
you're at a beauty it also does is it
gives you the ability to dab just like
every for say
you would do it puts mind-numbing davits
at your fingertips at any distance yeah
and then after about 20 seconds it beats
a opening yep that's it and beep so you
push it twice and it read does another
20 seconds
yeah so you can do that before hope you
like what channel is on because you're
not changing that is no and Joe do you
tell us the story of the dude who got
skull belong to no it's just from
Thailand where they do not care for
cannabis yet but I figured it would be a
good place to put you weed so I brought
back for camera and of course he put his
weed in the fucking eyeballs and not it
was missing a little something
that's so tasty all right well so
compare the taste of the same Frenchy
hash out of the Firefly and the puff Co
we're gonna have to go back and visit
and when doing a concentrate you need to
give it a few pulls to get it melted and
you get there I was weak I need to put a
little more so much I need a little bit
bigger part
yeah yeah yeah it's really tasty
I love the puffs go
that thing's awesome I feel like yeah
yeah we had this thing in Pebble Beach
is awesome you're getting when you took
the selfie in front of Tiger Woods and
we enjoins to I'm sure Tiger Woods time
it both great it's a similar concept
yeah it's almost the same thing
I was actually in balance
well the puff co felt more like a dabit
yeah you get us is the crew tapping out
mm-hmm and then pulled into stage screen
so it'll flash green a few times so you
got a hold on the up on the top will see
yeah very top and then yeah if they give
it like ten seconds oh yeah wait a
little bit just buzzed again yeah that
feels more like a dab experience that
it's Alegria you're good that's what
yeah when this thing is really ripping
it feels too good
like a fold dad yeah for sure
this is this is nice absolutely this
makes a little bit more more modest
although this thing travels really well
to it come this little box is perfect
you know I claim it for a little water
in it you know I got problems
yeah it could be easier like yeah you're
not whipping out then or nothing like
that and you can sit there if they bring
it everywhere murders traveling where
they don't even those that is yeah let's
talk I can't decide which one I want to
stick with so I walk with I don't always
have a dugout on me but I walk with one
two or more of these I think my bag I
have to stop every now and then and
start pulling things around in joints
and pre-rolls and all different kinds of
smoking utensils and vape pens and
cartridges and I love it because we all
share it's always we're always handing
each other a different
parrot cart to try or we find somebody
who's doing something really like you
know out in the middle of nowhere and we
grab a little bit of their stuff when we
share it out and get doll try it yeah
it's why our television was better than
that it fucking booty some nice features
yeah I think they're fucking lucky as
shit to me smoking out of these two huh
you tense and Frenchy cannolis hash and
it's fucking ridiculous
this is lucky as it gets in my world
instead of course a together they didn't
tell you about this job in high school
okay
cannabis device product tester what
today where it's like Car and Driver
ordinance eventually get to that yeah we
spoke so much at Frenchie fashion so
delicious then I give you soon I'm like
look no one wants this tube okay keep
smoking you know your thumb over to the
sucks Wednesday and you're like wait I
do like block let's already got two
bells got to well I think you do anymore
like I have to hold this year and I'm
not gonna stand there with it not
smoking
and all of a sudden there was three of
us like I respect you one as like buddy
oh yeah give it that opportunity to hang
out like that and oh yeah look that
quite thing was that than it was like
French cheese drawing splits he has the
Chilam like back to the pooka experience
that it's just so cool you know to be
with so many like-minded cadiz
professionals you know like Pele been
crying and doing this for so long you
know exchange ideas so freely like
you're saying it's it's still need to be
able to talk about me open like if
people tell them things you would never
ever talked about to anyone else you
know three or four years ago and now I
mean hey man you've done this okay hey
try this you know you talked to this
person like no shit alright and it's it
was such a cool thing and then to have
Frenchy sharing his house with us and
his team and you know everyone bringing
their own stuff into the place yeah it
was really cool you know a really fun
time
yeah I was like group therapy in the
woods seriously I said get out there no
cell service just shut off and all this
problem-solving together and that's
pretty cool me meeting people in the
industry you a tequila tasting at 3 a.m.
I'm good on the TQM battle is like you
know it's Aguila tasting and I was like
Daddy here really like shrimp my socks
off but like I would really like
watching my two babies like we should
hang out and talk to Kela for the next
hour try to stop me from talking now
good luck yeah the underlit trees
spiritually the first night the fucking
car alarm went off in the parking lot on
one end from 10 o'clock 2:30 in the
morning was that were you guys for her
yeah yeah it was right back in mindo
they'd been going off for two hours and
we all had like ten that was like fuck
this there's no way without my fucking
fury after that like I would have gone
to bed like a human head car alarm
instead I almost won the fucking bonfire
again how it happened Saturday
mmm shouldn't you work here too okay
all right I think when you thoughts or
insights they can't wait stay tuned yeah
please edit well I'm super high thank
you dinner with a ten month old baby the
funny thing is how long you bet before
journey lights up another dark