[Music]
my name is yes Joshua Shelton I'm a
co-founder of pre-treat agency based out
of Los Angeles and before we get into
the panel I just want to say the topic
we're talking about his brand and for me
it's I'm like honored and inspired to be
talking about this topic because you
know as a young attorney I was working
with brand well I say brands but guys
whose I only knew their first name in my
phone because they didn't have a brand
they didn't have logos they didn't have
websites or social media and they didn't
want anybody to know that they were even
associated with the product being sold
in the stores because it was a gray
market and brands didn't exist and the
hyper growth and maturity that I've seen
over the last five to seven years is
unbelievable it's inspiring to see the
success the companies have built and the
brands and the culture and really what a
brand is is trust it's the consumer
being able to connect with your brand
and trust that your product is something
that they can consume and value and that
that's something I'm seeing more and
more every day so it's exciting to be a
part of that and I'm gonna welcome our
panel to the stage and I'll let me
introduce everybody and then we get a
warm welcome for everybody it would be
fantastic mr. Tim Moreland with
compliance and policy director of River
Wellness Ryan Smith founder of leaf link
Megan Phillips the owner of the honey
agency Dean Ray's artist manager of c3
management and amber center CEO of
leisure life please let me give them a
warm welcome to the stage we have
microphones for you guys awesome and
this is all our first time meeting so
it's great to meet everybody and I hate
that I'm standing up here like I'd
rather just be with you guys but here we
go anyway so we're gonna just something
a few topics we're gonna do a little bit
of conversation with the panel over a
few topics I'd love everybody I think
will provide some value to us as an
industry some information and some
education and then we're gonna open it
up because really I think what everybody
is here to do is if you're not a leader
already is to become a leader in this
industry understand what that takes and
I assume that your brains are full of a
ton of questions that we are hopefully
here to be able to answer so let's start
off with our first topic which you know
I think in our industry I've worked with
a lot of people that because they've
only worked in the cannabis industry
they feel like they are inventing or
creating certain aspects of their
business whether it have been extraction
or distillation or a certain type of
processes within their company the
cannabis industry is a you know doesn't
have a lot of perspective from outside
because it's self-made millionaires
within the industry so one of the things
I think our panel can help us with today
is applying some of the history and
trends of other industry parallel
industries and what types of things have
made brands successful in industries
like fashion music sports apparel so
let's talk about that a little bit I
want to open it up to the panel maybe
start with on this end and work this way
as as we see fit I feel like I have the
privilege every day of working with wine
coffee tea and consume consumer products
and cannabis is an amazing amazing
opportunity for us to take what we can
learn from other industries but also
remind ourselves that we have the
respect of a lot of farmers and we have
to make sure that farmers are still at
the forefront of what we do and so every
day that's my job it's agriculture where
we're talking about an agricultural
product and I think that's a it's an
honor to be able to work in that so
that's been what I've been doing brands
are one of those moments where you break
bread and we have the honor of being
panelists on this but when you are
selling something that you can enjoy as
a community and a communal event where
you do break bread it becomes a
different experience it is not just a
product it is something that unites
people and it's something that unites a
lot of people and so that sort of
branding is really hard and really
interesting because it's not just a
widget it's not just a cog it's actually
a very memorable experience and I think
that's something that's even harder in
branding because we're taking something
that's that's very very passionate for a
lot of people and it's it's something we
consume it somebody put in our bodies
and I think that's pretty awesome
definitely Green the cultural elements
so one of the co-founders Ryan Smith
that leaf link and we work with over 700
brands more than 2,300 retailers now in
12 states and one of the primary bets we
made when we started the company was
that this industry would be similar to
as it matures a lot of other industries
right consumers
looking for consistency same pricing
things that feel comfortable to them
especially if they're new to the market
and over the last two and a half three
years since we started the company we
went from meeting with our first clients
that were running these you know middle
eight-figure businesses on whiteboards
text messages Google sheets to saying
well you know asking basic questions
what was your most sold product
yesterday oh we think it was this kind
of these subjective answers it was the
drink and then we're starting to see now
more of this professionalism maturity
around these businesses as they grow we
build tools for that I think that's what
clients at the end of the day want to
see the the results of so there's
definitely quickly growing which is
exciting to be a part of good morning
thanks again Susan for having us here
today to talk about brandy
so I can actually I'm going to talk
about branding from a different
perspective
I can I can talk about products we have
we manufacture a product that's infused
it's infused popcorn but I'm also I'm
also the co-founder of supernova women
which is an organization that works to
empower people of color to become
self-sufficient shareholders within the
cannabis industry and I bring I bring up
that brand because the that brand was
something that we were able to create
and create a movement behind it and it's
been a very powerful experience just
kind of speaking to two needs within the
community and getting people to rally
behind us so you know of course you can
also you build consumer brands and
things like that but when you build a
movement behind whether it's a product
or a need within the industry or an
industry need you can see a really
exponential growth behind that so yeah
movements behind brands
hey everybody my name's Dean rays I'm an
autist manager at c3 management I come
from the music side I've been working in
cannabis for a couple of years now
advising cannabis companies on branding
strategy marketing design packaging at
c3 we produce music festivals and manage
artists we produce Lollapalooza in eight
countries Bonnaroo Austin City Limits
and we manage about 65 bands The Strokes
they had in the heart Sylvan Esso
justice Phoenix Grammatik and several
others and so I've been kind of coming
into the cannabis based the last couple
years starting with the revolution as a
band a reggae band I've managed for 10
years we partnered with Flav Rx a couple
years ago to release some cartridges and
disposable pens so that was kind of my
entry into the cannabis space and kind
of looked around and saw that a lot of
the branding and and a lot of the
products kind of all looked very similar
and something that I've been trying to
do is is normalization in branding and
making sure that that you know when a
cannabis for that that my family and
other people that I'm not your
traditional and maybe newcomers to
cannabis can feel comfortable with their
consumption and that they don't have to
hide it and that the the branding is you
know it looks very similar to other
products such as you know a can of beer
or a bottle of whiskey and that it's
just making sure that it's fine that it
sits on the coffee table and that if
somebody wants to consume cannabis as
opposed to drinking alcohol and so that
was kind of what kind of what I'm going
for in that space is making people feel
comfortable about the consumption
there's absolutely nothing wrong with it
it's you know it's healthier than some
other products so I just felt like a lot
of the branding was kind of
counterintuitive to that process so I've
been focusing a lot on that and having
some fun and happy to be here
my name is Tim Marlon I am the
compliance and policy director for River
distributing a large distribution
company here in California my background
comes from I'm on the compliance side my
background comes I was a legislative
director for fiona ma who speaking soon
go Fiona's running for treasurer vote
for
we're gonna get my plug and before that
I worked for the state assembly for
probably about almost eight years so my
focus right now with with marketing and
with Pat with brands has been on the
compliance angle which as we probably
all know that's been really tough we've
had some major deadlines the July first
the grace period we have another
deadline coming for for branding and
labeling and packaging with the proposed
regs that will go into effect I mean to
be honest with you guys there are brands
that are not on the shelves of retailers
right now because of labeling and
packaging and this is a huge issue this
is something we fight every day a river
we try and work with our brands and help
them and give them the the blueprint and
what they need to do to get there their
package to get their products on the
shelves because we want to do that we
want to sell that it has been a constant
battle and we're gonna continue to fight
it so that's where I'm coming from I'm
sure we'll talk about this more during
the panel our next topic I want to talk
about here rather than just the
parallels on the mainstream is you know
have a plan you know most of the early
companies we've worked with we're kind
of shooting from the hip and creating a
plan as they went and I'd love to just
pose it to the panel what are some of
the essential elements you guys think
are necessary for a company when putting
together a go-to market or a yearly
marketing strategy plan once again guys
I'm gonna go on my compliance angle when
you're a brand you need to figure out
exactly what needs to be on that
packaging so you can sell it that's step
one work with your legal counsel work
with your distributor if you have a good
distributor that I'm sorry of kind of
bragging but they're gonna help you out
with your with your labeling and make
sure that making sure that's compliant
and they'll work with you I spend a good
portion of my day working with brands
and just advising the engl advising them
on what's compliant labeling so start
out there and that's my two cents on
this and I'll let all these pros here
jump in I would say you know figure
to call what your story is you know who
are you what are you about where do you
come from what you know what is going to
be that emotional connection between you
and your audience and your brand and
your marketing and your design and your
social media and and your photos and you
know your articles and what is your
story
don't just be you know figure out the
core like who are you why are you doing
this where do you want to go and and
build a connection and try to find an
audience that agrees with that and give
consumers something that they can
connect to that they feel a loyalty
towards your product whether it be you
know a cause who are you giving back to
what organizations are you supporting or
you know what's your sustainability
angle what good are you doing as well as
you know where is your product coming
from tell tell the consumers everything
about you because they're going to find
out and you want them to know so don't
just you know go deeper go deeper try to
find it something emotional or something
meaningful in there without just
throwing you know a product into the
marketplace and expecting people to want
to buy it you know there has there's so
many products and people's attention
spans are so quick that if they don't
like yours they're gonna click to
something else and go somewhere else
try to draw people in with something
meaningful yeah I couldn't agree more
Dean I think that's it's one of the most
important things and a company we all
know and probably have a device in our
pocket from which is Apple their early
mission statement was about the Y right
it's not to make great cell phones and
sell a lot of product it was to make
devices that make communication easier
for human beings and I something along
that lines I'm paraphrasing but then it
was okay in order to accomplish that why
we're gonna make tablets and cell phones
and reinvent all of these devices order
to do that and that was really the story
and the reason behind it and why people
got behind every product that Apple
brings is because they connect with the
why of the company and I think it's
tremendously important yeah I just want
to build on what Dean mentioned as well
telling your story is is essential and
connecting with your audience is key so
making sure that
the visuals on your packaging the
imagery that you choose and marketing
your product whether it be on social
media or on a billboard that it connects
with your audience and who you're trying
to target and and all of that and also
be genuine be very genuine and be
transparent people want to know where
their cannabis is coming from they want
to know what they're putting into their
bodies people really want transparency
nowadays and that's why the
farm-to-table movement it's a so huge
and had such success and people are
smart smart consumers we have the
internet we have information within the
palm of our hands that we can access
right away so you know and and and and
all of that also plays into building the
movement behind your product well if you
can do this successfully you can get a
lot of people on your side and and once
you have a customer for life that person
is going to tell everybody about your
product so yeah just be genuine be real
connect with with your audience and yeah
I just want to add something real quick
sorry to what I was saying doesn't only
pertain to like physical products if
you're a grower your brand is who you
are and how you're growing tell people
the nutrients that you're doing tell
people what you're doing tell people
where you're selling to if you're a
distributor you have a brand this is
what we do this is how we take care of
people it's not I don't mean brands just
in terms of luck a you know a jar of
flour on a shelf I mean like everything
about your company if if you are you
know anything within the industry you
have a brand you have a story you have
an audience whether your audience is b2b
or b2c or you know if it's consumers or
if it's other professionals everybody's
paying attention so don't you know don't
take for granted that people just know
stuff about you try to make sure that
that you're telling who you are and why
you're doing what you're doing I think
it's a great point like when a lot of
the companies on our platform so you
work with you know some leading brands
like Kia and California Juana and
Colorado's suits up in Washington but
there really isn't yet
a national leader there's no Coke no
Pepsi people like market caps might say
otherwise but that's just you know
that's just today what we are seeing is
a lot of companies are pretty small and
they're looking to scale and getting to
other markets and I think some of the
mistakes that we're seeing happen is we
have companies that launch in Michigan
or will launch in Colorado because they
work with us in Oregon and a lot of
these are startups right everyone is a
start-up to a varying degree and the
eyes get really big we want to be craft
so we have to be everywhere and if you
in the more internal operational side
haven't really set what your mission
what your goal is how you should be
known as I mean it's a business right it
has to be operating at a certain level
efficiency with accountability and
transparency to actually be successful
and so we're seeing mistakes like people
jumping into these shotgun marriage
jayvees in other states to meet
residency requirements and just to get
live and what's happening is if you only
have a team of 10 to 30 people in state
1 and you want to be in state 2 and 3 in
the next six months things just start
getting so sloppy and so forget about
the beauty of the packaging or the
mission at the end consumer sees if you
can't keep it straight internally and
have a consistency of who you are as a
team in a company forget about I mean
being yeah it's it's it's really through
and through from what we've seen coming
from the creative side I think we get a
phone call every single week and it's I
need a logo and I say you got to
rephrase your question because it's not
about a brand of so much more than a
logo a brand is so much more than a
package a brand has like many many
multifaceted prongs and it's really
important that that brand strategy that
written word is completed first before
you ever put ink to paper don't get me
wrong I love putting ink to paper it's
what I get up in the morning and do I
want to create I want to make design I
want to create a package that's gonna be
unforgettable that you want to bring and
share at you know with your friends I
want it to be resin the biggest thing
also is it needs to resonate I just came
back from Denver cat Joe we were all in
Denver for the past couple days and you
know six years have passed and I still
think that the net was cast really wide
and it was kept it was cast by a
category called cannabis it wasn't cast
by a
nating audience driven why I think that
that's a moment here in California where
we can we can expedite what that process
looks like by thinking of brand strategy
first so instead of looking at you know
a big net that's being cast and we're
all going out into cannabis we're
actually you know we're actually
targeting a person on the other end who
wants to resonate with the product that
believes in something that is bigger and
beyond and I think that that's really
important so think beyond a logo think
beyond package think about the strategy
first and really make yourself stand out
and be different and be authentic
because if that happens you will pull
out from the crowd I'll tell you going
to Denver there was only a few people
that really stood out to me and it was
just all very similar and homogenized
and I think that if you saw real brand
strategy you knew immediately and it
popped off the shelf and it maybe even
sometimes wasn't there package maybe it
was the way it was merchandised maybe it
was the fourth for that patient who
needed to open that child-resistant
package
innovation we have in California right
now and we have a really big chance to
do it right
totally great and so we keep hitting on
packaging right and it's become and I
remember back in a day when the retailer
that I worked with was I'll do retailer
didn't even have packaging you'd have to
bring your own baggies too now we have
the most sophisticated packaging I think
in almost any industry with some of the
child proofing that exists how important
is it what do we need to consider how
expensive is it how much should a
company be contributing into its
packaging design and utility let's throw
that go ahead yeah you seem excited I
can talk about this because what I I
have a lot of I feel your pain because
we can't design against it right now
because we don't know exactly where it's
gonna go so I do feel the pain of the
industry because we cannot create the
package yet based on where the rigs are
we don't we don't know where that
child-resistant mark is gonna land with
that said I think that's also a mistake
that's happening right now with brands
is they're thinking like they're pulling
back and waiting because they're just
like I'm not gonna invest in my brand
yet because I can't I don't know where
child-resistant it's gonna go that's
good
lose you have to come out and strong
with your brand and still feel like oh
oh I'll be able to pivot when I know
what the rig's are gonna look like so
that's just something I want to say as I
see too much of this pullback of people
being like you know I don't know what my
brand looks like yeah and it's like your
brand isn't your package I don't don't
stress but I feel your pain because we
don't know what where that's going sorry
I don't mean upset the order no but
please please whatever you do if you're
a brand do not wait for the regulations
to drop just can just act like you're
under the regs you are now and it has to
be in child resistant packaging because
if you're not and they do take out that
requirement guess what can't sell your
product you're going to be waiting to
find packaging and and that could take
months
well I have brands right now River
represents 30 brands I have brands right
now who can't haven't been able to
secure packaging and that's the only
reason why they are not sitting on
shelves of retailers right now are being
sold are you guys seeing more packaging
locally or from abroad is that mainly
from abroad I mean you know I mean to be
honest a lot of it's just Chinese
packaging though and I don't know how
the tariffs are going to affect that so
there's a whole host of issues but just
be proactive
I think the child resistance standards
are the child resistant packaging will
be placed on the retailer's ultimately
just kind of following what's going on
in Sacramento but you know be prepared
be prepared if it's not because if
you're not you're we can't sell your
product have a little bit of wiggle room
with not knowing what was going to
happen with the regulations I went out
and bought a 10 thousand dollar Epson
printer label printer so we would have
the flexibility to be able to print
in-house no matter what regulations
changed tomorrow okay we go to print so
yeah just be smart about it and invest
you know don't invest 10 grand and
pre-printed packaging and the rags
change in six weeks you know I have make
sure you have some flexibility
and sorry to jump in again don't think
you're gonna fool a retailer because
they're pretty smart right now they
refuse products even product that's
compliant because they are seriously
nervous about taking product that the
BCC is just gonna pull off the shelf
during an inspection so everyone's
paying attention distributors are paying
attention I pay attention I have to send
back product every day because someone
tried to get queued and placed it in you
know a bag that's technically not child
resistant or they didn't put the proper
labels on they didn't put the universal
symbol in the front of the product if
it's a manufactured product there's all
sorts of little nuances that we simply
just can't distribute your product this
is it these are big I have retailers who
who will turn down products like flowers
a perfect example technically flower
doesn't is not a manufactured cannabis
good and it really doesn't need the
universal symbol because CD pH regs
don't govern flower
however retailers are freaking out about
it when there is a universal symbol on
the back but it's in a different color
and they're simply trying to refuse this
product so I have to get on the phone
with the retailer and we have to go back
and forth and then I have to dig up
emails from CD pH saying that's not
required for flower and it's this long
process so I guess what I'm saying is
just make sure you're dialed in you're
not gonna fool anybody
you're not gonna fool anybody but you
know and this is get cute I'll just
place it over here but you have to
really follow this those guidelines that
the states giving you it's I think it's
a cool opportunity at the same time
right because we have there's one brand
of thinking of in California that we
went to visit their facility a few
months back and they had half of it was
just packaging that they way over
purchase and they knew it was gonna be
beyond even you know if we weren't gonna
be operating by a grace period or hoping
for another one this is what was gonna
be compliant in the very least and we
released new badges now on leaf link
that you can be a compliant product
people are asking and looking for it but
there was a whole like methodology to
releasing this compliant packaging which
kind of keys into some retailers are
smart but there's still like a lot of
lack of communication in the supply
chain and especially between buyers and
sellers and regulators so they not only
pre bought all their packaging more than
they
we're gonna need for the next you know
six twelve months but they also had a
whole like educational one-sheets that
went in with all the deliveries and
educated their sales reps to explain
this is you know what you can and cannot
buy and here's why because there's a lot
of ideas and there's granularity to
those ideas and what's okay and what
isn't okay so it's almost like launching
a product in a new product that people
aren't quite yet familiar with and
companies that did that seem to be we
could see their transaction on the
platform far and away where others are
really almost at a standstill they're
sitting on millions of dollars of
product kind of like what we were
learning to earlier yeah so one of our
recurring themes of the panel is the
regulation surrounding all of the
marketing and branding right so and it's
the first time in our industry at least
here in California that we've ever had
to deal with these types of threat of
losing your license so I want to segue
here into the don't lose your license
conversation and what are a few things
in addition to obviously compliant
packaging and everything being compliant
what are some pitfalls in just the the
overall compliance area that brands
should be aware of whether it's
marketing to minors or children or
caricatures or packaging let's talk
about a few of those areas one of the
issues that I dealt with when I first
came to River was marketing to children
I looked through all of our SKUs you
know looking for names had to
unfortunately tell a lot of brand brands
you can't use the word candy and what is
that started cutting tin but to you guys
what is your interpretation because it's
not 100% where you can and can't market
its marketing to children is kind of
what does that mean to River what does
that mean tahrir I mean we're just
overly cautious where you don't want you
know we look at these brands we looked
at the packaging this is really isn't a
too big of an issue right now but you
know when I first came there where we
were really with a fine-tooth comb going
through these brands and and looking at
them and looking for keywords looking
for cartoon figures and stuff like that
it was kind of silly but it's actually
something that we had to do because once
again you know we want to sell these
brands but we can't sell them you know
when they have a certain certain names
in there that a lot of candies you know
like and it's very explicit in the regs
you can't use the word candy on your
packaging you can't and then as far as
what's like appealing to children
I'd really don't know
we had kind of had to take kind of a
conservative approach because no offense
to the state but there's really no
guidelines on they just say it and
there's this kind of like oh you
interpret it and there's this nothing
there so that's been an issue right
infringement is a real thing so don't
make a candy bar that looks like a
Hershey bar and call it stoner bar yet
real companies are coming in you know
and that's something that as Tim kind of
mentioned I've seen a lot of cleaning up
in the last year or two of you know
variations of Disney properties or
Marvel properties or Star Wars and that
was I think something that early on a
lot of brands would attract you and have
these limited runs and I think that's a
pitfall at least at this point because a
lot of the big boys are starting to step
up and their IP departments are
labouring litigation all across the
industry and from an advertising
standpoint you know as we all know we
cannot take out you know anything that's
federally you know FCC there's no
there's no advertising for television
radio so what actually is kind of unique
about this is you get to drive a
language in an organic fashion and I
think what we need to look at is making
sure that brands are very connected with
the end consumer through training and
through connecting with their retailers
and to make sure that they're educating
and changing and driving the message
about their brand for to the bud tenders
even and I think that that's really
important when we when we when I think
about alcohol and coffee there's a lot
of trainings that are coming from the
brands there's the distributors are
going in they're meeting and they're
saying this is this is how you
administer the product this is what the
product is this is the farmer that grew
it and that's an opportunity to kind of
do the advertising in a very internal
way while we still have a lot of you
know sort of requirements where we can't
advertise our brand social media you
can't you know we're no we're gonna get
into that but that's another amazing
place for you to drive your why you get
to drive the message you can account you
can connect and talk to the right people
that you want to have resonate with your
brand in your product it is an amazing
tool right now they can be used to grow
a very loyal following and I think it's
really important that that's that it
that's addressed and looked at yeah I
think let's jump into sorry Tim but
let's just jump into social media now
because you know
I've watched the industry grow and I
think it's been more of a community
rather than an industry up until this
point social media has been a platform
that was readily used by everyone and
I'd say like the cannabis industry runs
on Instagram essentially right despite
the fact that we can't advertise people
are touchy accounts are shut down every
other day it's the same as like the bank
accounts have always been so despite
that that does the cannabis industry run
on Instagram and social media how does
our panel feel that branch should be
activating and where should they use in
and what are good strategies for using
social media and other mainstream media
channels I think email is a great way to
connect with an audience as long as
you're not over emailing and pissing
people off because a lot of people do
that or texting but you know a lot of I
think everybody should be worried about
what platform that you're building your
audience because whose audience is still
on MySpace
nobody's you know those social media
companies could go away or they could
you know things could change so don't
just you know build your audience on
Facebook or Instagram you know use them
to reach an audience but really try to
collect emails and really try to you
know build in-person experiences with
people and connections because you know
those platforms could go away and what
types of mainstream platforms are you
guys utilizing or that you see it all
whether it be radio or television or ads
in print in magazines like what have you
guys seen be effective for the brands
that you guys work with oh I was a
former CEO of Magnolia wellness which is
a dispensary in West Oakland and I think
we were probably the first dispensary to
have a billboard
on 580 which coming from San Francisco
going into Oakland and we had that
billboard up for four years and we saw a
lot of success from that billboard
mainly because we were the only
dispensary in the state that had a
billboard and it was it's kind of
expensive but it paid off you know we
were able to kind of retract out from
track are we
turn on investment by seeing who was
coming in signing up and how they found
out about us did you find out about us
do weed maps billboard what was it
and so the Billboard was cool we also
did a TV commercial which was really
expensive I think we're one of the only
dispensaries that have TV commercial too
and I don't think that's very good there
but it was cool they would show our
commercial during SVU at night and but
print print print seems to be good but
you know I do agree with Dean here about
collecting emails because that's
something that you will always have
whereas all the other platforms could go
away you will always have a way to
connect with the audience through email
I think a lot of the main outlets or the
ones that are industry leaders are
pretty underwhelming at least on the
metrics that they give back on
advertisements click-through rates and
impressions are usually pretty pathetic
and then at times there are these very
like what we call like v1 tech companies
in the space doing pretty predatory
advertising regimes so there's that side
and there's limitations around where
like even getting access to billboards
or like public TV is is challenging the
nice part is the industry so small and
the community is pretty tightly knit
that are people ask how do we get to
2,300 retailers how do we have over 350
in California because we're we're
knocking on everyone's doors I mean you
could spend a few weeks and pretty much
meet everyone you need to meet in this
space and people talk and it's very
communal so you may not have all these
quick sexy methods of getting everyone's
eyeballs but you could pretty much get
everyone's bodies in a room pretty
quickly and then meet them in the
old-school old-fashioned way so that's a
good thing that we've done and I just
want to say everyone in this room is
here because we're probably an authority
on something or we have a voice in
cannabis and we need all of our voices
to be the advertisers and so I always
tell people please like be right go and
say you'll do an op-ed talk to media
connect with influencers who are
probably not in cannabis to change to
sort of change the tone and to get more
people that are not even thinking of
cannabis is something that they should
have as a as a budget line item and a
purchase and their you know in their in
their household to think of it as
something that they can bring into their
household and that's sort of the thing
that I want to say is that we need to
get more communal connectivity and media
to be talking about it and writing great
articles about brands that are doing it
well
cultivation that's doing it well and
that's our job to really raise voices
together yeah you know from rivers
perspective we have a team of 23 sales
managers who go out around the state and
sell the product but the brands that
work with our sales folks are the ones
who succeed the brands who do the ride
alongs with us who go out and promote
their own product with our team the
brands that show up to our sales
meetings and and educate our sales
associates about about the brands and
the benefits and the message they they
all want to convey and the story about
the brand those are that is so important
just just getting out there yes social
media and print and all that's great
but just getting out there and and
preaching your message and advertising
your brand those are the brands that
River really we really do well with it's
when they play an active part with us
yes we have the team we have the the
foot soldiers sort of speak to go out
there and sell the product but it's the
brands who actually step and get away
and advertise their products themselves
in conjunction with us they do well the
hard work wins right yeah it's gonna
take time you know it's gonna take a
long time you know you're not set up to
be able to get you know mass media
coverage and there are a lot of
limitations on the marketing if you want
to have a brand of any sort you're gonna
have to go down go out there on the road
foot soldier
go and make you know connections 1 bar 1
bar 1 bar 1 there is no launcher product
and immediately you've got a following
and you're selling 10,000 units and
you're it's gonna take a long time so
make sure you're managing your
expectations and the expectations of the
people that you're working with and
really put in the effort and put in the
time and be really passionate about it
because people can see that and they can
read it - one more thing
so when I moved to California four and a
half years ago I worked for an edibles
company with actually beer brothers
those two guys in the back and they were
my sales team here in LA and I was
working up north and we took that that
brand that edibles company from four
dispensaries to fifty dispensaries in
six months and we did that because we
were on the ground going from dispensary
to dispensary talking to folks we didn't
depend on you know it's great to have
River as a distributor or a distribution
company but you've really as the brand
got to go out and do your own work and
build those relationships yeah I think
the point here is that the industry is
still young enough and still small
enough that you could start a company
tomorrow work hard and still play among
the biggest in the game here and that's
available and work Yeah right come on
I think this industry is the epitome of
the American dream I've seen more
self-made millionaires than any other
industry I've ever worked in so that
that's why I say that but we're hitting
here a lot on the issues of the
limitations of advertising and marketing
right advertising is a part of having a
brand where do we advertise and pay for
ads and get get the word out there
because social media is limited
Instagram Google Facebook that's where
everybody else in the world and
advertisers and spends millions of
dollars we can't do it I think we've
seen a turn in cannabis to a lot of
influencer or celebrity branded
marketing right so there's been some
good ones there's been some bad ones
there's been how do we use celebrity
influencers how do we use just
influencers on on the ground the guys
who have 20 40 50 thousand followers as
well I just want to throw that on the
table and let's get a little topic going
there yeah I can speak a little bit to
the celebrity branded products I've
launched a couple of I've been paying a
lot of attention Tom will tell if it
works if people care it's difficult
enough to have a product on a shelf
especially in the state of California
period then to now slap a celebrity logo
on it charge a little bit more and
actually have that work yes it's going
to help because that celebrity has a
pre-existing following and an audience
already but who's to say that if you
know we won't use any names but we'll
say celebrity
has a huge following and they go and
they partner with you know a farm or a
manufacturer or something and they'll
end up getting a product on the shelf
you know if they're fans of their
audience walk into that dispensary and
they see that the product is at a you
know a higher price point because there
are more you know the pie has to be cut
more ways but the product isn't that
good and it's not as good as a much
better product that's next to it on the
shelf that's cheaper I don't care if
you're the biggest fan of celebrity X in
the world you're not buying that product
more than once and it becomes a novelty
item and the problem is that it'll ends
up being brand depreciating because the
the fan and the loyal follower of that
celebrity will go into the store and
look at it and get pissed off and go
what what are you doing you're trying to
sell me a product that's not as good
that's more expensive and you now you're
just trying to cash grab and you
obviously haven't paid attention to the
product you're not really a huge fan of
it and then that deadlines are being
depreciating to the celebrity or the
musician or the band or whatever so you
know I think I think everybody needs to
be a little bit careful about what kind
of products that they're putting out
there and people you know really need to
make sure that it's legitimate because
you could let it could land a backfiring
on you so I want to piggyback on that
that's a great point River we distribute
Cheech and Chong I like to joke around
so we got both of them and you're
exactly right it's about the quality of
the product yeah sure it's a novelty
like Cheech and Chong it's great product
we sell it all the time only because
it's great product and that's why we
have a team that goes out there and make
sure it's actually a good product
actually good flour because we know that
it's just simply not gonna sell yeah it
might sell right away and you know it's
gonna be a short time thing but that's
definitely one to piggyback on that on
that point as a distributor actually
carries two brands for celebrities
yeah I think what they bring to the
table is attention all right you get a
flash of look this way at your company
and they're you know encouraging an
experience and if that experience is not
through the roof people are for sure not
going to be paying your premium you know
I think that's a mistake that brands
make is charging the extra 20% over
their standard thing to cover the
licensing deal that they
just struck consumers won't pay it they
know they can get the cheaper name of
your brand version and not the shiny
package with the gold trim and it's the
same product inside so I completely
agree on that I think it works -
apparently it depreciates the brand it
depreciates the the celebrity or the
influencer involved
I think the net result is that they've
lost money all the way around that the
the envelope because it's expensive to
bring brands it's expensive to do new
packaging it's expensive to do photo
shoots and coordinate social media
content and do all these things that
most of the brands in this industry are
just brand new at getting so they strike
up one of these expensive deals pay a
large guarantee upfront and it's more
high-fives and pictures I've at least
I've noticed then actual value in ROI in
the relationships yeah it's not as cut
and dry as just creating a product and
putting it on the shelf I think
everybody in here knows how difficult
that is and how to bring a product to
market and I think you know if the
celebrity isn't like fully endorsing and
marketing the hell out of that product
dispensaries are gonna go why am i
carrying this product you're you're the
celebrity isn't even marketing it and
endorsing it and then you know you've
got issues with distribution and sales
teams and and people that are just
trying to cash in and put products on
the Shelf that they don't actually use
that aren't authentic to the brand and
you know and you know dispensary start
asking questions and they'll say like
well you know you just played a show in
the city why didn't you guys come in and
do meet and greets you know with
revolution we've placed a big focus on
actually going into the stores and doing
signings and doing giveaways and
marketing the products and posting
videos and talking about it because the
band actually really does use and love
the product and that comes across and I
think that people can see that there's
an actual connection where they're not
just trying to slap their name on
something and call it a day and hope
that dispensaries order the product and
that sales teams sell the product so I
think you know I think that's been an
issue too but it's also we we have seen
it work for us because you know
dispensaries are very open to something
like that and it's something special if
you know revolution just played two
nights at Red Rocks in Colorado and we
went into the clinic and we you know
they sat down and they did a table and
they did a signing and everybody who
comes in got a raffle ticket
tickets to a sold-out show and I think I
think dispensaries appreciate that I
think the fans can see that the band
actually loves and supports the product
and they're more inclined to support it
- yeah I think that's a big thing to hit
on is that the band or the celebrity the
influence or wherever it is needs to
love and support the product and I think
it's less about slapping that name on
the product and their followers knowing
that they love and support something
because that they want to participate
and they want to enjoy the things that
those the people that they idolize and
that they think are the the culture
tastemakers they want to participate in
the things that those people love and
and and and participate in not something
that has their face on it
right I mean in that and that's
something that's been traditionally
improving and I think other mainstream
music fashion apparel industries and now
that it's coming over to cannabis I
think we had a flush of put your face on
it kind of brands and really generic
products and we're seeing that that's
not not something that's been effective
and I think we're gonna start seeing
more of a generalized brand that is
supported by a collective of these
influencers that will be more effective
long-term you don't need to think about
your brand like this and I think that we
can look at other industries you can
have multiple products within your
portfolio that are going to be beyond
they're gonna be tiered there's gonna be
some or like limited edition you've
poured your heart and soul into it maybe
it does have somebody that's being it's
endorsed by then think of it look at
your portfolio and say well I want that
shelf space up at the top and I want to
have that beautiful high-end product
that I maybe spend a lot more time
curating or it has a little bit more you
know sort of you know something unique
to it and then have your space in the
middle where it's hey you might be
targeting multiple consumers but do it
in a way that's that resonates and has a
story behind it there should be a reason
why it's on that top shelf and there
should be a reason why you know that you
have another piece of portfolio that's
taking that bottom I mean not to do it
back to the alcohol industry but you go
into Safeway and there's there's three
people in that game and they've figured
out a ways to create brands that are
there sitting on multiple shelf spots
and I think that's one thing that I want
to say is look at retail look at what
retail is doing what retail wants the
biggest thing that's gonna happen is if
you don't have shelf space now you're
not gonna get it in a year because that
shelf space will be filled and if
they're doing it right there's no one
else that's gonna they're not gonna take
that brand off and put another brand on
so fill that shelf space and
do it in ways that are creating creating
a lot of value at each place yeah you
know and that's something we see with
brands you know everyone wants a
high-end brand that's all they want to
do that's great that's really great but
you know using the supermarket analogy
you're gonna want your Budweiser you're
gonna want your Sierra Nevada you're
gonna want some of those you know low to
mid to high high great products and you
want to diversify diversify your
portfolio as a brand otherwise you're
not going to command that shelf space
and the shelf space issue I could go on
for days seeing that as a distributor
that's been that's been an interesting
challenge for distributors and brands
because you have some places in the
state who some retailers are saying do
you have to pay me X amount of dollars
to buy this shelf space and this goes on
in the liquor industry as well actually
it's been outlawed in the liquor
industry but paid you pay me X amount of
dollars to put this on my shelf and I
can sell it and note with no guarantees
like you know they're gonna push your
brand or anything like that so that's
something as brands and its distributors
we need to have an honest discussion
about maybe sorry retailers I may be
making you mad right now but that's one
of the issues we've kind of been dealing
with yeah I think it's a great point is
look to the retailers in almost every
other industry in the world the
retailers are the one that determined
size of package type of product how many
are sold together they report back to
the distributor the distributor tells
the manufacturers guys this is what
works at a retail level and this is how
it's selling this is the product you
need to make and a lot of other
industries the retailer simply won't
take product which means the distributor
won't buy it from the manufacturer
unless it meets their certain criteria
to encourage the most efficient sales on
the store so the retailers are
eventually and it's underrated now but
you're starting to see retailers sell
the shelf space and understand their
equity in the game it's going to be the
determining factor on what product is
endorsed by a budtender or somebody in
the store level and what actually gets
sold so with that guys let's give a big
round of applause for our panel that was
fantastic include our question area
and I wanted to just open up here we got
our 15-20 minutes of question and
answers whatever you guys would like to
answer and if you just want to stand up
for a point and I'll yep perfect you
know the target segmentation and
everything that is really important I
come from the media marketing
advertising background and I just wanted
to kind of expand a little bit that yes
that is definitely what brands and
products need to do is to really look at
you know a strategic target segmentation
what I also think that in addition to
that the market research is also very
important understanding the market
trends and the category that you're in
what percentage that they're kind of but
I was just saying as well as competitive
you know analysis and so forth that it
is really important to understand and
you guys were talking about in terms of
you know the the aisle and so for the
competitive analysis and information is
just very important for brands to make
sure how they can also play in the same
sandbox
I completely agree and that's and I you
know when we when we look at brands in
other industries coffee wine commodity
products that we work in we have data we
know that that person who is 35 years
old in San Francisco loves herself a
Pinot Noir we don't have that yet we're
gonna get there but you know the fact
that we're not data collecting and we're
in it there is a lot of security and and
things at the dispensary level it's
going to be a challenge so back to what
Dean said you have to control the end
consumer get their email talk to them
because you're not gonna get it from
anywhere else there's no way that you're
gonna get that information right now at
least so really try to get as much and
gather as much information about who's
buying your product because that's the
only way we're gonna do it but thank you
that was such a very good point I just
wanna elaborate on the collecting emails
I'm sure everybody knows but just in
case an easy way to do that is to just
put a email signup form on your website
you know right as the website pops up
chances are it's gonna say are you 21
and over
yes have the email website up there when
you're going in and you're doing
in you know in dispensary demos have an
email signup sheet and just say hey
someone comes up like I love this
product to really help my back cool sign
up give us your email address then the
next time we launch a new product you'll
get it first or the next time we're
coming back to you know Santa Ana at the
from the earth dispensary you know you
well you'll know first and you can come
in and you can you know check us out and
give us your email and we'll give you
discount codes and we'll you know run a
contest on your website and say sign up
for an email and it will give you you
know 15% off your next order of whatever
the product is be creative give people
incentives but you know technically
that's the way you can go to companies
like MailChimp and they have software
that allows you to import all of the
email addresses that you've collected
and then easily export and send out an
email with whatever you want to design
or put on there I wondered if you could
comment on maybe some less direct
marketing things that companies can be
doing something I really appreciate is
having like a longer-term vision with it
and education programs and sponsorship
where it's not necessarily directly
trying to sell a brand or product but
educating the consumer on how to use it
and how it might be beneficial and some
of the companies that are maybe using
that approach as their way of getting in
front of the consumer yeah I think
collaboration is key and those things so
for instance I'll just use my own
organization supernova we do a lot of
outreach to black and brown communities
we don't necessarily do expungement
clinics because that's very
labor-intensive so we've partnered with
SSDP and they do expungement clinics and
we just sponsor them so you know yeah
sponsoring with other maybe nonprofit
organizations or any organizations that
are doing educational outreach and just
your logo being on there its brand
recognition you know takes five five to
seven times for someone to see your logo
and weirder for it to really kind of
click and resonate with them so yeah
yeah it makes a lot of sense and and
with that it's really just a lot about
collaborating with other folks you know
you don't have the bandwidth to do
certain things you collaborate with
someone that can and all of our top
brands have River do that I mean they're
doing that they're going out and
promoting the benefits of their products
with the retailers alongside ourselves
team so yeah yeah something that I've
seen be very effective in that regard is
you know supporting the community
holding it up being a part of it and
participating right the the the most
successful brands that I've seen to date
are the ones who have invested the most
in supporting and hidden ways right
helping other people carry boxes helping
companies use their license when they
were going out of business
housing people during the fires this is
not things that hit the news headlights
but our brand equity and building within
the community like building up your
social equity is a very real thing here
and the industry is still cottage enough
where that has a ton of value and I just
just adds that get on nonprofit boards
in your community we're not seeing
enough people in the cannabis industry
having a voice in powerful boards I
believe there's a lot of nonprofits that
could use educate more education and
there's no there's not even the thought
of a cannabis industry having a seat at
the table
we have banking we have you know a lot
of big health professionals we have
elected we have people in different
industries sit on boards be a voice I
work a lot in food and agriculture we
were just doing this huge event called
women and AG and I was so disappointed
that there was no one represented in
cannabis how is that even possible that
we're having a you know a legal
environment here where people are
growing something and that there was not
one woman in cannabis so please sit at
the table please make sure that you're
on nonprofit boards even outside your
industry you know it's awesome it's a
great way for you to show that there's
there's brand equity and that you're
also making a difference
get on your chamber or local Chamber of
Commerce I mean you guys we're an
economic powerhouse we're bringing tax
revenue to the door for these cities and
for the state will bring more eventually
to the state that's been a another issue
but we are really an economic powerhouse
and this you know cities are looking to
us for a lot of for revenue they're
struggling see all these cities are
struggling they have pension debt they
have all sorts of debt they're looking
at the cannabis industry to kind of help
solve those problems so
we do have we do have some power when we
come to those staples yeah absolutely
I also do consulting around branding and
packaging work so I wanted to ask each
panelist just real quick can you name or
think of one brand besides your own that
you love the design you think the
branding is on point something that's
really sharp and that stands out to you
in today's market I think broccoli
magazine is doing an amazing job I I
think it's beautifully designed it talks
to me I love lifestyle brands I left
kinfolk I love great design and I think
broccoli magazines doing a great job the
people that are advertising and broccoli
magazine are doing a great job
from a product standpoint I think you
know Bebo is doing a great job bloom
farms bloom farms does a great job for
multiple reasons great packaging great
design but even better transparency in
their storytelling I feel like I know
the cultivators I feel like I know the
farmers and they're doing a great job
through social media I think I'd say
dosis there's done a really good job of
spanning people that are not in the
industry again and to understand the
value of the brand and then also there's
a lot of brands and make a lot of noise
but don't have the sales that really
follow on being existing they do and so
I think that would be one that I'd call
that I have to be a fangirl to you and
say big Pete's treats Vic peach treats
website just blew me away it's amazing
so awesome and really the story and what
big peach trees has been doing over the
years you know they participate very
heavily with in Santa Cruz community
they do a lot of beach cleanups they
work with with the veterans in the area
and Santa Cruz veterans Alliance so I
mean I have so much respect for big
peach treats I think they're doing an
amazing job
I think Flo Connor is doing a great job
I think their storytelling is great I
think the message is great I think the
designs are great I agree with with
dosis I'm a simple man I like the clean
lines
I like minimalism I think they're doing
great in terms of their packaging and
their design I don't necessarily like to
be told how much I should be consuming
for like the DOS part of it with the
vibration
that's just my personal opinion
sometimes I like to take a smaller or
bigger and I don't like to be told you
know you need to be doing this much
because each person is different but
their packaging is outstanding and I
really like what they're doing with
trying to push sustainability and and
recycling how they have the drop
stations and the dispensaries I think
that's really cool too I'm going to use
two brands of river carries lulz and
utopia I think they're all doing a great
brand especially utopia on you know the
community benefits once again based out
of Santa Cruz they're just a really
great company really great people so is
lulz I think they're killing it there's
other brands out there like and acid and
stuff that I feel are doing really well
so kudos to them we need more of those
yeah and I think for me it would have to
be Apothic Anna from a lotion SOT I
think their aesthetic and their their
company angle ambition is one that
really resonates with us and a lot of
people in our in our kind of world and
on the other end from like a flower
product I think Henry's and their story
and their packaging and the way their
employees and the way they talk about
their brand or their language is
something that they've really
[Music]