[Music]
I'm a small farmer in Mendocino County
we have applied for the 5,000 square
foot permit but probably only have 2,500
square feet and cultivation currently we
have been farming in Mendocino for the
last 5 years and we are in the Willetts
appellation of Mendocino County and I
think what makes us or our small tiny
little 5,000 square feet farm unique is
that we are at 2,500 feet elevation we
have a lot of afternoon shade so we're
not in full Sun we have really warm days
but it never gets over a hundred and we
have cooler nights with a nice breeze so
having cultivated in different counties
around Northern California I've found
there's something very special about
that combination for where we are that
produces a really high-quality resin
content and a really nice looking Sun
grown flower there's not as much dust in
the air for me so it stays cleaner for
the first few years we have been really
into testing genetics so we we tested a
lot of different varietals and a lot of
different genetics and I have really
kind of started enjoying the orange
varietals I think they have a really
lovely terpene profile and something in
that area makes it very clean tasting so
you really get the the orange flavor
they have been pretty good at pest and
mold resistance especially in that area
because we do get some moisture coming
in from the coast so something that's
mold resistant and not a really super
large flower but still dense nugs
I find that some of the more oh geez or
larger denser nug profiles tend to not
do as well although I'm really excited
this year we are testing some from a
friend who has a genetic company on the
coast who's been doing mixes and have
kind of acclimatized to the the wetter
areas so his name is Jessie Dodd with
bio vortex and he's an amazing amazing
cultivator and regenerative farmer so
yeah really excited to see how those
genetics do so we grow all of our plants
in the ground in soil and living soil I
think it's becoming more it's becoming
more popular it's coming back in my mind
growing outdoors in the ground because I
think that's how it originated that's
how a plant grows but I think because of
prohibition and moving inside people
took to growing in pots and then when
they could go back outside they just
kept the pots so I think that it's
unique to us but not just to us it's not
a Mendocino thing I think it's becoming
more popular especially with the terroir
and the Appalachians becoming a point of
focus people I think in order to really
know how your terroir affects your
cannabis you have to be in the ground
you have to be in your terroir for
people that are not growing in the
native soil in pots they're not really
experiencing the full terroir or their
full appellation so I would go as far as
to say they can't really classify
themselves in any terroir because they
were only like halfway there they're
only getting the outside elements as
opposed to what's in the ground and
what's in the ground is so important
because it's what's feeding the plant so
we do all compost teas we actually my
partner is the mad scientist behind our
compost teas he's who I've learned
everything from he's been on this beyond
organic growing practices
for the past five years seven years so I
can't I don't know that compost tea
recipes but I know that we basically
feed our soil stuff for the bugs that's
in the soil and then the bugs are what's
feeding the plant we don't use any
liquid nutrients or fertilizers we
actually don't use any pesticides or
fungicides we actually have a full
integrated pest management program that
I've been working on for the last two
years and I've really found really
awesome success with outside I think
it's not about like not having anything
out there it's about maintaining and
knowing your ecosystem and so I have
with the testing regulations and
everything going on right now our
biggest battle is microbiological but it
feels good to not ever have to worry
about the pesticides well we have a
50-gallon brewer and we have a 1500
gallon Brewer that we only have five
acres and when we got that one my
partner's intent was to do like all of
our other vegetation as well because at
1500 gallons of tea is a lot of tea it's
been a really interesting and amazing
learning journey for sure learning
everyday I think if you're not learning
you're not doing it right well we use
ladybugs so pretty constantly we use I
just released our last release of cocoon
muris mites and californica s-- i like
the slow release sachets of the cocoon
murus because seems like they like to
stick around we also use green lace
wings we've used Trico
dirt awesome some of the names I'm a
little but for for moths for
caterpillars we use an der Sony and
Swarovski I don't know there's there's
kind of a own array depending on what
you're trying to combat and for me I
like to kind of have a
steady supply of a good few of them so
yeah I'm still learning I think it's
super fascinating and we've been working
with a beneficial and sectarian reading
and I've been really excited to learn
from them and Kelly Vance that's really
going yeah
[Music]