over the last year I like many of you
have been dealing with a new thing in
this industry I've been I've been in
this game for 12 years I've done
everything from trimming bud to being a
mule to packing flowers from humble to
Los Angeles and it's been a a really
remarkable journey I've learned a lot
but now we're getting into something
that I know very little of and that's
keeping paper records and complying with
state law so it's a new world we're
entering in and it's probably the most
difficult part of my business today is
figuring out not only how to be
compliant today but where is this all
going and so on the stage with me today
is Sherwin Omron at the end
Chicago based ethos manufacturing he's
the chief technical officer in the
middle is Brett Pritchard he's here in
California he's part of the owner of
results matters group a consulting firm
that's been getting not only myself but
many many many cannabis companies in
California compliant and Andy spoone
really good friend of mine as all these
three gentlemen are he is the CEO of
ethos manufacturing and Ann and Sierra
the chief operating officer of Sierra
labs Sierra labs has been working on FDA
compliance for many years Andy's been in
the FDA compliance space for many years
writing software that gets
pharmaceutical companies and I'll give
you a quick introduction it's probably
better to read off this and just ad-lib
yeah so sure one of the chief operation
officer ethos manufacturing Sherwood has
comprehensive experience in the design
manufacturing operations of fluid based
processing systems and facilities a
graduate of University of Iowa yes
yes in political science is that a B s
and BS I gotcha
in economics with over two decades of
industry experience sherwin has
extensive knowledge environmental water
soil hydrocarbon and agricultural
processes and his manage operations
installed in a variety of far-flung
locales including throughout North
America Europe the Middle East and South
Korea his administration record that
includes bidding site selection facility
operation Personnel Management and
intellectual property management Andy
spoone has worked with multiple startups
and high compliance environments
including clinical trials medical
devices in cannabis most recently Sierra
labs was started to help companies
automate software and hardware
development processes to meet regulatory
demands and stay compliant Andy's focus
is helping ally in fast pace innovative
teams with regulatory frameworks and
quality systems and again just so I
don't screw up the Brett Prichard
founder of results matters group a
cannabis consultant that includes
project management for the application
process build-out business consulting
budgeting and compliance so that's the
real theme here today is is compliance
how do we get compliant how do we stay
ahead of that curve a lot of people
think that federal regulation is coming
down the line fairly quickly
what is the FDA going to say about CVD
consumption what is the FDA going to say
about smoking psychoactive compounds
none of us know so it's a it's an
interesting Avenue if you're looking at
longevity for your cannabis based
business you need to start focusing on
compliance today you need to start
looking at the regulatory landscape and
seeing where your business fits into
that into that model so we're gonna
start it out and based on your
experience I'm gonna start with Andy
what have you seen and based on your
experience what have where do you think
cannabis is going on a federal landscape
oh just a quick question just to get a
show of hands so how many in here own or
work with a cannabis company okay and
how many of you are those with your
hands raised are directly involved with
compliance
it's at those companies so cool pretty
good number so you know our perspective
from coming from the FDA space is we see
this being treated just like every other
pharmaceutical you know we're our goal
and working with companies like Travis
and producing cannabis based projects we
assume that's gonna go the direction of
just the same way that you would expect
GLP practices GMP practices to be
applied at a company producing Advil or
aspirin kind of a couple of interesting
things about that is it it has to
balance with the pace of innovation to
the standards and compliant workflows
and processes that come into that and I
think that's one of the biggest
challenges in the space right now is you
know how do you continue to maintain
that agility and as you just saw in the
past two presentations like things are
moving very fast with the technology and
it's still not completely understood
what are the best ways to extract is
still remediated I salute so I think as
you want to keep that pace up you have
to start thinking about okay how do we
start putting the processes in place in
our company that we can you know make
sure that we're producing consistent
product a product that can be researched
tested research studied and essentially
be dosed and I think that's where we see
it going as a product that that's stable
and that dependent sure and I was gonna
ask you
or maybe Brett to start out where's
where do you see the landscape on a
state level right now and and do you see
that this is the the beginning and that
there's a long road ahead of continuing
I know seek was coming up in California
in a year give us an overview of the
landscape today and and in your head
where it's going from here I think they
did a lot in the very beginning so I
don't think we have huge changes ahead
but they they have already let us know
that they will be changing it basically
every year and so they're learning from
either problems that we in the industry
run into that we then go to them and say
hey here's an issue adjust the regulator
so that we can deal with it partially
because of the innovation that goes on
and just things they didn't think about
but they're the cities and the states a
lot of it is around keeping track of it
from a security diversion standpoint but
also from a tax revenue standpoint and
of course the other big thing for them
is is the safety of the public so
there's going to be a lot there may be
more around testing or more around the
GMP issues that we make sure that
everybody is producing it as a
consumable product so I think that's the
the things that will it change as time
goes on
I hope there's more kind of making
things easier but it's not going to be
as in getting rid of regulations it's
just going to be hopefully filling some
of the holes and so it's been mentioned
twice sure when you know there's a lot
of talk about people like oh we're gonna
build a GMP facility or an ISO facility
what does that mean well a lot of that
really means keeping track of everything
that's happening in the facilities
record record keeping it choke up on the
bat the so record-keeping process
tracking maintaining and mullet e to
maintain and monitor processes that's
really what all these systems in the end
are it's the ability to be able to look
backwards in time and understand what
happened on a production side on a
product side on a process side for
safety side energy control hazardous
materials control all these elements are
driven in those programs and I think as
those things become more formal more
well understood and part of the
conversation that ends up as part of the
conversation with the regulator's so the
ability to keep that data flowing
upwards into those regulatory bodies is
and maintaining that conversation
between us between the industry and the
regulator's that's how this regulation
has been involved in a productive
fashion it couldn't just extend that a
little bit one thing to keep in mind -
anytime you're talking about gmpgl p.i
so you're pretty much all talking about
the same kind of thing which
how do you put records in front of an
auditor and how do you explain what you
do in a repetitive way in a way that can
be shown that if I do this again I end
up with this same result and one
interesting thing to go back and do next
week going back into your company is sit
down and see how would I explain this to
someone who knows nothing about how I
operate and there's nothing about what
I'm doing but if I - auditors show up
what would I put in front of them what
story would I tell them and start
thinking about that internally and
another interesting way that happens is
with new hires I mean how many of you
are hiring people at those companies
like probably pretty regularly right so
you have a new hire coming in you have
to train them you have to tell them what
you do what they need to be doing on a
regular basis that's a good way to start
sneak peeking into what an auditor would
expect to see when they show up at your
facility and want to understand what
you're doing there it's a good point you
know we've been seeing there's there's
tons of edibles hitting the market
there's you know and and and coming from
you know the the California regulation
through the cbfa but when that goes to a
federal level we're making cannabis
based food products nationally you know
give me an overview of what the FDA is
looking for the USDA is looking for when
it comes to those products so I'll kind
of speak from the FDA perspective I mean
that the main thing that they're going
to look for first of all is what claims
are you making as many of you know the
number one dreaded thing that pretty
much any entity making consumable drug
beverage vape is they want to make sure
that you're not claiming that it can do
something that hasn't been proven can be
done in other research studies that have
went through an FDA approval process and
I show of hands if you're undergoing an
FDA approved process in your development
right now so no one right so that's a
thing you don't want to be producing
edibles right now that you're claiming
can cure Alzheimer's or you know there's
a awesome series of talks right next
door right that are showing that there's
research being done to make those claims
but it's not there yet and
only one drug has actually went through
that process which was kind of a
double-edge short it was good in the
sense that you now can see that there's
drugs being proven that the FDA is
accepting our THC derivatives that can
be used to treat things but now that THC
is a recognized drug by the FDA for that
treatment of that specific thing they're
gonna be super sensitive to you claiming
it can be done for other things see the
cantilever warning letter that went out
this week so they claimed that there
topicals or things could treat anxiety
sleep depression a number of things and
so they got a warning letter saying you
can't make these claims and and that
could potentially slow down the
development of that product pretty
significantly and how it goes on the
shelves at CVS or Target or you know
where they're trying to put that
consumer based product in front of so
that's that's the first thing I would
say from an FDA perspective is be very
careful in your marketing material what
you are claiming publicly your your drug
can be done next going beyond that so
let's say I'm now starting to prepare
something i doing expect to engage the
FDA on it goes back to what you know
Bret and Shawn were saying I need to
start keeping records I need to start
keeping records of how am i producing it
who my suppliers are what technology do
I have in here how is it being operated
there's just a whole set of series of
things that you're gonna expect to show
from a you know auditor perspective
coming in to that facility one of the
really interesting things about that is
that record-keeping that processing it
that doesn't necessarily mean having a
perfect record or not having any
mistakes or any errors when those
auditors come in they're gonna expect to
see the things that went wrong and what
was done to address those things and
oftentimes companies will go through a
scaling process where they're
implementing ISO like processes and
everything's 100% compliant that's
actually a huge red flag of a process
that's not properly implemented because
it's not actually capturing the things
that are the improvement cycles that are
occurring in the facilities yeah there's
a little joke in the industry like if
you have auditors coming in and their
job is to go through and find things
that you're doing wrong like you
probably want to know where those things
are that you expect them to find so you
can act surprised and be like oh I
didn't expect to see that
you know when they find it and it helps
them feel like you know they're actually
doing their diligence but at the same
time their areas that you know that you
had some you know kind of soft or weak
spots or areas where you potentially
weren't following your processes but one
on the stage that I work a lot with
Clark new part LLP and don't use that as
your philosophy on your cannabis
compliance please because that they they
are looking for something and they may
find something but don't don't give them
something to find and going back to
products and processes it's remember
you're depending on where you are in the
chain part of your responsibility is the
due diligent is coming from so if you're
a in an extraction operation you really
need to know what's going on at the farm
where your biomass is coming from and
you can't just assume it's it's good
it's great from not only a financial
standpoint but it really could hamper
you if you get something that's tainted
god forbid it's something that's tainted
that continues to go through the system
so also remember that wherever you are
in the chain you're kind of responsible
for where all this came from it so we in
my facility we talk a lot about
deviation and how it affects batching
can you can you explain why deviation is
important like downstream product
recalls happen you can go back and you
give us kind of insight into that well
any of you that open question well so
how it's important in terms of liability
how it's I mean there's a what why is it
important I mean if you so we have
consumer goods hitting the Shelf
something in general consumer goods
outside the space every space the the
ultimate quality is important but the
the repeatability is is more important
and those deviations they create
variances in
the products that are out there in the
market space which those exceptions
become a lot of the way that the product
is interpreted from a liability
perspective from a environmental
perspective from a health and human harm
perspective the ability to control those
track those respond to them to keep
those extremes from becoming something
that's in the wild and uncontrolled
that's ultimately the thing that's being
that's most important it's a reason that
mass-market companies often get away
with a solution that's 85% because
they're very reliably 85% generally
that's a solution that's considered a
less risky solution than higher quality
products that have a greater degree of
variance that's often why there are
unregulated agricultural operations
dairy operations that really run into
trouble despite having facilities that
are some of the best facilities in the
world because the lack of that
traceability the lack of knowledge about
when those deviations occur they
introduce an element of risk and risk is
what generally drives regulators crazy
yeah and just to kind of go back up a
little bit higher level those deviations
are typically opportunities seen as your
quality team to figure out where
something needs to be addressed and it
doesn't necessarily mean you did
something wrong it just may mean you did
something that wasn't documented
properly or there may have been a work
instruction that wasn't exactly aligned
with a new piece of technology that went
into that process so I think you know
you got to kind of shift that mindset of
thinking that okay we don't need any
deviations because deviations are red
flags and we don't want those on our
books to thinking of no that means you
have a healthy quality program in place
like you expect to be finding deviations
and you expect to be improving and this
whole model of continuous improvement is
is kind of based on that idea is that
you make mistakes you learn from them
you continue to improve that's that kind
of leads me into the technology side and
you've all had a chance to see a slew of
different operations and different
equipment and and you know someone who's
been been kind of growing the extraction
business for the last six seven years
you know I started out with washing
machines in my kitchen doing bubble hash
to
you know plant sized or factory sized
processing and a lot of that was just
kind of throwing in equipment that could
be implemented today you know and that
was always you know he had a we don't
say this anymore but we used to say
compliance third you know like
production number one and then there's
something in the middle and then
compliance there I think you still say
it sometimes don't say that so from from
a mechanical an equipment side where's
our equipment today and how does that
translate to scaled consistent product
being delivered in the future and and do
you see some shifts in the in the
landscape where equipment that
everyone's really comfortable using you
know short path distillation or wipe
film or or new Qi filters for isolation
or whatever it is is that is there going
to be a shift to move towards equipment
that are potentially more automated more
data driven more consistent in the long
run yeah I mean I think that there are
there's a lot of chemical processes that
are implemented in the space for a
variety of different extraction
mechanisms that are at best currently
roughly defined where the manufacturers
have a reasonable idea about what's
happening everybody's rushing to scale
to reach new heights
that scaling is its course in a lot of
ways so as the processes become better
understood better to find things like
tracking those deviations so you learn
more about what how the processes evolve
over time I see that equipment being
we're fine to a very high degree
the other interesting thing that's
happening in the space is and it's it's
a consistent theme because of
prohibition I think in a lot of ways is
there's a lot of interesting mechanisms
know-hows technologies pieces of
equipment out there in other spaces that
are 60% solutions for what we're doing
the evolution of those pieces of
equipment from something that's a
water-treatment piece of equipment or an
agricultural oil processing unit to a
cannabis processing unit
that's really interesting stuff and it's
a very active live evolving it's
evolving a way that other industries are
not right now it's pretty exciting stuff
and I would say also we were talking
about compliance is make make all that
work together in your company so as the
the technical people whether it's
technical on the chemical side the the
process side or technical on the
software side make sure that all your
advances are interwoven with the people
in your organization that are
responsible for compliance so that you
don't kind of run past what you need to
do and you kind of have to look back and
say wait a minute
we quit tracking something because you
want to build a good foundation and keep
running with that and whether it's
people in your firm or hiring good
consultants that help you with that
but make sure that that those
conversations are happening kind of in
unison so that the compliance people
understand what the production people
are dealing with and where they're
trying to go and vice-versa that the
production people say yeah it's you guys
responsibility to figure out where we
got this from we're just gonna crank it
out because both people will both sides
will suffer if they don't work together
yeah but I'm a big believer in I think
compliance done right will make
production better I think that's a
universally true if compliance is a drag
on production over the long run there's
always hiccups there's things that need
to be worked out but over the long run
compliant compliance done right will
make will improve production throughput
the economics of production everything
if you think it through it will at first
when we all saw it it was like oh my god
this is going to slow everything down
but work working with the right people
working with you know all sides together
it can be a nice flow it's not that bad
and it's we're now seeing a lot of the
things that were implemented and just
strict cannabis regulations actually
dovetail nicely into the GMP and ISO
stuff because if we do produce a product
that has to be recalled we need to
number one know at what point it has to
be
called from but also where that that
misstep took place so we can go back and
fix it or maybe that you know it's it's
just something that happened at the
final stage I've seen it where
everything was fine right up into the
very end and the packaging is what you
know tainted something or whether it
started the very beginning with with the
farm yeah I just want to make a call
back to it's a great kind of thread from
Dustin's presentation earlier is you
mentioned machines and he spoke about
open sourcing machines and sharing those
innovative ideas I think compliance and
your regulatory should be another great
place to apply some of that same
principle like I'd love to think that
there was a community of forum there
were people able to go and discuss kind
of this is our interpretation of the
regulations and how we're doing it and
how it's working for us and being able
to benefit the whole industry by sharing
those ideas of how you're addressing
those standards and regulations agree
and the regulators would love to be part
of that discussion and they will write
the regulations in a lot of ways driven
by those discussions do you do you think
that's what's missing in the cannabis
space specifically that we're not seeing
enough voices speaking directly to it it
has always seemed to me that a lot of
people whose voices are being heard in
the cannabis space have no idea what
they're talking about so is that is is
how what's missing is that there needs
to be more true true story
it's probably a mixture it's a mixture
of too many voices that someone is
speaking loudly the squeaky wheel but
they don't necessarily they're not real
they're dressing their own issue not
something specific with the industry or
they're addressing it on a small scale
and we really need something that is
dealt with on a very large scale and
it's other other times it's a lot of the
people that really know a lot of stuff
sometimes stay quiet and because they're
so used to being quiet and so they're
not they're not bringing that stuff
forward and that's where whether it's
the political political advocacy or
working directly with regulators but
they I can tell you from talking with
them when things pop up new regulations
pop up or proposed regulations they get
tons and tons of input and I'm wondering
if it's just too much that they can't
really digest it when it's just a bunch
of noise and that's where these advocacy
groups and trade associations and things
like that if they can focus and not
focus on their own trade alone they can
focus on some of those things and help
the voices be a little louder we see an
interesting parallel not quite the same
as the cannabis but it happens somewhat
similarly in software and technology
development and pharmaceutical
environments so as you start shifting
from you know let's say 80's 90's there
a tech where a lot of these auditors
were writing the regulations of how to
regulate software in salt and
pharmaceutical development and now
digital health technologies that are
being put out there you can go get an
app on your iPhone that can help help
you stop smoking right to kind of help
the previous generation of auditors and
regulators that are writing regulation
think how to talk to the modern-day
software writers and software agile
technologies and software development
platforms you had to overcome a little
bit of arrogance from both sides of the
table and and I think there's a little
bit of that too like your auditors think
that they know you know everything they
wrote the standard
you're practicers and your developers
think that they know what's best cuz
they're able to go and and write the
best software I think you are going to
see some of that with the cannabis space
as well you get you got people from both
sides now maybe I don't know the
regulator's in the space it's it's
fairly new so you know maybe they're not
quite as thinking that they know
everything about it but you you do have
to have a little bit of meet in the
middle you know kind of mentality going
into those conversations
shirring a conversation we had a while
back that I remember about the safety
and compliance of the machinery using
and you know I know show of hands how
many people have used a a short path
distiller so I know many of you you know
we go on a we buy equipment from whoever
we set it up in our garage or lab or
whatever we have at that moment and we
we we start going and we learn through a
process of failing but as you scale up
we had this conversation about doing has
ops to see where our failure points are
and to see where can you touch on a
little bit and how important that is is
being part of the the roadmap to getting
towards a compliant facility yeah so the
process management from an industrial
scale involves trying to understand from
a safety perspective an environmental
perspective a hygiene perspective and an
operability perspective what your plant
is going to do what your facility is
going to do that's a pretty involved and
detailed process it's I think it's very
valuable it fits into the whole theme of
ISO and FDA compliant but it really is
about understanding every step every nut
and bolt every pipeline every pump in
your facility and looking at it from a
couple of different dimensions of
control of energy control of heat
control of pressures and and things that
can interfere things that could
introduce toxins or contaminants perhaps
even benign contaminants and being able
to track and manage those things these
these processes in order to have a what
would be considered an OSHA compliant
facility it has to be a process itself
it's
not something that should be started in
a day or solved in a day it never
happens that way but it's it will be and
I think it's going to be a very
important factor going forward being
able to manage those risks means being
able to continually make progress on
reducing those risks otherwise I think
what ends up happening is facilities get
shut down you could stop work orders you
get more regulatory review you get
auditors that are coming in that then
want to run through the same process and
identify errors that might be made which
that leads to further work stoppages
it's it's a mess it's it's much better
and more productive to stay ahead of
that I think and you're going to end up
having to do it anyway the cities the
state requires it to a certain extent
and the cities are requiring it more and
more as you build out the facilities and
go through the building and safety
concept the fire development services
departments are getting more and more
involved and they realize that some of
these machines that we build are big and
they involve you know pressures they
involve an employee safety environmental
all that stuff they're they're kind of
figuring out and they're gonna they're
gonna make you go through it anyway so
you might as well do it now get a handle
on it and you know liability there are
there are people lining up to sue the
cannabis industry and employee safety is
just going to be one of the the many
areas and so just like any other
building you would expect if you're you
know producing peanut butter.you if
you're working there you expect it to be
safe and you don't you know you hope
that the company has done everything it
can do to keep use and employee safe as
well as produce a safe product it's it's
really no different and these other you
know hamper cannabis and we just need to
recognize that and get get on board and
get your your proper people involved and
you'll be ahead of the game with a lot
if you're doing a lot of this quality
control and understanding what you're
the equipment that you're using that it
is safe for what you
using it for and that it's going to be
safe you have protocols SOPs all that
kind of stuff to develop a good product
and to do it well and it a lot of it and
I think from outside the industry from a
regulatory perspective from partner and
customer perspective if they were doing
due diligence on a large scale
a lot of it starts with respect for the
forces at work in the industry we deal
with things that are very hot and things
that are very cold things that are
potential asphyxiant things that can
catch fire things that are at
potentially very high pressures things
that can go boom things that can go up
and starting that discussion starting
the process the first step is is
recognizing and identifying at least the
sources of energy the hazards that are
out there and just understanding that
they need to be treated with respect
just getting to that point is is at
least half of the work honestly and that
and then final question before we take
some questions
you know we've seen we ate a company on
HCB over here in southeast downtown
building a pretty sizeable plant and as
we've had inspectors come through and
people come through that are in a
regulatory position they kind of don't
know what they're looking at and so it's
it's difficult in some ways to kind of
get them to process like you know cuz it
to them it looks like you know an
episode of Breaking Bad
Marya ly know what they're looking at
they don't know what it does how do we
get around that how do we educate how do
we bring those regulators into the fold
of like being comfortable with with what
we're producing I think part of it is
understanding their language what are
the things that they freaked out about
things that make things go boom or hurt
people and if you've already dealt with
all that you've documented all that then
when they see this and they say ah okay
and then you can walk them through this
is the precaution we put here this is
designed here here's the has
hazard associate analysis that we've
done then you're speaking their language
and they're going up these people do
know what they're doing they have asked
some of the same questions I would and
they've already gotten the answers and
they've already dealt with it so that
their that their blood pressure can go
down a little bit and I think part of it
is as they go through these inspections
they see this the other part is I know
part of what we do is try to develop
relations with these people so we can
find out what they're looking for so
that we can talk to the clients in
advance but honestly in some departments
they're still trying to figure out what
they want these things to look like and
so it's it's looking at other industries
and saying okay when they remain you're
fracturing peanut butter they wanted to
see this this and this so let's address
those same pressures and flammability
all the different things that we know
they're going to freak out about some of
that starts with some pretty traditional
activities if you go into a peanut
butter plant or a steel mill or a
plastics facility it's going to start
with signing and start with a short
safety briefing there might even be an
evacuation briefing an explanation of
what you're going to see perhaps a
brochure that explains it on a high
level and then you know questions in a
review and a tour those are kind of the
normal steps that are expected and it's
it's a relatively basic stuff it's not
for most people that are involved in
these facilities these are pretty
straightforward concepts that we we've
internalized we understand if you can
communicate them things that you already
know pretty well on a pretty basic level
I think that goes a long way to being
able to show that we take these things
seriously well and the not-so-fun answer
is you make it boring like taking sexy
out of the picture I think so many times
like you come in and people are very
fired up to talk about why this is the
best you know short path because of
terpene or compound and you're obviously
a fanatic about the product where you're
talking to someone who wants to think
that you're you're creating a water
treatment facility like you know you're
excited about like steaming something
over here so I think you know
from that perspective to that it's not
necessarily the answer I don't think
really anybody wants to hear but it is
doing some of those boring things and
and making it a little bit more you know
that's less exciting yeah intangible
yeah and Sherman rings up an important
point it's you're going to get inspected
whether it's just traditional
inspections that happen to any business
or whether it's specific inspections to
the cannabis or hemp business you're
going to get inspected so I think
preparing for that and knowing not only
do we do this with every visitor that
comes in they're gonna sign in they're
gonna get safety glasses they're going
to get a briefing on don't touch this go
this way if you hear this this sound
then if we get into the habit of doing
that with our visitors then when our
inspectors come it's like okay guys gals
we do this with everybody that visits
the facility sign in safety glasses
evacuation drill then again if they say
these people know what they're doing and
it's a it's a little bit of taken away
the sexy but it's also taking away the
fear that I know sometimes when I review
things I get to review a lot of premise
diagrams to make sure that there are
compliant with city and state
regulations and sometimes I get them and
from you know from the front page I can
tell oh I got this is gonna take a lot
of time they have not really gotten
anything right and I know I sit there
and pour over literally almost every
square inch of the drawing and other
times I get them it's like okay they've
got it oh this is right they've got they
figured this out and you're your guard
goes down because you feel like you're
dealing with a professional that knew
what they were doing when they put this
together and you're not so feeling like
I've got to find every single thing that
they did wrong because they did a lot
gotcha I want to open up we got a few
more minutes if anyone has a question
these are three great guys to talk
compliance with so if you have a
question raise your hand and we'll
identify you anyone in the room right
there in the middle
[Music]
I'll just take a yeah yeah take a step
you know that is something that's
amazing about the cannabis space we fall
under oh I'll paraphrase it yeah sorry
so what standards what regulations are
we looking at overall in AFP or is it
health and safety is it FDA is it you
know where do you go to to find what
standards are your you're falling under
like cover that yeah and I I think
that's the interesting thing about
cannabis specifically you know we we
make food products we make smokeable
products we make topical products we you
know there's so many things that fall
under so many different categories we
manufacture all those products and
buildings that could be you know a nice
sized boom machine for lack of a better
word so how do you kind of navigate all
those different regulatory bodies and
and and and make them work for you
well one important thing to realize too
is I think you you have roughly at least
three or four different angles of what
compliance means up on the stage here so
I think there's legal compliance which
is a lot of what Bret's talking about
your state your local hope soon to be
national regulations right that you're
required to just because you fall into a
business of cannabis right the other
piece of that is from a manufacturing
perspective right so if I'm putting in
an ISO 9001 quality system into my
facility there's tons of information
online of what that looks like it's a
pretty standard thing right and then you
start getting into you're making a food
you're making a consumable you're making
something that's going to be inhaled
digested that's a whole nother set of
things right and then as I start
bringing my different pieces of
equipment into that presentation you're
going to start engaging you know
potentially you know a fire
or some or co2 code or another code
that's from another industry or
electrical code from an electrical
industry so keep in mind it is a complex
topic there's there's there's probably
once again going back to the earlier
comment it's one of those things that
would really benefit people sharing
information of what they're encountering
like this is kind of in California I'm
doing this I'd like to talk to other
people in my area about how they're
addressing DC or how they're addressing
you have fire compliance or metric
compliance that's probably a great one
right there right I mean there's so many
people we talk to or saying like well I
know we're supposed to be doing it it's
really unclear what we're supposed to be
doing I just wish I could go talk to
somebody else that actually is going
through the same thing that's a that's a
big point right there if anybody sees
Dustin later on make sure we get a
compliance portion of that website built
before G long right there in the in the
right
so the question was how do people budget
for this activity and where do they
budget that from his era is there a
formula is there a percentage the easy
formula is budget more than you thought
it would be because that's everybody has
underestimated that and I would say
treat treat it like a business you've
got different pieces of the business so
if you're doing you know equipment
compliance and safety that's going to go
into the you know the buying or the
building of the equipment you're
probably going to have a legal budget
you're going to have a business a
staffing budget that's more of your
human brain power compliance issues and
you know if you're producing products
that fall into the FDA realm we've seen
a lot of different facilities and I
would say almost every single one of
them have one if not four or five people
that that is their only job is to know
what the rules are to train the all the
staff in the facility to follow those
rules and then a team to continually
watch to make sure that as we're doing
it we're following the rules so it's
really budgeting it I think falls into
the different areas and it's all gonna
be on the scale but generally people
have under under budgeted that it's I'll
just mention this it's it's a lot
cheaper line-item if you start it at the
beginning that if you try to bolt it on
later retrofitting in compliance quality
safety these are very hard expensive
things yeah and just one more coming on
that which I think it just mentioning
once again like all things compliance
its risk management based right so
assessing what are the risk I exposed
myself to and aligning that to what the
right dollar spend would be against it
if the risk is me getting shut down and
having a million dollars invested in
this license in this facility
evaporating out from underneath me you
know you probably want to allocate a
chunk of that in to protecting against
that from happening
and one one real quick add-on to that
as working with your whether it's
architectural GC your engineering firm
because some of this some compliances
flow you can make it really easy to be
compliant or you can make it really
difficult where people are having to go
back and forth from one area of the
building to the other to do what's
what's needed so think of it from build
a good foundation think of it from the
very beginning and build it build it
workable compliant good workflow
efficient from the very beginning back
there in the white t-shirt
I got it yeah so the question was is
there programs to start training
compliance officers compliance personnel
inside of companies it you know the
thing is this this is there's tons of
them and the interesting thing is this
is an industry that's kind of
approaching compliance is not a new
thing but as a fairly recent thing to be
aware that there's a whole lot of
training of compliance outside of
cannabis that will dovetail exactly into
what you're trying to do
for example USC as a regulatory affairs
program that produces compliance and
regulatory affairs people looking for
jobs in pharma I guarantee you some of
those students graduated from those
programs are very excited to figure out
what that looks like inside of cannabis
so the those programs are out there they
may not have cannabis on their name but
there's definitely people in them that
are very excited to get into the space
and figure out what that looks like you
know bringing those principles into the
space they're tuned into that frequency
yeah yeah so so go and blanking on the
names but asq the American Society of
quality regulatory affairs societies
international societies ISO obviously is
a huge one all those large networks
produce quality professionals and
training programs for quality and
compliance awesome and then right there
in the black shirt and then we'll just
last question right here
so the the question ons my GC and and
and the awesome question was he's
building out one of our facilities and
from a GC general contractor
point-of-view things keep changing we
keep putting new equipment in there you
know the plans have to change the
electrical has to get redone we're doing
a lot of research and development in
there so you know there's a facelift
every month or so and and and he's
wondering is there at some point they're
gonna be a stop and we're gonna say okay
this is it this is what we're moving
forward with sadly I would probably say
no there's no stop for that I just don't
think the industry's quite got there yet
I think you know you're you're still
figuring out what's the best technology
what's the right scale I mean what is
the right scale I mean it's interesting
just looking at the market of extraction
right am i extracting you know 500
pounds 5,000 50,000 I mean all those
have very different answers from a
compliance perspective and you're not
you know you're you're not um building a
restaurant that has a pretty established
like if I know if I'm building a
restaurant in LA this is you know how
you do it this is I know who I'm going
to talk to what inspectors are gonna
come in here I don't think you've quite
hit that that point yet in cannabis
build-out and it's gonna be interesting
to watch with him I I think one thing
that we haven't spoken very much about
yet is how hemp I think it's very
quickly going to dovetail into this
conversation as well and get treated the
same way as cannabis and and help
standardize a regulatory compliance
approach across and processing both
those points which is how it is in
Canada right at the hemp and cannabis
fall into the same same same legal
regulatory framework and I think also to
your to your question that's part of
that getting everybody to work together
because some things you want to find out
I know I I kind of sometimes find it
along the way with clients that they
want to build this and then they want to
build you know this times too and so
it's having that conversation if you can
because not all the time did they know
it what is what is the scale up on this
and as a result if we're putting in and
I'm just I'm just making up something
here we're putting in something that
needs a 200 hundred amp circuit today
and it's it's you know from a GC
standpoint or an architect standpoint is
that where we're gonna stop and a lot of
times the owners no no that's not what
we're gonna stop but we didn't ask the
question and so then it's like no we
would like to actually put two of those
in that's like okay well maybe we'll run
conduit for two or maybe we need to pull
a different transformer off the pole and
so it's us using what we know to help
the clients vision what they're gonna
have in the next you know three to five
years versus looking at what's right in
front of them because I also find that
in in the clients might there's a
thousand things running around in there
and sometimes the thing that's not there
is what we're gonna need to do to comply
with the electrical you know a year from
now and so it's us doing those that are
in the fire or electrical or plumbing or
whatever to ask those questions and say
do we need to do we need to beef it up
for you from day one so that you can
expand when you're ready and that's a it
is a moving target I mean we saw from
from dr. Calaway you know short path
distillation you pump something through
it and all of a sudden your your results
come out at 75 percent total
cannabinoids what's the other 25 percent
you know you know it's not water you
know it's not a solvent you've burned
all that stuff off what's what's the
rest and is that acceptable from a
consumer good standpoint if someone's
marking something on a box is 75%
cannabinoids that means there's 25% some
sort of inert material in there that
you're not identifying whether that's a
psychoactive material or or anything
else so those things really haven't been
established yet so I see that target
continuing to move as more regulations
come on board I feel we're in the boat
there's probably a long road of
regulation ahead of us and it's not
going to shorten anytime soon for
getting you relief from that last
question right here
[Music]
it's great yeah it's a great topic it's
getting a lot of discussion in the space
right now I think the interesting thing
is FDA's mandate is to protect the
public health
right and I think that it's easy for
them to look at supplements or
nutriceuticals and say there are lower
risks they take the same approaches
we're encouraging you to do take it from
a risk-based approach right so they say
hey I can go take these vitamin D pills
over here what's the risk of that what's
the risk of that producer being way off
target of what they put in there and
it's a it's a low risk and I think
that's how the FDA looks at that whereas
if I'm making something that I'm
claiming has ability to treat pain
relief or potentially has an addiction
component or potentially has a liver
impact they're going to see that as a
much higher risk so I think that's going
to depend on the you can't really steer
it from a PR marketing kind of strategy
you your doctors are gonna be steering
that for you and I think if you're
trying to do and reach the full
potential of what you think this plant
can actually do I think it's gonna land
solidly as a pharmaceutical compound as
I think what's being spoken about in the
room next door yeah and I would
recommend just on that note talking or
listening to dr. Jeff Chen who's speak
he's speaking about the war for
cannabinoids you know GW pharmaceutical
put out epidemics there's an analog THC
out there right now that's been on the
market for more than twenty years and
there are flags being planted in the
ground at the FDA as soon as the FDA by
law approves a drug then it is no longer
you you can't make it yourself you know
you can't go out and make opioids
yourself because it's under the FDA's
Burgh you has a drug so right now CBD
CBG CBC are all under a drug under the
FDA's regulatory approval system so what
does that mean why is there so much talk
about CBD and then and then limiting the
market for edibles and things like that
because that is already found those
flags have Arden planted in the ground
and then and Jeff will speak about this
probably more elegantly but he'll talk
about
you know what do we do to prevent that
well there's prior science right and if
we can start developing that prior
science and an open-source kind of
methodology then those patented flag in
the ground claims can't really keep
rolling forward but but jokingly embrace
it I guess that's kind of the joking
answer right instead of trying to fight
it I would encourage the industry to try
to embrace it I think that's gonna be
your best it's been the biggest
stumbling block and the reason for this
panel I've seen over the last 12 years
and and certainly after prop 64 in 2017
we had 30,000 cannabis businesses in
California today we have less than
10,000 why is that because people looked
at this new regulatory system and like
these guys are trying to screw me this
is too arduous I can't keep my business
afloat and they don't they don't turn
the corner but this is reality this is
what's happening and if you want to keep
your cannabis company moving forward
this is kind of what we competitive
advantages I think that's ultimately
this is leverage for you to stand out
beyond your competition you embrace a
new show that I can do these things I
have no problem with quality compliance
like then you're on the path to become
whether or not you want to be or not I
don't throw up I know Big Pharma's not a
good name here but you know if you want
to be the next generation of bear or you
know J&amp;J I mean that you embrace that
and that's gonna help you stand above
the rest absolutely thank you so much
guys I really appreciate you how big
around applause
[Applause]