[Music]
so Monique has a presentation now she's
going to talk about more of ways to be
involved in the state level as well
because we we've got to try to get some
relief here for farmers that are being
totally totally crushed by all the fees
and the market not being there because
it's across the board and so with that
Monique let's hear how we can get more
involved I'm just a small-time farmer
and I started getting involved in the
local policy by going to the board of
supervisor meetings watching Ron
watching KC from my television screen at
home watching YouTube and was like I
gotta get out there I got to speak to
this because this is really important
and so I have been really engaged just
as my own and so I went to the last two
state meetings that happened in
Sacramento for the cannabis Advisory
Committee and spoke during the public
comment period about the topics that
were important to me and my community so
I'm just gonna hit some highlights they
have I think 10 subcommittees and in the
interest of time I just picked out micro
business and the cultivation
subcommittee and just give you guys an
overview of where we're at with that
right now
so the cultivators subcommittee made a
couple recommendations that they want to
see the bureau of cannabis control
basically change in the current
regulation so this is hopefully the
hopeful part of our presentation today
the first two were the generator our
meters they want to amend section 80 306
number d to allow aftermarket non
resettable our meters to be installed
and the comment from CDFA was that
there's no provision right now in the
ordinance or in the regulation that
prohibits that but they still wanted to
get this put in because they feel like
it's not clearly defined for
public so that recommended motion passed
through the larger subcommittee the
second one was to add the definition of
outdoor cultivation by allowing the use
of light deprivation techniques that was
also a path or that passed by the whole
committee and then the other
recommendations were unfortunately in
statute so it has to be a legislative
fix basically okay so these ones we are
good it's gonna be a little bit more of
a battle to get them fixed
so I'll just hit them really quick
number one was composting a waste and
waste definition and the ability to sell
unused waste products that lack the
cannabinoids the second one this one is
really important to me personally
because I do have a twenty five hundred
square foot permit in Mendocino County
but the state for this type of license
only allows me twenty five plants so
they want to add square footage of
twenty five hundred and five thousand to
the specialty cottage and the cottage
license types it is Oh five thousands in
already just not the twenty five okay
cool
and then number three is to allow
cultivators to transport their product
to nearby licensed processors without
obtaining additional licensure that's a
really important one the ones that are
going to be in bold that you're going to
see in a moment these ones were taken
out of the the meeting in LA and they
wanted to it was my understanding to
basically bring those ones forward in
that meeting but the meeting went so
long that they didn't even have enough
time to really talk about it obviously
go back so the other one is to allow
cultivated material to be transferred
between a and M designation license
types until the point of sale this is a
topic that was discussed in a lot of the
different subcommittees and a lot of
public comment was expressed about how
cultivators really shouldn't be the ones
designating the crop as adult use or
medical use we should wait till it goes
to the retail location for that to be
ignited because the plant stays the same
the whole time it's really at the end
point that that should be decided so
that got a lot of support the next one
is to create a cultivation based tax
incentive for products being set aside
for compassionate use programs that was
a really important topic and they all
agreed to move that one forward before
the next meeting number six was
cultivators should be able to batch per
area at the time of harvest for track
and trace purposes and that they should
not need to identify each harvest back
to the individual plant number seven the
CAC make changes to the lab testing
system to address the burdens that may
impede a path to legalization such as
the loss of strains high cost
inefficient accuracy levels lack of
protections to the cultivator among
others they said that some of those
items are in statute and some of them
aren't so they have to kind of pick that
apart a little bit more number eight
consideration of issues related to
scaled licensing tears for nurseries
packaging of seeds in batch count by
bulk weight established genetic
repositories providing flexibility to
develop genetic diversity allowing
cultivators to transport propagated
plant material and seeds removing the
requirement for nurseries to designate
seed and/or plant stock as a RM material
allowing cultivators to provide
nurseries with genetic stock allowing
cultivators to provide other cultivators
with plant materials in an emergency
provided proper documentation for all of
the above and I just think it's great
like they're really trying to work to
fix these problems so yeah cuz we're
showing up we're speaking to it number
nine create a mechanism for cultivators
to conduct self transport distribution
of their own product to a centralized
processing facility manufacturing
facility distributor or a lab for pre
testing without the same requirements of
the existing transportation license
including BCC regulations sections 504 4
and 504 7 which really pertain to
cameras by either amending the existing
transportation distribution license or
creating a new license type this one
I'm really excited about and I really
hope we can work to figure this one out
because as a cultivator we need to have
this is a bottleneck right now in my
opinion if we have to take our product
to a distribution facility and then a
testing lab has to go to the distributor
to test the product I mean that's a lot
of movement happening so if we have the
ability to bring our product to the
testing lab that's gonna alleviate some
of that bottleneck so and that was also
voted on by the larger subcommittee
subcommittees and then micro business
the committee didn't even have a chance
to speak at the LA meeting because they
ran out of time and that meeting went
for seven hours I think they had a half
hour lunch break they didn't take any
other breaks besides that so this is
going to come up at the next meeting and
so I'll go ahead and go through this
these are recommendations related to
regulatory changes that can be adopted
the first one is about security
requirements for micro businesses and
that they should be determined by the
local jurisdiction and the regulations
should not be unduly burdensome to small
businesses and micro businesses there
was a lot of discussion during this on
this topic and that what works in LA
doesn't work in Mendocino County so
let's put it up to the local
jurisdictions to decide how they want to
maneuver the security issues number two
clarification of micro business that
includes tiers based on gross receipts
and the number of employees the fee
schedule should be redefined to include
a ceiling that delineates when the
business is no longer considered a micro
business incentives should be provided
based on equity for compassionate use
and rural operators on this one they
were really talking about at some point
a micro business isn't a micro business
anymore well in like where are we going
to cap it because people are going to
take advantage of this license type and
it's really designed for small farmers
small businesses to kind of be a
computer or a competitor against the
larger corporations but if large
corporations are taking advantage of
that micro license type that's an issue
so I think this will be a good one if we
can get that to be amended
then these are the recommendations that
do require statutory changes number one
micro-business licensees should be
allowed to utilize farm stand sales as
well as farm direct sales model such as
CSAs without a brick-and-mortar to
satisfy retail component of the license
number two all micro business activity
should not have to take place on a
single premise number three micro
business licensees should be allowed to
conduct offsite processing as one of
their qualifying activities and use
shared facilities for any of their
activities
number four recognizing that micro
businesses frequently cannot operate at
one contiguous location in large part
because of local land use ordinances and
that it can be cost prohibitive for a
micro businesses to obtain multiple
licenses an accessory license should be
created to tie premises together beyond
the simple geographic location while
ensuring that the flow of the product
maintained maintains a single chain of
custody and I just think there's a lot
of thought going into these subcommittee
meetings and you know a lot of it too is
the public getting up and expressing the
issues and the concerns and the people
at least that I've witnessed in these
panels they really are listening to us
and this is what's coming out of it so
see and so this is the next cannabis
Advisory Committee meeting is on May
17th and Oakland they haven't announced
the exact time or the location yet but
this is important go to this meeting
like really it's amazing like to get up
and to speak during public comment and
express what you're facing as a
cultivator or whatever business type you
have within this industry they want to
hear from us like these people are our
voice right now so unless we tell them
this is a problem this regulation
doesn't work then it's not going to
change and we have this opportunity
right now to affect it and it's really
empowering as an individual to just get
up and speak and have your voice be
heard so I hope that that's the takeaway
for all of us is that we continue to
stay engaged because this is our
livelihood this is our life and we're
not going to just give it up so stand
gay
and also make sure that you stay in the
firm like people sometimes people see
those and they think that the rules have
already changed and that's not how it
works so understanding how the
regulatory and the statutory scheme
works and how the law changes these
advisory meetings are critical towards
establishing better regulations and if
people show up at them and give public
comment then they're the people who are
listening to those are advising the
individuals making the law so you can't
read what was just said although these
are great ideas and these are things
that the industry is hopefully moving in
and walk away thinking that those rules
a party
[Music]