I'm a field operator that's what I'm
about I'm about getting product to the
table and I'm about helping farmers get
product to the table I just absolutely
immerse myself in the science so that I
can understand what product do I get to
the table and how do I get it to the
table and how do I get around problems
that are coming from other industries
that were involved in and so when Abrams
and I got to get together he came at me
academically but it wasn't aggressive in
a negative way it was like I want to
disprove approve your theory and once he
saw that there was a validity to it
which was awesome for me because they
let me know I was on the right track
because not every time does your theory
work out you know we all have theories
that not quite accurate and then someone
tells you and you're like okay I'll
adjust and that that's called
controlling your ego so you subjugate
your ego you get better information you
run down the road with the new material
and you do better and he was able to say
hey this is accurate can I use your
material to go play my own game with it
and I said yeah I'd love to because you
guys can do stuff I can't do with
Diagnostics scatter plotting you have
the ability to use scientific tools to
measure things in ways I don't have the
ability and you guys are statistical
geniuses so you'll be able to see
relationships in ways I can't and now we
can start to see how varieties really
lay across a spectrum so now we can
start to give people choices that are
accurate dispensaries an opportunity or
storefronts whatever we want to call the
modern in cannabis store the ability to
relate to the patient the customer
that's coming in and say look what are
you seeking and if you'd like a range of
products that reflect reality I can give
you a range here in ways that you like
so if you like flavor spectrums I can
give you stuff in similar flavonoid
profiles but on a gradient that'll say
similar experience through the mouth but
radical different experience through how
you in your head and that way what we do
is we start to be able to really work
with a knowledge base on customers which
then as producers it allows us to be
able to produce in a smarter level
versus strained as your because you
don't
this is constant new thing new thing new
thing I'm like you renamed it seven
times it's still Mendo purple yeah but
no it's still mando prep I don't give a
shit what you do DNA it all right it's a
perp and so why would you want to have
17 different perps and it's the same
with a lot of the oh Jesus you find the
best oh geez and that's what you work
with and you get rid of a lot of these
redundant lower quality ones that people
are playing with because ultimately the
buyer comes in and they look at it they
go there's 42 different ones how do I
know and so when I went into a
dispensary in Seattle my partner owns
dockside so dockside is the largest
Seattle the distributor dispensary in
Seattle so I go there they don't like
seven hundred varieties literally
there's seven hundred vary the board
that's on the wall it looks like you're
at a racetrack with so many different
horses running and you're just like holy
shit and it's overwhelming and I'm like
how would any customer ever get to
understand what they were looking at and
so you know I make it easy give me
something gassy give me something floral
and I ask the bartender
what are you into and they go easy this
is what's gassy that's hot this is
what's floral too taut and I've been
really enjoying this one recently so in
a single sentence I just knocked out six
hundred ninety seven farms slow velocity
and they sit and they get something
called dust in the Shelf but ultimately
the people believe there needs to be
variety in order for you to compete with
these other dispensaries you have to
have the varieties otherwise they say
truncated so like for me at my new spot
I did the opposite I shrunk it down
because I know that the majority of my
market is going to be tourists coming
through I'm gonna have locals coming
through so we can cover some very high
quality products that the locals want
but I want to make sure that there's a
gradient in in what's available and in
pricing so I'm not just trying to target
and peel you because I I don't agree
with that and I came from a different
background so I gotta get her a
successful family but I came out of the
hood and so all the years you're in it
you start to realize that not everybody
has a lot of money so therefore me
beating you to death on price all the
time isn't the way to go that's a
specific group so a specific group pays
premium prices other people pay less
prices the difference is in nuance
not in overall quality qualities quality
the nuances of the rarity the very
distinctions of what Lao with a
separation and so I want these gradients
at my new store but I want a truncated
selection so that when you come in it
only takes you ten minutes you walk in
what do you got we got all this stuff
right here this is what we have this is
what does this and then go great I can
buy it leave and they can go and do
their thing otherwise you're in there
for two hours and you're shopping and
you're exploring and you're wandering
and it doesn't work yeah exactly two
hours a time and so I don't agree with
it and I also don't agree with the fact
that you take on 700 farms and you're
only moving the product from 40 and it's
not that and oxides a fantastic
dispensary in all aspects and it's
managed well and it's got quality people
so to me it's an example of everything
that's done right in normal cannabis but
having to respond to the lack of market
knowledge and once we get market
knowledge where the market starts to
become educated and if you allow anybody
to educate them other than the
cultivators what's screwed because
everybody who's trying to educate him
trying to educate upon fancy boxes and
kill the packaging and a nifty new thing