why don't you tell us what's on what's
on the menu today a lot of different
options here this is my repurposed jar
of gay cush bought from MJ to celebrate
I no longer yeah a little but this
[Music]
exactly and in remembrance members of
July our noon and then for the CBD we've
got the gift from THC design which is a
CBD flower high in limonene pining and
mercy which I mentioned because you
actually get to taste them in the ghost
which is my favorite part
and then for concentrates we've got a
honestly of just kind of cheap not great
CBD isolate from bang it's like really
it's very inexpensive that's how I feel
about it I feel very good about how
inexpensive it is container looks this
container feels like yeah this is this
is a whitest thing in the world
oh yeah it's not no very very light no
and if you compare that to action
expensive if you're better quality oh
yeah
that's glass this is like 20 times the
weight of that way exactly yeah so then
this is I believe also a brand of THC
design called resin and it's crescendo
is the strain so it's only gonna get
better and louder a nice nice yeah this
is however the most difficult lid to get
off because it's a teeny tiny thing and
uses like a pressure well it looks like
it's taped shut it's not trust me
except for that part no it's not look
look it's not it's childproof okay no
it's childproof in the sense of like if
your hands are at all oily it's almost
impossible to get yeah and if you're
already high just leave the lid off I'd
like to turn our attention to the head
of engineering this guy right here what
I thought would be cool is to have a
conversation about industrial
design sure and kind of the the
trade-offs that go into product
development and the macgyvering of
solutions to make something happen that
you want to happen that doesn't
currently exist so can kind of talk
about the product development process of
developing the ghost babe sure can you
hand me the ghost man please unless your
hands are too oily from how the we'd do
you want the constructive one it's the
constructed one is perfect yeah well
this is your baby yeah it's our baby
it's and it's very iconic you know I
mean the shape the form there's nothing
out there like it and and that in and of
itself from an industrial design
standpoint is is you know a goal
definitely to get something where people
first don't know what it is and then
they start to become familiar with it
enough to know that wow that's that's a
ghost I can recognize that immediately
and that's that is kind of like the
visual recognition we have from from
this form and shape a couple really cool
things about this one is that the device
just fits in your hand so comfortably
you know the ergonomics of this make you
even no matter how you hold it in your
hand initially eventually you find the
right spot because it just leads your
hand to the right position and part of
that is due to this this cutout here for
your thumb which when you're vaping and
there's a little button that's kind of
like disguised in that surface but you
can you can feel it really nicely and
it's if most of it is that your hand is
in the perfect position when you're
ready to vape and when you're activating
the vape button but the other part I
love about this design is that the
rounds and the shape of this make you
want to play with it a little bit make
you want to just move your thumb around
on there until you find the perfect spot
and it's very very comfortable in that
position the other thing that I really
like about it is this this belly in the
front here which actually has a
technical purpose
also really helps you grab it so that I
know exactly where my fingers are gonna
go it's almost like the handle of
something that's really comfortable to
hold and my thumb goes there and that's
just you know that that's just perfect
the other thing yeah so the the center
part is what actually we have patents on
and does all the air handling and the
cooling and the heating of of the the
flow through the device so when you draw
here you're actually pulling air through
this heat sink and down through the
outer collar of this basically a pipe
and when it gets down to where the
heater is it actually preheats by moving
back and forth across where the heater
is located preheating your air and then
it goes through the cannabis in the in
the crucible and then it does the same
thing in Reverse up here it actually
cools down so this tunnel is the right
size to be able to deal with that
airflow the crucible inside with the
material in it and the preheat and the
cooldown cycles are just right and
balanced so that you can get a really
good cool draw from it so the the draw
is very very cool and comfortable versus
other things that might be a little bit
harsh or it's sometimes it's hard to
even quantify it but it feels like it's
just a little bit harsh on the throat
this doesn't do that just because it's
cooling cooling the vapor down before it
gets to your mouth so the compromise is
that you're exposing this feature from
the insides it's really a pipe so some
of it has to be exposed underneath or
the shape of it requires the outer
enclosure to be the shape however it
works perfectly because that's where
your fingers go naturally so that's
that's the benefit of this shape and
that's the technical limitation if you
want to call it that that we have but
it's also extremely easy to get this
heat sink out and to and to clean it
which I which I really love about that
and it's it's funny because as soon as
you oh
and this it may not be intuitively
obvious as to how to take this out
because it's meant to integrate really
well and I found that the best way is
just really to push the green area and
it just comes right up and so that's
something you know then that's one of
the struggles I think because that part
of that is that part of this device is
not as intuitive as I would have liked
it liked it to be but once you know it
it's super super easy so you don't come
from a background of developing babe
devices so like when you the challenge
is laid in the front like were you a
smoke a vaporizer smoker before like do
you have experience with lots of
different beep not right like I could do
it better or not at all I had personal
experience in in the category for years
I've been either smoking because I
didn't know what vaporizers or using a
bong or something like that joints and I
knew nothing about this my background
and my whole professional career has
been in consumer product design so
anything from computer joysticks to Lego
to water pitchers coffee makers things
that are very high touch products so in
amazingly large volumes and integrate
technology in a really meaningful and
interesting way so with this you now
know what the homework assignment is
what did you like start researching and
reading up like talk about the the
process of what was the mandate what was
it like do you have a price point if you
have a product size or weight you know I
think what it all comes down to is is
trying as much of the competitive units
that are out there you got to give
everything a shot whether you're not you
think you know it you have to use it you
can't look at anything and assume either
by the way it looks or by what you've
heard on the market that you know it so
yeah there's a lot of background
we talked about what you liked and
disliked like as you were trying like
what products were you trying out and
what were you like oh this is kind of
ingenious or I could improve on this
part well I think you know each one has
its own limitations as ours does as well
you know there there are some
limitations here and there but I'm
trying to think of what might jump out
as being you know something that was
like as an example for me the first
dryer vaporizer I ever tried was the
Sapir remember the one that was like a
it had a long straw at the top do you
guys ever try that I think so yeah yeah
and they were for me the first one and I
was like this thing is brilliant you
know I think the first one I really
tried and again I'm a relative newcomer
to the category but I think the one I
tried was was the packs just because
everyone was talking about it and it
seemed very consumer product key you
know very like a consumer product and so
I used it and you know compared to
smoking a bowl there's a lot of
convenience there but one of the things
I really didn't like is the the flavor
and the taste just kind of you know it
didn't the flavor to me kind of tasted
burned or yes I've heard people say pop
corny and that's kind of what I taste it
as well and so as you disassembled a
product like that did you identify like
why it has a burnt taste to it
sure yeah why was it well I think
there's a lot of the way that the
material is heated up has a lot to do
with it and the fewer the less contact
you can have of hot surfaces with the
the cannabis itself the better because
as soon as you heat things up the
contact just burns things it's just
going to be like leaning up against a
really hot engine of a car you're gonna
you're gonna burn yourself and the weed
suffers from that where the ghost is
different is that we're actually just
sending hot air it's true convection and
convection is your your the hay
the air is sorry the heat is actually
distributed into the air and the air
goes through all the parts of the of the
consumable that's inside there so it's
not the way to look sadly probably the
best example for this in this specific
case here is the difference to retain a
an electric stove and a gas stove so the
PAC's is an electric stove and that with
electric stove you turn it on the coils
take a while to heat up it heats your
pan up and then once you've once you're
done cooking you turn that off
but the coils take a while to cool down
the pan takes a while to cool down
everything has tests take time to cool
down
that's the PAX that's any conduction
vaporizer that's the PAX that's the
mighty that's the solo that's every
other vaporizers on the market except me
- the Firefly right but ghost being an
on demand vaporizer is much more like a
convection stove where you put your pan
down you turn it on gas comes on heats
immediately once you're done cooking you
turn the gas off heat dies immediately
right and because we're using a a
medical-grade ceramic crucible that heat
dissipates from the crucible which is
what we're holding the flower in that
heat dissipates from the crucible very
quickly so as soon as you turn the heat
off as soon as you let go of that button
and you stop drawing you stop applying
heat to the flower and makes it
extremely efficient which is probably
the I think it's the only device that
I've ever used that has that same kind
of functionality by the way while we're
talking about this critical
functionality let's pack that with some
yeah let's do that let's do the gift
let's start with some CVD let's start
light because I think this will be this
is my favorite demonstration of the
actual flavor so we'll do so here this
is actually a great example of the
biggest problem that I have with the
Ghost which is that I am incapable of
grinding a single crucible worth because
I just grind a hell of because it's like
no matter how tiny of a nug I grab it's
always too much and I actually don't
know if I have I have an empty crucible
empty crucible okay so a great example
is if you try to use if you were to try
to grind for like a joint or a bong or
anything this amount would just not be
enough this is like a teeny tiny little
nug but this tiny tiny little nug will
probably be a little bit too much for a
crucible like 1/10 of a gram is a lot
smaller than you ever imagined
particularly when you grind it and I
personally like to use the our
Phoenician grinder that we have branded
here because it gives a very kind of
corks loose grind which is really ideal
for convection yes you actually talked
about the coarseness grind and different
yeah why is it coarser grind better
versus a yeah yeah so if you think about
it if you think about it the what he was
just described he was describing about
the air flow is because we're not baking
because we're not heating the actual
oven that the material is kept in
because we're drawing we're heating by
drawing air across it if you grind to
fine or you pack to tight there's no
space for the air to go and so typically
what you'll end up if you grind it to
fine or packet through tight what you'll
end up at the end is a hot crucible M no
vapor I find nothing coming out of the
end but the crucible itself will be very
hot and that means that the air has
nowhere to go and it's getting stuck so
if you grind it really if you grind it
really loose you pack it nice and loose
it gives that air plenty of space to
travel over the flour to transmit its
heat he'd love to create that vapor
really even distribution exactly exactly
and I personally like this grinder as
well because it's got this nice rounded
bottom that happens to perfectly fit the
contours of our crucible so this is a
nice want to get that it's a nice loose
grain and I like to just straight out
the crucible either straight out of the
grinder I like to just kind of scoop it
up pretty loosely give it a nice little
kind of brush off the top that's not too
much packing nice and loose so you can
kind of see that it's it's packed pretty
loosely in there like you can see space
around it and that's ideal I'm pretty
sassy and I'm pretty satisfied now
graded by high hopes
got really high hopes that this is going
to produce a lot of a before us like I
see my deny scene so one of the things
that I like about the crucible system as
well is that you can pre pack a bunch so
we use the we have this nice little
crucible dispenser I actually know we'll
bring you one we've been I was like
that's the on the go it's they've been
so popular we had a such a hard time
keeping them in stock and finally have
them back in stock we're sending them
all out so whose idea was that whoever
first said oh I want to have a whole
bunch would be able to pre pack yeah
during my day so whoever said that was
the one who invented it yeah so like
Steve was saying the once we actually
load the crucible in here if you notice
they're a tiny little they're teeny tiny
perforations on the bottom of it and on
the top and those are specifically so
that the air can travel through the
flour and not get caught there and not
heat the crucible too much and not heat
it up but the here airs gonna be
superheated down here we're gonna draw
it up through the flour it's gonna go
through the heat sink and if we're
talking about comparison to other
devices that heat sink is probably the
biggest difference personally when I
tried the when I tried the packs myself
the thing that bothered me the most is
that that mouthpiece got really hot
really fast like after one drawer so I
felt I remember feeling a tingling on my
lips I was like what's so strange and
then I realized that is because the
whole device was getting too hot one hit
but this because of the heatsink and the
fact that the mouthpiece is actually
separated from the rest of the device so
it's like a it's like one of those no
heat pan handles right mm-hm
but melfi's never gets hot even at high
temperatures so yeah well cuz I want the
the reason I'm going into the app here
so we have 3 we have 5 presets preset
temperatures of 338 362 390 to 405 and
then 428 I believe those are the 5 no
hilariously enough actually because
we're converting from Celsius because
it's all based in Celsius and we're
converting it is impossible to set it to
420 it was a huge oversight but we'll
fix it yeah yeah it's the downside every
vaporizer that's based on the Celsius
temperature scale can't hit 420 just
because of the conversion it's funny so
anyway so I will connect it to my app
and the reason I want to connect to the
app is so that I can set the temperature
specifically for mersin and limonene and
mining which are at a very specific
temperature that I have saved to my
phone in a fantastic little graph that
we like to keep track of so PI 9 is at
311 degrees is when that terpene
vaporizes Mersin is at 334 and limiting
is at 349 so what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna set this my custom temperature
here all right it set the custom
temperature so I'm gonna set the
temperature here to 311 and my my first
temperature here that's gonna get us
mostly pining its that lowest
temperature so because it's a convection
vaporizer your lungs are part of the
machine right so like the the volcano is
going to use a fan to blow air across it
but here we're using our lungs to draw
it across
[Music]
very pine-sol so interestingly I was
using this with Cameron jodieandandy
from Fiddler's Green yes your
expectation is you're gonna blow out
this huge billowy puff of smoke
you don't which I think from an end-user
standpoint you're like is it working in
your highest fuck so can you guys talk
about that because I think perception
perception wise people are expecting
that they're like is this thing now I
kept thinking I needed to crank up the
temperature yep so I'm actually really
glad you asked that because this is
something that I've been like a passion
project of mine
most recently which is there isn't a ton
of research surprise surprise people
haven't done research but I would argue
that you're if you're getting the flavor
and if you're getting the effect it
kinda doesn't matter if you're getting
visible vapor right it like weird what
you're just saying is that you're you're
used to blowing out a cloud right and so
if you're blowing out a cloud you are
likely at a very high temperature and
are vaporizing pretty much everything
all in one go which is a huge waste or
you're combusting I mean if you're using
a poorly constructed conduction
vaporizer you're combusting right it's
gonna get to a too high of a temperature
in that case you're actually producing
smoke not vaporize I I agree but I think
there's an end user because you're sure
that's the first episodes you're like
this must not be working well the other
thing too is as soon as you start
exhaling and all that vapor goes out
that's vapor that you're not consuming
you're just bringing into your lungs
none of it has actually attached or very
little of it and then you're you're
exhaling back out so there's some
element of less vapor is actually better
in that you're retaining more and you're
you're consuming in a more delicate way
we will get vapor at higher temperatures
for sure yeah you'll even get vapor so
you'll even find at the lower
temperatures I found that so this is
right now at 311 degrees which is a
common temperature that you
don't get any vapor from but even on
just the second puff I already got some
vapor so a lot of it is a matter of the
cure of the flower how moist it is
sometimes you have to dry it out a lot
of people grind their flower and then
let it sit out for an hour before they
actually vape it because you wanna give
that a chance to dry out this one is
pining so this is this tastes very much
like pine sometimes if you get if you
hit the right temperature particularly
with this flower the biggest downside is
that if you hit the temperature between
pining and limonene which is about 338
just our lowest preset you get this
almost pine-sol flavor because you get
the lemon and the pine and it's a it's
like a it's a good flavor but it also
has the reminiscence Oh am i poison to
myself the XD oh just bring some fine
right now yeah is it going around the
circle I don't know about this it's the
circle is very small I think right now
the circles a dot there you go you want
to you want to set it up too
you want hit the pine you want to set it
up pining sure let me just do my name
put the pine in first and we'll settle
up you can also do some this really fun
stuff you can temperature step so you
can start at the low temperatures take
one long 15-second draw then step it up
to a slightly higher temperature take
another 15 second draw and if you want
to talk about getting big clouds if you
start at these lower temperatures yeah
yeah see so this is still in a 311
degrees yeah I have not changed the
temperature it's still at 311 and that's
the fourth fourth or fifth it's the I
think it's the fourth yeah so you're
right very tasty yeah so with with flour
that's really dried out or kind of old
stuff you'll find that it it vapes of
the lower temperatures very easily
sometimes too easily but it's usually
because it's very dry it out like I
found that a lot of my old stuff that's
I've had for a long time it's just about
any temperature but good stuff that's
well preserved well cured I know so you
got the Boveda packets if you use those
to keep that yeah so if you use those to
keep your flower at a good moisture
level chances are pretty good that
put it in the end of the ghost or any
vaporizer you're gonna want to either
let it dry out a bit or hit it a really
low temperature to kind of to activate
it more so we boosting this baby now
well let's give it let's give Daniel a
try oh oh you want to you want to go
other around you want right yeah go for
it give me some more
let's hit the industrial design part of
the conversation so what so we talked
about the like the crucible and the
heating like give me a challenge that
took a long time to find a clever
solution to hmm you know and a lot of
these devices I think the the layout is
fairly straightforward on a lot of these
so the air is gonna pass through a
heater and then pass through the
material and then go into your lungs I
think where it becomes difficult is
managing the firmware and figuring out
what the temperature set points are
going to be and it's not as as glamorous
as you might think but that's where most
of the challenges come in is what what
how do you drive the heater with the
batteries you have to consume the least
amount of power but you know provide the
most longevity and have the most
efficient thing it's it's a balance in
engineering about you know proper use of
the battery yeah and I think you know
and we want to be right sized as well so
you know consuming the battery and
they're in the right amount to to deal
with someone's expected session use how
many times you're gonna pass it around
before you exchange the bowl I think is
you know this there's a lot of science
and engineering that goes into that so
that's that's one thing you know from an
ID perspective a lot of it's all about
organ a'm --ax and balance I think the
other important part of this is for
instance the front in enclosure on this
device is all casts
which adds a forward waiting to it and
balances very well so that when you're
holding it in your hand and it just
feels right and a lot of the times
weight contributes is that the reason
you use cast Inc or is that just a it's
has to do with the temperature I guess
so talk about the wreath what is cast
Inc good for well why does one use cast
as Inc well good question but I think a
lot of it is a durability for the most
part there's there's a lot of plastics
that can do that but zinc is very bio
neutral it's it's very safe material
it's also super strong and it adds the
right amount of weight if you think
about making it out of aluminum that
wouldn't be as heavy and wouldn't give
it that that quality feel it also reason
it's very very durable so if we were to
make this out of say plastic and you
dropped it on the ground in cold weather
it would probably likely be a brittle
failure this material is strong
everywhere and you know when we design
something we have to anticipate all the
use and all the abuse you're going to
see people are going to drop it out of
their pocket people are going to leave
it in their cars overnight or even on
the dashboard underneath their
windshield so when you design a product
you have to think about all those edge
cases because they're not as uncommon as
you think they'd be and it's just
something that you have to design for
that people are going to be use the
product what happens when they do that
hopefully they get to use it another day
and that's the goal of you know the
design team well some of it some of this
leads into having to make trade-offs
when you develop a product of things you
want to maybe put in it like materials
or features but you also want to hit a
price point so can you talk about
something that you wanted to do but you
had to leave on the idea floor because
you couldn't hit the price point you
wanted to hit for the market hmm
it's a great question I would have to
say that you know where where there's a
bit of product improvement that could
happen on this and that where I think
you use the word compromise I think
that's that's a reasonable word here is
that the interface is was initially
thought of to be simple with one button
you can get everywhere well with that
simplicity has a little bit of you know
interface user interface issues and
while certainly it's easier for people
who are programming it it's not one
button and how long you hold it and in
what order is is critical and give you
the right output the user these days
wants to just push the button go and
they wanted to know they want it to be
as smart as they are they wanted to
anticipate everything that they want
without saying it that's kind of what
our devices do now so you know we took
the route of one button does all and it
really does a lot of things that many
vapes don't do just from the button
alone most vapes need the ones that are
app connected need that app to give it
that additional versatility well the the
I think the the biggest comparison is
the Firefly is the only other real
convection vaporizer out there right and
after using it they also only have a
single button relate but that button all
it does is turn it on and off yeah all
it does is start the start the
temperature increasing and stop the
temperature increasing and so you're
required to use an app and if you don't
want to have to use your app your can
out of luck yeah that's right I mean
sometimes I just want to sit on my porch
and you know use my clothes paper and I
don't want to have to worry about where
my phone is
you know I I don't care what the phone
is I you know I'm here I'm ready to vape
I want to relax why should I get my
phone and so we have the ability of
adjusting many many things and you know
that's important what the device does
without an app at all without being app
enabled some people don't want to attach
their device to an app I get it
well so it has to be as capable there as
it is with
yeah and what I like is that you can use
the app to set it and then you don't
have to use the app so you can use the
app to set the two custom temperatures
and then once you've set them you don't
have to use the app again you can just
switch to those custom temperatures and
know that they are yeah so like I've got
one of the custom temperatures set
whatever 349 right now is that the
limonene we're just we're gonna hit next
right and then I got the other custom
temperature set to 428 which I always
like to clean up any bowl I like to sure
and you know I think another let's not
say compromise but design selection has
been the battery
you know the batteries are super capable
has to 18 650 cells in here and what you
can do is integrate the cells themselves
into the device and close the door and
some people do that some people you know
and but what we decided to do was make
this a custom battery integrated with
the back so that you're really using the
least amount of wall thickness that you
need to make the plastic do what it
needs to do there are a lot of different
ways of doing this I think in this case
it's an extremely economical and nice
touch but you know those decisions
aren't easy for any designers or
developers there's so many options out
there on which way to go you really have
to think about usability and you know
refurbishment you know just there's a
lot of different considerations to
battery selection how long you want it
to last you know we decided to make ours
last a hell a long time and you know and
so that's that's what we have here
something that maybe is slightly bigger
than than others but again with the
ergonomics you don't feel it as much and
it really gives you the the feel of a
super capable device and and it gives
you you know you know as well the other
the other advantage that once you start
looking at the once you start
considering the idea of a removable
battery
I mean able to take it out probably one
of my favorite accessories is the fast
charger mmm being able to have
particularly having two batteries be
able to just pop one out
leave one always on the fast charger on
the desktop and then
whenever I even basically whenever I
leave my house I just grab whatever the
charger is on the whatever batteries on
the charger and pop it in and I know
every time I've got a full charge so it
makes it super super easy there are
plenty of devices that have batteries
and have good batteries also have
eighteen 650s but they all plug in and
if you're if you were you know about to
head out and you realize that your but
your vape is dead I'm really cool about
this bag is that you can charge it
through a USB you don't need a custom
charger oh you don't even need to put on
the fast charger you can just take the
battery off and charge it via the USB
well yeah yeah you can I hope you
haven't been wasting your time in a fast
charger no no no you can charge it this
way but but the benefit to that is I
don't have you know wherever I have a
USB cable that I can charge it up yeah I
don't need to oh now it's dead and go
home to my custom charger yeah and I
mean not to keep using this word but the
Firefly does that and I actually have a
Firefly that I've been playing with and
you know whenever you go somewhere you
have to either make sure that the
battery soup-like fully charged or bring
the charger along with you I'd rather
just bring my USB camera do you like I
mean I have so many different types of
devices and a camera equipment right
audio equipment I have smoking equipment
and anything that uses standard
standardization is beautiful versus
proprietary proprietary drives me crazy
sorry yeah the same that's what we have
so that's where that's kind of the the
idea of balance as well is that we have
the removable battery with a proprietary
connector and a proprietary fast charger
that you can sit at home and you can
charge nicely but like you were saying
if you're on the go if you've got a
bunch of other devices that also use
micro USB you're never without a charger
so you have that kind of flexibility in
it which I appreciate so we just tried
some drier I want to mix it up let's go
straight you want to go straight to
concentrates all right so really quick
before I move from the concentrates
though I'd like to point out with flower
vaporizers with dryer vaporizers like
this the the biggest judge one of the
best judges of them
is what your flower looks like
afterwards okay so here's here's the
example here so we had what I had like
to click four hits before I passed it so
I went four five six seven eight nine I
think I took another one so we'll just
call it ten hits at 3:11 degrees and
this is not even brown this this
specific crucible I could bump this up
to probably 349 get another four or five
good hits and I can probably get another
five or six good hits at 428 so I always
tell people depending on how you use it
depending on the temperatures depending
on your process you can get a whole heck
of a lot so how many more hits are you
gonna could you get from that across all
the temperature ranges probably another
six to ten we might I guess yeah yeah
realistically that's after another
already hit taking nine hits out of them
so conceptually that's actually pretty
interesting the idea of almost like
watching your terpene intake of like
yeah I'm gonna do this slice and I'm
gonna get these terpenes that this
specific terpene that I'm gonna like
move on over to the limonene or whatever
uh-huh yeah what a great example of that
what I like to do is there are there are
two cannabinoids that I love Delta 9 THC
and THC v the reason I love them is
they're both you for ian's so they give
you that kind of euphoria hi and Delta 9
THC vaporizes at 315 degrees which is
very very low and THC v vaporizes at 428
degrees which is typically what you're
getting when you're smoking if you're
smoking at all whether a joint a bong
anything you're getting a whole heck of
a lot more that THC because it's at that
high temperature that's one of the
reasons why you associate this kind of
euphoria high with smoking and it's a
very common it's very common feeling
when you smoke in general and that's why
a lot of people find vaporizing it's a
very different experience because you
typically aren't hitting it at that 428
and you're getting these kind of
in-between cannabinoids that give you a
little more sometimes a little more
mellow high and little difference to it
so I like 315 and 428 allows you to
really like dial in what you're looking
for
so for concentrates what I like is that
we use this we use the same crucible
system so it's the same medical grade
ceramic gruesome
all same stainless steel lid but we drop
in this stainless steel mesh pad and the
pad is what actually captures the
melting and concentrate so you stick a
little rice grain size amount on the pad
and then on the first heat up it melts
it in and then every other draw after
that you're really kind of vaping this
stainless steel sponge essentially
that's holding all that concentrate what
that also allows that I like is that you
can then once you're done pop the whole
thing out and drop everything in
isopropyl and it just kind of cleans
itself so easily the the easiest cleanup
for concentrates so did you have
anything else you want to add about
going on to concentrate some when you're
when you're vaping it on the pad the pad
actually lets you get all your
concentrate that's out of it so you're
not really wasting anything I'm not too
sure if you guys ever dab and you guys
ever dab you guys have to clean it with
a q-tip after and you're cleaning up
you're cleaning up all that constant
rate as with the mv-1 you're actually
vaping all of it out of the pad so
you're getting the full use out of your
concentrate which is crazy because you
could get like 15 to 20 hits off of a
concentrate pad so it goes back just as
just to the efficiency of the device
with flour with a concentrate super
efficient I mean 1/10 of a gram compared
to other baits on the market where they
use point three grams and we're using
point one we're saving them we're saving
a lot of a lot of flour and going back
to what they were saying about the
heating system if you're just pushing
the button there and you're not drawing
your materials not burning you know
because your lungs part of the system it
becomes part of the vape so if if I'm
sitting here just pushing the button my
materials not gonna burn it's not going
to waste which means it's not gonna come
bus either since there's no contact with
that with that heating element in your
material right exactly yes yeah and for
concentrates you're really only you're
really only hitting it when you're
taking a draw and when you're pulling it
across it is when you're because we're
still even for the concentrates we're
still using the same convection heating
we're still heating in the same way so
you get all the same benefits of the
on-demand it's one of the only places
that you can take out of your pocket
take a hit of your concentrates and then
put it back in your pocket making me
anxious here by just holding that ready
to be put in well I wanted to feel I
wanted to show that this is all you
needs this is about a little less than a
rice grain size amount this is all you
need so you drop it right here in the
middle of the middle of the screen here
I'm not a I'm not a
what that concentrates this is my first
my first jar of it but I'm pretty happy
about it so drop it right there in the
middle and you usually want it for
concentrates you want solids right if
it's too liquid it's just gonna melt all
the way down through and you don't want
that so we you want to go with more the
more solid bit better in my opinion but
like I said the same one do you have
anything else on there we cover we cover
most of it yeah so put on the same
crucible stick in the same device so
it's all the same stuff which makes a
lot easier and then for concentrates we
have one setting so I'll change the
setting on the device up from my custom
all the way up to three Reds three Reds
means concentrate it's important that
you don't try to do herbs in the
concentrate mode because concentrate is
at a much higher temperature
understandably and you'll just burn your
flower and that's not good experience
but for the efficiency purposes we
preheat the device for concentrate modes
so normally when you press the button
you're going to start heating and you're
start drawing after about seven or ten
seconds to start drawing the heat across
it but for concentrates we're gonna
press on hold and you'll see it'll start
blinking as if we should be drawing
right now but instead it's preheating
so we're preheating the air down here
we're kind of getting everything set up
and ready to go it'll take about and so
once the yellow lights on then you know
that you're at concentrate level and
you're ready to go this will actually
turned on if you let it sit here for too
long and I'll turn back to green because
it's cooled down too much so I have
concentrate level will press it you can
just start drawing immediately and you
want to draw relatively slowly because
you're drawing that heat across and
letting that that concentrate Milton to
the pad
[Music]
and then going back to efficiency like
you were saying on the device um with
your material with your flour especially
once you're done using it
I tell people not to throw it away and
save it because you can make edibles out
of it with later so you could really get
that full lifecycle out of your material
that you're using in your rate because I
know it prices are getting expensive now
so 1/8 instead of rolling you three
joints you could have 35 crucibles you
know yeah so yeah there's there's a
super it's really it's really efficient
with with all the material you're using
yeah I like to the I've always started
since I started using the ghost I've
transitioned from buying really cheap
eighths to buying really nice grams yeah
I have I have wheat that I only smoked
in vapes because they have certain
certain cannabinoids tincture peens that
I want to hit and then there's certain
weed that I had to smoke out of a bong
or joint because I don't care about them
you know so I really like Wonder Bread
because they have a bunch of different
cannabinoids in in their flower so
because of that they are you able to hit
different flavors will to get different
highs um with that because a lot of
people will just want THC but what those
with those terpenes you that's where you
get the different flavors and things
like that so that's why I don't always
look for the highest THC flower but the
ones with the most different
cannabinoids and wonder Bret has a bunch
of those yeah exactly and so what it
what is your current Wonderbread flavor
I like the blueberry the blueberries
really good yeah you know and speaking
of that I think that one of the things
that people forget is you've everybody's
been so trained at this point to go to a
go to a dispensary to smell a much
different flower to find that flower
they really like and find a delicious
flavor and they buy it based on that
smells like awe smells so good I want to
try this but as soon as you put it into
your anything that's gonna combust put
into a bowl a bong a pipe and you loot
you lose most of that like if you roll
it into a joint you smoke it you'll
usually get a hint if you get like a
strawberry banana strain you'll get a
hint of that but you don't even realize
how much of those terpenes you're
missing out on until you try it on the
ghost like I've had people I've had
people who really enjoy their specific
strain we actually a fantastic example
there was a grower at one of these
events that we went to that's been doing
it for 15 20 years been the industry
forever and he tried the ghost for first
time and
his like private stash is private
straining the stream and he's had a
million times that is like his his go to
and he tried it in the mv-1
and he was driven to tears my verge of
tears
eyes watering up and he said it's like
he was tasting it for the first time
which i think is a fantastic example of
how when you've tried when you've been
smoking weed and you're familiar with it
so much you kind of get used to the low
quality and it's only once you finally
taste it in something that really
highlights that flavor that you
understand everything that you're
missing out on them and you go back to a
joint and you're just it's kind of
ruined for you you know yeah no you're
you're completely right on that because
I'm the same way the first time I resize
I was like am i smoking oregano am i
smoking a herb like what did you guys
put in this because I never tasted we
never toasted like what it smelled like
out of the jar so I think I think that's
a good experience to that if you never
tasted weed what it smells like you need
a taste out of but ghosts vape and like
what Collier says you could hit specific
temperatures for specific terpene so you
could even get more more of a better of
experience that way so let me ask you a
question cuz when were in drier mud we
were tranching we're going like right up
temperature-wise to hit and isolate
specific terpenes and cannabinoids but
in concentrate mode there's just one
temperature temperature okay so can you
talk about yeah yeah so concentrate is a
concentrate is concentrate I mean it's
it's a concentrated form so it's a much
less complicated material that has far
fewer compounds involved in it so we
still got terpenes you still got
cannabinoids but it's going to vaporize
about the same temperature at that high
temperature because you're not
vaporizing the the terpenes and
cannabinoids you're vaporizing the
actual like material itself you're
vaporizing the concentrate itself and
that's gonna vaporize it's gonna
vaporize at different temperatures but
the temperature we have a set-to is the
one that will vaporize pretty much every
concentrate around there so the reason
you want to build a set different
temperatures for flour is that
unflattering itself you want to vaporize
the things that's that are in it and to
do that you want to hit those very
specific temperatures that's the that's
the simple version yeah
just like yeah so no definitely not so
is it against TV oh yeah yeah I can get
into a lot of the specifics for flour
are the quality of the flour in general
as far as where it was grown how it was
grown the age of the flour so sometimes
if it's far too old when you grind it
I'll get way too powdery and you'll just
you'll get a bad flavor out of it but
cure a lot of flour isn't cured well
enough and then the moisture content is
what we're talking about so for good
flour if you're keeping it properly
preserved what you want to do I'm not
saying you shouldn't use the Boveda
packs I'm saying that you want to use
them to keep your flour preserved but
when you go to vaporize you you're going
to particularly fits well-preserved
those first couple hits are gonna be
pure flavor very little visible vapor
but you'll get some fantastic flavor and
once you get out of that flavor range
you've kind of dried it out you've
gotten rid of a lot of the the terpenes
at that level and everything after that
it's gonna be a lot more visible vapor
you can get a lot more a lot less the
flavor lot more vapor a lot more the
effects so as far as flour goes it's
it's all over the place I mean you'll
see a lot of people say that CBD flour
doesn't taste good and that's typically
because they're burning it and CBD flour
doesn't have a lot of terpenes at those
high temperatures so when you burn it
you just get kind of grass it doesn't
taste very good
but a great example is that this stuff
we had because even though it's CBD
flour because it's got those terpenes at
the low temperatures but piney in the
Mersey and aluminum you get the low
temperatures where you don't get the
kind of Burnie flour ease the Bernie
plant taste and you get those actual
terpenes yeah you know and so many
people these days are heading to oil
cartridges and so forth which are really
just they're extracted all the terpenes
are taken out mmm does fill them and
then they're put back in later with
flour it's really more of a natural
extraction in a way we're extracting and
consuming all in one and that's what
makes it so much better the terpenes
that you taste are natural as a part of
the flour and whereas with oil it's just
there's always this kind of like well
it's either too much or not enough and
there's very few that are balanced
correctly with ours we really do
getting the taste of the flower and
that's really a wonderful thing yeah and
I like to the to your point about the
oil cartridges I like to associate it
with kind of this move towards vitamins
all right there's a period where we were
eating a lot of just regular old food
back in the good old days of the you
know the early thousands and then when
we started doing manufactured food we
started having canned food and
pre-prepared food pre-prepared meals
that was a huge was a big deal everybody
loved those we flocked them was great
and then we've we've gone to this point
where we're doing vitamins right people
are taking I wake up in the morning take
vitamin C vitamin D vitamin E like I
take all these different vitamins and
now even more recently we're getting
back to this idea of Whole Foods right
we're doing the backs idea of just
taking vitamin C isn't good you need to
take vitamin C as part of a food that
you're eating because there are these
other things that come with the food
that we kind of don't understand fully
their benefits in the same way vaping an
oil cartridge is just like taking
vitamins like you're getting the THC
which trick which gives you THC and if
that's your goal that's good but what's
what's being missed that we don't have
enough research to really back up is
this idea of the entourage effect
which is that when you vape flour you're
getting those cannabinoids but also the
terpenes and also the other camp
annoyance and they're all kind of acting
together to increase the effect and give
you a much more rounded experience that
isn't just like a like a blasted head of
high it's like a full kind of experience
yeah it's more of it it's more of a
journey right exactly that when you know
when you when you taste the flour at
lower temperatures and then halfway
through like after six or seven hits
yeah change the temperature higher it's
it's really a much more versatile of a
way consuming it no to that point why do
have a different flour here that was pre
packed from one of our other events
called XJ 13 and the reason I mention it
is that this flour if I'm not mistaken I
think it's this one is high inter
pinnacle which is a terpene that tastes
a lot like diesel that is that the
turpentine kind of kind of alcoholic
gasoline kind of flavor and that
vaporizes at 426 degrees so that's
strain to your question about the the
different flours that's strain if you
vape it at lower temperatures doesn't
really taste very good
it doesn't have many terpenes at those
low temperatures but if you hit it at
426 or 428 at the high temperatures you
get a very strong kind of sour diesel
flavor that goes along with the
cannabinoid THC v that's vaporize it's
that that same temperature so that XJ 13
with that high terpenes her pineal is
very much like I'm considered as close
here and get like a smokers high oh it's
interesting there is I kind of feel like
cultivators and brands should understand
when people are vaping their products
what's the ideal temperature from my
flower for sure which you're hitting on
conceptually that is that is one thing
that we've worked with a lot of flower
companies and we've made a lot of
friends with flower companies and they
they all have that same idea which is
that they're working so hard there every
day is trying to make their flower
unique make it different make it special
make it great and no matter who's
selling it no matter how much time you
spent on it if you sell it and then roll
it up into a joint they might as well be
the same as every other quality like
produced in the curing process and by
that do you mean short curing or you
know yeah as not a grower I have no idea
all I know is that it needs to be well
cured I've been told by a lot of by a
lot of growers when I showed them flower
that I bought when they when they have
told me like but this is not this is not
well cured this is not good because not
well cured
I don't know exact what that means but I
know it needs to be well cared I believe
this is the so the what I was just doing
there there's one of the things I love
just that it's one of the only
vaporizers that what you smell is what
you end up tasting right so I always
love when I do a demo at events is I
like to have people smell it and then
put it in there I think that's the puff
Co peak they're different they're
totally different you know I mean the
peak is essentially around concentrates
and only constitutes only there's five
different settings for concentrates
whether you like hot dabs or cold that
that's kind of kind of what it's for
people that just wants an instant high
as where the ghost it's people that are
looking for flavor you know they're just
looking to get high they want to hit
those terpenes they want to get those
flavors they want to get the most out of
their weed for example someone smoking
three joints a day that's an eighth the
day you know and if they switched if
they switch to vape there's gonna be
anything we kept they're buying you know
they're gonna have that good quality
weed using a vape as even is even
healthy for you for those people that
smoke like backwoods and things like
that that tobacco is horrible for them
you know if they're smoking joints or
bongs or getting that butane as or all
this it's it's pure and like Collier
said you get a different high from it
you get a cleaner high from it cuz
you're not getting any of those things
that you're not supposed to smoke if
that makes sense you're not supposed to
smoke the butane you're not supposed to
smoke the tobacco you know and that's
when people will say that they're we
doesn't taste good like what about what
tobacco leaves you know because you cuz
you're you're covering up that taste
with the tobacco leaf
however this you're just getting the
full the full tasting even with the
puffs go peak I don't think we were able
to get a hit with that grain of rice we
use in this out of the puff go peak you
be lucky to get one draw one person to
get one draw out of it and then you
still have to clean it up after this we
could just keep hitting it you know
they're two totally they're two totally
different devices but I do like how this
it gives you the option to use both and
then you get the best out of both um
when you're using it because I don't
know if you notice to concentrate it was
very very tasteful you're able to taste
it and that's what we get by having the
one temperature uhm you not have to
worry about over burning it yeah okay so
what are we oh yeah okay so this one
what his temperature is it's like the
cheat code and a video what temperature
the temperature I believe is up up down
down left right left right B a start if
I'm not mistaken that's how you unlock
this temperature no that one would be
contra that is the correctly everybody
does so I'm not gonna lie to you I'm not
entirely sure if this is x-ray 13 or not
because my nose is not good enough to be
able to smell it but just judging by the
look pretty sure it'll go to that I can
tell you yeah okay so here's the test
this will be the test I haven't set to
428 degrees right that's right around
that 426 the terpin e all so we're gonna
get high flavor of the terpene y'all and
a lot of THC fioors that euphoria and
high so if it doesn't taste like that
then that's nuts turn the
this is where we need like the like The
Bachelor where like someone's someone's
about to get kicked off and they cut to
each person like looking at you to see
if you're gonna you're gonna taste it
everybody's looking at you at this
temperature though you should get a lot
more clouds as well have you guys used
the peak before or any other vapors
before
what is your guys's opinion all those
compared to the girls you guys you found
something so that's it this is a great
example of when you started it when you
go straight to 428 I think that's the
term I think that's the that's the exit
13 when you started at the high
temperature you usually can only get
instead of the full 15-second draw on
the particularly the first couple
drawers I can only make it five or six
seconds because you they produce is so
much vapor so quickly that's the long
one the other taste like you get that
diesel a little bit a little bit yeah
I'm not sure if that's C not sure if
that's the XT 13 because I'm getting I'm
getting a little bit diesel into my head
yeah I I primed you but one thing what
you're saying about the the flower as
well is the pack is very important so
I've noticed a lot of times on the first
draw if it's not good I'll just kind of
I'll pull it out and I'll just even use
the lid here and just kind of not even
stir it just kind of rough it up just
give it a little loose and show who's
boss but if you notice when you do that
you get you get much more much feathery
much more feathery pack which is ideal
I'm not sure if there's nothing it up
yeah but you can get even if you get to
a point even if you get to a point where
you're not getting any vapor or any
effects sometimes you get to a point
where it's it has vaporized just about
everything you can get and all you got
to do is stir it up little get you can
get two more good hits and what you just
did there that I want to i if I could if
I could say anything I would say that's
like the that's like the call sign of
the ghost if you've ever tried a ghost
the most common thing is people even if
you don't get a visible vapor they blow
out and I go hmm yeah
yeah I get that and people don't even
realize they're doing it it's my
favorite part let's see if I've got I
wonder if I don't do you have cuz I mean
I think I have a jar of XJ 13 I may
but we we like to partner with different
flower brands yes actually so talk about
that well yeah what's your interactions
and relationships with yeah well so it
works really well flowers the flower
brands work really well with us one of
our good friends is THC design which is
what we're which is what we've been
smoking this whole Bay the reason that
they love us and we love them is that
they like I said they put their terpenes
on the packaging not many other brands
actually put what terpenes to expect on
a packaging so that helps us because
people are looking for those terpenes
and I know that the first time that the
folks from THC design tried their flower
in the mv-1 they wanted to work with us
and the reason is like I said earlier
you put so much time into making this
flower that tastes a certain way that
smells a certain way that has a certain
effect and you really only get to
maximize that and get the most out of it
in something like the ghost I do like it
because you can seek out those specific
terpenes and look for them and one of my
favorites that is not as common is mercy
and I learned recently that mercian is
the same chirping that's found in
mangoes and if you vape something like
the gift at 349 to get that mercy and
you eat a mango or eat something high in
mangoes it's like it's kind of like
drinking red wine mistake has this kind
of multiplier effect that just really
enhances everything so in THC designs
Power Move would be next to the terpenes
to list what temperature exactly you can
isolate that exactly yeah so give me an
example like you talked about part is
partnering just like mutual love and
admiration or is partnering like we have
a business deal together so yeah about
partnerships with THC design as our case
Ted sure so as you probably guess we're
a relatively young company still and as
you can also probably guess we are still
working very hard to get our name out
there and get the product out there get
people trying it make people aware of it
so right now we're still at the stage
where we're just good friends
we're dating you know we've had a couple
dates you know we we've exchanged phone
numbers we were Facebook friending up
with other
exactly exactly but the the kinds of
partnerships that we're building are
very mutually beneficial in that there
we have one there's one brand that
probably does want to be mentioned but
they're using they're they're taking the
ghost MV one around with their sales
team and they're bringing the ghost and
crucibles and their flour to
dispensaries and distributors and all
these places to demo their flour for
those buyers all right because right now
the current process is if you're a
grower when buyers come to your to your
grow to test out your flower to see if
they want to buy you're rolling you know
seven to ten joints of an eighth or more
a piece and it's a huge waste right
that's a good time speed fears but if
you think about it from two different
perspectives if you're the grower that's
a huge waste and if you're the person
who's trying to judge it's difficult to
like you can if you're professional you
can judge the difference between a bunch
of different strains by slight
variations but those different strains
and the mv-1 at the temperatures that
highlight their terpenes like buyer goes
a particular brand brandy flower for
either yeah yeah that's definitely an
option I mean everyone might be yeah
yeah that's that's definitely something
that we're we're considering going down
the line there and you can also do by
can extend dispensaries so yeah we're
actually in a lot dispensaries right now
yeah so dispensaries can sell vaporizers
actually realistically almost anybody
can sell vaporizers we're also sold in
smoke shops all over the place because
it's you can vape lavender out of it
like it is it's just a vaporizer kind of
depends on what you put in it most
people put cannabis I know yeah I'm
gonna try that later well you know if
you want to try that yeah yeah other
herbs for my garden so I hear that I
hear that sage is a really good it's a
really good combo if you grind sage and
cannabis together that Gary
and multiplicative effect exactly it's a
doe it's a dual-purpose
right but you can also you can also what
I've started experimenting with more
recently as I grind I usually do like
two nodes of THC flour and one lug of
CBD flour I just grind that all together
and load my crucibles because one of the
one of the downsides of the modern
cannabis is that modern cannabis is
bread and and grown to maximize THC
right the whole purpose is to get the
highest percentage THC that's like that
the goal of every single grow right now
is the THC percentage is how we're
judging the quality as alcohol came out
of prohibition you only had moonshine
exactly you had exactly exactly and so a
woman a bunch of craft beer - which is
like we're not even trying to get drunk
here we're just enjoying the beer and so
firewater yeah some of that wine some
flavor to that point the what I'm what
I'm trying to replicate here by grinding
some CBD flour back in with it is to add
that CBD back into the flour that's been
bred out because for the longest time
there was no value in CBD right it
wasn't the thing that was getting people
high if your purpose is to get high CBD
has no value to you so there's there's
no purpose no I people yeah you know
like when you actually understand fully
like CBD has the has the combination but
like to the general consumer THC is the
thing that gets you high and so having a
high THC percentage is what you're
looking for so let's brainstorm some
business partnerships with a because
obviously there's just like the mutual
marketing and publicity of partnership
alike I'm thinking more like there's a a
legal business deal in place like what
are you guys what could you do so - it
brands yeah so the two types of brands
that were most that we have the most
synergy with for lack of a non-business
term is consumption lounges and
retailers and flour brands flour brands
we are providing the best experience in
many different ways for them so
providing the best experience for buyers
trying their flour we're providing the
best experience
for their customers to actually be able
to appreciate the quality of their
flower which means that if I've spent
$100 for 1/8 instead of my usual 40 or
60 dollars for 1/8 I want to I want to
know that that was worth it and using it
in something like the mv-1 makes you
actually feel like it was worth it
because you taste those terpenes you get
that effect you get that smooth flavor
and you actually feel like it was worth
$100 multiple testimonials from
cultivators wanting people to use your
device to show off my flower I mean its
best
exactly exactly and then the consumption
lounges are our best friends as soon as
they start getting up and running
they're our best friends because they've
got costs on the mind right every time
somebody's come in ER up and run it like
we're zero there's a lot there's a lot
that aren't licensed yeah there are a
lot of underground ones yes yep yep so
we're friends at the consumption lounge
opening there I know that the 101 the I
think it's bud berry is opening in West
Hollywood but they they're we're friends
with them but they won't be hosting the
mv-1 because they're entirely edibles so
it's all it's all consumables not flour
which is fine that's okay if that's what
you want to do but consumption lounges
if you're particularly if you're
providing flour if you're providing
flour for people to demo to try to sell
or whatever your goal is being able to
just use a tenth of a gram there's a
huge cost savings right a tenth of a
gram instead of an eighth in a joint or
even in a even in like a little mini J
like an even a mini J is gonna be you
know probably 2 or 3 grams at the very
least probably two grams fairly what
okay so this first one on the market
what like when could I first buy know if
first one on the market I want to say
like June of last year but we really hit
our stride in October October is when
you would have when you would have first
really heard of us and the reasons we
launched the the stealth Black Edition
weird
well you got over there so the stealth
black was the first the first version
that we had that is that was all black
comes this matte black but the torn down
ones actually a better example of it
because I've swapped out my heat sink
here you know we just in a weird way
we're actually doing better and the
reason is that those shops you can pay
with credit card probably the probably
the biggest barrier right now is that
people love it people people understand
it they see the value of it but if
you've got to pay $300 in cash usually
if you're going to dispensary like the
most I think I've ever brought into a
dispensary was 200 ollars in cash and
that was to buy weed right and I'm not
gonna then turn around and pull it
another 300 dollars to buy a vaporizer
no matter how good it is so we're
working on solutions you can obviously
buy it directly on our website go
space.com
we ship internationally pretty much
everywhere everywhere that's a lot more
allowed to ship which at this point is
most places yeah we shipped all states
that the I would say there's two one of
them is user error which is they just
didn't read the instructions that
understand how vaporizers work they
didn't bother to you know look up
anything okay usually didn't break it
it's very difficult to break obviously
being made of such high-quality
materials they said so when I when I was
with the the Fiddler's guys yes we
actually had to bust out the instrument
and and you have shown me how to use
that and I totally like was blank I was
like I know there's something about
hitting at three times I don't remember
what that does but
that something I think we're trying to
change the temperature yeah
[Music]
fortunately Jody I know sorry Cameron
was like I'm gonna focus and read
through this instructor it out if it's
green flashing that's giving the battery
indication it says press and hold the
mode button to display battery level
release then press and hold again to
display the current heat setting to be
fair when I first got it I first got
mine about two or three months before I
started working for ghost and when I
first got it and I found out there a
smartphone app I just downloaded the app
and never used the buttons on the device
like I used the vape button on the back
to use it but otherwise I just turned it
on and did all the temperature
management on the app it was only once I
started a ghost and I realized that you
could change the temperature on the
device itself that I realized that I
needed to look up the instructions and I
as an employee of ghost pulled out my
box I pulled out the instructions and I
read up and literally read it one time
like once you figure out the button
sequence it's it's not difficult to
remember but I read the instructions and
figured it out and most people that we
find they after about one day of use
have figured out how to turn it on they
figured out how to change the
temperature is they figured out the draw
speed there kind of technique on using
it and after about a day there they're
golden
so the second complaint though is it was
the second plane it was user error and
no visible vapor that's a common and the
reason I say no visible vapor is as we
were discussing before I would I would
argue that if you are tasting if you're
tasting something and if you're getting
high then it doesn't matter if you're
seeing oh yeah I think anybody once they
get it gets it it's the process of going
from your initial expectation to get and
when I was with like you can watch the
video you literally watch us in real
time figuring stuff out with the ghost
which is like a how to use that one
button to do 18 different things and
then number two was we're all sitting
there like everyone's sucking really
hard on it
and we're like is it working and then
we're like we are all super high right
now
so I think it might be working yeah
there's just and that was when we were
like oh me and I was like maybe it's
like better if you're not blowing vapor
out so to that point the only recently I
discovered the best the best
instructions for breathing technique if
you've ever done a guided meditation or
any kind of any any kind of yoga
meditation or anything that has a
breathing exercise where you're like 10
seconds like
well you want to it's not that you want
to take a 10-second breath
it's that you want to spread your breath
across ten seconds and if you do that
then it forces you to draw at the
correct speed because if you guys are
sitting there sucking on it there's a
very good chance that either a it was
packed too tightly or B you're pulling
too fast and because the the definitely
only downside of having your lungs be
part of the mechanism is that if you're
pulling too fast you're pulling that hot
air across the material before it can
actually transfer its heat to the
material so you're essentially not
giving it any time to heat up well it's
like when I try to teach my
four-year-old daughter how to swim and
I'm like the more you flail around the
worse off you are just relax and float
on your back yeah you could like float
across the entire pool exactly so in my
research you know I I don't I forget how
it is I made my way to ghosts but but it
just it just you know and there's just
so many products on the market and the
one and the one problem for that article
at is I'm hands-on so I wanted to be
able to try it out is that a problem is
that a problem well no no I wasn't able
to oh no I don't that is a big yes so
you know I kind of had to you know do
that part a bit blind yeah pretty much
it was a learning experience for me and
you with respect to ghosts specifically
I don't I don't have any follow-up
questions and it was a quality product
and all I knew from that one after the
article was I wanted to get my hand
that's good you know that's good and
that's that's good and again you tried
it with the concentrate what do you
think about the concept it was it was
awesome yeah I was a flavor and listen
the flavors you know bringing out the
flavors is really what it's all about
yeah you know there's there's a lot of
things I appreciate about this one right
now the fact it doesn't get really hot
it's easy to use that electronically is
well-made but the bottom line is the
experience
and if you can because that's my
experience longtime smoker yeah longer
than you guys have been around but the
last few years learning to appreciate
that nuanced experience has has really
been very exciting yeah you know so and
I love all the look like because I'm not
a blow my brains I don't go to show her
and dab and write down I wanna be able
have conversations I want to do that so
now experiencing the new you know like
Rosen's new Levin resins and those
things and to be able to consume them
properly and experience them properly is
mind-expanding literally yeah it's not
my numbing yeah it's the opposite
exactly yeah so that's a beautiful thing
about you mister we're in mr. Rogers
neighborhood
hey there's trolley it sells well people
love it we're doing great we're yeah
we're just working on expanding and
visibility and get more consumers so
weird one of the main things that we're
trying to do is get to as many consumer
events as possible there's many
opportunities to get it in front of
people because as you know I can sit
here and tell you all day every day how
great it is how great the flavor is how
easy it is to use how you would dial in
those terpenes but because there really
is no other device that gives you that
kind of control there's no frame of
reference right so you don't actually
you don't actually understand or even
believe what I'm saying until you try it
like we were just this Saturday we're at
an event downtown that was a consumer
event and we had plenty of people coming
up like and these this is a consumption
lounge where people were smoking joints
rolling huge joints and they would come
up and they're like oh what is this oh
it's a vaporizer oh it's nice and once
you gave him a shot once you give him a
chance to actually hit it every go every
single one guaranteed they blow up the
smoke blog the vapor oh whoa oh and
because of the heat sink
the vapor comes out so cool that these
people that are used to taking huge hits
from bongs or joints whatever it is they
don't realize how big of a hit they're
taking so they're sitting there kind of
like mmm that's good I'm getting good
flavor this is good it was good and then
they they finish their draw and they
blow out and that's the vapor just keeps
coming and keeps coming and they start
coughing oh I liked it Oh
like we have a lot of people that walk
away from our booth or walk away from
our table wherever we're demoing and
coffee just like what did not expect
that was not expecting that
because the vapor just comes out so cool
so sales are good
[Laughter]
this is like the first product the hero
product I would say so
is there another product in the pipeline
and what what do you want to do is it
just like the Model S of this or is it
something totally different for a
different purpose you know there's this
there's always a lot of different
answers to that like what's this one
called this is called the ghost mb1 so
so you're talking about the MV 2 for
instance okay but let's say not oh what
happened to two things one
what's the improvements that you want to
make or not improvements what's the a
different word additional features you
want to put in the MV 2 and then
secondly what's a totally different
product you guys are conceptualized yeah
I mean I think the the idea of
improvement is is pretty clear you know
we listen to our customers you know we
hear what they have to say and you know
I think most of them focus around the
interface and so that's a clear
opportunity for us and there's a lot of
ways there are so many parallels like
here is a Panasonic
EBA one here's a Panasonic gh4 I have
can it like they each and then your
phones and things like all these things
have different interfaces that you need
to learn and some are just you're just
like that's so frustrating why do they
make that
interphase decision right right and as
you said you know everyone now is aware
of user interface and and so now the
playing field is different your minimum
product has to be it has to meet
expectations or exceed them and that
means it has to take all of this into
consideration where users are going to
expect the feedback to be what kind of
feedback it is and is it intuitive and
that's really what we want to make is as
intuitive as possible so that you need
no instruction whatsoever you just have
it in your hand and the product tells
you how to use it
it just it just knows and it knows you
right away so those are the things you
know aspirationally and you know for a
next-gen that's what yeah I totally
random funny example you know I was
looking at like a GoPro and I was like
this one's cheaper and it has great
reviews I bought it and the first time I
filmed with it
I pulled the footage and it had the
timestamp in the footage and so I
emailed the company being like I can't
figure out where and how to turn off the
timestamp because I don't want it to say
like January 1st 1999 or like what cuz
you never said that thing and they were
like yeah I know you can't do that and I
was like am I the first person who's
brought this at it and that's that's
like a firmware update right that should
be a simple very mine and they're like
yeah sorry yeah well to that point one
of the things that we that I really love
about the ghost and that I love about
the fact that this is this is more a
technology company than ever than
anything so we have we obviously have an
app we've got firmware I can tell you
late-breaking news we have a new update
to the app coming out I have the beta
version of it
you heard your first app update so and
what's interesting is bad news obviously
we can't change the hardware so we're
limited by what we already have but with
software we're able to make some very
kind of minor but very valuable
improvements and one of the changes that
I love that was a big for me as
that the current way to change the
temperature that's I don't have a
different one but the way to change the
temperature is you press and hold on
this multifunction button for about
three seconds you'll see the battery
level blink and you press and hold it
again to get to the temperature right
when you do that once or twice I call
guys normally impressing hold give the
battery press an old you to the
temperature right once you've been doing
that for a few months and you do it
every day all day and you're changing
the temperature a lot having to go
through the battery level every single
time gets a little bit tedious not a
deal-breaker it's not a reason to return
it it's not a reason to hate it but it's
just it's not great so to have like fuck
the function one button which gets you
right in so what we so what we did on
the newest version of the app and the
newest version of the firmware is we
just gave you the option to change the
order that those come in so I changed it
so it goes straight to the temperature
so when I press and hold temperature not
battery level so it's those kinds of
little changes that we can very easily
make via software and we are obviously
making that we don't have to do a new
card where we don't have to release any
product people don't have to buy a new
version of it we can just roll out
software updates and suddenly your vape
has a whole new mode or a whole new
setting or somewhere in color or I mean
we can do we can't do that it just
change the color of the LEDs but yeah so
there's there's a lot of opportunity
with the fact that it is a connected
device
yeah I mean in the ghost I think ship
rinsky's works really well um wonder
Brett works really well I've actually
just hopped on the trend of Fidel's
he sells at her rhenium in LA um really
good concentrate really good live resin
rock garden works perfectly perfectly
well in the vape as well um honestly
anything that's just grown really well
that's grown with respect because we
like to respect the flower that people
really put the time in to grow their
flower to get the best flower to it so
that people even growing like terpenes
you know for THC design putting them on
the on the on the bottle it's perfect
for us you know to specifically hit
those temperatures so if you know what
you're getting out of your you know what
terpenes are in your flowers and big
doses for any of those flowers you know
anyone who puts that time in to
cultivate and get those terpenes out of
their plan
okay we're gonna go right down the line
when not using the ghost babe what are
you smoking out of are you rolling
joints a bong another usually doing
joint pattern no usually doing joints
joints or bongs I currently have a graph
a graph helix long so if I'm not using
them b1 I mean that's what I'm using
yeah same question I'm not gonna lie I'm
like 99% mv1 like I've I've now just
added the interest of product research
I've now tried the Firefly the solo to
the mighty the crafty a bunch of cheap
Chinese vaporizers a bunch of knockoff
brands and every time I come back to the
mv-1
pretty much immediately because the
other ones are not great I have on
occasion smoked a 2 or 3 puffs from a
joint because that's about all I can
ever handle and then I immediately wash
my hands sometimes take a shower at the
very least change my clothes because I'm
not I'm not wild about the lingering
smell of cannabis in general which is
why I like vaporizers wait what else do
you smoke out of you know like the whole
time joints I do I was never good at
joints I was really good at bowls though
yeah and at any time it's like okay you
know I have the ghost and I love it but
sometimes the closest thing is the
preloaded bowl that I always keep in my
shed and and it's always ready to go
it's the perfect pack and so I'll I'll
hit on that every once in a while just
because it's right there and the lighter
sits right next to it and then I
realized though why now I've discovered
vaporizers cuz it's like okay I know
this will get me high in a second but
still it tastes like shit and it's like
I feel like my my throat is literally on
fire
so it's like it's good to have that so
that I can appreciate vaporizers as much
as I do so yeah you're completely right
on that I love how we get no coughs on
them v1 yeah it's great it's a surprise
actually get I forget how smooth it is
until I hit a joint and then I remember
her look that's why I only get like two
or three puffs because I taste I like I
get like a pre-roll or I use my
my fancy Auto to roll a joint for me
which is nice and then I'll pack it and
I'll light it and I'll get maybe two or
three hits and then it's just too much
it's too much it hurts my chest throat
right I'm done okay I guess I'll just
I'll just untwist it and pour the
underneath that remaining stuffing
crucibles
[Music]