okay well i'm here with jill from golden
gardens farm and we're going to be
talking about her farm a bit and
checking out her flower so hi jill hello
how's it going good good glad to be here
today me too um so tell us a little bit
about your background with cannabis and
you know how you got started
well um
my husband has a degree in horticulture
and landscape design from michigan state
university and he started growing in
college
and we met in 2011 in san francisco
my background is in construction
management and together we realized we
wanted to get out of the rat race and
the corporate jobs that we were in
and we together had the experience to
start cultivating cannabis so we started
indoors in san francisco and the east
bay okay and had the opportunity to move
up to humboldt uh when legalization came
around
which was great
we were a bit more interested in
or we are excited about being outdoors
and
and gardening a plant
is awesome but we were walking into a
concrete building every day still under
fake lights with dehus and co2 emitters
and air conditioning
and so
we ourselves wanted to be
gardening outside in the garden and how
much more would the plants like that too
so we jumped on the opportunity to
come up here and have been here since
amazing that's awesome
um
why do you
like what draws you to farming like what
is it just the freedom of not being
attached to the corporate jobs because i
get that yeah but is there something
else you like about it there's also
farming not only cannabis but having the
ability up here to grow our own food
um farm vegetables work with the soil
you're really a soil soil farmer if
you're a farmer or gardener yeah
but
working outside and in nature and with
nature
having hands in the soil touching the
plants being active and in it is
hard to explain but it's very
can be very stressful owning your own
business but it can all also be very
meditative
just putting on a podcast or music and
just
connecting with the plants and figuring
out what they need what they want yeah
for sure i hear it i know it
so um anything unique about your farm
like is it an interesting microclimates
challenges like what's um we're at about
1800 feet okay so
relatively high yeah we uh we're up
there we have a very small farm
and
my husband and i and we have one
employee out there
full time
which
allows us to be very hands-on we go
through and touch every plant multiple
times through its life
we have
we have beds but we have fabric side
beds
so we actually do three runs a year we
do a spring a summer and a fall run oh
yeah it's having the fabric beds allows
the beds to breathe when it's not
necessarily hot outside and then you can
still water yeah water consistently
better drying and it dries out exactly
yeah it makes sense yeah the springtime
i used to do some springtime runs too
like march april yep and they're very
challenging yeah uh temperature and
moisture levels yeah when the in april
when it's in the daylight is about 12 12
that's when we start our first run
typically yeah
most some cultivars do better than
others in the spring we have found for
sure some are a bit more robust and
tend to
not necessarily notice the cold at the
beginning of their life and then by the
time that they're harvested in june
it's warm and dry outside yeah
do you feel like i mean intuitively when
i just when you say that i think about
like more you know
for lack of a better word indica
dominant or broad leaf you know like
afghan
varieties that are just used to the cold
i don't do you feel like that's true or
not um
i haven't noticed that in particular we
don't go through a lot of varieties
because of our size we can't have many
cultivars or we don't have enough
material of each
yeah that's so that's a unique challenge
for you guys that's true that is a
unique challenge and just keeping up
with the industry right now we still
have to grow something high t and
high in thc to have it move yeah so your
options are kind of limited what we have
found the best um is the longer the
flower cycle the better it does in the
spring
probably because it has more of its life
time oh sure like the later stage oh
that's interesting yeah no that makes
sense it's like the later by the time
it's flowering a week five six seven
eight right nine it's you know the
development of those flowers can
rapidly expand and if it's already
warmer out then that's the right time
for that exactly that's interesting the
shorter strain in the spring is not good
although we do pick a shorter weak
strain for our fall run yeah six to
seven weeks strain because now it's
finishing when it's getting cold and the
lights decreasing outside more and more
do you feel like there's any other man
like do you have any interesting
management practices just regarding um
you know
methodologies you use like entire in
terms of inputs or um
we get our anything say it again been
working on any
my husband has the horticulture major so
he kind of he understands the science of
it and that's where i've learned most of
the science of cultivation
um we do get our soil tested and have
amendments made to the soil cool um and
we fight a lot you know
as a farmer like i said before you're a
soil farmer so we it all starts in the
soil we
fight a lot of uh
molds mildews bugs a lot of that stuff
can be fought if you treat your soil
correctly and they don't have a place to
to breed and develop
um let's see so speaking of of your farm
and flowers let's check out some of
these flowers we brought two samples for
us today yep i got an apple fritter oh
apple fritter yeah
this is
you'd think i'd
see more of these trains
as i go around so these funny funnily
enough some of these are first for me so
it's great so let's see
apple fruit is a good one it grows on
our property really well it uh
oh it smells good yeah
we used to grow sherbert and those sweet
strains and this
yeah grows very similar to that oh it's
just sticky to the touch like it's
already like tacky yeah like sticky
sticky this one came out of our fall run
actually so we harvested it oh man it's
all it's got some nice purple hues to it
it really almost has that appley
oh wow
it almost smells like my wife's making
like green apples into a pie or
something yeah
yeah it's interesting yeah it's amazing
and this was was this dap or yup yeah
well yeah
yeah yeah sort of yeah okay yeah we have
a full dip farm amazing
and then we have the p
you see pineapple upside down side down
cake that one i know
that's a shorter
life cycle so it does does good for us
in the fall and the
cold at the end of the
flower's life
yeah wow makes colors come out
it's got that pineapple smell
oh it's so loud the terps are so loud
yeah that one is did they ever do any
pro concentrate processing with this one
do you guys just sell flowers we just
sell flowers so i'm not sure
wow right now yeah that's amazing right
you never know yeah
there's another year ahead
wow and then um
do you guys sell locally or do you have
products around the state
um right now we wholesale
one of the questions we've been asking
everyone if you could change one thing
in the industry whether it's like
through education or regulation
what would that what would that be
um
i think
the biggest thing for me right now would
probably be consumer education
and understanding
i mean i don't think any of us really
understand what this plant fully can do
but just to understand uh right now it's
so much about thc yeah and and
personally coming from indoor now moving
to outdoor you see how much more the
terpene profile
gives the plant its full full potential
full expression and how much more
important that can be yeah and how you
can have a very low thc plant that has
the terpene profile that speaks to what
your you need or what you're feeling and
it can be the best strain you've ever
and and even minor cannabinoids like
other minor for sure
yeah exactly
i agree i think there's a lot of
research that's that's going into that i
think there's a podcast uh kiss organics
i don't know if you know this guy you
know
yeah he a while back had an episode i
wish i could remember which one it was
but it was a scientist lady and i think
they were out in colorado i'm probably
wrong but basically the study was they
did a blind study
where people smoked weed and they were
doing high th seaweed and basically you
know 15 like a 30 thc versus a 15
with minor cannabinoids and higher
terpene levels and they showed that
consistently people chose the lower thc
weeks it just made them feel better
right is better body high absolutely
just in general well-being better
feeling of well-being overall right so i
think we got a lot of ways to go with
that but hopefully we can get there and
education's key we should talk more
about it because yeah it's interesting
for sure i think a big way to do that is
what many people have say is uh farmer
to consumer sales
because if you think about the vegetable
industry
and how you go to farmers markets and
you can talk to the person that grew
what you're buying and you're about to
consume
you know if if we could have um cannabis
farmers markets that's the best way to
maybe not the best bit it's a great way
to educate the customer
and they can now talk to the farmer the
gardener who grew it that's a great goal
to strive for yeah absolutely um let me
think there's one more thing i don't
know if you want to talk about it but
do you have anything that makes you'd
like to you know single out your product
against like a corporate model like what
what do you think makes your product
better than you know just like
mass-produced weed
um
i would think the biggest thing is the
love and care we put out there it's me
and my husband we're in our front yard
we have one worker and we're all out
there across from each other looking at
the plants caring about what the plants
need
individual needs yeah i'll go out there
to our employee and i'll be like i may
be the owner but these ladies are the
boss what they need goes
you know if they have a different
schedule we cater to that absolutely and
it shows in the flower so thank you
awesome thanks for that i appreciate it
thanks for your time today yeah thank
you all right have a good one you too