man gray wolf - like ya of man open like
there was a fierce board a there's a
couple guys who are like awesome in this
tech community - because they have
openly like upset a lot of people but
like kept this small band of people in
the technology side side of cannabis or
specifically in processing kind of
hanging on to each other like we all
follow each other not AG we see each
other at all these events there it's not
a huge group of people and so gray wolf
and he doesn't even he's not even on
Instagram which is yeah but he he's an
old codger that that he's been designing
closed loop systems for well he he's an
engineer and the closed loop systems
he basically Oaks open source them on
the internet so people could so it would
destroy the ability to make patents
around them so then people could
actually yeah make the machines
themselves so he open-source them very
to just make sure that people would be
able to make closed-loop butane designs
and don't know if you're familiar with
connoisseur concentrates the mister
extractor it's a it's a about to say
something that might cause drama there
we you might there was a big video
series about how this company had owned
all these patents and they tried to
patent this stuff but it's really
they're not enforceable patents and
there's kind of Supercop kind of they
they got it and he was he's made a
pretty funny video series of him up and
this big no drew that's all i know him
as drew and with a couple of pretty
blondes and him in front of a desk
overseeing like LA or something and he
talks about and he gives
an hour-long series about how he's he
owns all the patents he's gonna be the
future of the industry and it was like
it was pretty cringy yes it was a
groaner yeah the whole thing yeah and I
believe that he's actually the gray wolf
has been sued for some of the stuff they
put out he's had to deal with no
actually
skunk farm had gotten bought from
another company and there's some really
ugly stuff going on around the open
sourcing of that but people have
attacked gray wolf for what he has tried
open source and he's been like copied
all over the industry like if you see a
closed-loop butane extractor like
something on it's probably like taken
from one of his designs almost
everything out there is based on a
terminator design the terminator was you
know a bunch of try clamped spools you
put the material in the small ones they
have passive passive ones that use high
you could just put in hot water and ice
and recover your butane but it started
out with just a small little Turpin ATAR
series on scum farm research comm and
then eventually he started showing an
automated mark to version that they
worked on to where it was all pneumatic
valves and then they and then they they
brought it as the mark 3 was the basic
design that everybody's been working
that the early design for the mini
closed-loop to everybody worked on these
are hydrocarbon closed-loop extraction
systems so just getting the oil off the
plant yeah so basically zero business
you have a column you pack the the
material in the column you pass butane
through the column at the bottom it's
all collected with oil under vacuum and
then you heat
that and you heat that bottom pot and
then you would pull all the solvent out
and then recover it with some type of
condenser or a pump that was the fun
days of using a peon HVAC recovery pumps
and then eventually it moved to TR 21
HVAC recovery pumps and then you had
companies come in like with the camera
over the name of the company but the CM
e pol series of these little stainless
boxes for recovering like most of the
pubs like that was a that was the first
approved one I believe there's that and
then there was the pneumatic Haskell's
that were built around that as well but
eyes were these most of the pumps that
were used for the first at least five
years four years are doing it we're all
like the same kind of pumps you would
pump freon into your AC system like
that's the only thing that really fit
that marketplace and a lot of the
technology that you would use I would be
a lot safer was kind of like you had to
go through I was passive they mean a lot
of people you could just add heat and
add cooling and one slide trouble like
going to specific companies and saying
hey you know this is our company and
this is what we do and they wouldn't
even they wouldn't sell us anything
they've like no you don't fit the
criteria of people that we sell our
products to with like pharmaceutical
supplies you know like even inert you
know getting via bees yeah yeah getting
butane and mass you know like all these
limonene yeah and trying to do it
legally you know so yeah as much as
possible