[Music]
you won the SoCal grow off last year and
where did the genetics come from those
from dark heart nursery I think was the
grapefruit in the romulan then that was
but but you didn't know it at the time
no no I mean everybody had their ideas
but we were way off we get - it was
funny because when we got there we
didn't have at the money order so to
find the money order we went on a
mission walking four blocks to find a
place so by the time we got there it was
it was funny because I'd saw heavy tea
or Tyler at the time and this is just
before we started doing the podcast and
it was always fun for me I think that
whole contest was really for me to see
what I could do against him in my mind
so it was a fun little aspect to that I
just see them pop up randomly you get
two clones and you bring them back and
not knowing what it is how does that
affect you in terms of a growth it's
just like being a chef I would consider
it it's like I like to cook and I think
that a lot of good chefs out there you
can give them a different stovetop you
can give them a different pan and they
know enough to where like looking at how
it's searing looking at how it's cooking
they already know when it's close to
done just by feeling it and you know to
me you know part of being a good growers
experience so over the years it's
knowing little things like that is
knowing the plant structure as it grows
I knew immediately it wasn't a very
stretchy plant will call it it was
definitely a long veg but in that long
veg I think with you know different
varieties of strains they would grow a
lot more lankier in that time period
which was a nice thing that it states so
squat because for me at the beginning I
thought the whole contest was based on
who can grow the biggest plant you know
and for me it was just I think
everybody's mindset and in I don't know
since like 2010 yield you know everybody
it was big thing to hit two pounds
alight and then people were hitting
three pounds of light you know and it
was a big thing for people so for me it
was like okay I started out growing big
plants originally because when I would
have a personal grow you know to be
perfectly legal it was six plants in
California so I was like okay well six
plants one plant per light I got six
lights here we go you know most people
are thinking oh I'll put six plants
under one light it then it became okay
so we're able to grow and and for me
everybody learns from somebody I'm not
gonna say the guy's name cuz he was a
rule I call him old man chicory but he
was a family dude you would have never
thought this guy Groupon it and I
remember walking into his garden for the
first time and it felt like a scene out
of Jurassic Park like I've been growing
for a long point to that time and to see
somebody growing these monster plants
that were just kind of trellis tout and
just these huge colas I was just it blew
my mind and you know I think when I saw
that I was like oh this makes sense and
we started to grow any genetic one plant
for light and just knowing the veg x of
them and how to manipulate the plant
that we just need to fill that 4x4
square under that thousand watt and and
we knew that we're gonna get at least a
pound and a half to two plus pounds off
this one plant and you know between two
people we could have 12 plants you know
and it was kind of a loophole for us in
a sense you know most people like for me
sometimes like people smoke
I think chain smoke cigarettes it's not
that I change smoke but I love to smoke
just the act of it so if I'm medicating
I think that you know unless I grew
enough it wouldn't have been worth it to
me to just grow one light and six plants
after seeing this it just blew my mind
when I saw the contest I was like okay
I've been doing this forever this is
gonna be easy
so you know I think that everybody was
so focused on the quality and in the the
potency and these other aspects as Minh
to the results because we yield it's so
much more than even the second-place
competitor I think maybe they got a half
a pound and we got almost four pounds
off this one plant which it was cool to
see the Colorado contest kind of step it
up I saw even before this contest a lot
of people were really focusing on
getting these huge yields off one plant
and I think that's really cool that you
know for me most people have always said
oh don't grow a big plant because it
wouldn't be as potent as a plant that's
smaller and there's philosophies where
people would say well growing a smaller
more compact plant takes that plants
energy and and puts all of this into one
smaller bud meaning it may be more
potent here say and I know that we
stretched it right to the deadline when
we when we we turn it in I think even
the product we turned in was it was
unflushed because it was I I think it's
still needed at least about another
seven to ten days before we pulled the
plant but because of the deadline with
se labs and the the laws everybody's
hands were tied we had to do it by the
31st so you know still being able to get
third place and potency in fourth place
and the terpenes it was huge to me
because I know we didn't finish the
plant how we wanted to but the the yield
was just what over three pounds over
even second place I was like that to me
spoke a lot because you got situations
like you know I talked with people that
are in Michigan and having a large full
mature plant count stipulation where you
don't see that the same in other states
while being able to grow larger plants
is a huge advantage for people like that
because then you're actually increasing
the amount they're able to produce as
well so you know
it was a cool way that I guess she'll
showcase something that I've been doing
for a long time and you know I've been
the guy that worked behind the counter
in the Hydra store and you're always
giving people advice and I was always
that crazy guy that would grow one plant
for light and you know they'll be like
no show him a picture of it drums show
him a picture and I would show people
pictures and then just blow their mind
that you can do this so you know I think
a lot of you know what people don't
believe is possible is because they've
never seen it and I think the more this
competition actually grows they're gonna
be able to actually bring people in
there with cameras and and really go
into detail about their growing
practices and let's be honest some
people aren't gonna give away all their
secrets you know for me growing at least
cannabis has always been about for what
I could do for my sister who passed away
from cancer you know at the time we had
dispensaries but it wasn't tested and it
wasn't as strict and you knew that there
was harsh chemicals and there was things
that we didn't even know to this day
that were happening that we could have
prevented for people to get the cleanest
medicine and for me to do that was to
grow it for her and she wasn't a smoker
basically so you know exactly what's in
it yeah absolutely you know that it's
the peace of mind and not many people
get that experience you get something
we'll call it stepped on you never have
the opportunity to get quality medicine
right from the grower themselves right
to you it's very rare for people to have
that experience because even in today's
date you have a product that's being
produced at a legal you know clean
facility then that products then being
sent for testing and by the time it's
packaged it's been touched and and moved
so many times that you lose kind of to
me that visual aspect of quality that
you get when you you actually get it
right from the source it's just like
anything that's fresh there's there's a
slight and subtle difference that only
the people that would know will know and
that's the thing that people need to be
educated about and for me to grow clean
cannabis you know I've always wanted to
do as clean as possible and it always
didn't make sense
well we have an indoor grow but we're
gonna take outdoor elements like cocoa
or soil and bring them indoors to me
that wasn't necessarily a the most
sterile thing that I could do as far as
a common sense factor to me is I
wouldn't take something that necessarily
is for instance cocoa core they they let
it sit out doors it gets heated they
turn it you know it doesn't matter it
shipped around these are things that are
not necessarily isolated to know that
that was probably in a processing
facility where they have rats running
around the floor and to me rockwool
because it's fun it's such a high heat
level I think they say it's at 700 some
long degrees you have a very sterile
substrate to me that comes from an
organic source being it's it's spun rock
come down into like a cotton candy kind
of substrate so is that your preferred
grow media I think so just because of
the sterility of it it's it do we factor
in ecological and environmental factors
I think you know with that there's a lot
of water consumption savings in benefit
to that because you're able to
necessarily not use the abundance of
water you would have in deep water
culture under current systems where they
use an ample amount of water and at the
end of the cycle or for that reservoir
change you have excess water that you're
dumping down the drain so when people
here drained away systems or feeding
systems that wastewater because there's
actual runoff coming out of the bottom
of the pond you have to really think
about how much water it took to saturate
those plants how much water you're
actually wasting in versus you know
people use what 40 to 50 gallon
reservoirs per 4 by 8 table in old
school days doing these flood and drain
systems when to me that's it doesn't
seem logical because they're topping
that off through the week and then
they're just dumping it down the drain
and that's a lot of wasted water and
nutrients and you know depending on how
that setup different states have laws
and stipulations about the chemicals
that can go down the drain some of them
have different type of systems that
collect this runoff ways so it's not
contaminated
where we're dumping it for instance I
believed and I could be wrong i believe
california doesn't have a law on this so
we kind of just dump it down
I believe the ocean is where a lot of
this goes you know we're Altima all
trying to do the right thing
you know at least you could always just
hope that people are at the end of the
day you know we want to have this plant
broken down and isolate it into ways
that we can actually save people's lives
and and use it for a benefit you know
and I and I think that realistically I
would love to see cannabis get to the
point where you pay for your health
insurance you pay a five to ten dollar
copay for expensive medicine if people
didn't have to spend let's say two three
four or five hundred plus dollars a week
on their medication going to a
dispensary and paying these taxes you
know and it was worked out that way I
think everybody would benefit from that
you know for me I've always been the
person that knows how to do it in my my
head at least the right way and you know
it's kind of cool to be able to answer
people's questions so I've always worked
you know whether it's doing the podcasts
and things and in speaking at different
events it's like I almost wish I never
had to work for anybody in particular
it's almost fun to just consult with
different people because as much as
they're learning for me I'm learning
from different situations can you kind
of talk about your own evolution and
things you've experimented with you're
doing kind of so cal indoor right is
that kind of your main I mean I don't
know if it's SoCal indoor you know I
base everything on me it's it's all
about common sense for me and for me to
optimize anything as far as plant growth
you don't have to be a scientist to
realize the faster you can get a plant
to go through the water and nutrients
that are in the media itself more
rapidly the plant is going to grow just
as fast so the thing is is it's always
been in being able to grasp whatever
system it is the biggest thing well -
like obviously deep water culture in
in true hydroponic style systems where
the roots are suspended in water where
you have to play the saturation game
whether it's in soil or cocoa or rock
well you're always looking at the drying
time period in the wilting points of
this plant and not letting those roots
dry out too much to create a lockout so
there's good and bad stresses that you
can give to the plant and for me
common-sense is obviously get them to
drink as fast as possible have the most
root mass as possible meaning for me you
know you look at the different types of
potting containers whether it's a smart
pod or an air pot the whole philosophy
for that is a root pruning pot so the
science is is when the root tip makes
contact with the air it causes that to
some necessarily die off at that point
and stop growing but it also creates
supplementals that branch out causing a
much denser root system where you don't
have the spiraling of the roots choking
the plant out at a certain point and you
know you can extend the longevity of the
plant's life in a smaller container
which with irrigation you know you can
obviously cut down on the amount of
transplanting I think that's a huge part
of you know people using rock wall
blocks once you transplant them from the
clone stage they're in the same
container till the time they die
essentially and so there's not that
stress of going into a different you
know and there's a lot of benefits to
that you know as far as the cleanliness
to me and being able to clean a room
after and the the different types of
cleaning methods that go into a soil or
Coco room you have a lot of different
problems with drains clogging up biofilm
and sludge accumulating with a lot of
different organics and I'm not saying
I'm against organics but you know
there's benefits to it in a true sense
of nature if you're collecting data and
you're able to take a plant and take
that plant and actually plant it let's
say every square inch of the entire
earth and collect the data don't return
let it do its own thing we're gonna see
where this plant thrived the most
collect the data there
and try to recreate that in an indoor
environment so with that plants will be
able to create their own food whether
it's environmental or it's the plants
themselves being able to break down the
the foliage or whatever type of forms of
compost that are there naturally and
what's occurring there in the soil is
meaning those beneficial microorganisms
that we create teas and additives to try
and simulate but some of them are
actually beneficial and you take those
that are in nature and you try and
create a tea to brew those specific
species of fungi and bacteria well all
these things are just basically
chelating nutrients to the plan I
believe in any type of environment
whether it's hydroponic or not a plant
having its own sugar production you know
from its roots we have cellulose that
needs to be broken down by cellulose so
or I'm sorry cellulose that's broken
down by cellulase and that's the plant
creating its own sugars to feed those
beneficial organisms with its own form
of carbohydrates
we have different types of additives we
can add to feed these which help them
colonize at a much faster rate assuming
that the higher collimation rates of
these microorganisms were able to
benefit the plant by feeding it faster
it's it's my way of saying imagine
having a milkshake that's really hard to
suck up the nutrients with a straw and
then giving your plant a bigger straw
and in with that in turn you're
optimizing all the other elements
whether it's temperature humidity
lighting and all these things go into
the the benefit of the rapid growth that
you see and you know that's why when
people are so stuck in one way it's it's
a terrible thing to see because I think
I can get better every day and the thing
is is if you aren't that person
searching out these different aspects
like for me seven eight years ago
telling people about LED technology and
they're just kind of like rolling their
eyes I've been using that technology for
years especially in like a vegetative
state it was always a difficult finding
the right way to do it in Flour and I
never had the success that we have
but as people are switching over to LED
we see the benefits with that with
electrical consumption we see
substantial benefits for different for
instance like we have DWP here in LA in
Southern California Edison and different
states have their different power
sources but they're creating different
rebate programs that if we're consuming
so much energy with a thousand watt amp
you know or a thousand watt ballasts and
we designed that for HIDs and switching
to LEDs they're giving these people huge
benefits as far as rebates to pay for
these lights so it's helping the owners
and you know we get into people that
have been doing this for years that
we're brands that that you know have
been struggling to stay afloat with all
the loopholes like you know for instance
different cities have stipulations I see
all the time where they're asking these
20 light rooms all of a sudden to shut
down because they don't have a co2
monitor that can only be installed by
the contractors from the city and it's
$28,000 per room how do you tell
somebody that's already struggling at
that point to come up with this money
and it's a sad thing to see but at the
same time it's gonna evolve to a point
where I'd like to see all these
companies survive but at the end of the
day unless that company is putting the
money into the technology to research
exactly what we need in the plant we
need to figure that out because now
we're just now integrating lighting
systems with infrared and ultraviolet
light which to me was a no-brainer back
in the day if we get to the last couple
weeks of a cycle we were putting in
10,000 K UV bulbs and getting this spike
in to me it's like plants naturally have
defense mechanisms and people know as
resin to be one of them and different
resins for instance like especially a
lot of people that grow there's certain
strains I just have a negative reaction
to around like I get itchy
my skin gets red or irritated and you
can only accommodate that to what's in
the plant naturally and as they have
these resin glands we have to think not
only do they get us high or Medicaid us
but they deters things that they would
sustain in nature
were they originated from so to me we
get burned our skin from ultraviolet
light a plant creates more resin content
towards the end of its cycle especially
when it's developing the resin when
finishing by creating its own sunscreen
protecting itself from ultraviolet light
so it's a no-brainer to me and you know
I think the further we actually bring in
real gardening practices a lot of people
always called them strawberries or
tomatoes walking into Anna hydroponics
who are trying to get advice from
somebody that was growing in their
closet or whatever it may be and you
know whether it's a dosatron system
which is what from car wash industry and
agricultural industry and we're just
like oh this is the next greatest thing
this is things that have been around and
you know it's the big gold rush for a
lot of companies to create the next
gimmick but all these things have
already been implemented into large
systems already whether from greenhouse
or large-scale farming so you know we're
gonna we're gonna see I wouldn't at
least hope all the hype kind of stop at
some point then was so you mentioned
LEDs so you're growing with LEDs and
you've grown with them for a long time
and you said you're flowering with them
too or right now we're converting a lot
of them to the flower
we've been doing a lot of experiments
with a company called Pro grow tech and
they've been doing custom lighting for
us that we're gonna basically take to a
cannabis project I'll speak a little bit
but we'll be developing the second
research facility at the University of
Gainesville Florida to research cannabis
and we're gonna leave fun our licensed
facility yes and where's the FIR the
first ones in Mississippi yep okay so
this will be literally right yeah it's
it's gonna be a lot different right you
know we put a lot of thought in this and
you know for me to to meet some of the
the scientist that are involved with it
actually there's just past MJ buzz
Connor
was introduced to some of the people
involved with a company called medicinal
genomics and yeah I sat down in a
meeting with Brian mckernon and and a
few other guys there from the the
company and it was almost a match made
in heaven I guess I didn't know till
about 12 hours later when I called back
for another meeting and it's it's really
cool to be a part of something like that
I think it's uh it's really a dream of
mine because for me I've always wanted
to be the best or whatever I do that's
why I love golf it's you know I always
tell my nieces it's like look if you
don't like sports but you want to get
involved in some of golf's a great thing
because if you're good at it and get
paid to take a vacation and get paid
every week and it's you against the
field it's you and everything that you
do you can't take away from you that you
accomplished and you know being able to
grow a superior product or you know
something that makes somebody feel
better even if you don't hear it that's
a great feeling you know it really is
let's say for the grow-op specifically
kind of what was your setup so it seems
like LED lights like what like are using
BIOS are you using well we used an LED
so let me explain the process for me I
started out the first half a flower
meaning the first four weeks for me I
just called it a nine week cycle just in
case I think we really should have ran
that plan about ten ten and a half weeks
but for instance the first four weeks
especially having a higher orange-red
level of light with an HID HPS like a
Gabi delight for me I took advantage of
getting this plant to stretch out and
cover a massive area so you know getting
those Reds in there was huge and that's
why you know at the time I used a black
dog LED for the second half of flowers
specifically because it being a full
spectrum light incorporating the
ultraviolet in there as well was great
to finish the plan especially to bring
up resin production after I already got
the plant to stretch and that was the
plan I think that you know that's why
with the
Rotech one of the things that drew me to
the company immediately is the full
capability of tuning the spectrum
meaning I can go ahead and take the the
red levels and tune it down by you know
a five ten percent ratio of the white
blue levels and then being able to
custom integrate infrared and
ultraviolet light into this as well I
think that what people are gonna see
what I've always noticed with LEDs
especially for veg it was nice because
we were able to double stack by
controlling the height level of the
plants and I think that really came down
to the frequency of the lighting itself
Jay era was one of the guys that brought
the the Gavita to life to market years
ago and when nobody was using
double-ended liens and one of the first
times I had met him he was showing me
the light I was like what is this thing
and after he explained it to me what I
took from that was we needed to increase
the frequency of the light for people
that have been growing a long time we
started with magnetic ballasts there are
these huge white boxes that would hum
and get hot not many people today that
are growing probably even know what this
is but they operated at such a low
frequency that if you took a picture of
your grow back in the day you'd see
these little wavy lines and you can
never get a great shot I don't care who
you are you never had a great shot of
your garden without getting these little
wavy lines even if you took a video and
what we noticed I compared this to like
for instance we all had flat screen TVs
10 years ago what's changed besides the
the 1080i you know picture it's always
been the same it was the the Hertz level
or the frequency of the lights blinking
himselves
for instance the first TVs operating at
like 60 Hertz so what I took from that
is if you watched high-definition
fast-paced motion action like sports
it would pixelate and you'd see this
ghosting effect and as that increased to
120 240 and beyond you took that away
and what this does as far as the
frequency of light for a plant is that
is measuring the times that that light
blinks for every one second and
operating at such a low frequency let's
say even if it's too
forty Hertz we're looking at something
going to a hundred thousand-plus Hertz
when we're going into like the type of
technology that Gavita brought in and
now that we're looking with LEDs you're
operating at such a high frequency that
you're optimizing the amount of light
that the plants actually getting every
one second and people don't realize
those little things like that
made a huge difference and when you
bring up the frequency and you can
actually manipulate the actual spectrums
of light you can manipulate the type of
growth you get from the plant meaning
whether it's tighter internodal spacing
a more compact plant or even being able
to take a plant that wouldn't be so
compact and with stretch typically and
being able to slow down the vertical
height of that by manipulating the
spectrums so with some of those
scenarios can you talk about how you're
dialing to make to achieve specific
effects well everybody's got to work
within their limitations your space is
your space so whether you have a four by
four tent a four by eight table or a row
you're you're always at the limit of
your space and knowing the amount of
edge time needed into accommodating for
me what I like about see when I say
Rockwell I use a loose rock wall and
it's hard to really explain to people
sometimes because grodan themselves has
made very different types of rock wall
over the years there was something that
they used to make that was granular or
absorbent granular repellent now also
known as grow wool they make like a cube
style and then a chunk which is probably
about 60% bigger than the actual cubes
which will compare to like a crouton
being able to know how to stuff these in
the pot the density at which they're put
in there and knowing the plants drinking
habits are huge and that comes into
experience when when you know certain
plants have a slower
vej time meaning they may just take a
longer time to grow to the size you need
them to fill a canopy with a certain
amount of plants or the amount of times
it drinks you could really put together
a room with multiple different genetics
and customize the media so that this way
it dries out whether it's just
evaporation of
natural moisture into the the atmosphere
itself or the plant absorbing that
moisture through the root system we want
them all ultimately to dry out at the
same time and being able to optimize the
amount of times you get them to drink
you can take a plant that doesn't
necessarily drink is fast and manipulate
the way that that potting media is put
together maybe it's a lighter mix where
repels more water from being held on
just naturally for a longer period of
time and it will dry out at the same
time as a pot mixed with maybe a more
absorbent style concoction we'll call it
the the loose media so you have your
little rock wall cube what's the rest of
the grow media that is surrounding it
for you and what size pots do you like
I've really liked the air pot
specifically for me we'll go back to
common sense there's a lot of root
pruning pots but to me it's the only pot
out there that actually raises the
surface level of the plan itself of
approximately 2 to 3 inches off the
ground which is benefit for a lot of
people some people are still in old
school saucer systems we'll call it
where you have runoff that the plant
will sit in and when you have a pot
old-school plastic container the roots
are exposed sitting into this stagnant
water we'll call it you're in a root
pruning pot like an air pot or a sack
pot it's still wicking this moisture
back into the pot but it's sitting in
stagnant water it was a great thing for
me I was like well there's multiple
benefits obviously if you're in that
type of a system it's not sitting in
stagnant water
you see rockwool systems even with cubes
now there's a lot of promotion of these
little screen inserts that you put into
the tables to me is just another
headache to clean later where it's
giving the roots more area because it's
raising them off the surface of the tray
which this pot does so there's benefits
like that just the amount of potting
media that you use in comparison to a
normal setup where you're using cocoa or
soil it's it's just a lot easier for me
it's a lot cleaner you don't have so
much sediment building up into the
tables causing different types of
pathogens to a career later on down the
line but but is your potting media 100
percent rock wall that's 100 percent
it's just a very custom mix it's hard to
explain people exactly how it's done and
how to stuff it in there because it's
one of those things when I when I
actually train people to do this we do
literally hands-on and you have to feel
the density at which you put it in and
how it's broken up and how much it's
it's it's a little bit more complicated
than it sounds you were a hundred
percent just in rock walls so now I get
that and then you're using and I'm
blanking because there are a bunch of
air pots or smart cause air plots air
pots
okay so you have rock wall and then what
size containers are using well for that
particular plant for the grow up we did
a twelve gone air pot I started in a one
gallon air bag so you got four pounds of
yield out of a 12 gallon air pot and
then in the end of the past I've always
used sevens and tens we went a little
bit bigger I think it's not huge no it's
not a big time yeah okay and then in
terms of the nutrients so for me I think
of two things one I want to talk about
kind of your nutrient mix and what
nutrients are using but then also we've
touched on sort of moisture levels and
for me I think of like trying to keep
the roots within a band of moisture
correct you know so you don't want it to
like get super soaked and then like it's
finding that petering you don't--it
going like blow past the band and then
come back into the band blow past at the
other direction so are you kind of a
proponent of frequent small dose
watering absolutely a Mike reducing the
water to keep an even saturation or a
constant saturation where it's not
sopping wet but it's not drying and I
think that perfect mixture allows for
the right amount of airflow to get to
the roots themselves as well it we we
cut off oxygen to the roots at a certain
point by water logging in them water can
only sustain a certain amount of oxygen
level for so long and at certain
temperatures it depletes rapidly
it'll fall out of solution when we're
let's just talk about the boiling point
of water right and it's such a rapid
rate we're separating this but at let's
say a level of 66 to 68 degrees we could
actually scientifically put the most
amount of oxygen within that water and
and deliver that to the plant if you're
trying to be optimum we'll call it and
then finding those small fluctuations of
well the nutrient takes this long to mix
it takes this long before the feeding
actually occurs the variance of the
temperature goes up or down in a certain
direction depending on different
variables some people are in cold
climates where they have cold flooring
some people don't have that issue so you
know everybody's grows always gonna be
different and I think you know there's
no perfect way you know and I think a
lot of growers are almost like an art
because you you get a canvas it's not
always the same
and depending on now how the city wants
you to have whatever Iowa space and
drinking fountains wherever and you know
you design it based on that to optimize
what you can do there and it's always
gonna be different for everybody it
doesn't matter who but you you develop a
good recipe to do that and then what's
kind of like your preferred not on the
commercial level right so set some of
this stuff I want to start exploring
more is is like bloom at tensiometer z--
they're basically these little carrot
looking intense geometers and basically
they you can set it so you kind of have
your moisture level you want to achieve
and if it's less moist they'll release
water or water plus nutrients and if
it's you know once it gets to the
optimal moisture level it'll stop so
let's say I mean think of it let's say a
greenhouse grow right one end of the
greenhouse that's maybe a little more
shady the other end that's hot and sunny
you know the air is blowing in one
direction so you're gonna have kind of
if everything gets watered the same
you're gonna have bok choy shirts yeah
you're gonna have its damp and moldy and
milled
we over here it's too dry over there
whereas if you have kind of each little
carrot steak well as long as companies
make these affordable for our operations
because we've seen a lot of that
technology and you know it's not very
cost effective when a lot of these
systems are you know ten plus thousand
dollars for the monitoring equipment
plus an extra thousand dollars per
sensory it doesn't make sense because to
me the raw materials obviously don't
cost that much so on the irrigation
front on the I guess let's say
commercial front and the personal grow
front like what do you what do you like
what you exploring you know every
situation is different if it was left up
to me you know I'd love keeping my
custom Rockwell mix I like using the air
pots but you know it really is tailoring
to the grows and specific like you said
some people are stuck on their ways and
for some people that are an ownership to
have employees that their success is
based on past experiences and being
familiar with what they're doing you're
kind of at the risk and I see a lot of
people getting the runaround where
everybody's a master grower today they
walk in and they're failing like I see
it all the time you know I was a master
grower and it's a foot by 10 foot space
and putting the owners and you know into
debt and making them feel like they're
not gonna make it and at the end of the
day it's it's it's it doesn't matter
what you do it's about how to scale it
and be successful and you know I think
if people will you know you can grow it
any way you want I think at the end of
the day it's what makes you comfortable
and for me I can't always be there so I
could recommend the system for somebody
and unless they have the people that are
competent enough to see that out this
way it needs to be done without any
screw-ups we'll call it you have to put
face faith into systems that will be
bulletproof we'll call it and you know
whether that's
just simple things like at a
conversation with people the other day
about is it better that we go to powder
nutrients versus liquid nutrients and
there's advantages to both I said well
you know let's ask ourselves well with
the powder nutrients there's a couple
variables that could change meaning
let's say the scale that you're using
isn't properly calibrated and or it's
reading a certain way but you don't
necessarily know if that was calibrated
or in calibration correctly which could
cause your measurements to be off too if
you have somebody that's weighing it
themselves you have to look out the way
it's you know being done meaning a lot
of people will necessarily different
products can't be in conjunction meaning
and a and B aren't in the same container
because they need to be mixed separately
and when you take certain concentrations
when you're weighing out powders and you
put an A in there and you have residue
from the a still in the container and
you have an employee that just fills and
back up with B you have to ask yourself
okay how do we eliminate small issues
like that we go to a liquid fertilizer
where it's very simple we don't have to
worry about the consistency being off or
contamination of nutrients creating a
lock out there's just little things like
that is based on the help that you have
and have hired you know from my
experience it's always been best to find
people that had no knowledge of the grow
industry whatsoever you know in fact I
called my protege but you know one of
the best people I know in this industry
he came from Craigslist he knew nothing
about growing his family it was you know
not from the United States and barely
spoke English and hated that he smelled
like weed coming home every day and you
know from working in the garden and and
the guy now can you know build an
irrigation system for you and do all
these cool things and it wasn't because
he was arguing he sees a common sense at
the factory I call it I don't care how
you do it but every situation is gonna
be a little bit different you know and
and and the thing is is when you have
people that always know what they're
doing they go into these situations
based on prior knowledge there's a lot
of science behind this whether it's the
water pressure
the the water to the emitters the the
the amount of flow rate the emitters are
that the actual things that are actually
dividing this water out meaning it's an
octa bubbler or whatever type of system
you have calculating the amount of water
and how much pressure and you know just
even the the PVC pipe size all these
things matter and you know this is no
different from any other industry that's
been doing agriculture it's just now
that people are seeing it is less taboo
I think you're getting the people that
are real professionals getting involved
and you know it's gonna put some people
out of jobs if they don't get out of
their mindset of their ways is the best
you have to open your mind when you are
doing the two plants for the growth did
you just bolt them on as two additional
plants of a commercial operation or was
this like at home no this is a
commercial operation okay and so you
basically like you know your your
commercial irrigation system you just
added one for each of those two pots and
I originally only plan for a four by
four section for the plant okay just
because I didn't see it using very much
more than that and even with that four
by four section technically we had about
fifty inches almost in each direction
for it and you know for instance the
plant wasn't a very stretching plant
whatsoever so even by the end of week
three I think I have a video I could
send to you where we took the tape
measure out and it was already about 52
inches in diameter in all directions
only three weeks into bloom so you know
it covered quite a bit of space but you
know I think that going back into this
and you know once we do a competition
that involves more of the commercial
operations again it would be nice to you
know I I already have some plans for it
but you know I'd like to put you know a
room together or maybe you know maybe we
put like four to four to eight plants
over one light and really make a
spectacle out of it and see if we can
get you know 10 20 pounds off a plan
you know so that then those two plants
were also on the same nutrient regimen
as all the other plants in the room well
I didn't grow them both out I
I killed the second plant through the
veg cuz the halfway through the veg
already knew which one we tagged was
they all-star so once we tagged him I
didn't need the other planet anyways so
you were talking about liquid nutrients
drying nutrients what are you using for
nutrients are you making at home
including manufacture well I've been
very fond of Mills nutrients for a while
and it really started back in the day
where my philosophy was is you're
changing the additives to manipulate the
growth throughout the stages and seeing
you know working in the hydroponic
business to see it all the time they
have a veg and they have a bloom Y and
for me I was like well they have an A
and B that works for veg and bloom and
you're just actually changing the
stimulates based on the plant's needs
throughout its cycle which really makes
sense to me in you know knowing the
secrets of the industry it's like a lot
of products aren't necessarily just
developed from scratch they're just
remodeled
it's another large AG product that's
remodeled and packaged and sold to you
for 300% more yeah and if you worked in
a hydro store right oh I know all the
secrets that's that's the sad thing is
you know knowing all that - it's it's no
different from any other industry really
you know if people didn't really pay
attention so much to the marketing and
hype of certain items and really looked
into the actual products they'd see that
this is really no different it's for
instance uh you know it could be wrong
but I'm pretty sure the DuPont family
and stuff like that owns several
different entities of products all these
different companies are large
manufacturers owned so many different
products that we would never realize
it's all the same company so if you're
against one you should be against them
all you know
everything gets like that when you
perfect it somebody perfected a nutrient
to the point where they could sell it to
large scale farmers my hat's off to you
and because
if they're sitting there buying liquid
fertilizer at our prices and this
industry we wouldn't see farmers using
any of that stuff whatsoever right and
is there anything else you're adding in
that various stages of the lifecycle I
do a weekly tea regimen I could do my
own teas I have my own IPM that I
integrate into the plant cycle whether
it's just for preventative preventive
and you know we talked about responses
in the plant and I don't want to give
out too much information about what I
use but just just to put it out there
there's something called systemic
acquired reaction in a plan and what
this really is is how do we tell the
plant that it's under attack just like a
human body has its own immune and
defense system and everybody's is better
some people have better tolerance to
getting sick than others plants are the
same and the thing is is how to trick
your plant into doing what you needed to
do throughout the cycle and how to
manipulate those reactions out of the
plant
is is is all part of you know trial and
error really I think all plants will
react differently and you know these are
these are some secrets that I'll keep to
myself but you know I've done a lot of
we'll call it nerdy experiments I've
done everything you could think of by
trying to simulate gravitational pull
effects in vibrations - root systems -
different types of frequencies of sound
you know you name it different types of
music we did rooms with rap music rooms
with classical music we've you know and
did you notice a difference what what
are your plants like to jam out to me
personally my favorite thing to use in
the garden is a just old school radio AM
FM frequency type thing to me I feel
like there has to be some kind of Voodoo
to the the frequency of the sound coming
in through reception and the frequency
of an old speaker being a little bit
more higher pitched we'll call it then a
lot of the new-age style of speakers was
their study on like the sound of birds
chirping in the morning I haven't seen
much of that what my favorite studies
were looking at tectonic plates and
vibrational sound patterns and what they
do to sand you look up different
university research and certain
frequencies will make the sand develop
certain patterns and I think that really
had something to do with opening up the
plants actual called skin or its pores
whether that's to transpire or to being
able to absorb more co2 levels more
effectively these are all studies that
you know I'm interested in but you know
I think that there's a lot to vibration
and sound well so first of all with the
T's that means you're introducing sort
of microbes and okay so you're not a
just a pure synthetic nutrients to see
you know people could say organically dr
synthetically derived but to me in all
aspects it's not about what we think
it's about what the plant can absorb
most effectively and I think in a
medicinal quality standpoint for me how
a calcium or magnesium is derived is
pointless because I want to have the
cleanest most available source it's kind
of like the same difference between
calcium carbonate and calcium nitrate
calcium carbonate is a much needs to be
broken down it's it's very slowly
absorbed or readily available to the
plant compared to a calcium nitrate
which is already chelated in a form that
the plant can absorb immediately so you
know when it comes down to organic or
not to me it doesn't matter it's all
about just raw minerals and nutrition
just like a human body if we need
certain types of nutrition or minerals
to do whatever it is we're training
ourselves to do and
a hyper-competitive level which we're
dealing with plants in an aspect where
we need to obviously maximize
profitability for the people that keep
things running but at the same time we
want to create a substantially better
product than anybody else and in doing
that you know you have to look at all
those key factors do you have different
tea brewing strategies for different
phases of growth like are you more
fungal dominant earlier you more
bacterial dominant later you know as far
as the teas I think that it's a very
simple tea is necessary for anybody
whether it's and this is where it's
going into like what I needed I think
there's a lot of products out there just
put a few out there that are very
similar products like extreme gardening
has Mike oohs and ahhs oohs and there's
great white there's life powder and a
lot of these different inoculants have
relatively the same agents in them
people need to realize that that powder
you see is a carrier that's not
necessarily what the plants absorbing
it's a talent it's a pharmaceutical
grade tell that this biology could stick
to so you could transport that into the
water and suspend them like I said I
think that a lot of these beneficial
microorganisms are a way for the plant
to help them chelate and effectively
uptake nutrients I think that there is
benefits for them as far as immunity and
defense in them but at the same time
when you get microbiology and an indoor
system and you know everybody system is
different you have a lot of problems
with that so running a clean irrigation
system to me is a lot more beneficial on
a large scale project versus going fully
organic with that you just have a lot of
problems along the down the line you
know and a lot more maintenance issues
for me it's about how to use those T's I
think that using them in accordance to
where you are in the plant cycle meaning
a weekly cycle we typically increase our
food regimens as we increase the amount
of time the plant grows whether it's
from beginning of edge to
vej beginning a flower to end the flower
and by increasing those nutrient
regiments for me
you also have salt build-up and the
thing is is we need to realize obviously
as an accumulation of salt builds up
you're gonna create possibility for
plants to lock out nutrients so we need
to flush out those excess minerals by
releasing these bonds to me teas this is
one thing I can guarantee you the best
time for me and anyone to apply them in
my opinion would be when you're actually
flushing your plant or leaching those
out on a weekly basis because what
better to have these beneficial
microorganisms that are in there that
can help chelate and break down these
minerals that are accumulating and we're
not having to add food at that point so
you know in a large-scale agricultural
project you're gonna have to in my
opinion I always like to splash these on
top of the plants and not running them
through the irrigation so we'll have
somebody that goes through and literally
hand feeds teeth you know and we're
talking about a micro dose so it's not
like we're talking like foliar or into
the rock into the into the rock wall
itself absolutely you know and being
able to any foliar spraying you know as
far as folios one good tip I could say
is it depending on your situation
there's different technology than I've
been able to incorporate now to cut down
on some of the uses for different types
of foliar sprays whether it's to prevent
different types of fungal or different
pathogens from attaching themselves to
the plant so everybody's environments
gonna be a little bit different I think
a lot of people are getting more into
the preventive aspect of knowing that
your room may look clean but you
bringing in outside contaminants is huge
so having a good practice of making sure
that you don't bring them into the grow
in the first place is critical as far as
you know with large scale grows it's
hard for people to say we're gonna have
these things hand sprayed a lot of these
systems big systems are a beautiful
thing
they're so automated you have track
systems with fogging machines that will
literally spray whatever you
to spray when you need to spray it some
people like for instance that actually
manually apply these you know great ways
to cut down on the amount of application
rates would be to atomize this or you
know use paint sprayers a lot of times
and meaning you can have a little bit go
a long way instead of going through five
to ten gallons you may go through one to
two gallons of foliar spray depending on
what type of application you're applying
it for but getting down to the
application of folders I like it
throughout the veg cycle I try and not
do it past maybe week three or four the
bloom cycle and even in that it really
depends on the situation if you know you
have strains that are finicky meaning
that they are a little bit more prone to
pathogens or mold then yeah you have to
keep a regimen of different types of
chemicals will call them whether it's
something organic like a I think maroon
was one of the sponsors so they make
products from regalia grande Evo
venerate all products that I use you
know there's other great products out
there that necessarily would kind of
contradict that because let's say you
use something like a plant therapy that
has alcohol you know and and different
types of extracts in it and citric acid
you can't necessarily apply that to
something that you put beneficial
organisms but let's say you're spraying
a fungal dominant tea you're not gonna
spray plant therapy right after it's
kind of pointless so it just depends on
when you grow more you know in a lot of
people you know with a lot of different
apple applications whether it's the type
of protection equipment whether it's the
respirators the protective clothing
being able to simplify all those
practices for people is is one thing
everybody is getting better at and I
don't there's no perfect way to do it
everybody situation is different and
like I said it also depends on the
people you have they're actually doing
the applications right so getting back
to the initial grow off topic
so you basically didn't it was almost
like an Iron Chef competition where like
you ran out of time obviously I'm sure
everybody felt the same way whereas like
I could have just done that one last
thing well they did originally give us a
date that was further out but because of
the law changed it was out of their
control so even though we properly
planned our schedule to pull down on a
certain date it was out of our control
at that point what ultimately I forget
you said this earlier but what
ultimately was the strain grapefruit
Romulan okay describe what you saw at
the you know as these you know buds
started to develop or you you you kind
of had a general sense of what it was
well I mean I had my guesses it was a
sweet smelling plant it put it this way
it smelled a lot better growing than a
they'd smoke died I'm sad to say it I
call it the boofie kind of a poufy
strain it's it's nothing special about
it I think that there's a lot of strains
out there that are nostalgic for very
different attributes of it whether it's
the color the smell the taste the high
and the effects of it and you know we
can joke about it there's strains like
blue dream that people would be like
I'll get that out of here but people
loved it
you know there's strains like green
crack that people are like what's that
some people are like oh man no more that
people loved it you know I think strains
like OG Kush now OG Kush you can get any
strain that's named something different
and just by smoking if it is really an
OG Kush it's gonna taste very similar
and by putting all these different names
on has always been kind of a joke to me
over the years that people do this
because we've lost sense of what truly
what it is they're all kind of the same
planet and now that people that are
breeding and doing their own Fino hunts
will realize is they all came from a
seed they're all very different but
they're similar and we get different
types of attributes out of different
phenotypes meaning the structure and the
way that the calyx is grow the structure
of the Leafs and how they form the
amount it yields the potency of the plan
how tolerant it is to environmental
conditions and/or different types of
attacks from mold or bugs you know and
being able to hone in and I think that's
where your tissue culture is a great
thing where we can not only clean up
strains that people damage over the
years by using toxic chemicals that in
some case that we're out of our control
I make the comment people complain about
equal 20 but they use Spinoza Spinoza
was labeled organic but it was a
neurotoxin when in combustion toot
inhale so that was organic as labeled
organic still by it is organic so when
people say organics healthier sometimes
I'm like well is it mercury organic you
know there's certain things that'll just
kill you this was a purple punch yeah
that's a purple plant okay so talk to me
about
I view cannabis in the same way I view
music there is the Katy Perry strains
which may be the most popular okay
popularity in my mind doesn't mean the
best and then there's like the Miles
Davis of strains or the you know
experiment being played on every major
LA radio station so everybody's
different right so can you talk about
just from what you're seeing snapshot in
time 2019 what's becoming popular in the
LA market and then contrast that with
just what are you personally into right
now in terms of genetics and breed like
what's exciting you like who's your I'm
excited right now our artist who's
coming in versus the the the purple
punch or the blue dream or the well I'm
just happy that people are over just
there's still people that are diehard OG
Kush fans but forever it's like oh if
it's not og I don't want it and I see
the times are kind of changing and where
people like more exotic flavors and in
meaning there's so many good weeds now
that people are finding what they like
the best
and with that you know you go over to a
friend's house and they have whatever
strain it is and you have whatever
strain it is and you've never tried this
strain and now you like this strain
before it was like let's just put it
this way black market days you go over
to your you know person's house to pick
up a bag of weed or even at the
dispensary it was like 13 different
types of OG Kush and like three others
and you know I think that now people are
seeing better variety I see that people
are really into colorful strains and and
more of a kind of exotic smells or
fruity smells and I think that really
goes to the point where they're all very
similar in THC I think until we really
feel a full spectrum of what's in that
plant that makes us feel the way that we
do that we like that maybe somebody else
doesn't it's all about flavor for me at
least you know I'll smoke enough to get
high I don't care what strain it is and
I and I have you kind of where we are
with cannabis right now as as alcohol
came out of prohibition kind of everyone
was so focused during alcohol
prohibition on highest proof so you had
kind of like your whiskey's in your
bathtub gin your gran outcalls
and kind of like a fine craft wine sort
of came later on right it wasn't like
1935 that there's always those Krauts
but you had to know the people right now
I'm thinking of the general public like
for me like you like I could drink six
glasses of wine and my goal is to get
drunk
I can appreciate each one and what
you're saying is you know your cannabis
doesn't need to go up to 11 on the THC
scale you just smoke a little bit more
and what you're more focused on what I'm
more focused on is kind of like the
flavor the terpenes the kind of overall
the quality of the excitement and but I
feel like there's still a lot of the
market who is kind of THC driven like
you know this one's 90-proof yeah but
it's like D once and that's to say like
okay
alcohol gets you drunk right at a
certain point but to me I've never
really liked the taste of like people
love whiskey and bourbon it to me it's
like it burns when you drink that stuff
and to me it's like okay if I'm chasing
this effect don't I want it to taste
good and not be so harsh so the thing is
is well we will look at high
concentrations of THC and concentrates
for instance some people don't like vape
pens because it's real harsh and I know
for me at least one vape cartridges the
more you smoke em is kind of like that
old effect you'd get from a vaporizer
you kind of get this cough I feel like
or you smoke dabs and it's 70 plus
percent THC but there's people out there
that can just do dam after dam after dam
but they can't smoke three joints why is
that they've consumed so much more THC
so that already tells you that everybody
is slightly different what is that
difference that's what we need to really
focus on so what's your preferred do you
like rolling joints do you like I like
everything okay
III got off the tee like okay like tapas
a little bit of everything well you know
getting involved with different
companies and just getting involved into
the testing process like a lot of people
don't realize like I had an argument
today with somebody I was like look
papers blunts hemp raps to me the
ultimate goal in life would be to smoke
weed wrapped in weed and it doesn't
change the flavor how do we do that
that's what we need to do because in a
real rural health aspect is it really
healthy to smoke paper probably not
whether Trice paper had paper any paper
how about kombucha paper which that's
how in the market well the thing is is
all these things have a subtle taste
difference and it's like the same
argument with people be like oh I only
smoke with big lighters well it's
because you like the taste of the the
lighter fluid if you change the lighter
on them they could taste the difference
what are you tasting you're not tasting
the weed completely it's it's almost
like a mixology at that point you know
even if you go into like a hemp wick you
know it's like even hemp foot
their own certain flavor profile when
you put them out you're smelling this
kind of burnt smell in you know at the
same time when you're trying to inhale
your weed so you know finding out what
what really suits people don't chase
after the THC content because that's
just like going to the bar and saying I
want the strongest thing you have on the
menu and that's all I want I don't care
because that's the effect I'm chasing
and I don't care what it feels like to
get there I don't think you know when
people are really getting approached and
that that way that they're gonna say
yeah give me the strongest thing now you
know realistically if I gave you a glass
of wine that was 12 percent alcohol and
14 percent alcohol and you drink six
glasses of each you're probably not
gonna see much of a difference who's a
reader who you respect and what what
some of the new genetics that you're
excited to play with one of the people
I'm gonna mention it takes me back to
working behind the counter and seeing
where they got today
for instance the the vault seed bank
guys were a longtime customer of ours
through a company called green coast
hydroponics where I originally met the
owner of that company and just seeing
the the evolving you know times for
everybody and seeing what they've been
able to do it's really cool because the
strains that they're able to create you
know there's people that they have
promoting these strains for them people
that I looked up to you like people like
be real or everybody's heard the song I
got five on it and you got people like
the the yuck mouth cool ah no strain or
whether that's the strain for me or not
you know I'll say it's not bad but it's
it's some people really like it some
people aren't just like any other weed
but I think that you know what they've
been able to do to this point and seeing
the the whole kind of progression of
it's almost like watching your kid grow
up you see somebody start at one level
where you mentioned the word IPM to them
and they're like what the fuck is that
to seeing where they're at today it's
really cool to see people all involved
you know I know that a lot of people do
a lot of marketing and at the end of the
day there's so many different strains
that it's it's really hard for you to
say that one is better than the other
because really wheat is different for
everybody
and for me I always have the strains
that I like in all aspects I don't
research a lot of the stuff that's
nostalgic for instance you know there's
strains that I've had for years I have
no idea who made them I have no idea
where they came from I know how to grow
them and what are some of those trains
oh man
seeing one strain that I really like is
I have a cut of I call it j1 but we've
had this cut for man probably two
thousand four or five something like
that never really had a long term mom of
it's always been cloned of cloned and
this is something that we were given at
a Orange County normal meeting at a long
time ago I got the privilege of meeting
Jack Herer and I mentioned that I loved
the strain so much somebody that was
there with him gave me a plant of this
years ago and it was always a fun plant
to grow I've always liked the taste of
it it's one of those plants that just
gets enormous buds too so I don't know
if anybody's ever grown it or gets the
chance to grow one of those strains like
a jack or j1 but you know it has those
huge pineapple buds like you get from
the skunk and you know for me before it
was just og cush days you know there was
a gray market aspect of things and for
me it was like well I can get a pound
and a half for light of OG Kush or I can
get three pounds of light of this right
there's a hundred dollar difference in
the market it's a no-brainer which way
I'm gonna go so it was one of those
strains that I just really started to
grow especially going after the
one plant perlite and it was just easy
for me and you know I just fell in love
with that strain in particular and I
think that you know going into a lot of
strains today I get a lot of that like
it it almost gives you that hint of kind
of like where that you get that tangi
smell or there's certain aspects to the
smell that I get different aromas from
it all the time it's it's a fun plant to
grow and you know besides that I think I
have a new strain that we developed it
was a cross of OG Kush and cookies and
cream I have no idea what we're gonna
call it but we're waiting to see five
more weeks and they'll be done and for
the second time we ran it just see
stability wise but I'm excited about
just being able to be a part of
something like that it was cool we never
really knew what we were doing with the
breathing thing we had a dispensary
owner that had a bunch of male plants in
his backyard and decided to do his own
breeding and that was kind of the start
of a lot of the different strains we
developed and one of the cultivations I
worked with is no longer so being able
to hold on to those strains was kind of
a nice thing just because they're no
longer cultivating themselves that was
actually the the place they originally
did the grow off with and since then the
the cultivation has been turned into
manufacturing and distribution the seeds
find it more profitable but is what it
is you know what's something that you
remember from 10 15 years ago that
you're like I wish I could find that
again or recreate it I love smoking
snowcap was a big one to mean back in
the day it was a cool strain it it was
just so fresh and kind of like pepper
mini it was a unique smell and where did
it originate from or what's the back I
think that was a Mendocino County strain
Humboldt constraint I always loved
trainwreck was a big one back in the day
I love the the kind
lemony smell and taste there's another
one when I was really getting into
growing around 2003 I want to say 2004
we called it juicy fruit and it smelled
and tasted just like the gum did it was
it was incredible there's all kinds of
strains back there remember one was like
a squirt that was kind of a version of
it I believe but it was just more
citrusy shit we used to do the original
skunk number one we did a lot of that
White Widow another old one it was funny
there wasn't much to choose from back
then it was like if people had seeds or
if you knew the person with the cut I
remember paying $5,000 to have a cut of
Bubba cash just to grow the original
Bubba back in like 2004 we were growing
bubba kush you know in 2003 the same
person that gave me the Bubba I had the
OG Kush from and you know that's kind of
what the the dominating strains were
then it was like the Bubba was huge for
a long time I actually love that strain
I don't see it ever and this was all
your kind of like OC scene is that kind
of where you're sort of epicenter is I
mean I came from Michigan to California
I grew up we'll call it high school days
more in like Southern California Garden
Grove Long Beach area so you came to
California in high school like junior
high or junior high but so cannabis wise
for you growing up was SoCal it wasn't
yes you hundred percent is SoCal okay so
you're so cowboy you know we're we were
highly influenced in the area I was at
by like the Kottonmouth Kings kind of
music scene and a lot of the people that
were connected into the egg
up in that area and not only that like
just that whole scene back then and was
different it was it was kind of like
smoking weed in your car we loved
driving in traffic on the freeway for an
excerpt ooh - because you can hotbox and
not get in trouble it was different
everybody has different experiences for
me it was kind of nice because you know
I was one of those people that always
had a cigarette on me or a cigarette in
my car because you know you can't smell
like weed and go home so I puff the
thing blow it in my shared a bunch of
times and blow it all over myself and I
remember getting a bunch of messages
posted to my room for my mom one day
about like how I shouldn't smoke
cigarettes bad for you and he's anti
cigarette ad tapes and pamphlets and I
remember just like going to my drawer
and I pulled out this film container
with a fat noggin it I was like mom I'm
not smoking cigarettes I'm smoking this
and what was your reaction to that I
mean she was happy actually like she'd
rather me smoke pot than drink alcohol
it was more like look if you're gonna be
doing stupid stuff like that at this age
don't get in trouble
you know don't let your dad see that
you're smoking pot obviously but you
know I think that was the the start of
having a good education about it for me
is being open and having some of you
could be open with at that point of your
life because I mean my parents my mom I
just her and her sister were groupie
hippies you know went to Woodstock naked
type shit so they were very
understanding people when it comes to
whether it's psychedelic type stuff or
just pot in general so alright well
Jerome the wife has returned home so
we're done
done I appreciate it yeah that's it so
I'm gonna you're gonna be out to grow
off 13th 13th of the 14th one of those
Saturday whatever I'll see you down in
your home turf and in like two weeks
that's where I live
[Music]