[Music]
actually I have a real admiration not
quite like the gentleman you just met
about who doesn't watch porn but watches
strain hunters but nonetheless an
admiration funny one that was a good one
nonetheless an admiration for you know
all of the work you do to further the
plan and all the traveling that you do
you and your partner and well there's no
what's next I mean we're having you gone
to find cannabis strains well thanks you
gone yeah well I still have some
countries on my list but I want to pick
up some stuff but just look one of the
most difficult countries in the world is
DRC Congo and at the same time one of
the most easy countries we have a
country the size of Europe exactly on
the equator well hard because you can't
get to it in jail there's also war in
the eastern Ebola in the north there's
all kinds of stuff and it's just
Africa is Africa you know I don't know
yeah well I'm from Africa as you know
I'm from Zambia originally I guess you
can say but the same kind is very
rewarding when you can do something
there so we are doing clinical trials
with University and hospitals of the
country with a group of professors from
Europe and from Africa we're keeping it
clear bit under the radar but we're
coming out with it very soon why are we
on the equator well very easy
we are 1212 the whole year around we can
basically grow outdoor what we do the
whole year around so I have at anytime
between 50 and 100,000 plants and every
time I put out a whole valley of plants
and I make whatever seeds and I do
whatever genetics so this is the world's
biggest genetic pool I have a few
hundred phenotypes there and I in breed
and I cross and I do whatever I want and
I put every time whatever seeds out and
I can test them directly for whatever I
want to see him after this uniformity
male/female feminized the whole story so
being on the equator you're the Hugh
Hefner of cannabis you get to play with
as many girls as you want
yeah oh you can see the mountains there
you know like I put out I've at any time
so I got now 20 glass houses with
between fifty and a hundred thousand
plants and every time when they're two
feet I put them outside flower them off
make seeds magnificent we have seven
valleys so we're gonna increase to
fourteen valleys so at any time I can do
my breeding there so we have hundreds of
varieties and isn't it the greatest
thing in the world that the whole year
around you look outside to the Sun and
it's always between 20 and 32 celsius so
it's always the perfect climate we have
a rainy season November in Ghent
November and December which is a rainy
season but we can still grow outside we
have a short draining season in March we
have rivers we have free sunlight we
have free lands we are one of the few
places left in the world where
everything is organic I use only bat
guano from the caves yeah and I use my
powder feeding that is completely
organic
we have a whole community of people that
we are feeding we also have four
hectares of vegetables so it's a very
nice culture of everything coming
together so though I don't even know if
any - so what is your favorite country
for cultivating cannabis Congo Congo how
interesting and also don't forget think
very logic Congo is the country in the
world you can look that up and ask any
teacher in the world is the most diverse
in plants and fruits so that says enough
yeah yeah so the most plants and fruits
in the world are in Congo oh how nice so
why don't copy that with marijuana yeah
and we are only a quick look I don't
have the icon grow my plants big so I'll
do that in a glass house that's the only
little disadvantage but you don't need
big plans to make to breeding love the
breeding course not I pre Rotem you have
understand one glass house I have it's
it's 8 meters by 30 meters so it's 240
meters like a normal glass house you
know like the tunnels you guys have 100
feet by 25 feet but is it you have in
America sorry L goes nice through well
you saw my pictures you know them that
they're on Instagram all over and I have
LEDs in there 150 times 6 watts so I
have a thousand watts for a whole glass
house for sub sub sub light because I
only put the lights on at 5 o'clock to
11 o'clock because the rest is sunlight
all day so I use 2 thousand litres of
diesel in a whole month 420 glass houses
amazing kind of off the grid you know
we're lazing so this is this is what you
had to make me give wanna give up
California both why not
like P we were talking about I'm
everywhere you know I love the fact that
you're so dynamic man you know you're
not you're not uh you don't just settle
for doing this here or doing this there
and you constantly moving out and
expanding and the organics you know I'm
all about that you guys if you want to
smoke hydroponic we'd be my guest but I
save the organics for me and the
vegetable so it sounds like you're just
uh your your as they say living the
dream but in the Congo yes yeah how much
time do you spend there a year so I
spent one week a month in North America
uh-huh and one week a month in Africa
and we have two weeks left which I spent
ten days home and the other five days in
Europe yeah it's a pretty busy schedule
I think you have the same problem as me
all of us are sitting basically
Annapolis yes I didn't even know was
existing but me my part is we have
diamond cards now on the airplanes very
nice so we got upgraded every time isn't
that crazy that's very that's a good
thing or a bad thing but fly a lot I
think it's a good thing well I don't
know so what we do in Congo which
strange
I have ten valleys and we created a
system there that we put out every time
one hectare like five thousand plants
but we put the pots in the ground so we
pollinate yeah so the males are there
already then we bring the females yeah
we pollinate the crop
once we pollinated the crop for ten days
we cut all the males we already bring
the new male for the next crop
what's another variety we move out out
of the ground all the pots back to main
base three miles down roads and we put a
new five thousand plants so we can do in
ten weeks two crops times ten valleys is
20 crops nominal yeah so that's the
first and only place in the world where
we can do this so we have 7 valleys like
all to 3 miles from each other and a few
trucks and we drive the plants up and
down but this means we can speed up the
process twice sure which is great and
then also the finishing the crop happens
where the glass houses are and we just
have a huge field there of 500 hectares
so we just put all the pots again in the
ground the holes already there so we
dropped them after five weeks bring them
back there just pollinate it and then we
just finish them off in the main field
and we only have to water there we don't
have any cross-pollination problems I
love it it's amazing outdoor growing is
something that I haven't done too much
of I'm primarily an indoor grower
nothing I'm proud of I wish I could grow
outdoors I don't have the space well
this is the other reason I went to Congo
not because of the diversity of plants
and fruits but also because the space is
enormous exactly you know it's big as
Europe you mentioned so of all of these
strains and that you're working with in
the Congo
how many of them what percentage are
actually indigenous and what percentage
of ones you brought with you from
Amsterdam well most of them we
technically have nearly all the strains
of the world there of course it's black
congo red congo mm-hmm better is also
Santa Marta Punta Roja Limon Verde there
is a mango Rosa from Brazil there isn't
anything that we are crossing with
anything
huh so it's just like a great pile yeah
that's great yeah dream come true what
about on the medical side are you
involved in any with any medical fully
of course this is the main reason why
there is a medical license I mean really
in farm I mean bar are you having any
big farm oh yeah yeah we well no we're
not be involved in big we are because
you know that well are creating big
pharma I cannot say too much right now
sure but there is people putting in a
few hundred million dollars in big
investigations concerning alzheimer
parkinson and that kind of stuff we are
working very close with this group who
this is just a really rich group of guys
mm-hmm that are not related to Pharma
but want to do this that sounds good
yeah that's actually even better fresh
right they're a little more altruistic
yeah yeah what I really like so good
we will probably announce that next year
somewhere awesome but yeah yeah of
course Pharma is gonna get involved that
what I would rather be done by our
community
yeah and that's what I've said for many
years is that you know there's nothing
wrong with corporations if the
corporations are run by good people yes
and we have to work together with
corporate corporations because we sad
money we need an experience we need to
know how we need their business skills
we need their backbone we need
everything from them and then we can
change the world and then we can choose
a world absolutely as if we already have
it
[Music]