I would like to do clothing like like
work wear clothing a car hard like real
because the hemp is really good as far
as it lasts that's why Levi used to
build their Levi's out of hemp and then
they drive cotton because the cotton
wears out right and you can buy early
Tesla is using hemp in what it seats
your sita is it gonna imagine most sales
make anything so I'm gonna I'm gonna
this year I'm doing the hemp and I got
I'm gonna do 8 acres and I'm gonna do it
orchard style I'm gonna you know rather
than a lot of people are just you know
doing it you know as much as they can
fit on one acre I'm gonna try and grow
trees quality and then just process that
whole plant from stock you know
basically from route up and eight acres
like is that comparatively that's a good
amount yeah I mean it's a big fir for
right now if I go too big I don't have
the budget right and if I fail would
this be your so this would be your first
so be my first well no I grew some hemp
last year so just quickly what area are
you like what's the Appalachian you want
to end into a longer but give me
something more people like River
represents Temecula Temecula they say in
Riverside County because everybody's
like ants I know ah but this is housing
here Doug yeah it's a stigma to a
Riverside County Anne's Appalachia
Association Humboldt yeah weird outdoor
Nixon I get but you're humble or high
country what's it worth what's there
there's is Humboldt County Growers
Association yeah yeah there's a southern
and there's a northern HCG oh but why I
mean not that it's not legitimate what
high country
yeah and that's one of that regions kind
of high country like anything that's
coming in like the 408 so that has a
meaning people you know with it we you
know I grow in the high country people
they know it yeah okay well then that
would be a legitimate part of your Apple
especially if you're out in that area
like all the like the 4-h club for
instance is high country 4-h the
newspaper's high country Journal okay
and everything's kind of this okay they
wanted to do some of the other guys were
like nah let's do high desert and I'm
like it's not really well not really
high desert right you know right and
that's specific you don't you wanted
your name to represent and it's
important where you're from right hmm
that's the whole point
yeah totally yeah that's a big part is
oh yeah this is so crazy to me because
only California like but tell afford not
only but most of all has all of these
local associations and in the scheme of
things you figure that's not gonna last
because you know as the industry matures
there should not be the need for so many
so many and then we'd amount God or they
really combined or they combined exactly
yeah but for the moment cuz I was
surprised because I've been covering the
industry for like five six years and and
I've talked to lots of people in
different associations especially around
California goes yeah hi hi hi country
Growers Association
I mean every room you know I go was
pretty new too so that was the
interesting point to me that even now
kind of like after you know a little bit
of time there's still a need to create a
new Association
oh yeah cuz there there's a Cannella
Valley Association Growers Association
or can't they could selling cannabis
associations right but they're all about
indoor well no and it's still growers
and often these associations for these
areas will represent not just growers
but the ancillary industries as well
manufacturers that's what these guys do
they're more retail manufacturers
distributors because they're down in
Coachella Valley and they're working
with all those different entities
they're so they're like all you know we
need to get him we kind of put heads
with them because he doesn't like us
because were the black market guys right
you know and we're the dudes that like
right but you wouldn't start an
association if you were kind of weren't
interested in going legal no that's the
whole reason we started it was because
we were getting screwed and reg reg you
know regulation and we're like we gotta
come you know we got to get like-minded
guys cuz up there nobody really wants to
expose themselves right you know there's
20 million plus people out right around
us so there's no real reason to come out
and say hey look at me right
you know I grow I want to make a brand
everybody's happy because really the
reality is is people are showing up this
that and it's easy because they can fly
into la San Diego boom they're out there
in an hour they're not going up north
right out in the middle of nowhere up
there it's so broken up - I mean you
have it's so large of a vast area you
can go right into our little area and
you can one broker can see five
different products from from ten you
know different farm arms Wow within a
couple hours wow that's great yeah yeah
easy in and out well that's you know I
mean yeah please
thank you sir Jesse Joey nice to meet
you Jody
hey that's why I think the Appalachian
up there's real really take off because
of the tourism right and the canna
tourism that you know cannabis tourism
so but you so you let you guys are our
only grow yeah as far as the Association
yeah yeah right now it's so like so how
new you have
we formed a pack in
2018 of March so year and a half yeah so
not really because I put my face out
there I've been in newspapers well not
entirely we actually got a guy who's
running for a County Supervisor
excellent because we were getting fucked
and we're like well - we'll just take
the seat you know we don't get it this
time we'll get it next time so like
right now is he yeah he's yeah help me
out right now I got tomorrow like I just
post a bunch of shit on my facebook you
know the like kind of will see you know
I think he's actually he's got a chance
it's not that many people vote do them
no and and when when you take areas like
that to where their rural areas and it's
hard to get the word out there and you
know a lot of people don't really care -
like I said a lot of those people you
know they mind their own business right
you know they take care of themselves
they might not even vote but they might
vote if it's someone who will like go
look I understand I'm one of you I'll
leave you alone that's where I was like
I'm not a voter like I'm gonna I don't
believe in that it's I don't believe in
a two-party system it divides us you
know and so buddy's like now you got it
how about I donate a little bit of money
and I pump me you know I put your name
out there and help you out a little bit
but they're cool he's a cool family
they're uh they're from Mexico
Ensenada explain that Sidewalk the canna
gar yeah I was gonna get into making
these and I was like fuck that's a lot
of work to do it I'm into do them
handcrafted you know and hand-rolled
like you got they got these presses you
can stick them in no no I mean that one
time I did now I'm you know if I want to
smoke something's gonna be cannabis yeah
I would say I mean I don't see anything
just the other day a guy up here was
rolling in
but he didn't say he was rolling uh yeah
I mean I took a hit and I'm like oh good
tobacco and now yes it's kind of for me
it's like you're ruining it he's like
yeah yeah some people love it
that's cool for 17 years in st. Croix
and the local font and yeah I mean
obviously a boy let me drink you know
because obviously in Amsterdam the
locals do that too they mix them and
they always have and they go oh so cuz I
don't want to get that like but it's
like it actually adds something I'm like
no you know just cannabis alone it's not
that it's it's not that it adds with
what cannabis does is the answer the
tobacco is no I know but they think it's
adding something to it what it is is
cannabis isn't an enhancer and so
whatever that terpene or you know
flavonoid whatever's in the tobacco
that's giving you that high the cannabis
is kicking it up and so you're getting
the boats that's why they're saying yeah
we need this for the opioids because you
can do a little bit of cannabis and half
the opioids you were doing before and
it's gonna be huh Jesse so why don't you
introduce us to your appellation of
origin and talk about what you're
growing there
alright the appellation of origin that
that I would like to see happen one day
is out in Riverside County out in the
Anza Valley it sits at about 4,000 feet
3,800 to 4,000 it's it's one of the
personally I think it's one of the best
places in North America because of the
micro climates
the dry the the way the Sun hits this
particular region it sits on the 33rd
parallel so it it duplicates the same as
a lot of these strains that come from
Morocco or Lebanon that sit in these
same regions so it's it's it it's one of
those spots that you really got it you
know it's it's small it's only 16 miles
by 8 miles a 60 miles long by 8 miles
wide so it's a small little region and
and cannabis has been grown there for a
while yeah yeah I know people have been
growing up there since the early 70s so
because that's an important element of
the creating an appellation that you can
also show you know a history of sort of
use you know and for a particular crop
for growing in the genetics then also
show there's a plant doesn't know
whether it's legal or not illegal you
know so the plant history is still there
and that's really know definitely we're
looking at appellation that's all
they're gonna need to care about
yeah the science as far as the genetics
and the the plant morphing back into her
you know space and knowing that oh this
is where I'm supposed to be and this is
where I thrive you know it's not too
humid
it's the perfect dry it's the perfect
altitude it's the perfect where the Sun
hits the plant and all these things come
into play there the particular strains
are in genetics very well there yeah all
the the the Afghan or endo cush strains
all those into cush strains anything
that that came from the Hindu Kush
mountain range or Afghan mountain range
would do well in this energy because all
your genes exactly
y-you know like that's how they got sent
on my nap when I say parallels burgundy
and Bordeaux and stuff and everything
you say just translate you right across
yeah once you start connecting that and
really doing the research into yeah it's
still farming but once you start
connecting those parallels and realize
oh this is why this works so good in
this region then it clicks and it's eat
it's easy to place that cultivar where
it needs to be and you're not you know
growing some sativa up there and going
wall
yeah it's getting huge because it's
getting the Sun and she's getting what
she likes but it's not producing what
you're looking for you know and I've
learned up there that you can mix these
two Tevas into some of these heavy into
cos and come up with plants that are
yielding eight pounds really simple yeah
do you guys have a voice at the groups
that are working on this a california
appalachian CCIA has a group you know
you gotta get in there not yet working
towards that it's you know like I said
it's a small region and it's taken time
to get like-minded people together and
that would increase the value if a
valley like that we're you know the
environment is like really conducive
mm-hmm that's why that's key is to get
well and that's the other problem is
that true it's all unincorporated it's
all incorporated and that's the other
problem is the the license process has
gone to where they want things to go
indoors and and to have an Appalachian
we need to have the Sun that's the huge
problem that now the soil or wine no
yeah right well which which I was gonna
ask about because you know even up in
Humboldt in in up in the Emerald
triangle like they grew in pots up there
love but they still want the Appalachian
shit in Appalachian only apply to in
ground it smells great doesn't it I
personally for me I'm finding that the
native soil up there is fired I mean
this stuff you cannot make it up
yeah so it's up in the fort like what
kind of is it like no it's more of a
mineralized you
we're in a you know highly mineralized
rather than forest and so what I'm
finding his body by having soil that's
neutral high in mineral it's a lot
easier to to manipulate the plant when
she's in flower and he said it's
fungally dominant right no no i'm
finding that that you know when we were
pressing some of our material like i was
talking to the guys from sasquatch we
were talking and they were saying a lot
of the stuff that they're pressing from
up north has that fungal flavor in it
because of of you know there's so much
plant matter up there that's breaking
down in the soil and there's so much fun
fungus and plum you know the words that
breaks down and out plants sucking that
up into the flowers here it's a lot more
neutral to where it's you're able to
when it starts going into flower rather
than you know you're you're able to take
the plant and really manipulate the
flower process rather than some places
up north you get into where you're
you're stuck in that soil that's full of
broken-down fungi and the leaves and all
this stuff that that you don't
necessarily want the plant to uptake now
you're stuck with that in the flower and
then once you press it we're finding
that you know by pressing flower up
there and flower down here you're seeing
a huge difference in the turps
and the flavor and all that stuff you
know and i think a lot of it has to do
with the soil so you think you're
getting a pure expression of the
genetics down here yes with more of a
neutralized soil and more of a mineral
high mineral i'm mineral content so do
these minerals do they have any taste or
I mean do their well what they do is the
plant takes those minerals and makes
different terpenes and different you
know
all right so but that makes it just
unique to the area then yeah well that's
what makes the two are so important when
the soil comes into play because you
know you always tell flour from that
area yeah yeah there's a hue of the
smell yeah that's a smell and there's a
few little unique things that give it
away yeah if the outdoor stuffs got
these little flowers in it that blow
that blow off in the wind layers they're
Mountain layers
yeah it's a little cold all right so
actually start start from the top again
you're you're at 4,000 feet I'm at 38
but the valleys bout from 4,000 to 3,500
and it's you know it's got a very dry
climate to it there's certain micro
climates within the valley like my areas
a lot different than some of the areas
that are a little bit further east that
would be a little higher up which I get
kind of a little bit of a coastal Eddy
that comes in and kind of keeps it a
little bit warmer then some of the areas
that are higher up that don't get that
coastal Eddy
so I where do you get your because we
just came from this conference where do
you get your energy and your water the
waters I sit on an aquifer so I'm on a
well so it's all groundwater is anyone
doing any dry farming I'm gonna try this
here if we get another you if we get
some good rain he'll turn
okay good topic what was the answer we
all I think and I think I can do it
because where my water table is I sit in
a little Valley with an aquifer well
that's why it has to be like that plan
totally at all and I think you can get
this if you do by seed you're gonna get
that tap root I personally think and you
know you can get a tap root to go at
least six if not deeper six feet eight
talk to some of the farmers who are
doing this up along the eel River
mmm they have several years under their
belt and though they'll share they'll
share with you all day long I think if
you do you you start them and you starve
them what you do because I do grapes - I
got grapes and Malbec Malbec petit petit
Sirah is what I got going right now
yeah the Malbec fire yeah same thing we
sit on the same parallel is that
Argentinian stuff I'm a big fan of all
that no it's just a hobby this is just a
hobby race but it's for pressing press
there wine grape yeah yeah I have some
table grapes some I'm playing with it
I'm playing with it I wouldn't you know
but it's it's a fun hobby you know it's
another it's another one of those
hobbies I enjoy when you grow things and
then you get to enjoy the harvest
I have eucalyptus the baby the sweet gum
eucalyptus the ones for the the forestry
arrangements are you finding that flavor
in your grapes I want to because I could
tell I have a terrible palette but
eucalyptus and green pepper I can tell
if there's a job well it's a great
recipe is very dominant Oh totally I've
dad the capsicum and um it's a great
pesticide though natural yeah
oh yeah no no because we're so so dry
that's why we do we can do the the oh
geez D I mean I'm pulling stuff in late
November you know when people are
panicking up north and September your
honor there comes the water you know
here comes the rain let's go you know
we're sitting back and just you know
it's it's definitely one of those spots
where the future is going to be in these
Appalachians and you know what cultivars
are coming out of them it's a it's a
water it's a shelf it's a it's a
watershed basically oh yeah it's one of
the most pristine water shelves in
Southern California oh yeah I mean the
good clean water is is key my water
comes out at six eight pH 7 7 oh I mean
that's perfect water down there sar DHA
you know but ya know that's the thing up
there is we got pristine water we got a
lot of it you know we sit on a water
shelf that feeds a big part of Southern
California you know and so that's that's
a big key for a lot of us is to be able
to have clean water and not have to
reverse osmosis so just quickly are
these different cultivars yes okay so
what are we what can we start with the
category yeah that thing looks young
yeah yeah you need to be proud of that
so so III hand-make a bunch of them
every year when I harvest and so
interestingly I in my mind I thought you
would you'd cure the outer leaves first
but you actually wrap it fresh yeah then
you cure the flowers cure
yeah and then I'll wrap it with leaf
that I pick and then let it cure after
the fact
those are candies yeah and then and then
I'll use a little bit of rosin to
basically glue those on there in the
whole plant yeah it's the whole plant
there's even a little bit of Keef in
there to just kind of lined everything
together and kind of yeah yeah I mean
definitely I mean it's something that
men do for me it's it's a it's the aroma
it's not so much too high you know it's
more of just the aroma you will see in
one second so that's going to start
glowing in a second it'll be hot it'll
be very hot and so hot so you roll
because you got to do it kind of bet
harvest because you need you need those
fresh leaves so how many do you roll a
year and you give them in like a humidor
yeah like like a cigar yeah I'll do like
maybe a dozen yeah it's a craft thing
you know it's something yeah it's
something that you know there there's a
lot of guys that are making them some
guys are more into the craft part of it
and some guys just want to mass-produce
them how long to be what 15 20 minutes
depends sometimes I'll do them different
you know sometimes I'll put a lot more
keep you know keep on them each one's
yeah they take time definitely they take
few days - yeah definitely they take
some time
- smokin is this thing ready Peter
[Music]
[Laughter]
what's the strain in there you know I
want to see the tangi girl which is a
tan G and Girl Scout cookie
these are really really nice trips and
you wouldn't expect from such a really
tight and this is rock-solid they're
just a regular I try to over seven days
dry and then the care process is can be
from three weeks to a month sometimes
some plant settle yield board five
pounds some that'll do you do you have
like different parcels where you're
doing different like some are bigger
plants and some you're going smaller so
I'm you're planting like well actually
do you do everything from seed Dan yeah
okay that is like a cigar so basically
just hit the yeah and then it takes like
10 or 15 seconds alright wait so get it
getting back to everything's from seed
and where are you getting this is it
your it's all my personal seed I've been
so you're doing the breeding what
indoors or how you keeping that one male
away from your house does not always the
easiest thing but it just very carefully
and I do indoors and trap that Paul and
so you put it to you put a stick in the
middle right and then you fold it up so
you get that drug Jacqueline
yeah yeah that one's not one of my
better ones I it's a decent one by used
to own a nursery oh go I know all of
them so you've you touched most yeah my
brothers had some really good genetics
late 90s yeah that some of it I've been
able to hold on do and some of it I've
lost right like what did you what did
you miss Halle Oh kaleo's a hard one to
find he's got a lot of like the old
original like San Fernando Valley stuff
what's in the joint
it was tangent Angie girl alright
thought daddy so what was this one dad
you girl but that's slate that you can
actually take yeah that's Dave you sure
can well the microwave knocked
everything out like that mom I think the
first they could drive hit I got off the
beginning of it yeah let's
by the way Saturday night I was all
alone back there so what what's been
kind of like the history of genetics in
the area and I mean is it like what do
you travel around like do you see do you
go up to like now I kind of see what
they're growing in different places my
area kind of I mean yeah problem is
right now is there's a lot of the new
stuff that's out there and logics clone
material and so there's really nothing
that good that's that's that I would say
hey yeah this is what we need to make
sure this is known in this valley
haven't really found that right there's
some hogs brick that's floating around
out there that's that's decent but it's
and then you also had the problem of
people that are now realizing oh my
genetics nobody else has these genetics
so no I don't want anybody else to have
these genetics you know our garden yeah
now that's what you're finding is a lot
of people are like well you know what so
does that imply that like 10 years ago
people were like you need seeds here you
go they didn't even care really it was
like oh you know 10 years ago there it
wasn't you weren't thinking about
spreading genetics the way it was up
north you know the way it was up north
was everybody
like all we need to start building up a
name with genetics and I need to be a
breeder and I need to be known for this
cultivar here it's all about money it's
all about what's what's making me money
and what's making me money now and so
it's about where's your market and who's
your money yeah I mean it's yeah I'm in
volume of course but it's knowing where
your market is and who your market is to
and you know right here right now is oh
geez everybody wants that gassy oh geez
you know because most likely it's going
so that's you know and so nobody's
really that's all people care about
right now they just want to open a bag
and get hit by that gas rather than what
is the cultivar what is deterring but
are you growing for the market and then
growing for kind of like what you like
and they're entirely different things
yeah I mean that's what everybody's fine
so what do you like like what do you
like I like this you know I like fruity
with I'm fine like this is fruity but
it's got that gas to it it's gonna get
you it's gonna kind of get to stone but
you're not gonna be couch lock you're
still gonna be able to have a
conversation somewhat you know markets
are like real pure markets but they're
also because they are the purest market
like blind because you really don't know
your end consumer at all you're growing
for yourself but in the legal market you
have it's like that you know you if it's
not selling in stores you're getting
labs well I'm getting laughing about it
you have to like
[Laughter]
you guys want any more this oh you can
we started with an aggressive pace I
find that I you know because I consume a
lot of cannabis
I want that full that full spectrum
flavor of all of it you know it's not
for me I don't want to just be knocked
on my ass you know I want to I want to I
want to function
yeah well the function but I also want
tend the farms yeah to feel you know I
get very creative I've smoked certain
cultivars so that's where I want to you
know I want I don't want to be on the
book I'm not dying a cancer right you
know so for me it's uppity stuff you
know and it's and it's taken those
sativas and mixing it with different
things that I know okay this is gonna
get me pretty tough for sick people
Wow they're just for this day if you
want to be slow I prefer like the lower
alcohol wines just because that way you
can enjoy it and drink more of it as
opposed to like these high content high
alcoholic oh yeah hmm that's kind of
like that sounds like which you're
talking yeah I've never really met about
the fact that different wines of
different uh it's a tremendous
difference you and your B leagues or
more you know depending on yeah that
makes a big difference on how look you
know if you like just wanted like you
said sense that leg whatever wine has a
higher alcohol content but it also has
that flavor body that you just love
you're gonna you maybe just seem a
little bit left to sip on it yeah as
opposed to like really it's the same
thing here I mean shirkers totally know
their modulate their I mean that's the
whole point you know my final course
mixing flowers when you're smoking them
in a joint is all
a way to you know when you're blending
like wines you're blending different
grapes wool same things and you get this
really cool effect like you just mix a
little bit of this at the tip of you
know and a little less of this that's
the end of a day while I'm working I
smoke a combination to Durban and ACDC
so you get all the focus and
concentration about 30 to 180 CDC
straight but then all the uplifting you
know go get them sativa stomp like
that's the gift when you do farms that's
the gift of it is is this gift of being
able to play with flowers like nobody
else does and so you can you know and
then once you start breeding it's really
cool because then you you take this this
mama and this daddy you know and you
sprinkle them on her and you you know
all sudden you have all these children
that start throwing these different
profiles and then it really gets
interesting because then and then when
you can sift through that one mother and
and then find some children from her
that now you're onto something and then
you take that kid you mix it with this
is shit that's really that's the future
of cannabis because we really don't know
how these certain terpene profiles work
with individuals bodies so that's what
we're finding with all these illnesses
yeah these cannabinoid effects on on
these you know for instance with the the
Charlotte's Web like they're you know
and so many patients that they're
finding like oh this works for them but
this doesn't you know and so now we have
this this field to work with where we
can start really mixing a lot of
different cannabinoid profiles terpene
profiles flavonoid whatever works all
sudden you start doing that and then you
start mixing them into flowers also to
where whether it's you're smoking it or
you're blending it up in a you know a
shake which is phenomenal that's what
you really said as you put them in these
fruit these smoothies yeah you want to
get on the level you know and you're not
even you're you get to a point to where
you're so homeostasis that you don't
even need to smoke because you're you're
just you can deal with everything you're
just in tune because your whole body's
like through the gut and all that you
know rather than the smoking is cool but
we need to really figure out yeah
perfect you know we really need to
evolve from that into in these different
tinctures that we take away ya know so
what do you you have teachers here so
what is that this is some project that
I'm helping working out working on it's
a line of THC free so I mean this is
we're just trying to work within the
regulations of things it you know and
for me it you're finding that a lot of
people want to go to THC free and so
that's what this line is it's mostly but
even if they're not getting high don't
you want some cheese in there your
I mean that's the balance what's what
the plants doing is taking the iron and
it's making CBDs and it's taking
magnesium and it's making THC and and
whatever you know when we take that so
we see there's so much we don't know but
when we take that CBD when we take that
THC we're taking essentially the plants
iron in the plants magnesium what she
did with it or he did you know that and
so when you take that into the gut we
really don't know what reaction is the
ones doing to the other we're finding
out they both play on each other and
it's very important to have them both
you know flowing through the bud but we
really don't know if we have a
bunch of THC is that going to cancel out
the cb1 receptor or if we have too much
CBD is that gonna cancel out the CB - or
you know I don't really know the science
I definitely interact with either of
those receptors of CBD doesn't it just
blocks the teaching going all the way
into all the receptors mostly yeah but
what happens if you build up too much of
one or the other
yeah that's kind of where you know
drowsy so we're this is yeah this is
this is well no this is full-spectrum
yeah so zero point three Pam full
spectrum ham full spectrum means so
little now it stinks we got to work with
what we have use these distillates
though when they're playing it apart
just a low THC plan extraction you once
right those are the gummies this is the
tincture and this is the whoa but the
beauty of this is that you can send it
out to be a blow point yeah but see
there's a lot of moms and there's a lot
of parents and there's lot of people out
there that don't want to fuck with THC
for seven years you know and so it's
important to have products out there
that people can go to and start baby
steps and get knowledge we know we do
CBD THC a cousin CBD or THC in theirs
that people have been told for seventy
years and it's terrible for you're gonna
see the amazing drippings you'll never
you know back to it we'll hear something
that you're not you're gonna get that
full body like the flower you know this
is flower right here
this is this is a flower so dude so
there's no cherry wanting I had some it
was like 11 to 2 c dv/dt she was in a
candidate stop officially it was one out
of the ones have in the desert it was
phenomenal it didn't get me high but it
was the thing yeah all my pension away
recently she's amazing
it was so phenomenal it was the clarity
that it created almost made me go on
yeah that's it that's how you're
supposed to kind of balances yeah
there's nothing cameras
this isn't even cleaned up you guys go
on that tour
yeah that's what I'm doing 8 acres of
this orchard style just big trees and
not you know yeah and and put love into
it to where your yielding at least four
units on top of whatever you're
harvesting from route up so I'm be using
stock you know everything everything now
their gates in here or you have to
remove it no it's this is rain it's it's
zero zero zero point three point three
yeah right there exact which is good
which solid asking yeah there's some
indigo because the way see the plant get
you hot reduces it you know it's
impossible to get it to not produce it
it's impossible
that's the tough so everybody's
happiness was so much yeah seeing three
copies
it's 1% it would save hope you they're
gonna go to 2 - we need three three
three and a half let's go for four five
let's just put thresholds up on okay
anything above 16 you got to be 18 above
or 9 to 20 years old buy it whatever
anything below you know you should be
able to get fucked just like Tylenol
yeah I just don't want them to start
doing the graduated taxation base
they're gonna do that yes here's the
thing is you can already see how they're
setting it up there there's gonna be a
lot if you're a patient tolerance
they're just it's just know already 39
percent is it's unacceptable I've told
them I mean the most powerful
constituency potentially of course is
the cannabis consumer if they realize it
but it's not going to happen that okay
but it's an excitatory or another one if
you're a patient if you like our
legitimate legitimate what's legitimate
well my definition is is I'm loose no no
it's rather wide definition it's like
well if if you you would use it if if
you go home and you have you know
whatever you know - after work and
you're gonna smoke a joint rather than
you know other things one could do when
one doesn't smoke or if you just use it
to maintain homeostasis absolutely
so you know sort of like yeah
[Laughter]
clear-minded Bernadino fucking that was
it called imagine imagine he does if you
talk to me probably tell ya I've been
alive like campers and stuff like that
the ropes and like add that stuff into
like make it this product's gonna be
mostly equestrian but eventually like -
yeah that's where it kind of started out
with horses and then yeah it's actually
a friend of mine a lady friends product
that's the pet lion
yeah that's also you could take that yes
and the gummies and why did I have to I
have four nope you know what keep my bad
I'm here
[Laughter]
it's going through the right here is
this like yes it's got all those other
benefits we make a tincture THCA is 20
times more anti-inflammatory than an
advil is too high
advil system now yeah right it's great
for that inflammation for the older
animals yeah we found a great work for
the CBD was great for the anxiety and
the stress that came along with that but
then we made a wonder one with the high
CBD a and the high THC a in the same way
because very few people have anxiety but
not paying papers aya tea you know
everyone's bodies are so different than
can I get an internship in your
laboratory that should take a class they
said people spend more money on their
animals healthcare in California my
mom's dogs watch the fireworks in
Massachusetts for the first time in
eight years that she heard what he said
well fuck did you do it up like I did of
my dog for the fire yeah one or two
drugs per 15 pound well we do an olive
oil based tinctures tomorrow what
they're doing yeah we just grabbed the
cannabis have infused it in olive oil so
now all right we grow ac/dc and just
draw it up into in dollar for coconut
good I make a honey I put it mighty
through the gut is how you're supposed
to be well stomach did you live or your
kid needs to get to there you
suppository or put in your bellybutton
moments are there did you tell me oh you
made that good sleeves rolled I rolled
it like a Cuban but it's all it's all
part of the plan
rising yeah it's beautiful all from the
same plant
let's go dear that's pretty awesome
it took cool it's pretty cool it's a fun
harvest season like that much special
because that's from that's from 2019 but
it's you know that's a piece of history
from that Harbor you know I mean ya know
one day I'll see I see it as wine you
know like it'll be like that like did
the artisan you know and I'll sit down
with somebody like snoop and and
you know or whoever and go over this and
then I'll send that fuckin thing will be
worth a thousand dollars you know in a
glass case whatever you know and and
that that's that year especially yeah
you know that year and that terpene
profile cannabinoid profile and eighteen
and nineteen next to each other it was
amazing like Jews do with wine all the
time these verticals verticals they'd
never done with the cannabis before it
was really cool do tours gonna play in
this thing like no other like in the end
that will be Whittle play like to where
these people and ten years there'll be
these farms that are just known that
only that place because that you know
that the way the fucking Sun hits it the
soil and just like up in Sonoma when the
whole thing went down in the seventies
in there like oh how do we figure it out
would it and why doesn't this property
play and this property does well it was
it was all the science behind there
you know there's all the little secret
area maybe actually a science wise yes
search me kinetics yes
because I never would say really Sonoma
or any of those areas are really like
there's more like well yeah they got out
of the fucking city and you went up
there because you could hide in the
redwoods and you can hide in the hills
up here well we're at we're open we're
out in the open there's no hiding
there's a little bit of Redshank you can
get under that if you're lucky it's 16
feet but everything else and then cured
it yeah over time we've learned now
you've learned that you know yeah put it
there put it there yeah for sure they
just have to so because we were involved
in the grow off the NorCal grow up and
it's so Beijing to get like 70 70
cultivators got two clippings off the
same plant and then grew them and we're
gonna do one of those this year where to
where we take same thing do give you
know punch cuts off one deal you
submitted and if you told somebody there
were 38 different buds gonna believe
them that's why in the end you know when
when you do encompass the outdoor to
indoors and the markets you know
eventually California's got to realize
that it's got to take advantage of its
outdoor market yeah pretty much for the
most part
there's a couple different ones then
there's some Stratus you know but yeah
and the light ski that light ski that
same light cycle you know being on the
parallels like that skis well into the
the the the biosphere like the the
Mediterranean kind of you know biosphere
it's been getting drunk and cold in
California that's right like right now
it's averaging I would say 38 up north
it was 40 last week when I was up there
you don't get a deep freeze for a long
time which it does cut oh I guess snow
oh yeah I get several storms every year
to where I'll get at least especially
last few years to where you know I'll
get five inches and it'll last a day or
two I don't know that's the thing you're
right on that layer where you're not
shoveling I just do a full-time Oh from
so do most people in your area do it use
new life if you're in it for the money
you're gonna do it for as much as you're
gonna do it as quick as you can and
you're gonna do it from clones and
you're gonna do it you know you're not
gonna care how you're gonna do it bottom
lines how much might make you know if
you do it and you got love and you put
into it and then it's different you know
it's a process called the marathon you
know it's a process you know you're not
doing it yeah the money is great cuz we
all got to pay bills we all go to feed
ourselves but if that's why you're doing
it you're gonna lose in this business
you know because this is culture in the
end
you know this so many people are coming
into it right now and like all woods new
it's this new business and how we're
gonna do the regulation how we're gonna
do this and that this business has been
around for decades centuries it's not
new it's been around for so long you can
do all the regulation you want people
are still gonna do what they do
you can put all see that's the problem
is you get companies that come in and
think I'm gonna get the first license
and I'm gonna monopolize this area and
I'm gonna be the guy you know fuck
everybody else
I'm canopy group and I got four fucking
billion dollars right and and so I'm
just gonna come in and we're gonna
monopolize I'm gonna on briella you guys
and we're gonna buy up everything we're
buy up all the licenses and we're gonna
monopolize it no you're not gonna
fucking monopolize there
you're not going to good luck look at
what they tried to do in the 30s they
tried to monopolize it you know the
whole petrochemical industry monopolized
this plant and said no you can't use
this plant because our patents are
inferior to this plant and we can't make
the billions of dollars and we're
insecure oh fuck you know I'm not
insecure about that you know and you had
the AMA the head dude of the MAA go in
front of Congress and say what the fuck
are you doing for one if you weren't
calling it marijuana the farmers would
be out here with the pitchforks and hang
you cocksuckers excuse my language but
you know and and they pulled the wool
over everyone's eyes and now they're
rolling out all this new shit like you
know and why why'd canopy lose four
billion dollars because they're idiots
they went into this and they thought oh
we're gonna you know
why med men lose 64 billion or million
you know or whatever they fucking lost
who knows how much money because they're
trying to monopolize that you can't
monopolize in the culture its culture
its and this is its agriculture but it's
also culture you know it's not beer and
it's not cigarettes so you're not going
to come into this and treat it like beer
and cigarettes fucking making people
stupid and dying killing them this is
going to yo peeps right you don't have a
Budweiser system in same with the
cigarettes you know those things are
caught you know causing people to not be
conscience conscience in running around
like idiots and so they're coming in
like we got a bunch of money and we're
gonna reinvent the wheel and this is a
whole new business like how we're gonna
regulate is all new I know it ain't
fucking new this is not new it's old get
in where you fit and you're gonna keep
losing money you know my area they're
out there with fucking Blackhawks black
ops flying around on these poor Asian
people that are probably already culture
shocked is because you know they were
shipped over here
and they're just trying to put food on
the table they don't have access because
nobody cares they can't get a license
now you know they're the bad guys if you
really want to talk about it they're now
they're now in there everyday you know
they're looking down on that area how
within it and there we a right puts all
types of ta it's probably it's within a
hundred miles of the border search
whoever it wants to be Wild West out
there you know that's the problem
weather like we just want to grow our
weed hey we just want a fair chance us
alone you know you you're gonna people
you know you got Coachella to wear hey
which will pay all kinds of money yeah
we're 20 plus probably would you want to
join a members Club started have you
been to the cafe Bondi but there you can
get you can drink beer and wine there
now so is this use the high country rose
Jesse Jesse I'm Kevin
my pleasure Michiko that is a piece of
art yeah
did you guys because I used I worked on
a show called was on there with the beer
yeah right right yeah from crater yeah
but we had a feature with that same kind
of method of rolling yeah maybe I got it
from that show so it's about 15 minutes
10 minutes 20 minutes you got your nerds
we've been we've been trying to give
those away for how many years or like a
year two years for the club now they had
whoever makes nerds and they whoever
makes nerd ships like a pallet of nerds
candy here and so every time we have a
party we just put it out to like hope
people take it you can eat all the Nerds
you want
so before you discovered crying if you
discover you all there's
I graduated it cocaine but try to make
something organic yeah I just cool
plantain and put it off oil they're not
happy about that right now but they
gotta figure something out here
so when are you gonna plant I'm hoping
to go have everything done by in
tomorrow yeah in there too small serum
plant putting stuff on top and seeds
right now and I'm hoping to have
everything in the ground oh yeah sorry
so we tied it wet site series growing
and smart supplies no no no not not to
him just Rose doing the roads doing the
roads and doing a more Church style all
the help is proceeded also mm-hmm now do
you have yeah exactly yeah no I'm doing
them what could stay like the vineyards
but but hemp to grow a lot bigger but I
yeah I'm hoping I get a taproot like you
were talking about the dry farming yeah
if I get an 8 6 to 8 foot tap arou about
six feet apart
yeah six feet with about 8 foot yeah
machine a lot of hand is it really a lot
of hands yeah everybody's a lot of
people are just doing you know straight
you know three foot plants you know real
bunched up and trying to fit you know
three four thousand plants into an acre
you're talking about of hemp yeah yeah
that's what they're doing in Camarillo
they were all like they're all flowering
and they're like four feet tall your
biggest one in two turns no well no
they're just they're putting them out
there at veg yet maybe you know on a
foot and a half two feet and then
they're getting another you know maybe a
month of veg out of them and then
they're going into flower at four feet
and they're getting you know pound pound
and a half if they're lucky I'd like to
see is three to four pounds a flower you
know eight pounds of biomass talking
trunk in root and the whole this whole
plan do you have seeds right you cut
down use and you now you you're not
using as many plants you're not using as
much water to keep so many plants going
you know so there's definitely a benefit
in it it's a lot more labor but I think
the best vineyards are the guys are
walking up and down the video it's
playing every day how do you so choose
your hand like what to grow what is that
right now I don't know really to be
honest with you that's like a whole new
happens in this is something that you
know we're in the new territory of what
genetics work in your what sort of ours
walk in your area exactly what was hot
me over point three percent oh and
that's a fine line so what you're saying
is if you get up to one or two percent
which you're shooting for then all the
sudden things that were just over point
three years Olli do you try to do in
then you'll go right up to the line and
so it goes yes a Weibull of that line
[Music]
let me see the Iran jyothi's doing
cheese out of it just like that you know
you go by the bags and use just couple
grams or whatever cuz CBD stops the tea
this tea even going all the way to this
one receptor so I said yeah it's a way
but actually more feeling not that this
is uncomfortable but for a lot of people
like ever at the air old cups and all
the things that don't go get too high a
couple of drops for sad make sure yeah
it's it's a view it just started dabbing
yeah that's why the couch it the two are
the two moms over there like oh yeah but
a couple of drops of the high CBD oil
bring you right to fuck out of that go
from trying to call the hospital to take
it a deep breath and being okay so you
can get a little because this is
gratefully said focus and concentration
you know like your view or driving you
to pay attention later no it's the t-shi
from going all the way into the cb1
receptor okay so teams block the
receptors blog they can add lie from
going into the receptor I don't think I
could find none they don't think it
blocks a receptor I think it blocks the
cannabinoid from going to other partisan
have annoyed
because they've already gotten to the
reset that does it pulls it out it stops
it yeah interesting that's why you're
too high quite a tool you've got here
his client came out Carol is like I want
whatever you're all having I feel Farms
man a lot of money off those paper roll
between the paper wool I work with
family we do we do have em performs and
Wisconsin job passion so but we do mom
my cousin started out sits well struck
by uh-huh so he started out doing co2
extraction so he got a PhD in analytical
chemistry in the late 90s and then he's
been doing extraction like ever since
and started like it's cool yeah so he's
sort of doing like I was going on in
Canada like way more what's happening
here so he's doing there so we put a lot
of other people in business you know
yeah doing that kind of stuff but but
yeah so it's like thank you to kind of
know but it's interesting to talk to you
guys with seitan you know like learning
all about like the different
cannabinoids I mean there's so many out
there what you were talking about
earlier it's like you everyone's
learning about how different
cannabinoids can affect different things
and they're gonna and we're all we're
still learning about which there's so
many of them and we're still learning
about what's gonna help one because one
thing helps one thing but that is
another part of the pharmaceutic
is already in cannabis they own all the
magnets all those guys on and that's why
the patents the things that you know
that you make dinner you know staying
away from small farmers are now starting
see that's the problem I'm having with
with local government and stuff there's
a lot of people and along with
California they're missing out on this
opportunity of these small farms and
getting these patents in these
Appalachians start any lawyers or that I
mean yeah you know and then people were
holding on to them but even with
Appalachians at some point no matter
what protect because you get it you have
to protect it you have to go out there
and protect it yeah totally and I agree
with Rhodes and I agree with you but I
don't have that gateway and people
companies like Bayer and you know do not
I mean yeah but but but but but smaller
operations are starting to realize that
that but ultimately that's their only
route to protection those others they're
doing good that's the key to my survival
Robert that's the key to my survival
nobody else can do what I can do on my
land
no one else can say that they're growing
with your Appalachian this will this
certain hold the var that this only
these scenes that were genetically see
that's what I was trying to get out of
earlier is what happened so Champaign is
like and when you go to the top raped
raped and they lost time after time
after time and loss actually in the
ports of their Appalachian and now it's
too late there's no putting the asshole
back in the body no the next Champaign
and that's a learning point for people
one of Asians right that's totally a
learning spot I think the appellation is
part of the key to the Appalachian the
cultivar the farm the farmer you know
and you know anybody can kind of be the
farmer once that techniques taught but
nobody can be the land and nothing can
be the cultivar except for that genetic
strain and so if you hold on to that
bear can't duplicate that you know bear
come you want to duplicate that and a
lot of companies can try and get pretty
close to duplicating it but in the end
if you do it right and that Appalachians
protected then you know numbers go a
long way you know and so if you got
enough people
behind you you know and I think that's
in the end that's what's gonna protect a
small farmer is you know being in the
right area you know the people that
aren't in the right area you know and
want a future in farming probably aren't
gonna have one thing about Appalachians
it's not just the soil and it's not just
that you that it's the history of the
region
it's the technique it's all of those
little nuances and it is the grower you
know that's like a part of all of those
that mix that magic you guys all had to
use the same technique because I feel
like with champagne don't they all have
to do the same technique and all like do
things at the exact same time as each
other you know what's more important
into the terre law guaranteeing is a
product that is consistent you know and
so you're getting when you're getting a
certain cheese or you're getting a
certain wine or certain you know
whatever it may be but you know tequila
that globby comes that grows in tequila
a certain way you know and so you're
getting a certain guaranteed of a
product and so that's what important
about establishing appellations and
cannabis is establishing the cultivar
also along with it you know and what's
gonna thrive there for everybody and
then the practices you know standards
elected what what cultivars are on the
table for were you I think I think you
know heavy indicas are going to be the
dominant stuff that stuff that works
with that parallel in time and in
history you know and not trying to
reinvent the wheel going you know
working with what what is there and I
know that you know heavy indicas are
what's gonna thrive there you know and
then from there is as a matter of
figuring out what works best there will
there be better years for
is just like with the grapes definitely
definitely definitely definitely
definitely I think dad's gonna be like
we were talking earlier about doing the
cigars doing some you know having us you
know something that's that time capsule
from that farm and that you know that so
if you made one let's say you have made
50 of these and they were marked as
coming from 2024 and they were made a
certain way over time they would have
value I think so
well I think you know what and if enough
people smoked it - well you but but the
value would be earned but oh yeah either
it would happen it would have value you
knows what we're appreciated you know
but it's also my TV show yeah with
increasing value just like just like the
template it would be you guys know like
wine right yeah like red wine if you get
too late the guards change I mean you
can keep a cigar humidor
what tobacco doesn't degrade from THCA
to THC to Delta a to CBS so if you don't
changing cannabinoids over time back oh
just but perhaps in a less tobacco so if
you create the temple bowl and Frenchy
you know if you're keeping it like
temperature-wise still oldy carbs yeah I
got you
time heat and pressure but he said
there's no it should slow it down but
you said they improve so the temple
balls difference is good news you know I
like to use the human how as a person
I think there's some character there but
the the health of the product isn't
quite there and so yes there's a lot of
character there and so it depends if
it's something that you're smoking
possibly it could be a different effect
it can be a different you know because
it's suppression spiritual whatever just
in you know
whatever it may be for you yes but I
think as a product as a you know it
loses its hole by it Peaks out that gets
to a point to where it so it won't be so
we did the three different Durbin's the
other day the 2019 was this bright you
know vibrant go get them the 2018 was a
more like full-body complex and the 2017
you could tell had aged didn't quite
have the terpenes didn't quite have the
flavor coming through it but the nuances
of the 2017 we're really neat
it wasn't our favorite one but you got
to smoke the you each kind of cannabis
another one like that people people he
refreshed I want fresh leaf fresh isn't
always better
you know it's got an aged into things
you know the friggin right core fill all
the stuff gotta come out of it like not
one cures their cannabis properly that's
one people rush it to market you know
it's really nice to see how kind of his
ages and right
furro we haven't been a part of that
process
ever before so it was really neat to
finally see there was early because I
said to be able to go back to that 2017
and deal the you know so oh wow there is
this difference to say no I'll be added
no it's just in jars just you know but
it been in jar for three years now yeah
but you say we open it up and the
terpenes are still there you can
definitely tell it's Durbin you know it
wasn't quite as poppy as the 2018-2019
you know but it oxidized a little bit
you know there was a little desk color
into it but think about the temple balls
was the coating gets hard so he inside
scraps is preserved yeah yeah that's why
I don't make the hash so it so they
could travel with it you know it's about
that when you manipulate by the process
so no I think it's a great in a
different way yeah things that need to
be explored more yeah once they start
letting us study that you know and you
can start studying the individual
terpenes and cannabinoids and shit you I
mean I the reason I was asking was
because you know so he works with
aficionado and so and surround us yeah
and they were but now actually has his
own stuff on the market so would Willy
would we see one day like like that my
father's eighteen year old you're likely
to see aged hashed and you are aged
cannabis is no idle people ever CH
cannabis people for what you yeah not
like that I mean it go back but like
wine some wines have 20 year life some
wines only have a five year life some
weird ones haven't we really you know
it's different it's a great past there
but it might be that you grew something
where one season it was like
exceptionally it's like oh it's always
like that wouldn't him it's always been
like that when something is exceptional
that and whenever it hit the LA County
line it was bombed I was like because
people knew you know so and so it might
was born fast but the met your memories
it's plenty the parallels between
cameras and wine every time I keep
talking about just seems yeah there's
well it's just the product the to where
there's a lot of parallels definitely
but to it's kind of two different worlds
you know ones pre annual ones the annual
and the cycles are a lot different but
definitely for culture yeah yeah yeah I
would say so yeah right that's when you
get on that next level is when you start
mixing those two just at the cannabis
cafe now you can there's a back porch
you can get food have wine and beer now
and then you can go inside smoke and eat
inside but you can't know it's there's a
door but you can't smoke outside you
can't drink inside what fuck ya add an
appetizer and a glass of wine came
inside and had dinner and dessert and
smoked all the pots so that's fuckin
great that's great
is so fun plans everywhere the few more
years
yeah wheels right to be
there should be at least that option but
also that was that was the great thing
about the the Emerald exchange is being
able to go up and see all these
different farmers and their product at
the same place was my first my first big
event to see their horn it's a different
culture the desert growing culture
different those two that's the whole
problem right now with the two different
worlds you know a lot of the northern
those farms up there look down here and
don't respect the farms down here and
you know there's something good going
down down here and we all got to work
together and understand
California's two are as a whole needs to
be protected you know well you have a
really good story to tell
yeah a lot of us do up there you know a
lot of a lot of these farmers in SoCal
and NorCal in general market down here
you're not allowed to grow outdoor
flower you can only get into our
licenses yes what hinders that I think
that's part of the problem between North
Cal and SoCal is if they believe in the
Sun in NorCal and they want help in the
legal market they're not allowed to use
the Sun like they should be able to done
your flock and it's not necessarily
anyone's fault except for the lawmakers
you know it's bad well as the money is
creating that dichotomy the money too
many greedy people look at it like oh
we're gonna make money here and we're
gonna make money you know we're gonna do
it our way don't look at how just let
things be and let let it be agriculture
let the plant thrive where she thrives
all hemp is is a war dramatic word for
cannabis you know so when you use hemp
it's like what about hemp will happen is
be farmed in a responsible manner you
know and it's not lately it hasn't
you know it says all sun is being turned
into this mono crop let's fucking blue
eco I'm 208-908-7815 I'm not trying to
hate on that but at the same time let's
just ease into it yeah let's do as much
as we can but responsibly responsibly
you know and that's the thing is there's
a lot a lot of people losing their ass
right now in the hemp industry that jump
didn't do it thinking they're gonna make
a lot of money and a lot of promises not
if you were somebody that got into some
stock and got out quit you know knew the
game but you know if you're a farmer and
you thought oh wow this is what's gonna
finally bail me out you know and it
didn't bail you out you know you're
thinking what the fuck there's so many
people coming into this game 20 years
too late looking for that money that
isn't there anymore you know and and
that's the sad thing is a lot of people
are you know losing their ass in this
industry and they don't need to because
it is in all what it is it's agriculture
you know and you got all this new
inventions of lights and all this shit
you know yeah if I'm on the East Coast
and I can't use the god-given Sun that's
wonderful you know from my trying to
make some specific medicine strain that
just needs to you know that I want to do
in a controlled environment and I don't
I don't discipline passive solar like
greenhouses like you know there's
certain passive solar greenhouses that
are regenitive and you're not sucking
off the grid or awesome yeah you know
yeah the basic greenhouse you know but
you're using the Sun in a way that you
know you're not normal greenhouse yeah
you got a lot more control yeah
you need to have control coz of pests
well that's a thing what I learned
breeding I've learned to be able to
breed certain genetics that work and
that don't okay I get a certain amount
of pests in this region all right let's
let's get a little more limonene in
there you know or the eucalyptus you
know there's certain Terps that you can
get into the plant that you don't see
that are pests yeah that's the shit that
people don't understand and why I'm
growing this shit here and and I don't
and they're wondering why they're
getting infestation you know because
you're attracting it you know and in
whatever cultivars growing yeah and so
once people start learning all I put
this here then that's when shit starts
clicking you know and and the real ad
comes out see people are trying to use
the old twenty year model of hiding it
indoors when it was illegal and that's
what the regs going to okay now we need
to put it indoors cuz we need to control
it because it's marijuana and you know
like it doesn't make sense it's just
like you got fuck these are super
structures being built and Coachella and
out and out along tow I mean literally
like fucking warehouses and in these
places are the carbon footprint they're
gonna cause I don't care if they're
they're making their own energy they're
just gonna be dissing general i'ma just
be in there and what they're gonna
create a few jobs you know put that in
an area to where the plant grows good
and if those people really truly love
being in the industry they'll move there
you know and though you know that's what
they'll do just like in the grape
industry you know or the avocados or
oranges it sounds like you don't use a
lot of power no I can't afford it
it's I don't have it in my budget
you know ya know I uses less power you
know shit
maybe when the TV's on yeah I don't you
know just doesn't make sense
for me yeah I mean when I'm trying to
veg I'll do a little bit but I try to
stay where I try to use as much Sun as
possible why not you know it's there I'm
getting that full spectrum of you v's
that the plant knows that the plant
needs she's not getting you know robbed
of something that needs to be that's
that's the thing that's where the future
is gonna be we're all gonna get cannabis
but it's gonna be some fucked up monster
strain you can't you know we're gonna
get our yeah yeah fucking guys they'll
sell you to death on those fucking
things what I gonna do now are you
getting all that shit from China now
what the fuck you gonna do on that whole
deal now you are getting that fucking
deal shit show know even knows the next
train wreck of it oh yeah totally you
know do you want to system that so
reliant you you know you're reliant on
the grid so if you have an outage all
the sudden your shit goes into you know
you know it's long has the power in the
first place yeah a few other places it
takes some two years to get it yeah well
look it like fucks on the projects in
shelhah
they're not even fucking on so yeah you
don't even have power yet and they're
still getting bled by the county hey you
gotta love California
properly guy we talked to say it's like
a two-year wait
and it's a first-come first-serve thing
so like if your first job right but it's
also like there's a line and these
people there's all kinds of fucking they
got Windows generating power I don't win
California baby and literally don't get
you'll get your power gonna cost you you
growing marijuana that's a special kind
of power
we're gonna send you magical power and
that cost more you know and that's work
with some of those guys that have been
going through that whole deal that's sad
you know talking about how people have
been bent over backwards you know some
people had high hopes down there you
know it's finally reality you know like
I said you don't push something that's
not natural you know and that those type
of deals are gonna work and the Midwest
and on the East Coast where it's cold as
I you know it's super cold you know
right now you can't grow much and
there's still a supply there and a huge
demand and so you got this little you
know warehouse could that can supply
enough that it's gonna make a good mint
and it can keep the power on you know
but here I don't see the shit like down
on the desert working no the more reason
we need to be able to ship cannabis
across state lines because there's been
an avocado is over they're not trying to
grow spinach over there cuz it doesn't
grow Bo doesn't roll over jack roll
where it grows the best and you ship it
to the rest of the country it's how
farming works like for some reason that
loop has been cut off I can't get it
back right now
certainly because it will ship that shit
these cousins always have it that's the
thing you're never gonna stop that part
of it until you you know I hate to say
it but I don't know if the the current
person in
office right now he kind of sees it he
sees that oh you know they're gonna get
it regardless you know they're gonna get
a ditch in is gonna be out there they're
gonna get their product regardless and
prohibition doesn't work you know
regardless upon his emotion if he thinks
he met you may sound stupid it makes you
sound stupid sometimes it does if you
know whatever his thoughts on what it
does to an individual don't really
matter it comes down to a business sense
and California is making a lot of money
on cannabis and all California really is
is a renter in the United States right
in one of the states so eventually the
feds coming for its money you know and
organs money and Washington's money and
Colorado's money you know eventually
that's how it's gonna go down and that's
why we're doing this is they're getting
their dry run on they're seeing one
how's this working what's happened with
the farmers where's the money
oh it's fuckin California those
cocksuckers they're sittin on it problem
is there's no money in health and that's
what's being held that oh there's no
money in hell they start teaching the
endocannabinoids system people get help
yeah there's no there's no money in
education or health because if you don't
the reason they make money is cuz you
get sick and they give you pills if you
don't get sick and they can't give you
pills
it changes medicine back to before the
30s when that's how it was plant-based
medicine but that Jeff is the face of
medicine again and for people to make a
lot of money run the government that's
holding you back right now you know so
even if the picture that does understand
that what big fine it's petrochemical
it's not just Pharma
it's talk a plastic textile fucking fuel
a man we're talking you know the plant
is gonna change the world eventually you
know eventually people will wake up to
this thing oh oh oh
oh please the waterer fuck we got all
this chemical in the water and it's
cleans the soil yeah what eventually
this shit will click with people and
[Laughter]
it's gonna take time I guess you know we
must had a perfect example because he
uses him saying that in the Tesla cars
but then he gets reamed for smoking you
joined Joe Rogan show yeah so you have
to apologize his wall speak comes out
him but he could have said how you
motherfuckers yeah I smoked the joint
but look what I fuckin do with this
wasn't so much the smoking sure I think
he said after he smoked a joint now my
stocks gonna sell for 420 actually Henry
Ford was building cars way out for Tesla
you know we should have been all the
work has gone up right Tesla stock price
Cano having a car I rock it in my theory
is a lot of their stuff in-house in this
whole China thing's gonna fuck the car
industry because everything you know you
want a pair of breaks it's gonna be the
main turn but they do a lot of shit up
there in California there are up there
and we're we're fucking NorCal there
that's a whole nother state we should
get separate but no they that factory
does everything in-house for the most
part yeah
or you invented some rocket that's going
to the mode and a fucking backup so we
got a ticket to moon he's ultimately
okay he's a pretty sharp dude he puts it
as it is you know common sense he looks
at you know I fuck you guys you need to
say I think thinking I can control pay
attention here real quick yeah it's
already out of control
guys swear to God I think about shit
that comes up my feet yeah that's half
of it that's not even any safety yeah
you wanted it fuckers want it safety
over three dogs
yeah alright so tell me about the
logical regulations that are being put
in place in Riverside County Cole there
is no logic we had an ad hoc which is
you know to to build like-minded people
come together and you know hash out what
should have been talked about and they
expunge that and said now or kick that
to the curb and so with everything at
the county level yeah because it's
unincorporated so either that either
they incorporate over there
ananza or they keep getting screwed by
the county and the thing is is that you
know a little Valley up there sits on
some of those best most pristine waters
yeah well it's the watershed so what
watersheds from there if it's shitty
contaminated water that sheeting
contaminated watersheds down into the
valley Temecula Elsinore Corona
manaphy countless down Vince League onto
you guys if you guys aren't pulling your
water from up north
I had a fucking moan oh and what's that
other little where are we
currently pulling our water from an LA
Charlie I have no idea I probably should
know just waffle between Ralph's and the
fauces pipeline that comes down from
this year there's a movie gun on it
China Lee in LA all the way from Mesa
you know it is above mammoth above june
lake up there from oh no pretty much
even further you know from there it
comes all the way down from there into
the Owens Valley from the Owens valleys
and you know it's it pipe it's not even
a pipeline it's this square fucking
thing that these cargo to the hills back
when Wayne you know there's a lot
there's a water company actually like a
right there that's crystallizer they got
popped for putting there because it was
half water for them yeah they got pop
for putting some pop pop recently for
them yeah yeah arsenic Tiger are still
yeah it's still good
arsenic yeah arsenic yeah pop for
arsenic that occurred naturally no in
that stuff man ochre is asking in the
ground I don't know the way the new way
looking wonderful media pitch did is
that these guys knew they were putting
it in there they news in there so it
might occurred ya know correct naturally
all that arsenic yeah so water water is
key for people you know and that's a
watershed so that's one thing that
people should realize is they're still
and Tom could be your neighbor
Sammy watch come on
oh yeah you could turn it into the next
Swami you could grow the beard
[Laughter]
country a country swarming yeah not too
shabby
but it's the regulation needs to change
because the Appalachian you know if
we're in somewhere down in San Diego
you say what the current regulations are
it's indoor and so it doesn't allow all
throughout the county they will not
allow any outdoor cultivation except for
your six or your 25 so if it's only
indoor then you guys can't create the
basis for Appalachia you can create the
framework for when you lose they can be
amazing I'm trying to tell you the
people there look at me like I'm crazy
other crops within the county well yeah
there's grapes there's all the macula
has all types of Appalachians that are
through the avian in or whatever
American visitor ABA so fuck they call
these other sure in this state could say
no Appalachians are real cannabis
Appalachians are reeling you should list
well we'll just let up north do it and
then I'll get you hey science all from a
science up science scientists
yes you we want one it's only fair and
we want the the social equity to
thank you we deserved it so you know
that's why I came down and visit woodsy
yes we we have many Wow oh yes there are
new neighbors so we got to get used to
it
the own property so it is what it is you
know it they started migrating in about
five years ago heavily and now bought a
good portion of the Appalachian and
they're there to stay is you know they
grow a good catalyst yeah that's the
problem is they don't know what good Kim
listen you know they're all you they get
their hands on some clones and I
sprained the shit cars and trucks and
they know every year and it's driving
the hillbilly people crazy country folk
crazy out there enjoyed country folk
well we're all country folk out there
you know and so these country people are
like who are these people aren't they're
coming in and they're raiding you know
like and so they'll fight and then
eventually you know what happened was is
the you know the the big money finally
came in last couple years and that's who
got the sheriff's route up and all the
everybody else share out up there
they're like we're investing in this
fucking shit so you guys better come out
and crack down on these fuckers black
market motherfuckers except for now you
have this whole new culture here yes
these people look different but people
get alike understand there's there's
there's armors and they're hard workers
yes yes and they don't like that side so
that makes it bad for the growers though
also because now you have that stigma
now you know oh you're you know rather
than looking upon you or you're bringing
like back in the early 70s 80s 90s it
was quiet money but it was the money
that kept the community going sure you
know but nobody talked about it and now
it's out and everybody's fucking face
hydro shops and fucking new halls going
up and down the road
up and down that you know it's gotten
everybody stirred up and it's gotten you
know it's gotten it's gotten a lot of
people stirred up now but that's you
know a part that the community needs to
learn how to accept and work with flow
with work with rather than work against
because these people are digging in
these are the same people wrote the back
of the US military with the Ho Chi Minh
Trail DNA they will break these fucking
Riverside County Sheriff's and they will
break any people up there they're done
it they're backed by the Chinese deep
money and deep pockets people that
realize no people who realize that the
Appalachian way before people like me
probably did and realize where do we put
that you know money buy land up there
put these farmer guys in you know let
them do their thing
yeah exactly you know people who realize
this shit way before others do and buy
into this area kind of like the
Coachella thing a few years ago all this
fucking desert land all of a sudden
turning into huge warehouses and once
was going for five thousand acre that's
now going for a hundred thousand an acre
shit like that you know you look into
that and then you realize okay that's
there shit's fallen apart real quick I
was down there not too long ago and
there was a lot of industrial and
commercial Lots up for sale or you know
rent whatever but people had pulled out
I know a lot of companies that were
doing the same thing you're doing that
pulled up shop and went up two or
and shut down fired everybody you know
and bounced out of that little area and
out of that situation you know so that's
you know eventually that'll come back to
the table but I think you know in the
next several especially with this new
thing that's going on with the market
and how things will happen with this I
think that's really gonna go on the
shelf for a while it's gonna be on the
show from yeah there's a lot of it I
mean it's their time to and they're
starting to already yeah because like
you said earlier people aren't
understanding like it's a huge market
and it's going to be a huge market
place's it's gonna continue to be but
they're they don't understand how to do
it yet or like you said it like
different strains work different places
and different things so it's like people
are buying spending a lot of money on
seeds and they're just throwing it out
there but they're not throwing them in
the right place yep so it's it's
problematic because it's there's a huge
learning curve on that and what you're
talking about on top of and that's where
it all starts and that's you know that's
where it all starts is with the farmer
because what we produce is what you
extract or you know what so there's so
much that people are missing and the
vendors are with something new into like
a new area the farmers aren't always
there yeah because you're like okay well
this we got to try different things to
see what's gonna happen you know that's
where the regulations at to where you
know you got to be so you're hidden and
kind of like all fuck you know how do i
express myself and you know the way you
know I grew up anyways we don't talk
about it you know I'm sure it's such a
now coming out the fuckin camera in my
face everything in my DNA
[Music]
what's Darwinism you finally realizes
you know I was somebody was talking
about his Darwinism you know you either
fucking getting the boat or drove Geordi
was taught said some about it and I was
like BAM and it clicked and I was like
fuck did you stay doing what you're
doing and you're dead in a few years
you're fucking broke figure in a war you
know I seen so much happening in like do
you know do I bring money in do I blow
up a brand do a war where do I go you
know I'm a venturi you kind of realized
we would have stayed in the black
mortgage yeah I've had opportunities and
I've had a little bit yeah I've had
opportunities yeah because I'd be
exactly I'd be in a situation to where
all fuck I'm sorry Shannon culture we
lost our place yeah I hit a bug you know
so I've been lucky totally you know
where I the first late I'm I'm not tied
to anybody or anything and I can do my
thing and I can stay in my lane I'm I'm
a farmer stay doing what I do
create a plant you know and you guys do
what you do with it you know not even
that you don't even want them to line
with you just wants to do an intent
return than have you telling me you know
what I'm doing you know what I'm doing
and you'll do it and do your thing you
know that's important I think and a lot
of people have and are in good places
and aren't set up you know it's license
and are doing their thing and making
money but you know it seems like this
business is always changing and so you
know what you're doing now is that gonna
be working in five years look at what
happened to you know med man like it
what happened to canopy you know
throwing it till
all these companies that was everybody I
think so I think I think it's not
necessary craft growers I think somebody
if you look into who the brands kinda re
if you look at somebody like you were
mentioning Frenchie somebody like that
for instance he's built uh he's got a
good brand he's got a good product he's
found his niche but he's he's he's
culture he's entertaining he's Swami
there these are people that are exactly
they have you know they have a niche to
them a certain something that people are
interested drawn to and so those are the
guys who will probably survive in the
end you know and and and the guys who
have the money who do it as a hobby
create the cultivars and create the
appellations with the cultivars and and
do it as a passion will be the dudes
that will be remembered it won't be the
guy with fucking four billion dollars
who is he's forgot about now now fired
like a guy strikes or a Volvo of
cannabis yeah I think I think I think I
think I think yeah because corporate
there's no killing that no but I think
we are the last industry as small
farmers and you know craft guys and that
have this passion that can kind of niche
out something special that awakens
people and causes consciousness and
causes people to realize all fuck maybe
the way I'm living and I was not
regenitive and in a in a manner that I'm
just taking advantage of everything and
we and we caused something to say oh
well the farming that we're doing back
east isn't healthy you know and the food
that we're eating isn't healthy and the
way we're going about it is it healthy
for the rest of the world and it's not
you know hopefully but that's the last
product and that's the last industry
that'll do it you know it's not gonna be
some electronic bullshit that all Sun
causes consciousness and people are like
oh
when yes it'll be a plant and then most
likely that plan yeah some about
economics there's something in an area
where you know especially up in that
region up there it's very opened so at
night you can see all the the galaxies I
mean you see all the colonies I mean I
brought I brought a half outside no
other lights and sums up to Alaska
that's important ya know it's important
to be and the plant should be a part of
that too
you know you should be taking that in
and that's what I'm talking about
cousin you know that people start
realizing the food clothes you know the
stuff that they're putting on themselves
and in themselves is having an impact
big time all over the world and all over
themselves work and like work clothing
Oh work clothing
basic thing that's great yeah that's
awesome
you make jeans well that's what leave
are used to that's where they first
started out with the ham and then went
the cotton so you can make more money
because you got ones were out hemp ones
did no that's a whole nother debate
Washington's him when he was talking
about plant the Indian hemp because at
the time everybody knew Indian hemp was
the hemp that got you stoned
it wasn't the pimp 200 years prior to
even Washington hemp was being grown in
the colonies
European hemp hemp for fiber and sails
for oil and things like that
yeah they pay their taxes with him
compared to during wartime you had that
you had the girls yeah you and you could
pay your taxes with it at one time but
he was the guy right now Indian have
this shit's good stuff it's for rope at
that time Indian hemp was the hemp that
was medicine
it wasn't European hem right in front of
our face the history's right there I
mean you can look it up and it's like
they're the guys quoting it you know and
he's panicking he writes a deal do as
was I think it's you know the guy who
runs is his Foreman of his garden he's
panicking where those seeds the seeds
need to be planted make sure those
Indian hemp seeds are planted make sure
it's the Indians later it's like no yeah
well that's the fight you know that's
supposedly the father of the revolution
you know that's wire like there's a lot
of crazy here so there's a guy who was
it crisp and and I think a guy who goes
into a lot of like the biblical history
and a lot of like like you know deep
into the history of the plant yeah and
you'll find that a lot of you know the
Revolutionary dudes we're you know
messing with some type of a she should
be some type of cannabis you know
especially the writers and people like
read she says it's an extruder you about
a hatch every morning really doesn't
like but like all of it like a bomb I
was it seemed like it would kill the
average human being
his presence tell me about good for you
like a Clif Bar size right yeah that's
how I met Peter it was through that hole
yeah I was I was interviewing a friend
she was screaming he was like his face
he was like spitting in his face and I
was on mushrooms and it was a it was a
Desert Hot Springs end of August I kept
going inside because it was like
ice-cold cool and then you come and then
I get cold and I come back outside and I
get like super hot yeah I kept having to
go back back you
but even medium units we were just going
at it about his toes about three through
parallel parallel yeah that screamin
nose good conversation you know he's
French
they were sitting like where these two
are and I was sitting here in base
enough now
he possibly shat on their appellation
because nobody's ever heard of it
he's like nobody knows about you so you
must be Mary who are you basically you
don't have no genetics and I was like I
agree 100% like but that's what I'm here
that's what I'm trying you know like
somebody's got it yeah I know totally
like where he's coming from and that's
what I said hey buddy you got the
culture but I got the science does go
way back it's not you don't have to be
here you know who's over you know
there's a lot of culture up there that's
come out of the closet because they've
had to it's a survival technique you
know I got to start building a brand I
got to start getting early sixties to
probably fuck it's not the Avenger
because it's a part of it part of
Appalachian I know I'm just talking
about bringing something I'm not I'm
just trying to bring attention to
something that's already there I'm not
trying to create anything yeah bring the
oil is that yeah thanks true oh that's
good you know that but you know and
seeing that the way I can do it is
through the Appalachian system yeah you
know yeah I don't that because I see it
and that's what's gonna do it's a little
area you know there's a lot of Aryan
salmonidae know and and San Diego
Riverside
so anytime I love that is something that
you have opportunity to get back in the
dry part yeah no I totally agree no see
on the dry farm there's some areas you
couldn't drive farm up there though
but there's a lot areas there's also
some so the Appalachian would encompass
also San Diego if I was to you know if
it was up to me yeah it would encompass
a little bit of San Diego County North
County there and probably a little bit
of South County salmonidae yeah exactly
it's all that high country it's all that
you know that is weighted or that yeah
yeah
Morocco anything along the 33rd parallel
all that stuff that's through the
Mediterranean all that Moroccan Lebanon
Golan Heights all the way to New Year's
to create something that you can throw
right back in Friday's not about that
it's about just bringing light I think
he sees it I think now I think people
are starting to see it like when I
mention it you can bring it up I mean
you can research you can google it it's
called a Mediterranean biome and it and
there's only goes along the third is
basically like the United States would
you find a matter of Terry nowhere else
except on the west coast it goes up a
little bit to Central some of northern
some of those areas but the hub of it
would be more subtle well yeah well the
Temecula Valley's producing some of the
a lot of people
most people like all this fucking guys
yeah and like this look at the fucking
science of it you know follow the pin
you know follow the history follow the
culture like it to give me know when you
do look at it there's other places
there's a lot of play you know there's
some but then when you still really
start opening it up and you say okay
where this where did the sativas work
because that's some of your in because
you know and and and so and then you
start going into metric turbid yeah and
then you start exactly some of the mechs
you know Mexico some of these different
you know regions to where you can
produce some fire
Stephen different growing regions will
you find in the high country probably
there's many different microclimates
maybe many different microclimates and
many different soils and different you
know there's a couple different aquifers
and the ABA yeah exactly so within that
let's say like how the whole the the
whole Mendo projects going is there's
several different areas up in that
appellation and the same thing that's
why I was saying it's probably gonna
eventually it would be multiple counties
it wouldn't just be the and valley
you know maybe starting out the ends of
valleys such as how Temecula does in
these oh and it's spreading actually
people that are working on this
particular climate elsewhere in other
counties that you know no I don't think
so I don't think there is anybody
because I mean there there's really not
a lot of people reaching out in SoCal to
do that so there may be a handful if
some work work during the day too cuz
it's all about gathering data and
nothing but that do in order to create
your organization that well that's just
work that has to start at some point
this farmers coming together yeah
sharing information chain hey this is
what's working for me over here
the only way you do it is go you're
either dead or you try which was like
five robots that came together as one
giant robot our bar up in Occidental you
walk in and every single person there's
a cultivator and you know I used to kind
of keep to yourself now if you have an
issue you ask a question you need to
answer right now and it's coming
exponentially faster now because we're
out in the open and we're allowed to
share information and it's okay to
finally grow cannabis up there you know
I got screwed from the trees that's the
biggest industry information you know
sharing information and now we're coming
in that stage to where IPS are so
important well ironically then but then
people get into IP that all of a sudden
they go I see it as either either you
got it or you don't
and then that's it life either you got
it or you don't you know and you can
fake it all you want and you can have
all the money in the world than you want
but either you got it or you don't you
know and that comes with cannabis and
that's gonna come with having an IP that
somebody in a product that goes along
with that that somebody wants but you
know that's so true and that's true with
genetics once once the genetics are on
the market they can't be patented anyway
I mean once and people put their clones
out and those clones can no longer be
patented but but so but whatever someone
can now that's right now future who
knows how that's all going to change the
law you know look at corn there Zoe I
mean look at these seeds that are
patented you've got to go to somebody
and you got to sign a contract won't get
any patents for all this stuff in the
patents may be broad and we'll see what
happens in court anyway but having the
appellation just that separates yeah
that separate that gets you away from
all that mulching because that's what's
gonna happen to those hemp growers and
Midwest that are you know Kentucky you
know what
Jinyan those dudes that are doing money
like my hemp impregnating to be - a
because their God Mon center Mon
syndrome seriously just dissolved away
you know it's gonna be somebody else I
will come a little organic compound see
that's where that's where the expression
of the soil and the cultivar and that
area is going to expect was nuts
so actually one of the most interesting
things she would this one was talking
about was that wine growers are noticing
when they test their wine new terpenes
appearing in their wine that had never
been there and like if you guys at
Sonoma growing down the street being
like sorry dude that's better than us
getting equal twenty one thing is that
whole industry so fucking poison over
the years was they need the cannabis but
but they're ready to see if people like
that or like a separate farmer just
decides to throw it easy like you know
what I'm just gonna fuck him throw a few
males on the edge of my fucking field
here oh it's coming let's fucking go
because then they'll just yeah that's
what I do because a lot of people are
you know the cannabis growers and now
that I'm on the 0.3 side if they if if I
were the government and I were watching
this right now I would oh they are I
would throw out the male plants talk to
the commissioner in Riverside County and
kind of discuss like hey what do you
guys think about that would be my
sportsman strategy what's a moratorium
on half in Sonoma County additional does
it there that's what they're planning
especially with the Asian
good luck everyone well they're all
outdoor water catcher so and so that's
what they're hoping is like Oh we'll
just fucking hopefully these hemp
brokers I've already talked to them and
see that's the thing is I'm not gonna be
I'm gonna do a little bit of breeding
but I'm not gonna be partying with Paul
[Laughter]
[Music]
knew that you're doing or the weather
sucks but that's what they're hoping is
pollinate those dudes that are just
illegally growing shit out there just
yeah they're just like fuck we hope that
you pollinate everything now like that
but I did somebody's gonna buy your
seeds all guarantee to be feminized no I
have some stock that I'm doing from
guaranteed and then I have some other
stuff but I'll go out yeah you're right
around that's all new hurdles I've never
done that much and you know yeah you
know I've done decent amount but never
you know and that's gonna be a whole new
way of harvesting and and what's gonna
work what's gonna be you it's got to
come down to dollar and I don't want it
to ever really come down to that but
that's gonna come down to where you know
can I afford to have flour hand trimmed
when I'm only getting yeah you know an X
amount for it yeah yeah just like you
know that you know we'll see
you know if I'm drawing it up and I'm
getting X amount for it then yeah I got
a market for it that's the big thing
what I'm realizing is is where is your
market you know where is where where is
your market and then
did you find you or do you find it you
have to find it yeah out there Carmen
I'm gonna find you that's the biggest
problem with farming you gotta go do
something with that now the problem with
a lot you know this whole industry got
so broken in so many ways there's so
many people get me gimme gimme
I got you know the fingers are out
everybody you know and in the end it
there's no industry without flour so you
gotta respect your farmer because if he
can't produce then what the fuck do you
have in the end whether you're a lawyer
whether you're whether you're a law
maker what laws are you gonna make the
mutant people can't pay your their taxes
you know in the end like why'd you make
laws that people aren't breaking them
well that's another thing but that's the
thing is a lot of people don't realize
like you know these products in the end
they come from a farmer and they come
from a farm and you know there's a
there's a life behind that that's like
what you're sort of things like seed a
shelf is like sort of that's a I mean a
performer or a grow up business that's a
huge deal - oh yeah because if you're
putting product out like this no no you
can actually do from here to here and in
house you know that's the thing is
you're not outsourcing we do all that
in-house and what's nuts now is from
clone to out the distro microphone yeah
from clone out to distro it gets tagged
eleven times through metric in and out
of the buzzer system 11 times it's nuts
so if you're not vertically integrated
becomes a whole
it's gonna break down what because what
it goes international national not ain't
gonna work fucking systems yeah alright
its hat yeah
far away can that be you know there's a
lot of shit that's breaking down in the
state that people need to step back and
say well suck being the first all these
things I use this that's the luckiest
thing I've been is not wait what's
driving on credit
Travis tanning crazy being the first
everything you know she had the first
outward cultivation permit in Sonoma
County she was the first people to go
through the whole process in Santa Rosa
getting warehouses and things like that
you know it is one of the first people
to get into metric and she's always been
ahead of the curve but the first one off
the boat shot the history that people
most of those people don't make it the
ones that you are like argh all these
years accompanies to not die yeah that's
our goal yeah
that's why I hunt I hide under the
appellation the problems like rising
structure you know I'm from this from
this journey is a BA we demand this
price from will go below this and as a
group you're stronger they just started
the first era cannabis-based Grange oh
it's in Sonoma County it's really
started to build that I always tell
Peter I think there's about two billion
that's coming out of that region imagine
if that grouped up and started
controlling yeah it's flour how you know
if once it goes across the states its
game in the desert we're coming up there
you do it then once that ran out
tell that to orchid extract all of it in
order because if it's just sitting there
in warehouses like you said it's gonna
gather this is gonna all these bad
things it's like alright well what do we
do we want to make any money I guess we
extract it that's one dish and then like
at least have like the oils and the
candle cannabinoids and just you know
stuff to work with it's got something to
work with it is valuing CBN because it
has the agent I think eventually the
desert is gonna be the hub for
extraction because of the climate
because the dryness and the facilities
that they have and what they'll do once
you've got international going and
national you can just start pulling from
everywhere and and that's when you start
blended you know that's when you start
blending some of these extractions that
people emulate Wow life well you know
you're talking about like with the CVD
like that's how you get your that's how
you use your brand out there
you get national nationwide then you can
go worldwide however there's one Great
Lakes and once it flips over like you
know you're already there that's what
you were asked for me because eventually
the Appalachian whatever plant it's it's
whether it's a 0.3 or not it's gonna
have to thrive on being able to coat the
cultivate X amount of acres it's not
gonna be able to be able to small farm
like what like sorry has it kind of with
some of those people are saying like oh
we're gonna put together these small
little you know into you know 10,000
foot be these collective word yeah
there'll be different places for that
but what I'd like to see is where I can
do those 1020 internet so what on the
global market you're also completing
with the exactly was a pentagram out of
Thailand you will reduce data planning
of Graham wool it's a Thailand product
yes it's a Thailand product yes see on a
global market but it can only grow a
Thailand product
see that's the thing that's that's the
whole thing see Thailand can't do
tequila and that's what the pencil II
people are gonna eventually people are
gonna realize that it's only good brands
are gonna come out of the Appalachians
what's good in Thailand what there's got
to be what know the suit in Thailand
what's to get oh good Thai soup fuck
yeah it comes out of that reason the
court you know what I'm saying that it
that what it's a different ice thickness
was the salmon needs you're not gonna
fucking so if I got Thai stick right
here but no I hear what you're saying
and and know that there it was
there is a market there but I don't I
don't see us you know I don't see you
see people like cash market so
California will still rule on this oh by
far by far
that's what French is always there you
dumb fuckers you don't know what you
have well it has to start that's why it
doesn't make any sense for him to argue
about the this valley
you know Valley has the characteristic
so and you're just arguing for
argument's sake but that's right it
doesn't have the hype yet it doesn't
have the name nor how my Internet
Explorer through any Morocco ok well how
dare do I compare it to the Emerald
triangle either you know there's a lot
of people that if if I would say I
personally think that the cannabis that
comes out of my range or better than any
of fucking rivals it you know when you
really look at it and and you put it in
some nobody there's some somebody's up
there that don't want to expose
themselves that do have fucking
beautiful genetics that people will
eventually realize all shallow they over
yeah can you bring me some of that plant
speeded life here but yeah I think
because of the dryness and the two are
that like I was talking about the soil
the fungi the the different you know the
acidity to the alkaline we had a
bacterias and alkaline and acidity we
have a lot more alkaline we're in that
mineral with mineral high mineralization
that the soul the the silicon and some
of the other minerals in it are you know
we had the crystallization there and so
that's what the plant when she's making
those cannabinoids those CBN you know
from that CBN that starts to break down
in that flour and and that uses the iron
he was saying is that iron so if you can
you just
when iron and war of magnesium into your
soil to provoke those things yeah oh
yeah but she's only gonna use as much as
the Sun and that she can work with as a
process you know and that come first
stage - if it's too moist you want that
dryness and you want that bright UV that
UVB light you know and that really
starts to create something in that wall
you know she's pulling these different
minerals you know when we know the iron
and the magnesium are the two important
you know the magnesium the tilts all of
these factors coming together yes
with mother nature did make mistakes and
that's what we're gonna find like with
these different profiles and cannabinoid
profiles is certain things work for
certain people let's say you got the
arthritis or you got whatever it may be
Malbec flinty you know it dries your
skin out it's a hard place to live it's
a hard environment like most denied you
don't know how the dusters come out and
to get this you dirty fucking they want
to get out of there as quick as possible
because it's a harsh environment you
know it's not a fun place to be that
shit is
it's a fucking shit show out there you
know because that's the thing most of
you know if you're out there but you
don't want to get out of your car and
shit you guys hey it was this bad like
when I first bought I wouldn't tell
people where I live like I was like oh
god I hadn't stood my Huntington Beach
address or wherever you're like you know
when I first had a long all you live
fuck oh that's what Reapers are wrong
that's a bad high desert a bad it's you
know it's not an easy place to live it's
but the plant thrives it's Roger and
sweet rice not so much no and whatever
you know your jugga-jugga choice me you
know that's a bad one Fox people's
doesn't number on people but essentially
these people there's a lot in the city
you know but essentially they kind of
stick out there but it is a harsh
environment you know and that's the kind
of people who go to those places to work
hanging out at the beach doing a bunch
of drugs so you went from Huntington
Beach climbing all over California I've
been I used to live up in Mammoth and I
was a patroller up in June I had
disappeared snowboard up there I did
both it was a patroller at Jun for a few
years so I had to learn how to ski
because you because you started as a
snowboarder yeah well I snowboard since
I was a young kid yeah in our local
mountains I skied first and then sort of
snow or into my first ski when I was
super young like 89 and I was like I
don't like that now has been
snowboarding was just getting cool like
you know mid eighties snowboard thing
you know it looks way funner and so I
never went back at times I snowboard
once and got hurt so bad and went back
to skis for like two or three years and
it took a lesson and once I take a
lesson I will never put skis on I hurt
myself pretty good on skis but they're
both fun you know
this skis definitely blow apart yardsale
it's all I could dig what he goes this
way
or catches like you like rip your it
hurts until you learn that's the same
that's life though that should be learn
these companies coming in for billion
pay your dues and that's the truth
that's just like snowboard skiing
baseball whatever whatever maybe acting
these actors don't become active
overnight burn rates though for
marketing dollars and like I don't know
how its sustainable to put a five
thousand dollar kiosk can do it
dispensary every month well you're not
selling five thousand crazy how are you
which one mighty confidence let's be
specific which companies are doing that
well so for example at urbe here down
the street they have a model where they
have like probably 12 or 13 now yeah
nice job paying between five and ten or
fifteen thousand dollars her booth then
I'm and eight by sellers from that you
know pay to me I was done now which
brands are in there so Cresco yeah
so yes select I think I'll in this got a
thing in there yeah can't craft cuz
there's a handful of alright it's the
same ones you've seen every dispensary
in SoCal you know but some of them
they've taken this model and they put it
out there and it's the pay for play
space it's tricky because it's working
out eventually if everyone starts
pay-for-play you're gonna be save twenty
customers the same twenty every state
did and the local municipal did with
permits you know here pay gonna spot
paying this spot how much money you
gonna pay
well it's up to you how good the spot
you get no becoming at breaks they've a
million dollars a year to spend on
marketing because that's what their
budget was
where else are you gonna go you know
they're trying to get mortgage chair
knows what everything else gets stripped
away baby something why they're doing it
you know to be an anchor brand and one
of these brands but they're still just
throwing away that's it for little
companies to fight against those
marketing dollars I think we ask all of
them alligator you know the we got some
put them on the spot you know the
retailer's about whether they're paying
to play and paying for placement and
forcing people to you know to do that
and they don't really talk about don't
we ask that question do you have people
pay for pretty lucky cuz we're a small
company that some of the places they do
paver play haven't charged us for spot
cuz they respect the small farmers they
want to try cuz those people the buyers
in the displeasure of their tokens yeah
yeah because they like their can make
her kill though if your craft come
Fiddler's greens digest abusive make up
although based okay no I think sure okay
but you know they allow because they
know they can make or break the small
farmer you know if they always just go
to pay and play it's over for the small
craft products well I would take a smart
way for a retailer even if you're doing
the token brand that represents the
number of farmers or something lad like
that at least fucking have that and you
charge the edible company you know what
last year I forget where we were back
east but we went into a little wine shop
and in there it was an independent like
wine shop not a huge chain and they had
like there was a basket with this wine
in it and we were looking for some wine
and they had a whole description of the
wine and how it was grown and the people
that I read the whole fucking thing you
know and if I don't know why I read it
and but I did and it was a whole long
sheet and they've gone to that trouble
and there was a story there about
Vineyard you now and the person growing
these grapes in this wine and it's and
cannabis has to do Center you buy the
wine we did get wine from there I could
get a bottle one and they had a club and
they who I had a whole thing and I think
we might have been in Orlando where my
brother lives so I think he was a member
of it yeah no there's got to be a story
behind it you know just saying you know
but they're allowed to do more things
where you can do a wine clothing you can
do uh you know so when you know I'm
telling you there's money to be made
when you know and we've thought about
this about curating you know and and
wait if you can go not everyone can go
to the Emerald cup but if you can go to
the Emerald cup and act as a curator for
that seasons for other people like
around the run and be able to curate for
them in the pre-op to provide that for
them it's a fucking business model yeah
it has legs on it and when you can
deliver that product freshly within a
couple of days or whatever yeah now
you're talking now this long farm or
hazard Iraq eventually when the
International National you know can and
that and that and that does require a
level of cure a because not everyone can
go there to smell and to see two years
in a row killing it no and to be able to
do those things that have none of those
had to understand I look at it this way
if you had clients around you're going
I'm gonna pick ten strains and I'm in
the village
if you were right half the time you hit
a home run
it's pretty subjective that what will
you take it just so that was cool but
they grow off was there was the same to
save strength everybody so you to see
the exact same terpene you never
denominations but the different levels
of the baby was it was a great a v8
experiment to show how different one
strongly yeah based on separate
microclimate that really has to be done
within the Appalachians year after year
I think you know to really start joking
and figuring things out
that's the whole thing I mean this
thing's this whole process dates data
prize data aggregate but how do you you
know when the data is being held up by
the regulation
that's the fuck thing right now you know
the data and then in the science people
do yeah they also hold on to their data
data ain't there's so much in Canada if
I could protect my data I would release
it all but right now okay I give you
know I like what happened with the whole
I don't know much about files I just
know some people feel they got the bad
in the file of stick the galaxy watch
too and you know looking back now you
know look like some oh yeah rat I want
to be a part of that I want to log into
that and now thinking about it like I
would be like oh fuck because it is my
DNA comes from my BOB now you can
duplicate whatever that particular you
know and if that was the fire that
everybody wants now you have that code
to it and that's the whole thing about
the IP is it protects that code it
protects that creates a lot of feeling
people well yeah now I can go up against
the Giants that's what's so beautiful
when you really start looking at this
whole thing and you start connecting
dots with the appalachian because with
only it's only take the only thing the
appalachian will work is because the
government's gonna realize oh yeah there
is two billion dollars in this little
hub right here that's why the hillock
copters are flying around and then
looking at the shit and they're going
holy shit how do we we just fucking
rainy them for a year straight and look
at their even more you know like they're
trying to figure it all out eventually
they're gonna go we'll listen quick
let's make it let's try and work with it
and that's when the whole thing will
start being protected what do you mean
fucking India you're doing this or what
do you mean you know this other states
fucking with our little bread and butter
over here eventually I hope to see that
kind of come out of it and that the
little small that that particular read
it's not just a small farmer but it's
all that the the whole and compass of
farmers within the region that are
protected under those IPS in that
Appalachian origin that they're
protecting that product we want that
standard and we want to make that money
off that now you get people to realize
that like oh shit
Wow there's a lot of money here all we
got to do is make it work then it starts
clicking and some standards and
practices to it you know something
that's fucking sustainable you know
let's not eat the whole place up spit it
out
that would be and then I'd be kind of
happy to die after that one someone
maybe a couple screenplays definitely
tell stories but now that would be cool
you know be one of the old guys look
back 20 years from now and go yeah that
was the dude that was thinking out side
the box with the other people you know
up north that made something out of this
area now it's just tourists yeah yeah
whatever
do you know those oh geez that we're
planting in Temecula you know same with
Sonoma you know that had that dream hey
let's make this put these grapes here
and see what we're gonna get now look at
it you know it's you know we claim alive
yeah it's actually way better than I
thought it was gonna be pretty fun good
yeah California no it's decent but they
need to clean it up they need to accept
the ham there and let the HAMP clean up
the soil and the water and you know be
partners with the old system and let the
to flow and not fight each other they
both bring business people are gonna
still want their wine you know I imagine
they're scared of the millennial
generation growing out of you know
alcohol and all that but steep you know
it's here's what it is you had change
with the times you know constellation
Brad's is giving it a go but yeah poor
Billy got pissed away somewhere oh man
but yeah see see in the end yeah no it
was good good combo and all that stuff
good talking to you guys connecting
Dobbs next time y'all come have you guys
up there come check out this gym
yeah no it's a beautiful you come up if
you look at wine you know it does better
in Topanga we always like you know
that's a lot of people ask me like how
do you choose certain you know like when
you're going through your clones or your
planets or whatever I don't fuck with
clones because they don't make it out
there so much I mean no doubt but you
don't do what my seeds do and and I and
I they're like this is a little too
tough for me yeah things out pretty
young because it hardens them up you
know and a lot of people are like well
you know I want to keep it so I'm like
it's almost like character if you keep a
good person in a bubble of their whole
life yeah clothes under things it builds
this character and that's what happens
in the flower you know that's what those
terpenes are they're they're they're
expressions of character yeah you know
they're expressions of personality and
and that's what you get when you expose
that flower to those elements like if
you call someone how she chose her males
and she said just tell them all out in
the woods and you come back looking a
month later though well this is all
alive to take a feat you take a male and
you got them in a pot and you put them
out with the females right before it he
bursts and it makes them go fucking and
the females nuts and that's what that's
when you really start getting into
male/female and really start unlocking
science yeah