I don't give a shit what what terpene
profile you put together it is not the
same as a cannabis derived you can't get
the complexity straight and you can't
get the ratio straight and so ultimately
the the experience is diminished so what
we realized was that if we put in
commercial level
stripping operations I can then have
farmers who have locations that are
optimal for higher quality do my crude
production and then I can have farms
that have better situations to do my
Turk production and then I take your
cannabis I pull the Terps
the rest of the flower gets blown as
crude so this way you make crude money
you make Turk money the Terps now can
get infused with the crude from others
because you're you're having a radical
amount of product that can be created
from serbian infusion and so it starts
to let me find how do we stabilize
markets