so i'm sam from the grove uh we run a
science-based competition where you know
we're reliant on uh excellence in
breeding because everyone starts with
identical genetics and then they're
judged by lab results for total terp and
total
[Music]
thank you um so yeah i reached out to
peter because
it's our biggest year ever we're going
to eight states uh this podcast is
actually representing every single time
zone in the country
and we need quality breeders state by
state to give out these cuts to our
growers
we put them through the ringer you know
they have to meet certain metrics pass
certain tests pest inspections etc
it's an awesome group of guys i wanted
to get them all together although i had
to wear my by weed from women sure
because i'm looking for female like
ladies that do some breeding and
genetics for next year so hit us up
uh let's i guess go through
introductions uh that makes sense right
so
this weekend we just handed out clones
in michigan
michigan and oklahoma
and let's meet them first so
uh this begins on the east coast so
technically we're first so
i'll introduce ross from fresh seeds and
i don't know if we can hear if we can
get questions from people tuning in that
would be cool and then they can ask
anything they want except what the
mystery strain is flower time like we
can't talk about what they got but we
can get to know these breeders and
genetics partners so uh ross fresh coast
seeds our michigan partner
what's up
so ross what do you want to tell what
can you tell us about yourself your
process what you love about michigan
well those are pretty broad but um yeah
so i'm born and raised in michigan um 39
years old um
i guess uh
just how i got it even into into
cannabis i was younger you know and like
in high school hustling
bricks of weed you know doing the thing
right and i always had a passion for it
but then throughout life i did other
things and then i had a major back
injury in the bering sea so i came home
and uh just kind of had to rework my
whole life so um i got into like third
coast um garden and i worked with him
for a while
and then uh
doing my own thing and
i really never had any intention of
necessarily of breeding um but i was
like you know up at four in the morning
buying
thousands of dollars worth of seeds and
looking at all the lineages um
and uh
and one thing led to another and it took
me about six years to lock down like
nine females um and i don't know
i'm pretty picky when it comes to plant
selection um but i i came up with these
females and then like i was telling you
i had an experience just uh having a
conversation with the universe um
and i just got i was really sick of
doing production stuff and
and she gave me the idea of a fresh
coast seed company and starting a seed
company so within 24 hours i had
fresh coast seed company llc
and uh i moved out of the lake houses
and we went and bought
20 acres in bel air and
we started breeding immediately and i
had the right females to do it with
and everything and that was seven years
ago so
here we are now and
the brand has actually gotten way bigger
than what i can handle so i'm working on
that part right now um
but yeah so that's just kind of a little
rundown of how i got to where i'm at
right now
awesome thank you
yeah oh this is a cool layout love this
okay cool let's bring up robbie from
nerds genetics our oklahoma genetic
partner
welcome robbie hey trying to find an
angle that gets me in the camera here we
go
all right hey welcome everybody
um yeah so
um this year i did the uh the oklahoma
drop we did the colorado drop last year
um for the the clone selection um
you know the this year we we had a
little bit experience with the the
contest um so we we had a little bit of
i would say different parameters um when
we were selecting for the contest in
oklahoma knowing a lot more about how
the contest works um you know and a lot
of the things that we could potentially
see in the contest
um because yeah when we did our our
colorado one we we broke a couple
records you know both good and bad we
broke records
um am i not talking
sam can you hear me no we can hear you
there's just other people in the
background that i'm saying to mute
yourself because we hear everything
going on back there but you're fine i
hear you
sorry about that
uh i just got confused um anyway so yeah
we broke a couple records in colorado uh
one bad one for most hermes and one good
one for highest terps
so you know that's that's just how it
works sometimes
um but uh
when we went and had seen how the uh the
contest works and knew a lot more uh
about it
um you know it changed the way we
selected for it when i selected in
colorado i was really trying to select
for something that had the potential to
uh break some records um and when we did
it in oklahoma
we were really looking for something
that was going to be uh you know
something that could be a staple strain
out here something that was really
different from anything that
is being seen on any of the shelves out
here or uh you know any of the things
that uh
um are are sort of what is hitting the
the norm you know like oklahoma's a new
market so we're seeing a lot of the same
10 strains that get recycled out here um
so we we tried to bring something that
was going to be a totally different
flavor profile something that was going
to be a totally different
high than anything that is
is really being brought to the table
right now and so that's what we brought
for the the oklahoma on the show
oh sam you're muted
cool yeah so that's a good point robbie
thank you that like i mentioned we have
certain metrics that we ask all of you
guys to hit when we look at strains and
you know
who is that crunching
uh yeah so when one of those is
it can't be me is it
is it me
okay uh yeah so and one of those metrics
is like that we are looking for
something that's not widely on the
market because we take these six months
of the competition
you know hyping up all these growers
this mystery strain
everyone that's in a competition is
going to bother every single one of you
and say what is it tell me tell me
they'll be making their guesses and you
guys have to keep your mouth shut
because it's part of the fun
uh and we want to make sure it's
something cool so when it hits the
market at the end of the year it flies
off shelves i mean
hey dave
and uh so yeah it's that's one of the
metrics the other is you know we we do
pest and pathogen testing to make sure
these are very clean cuts as well
if uh people watching don't know what
hop sleet and viroid is i encourage you
to google it reach out to any of us here
i'm sure we can talk to you through all
that
so just to recap michigan oklahoma
dropped on sunday but you can still pick
up clones there this week only you can
just dm us or sign up at thegrowoff.com
and let's move on our next clone drop
will be in colorado our home state with
uh dark horse genetics and i'm going to
introduce caesar now who's doing that
one
we can hear you but your wi-fi is a
little choppy yeah that's nothing around
here
uh yeah if anything we do have the
genetics ready i
got them in the clown a few days ago so
i'm looking at them they're behind me
just uh looking for them i got way more
than i needed but i'd rather have more
than i need unless the negative
i love it so actually caesar i need to
ask you because we're getting close to
the number that you told me we had to
cut it off at do we have more
entries available or we got to cut it at
100. so there's 206 in the corner right
now assuming everyone roots uh
should have more than i need
then once i get a little closer to the
dead i could possibly feel more
comfortable about opening up to a little
bit more people
perfect all right we'll keep you all
posted i think we have like maybe 10
spots left if we're keeping at a hundred
but actually this is a good point so not
only do they have to get us cuts for the
you know all of the participants but you
have to grow more than you need so that
we have you know an even
uh crop for so that everyone's getting
the same thing so
a lot of challenges we throw at you guys
i appreciate you so much for doing this
so
uh the one after colorado is going to be
california and because it's the biggest
friggin state we have to do three clone
drops those are going to be in humble
oakland and san diego and i will
introduce daniel and dave from hendricks
farm now how much of us are in the frame
are we both in the frame yep
nice
yo this is dave i'm daniel
uh we're with hendricks nursery we're in
humboldt county
we're stoked to do this is our fourth
year doing the grow-off um
it's kind of our favorite and like most
unique challenge is get everybody
perfect unique clones on a date and keep
a mystery strain um
that you guys haven't seen before and i
think we did a really good job this year
we love working with uh sam and it's
really fun to be here on this call get
to see all the other breeders it's like
i wish i
i i was a fan of the girl off before we
ever were asked to be the nursery it
just seemed like the coolest thing to
compete in and uh we wish we could grow
all your guys genetics all the other
breeders out there it would be really
fun to go from state to state yeah we
don't do a strain swap
can we make that happen
[Laughter]
yeah i mean daniel you've been reaching
out to previous years
genetic partners and linking up with
them i thought that was so cool and like
the one person who was not able to be
here i was bummed we have uh like an sop
officer now um wendy kornberg from sun
abyss wrote up some sops so we're all
kind of on the same page everyone state
to state is getting you know similar
clones or just quality um and she could
not be here today
but and i totally lost my train of
thought where we were headed but uh
she's oh she's trying to grab one of
each of them because she's doing those
pest inspections she's sending folks to
do those for her
uh so she's gonna try to grow every
single one of them uh but if you all
wanna try to connect i think that would
be very fun too maybe do some crosses
for future grow-off projects that would
be very fun yeah yeah that's my favorite
part about this and it's cool to get the
contestants too
it's just interlinking with everybody
it's a good way to find genetics is just
working with the people that are growing
the stuff too so as well as the people
on this call but you know contestants as
well it's a lot of fun
for sure okay well i will help
facilitate that if i can uh
okay so next on the calendar
i know okay so virginia we're still
looking for a venue
uh but i'm gonna bring you up next
actually mario uh so this is an
interesting story oh and if anyone
watching has a friendly venue for us to
do a clone drop i'm looking for
something near the dc area please dm us
email me sam thegrowof.com
uh but this is an interesting story so
we met mario because he won our like
beauty pageant bud battle challenge
and
it was with something really interesting
obviously everyone liked the photo and
they knew what the strain was because we
advertised that as part of the battles
and i said hey we're interested in doing
a virginia grow off do you want to
release la hepha
as the mystery strain it's the first
time we've ever told anyone what it was
so
uh the first ever like purposeful
release of the mystery strain uh so
mario from eaton's stars on mars welcome
hey what's up
how are you today good all right so um
yeah i mean it's been pretty interesting
with this whole thing that went down
um you know i didn't expect to win but
that was going against somebody who had
like i guess they had like 30 000 some
followers
you know i'm here just starting up my ig
like a couple years ago and
just having fun with it um i've been
growing for for a minute
i know in virginia we're going on a year
soon
um when it comes to home bro but
i've been growing a little bit longer
than that so it's not a va it's i don't
want to
say like i've been doing some hot shit
you know what i'm saying or something
but
um yeah i've been i've been doing a lot
of here and there throughout the dmv
area if
if that's what you want to call it
pretty much because it's you know like a
maryland dc
virginia thing so um we're all connected
it's a lot of good growers out here
um a lot of good genetics as well so
it's exciting
to just be a part of this little family
right here
and uh see how things go so um
especially with la hepha she's
i've been growing her for four years now
so i've i've got her really dialed in uh
so that picture was uh
like right at its peak where she's been
amazing you know i mean just uh
getting a lot of clones off for her
trying to like branch her out a lot but
um
he has just been amazing man this whole
thing is uh i'm excited for it
especially for virginia because i know
here it's
it's a lot of low-key folks out here but
they've been growing for a minute but
for me i think it's time for them to
just come out and have some fun
uh with this competition
perfect thank you so yes uh we think we
have a venue but if any again if
anyone's watching know some virginia
folks let us know
okay so next on the calendar is
maine i believe wait hold up one second
i was muted i was trying to get your
attention so hit up lou
because he has he has a venue in
virginia
yeah lou and i are chatting the venue
yeah we're yes i'm talking to lou we're
hoping to collab on a gene traders uh at
the virginia clone drop for the grow off
so that would be extra special it would
just require a little bit more space and
420 friendly venue where we're just need
to hand out clones so yes thank you ross
uh and if any and i'm assuming we have a
lot of growers watching if you don't
know what a gene traders event is
they're awesome it's a pop-up seed and
clone event where you can just get the
latest and greatest in genetics they're
all over the country and they're awesome
um okay so next on our calendar is may
or sorry june 25th we will be in maine
with bangladesh farms and i j uh peter
hopefully you can put john and jason on
the screen at the same time
i think that's possible
well while they work on it okay we got
john on screen
and then jason
and jason you're muted by the way
brick gotcha there we go
nice so yeah um a little background on
us i guess i've been playing with this
plant for about 25 years pretty
seriously did a couple breeds for
some outdoor folks here in maine since
we have such short seasons and
wet finishes they really have to be some
early finishers and very hardy plants so
that was kind of like my first
addition on my what i was trying to
breed for this area
and kind of threw together some really
depo g lines with the fotea stuff um
came to this farm kind of started a new
awakening and passion for this plan
after taking about a good year off um
before we got the 7200 square foot spot
i'm up and ready to go so now we're
excited because we just popped about 700
plus seeds and just
do the
fur
see
oh wi-fi that's the mix of
oh i must have lost it huh
yeah
we lost you at the 700 seeds
oh yeah so now uh with this 700c project
hopefully this will give everybody a
good view into what we're working with
moving forward
um so the selection that we'll be using
will be from that 700 plus seed hunt so
we're really excited to see what this uh
results should be because uh we're
really fresh and working with it now as
it is so um
we'll be you know pushing these strains
moving forward so i think it'll be fun
to see the test results and see how
people deal with them
oh yeah
100 percent
yeah johnny get anything bad
no i mean for me it's kind of like
obviously i started smoking really young
started slinging um originally from
boston started slinging packs in college
so kind of giving the kids
in the area something good um
used to go up to maine to grab the stuff
it ended up moving up there
kind of um
passionate about the plant so ended up
hooking up with jason and we just
you know this is our passion project and
we've taken our time for the last two
years building the place out making sure
everything was done right
and
you know making the decision to pop the
seeds was the best thing we ever did
because we didn't have to worry about
anything going around
um and we don't have to worry about
taking anyone's cuts into to get going
and then end up with a virus or bugs or
anything like that so it was a good
decision we're just excited to kind of
be part of this thing right and um
you know june 25th at urban garden
centers in maine we're gonna
have an awesome drop so we're looking
forward to it seeing what everyone grows
perfect thank you guys so much and then
i'm right after maine i'm scooting right
down to massachusetts uh but i will say
our main sign ups i know there are like
thousands of growers in maine uh i don't
know where they're at yet so we gotta
hustle some some mainers out to pick
these cuts up so
yeah maybe some more post and marketing
on our end and we can get them things
kicked up
perfect
so yeah absolutely
maine's been bugging us to come there
for years so this should be a good
turnout once they uh get signed up and
everything so after maine i'm scooting
right down to
worcester mass
uh where our breeder
fat cat select seeds is providing the
cut this year welcome travis
job i think you're muted
you're muted travis
oh there you go is that better
yeah so like kim said i'm travis from
fat cat select seeds uh my brother ian
and i uh do all the breeding the whole
everything right from start to finish we
um
we called it select seeds because we
actually um individually look at every
single seed before we sell and package
them
so they've been all hand selected every
single one
so to get to a brief history
we grew up on martha's vineyard
which is an island off the coast
we've been isolated for years and years
and years away from the rest of the
world really for genetics
um and we still are uh really out here
um people really don't know what's going
on with the new strains
anything that's happening out there with
the popularity so um
things have kind of evolved a little
differently out here
i could say from the beginning of
breeding it's been growing up wasn't me
who started it was the previous
generation
who showed me how to um
make seeds at a young age how to um
select the better plants how to um
you know pick the best ones and go
forward with them so
so we've always been interested in uh
breeding genetics uh right from the
beginning not only in cannabis
i've done breeding in other fruits
vegetables and things like that
um so cannabis has always been very fun
though
and something that out here um
genetics were very hard to come by
um so
you collected them as best you could you
uh when you found something you saved it
uh you tried to keep your clones you
tried to keep your seeds as as best you
can because you do not want to lose them
because sometimes they're almost
impossible to replace
uh now that you know things have changed
a little bit we can access strains and
clones through these places all over the
world um
it's a lot easier with legalization and
with the way things are going
uh so you know right from the beginning
of legalization we were interested in
having our strains tested it's the first
thing we did we wanted to know what we
were growing we wanted to know what our
thc percentages were what our terpenes
were
we wanted to know what plants we liked
uh what we didn't why we liked them
there were some plants you know you just
don't know what terpenes are in them
until you have them tested and when you
do then you know
uh which is why uh you know the grow-off
is
really really a great competition it's
really in in reality the greatest
phenotype hunt of all uh considering
that the phenotype is just the um
environmental expressions of the plant
so each individual clone would be the
genotype but the phenotype is up to each
individual grower to create on their own
through their fertilizer and their grow
rooms uh so it's the ultimate contest
really the the top that you could do to
be a grower um people say phenotype hunt
but
fido time pun is really
um
the same clone grown differently uh when
you're searching through seeds it's
really a genotype hunt but um
it's really just a common word that's
kind of misconception
so
um you know
creating genotypes
is uh what we do what we look for um
we take uh basically look to create uh
what we call apex strains
uh an apex strain i would consider
a strain that uh best represents the
characteristics of
uh whatever you're looking to do say
it's a blueberry or bubble gum
uh you're looking to make the best best
tasting best characteristics of
blueberry that you can find and it may
not be
everybody's favorite
uh that's where the breeder comes in uh
the breeder picks his favorite and uh
when a breeder gets a reputation locally
or wherever people trust in your nose
your what you pick what you like for
your plants so you get a following and
um that's really how it started with uh
fat cat and breeding
was um
a following of people and wanting to
make
better strains
and ones that were true to how you
wanted them to taste if i bought
blueberry seeds i want them to taste
like blueberry and good blueberry and if
i buy bubble gum it should taste like
bubble gum so uh i really like the
classic strains creating them recreating
them and uh trying to make them um as
best as we can
so
sam
i love that because um blueberry i
started in the industry co-founding a
seed company and we
crea or we reproduced uh dj shorts
blueberry as one of our first packs it
was that's a killer strain i love that
one
um awesome well thank you travis and i
i'm sorry i think we got um mixed up
adding questions from the chat we'll uh
start doing a round table but we have
one more reader to introduce uh last and
certainly not least i'm so excited for
this one because at the end of the
season we're all gonna need a vacation
and uh
we're gonna come visit jason on oahu for
our very first hawaii grow off
so welcome jason aloha
aloha everybody um i'm honored to be
here humbled
great people are around us and we're
just seeing this over and over again in
the cannabis industry this really cool
connection whether it's instagram or
whatever about all coming together that
used to be
old smugglers old growers old breeders
all that good stuff it's super fun and
um
it's just such a euphoric life nowadays
it's really cool
i'm in hawaii we're kind of stuck in
time a little bit but we're getting
there we're still at a stacking license
kind of
formula so
you can grow 10 plants per person
and there's no limit to where you can
how many plants how many cards you can
have at a site
they've tried to control that and try to
regulate it and try to enforce it but
it's never worked so we've officially
become
the largest patient-based farm in hawaii
with over 2000 patients on our farm
it's happening because we have
dispensaries that are open that aren't
providing
affordable medicine good medicine and
access to medicine for medical patients
so uh that's where we came along and
you know started rolling with the
affordable ounce we call it the 150
onion so kind of exciting
um and then we bring you know blueberry
back into the picture and
man a good blueberry is hard to beat man
i remember i was in vancouver about 10
years ago when mark emery was kind of
doing his thing and there was a lot of
short blueberry around man and when you
hit that thing man you better hold on
man that thing would just kind of get
you all like whoa reset so very excited
um we reached out to sam the girl off
because we're just trying to get people
connected here empowered
working with policy makers getting the
growers out of the closet to recognize
that hey if we don't do something here
we're going to run into a lot of
problems other states are having where
their big business is going to take over
and control our growth sites and stuff
like that so we're moving pretty fast
here and i think we're doing a good job
we're we're lobbying you know what i
mean that's what we're doing and we're
trying to open up thousands of local
based cooperatives rosin makers
everything around here and we're just
following maine that's what we're trying
to do right now so i'm trying to throw
maine on them as hard as we can we have
a medical program here
it's pretty much a failure it was
established in the year 2000 i don't
know if you guys do but hawaii was the
first place to pass medical cannabis and
the last place to get dispensaries 16
years later so it's always been a
conundrum um but yeah so we met sam and
we just i said hey well let's just try
and get a little grow-off going here and
see what we can do in oahu
i'm not a breeder i have bread many
times before but i would definitely not
call myself a breeder i'm definitely a
grower we have about a 20 000 square
foot site here without like i said 2 000
patients
um
my grow-off kind of plant and what we're
going with was a humbling experience by
meeting um
king lancelot the eighth which was uh uh
in the eighth generation of king
kamehameha that was still alive and he
passed away a couple years ago from
cancer and handed me some seeds
i can't tell you what they were because
then i'll give it away
but um there was some special stuff in
it so we ran about 100 seeds we found
some really cool old-school stuff in it
some blueberry and some cheesy stuff and
so that's kind of what we're going right
now we're going to try and run
those clones and then kind of like and
in memory of king lancelot so that's
kind of how we're rolling with it and uh
we're really excited it's definitely an
old
mercene pinene
old school strain for sure there's
something going on with it and uh i
haven't smelt that smell in a long time
so that's kind of what we're up to and
what we're excited about um
in a in a short story
that's i'm so excited jason's like
so good at just driving community around
just what he's doing and bringing
growers in and we're you're throwing a
party during our clone drop right so
that'll be fun and
yeah we do we try to run a couple uh
patient awareness days or patient
appreciation days because the patients
are what makes our site
it's just been insane you guys seeing
people come to the gate and just saying
hey we don't have access to medicine and
we're like here you go and
now we've got a lot of great things on
our side you know we don't see
crazy narcotics compliance checks it's
all gone now so we've really found the
right people the right lawyers the right
lobbyists to really take control of this
and start driving in the right direction
so people are not suffering you know
what i mean there's
there's so you know
i'm sure a lot of you guys started like
i did just growing we for our friends
and having fun and really not
understanding maybe in my opinion the
whole medicinal effect of cannabis and
now that you start seeing people coming
through the gate that can't sleep at
night and doing this and doing that and
trying to find a remedy for them it's
totally transformed me as a person and
um
it's it's it's badass i mean it's just
exciting and um and it gives you a lot
of leverage to kind of go back to the
people the lobbyists in our state or the
politicians in our state that are still
stuck in the reefer madness world and
just going hey you're looking at it all
the wrong way you got people suffering
out here and you need to move quickly
you know and so yeah we do not on
tangent but we do we did our first
medical
uh patient day uh about a month ago had
about 400 people and
had some live uh local reggae stars and
legal jordy some fun stuff and it went i
it was
you know how it is you guys when you get
these things together and they're safe
and sound and people walking around with
joints in their mouth and don't fear
uh persecution
it's just it's just irie it's just so
empowering so it was really cool so
we're hoping to have this next one on
another party
july 9th
and uh hand out some clones and see what
we can going on here we got a shit load
of growers in hawaii tons of them
they're all hiding out and starting to
make their way forward and uh we're
actually even starting to kind of hooey
up to kind of gang up with them to get
their flower to our farm to
kind of showcase them and start
branding them for the future so when
things kind of open up they already have
a great name and they're they're well
known and and they can make their living
off this wonderful plant and still help
people so yeah
well since uh you're the last clone drop
of the season i would i'll invite like
everyone on the call if you're
participating in the grow-off like let's
go to this party together i'll be there
we'll hand out some clones and you've
all earned it after all the hard work
that you're putting into doing this for
us like please let's go and yeah and you
guys you guys can pitch a tent don't
even get a hotel room just come up and
stay on the farm and
kick it and have fun and you guys are
all welcome man it's really you know i'm
very familiar with a lot of the breeders
on this uh
podcast right now and a lot of new ones
and you guys see what's happening you
got to have
breeders you can trust that you can get
clones and seed from
the seed industry is just out of control
so it's nice that we're all starting to
wrap up and kind of gain energy together
so we get
legitimacy and saying hey you know this
is the real deal we i got it right here
you know just like whether it's a cut
from
mendo or you know you're it's really
exciting you know what i mean so we're
we're excited we love bringing genetics
in there's definitely a lot of hawaii
genetics but as you guys know cannabis
didn't show up to hawaii until like the
late 50s early 60s surfers vietnam vets
so you know all the strains are from
outside of hawaii
although they've been here for a little
while so there's still some hidden stuff
around you know and um and a lot of it
lost as well and you'll hear every story
from someone here who grew as a kid i
mean this place is just
a cannabis
kingdom it's amazing to see like talk to
people who are my age or older that were
growing
durbin hash plant and sugarcane fields
in the 60s or 70s you know and you're
like what was that all about you know
those seeds aren't around anymore but
you kind of kind of know probably what
they were fooling with with some of the
old legends in place and the creators of
durban poison and some of the ghani's
that were being smuggled over here and
closed from back in the day from some of
the legends so yeah it's really it's
really exciting
cool all right well hopefully some of
you guys can come out and join us and if
not we're actually doing
for the first time ever all of the
awards are going to be in vegas on
november 15th that's like the first
night of the big convention that we
don't have to tag
uh
so yeah november 15th we'll be
announcing winners from all of these
states uh at a private party in vegas if
you're participating in the grow-off you
have free entry all these guys will
hopefully be there
um so that's it and then we'll also be
live streaming and peter maybe we'll do
it on here so that folks can watch and
see who won from all these awesome
states
and someone had asked who can enter
and uh i i made a point in the last two
years to make sure we could uh open this
up to homegrow caregivers not just
commercial farms we originally started
it was just commercial and then realized
that you know the homegrown caregiver
market is huge and a lot of them want
employment in the industry and so
by going through a grow off and some of
them don't which is totally fine but
they also grow fire weed so we figured
um if we can get the homegrown market
participating they have a resume item if
they win and then uh they can kind of
move themselves up in the industry if
they choose to but they are also their
test scores are off the charts so
uh in i think every single one of these
states homegrown caregiver is open
uh depending on metric transfer stuff
commercial might not be available in
your state
um so yeah val you should definitely
enter because uh homegrow is available
in all of the states that we're in this
year
so what should we chat about boys
[Laughter]
um what questions we had a question
about how many males you go through
before you choose one to breed with
and i know
there we go okay thank you
you go through until you find what
you're looking for
how many do you have
a thousand thousand
all day got the space and the time
you'll see it when you know like that
structure that stem rub
um you know they'll just the way the
leaf the complexion of the leaf the
waxiness of the plant you can see like
how like the plant health overall based
on how you're feeding people to kind of
dictate what sort of expressions you
might be able to pull out of it too so
um and always like i always just try and
make sure that people finish those mails
like don't just wait until they drop but
see what they do when they're done you
know
but you don't have the space for it and
can't get it you know can't get it
segregated from any place it shouldn't
have seeds in it obviously that's a
little tough but
well i think if you have the opportunity
being able to see the male plant flower
out to completion before you uh ever hit
it to another girl really is a a really
beneficial thing
there's a lot of things that you see
during that process that you don't see
otherwise you don't see how the the
plant expresses fire you don't see
how the plant like really uh
continues to to stack flowers unless you
really run that male completion
and i'm also a big firm believer of
putting them on revenge so let me finish
and re-imagine them and you know you'll
find out a lot about them too and bring
things and a lot of it comes down to
looking at the progeny and like what
came out of that you know because like
with the magnum opus breed so one of the
magnum really pulled through every one
of the crosses there wasn't one real
dominant female out of that group until
i
selected fur for a male that would
actually pass those straight so um that
really kind of you know time effort and
your dedication to what you're really
looking for you know well that's the
thing none of us can read the future and
so like if you don't watch the project
and you don't see which trades are
dominant then you have no idea like what
you were moving with in the first place
it's a mystery pundit you know it's like
there's so many different areas you
could go especially with the paulies and
the hybrids out there just there's so
much variation in recessive dominance
especially once you start talking about
felil generations and moving further
into the line
i would definitely uh stress test as
well with the certain strains like
you don't want to hurt like the smallest
amount of stress will cause it to herman
then you'll pretty much promote that
into the progeny into the next
generation so that's something that i
want to promote into the next uh
generation seeds so definitely stress
testing more as well to like treat them
like shit absolute garbage
well to me that is testing
you know testing is treating them like
shit and seeing what they can do with
because at the end of the day
you know like you can be the best grower
in the world and get my seeds or you can
be the worst grower in the world and get
my seeds and i'm not gonna know what you
are i'm just gonna sell you the pack of
seeds and then we're going to find out
afterwards when you do your stress test
yeah
and not everybody's dialed in either you
know you got to kind of play to the
environment and actually like you know
look a little bit deeper than just how
the plant reacted and maybe take a look
at what you did to that plant through
that situation
like i'm not always look i feel like a
lot of times people come up with excuses
for the plant or why it didn't work for
them where they might you need to look
at why you didn't work for the plant you
know
and don't be afraid to throw stuff away
too
you know don't hang on to everything and
a lot of it you know it isn't special
that they all are
special hang on them get attached to
them you know if they're not always
stronger if it's not no game changing
like
terpene profile or like yield or
anything else like that then it's
probably not worth keeping around like
you only want it's like
it's got to do all the things it's got a
veg well it's got a clone well it's got
a flower well it's got to give badass
bag appeal it's kind of smell good it's
got to get you higher than shit it's got
to do it all sometimes
and that doesn't mean that it's always
going to win
of the profile it's smoke it's pretty
much like very hard grow but
now everything should be completely
viable straight for it to stick around
because it's a lot
that aren't virtually probably
gotta earn those terps
beginning to know what you're looking
for if you don't know what you want what
you want a question what you're looking
for you're just looking to
just choose the one that maybe impressed
you the best one of the bunch but if you
know what you're looking for
in your seat then you can hear you know
to what to
what to pick
you know we use a method where we uh we
grade every single plant
we give it a one through ten score um we
do it sometimes every two days we'll
give a score on its stock smell on its
leaf smell its resin production it's
mode spacing bigger in size
it's resin smell it's flower size
compactness
all of the different characteristics of
the plant throughout its flower every
two days we'll give it a grade
by the end of the
flower you've got
an average of 15 different ratings for
each plant you average out all those
grades
the top one sticks out
guaranteed every time because you rated
it maybe 10 times and it gets a 9 or 10
every time for smell and you know it
gets uh
you know a seven or eight foreign
so be careful if you're a grower and
want to become a breeder because here's
your people right here giving you a
warning man
and you want to reach out to the feeders
if you're a grower you want to get your
stuff from the breeders you don't want
to be a breeder grower and try to pull
that off because that is a lot of work
and that's what we've left i'm like no
no no no no i'm reaching out to the
breeders that's what they specialize in
that's what they're taking all the
meticulous notes and trying to find all
the great crosses and you will save
yourself a lot of time and frustration
so yeah no it's time and dedication
right there
it's a lot it's a long process and a lot
of heartache
throwing a lot of crazy shit lately
people do what we got rid of
they
you know it is you know we built the
ferrari so now it's time to drive this
thing and uh start making the hard
choices
guarantee that whatever you select is
going to find like almost gay change and
so
when
opus number 456 they're going to be like
well that was the best of any one that
anybody could possibly find because they
went through that many seats
only takes one but you got a lot to go
through to get there
and then the process of running backs
said
once that you want to keep you know and
that's that's another year running back
two to three times to know what you're
really working with you know oh here's a
question that i've always had and wanted
to ask the readers but um do you guys
find that
you find your better expressions or
truer expressions to your keys or it's
from your clone testing
anybody
i can see i feel like seed runs always
the best run but i feel like you get the
honest expression when you're on your
second
like i've been third of just trying to
stay away from my seed my actual seed
hunts and actually do my first clone
hunts as like the baseline for animation
well that's what you're gonna get in the
commercial garden you're never going to
run that seed run again you know you
only get one shot at it so like if you
don't have something that does good in
the clone generation then you're screwed
afterwards
and i've i've actually been i've
actually been taking clones off of said
seed plant running that first
yeah yeah that's kind of what i've been
fine enough that worked really well for
me
yeah yeah
i've never been like 700 though
that's mine that's what that's happening
you can't keep 700
too oh yeah i think he was just saying
i'm holding all those clones back as the
process goes so now now in this day and
age like you know we've got our tissue
culture lab set up so i get this tissue
culture everything and it takes up zero
floor space for me you know and then i
can just eliminate them out of the
refrigerator
propagation like this much space like
700 for you
you know sometimes you should gotta
trust if you're selling someone a six
pack of seeds
absolutely i hundred percent trust in
the genetics with a six pack of seeds
they're gonna come up with something
that's top top quality oh hands down you
know we sweep 700 seeds those are 50
different strains
yes you have one strain you know i mean
at 10 seeds you know if it's a quality
cross and quality genetics
you really
shouldn't have to go through that many
to get a really really really top top
notch
now you i say that but you know i do
like three four five packs of some
people's gear just to find like that one
and they do exist like you're gonna find
you know out of every pack you're gonna
find a good expression out of like 50 50
parents um maybe some of them other
mother dominance or maybe some of the
males dominance but it really does you
know we can we can sit here and say that
you can find fire and impact but to find
one that's going to hit all expression
whether it's
nose look um bag appeal smell taste
growth rates veg like that's gonna take
a little bit more digging than just one
pack i don't care whose pack of seeds
i'm going through
it takes a while and you know when when
they go through a thousand seven hundred
seeds you guarantee you found a good one
oh hell yeah well yeah i think one
thousand seed plant once in the past i
found like
10 expressions of 10 things
you know like so there would be one
phenotype or or one expression that i
would see you know 20 times 100 times 50
times whatever but it would be like six
or seven different things that i would
see across the whole thousand and then
it was really just about picking out of
those six and seven things which is the
winner of the six and seven
yeah i think the point is that you're
gonna find bomb scenes from a great
breeder
we can go back as early as reserve a
providence
and stuff that sounds you get a 10-pack
of that man it's just like oh shit this
is crazy you know what i mean just game
changers so those were packs those
reserva packs you had six seeds and
every one of them was the same
like there was some homogeneity in those
facts like there were early
really big specific strains go into the
world go to like f4 x5 whatever now it
just seems because the end user's demand
is changing so much if it doesn't
instagram
if it doesn't load on instagram then
they don't want it and it's like most
people there's almost no one to take
certain selections
like that because people's demand keeps
changing instagrams keeps instagram
keeps making everybody's uh demand
change so fast by the time you work with
strengths
and you can smell it and you can smoke
it and it changes you so
you gotta have like i don't know
breeders just have to
you have to be partly crazy because you
have to know that you're going on this
like
10-year journey be an old-ass man yeah
and so yeah just i it all depends on
what you're
trying to create because then it tells
you if you need a million males or a
hundred females or you know
you're doing acres or whatever you're
looking for because sometimes you're
looking for that really rare thing
sometimes you're trying to improve your
consistency
yeah i like the 10 pack that's a pretty
fair way to look at though i don't know
where
well that's
for whatever reason that's what they
want
but at the end of the day the people
that are on this hall are generally not
interested
in you know
[Laughter]
i think i think that's pretty cool too
is when you get that pack and there's a
homogeneity that you know it's been done
right yeah you just know hey man
i'm gonna ban her back i'm getting this
i know i'm gonna get something right
you know i mean that's what you know
people are watching this be careful who
you're working with and how you're
selecting seeds the market's wide open
right now and i think it's the most
important part of bringing the peers
together to go hey who's who's doing
what and who put the time in so they get
you know
paid properly and um
you know announced properly you know
what i mean that's that's important
you know and to get purple to breed in
the reds we just came out with a brand
new red flower
we are all crazy
and uh we're also uh holders and
protectors of the seats so we all have
to have those i mean
and we should definitely think about
um
what we can do together the swap or you
know some shit for next year's girl offs
and the next year's after that
i think that would be really cool
you know like i can't wait to see where
this actually goes in the next 5-10
years
our entry this year is 50 bucks it used
to be hundreds of dollars and we just
said let's get as many hours as we
possibly can
all uh have a good one let's all get in
touch
man have a great day me too
yeah i mean we need to hop up too that's
that's cool um
all right cool peter join me for the the
end of this
there's space on the call now peter we
get to see your smiling face
what's up peter
all right yeah i was just trying to say
like you said you know we don't have any
female genetic partners on the call uh i
want to see them i want to see more
women wearing our wrestling belts for
your championship uh we do a social
equity grant so
you know we're looking for more bypoc
women-owned veteran if previous
incarceration entries get 50 off a 50
entry fee like i just want as many
people doing this as possible because
you can see just from like the genetic
side of things this is a community
that's what we do is get growers
together within their own communities
and then you know connect state to state
until it's federally legal and then we
can do one all together you know the
the conglomerate that you guys all make
together from all the different strains
everybody knows seeds are federally
legal right so we can now
the mail you can send them the u.s
postal service you can bring the
campaigns on votes fly with them i do
that every day i really never did that i
did before
never done it probably for 20 years
the u.s postal service is the biggest
drug dealer
yeah let's let's remember all of our
badass growers are incarcerated right
now too so let's get them out of there
yeah yeah all day
what
peter do we have any other questions
that came through i wasn't quite
yeah let me just mute uh
i'm gonna mute everyone for a second and
then uh all right so
evidently the audio is a little better
and uh as i was joking the the people on
youtube probably didn't appreciate it
but i was like it sounds great in the
stream yard
um
yeah i i think well
from me i mean the the first two people
uh kind of talked about like themselves
uh like they're kind of intent as
breeders and kind of if we could just
quickly go around everyone else and
you know i breed for medical i breed for
you know i play with land race i breed
for
the hype market i
you know like specific terpene profiles
and i breed for kind of what i like and
this is what i personally like uh
you guys can just kind of go around the
horn
or jason since you don't breed what do
you like to smoke personally
you know you guys gonna laugh i'm like
an old hippie green crack guy man i i
don't know but i'm just a goofy i like
that goofy high
you know um i mean i can i can throw him
down but i'm more of a green crack kind
of goofy guy you know what i mean
a lot of stuff strong a little strong
for me i'm you know i'm not quite the
smoke dog i used to be but um yeah i
would say
the skunks man i love the skunks and
some some of the skunks that really show
a little more sativa in them you know
what i mean and uh yeah anybody got any
of that green crack hiding around i'd
love to see that again so the original
you're up i'm up can you guys hear me
all right cool so uh you know our
project has always been to breed for
hash so we we breed mostly for terpenes
and uh secondary cannabinoids
um the like and then how that presents
into uh
extracts is is really what what our
interest level has been for for the last
many years um
and so you know a lot of our a lot of
our stuff has lots of cbd and cvg and
thcva and things like that and and has a
minor cannabinoids and then there
there's a lot of interesting turpoint
there are terpenes and flavonoids that
come
in our stuff too so that we can make
better
and when you do smoke hash what kind of
flavor profiles do you personally like
in hash i like fruit
in weed i like gas
so you know it kind of depends on what
i'm going for but um you know that is
especially rosins and things lemons and
berries are are where it's at for me
it's my turn
so one of my favorite terps is that the
question
no just kind of what i mean that's part
of it but kind of what what do you breed
for like what do you like to explore and
focus on in your projects and then
personally what do you like smoking
so currently right now i have uh
spritzer that was the 2020 grow off
strain
that is a strain that i'm in the process
of making a feminized seeds from so i
reverse the spritzer and i'm going to
make a bunch of new crosses but what i
had in mind for this was uh making a
hash line like spritz is known to wash
like around six or seven percent return
with some crazy high return on the press
so i pretty much wanted to
make a line that's going to be pretty
much hash washers unique tert profiles
breeding strains specifically for
connoisseurs
the aficionados the cannabis
cognoscentis out there i kind of wanted
to do some a little bit of both like the
cookies to cookies and then the cookies
cross the non-cookie stuff like oh geez
and chems and sours and stuff like that
skittles so try and get some different
uh
new terps in the mix right now the most
anticipated one that i got right now at
the top two is probably like the
hazelnut cream to spritzer and then the
african hazel eleven disperser that
african haze 11 if you have never tried
that that's from uh bronson farms one of
my favorite hazes period like an 11 12
week haze but this is like amazing
flavor like if you ever heard a pif or
had any kind of pif terps definitely
you'd like the african haze 11 so that
cross to the spritzer should definitely
produce some new unique turps into the
market which i'm definitely looking
forward to
hope it wasn't too choppy
there you go good
yes
the reason why um
what i breed for it started out as just
you know personal satisfaction uh the
challenge
of making something that was just
amazing or not just amazing maybe maybe
even the best
um being from an island we're we're very
localized and when someone has the best
it spreads really quickly through the
whole island that they've got the best
so it's always been fun and a challenge
has always been fun when people have
told me of anything that you can't grow
that that doesn't grow here
oh well that sounds like a challenge to
me sounds like i'm going to grow it and
i grow mainly outdoor so growing outdoor
i have to grow a huge variety the
seasons are crazy out here on the island
the humidity is out of control it's
probably one of the most inhospitable
growing environments in the whole
country
uh so you know i i have to have up to 18
plus strains outdoors all times and that
sometimes you'll lose
six strains in full so
breeding has to do a lot with the
finding the strains that work finding
the right ones and the challenge is
always great you know it's always fun to
pick something and say i'm going to make
this
and then go make it i don't find the
strands first sometimes i pick
what i want to make i want to make
something that smells like bananas
then i have to go find through so many
strains to find the male and the female
that actually smell that way to put them
together so breeding a lot of it is is a
challenge it's a lot the personal
satisfaction and it's the fun of it
finding something new something
spectacular when you give it to someone
and they go whoa it blows their mind
that's why we do it
oh well for me i it's
i'm not much of a breeder like everybody
here so it's a privilege to be even with
you guys um i'm more of like uh your
average consumer you know i have a few
packs from a few you guys here so
um for me i just love the hunt
um
if i do like something that's gonna drop
i'm gonna get two packs of it pop it see
if i can find something out of two or
three packs
i'm just that type of consumer so
for me i'm just having fun just looking
for those phenos and uh that's my big
thing just trying to have fun with it
popping everybody's seeds whenever i get
an opportunity to see somebody's like
work i'll reach out to ask um
for me it it doesn't hurt to ask so
the
whatever's out there i'm gonna ask and
i'm gonna try and get it i've even flown
out to
california a couple of times for some
clone drops
uh for me it's just having fun man and
trying to bring that shit over here to
like the the east coast side and dmv
area
and what do you personally like to smoke
uh right now i'm honestly stuck on a
banana cream cake crossfit jealousy from
a sea junkie
uh that shit is uh
shit's fucking crazy as flower or hash
it's flower yeah flowery up i went out
there and grabbed a clone for the drop
and
yeah it's probably one of the biggest uh
positives i've i've done since i've been
growing you know so that was a big thing
but yeah it's it's really stuck in my
library right now so it's rotations
heavy
all right let me do
all right say what's going on guys you
hear me the main crew
hey what's going on peter can you guys
hear me
yeah yeah we can't hear you bud nice
yeah i'm primarily a gas head i like
those ogs chems the sour that funk um
you know um but uh lately i've been
really kind of getting into the skittle
surfs um there's a few um cookie runs um
crosses that we've been finding lately
in the in this seed hunt that have
really started to open my mind to those
candy terps once again i remember trying
that back in 2016 at the emerald cup
with the turf hogs kind of threw that
out there and that was one of those
terps that just always stuck with me so
i love the candy terps i'm primarily a
gas head
i breed i breed for flavor flavor pretty
much um solely
effect as well we're looking for some
things that can help people medicinally
i did a couple cbd projects that really
helped a lot of crohn's patients and ibs
patients so we're trying to bring some
of that back as well but
primarily for terps and uh short
flowering times and hearty hearty plants
for this main weather
yeah
i'm jason's apprentice so i'm kind of
like
shadowing him through this whole process
which has been
unbelievable to watch but
i'm a big citrus guy and we have some
serious citrus coming down
so i'm looking forward to that and i've
kind of fallen in love with
the kawaii candy from 808 that stuff's
like gas candy all day long
so
anything with gas or citrus is kind of
my game and
especially on the exhale
i had to throw on a hat everyone in the
comments
[Laughter]
without a hat on
there you go you got a beard you can
throw on to
keeps the sun off of us
that's right
um well i'll answer what i'm smoking
obviously don't breed because
who would have the time after everything
else we're doing but uh
ice um preserving some of the hype train
from the last colorado cup with uh
some boveda packs so smoking on that and
then jake's cousin is this awesome
grower
down in crested butte i have no idea
what he brought us but it's awesome i
uh and he's unfortunately not allowed to
compete because we're a fair competition
and family or sorry family members are
allowed to uh join the grow off
unfortunately
maybe we can just do a friends and
family one there you go
so all right so any other
chat questions
someone asked about auto seeds i saw at
one point um and we've been asked to do
competitions
and i the
wrapping my brain around that you know
everyone gets a lottery ticket do they
pop do do they not like that's why we do
the clone thing uh but i am curious they
all have opinions on autos
i have opinions
lots of okay fun if i need some bumper
crop in my veg or an early like july
crop maybe but dude night owl's always
been it's kind of some of my go-to or
mephisto
yeah yeah
guys
but uh daz actually just moved up here
to maine so we've been kind of chatting
back and forth about a few things but i
trust his work a lot
um but i feel like as far as the
competition style it might be
something where you might give somebody
sick leads to kind of uh maybe maybe
everybody gets to make their selection
out of a 16 block
rather having to have like one
plant to kind of move forward with so to
speak but yeah but then how do you judge
it because like it can't be tested
because like one fino is going to test
higher than another finance but he can't
clone an autoflower
you damage the roots just once twice
like
there's really no way to have like a
baseline on that
you know autoflower and they don't they
just quote have the uh
they don't have what the regular
the photo
they don't really have those
capabilities so it would be tough but
you'd probably just have to do like the
best selection out of everybody's pack
of seeds and kind of hope that you got a
good selection but i mean as analytical
results it would be kind of a toss up
but
do you guys read much autoflower
i've i've done it several times and i do
regular autoflower i do i mean i've done
it a lot and i have some really cool
autoflowers you guys want to try them
out i have a rainbow mix which is like
i've got purple blacks reds blues greens
in the mix
so you'll get have a great beautiful
garden you know yeah where are you
where are you on the island where are
you on the vineyard
uh west hillsbury it's like right in the
middle i'll come i'll come check you out
because i always go over there oh fluffs
cool yeah yeah i'm around i'm i'm on
island i'm here you know we'll we'll
tour around we'll check out some cool
stuff you know and
yeah oh yeah feeds
absolutely man
oh
oh yes thank you peter uh this is we
just implemented
pathogen testing two years ago and it it
caused just so many additional issues on
top of everything else because people
weren't talking as much about hopsleyton
as they are now and i still don't think
that a lot of growers know what it is
and we are testing for it for the
grow-off clones uh so i'd love to hear
everyone's thoughts on the topic
i mean i saw a hop late in viroid like
years ago on some gelato cuts that kind
of making their way up here before
everybody was talking about it and i was
kind of noticing like a dudding the
quote-unquote dudding disease and it was
very random on the plant like there
could be one branch that was looking
funky but the rest of the plant was fine
kind of started noticing it moving to
other strains so at that point i had to
just kind of mix the garden and move on
and honestly i haven't seen it since but
it just seems to be
you know when you're when you're
purchasing clones from trusted places
it's hard to know where everybody's
getting and sourcing their things and
you know unless there's like uh some
sort of you know breed or pedigree you
know documentation that comes with it
there's really no way to know unless you
test everything it's only 25 bucks per
plant to get it tested so it's not a
very expensive test but
you know when you're taking in new
things you just have to take every
precaution and hop late and viral it's
going to be one of those things until
you do some seed pops and there is some
discussion that it can transfer to seed
into the progeny as well so
you know best thing that you can do for
yourself is to start from seed as much
as possible but i've heard a lot of
people say that they've um they can get
rid of it through tissue culture also
out and new cloning new tips you guys
have
is
so i've heard there's a company
advertising them with clans populating
thyroid out of uh tissue culture plants
it's in california actually i don't
remember what it was but they said you
could send them your infected plants and
they will cleanse them for you and send
you back the fun
you're going to keep that genetic though
they file those
in the cleansing of the genetics they
said they can do all types of
cleansing
interesting
it's possible for sure i mean the plant
is okay
if you get a virus you can cleanse that
virus from your system you know if
you're if you're a strong enough
immune system to be able to fight off
then you can fight it off and then not
necessarily transfer it into the next
clone generation
um because it doesn't necessarily affect
the whole plant at the same time you
know like some part of the plant can be
affected while other parts of the plant
are not and it doesn't necessarily mean
that when you transfer it forward you're
going to be transferring it forward with
the virus it's a really weird deal
honestly and it's
it's really important we talk more about
it because so few people know that it's
even existing in their gardens they have
no idea why entire cloners are dying off
or entire trays of plants are dying off
all at once in the middle of flower it's
just the weirdest shit you know
so i mean i i think that it's really
important to sort of try and understand
this and then also not to necessarily be
afraid of it because we can kill it we
can uh figure out ways to clean the
plants of it and it doesn't mean that
once you get it then your your genetic
that you've loved for 20 years is
necessarily gone it's not it just means
that you've got some work to do
yeah there's products like recall mess
that you can use to clean and sterilize
your equipment to make sure that you're
not passing it on to other plants and
making sure your sops are are good when
you're going from plant viewpoint based
on using new scalpels or making sure
that you're cleaning your utensils as
you go that's a product that you can
kind of find
at most walmarts it's in the pet section
it's a
yellow tub but it is a buyer side that
works pretty well for cleaning and
sterilizing equipment
well another thing i think is
interesting about population is that you
tend to see it in environments where the
plants aren't necessarily as strong
so um and real
and i'm not saying that this is is a
hundred percent of the case but the
place where i see hoplite virus the
worst is in complicated hydrogen systems
so if you have like a super complicated
drip system or an aeroponic system or
something like that and hopladen virus
has a real chance of taking over your
plants in a way that it doesn't
necessarily if you run
you know maybe a more organic based
system where the the plants uh
have a stronger uh
system or if you run you know a
a system that is is is just where the
plants have a stronger immune system
even in hydro you don't see it as much
it's really where you're having problems
in the first place is where you tend to
see a lot more oscillating virus
anything anything that's susceptible to
disease
is gonna get it first no matter what
especially with older plants like
specifically with like plant count laws
like some people are growing six plants
under six lights so you've got like a 10
or 12 week veg on a plant whereas in our
situation we're running three gallon
pots that turn over every three weeks so
it doesn't have a chance to express
itself as long as it's in like perfect
plant health
obviously we don't have those issues
here at the moment but um so you know
plant health above all and if these if
you keep them healthier and you have
plants that haven't been you know
mothered out so much and or growing in a
small pot for so long
replacing your mother plants really
often is is key
you know i i replace them every three
weeks you know i gotta bug out guys
that's the how long they'll last
yeah
thanks john um that's it see you guys
later
got to replace them and then
go again keep them healthy keep them
growing healthy you know uh when you're
when you're going on a small scale
indoors i don't do much indoor growing
but what i've found is that it once the
roots fill the pot size you're a hundred
percent relying on your fertilizer
regiment
but if you give that pot some space give
those roots a lot of space to grow
that way especially through flour i when
i grow indoor i have run into that
problem all the time vegging too long so
i only veg for 14 to 20 days
that's it hit them in 14 days veg bam
flower so that the roots never actually
fill the pot and they're healthy the
whole flower cycle if you can get to the
end of the flower with healthy roots the
healthier the plant the healthier and
better the bud
which in like um
you know larger rooms with larger plant
counts and smaller pots you can achieve
with more watering intervals and
watching your dry backs a lot and that's
where you know the technical aspect of
growing really starts taking hold
yeah you can't just plug it into a
computer like most grow houses who run
like a 70-day program for every single
strain and they wonder why half of them
are you know two three weeks too long
have somewhere too early it's because
you're just running by the computer
program you're just doing the 70-day
boom done and on the fertilizer program
the water and you're not you're not
catering it to the plant you're just
catering the grow to the system and it
does not work
yeah i always say that uh success will
grow as a culmination of the sacrifices
you made for that fire you know you
started a hundred it's up to you to keep
it like my old
history teacher used to say
but
i also need the cruise but it's been a
pleasure talking with everybody i love
meeting all you guys well should we uh
should we wrap it on that
it seems like we're dwindling down past
the brady bunch
we went from brady bunch formation to
the
yeah
punch
we can save for the next conversation
all right i love it yeah we're trying to
prepare for big pharma entering this
space
i will say like our focus is on finding
like breeders doing interesting things
we touched on this earlier people that
are using stuff that's not widely
available so i appreciate all of you for
what you do what you do for growers and
for doing the hardest thing that i've
probably
you've been asked to do is like create
100 clones that look identical and make
sure they're clean and on time and
all of that it's a lot and i really
really appreciate all the work you guys
it is really really hard
i want you to know that as somebody
who's done this a long time that is a
really hard challenge
well i'm excited to meet the three that
are left that we haven't been out to see
you yet so um our website has the
schedule on it the growoff.com entries
50 bucks um unless you apply for the
social equity it's 25 bucks so
i want to see all types of growers this
year can we think a future cannabis
project for for having us too because
always thank you absolutely for sure
peter thank you
i appreciate you man for having us let's
go eat my lunch now
yeah exactly right here you've been
holding off on
was that that noise was it a like a sub
sandwich wrapper
[Laughter]
he was the crinkler
no the crinkler is probably me we're
trying to deal with metric right now and
getting all of the seeds that i've made
in the metric is is one hell of a
challenge oh good job yeah yeah we've
got until the 27th and i'm through like
130 seats or strains so far and we're
just on thc so like there's there's a
lot more to do
well good luck and god's name
appreciates you guys man take care thank
you yeah pleasure to meet all of you
all right you're a saint thank you this
is so funny
thank you everyone have a wonderful
night right we'll end on that
just the two