we were in wonderland nursery on this
and Kevin Joe Murray and he is somebody
who's made this competition happen in
Northern California and Southern
California for the better part of the
year and he said he had something
special and wait he said there wasn't a
lot of fuel on the market
Gastein something that could dump me in
a commercial setting something that you
guys could all put your hands on I
talked to a few people are like yeah the
only stretch is to well you know
homegrown environment is could do well
anywhere I know that some of you know
this already but it was doc Walker
oh gee this is one of the mierqi knows a
dog walker I don't think that you can do
anything better out there
[Music]
if we're wrong for carts if we're over
hash that's what matters when you grow
strong plants they tend to be very
chirpy very potent this is the first
time that we have ever had somebody
sweep both this contest meant more to me
than the commercial or medicinal
facilities because it all comes down to
the home grower they're able to produce
medicine for themselves and always
having that peace of mind quality is
different once you have it at the source
in a sense he's the source he's creating
medicine for himself and to be able to
have that peace of mind and know
everything that goes into it it's a
whole different experience that people
don't know that goaded the dispensaries
even the people that are getting
medicinal quality products it's sent for
testing it goes to a packaging process
is handled multiple times you don't have
that same that visual luster definitely
it's just something about it being
straight one hand one set of hands and
that's it how many people show you their
jar weed and it's like it's better than
what you have it's you have something
that's never been crushed in a bag never
been you know mishandled it's it's it's
different I love it and I hate it cuz
now I look at so much weed and I'm like
such a critic and I'm it's like oh like
this is why I grow though you know like
I have to you know you'd be like I want
to see you be a millionaire if you just
tell somebody how to grow their weed
because you're just like this is just
not up to par I think it's just a lot of
love that goes into it
you know it's different it's not my job
it's just the thing I'd love to do
hello that's what brought me to it have
you ever grown commercially like no I
started growing less than two years ago
and just you know got a couple lights
and some I actually bought some cuts
from the store while I popped seeds and
my first cut run allegedly allegedly
yeah he allegedly
saw hypothetical so you know yeah no I
did less than two years in and uh you
know it's just it's just been a homegirl
like I I understand commercial and my
hair from Florida right yeah I for
twenty it'll be about two years we had
to smoke all my weed that I had left for
4/20 and then we packed our shit in the
car and we left and that was that was it
I just committed and that's the only way
you know I quit my day job and I was
just committed and thank God it so
paying off you know but I do a lot of
research and I do a lot of thinking on
top of that research cuz you can just
read all you want you can be told all
you want but what actually makes sense
in your head what it what makes sense
for your conditions your I think that's
what everybody gets wrong in my opinion
is they try to copy somebody else's
stuff and so do you it's it's you know I
was talking about this with families to
age technology it's not having things at
your graphs if it didn't exist in a
Webster's dictionary to me I had to used
my imagination and the thing is is you
run out of creativity but at the same
time it's always good to learn by
changing what you're doing to experience
new things meaning you may perfect
something you thought you have perfected
mm-hmm oh I never I've already learned
quickly that I'm always going to keep
learning like it's not this is a
changing thing it's not even something
you can get perfected in my opinion
because of all the new technology all
the new science is coming out everything
we're learning for me I've always been
aqua grower you know as far as your
grill methods and the mediums and the
type of lighting you're using and even
the nutrients what goes into the
thinking of picking out each one of
those individual items because that's
that's really one of the things that
that growers use is their advantage it's
just like a chef you can get any brand
of pepper any brand of pan any brand of
olive oil it doesn't matter what it is
what what went into you choosing the
different types of media different
things that you use this time that's a
good question because it wasn't just you
know what what is everybody else running
I watched quite a few people grow a lot
of my friends grow some really good weed
so I had you know luckily a lot of
things to take from theirs and some
things not to take from theirs but a lot
of people were killing it with the mills
so I decided that I was going to run
that and you know organics it's
intimidating I'm not gonna lie they do a
lot of work with live soil and keeping
things just beautiful and I didn't go
that route for you know preference of
with Coco it's just it's easier and it
it helps with I call it a hydroponics on
on training wheels
exactly you hard over feed it's hard to
over water the water retentions are very
similar but you just don't have the
nutrients you have full control of
whatever you're putting into there yeah
that's that's the training wheels
no and that's it's true but it works
really well so it's like well if it's
working you know it's a lot more perfect
that won't work you gotta hook those
bags of soil you got you know my back
home growers are putting them in they're
putting them in black contractor bags
and hefty bags trying to smuggle them
into their apartment or house whatever I
remember those days yeah I had a bag I
had a golf bag in a camping tent bag
that I could put two bottles of 20 pound
tanks of co2
and just bring him in there it was like
I was like golfing and I had like a bag
with whatever in it you know I can't
tell you you know I'm not going to tell
you this offer and her paint
Entertainment use only you know it's
really cool just the fact of I was able
to get cuts you know from a store and
neighborhood nursery gave me the cuts
and they worked out really well it was
some you know mango trainwreck and all
my buddies were giving me shit for it
they're like oh you're gonna grow some
trainwreck huh like yeah yeah I'm gonna
grow some trainwreck you know that's
what I got I'm gonna crush it you said
something to me earlier about Miami
mango there's a strain sometimes like oh
if you're from back Florida there's this
strain it was a it was a mango that we
used to have and everyone you eat there
used to be so much of it that everyone
would hit you up and be like hey do you
have weed no I got some mango yeah I'll
call you back you know I'm the one
that's sitting there like all right I'll
take all the mangoes her pious we don't
ever seen and it was just incredible and
now I can't get that mango cut Miami
mango get that cut man I mean one thing
that comes to mind with Florida is OG
Kush I think it's Josh Diaz story you
know that originated in Florida what is
your experience with OG Kush I mean we
had a OG Kush Pinot tonight we had a lot
of it um
everyone hates my palette I'll tell you
that nobody's okay not everybody but the
majority people are like you know I hand
them a jar I'm like this is my favorite
weed ever and they're like this is what
like this is your favorite weed ever
where's the gas and I'm like no it's
straight lemon it's like let me tell
some of you like blue dream you know
like hypothetically blue dream might not
be that bad I'm all about taste I always
joke I'm like saying I'm gonna smoke
enough to get high oh jeez nice and they
get me you know dumb high but it's it's
the flavor I smoke for because I'm gonna
get high regardless off of everything
and you know I just I really I really
love sativas but now
the did you treat this plant differently
this time I mean I didn't treat it
differently at all except for a veg I
was actually redoing my room and I got
kind of lazy with it kind of put the
time off and then we just came down to
it like alright this has to go into
flour to get sixty days and some dry
time and some cure time and it has to go
in today so it went in sixty days here
and I actually pulled it 57 yeah I
started to you know for whatever reason
I started to see it pull a couple little
nanners out and it's like I could pluck
up I could see what they do but I'm not
even gonna risk it you know so I pulled
it and worked out so I was get down
that's what I had me sketching the whole
time is you know did I pull too early
because everyone else is like oh we're
taking this really far I don't have time
for that you know people talk about
looking at the trichomes with the
microscope and stuff and for me on a
commercial level we don't really do that
we look at a monthly calendar and if
that's day we need to pull we pull yeah
I also look at people like Moxie who
make a lot of concentrates and you know
they get you know bashed for pulling
early but we pull early and it's always
concentrates is different though well I
like concentrates so that's you know
where most of mine goes so you know
that's that's what I prefer to smoke
what kind of lighting news
I used Phantom de's HPS that that girl
off plant was growing under 500 watts
yeah took up the whole 4 by 4 space it
was you know because of the issue in the
beginning they gave everybody a little
bit more time so I use that for veg
would not get for you about a pound and
a half yeah for a 4 by 4 for 4 by 400
500 watts what kind of pot Gigi 10
gallon smart pot meeting as far as the
amount of water saturation per day
leaders gallons how much did you feed
the plant per day uh so I always just
you know the feed for about 30 seconds
and then let it sit go to another plant
come back irrigation
no this is hand feed yeah I'm on a wand
I have been like for me back in the day
I would be like every one second counts
different I'd be like one two three four
five six feel like my starts slow and
starts uh you know getting faster
towards the know you know I tried but
I've got a TD so like even if I'm
counting there I'm gonna be like okay
well what is this like in there buddy
what I'm Han Feeny I would always jiggle
the pie one hand you know the retention
so I'll hit it for like 30 seconds and
move on to another pot and I usually do
like two rounds and the next time I give
it water until I start to see just a
drop start dripping out for runoff and
let whatever runs off of there you know
one leading per day yeah one feeding
firt it starts out usually every two
three days and then yeah towards the end
it's you know I'm hitting it every day
every day any teas do you flush once a
week I flush well I do you know to feed
days and then the third time is just
water in Cal mag and my future would be
like a Monday feed when Wednesday like a
Friday and then so every so I just take
care of my flush is that way I never
have like a set you know flush every two
weeks or whatever but I will hit it a
little harder my secrets on your flush
what would you flush with no these are
secrets just water just water yeah all
right so I'm just uh you know I'm just
what do you think people using flushing
agents of different things I've you know
I've heard different things and I've
tried you know something that one person
said was good and then the other person
says well that's how you you know kill
your plant I'm like well you know kinda
is the goal here but not really but you
know do you run off you're like this in
your head looking for me it's about
reading plants and if you're hand
feeding sometimes it may be telling me
there oh you know getting too much water
I start backing off you know won't run
them till run off and then I'll switch
up my flush schedule but for the most
part I noticed that most play
we'll stay on the same regimen if you
have a good regiment you know like it's
some plants are finicky but I also stay
away from those plants we got enough
heaters that are easier to grow and you
know like to work with you a little bit
better so so when you fed it this time
how many different varieties of plants
were you sharing the same reservoir feed
with three different okay are they all
indica hybrid sativa one of them is a
sativa leaning the other one's a
jet-fuel cross with fabuloso and other
one was to grow off so well you know
what the grow off being an OG for me
I've always laughed at the OG string
because I feel like so many people put
names on it and it doesn't matter it
could be my better than your OG this one
dog walker OG whatever it may be it's an
OG but in our minds we look for a gassy
diesel II kind of piney strain when it
comes to an OG I mean have you grown oh
geez before and away from them to be
honest everyone gives me shit for
growing the more fruity flavors more
sativa flavors but you know that's what
I like I'm not gonna grow because what
you like I'm smoking this stuff so if
you want to smoke my bag then you're
gonna smoke it I grew and that's I
what's nice is that uh you know I became
friends with a seed bank who loves
edibles so Oregon elite great guy great
company and he's made it very easy for
me to get my hands on seeds and I just
haven't stopped popping them you know
there's people who give me shit for it
other people are like you know pop my
seeds it's hard because out of ten
twelve whatever many seeds you have you
have to track the data for each one of
those seeds and see how each phenotype I
always tell people it's like you know
seeds are like parents you may have the
same mom the same father and I've always
referred to it as the Michael Phelps
theory in my head Michael Phelps has
shed you know he smoked weed one of the
most gold medals you know so when I look
at plants
whether it's taking the most amount of
clones for strain or even popping seeds
who's our Michael Phelps of the family
and the thing is is so many different
attributes go in to finding the
different fie knows of a strain and you
know picking those out really comes down
to not personal opinion at a commercial
level it's it's public opinion so you're
looking what the market wants and you
know when it comes down to whether it's
selecting different fie nose or clones
what's your process like for me you know
if I had to plant ten plants I was
taking fifty cuts and I was throwing
away quite a bit of cuts just to find
the ones that were accelerating the most
at the beginning yeah I mean if I can I
do that but you know sometimes space is
limited on moms and you know it's just
you take the cuts you can run and as
long as you you know give them the right
love most of them you know turn out well
but I don't go for what the market wants
everybody you know picks up what the
next best thing is and sometimes what I
like is the next best thing
but that's pure you don't have the
millions of dollars marketing I feel
like some shit gets so hyped up you know
I don't know about you but I feel like
it really gets hyped up and you've
actually seen you're like dude like I
can hype up something all day you know
I've always been a Salesman but it's
like it doesn't matter as long as it's
fired the markets gonna like it anyways
so grow what you like and there are
gonna be people that you know grow or
that like what you grow I don't go after
the the gorilla glue craze the writing
cake craze it's not like that my mint
lemonade is what's your ultimate dream
in this do you want to grow for a living
do you want to own your own type of
facility to grow see for me it's always
been a dream to me to do what you love
and you know I see all in the reason I
bring up marketing is is there's so many
strains are so hyped up that I feel like
people don't get a true sense of what is
actually good cannabis and the thing is
is if we don't have the type of money we
don't have the type of followers it's
not put out there and people get hyped
up and I think we all get caught up
sometimes no matter what it is
life
did you know purple punch it has a
visual and smell appeal that's amazing
so I think it's it's almost like the
Blue Dream I mean that will knock me on
my ass purple punch not so much for me
you know maybe it's and I always say
maybe I haven't had the right one you
know it's crazy you know it's actually
indica dominant it's granddaddy purple
and Larry OG so you think if you cross
those two would be you know would
actually have a punch it doesn't you
know it's crazy too but you'll find the
people that do love it and that's what
you know the market is the market is the
market and as long as you grow it well
somebody's gonna like it and you know
people say Blue Dream is a hype strain
and they don't want it or whatever I
grow some blue dream you're gonna want
it you know like there's it's gonna turn
out good it's gonna be his work be
amazing it's like very weight and if I
don't tell you it's blue dream you're
not even gonna you know some people
might but all the people that oh I don't
like blue dream half the people you put
blue dream in their face they're gonna
be like Oh what is this so it has a bag
appeal and it has a smell and I think
that's what sells a lot of times and
really at the end of the day everybody
has a different body and everybody's
gonna accept things differently it's
just like alcohol or anything else you
put in your body you're gonna react
differently some people can have spicy
food some people can some people will
you know have alcohol and they act you
know normal and some people fall asleep
some people act like an asshole and they
act violent and crazy and they black out
so the thing is is is finding out what
works for you and you know I think that
so many people discount different
strains because something's hyped up to
where they need to open their mind it's
like really it's all about full spectrum
full spectrum is everything all right
it's just I don't go for what people
hype up and I think a lot of people hate
me for that or what's your favorite
stream my mint lemonade lemon G and
cinnamon cookies my sin city and that's
basically what I'm referring to when
people will tell you
what is it like man it it's nothing but
that old-school lemon just strong lemon
train that kind of I think lemon GE you
know like I that's what I'm comparing it
to is the lemon G we had a lot of lemon
G in Florida as concentrates when
concentrates at the market
somebody flooded down there with lemon
Jeter pea batter this is what I started
on and you know I found a shop that had
a glass nail on a dry Jay hook and I
went to town everyone's like what are
you smoking you know at these parties
I'm sitting there with a blowtorch
they're like I think he's going on there
you know but it was you know I I love
that lemon G and that's what really got
me on it and then when I went to
Colorado
they had this you know 92 lemon OG that
I was like I hit a dab of it and I said
this is it
I'm like how they say 92 yeah whatever I
don't think Oh G existed to most people
by 92 by the story of it so it's just
very true I just you know that's that's
what I found and I was like holy crap
this is the you know smell again and the
taste that I found and so I just started
popping lemon seeds and lemon tree all
these other ones I didn't find what I
was looking for this cinnamon cookies
and lemon G cross is the closest I've
found I've found I've actually for a
while I was the only one that I could
find that had popped some and then now
I'm seeing a couple you know yeah or
grew it enough to post it or some of the
oh geez that just don't post you know
who knows that could be crushing it in a
closet somewhere but uh that's nobody
really agrees with me that mint lemonade
is their favorite you know I got a few
buddies that do but most people call me
crazy and they're like where's you know
the xxx og where's the you know fire og
we want we want all those and I'm like
it's not my style
they're the same friends you could
probably give them ten different oh geez
they couldn't name each one of them
anyway yeah you know I've got some I've
got some og connoisseurs that just don't
like what
I grow and I respect it it is what it is
I grow what I like
they grow what they like when we smoke
if if it's not what we want to smoke
we'll roll up our own yeah you know who
cares I'm not I'm not in any competition
with anybody I just want to do what I
love like you said and that's I quit my
day job to come out here and you know
chase my edible dreams it's my you know
growing dream and you're gonna have to
pick a dream yeah I have all sorts of
ideas you know I'm always constantly
trying to find something that's with the
edibles I do chase the market that that
is something I don't want the cookies
the brownies the gummi bears I don't
think the market does either but they
don't have much of a choice you know
they they want those but they want
something else and the problem is with
the baked goods is the shelf life and so
I've started making chewing gum that
we're trying to get into the ten
milligram bracket of recreational
because it will hit you better you're
absorbing it instead of digesting it and
so you're getting a little more bang for
your buck on the 10 milligram limit that
recreational sets and I also have home
do you have to chew gum to get the 10
milligrams I'm curious you know that I'm
not sure you know I do do you get higher
if you swallow it that's a test we need
to take but I like it because it's it's
easy to microdose you know chewing gum
only lasts 10 15 minutes tops
no I I just I run chewing gum and I've
got some other ideas for the rec market
because of that 10 milligram limit the
ropes my sweet and sour ropes I just
don't see being bite-sized I I have them
bite-size and we will go after the
market with bite-size but you might have
people like me think I'm saving calories
very true and you can't you know I'm
trying to get skinny but I don't want to
get too skinny because you can't trust
the skinny candy man that's that's what
I've always heard shout out Claude the
candy man you know it's just it is what
it is with that market I'm chasing what
other people aren't tackling and shelf
life is what I'm going for as well
because people you know they have to
refrigerate these cookies that still
have this it's not like you can make
this stuff on demand you know the thing
is is if it was a perfect world it'd be
like a farmers market you know
especially for home growers like you did
tonight it's like you know there should
be a home Growers Association it's like
people that are not gardening to a
commercial level should be able to grow
within their means or actual state legal
it means and be able to trade or barter
or sell their goods within a community
without having the same stipulations as
a commercial cultivation because let's
face it it's not like you're doing it to
survive a lot of people that are doing
things for cultivating at home is for
themselves I smoke a lot and I'm not
trying to buy all the boof from the
store you know that's that's the problem
I I do still I I grow at home I grow my
own stuff and then I still want to smoke
other people's stuff I'm not you know
I'm not the best grower out there and
tonight but but let's just put it out
there I had a premonition that I was
gonna win when I did way before and I
did I told you tonight before you won I
think you're gonna win did I not I've
been telling everybody that I was gonna
win from the start because you got a you
know hey it's all about mental you know
for me it's mental strength II you know
it's not being cocky it's having
confidence in yourself yeah and if you
don't have confidence in yourself then
what's the point
like I chase the dream because I was
confident you know and I I waited as
well I should have been out here years
before I did I waited because I was
listening to other people tell me that
it's not gonna work you know it's too
hard for you why like why didn't I ask
myself why before
that I was like you know you're probably
right like kicking myself for that you
know but I finally had the
self-confidence to come out here do the
damn thing and how'd you hear about the
Gras uh miss rad reefer um friend of
mine she uh she entered and I said
finally you know I kind of want to enter
to uh you know and I saw the party last
time I was like yeah well even if I
don't win it'll be a cool time you know
Blake is uh actually from my hometown so
it was cool to party with him as well
across the whole country you know have
him DJ for us and Maddie ghost and it
was just a cool event to come to with my
friends over here because you know I
only have a select few of them and do
they help you in the garden no you know
I do everything myself I do have uh you
know my buddy who comes over and helps
me tremendously but you know it's it's
for the most part hands on that's all me
and I'm in there all the time
music music oh yeah all over the board
too I mean you can't let them get too uh
too bored I always play music you when
I'm not in there ya know I
I do too I've got a speaker in there and
they I why wouldn't they love it I love
music did the same the winner I actually
put the speaker in the tray with the
grow off plant if that says anything so
for the first two weeks I left it on
Michael Jackson pandoro he's pissed a
simulated you know you know how to get a
man up and then I threw it all over the
place you know I had some reggae in
there some raps and you know rock it's
just whatever I felt like listening to
they were gonna listen to and I'd walk
out of the room and leave playing and
you know that was it but I have but you
don't hand me the aux cord cuz you're
probably just not gonna be stoked
I will hit every genre that you didn't
even know as possible so keeps life
interesting and I truly believe that the
plants like it did
you got to look at vibrational patterns
and tectonic plates and frequency and
what it does to sand alone when they
play it at high volumes it's it's it's
really interesting never even heard of
that look it up it'll get real high or
medicated and working on it that blunt
you gave me is uh that was purple punch
by the way you know I I did a bit of
trolling a little bit because I can't
help myself always a class clown and
everyone's like what is the strain and I
kept telling everybody glue dream and
people were believing me I was like I
gotta stop the grow offs gonna get mad
at me it's glue dream like what damn its
heard oh it was reverse to the the
strains you don't think it you hire
purple punch it it got him I grew it I'm
high for one winner to another
[Music]