[Music]
so I had a question I kind of like to
ask these guys what they think about
this what do you what do you guys think
about the significance of the DEA given
GW schedule five for CBD but it's still
schedule one for everybody else in the
world what that's weird to me and I just
wanted to get your thoughts on that
it's amazing what money can do in this
country so you know I think without
getting to down to it if we want to have
a viable industry and continue to grow
we need to support industry trade
associations like NCI a and C CIA
because the pharmaceutical Lobby is
massive and I don't think they would be
heartbroken if they could figure out a
way when federal rescheduling comes to
pull as much of this away from us as
possible
and they're only one of many industries
that is lobbying actively and could
benefit from you know being able to have
this but the the the timing also you
know it the timing of everything was
interesting right the declassification
came you know within weeks of the farm
bill and you know there's there's a lot
of public comment that yet to be had but
we'll see where the chips fall
so GW is done a lot through the industry
and trying to where they made some of
the isolates and such but they also
started off with full spectrum and the
enormous amount of information as far as
going back through the ratio of I think
it was a hundred and forty four
different initial components they were
looking at for the ratio of amount of
each one but the ratio to each other
even some of the minor terpenoids and
the fight halls and the alkaloids that
are in there I think the second part
that becomes from that is is my biggest
struggle is not having the American
universities universities the United
States being able to do the research and
so that's part of the problem where they
had the forty nine different
applications for other universities
being able to supply the the different
cannabinoids for for medical research so
University so Mississippi State add that
but they but it's not their fault on the
fact that they only had two varieties
they were able to use that was
determined by the DEA and NIDA and so
dr. Rizzoli was always I need more we
need to be looking at more varieties and
they would he would always be rebuffed
on you know you can't have more and so
finally he got 14 more I think three
years ago and then they started adding
more material for him to use but it's
also the other universities he got
Cornell you got UC Davis I don't want to
leave someone out Colorado State now
that I'm on a roll but all these other
ones that are there the University of
Vermont I'm on a roll now and so you go
back through these these places that are
that are agricultural centers that we've
used throughout our history of being
able to have the boundaries so whether
it's good boundaries or boundaries we
still need to know what the boundaries
are for each one of these cannabinoid
mixtures what else is in the terpenes
what else is in the alkaloids here's the
question for you what's in the roots
because we're not using the roots right
now if we grind up the roots there's
some minor trace alkaloids that have
shown some capability as anti fungal
that's typically where everything starts
we typically eat a lot of roots we eat
potatoes we eat carrots we eat a lot of
things from the ground and that's why we
eat them so the other one is is what
happens when you start to have different
varieties that that are able to be used
with other species there's some
preliminary work that if you have the
cannabinoids you have the the cannabis
plant and you plant it between different
types of species they grow monster and
you put us through some of the other
ones in there and they're stunted so
there's some communal work that has to
be done that the AG schools the
universities and so I'm an American okay
so at the same time I'm I'm not
prejudiced by the fact that we have
great universities but right now we're
getting we're not getting the research
done that's being done in Spain that's
being done in Colombia that's being done
in Uruguay that's being done in Israel
Canada
you got McGill now you've got Guelph you
got beasts you have all these places
that the universities in the in the
United States could really benefit from
the
and the next generation so Fritz and I
are okay you guys got a few years left
but at the same time we have these young
people that want getting their pH D's
that are sitting there 30s that they
were aching to get into it but they
can't there's no universities they're
gonna that are going to be able to
compromise their grants to be able to do
this and so that's that's what it is
it's it's a private research that's
happening it's a little tangential but I
think it's also really important to note
that a lot of anecdotal evidence and
experience for cannabis is from the full
spectrum of everything that that plant
has to offer and you know with
rescheduling it gets a little murky
because the FDA doesn't have the best
track record for wanting to authorize
multi compound multi chemical compounds
right they like it simple they want one
chemical compound maybe two but you know
getting into different ratios terpene
blends you know it's it's highly
unlikely that those products will ever
see the light of day given the current
structuring of the FDA if it moves into
a federal medical classification and
that's why it's you know it's it's much
more enjoyable from the consumers
perspective to smoke all those things
but also from a medical perspective you
know there's a lot going on that medical
cannabis offers that the pharmaceutical
industry just won't just inherently and
how its structured also throw in I guess
I'm a little fixated on this but it's
apart from the DEA giving GW schedule
five the FDA gave them an NDI number a
new dietary ingredient number four CBD
so that really I'm knowing a lot about
the natural products industry that means
that it's kind of like a patent the GW
doesn't have to enforce themselves the
FDA will enforce that for them so it's
all to use CBD as I don't know exactly
where we're you know where the
boundaries are but an NDI number is is
that's what that means it's a new
dietary ingredient it's like it's like
GW discovered a new
so if you look at the so I always I
always study every morning so I I did
look at some of the newer patents by GW
any other companies and now they're
doing it as a single component but also
can be used in a botanical dietary
nutritional supplement so that's a new
little clause that they're adding at the
end of some of the patent work that
they're doing so if you look at the FDA
guidelines from December 2016 it's the
it's a natural it's a dietary supplement
so natural products and dietary
supplements guidelines so if you see the
guidelines that goes through with
anything that you have to do with any
natural products it doesn't matter if
it's cohosh Saint John's wort it doesn't
matter vitamin E it doesn't matter what
they are you still have to be able to
show that you're you're growing a crop
that in three crops gave the same
relative amount of that variety that you
were expecting then so you have good
agricultural practices you have good
manufacturing practices you have good
laboratory practices so those are all
the guidelines and all you have to
really do is take that plat one
guideline and just add cannabis into it
and then all the guidelines are done
[Music]