I am actually super carrot here about
you guys as thoughts and uncaring
because you're a sink you're a single
season
I guess maybe where I've like talked
with him about this and I just something
I talk about a lot of people about it's
like and we're producing the majority of
our volume you know you know October
really for most of us maybe September
November but like in this small window
what are different methodologies that
like maybe an indoor even like I'm you
know all your greenhouse car isn't
really worry about of course they
process because they're moving in it
before the next one's coming in but for
us it's like the levels this leaving
herb untrimmed on the stock with all the
leaves is the least invasive and then it
gets more and more invasive all the way
to pre rolls and how it degrades the
product faster and faster trimmed units
yeah all the way yeah
viii jars all right kids
take it away well I just I was wondering
what you guys his thoughts were on on
this like storage of the product and
degradation for us with where the
majority of the flowers were bringing in
our October maybe September November but
it's this small window and we're like
working across the whole year and maybe
a greenhouse or certainly indoor guard
isn't have that and they're working
through these batches to get to their
next batch but that I see that by by
keeping our product on on the stock with
leaves minimal oxygen in a you know a
room that's taking care of humidity and
temperature wise it's you the best way
to store the flower and then from there
as we go to trimmed units or that the
least their conquer dated together then
when we move to eighth jars they've got
a lot of airspace in them and they're by
themselves and we see the further
oxidation faster oxidation and then
pre-rolls got awful
so just wondering what you guys thoughts
are on on storage and kiri yeah and the
curing and the maybe how terpenes are
the structure the flower different
cultivars factor in to the longevity or
when you when you introduce them to the
market or in well one thing I think is
important about store especially
long-term storage we we do one harvest
year so we plan to store it you know for
a whole year it should last that long
and a big part of it have to do with it
is how how has it been dried and has it
been bruised and so whether it's trimmed
or not I actually prefer to store it
trimmed because it's smaller and it
takes up less space but it's important
that if you're gonna store it trimmed it
hasn't been it's properly dried and not
bruised so like if I don't like to store
weed that squishy you know because I
feel like a lot of your color
degradation happens from from too much
moisture in the herb permeating for too
long of a time and also that has to do
with the bruising too so if it's been
bruised you know by a rough trim job
that's been cut into the bud or too
close you're not going to be able to
keep that fresh look for quite the same
same amount of time or even in the
handling during the harvesting process
you can really affect how that flower is
going to dry in the way you handle it
from the minute you cut
to the minute it hangs and the sooner
and as smoothly and delicately as
possible as you can get that flower from
cut to hanging the there's a big effect
that's going to have on on how it drives
but when you want a cure for long term
we have noticed that when we keep things
on the stem and and don't trim it all
the way it does preserve it really well
in the right environment if you as
you're saying and when it's properly
cured out but in that state it's
properly dry and it's not bruised you
know what I mean so that definitely but
I feel like a big part of it is is what
happens after the harvest how is that
going to affect the long-term storage
you know so every moment of handling is
like has an impact on and how it's
handled because we have dry flowers that
are covered in little tiny balls of
resin on little tiny stalks you know and
so too much resin being knocked off too
many leaves even like in the trimming I
feel like too many leaves being left on
with the weed will we you know like if
the it's not cleanly trimmed and the
leaves will affect them yeah you know
and I see I see that too and and that's
kind of where I go into structure and
maybe even terpenes as well because I
noticed that with the certain cultivars
certain varieties that I work with that
they have an ability to store much
better than others and
oh if we're talking about nose I do
notice that there's certain varieties
like I see it with a lot of my sours
that I don't really want to consume them
right away and I typically don't in that
type of realm and that after a few
months they're really primed for me to
consume and then other ones that certain
I see it a lot with citrus with the
orange where initially I'm like wow
that's that's amazing that's great crazy
it's really different than than other
varieties and that that amazing feature
that single very specific nose it kind
of flashes off and so those varieties
yeah I might like to get to market all
different urban snow piles
terpenes are molecularly so volatile and
so sensitive to the environment and so
they do evolve over time and it takes a
minute to really see where it's going to
settle out what that's part of the art
of the Cure is letting it cure into its
really optimal proportions of where
everything molecularly is is gonna sit
but to hold that some-some terpenes are
extremely volatile and others turn into
other ones that are also really
interesting over time so when you're
talking about how the flavor changes
over time we'll go through the whole
year and we'll taste our cannabis that
we're storing and what to change and
it's really love it different stages and
it's it does change a little bit but I
love it in all those different forms of
itself so you get like in addition to
the different experiences you're getting
with between your varieties it's like
you're getting even more experiences and
variety yeah absolutely great yeah
that's that's a cool thought I like that
and some of them transform very richly
some of them at ten months they're just
getting to like where I'm like this is
getting better and better and better
this is really hitting its peak wow I
didn't even know it could be like this
and of course when you get it again the
next entry comes out and I feel like
it's a year-long thing you know
experience that goes the whole year
until the new flowers come and then you
get excited about them because they're
that doesn't mean that just because
depths start coming out now in the early
summer I don't think that means that the
outdoor suddenly isn't good at nine or
ten or even a year which it depends on
how good of a job you did at your job
which used to be which it is part of our
job I think when you're putting out
batches all the time and they're going
straight to market it's a totally
different scenario as far as it's a cure
you don't even have the opportunity to
do the kind of cure that you would to
make it really amazing all year long but
it's possible and I think it's a myth
and fallacy and it's also like you have
to say I'm planning to try and cure this
to store for a whole year you know and I
mean we have a small root cellar we
restore everything we're not like
immediately smoking in you know so it
stays out of like a 55 in the dark and
it's you know it definitely I feel like
if you want to go longer than a year
then you need to think about separating
the resin and curing just the resin you
know what I mean but yeah what one thing
that like just from like my experience
in like how we looks and what what I see
is like a lot of people trim too close
or too loose
and they also don't dry it quite enough
to get past the first few months because
for the first few months it looks really
great but then after that you know like
maybe it'll get dry but it wasn't dried
to preserve the color and the freshness
to last you know and so like if it's a
little squishy and you leave it like
that from drying that I think will
degrade quicker shelf shelf life hazard
and something that was a little bit more
dry at the beginning or it kind of
locked in the freshness because I feel
like with cannabis you know it's not
tobacco it's not like a leaf you know
you're actually what you're hearing is
the resin up on the plant so and that's
what we where all the flavor comes from
and all of the cannabinoids and and some
of that is intermingled with the with
the plant tissue but most of it is just
in the resin and so when you are curing
you're not necessarily curing the plant
material you're curing the resin and so
for like a long-term storage if you
think about resin as your main
ingredient then that you want the plant
material to be like less emphasized yeah
oh absolutely and I mean I think that
that plays back in the dissipation of
the chlorophyll that you're getting with
that long-term dry and in tech texture
as opposed to structure there like
structure ties into the visuals when
you're talking about that a lot but like
I I deal with texture a lot and it's
when I start breaking down so it's gonna
keep yeah it's kind of clogged up again
a good good sign but like that that when
it's when it's been dried really slowly
you get to this point where though the
stem snaps and you're like wow it's
incredibly dry yet somehow this kind of
magic trick has happened where it's
still gooey on the flower when it first
is when it happens the other way and
people are like no it's totally dry cuz
the flower feels so dry but you know
there's still moisture in that stem that
products degrading in a few months and
they're bagging it like that
your stems have to stuff like hard and
yet at the same time have that kind of
suppleness to the flower itself and I
think that translates into some of
that's varietal differences but some of
it into how it's gonna break the feeling
of how it's gonna break down not
necessarily just like whether that
whether it's oily or sticky and the in
the resin but the actual plant material
that's left I don't know it has this
certain part that it peels apart for me
if it's actually really cured out the
way you guys were talking about versus
when they it's dried too fast it like it
kind of crumbles in this certain way I
noticed and it's in relation to the
chlorophyll it's just something that's
where I think what they're talking about
about this this phenomenon of the
product that's gonna in a three or four
months just be totally fine and I'm just
seeing one one thing that I correlate
with that is the texture the feeling of
this I know it's the same variety as the
one over there but there's it breaks
down into more crumbly fashion and I
don't know exactly what that is but it's
something that I see that that tends to
tie with the product browning out faster
I think it's the preservation of the
integrity of the cellular structure and
the handling and the damaging and the
bruising are also ways that kind of
negatively impact that and so I think
the brittleness could be an impact
similar from you know in a lot plays
into it and what picking it at the right
time definitely plays into it and yeah I
think you know when we're thinking about
drying we're thinking about about what
nine days you know and I mean I don't
think I think five days is very fast to
dry them in five days they're never
either fully dry or they're too dry and
you know like powder
yeah but then fourteen days is too long
and too soft you know what I mean
doesn't mean you're still not but drying
and curing that after the nine days
because because then at that point
you're like putting them in some kind of
getting them ready to trim cream in a
tote or a bag and then and burping them
from there burping a lot you know we're
still releasing constantly they're not
you know they're you know finishing
process also when you're talking about
oxidizing and things like that I'm a
strong believer in fresh air flow
constantly you know what I mean I don't
I always have a window open in my dry
room you know like just cracked like if
there's not fresh air I feel like that's
when you can get stale and kind of wreck
your cure
but there has to be a good flow to the
errors yes I even cracked two windows on
both sides of the room and our airflow I
think is really important you know
keeping your flavors fresh what were you
saying
we think we sort of got into a little
bit you're talking about texture when
you're breaking bud down and what you're
looking for what do you want a roll
joints yeah it's yeah I don't know it's
it's just this this texture there's so
many variables that I'm not gonna speak
to specifically what I see but I just I
do like for most tendency somewhat
difficult for me to break down by hand
that I just usually herb that can
crumble out really easily and it could
be just that the structure of that
variety so I don't want to make this a
universal blanket statement but if I if
I see two varieties and they were both
they're both the same variety and they
have that textural difference is really
extreme yeah and the other one maybe
it's even still sticky but it just
somehow is able to crumble down I like
what they said about the drier this
structural because there's like a point
where like it's is it because the the
weed should be a little firm or like it
shouldn't be like oh really squishing at
least in my opinion you know two people
have different opinions of course but
like at least if you're gonna store it
all year long and smoke this one
harvests like all year long it should be
more dried to be more firm yeah I agree
we we started it will crumble a little
right before but then the question
becomes also like what environment is it
going to be introduced into when it like
when you
you bring it out so like I don't know
the specifics and study of high-end palm
but like when you guys bring your herb
out if it's been stored in a dry whether
it's trimmed or untrimmed what is it
typically going into a more moist
environment in your house or in your
bedroom or in your whatever our general
climate is more dry when you were
talking about like a nine-day drying can
you talk about now the next stage of
curing and are you curious of ours for
different amounts of time and can you
talk about some of that well we're very
small so we kind of some are cured
longer just because it takes the next
step of processing things gets you know
takes tell us its story
so what we're smoking is pink cashmere
and so we harvested this on October 14th
from there we dried it it hung for nine
days
at what temperature humidity roughly we
usually I go for as cold of temperatures
as I can manage we don't use a lot of
power to manage the room but it's a
darkroom and basically we keep it at 45
and 55 temperature are 55 degrees at 45
humidity for nine days until the stems
snap and then we'll take it down no and
then usually what you'll do is you'll
take it down and you'll put it in a in a
bag or a tote and and close it and
usually we'll do that for like three
days or so and a lot of the moisture
that's still in it will come up come you
know like it'll rehumanize
in the container from its own thing so
you have to be careful about not making
fun of your product mold by just
forgetting about it but in those short
amount of time after that and then
you'll open that up leave it open for a
little bit let them dry out and you'll
just kind of keep doing that until they
reach like an equilibrium that now they
are I guess at a stable you know and
work the thing is we're doing it with
all of the strains as they come down and
so this didn't get trimmed until a
couple weeks ago so it's like
you know yeah wait no wait that's that's
my that's my philosophy on it but like I
think close to sale yeah but I think his
point I think some of the factors that
he's talking about like at whoever's
prop doing the processing being really
careful I like particularly you're
talking about that already good so just
scissors yeah the scissors aren't too
close to the flower or too far away from
the flower and that they're touching the
flower as little as possible the more of
that stuff that happens I think provided
that the flower was grown well is that
that it allows it to after it to be
trimmed just still preserve itself and
not start showing this because I think
some of the oxidation that I see and we
talked about is the micro bration from
the scissors and the fingers that time
it's a bruising so bruising it yeah it's
like if you if you drop an apple on the
ground it's gonna bruise right like if
you do rough it up and it's not gonna
keep as long as something that you and
you keep well like I guess the
difference between the the wet the wet
bruise and the dry bruise so like if
we're using totes for harvesting how
much is stacked in how vertically are
they truly is there like the first ones
that are put in it's not that that
corner is that a pressure point how long
are they left in that bin between when
they're harvested and when they're hung
like there's ideals that none of that
would happen but if it does how can we
at least mitigate it to be as least
damaging to the product as possible yeah
actually prefer to use flexible
containers on shelves but nothing is
like stack
too high or heavy lack names well like
there's a series of shelves and all of
the usually we put them in like a food
grade bag
that's not translucent you know what I
mean and so we can easily open that and
close them this is problem the show
everyone is dry yeah once you take it
off and it's still on the stem and on
the leaf ready to be trimmed like
transferring between your garden and the
dry rooms as quick as possible and we we
just cut and carry the basket it's not
very far just right from the garden for
the dryer
there's no sleds they're the perfect
shape and that kids sleds like that
they're like the long that like a
toboggan like that but it's just like
that it's like shallow shallow and long
so you can put or you would be but you
would yeah you would almost picked them
down in the future you like that design
it makes me liked it because it was like
long and you know you could you could
put more and fill the whole thing but
not stack them too high I really like it
it's it's um you know it's something
that I think a lot of her amount is when
we're cutting branches how we put them
like if when we use bins like I really
like when guys just start off as
vertical as possible because if they got
an angle well we are at same with me I'm
just like I when I get to the end if
I've stacked a bin and I don't take any
damage just those first flowers
that's what you said like shallow and
long so you can put longer you can just
cut your colas you can just cut your
colas and lay them like a like it's like
a bouquet of roses but you can just lay
them without having you know you can
just make everyone cut their colas down
and then you're not there yeah I mean
because it makes a difference and then
we don't we don't cut so much that it's
sitting there all in the pile we just
like you know all the colors are however
far we're cutting and to the basket and
then that gets hung so we don't pile
like Toni some stuff up for hours before
it goes into the dry room it makes a
huge difference to us it's like a little
bit like roses and wine and tea you know
because like roses are you want to look
at it they're beautiful flowers they're
not just like I mean you can be like oh
yeah it's just her but you know we think
of them as beautiful sacred flowers a
little bit they're gorgeous so like
they're not for making high tax no and
that's just you know but they they're
beautiful and we like to preserve that
beauty you know and that's important to
us so we are very gentle with the way we
grow like when we try to make sure we
make sure everything that is done in a
gentle way it's so that resin isn't
being rubbed off or shaken or anything
like that knocked around and dropped too
much on the market you guys
- or this flower it's just flour and
we're gonna be doing some dry see