shit oh here we go deal grows just in
the fucking time for a dab
brother fuck yeah just in time
for that what's up bud
fuck yeah in the cold room too that's
badass
this is going to be fucking awesome oh
that tasted amazing
beautiful how are you brother good man
just a daily grind bro just trying to
stay busy
trying to keep the train moving forward
you know absolutely
you're enjoying your uh off season or
you're off time
the off time is only because uh due to
ac
issues you know but uh i'm always i'm
going full time
all the time you know my i work with uh
as many farmers as i can you know right
now i have a good handful so i stay
very busy and i'm very fortunate you
know
nice nice i figured i most people i know
are taking off at least for the holidays
i feel like there's always this little
bit of a break
oh yeah yesterday was that kind of for
me i told myself yesterday i'm like
not gonna work no instagram nothing you
know and
i did pretty good i hopped on instagram
a few times i think some work here and
there but
you know i i'm uh i'm just trying to
build this you know from scratch so it's
like
i gotta just keep on building keep on
grinding
all the free time i have you know i put
into it so
fuck yeah that's awesome man it looks
like a legit room it looks really
fucking nice
yes it's a small little shacky room you
know
dude you got it you got it sealed up
though it looks good it looks fucking it
looks like a legit cold room
yeah absolutely you got yourself a
little laboratory fuck yeah
i mean it's like a stuccoed uh
it's a stucco shed you know and i just
insulated with that thick like i doubled
up on that
thick uh rmax insulation
like super thick shit expensive shit you
know
[Music]
that was my big investment into the uh
into myself i guess asides from the
press
i needed to make that cold from
happening it was the cool bot and the
insulation
it was like a good like
[Music]
the cost of the infrastructure to do it
right
that's like the first thing that i would
suggest doing you know whether it's
growing or anything like creating that
good environment you know saving the
money and cleaning it out but
you don't really know when you're new
and you don't really have someone like
leaving you on you don't really know
what you need so
i just bought some bags and started
making hash and i'm like oh i mean
you know ice and this and just kind of
like slowly
build from there you know and that's how
you you know you guys know the deal
no it goes cheers
what are you guys dabbing on right here
i'm gonna want to join you guys
i just found some hurricanes from this
oh yeah so i remember how beautiful that
looked
i don't know if you can see it good or
not like oh yeah
hey it looks like uh tim's trimming
actually popped in so our buddy tim's
trimming
also uh joined us for this chat he's got
a bunch of awesome stuff
to contribute to the solventless world
um this is awesome so
uh deals deal grows um i would like you
to introduce yourself man it's the first
time having you on the show
nice thank you man to introduce myself
to tim or to everybody
that's everybody yeah my bad i just it
all happened at one time
no worries uh yeah so i mean my name is
fred diehl
bros oh sweet man fuck yes
just stepping into the industry you know
about like
a good serious good year or two into it
you know where i'm really trying to like
dive into it quick to quit my job you
know and just
all in you know and uh i feel like
solving this in my lane
and my goal is to help growers you know
create their own fault in this thing
and just teach and learn and grow from
there you know that's my goal here
and as always quality first dude
sick fuck yeah fuck yeah
so where were you uh what was your
employment before you were doing uh
um before you got into cannabis and
stuff get a load of this guy he's got
the email
bud oh yeah yeah see what i was
literally just thinking about you know
we were just looking
at it yeah maybe you could tell us a
little bit about about that
oh dude this is an email from 710 coils
man
highly recommended uh recommended by a
few friends dude
but um i know it's going backwards but
this guy's customer service
is is uh it's so nice it's
it's quick super fast he answered all my
questions i had about it
sent me pictures of what i wanted to see
and it was delivered quickly
i even sent him a recently sent him a
video of the box
kind of like melting a little bit and is
acting a little weird
no questions asked send me a replacement
and
i just can't be more happy with the with
this email you know and for me
so busy always working i just leave it
on like don't judge how dirty it is you
know it's kind of dirty
because it just stays on and i just like
dab away clean off
you know i could do a lot better with
the cleanliness of it but i'm just so
busy and
it just does the trick man highly
recommended for the busy dabbers
sweet how much does that go for
pretty affordable in my opinion man like
we're talking the this is a 30
millimeter bucket so the banger the cap
the email the cords you know the box
everything was like around 250 i believe
oh wow okay cool everything but the bomb
or the you know everything about your
rig yeah sweet sweet sweet sweet okay
cool man
fuck yeah yeah pretty quick yeah what
temperature do you use that
uh right now it's at 467. okay sick bro
cool he has to come stocked at 420 which
is kind of low temp and works pretty
well
uh i take fatter dabs i think and i just
raised it higher sometimes i have to
raise it a little higher but
rotten you know play with it fuck yeah
i love that people's preferences on it
totally yeah exactly they're all about
the text
smoking tech you asked me uh what i did
before
cannabis and uh i did a few things man
like
but right before cannabis i was in the
hvac world you know
doing a i was an air technician you know
doing
doing that and i chose that profession
because i used them poorly directly with
the campus industry you know
um but yeah before that i worked a few
jobs
and mainly it was like i worked at in
and out for like seven years and got a
really good idea of uh
training team building uh quality
control
production and then uh like customer
service
and then i moved on went to school and
got into hvac you know and learned to
trade
fuck yeah went into sales with hvac
and then on my way out into the camps
industry
i got a warehouse job and then just like
peace out
you know i did my own thing and all
during that time i was always
doing what i could you know on the side
you know
after the nine to five you know trying
to be trying to get my experience you
know i said i was throwing for
like a year and a half and then i was
making hash you know while i was working
and then i finally stove already you
know
and uh about a year and a half later man
i'm here and i feel like
i feel like it's been 10 years it's
crazy but it's only been like a year and
a half but i feel like it's been
such a long like a long short journey
you know
fuck yeah that's awesome
fuck yeah so what what made you love
solvingless
good question man um back in the day man
back when like
phil probably first like invented it i
didn't
like i wasn't deep in this theme but i'm
always a part of cannabis i remember my
friends
standing on uh hair straighteners and
doing the dabbing you know
i remember giving him an eighth of like
my my best that i had like either it was
bubba kush
or it was uh god's gift or it was um
something purple you know um gdp
but then he pressed it and i got like a
little sport out of it i got one dab
maybe like two dabs and i'm like math
fuck i want to smoke weed you know
but uh what got me into solving this was
basically my time you know i tried to
grow it my biggest dream was to be a
grower you know
um but at the time of me starting to
pursue the growing
side seriously i had uh
my son was being born but you know i had
a daughter already
like just recently married a headlock
going on and
you can't really allocate all the time
to the plan you know when you have
you know as a beginner i guess but i
tried i went through it all
and i went through all the you know all
the different like uh
mediums you know like rockwool coco core
and it all led to
uh living soil you know because my mind
was always about like what's the easiest
um this most sustainable you know and
like i just want to add a water to these
bitches you know and grow the best i can
so i found uh jeremy at bill soil
followed him a lot and kind of took his
approach
and and uh started doing living soil and
then we had to move
and then i just couldn't grow anymore um
and i just started i always chased
like the best quality you know smoke
like all of us mostly do you know
and so uh i used to do a lot of dabs and
shit and the pants came out and i'm like
ah fuck the pens and then that's just
kind of how i found solving this you
know fuck yeah yeah
yeah yeah and i saw how to make it and
i'm like
i can do this and you know i saw that it
was new
i'm like all right fuck this i'm not
gonna be
five years from now you know sitting at
this job i hate
pissed off looking at a guy and saying
oh i could have done that
you know so i'm like no way dude so
awesome
you know you know you guys all know the
same story like everyone
i'm one in a million you know what i'm
saying uh
i'm happy to be here though i appreciate
it right yeah fuck yeah right
totally yeah fuck yes thank you so i can
start making hash for my my grower guy
you know working at that warehouse
at the hvac warehouse right dude came in
no one was giving them attention and
just because of my background like
in and out you know customer service i
helped this guy all the way out the door
you know small talk i'm like what do you
do he's like oh i grow weed
i'm like sweet and
we were just we were friends instantly
he gave me some bud
and then um i started washing his trim
he gave me his trim
and then for without him man i wouldn't
have had that material
to really start and do all my work and
trials man like
i went from washing like ounces of trim
and then i washed out the bud because i
wanted to wash everything then i got my
press and like
started pressing everything and just
literally grew from there man oh that's
fucking awesome bro
fuck yeah and everything so far has been
like the beer fridge i have that
um you know the beer fridge oh yeah
this thing came to me too man a
refrigeration technician that
shops at our store you know he he just
asked me if i wanted beer fridge
and i just said sure let's check it out
you get a whole bunch of these i pick up
the best one
and i was you know making hash at the
time and i had my uh
home fridge full of pizza boxes my wife
was pissed
this guy came in at the right time and i
got the fridge and wow
shit just seemed to be happening like
that just uh
effortlessly almost dude like
non-forcefully like even my first job in
the industry bro
um and i hate to take up the time right
here just need to please do you no no no
this is exactly what it's about
no rush yeah the the
my first job in the industry so i quit i
quit my job you know
um the first job wasn't what wasn't what
it was like the dudes
promised things and i wanted to get into
that story but
after i realized like what this industry
kind of could be like like it's not all
what you see
it ain't all you know
totally bro i just uh i had a dedicated
community and uh peter from the future
cannabis project
was holding a history of rosin event
with uh
nicotine phil salazar um
blue ice extracts and uh
and a few of the guys on the panel but
you know i just drove out there
met all the guys on the panel and then
afterwards i talked to peter and said
how can i get more of these and peter's
like
well tomorrow i'm having an interview
you want to come over and i'm like you
just
in my head thinking you just met me yes
of course you know let's go let's do
this like that's so weird that you're
gonna invite a random guy
to sit in on an interview you know but
okay and i went and sat on the interview
and the guy that he was interviewing
offered me a job i got a job in the
legal industry for like seven months
like as their uh quote unquote like lab
manager you know
wow and again it's not all what they say
you know
i was told a licensed facility you know
bells and whistles
there was nothing i had more in my shed
than he had ready for me you know
but uh it was experience that i was
gonna i was chasing
and uh i got the experience
and walked away when that situation just
i realized
it was all like make-believe you know
i'm like all right i'm gonna go uh
you know build my own tree you know what
i'm saying
wow it's been great it's been crazy man
it's been uh
like destiny tested i don't know
weird but it's cool no i totally hear
you on that man for sure that's that's
very interesting and
actually this is uh that's what it's all
about i really like having people like
tell their story and
kind of like you know the way i feel
about it it's all like everyone i've met
at least you know it's passionate people
that want to change this industry make
it better make it into something that we
all like
feel represented by you know where
everything else all the other industries
are destroyed by like some
unattainable goals and shit it's like
this is stuff that's like we all really
want this to
you know remain how it is and we're
trying to keep it that way by putting
our passion in at 100
and i feel like everybody that's
involved is the same way so i felt that
from you when i when i met you on pete's
program
uh what you're just talking about um uh
future cannabis project and shit and i i
felt the same way i was like i'm just a
guy from instagram
you know like anybody else is taking
pictures because i'm in awe of
stuff i'm working with or around and
stuff like that i'm amazed that
that uh you know he'd asked me for my
opinion on stuff so stuff and
and all that but it's it's really cool
to hear your story man like that's
really badass so i have a bunch of
questions for you um
so we work with that farm on your hat uh
growls valley
um oh for real yup yeah we've worked
with them before we bought a bunch of
material from them they actually
literally make some of the best material
i've ever
washed as a hash maker cured material
yep i got this from uh
eon farms um at the
[Music]
[Laughter]
this is a great uh this is a cool story
man this is a really actually um
pushed me to actually quit my job dude i
still have to fuck yeah
well i didn't know and i'm like i'm
gonna quit my job and i'm gonna you know
chase the dream and like you know hold
it to your guys standards you know the
grass root guys
fuck yeah that's awesome
dude that's fucking awesome yeah it was
just random i was like oh that's fucking
badass that you have their symbol on
your head if i have to
point that out i actually want to talk
about this meeting dude it was their
first coalition meeting um
that fabian you know genetics
he he held his coalition meeting it's
all about the grassroots guy
standing up and building their own seat
at this table
before all the corporations come in you
know and before all the big money come
in
and i want to be a part of that so bad
and i think i was like
one of like two people that came from
like the la area
drove up there i guess i think it was
beard bros myself and i think one more
guy from l.a was like
up there but um it was pretty
surreal man being in a room full of
people like a whole like
uh a whole spinal bond of on farms it
was held at his spot
that he's actually building out now man
so i know exactly
crazy man that guy kyle is killing it
and people like that i do are the people
that i'm trying to work with and that
people i'm trying to become as well you
know i want to be someone like that it's
industry
like kyle's killing it cheers and cheers
to that
it was crazy bro i met bob and that i
just felt like it was
such a boost man of energy and i felt at
home
dude and that was what i'm like i
decided like
i'm family i finally found my place you
know it was crazy
yeah dude i feel the same way about the
cannabis industry man for sure that's
why i want to put everything into it and
i want to educate young people and shit
fuck yeah fuck yeah
that's awesome dude it's great to hear
your story and shit it's
inspiring it's inspiring fuck yeah
totally exactly
that's not a thanksgiving fuck yet
yeah but like i said man there's so many
people like me out there dude like y'all
we all have the same story man just
different books you know what i'm saying
love it straight up fuck yeah
so you grow too that's an interesting
aspect that's cool
i i uh i used to grow you know
i can't do like i can't allocate both my
time right now
i'm trying to and that's the goal
actually and i was hoping this year was
going to be the year i do my single
source
i had a garden you know growing
vegetables
and uh i had had a volunteers pop up
because uh sometimes i wash seated
material sometimes farmers get
you know how it goes see the material
and if it's not like
pollinator material if it's just like
seeded and not like
you know dusted you can wash it and get
some fire from it totally oh totally
if he's pollinated you might get some
like orangey looking rosin you know i
gotta be careful
but um yeah i got some volunteers man
and uh my wife's kind of crazy on dude
she'll she's been topping it down
because she's kind of against growing it
and for the neighbors to see we lived in
a close to neighborhood
but uh one made it through man i made it
all into flower
it's about like a foot and a half long
plant
and uh i got my first single source i
just washed it and pressed it just like
last last week or so oh fuck yeah dude
that's awesome though
you know but uh i'm sure you could
manage to put a light or two in
somewhere and just do a couple a little
something for yourself too
oh i'm building uh whether she likes it
or not i'm building a little tiny
greenhouse there it's for vegetables we
have raccoons so i have a reason to
build it you know to keep raccoons out
you know and uh we're gonna have at
least sticks in there and we're gonna
have some fire fresh frozen
perfect yeah yeah that's the shit man
that's just shit so you're in la
i'm like right outside of l.a oh sweet
sweet
sweet so so what is it like looking for
material for solvent list down there
that is my
question i'm blessed man
plus every pass maker i know they
i can't speak for everybody but i know a
lot of them are buying out you know and
i'll have to
i'll have to say that i i've been
blessed to just work on uh splits and
partnerships you know because
i'm willing to work with the farmer that
is only willing to give up their dry
trim or something you know
and i'm going to grow with the farmer
from there and get their nugs and get
their fresh frozen musical
um i'm starting out small so i'm not
picky you know a lot of smash makers
they want
the best all the flower all of it you
know but
i'm going to put a long ball in the long
term i'm willing to start small take the
trim
and get the big nugs and you know
because i know the growers have
systems already like you know 10-15
years
doing it you know and they were flower
yo totally no exactly for sure i agree
and i mean honestly being able to work
with trim is going to be something that
no not a lot of people are able to do
and
as we we chatted about in the past like
you know not a lot of people know how to
make the best
material out of trim so it's like you
have to know how to actually make cash
if you're working with trip
so that's interesting and your stuff
looks fire dude so that's awesome
you know straight up
that's all yeah that's awesome yeah
yeah it's like for me it's kind of kind
of easy for that aspect you know i
have a few farms i work with um but
i know some i think it's kind of
accessible
in my area you know i feel like
everywhere i look it is but
i have to remember that i'm now like in
a world that's
that's uh you know so foreign to so many
people you know
and like my brother for example he just
drove down here from missouri
and uh he's been here for about a week i
put him in three different farms
and he's hashed out like two different
times i give him like
five different tastes you know and it
just blew his mind of like he didn't
know it was even like
it was like this you know what i'm
saying so
i think it's pretty easy but for the
average joe i don't
i don't know i don't know it's gotta be
tough
you know but it's
crazy man right oh no actually it's a
great thing we need to continue to
spread our message and end the message
right now
just like that uh because some people
have looked at it like you know
hoard the secret and poured the gold
type of thing
that what what right at your disposal
and it's nice to be able to share and
just tell people you know
if you really have the passion for it
you will be able to make it happen the
same way you made it happen
i made it happen frank and anybody else
and
those that will come after us it's as
easy as that man if you if you want to
get in here
you're already in here you just got to
put in the work and time's going to
catch up
it's as easy as that it's easy as that
with solving this too people are always
tripping on like
bag sizes and this and that it's as easy
as having
good starting material and making good
hash you know and
there's no secret everything else this
is all preference in my opinion you know
well tell us though what is good
starting material to you
fresh you know fresh is good fuck yeah
that's what i've been saying too so how
fresh uh i say ideally
you know and and stretching it you know
it's pretty like stretching it as far as
i
can stretch it i would say no more than
two weeks
no more than that shooting for really no
more than 10 days
off the plant you know but if someone's
like
really want to try it out and they want
you know
you know two weeks max you know i'm
saying but
ideally five days right off the plan
like fresh as possible you know and
and you gotta keep it cold you know
preserve it you know washing right away
is good too
i found with trim um
washing right away is good freezing the
nugs you gotta freeze the nose but
yeah cool dude fuck yeah
sweet awesome uh do you have anything
you want to talk about specifically or
anything any stories or anything like
that about
your uh process and stuff like that or
what kind of press do you use also i
meant to ask that earlier what kind of
ros
press oh man my rosin presses that's
that's a good story man because uh and
that's another thing everyone trips out
on i feel like there's so much uh
paralysis analysis going on you know and
i hope that i could put a stop to that
help people out just sharing my journey
like just starting you know
totally there we go you know just
starting man
i mean this started with uh a hair
straightener and people standing on it
so you don't need the five thousand
dollar press right away like just
let's go yeah
i don't know if i could turn my camera
around
let's see well it's a crd press it's
it's
just a diy press kind of oh wow dude no
badass that's the best
i've seen videos of it now that you i
didn't realize it was a diy but that's
badass man
yeah it's pretty cool i'll show you what
it came like
and the first press i had um it was a
you know i'll say commercial press
meaning it was like
you know it was made commercially you
know it was a commercialized press it
was
like 500 bucks but it was a two-ton
um it was a two-ton press and the plates
were
two inches by two inches you know a
small little square so
which is which was kind of cool it got
me started because i didn't have that
much material so it was like the plate
size was ideal you know
but uh it was kind of junky you know i
just i worked with it
but when i found this this press i was
blown away i was like
it was day and night you know just for a
couple more hundred dollars
and it was a much much bigger place
these are four by eight plates that came
with originally
sick and uh you know this is the
original
harbor freight you know 20 ton hand pump
press which i prefer
i never time it this timer is used for
my my washes
you know i don't time my rosin questions
i just every press is different you know
everyone's asking time temperature the
temperature is based on me loading the
bags how melty it is in the bags
and then then i go i choose the
temperature you know and then
what range what range do you choose from
okay so uh i say low range if it's like
really
melting in the bag like i'm gonna press
it at 160 170
okay maybe one maybe 180 you know
that's like a low range like 160 to 179
mid range is like 180 to 200 204
and then anything between like 205 to
220 is pretty high you know
okay i mainly immediately live
in the 180 to 200 degree range um
even when i do get a great shit that
melts awesome
and i can't press it out at 160.
um sometimes my workflow and this comes
kind of flowing i have a lot of work to
do i just got to get it done with the
but i'll do like one press at 160 just
to check it out
and then i'll finish like the next five
presses at 180 and just kind of get back
in the rhythm you know what i'm saying
awesome fuck yeah yeah and as this press
has done so good um i've had it for a
long time
i am actually looking at upgrading
you know i've already did some upgrades
to it i had him change out the place
because um i liked i like how my bag
it fit better on these plates and the
rosin floors off faster
kind of got the idea from uh looking at
peer pressure plates you know
how they're long and skinny but i could
have the bag sitting on here
and then there's just about like an
eighth or a quarter inch on both sides
and the rods will fall off pretty
quickly
dude that's fine i like that a lot
but um yeah you know
always room for improvement you know
with everything
totally no that's fucking awesome man i
thought that was a machine that i just
you know i i am not too up you know
up to date with all the machines so i
just figured it was a legit one
that's fucking awesome one of the best
features too i like a lot
i don't use it too often anymore but it
was really fun it was like the trip mode
he has it
on a cradle yeah it could uh it's
against the wall a little bit but it
could it can go
full you know 180 degrees flat yeah
gotcha yeah that's badass and you know
the moment came out
a while ago you know it's pretty dope it
could just
drip all out right but
my plates are so small the rosin flows
off quickly
having it straight up and down is nice
yeah fuck
style yeah that's awesome dude
[Music]
yeah so you said you had a story on the
press
oh my bad brother that slurping slapped
me
a little bit the uh oh basically the
story
pretty much i kind of said it a little
bit uh it was it was a
like a 500 price and it was small it was
two times small plates
um when i when i would press it the
whole thing would rock you know i had to
like really hold it with one hand
press it with the other you know and
like
you know it was kind of hard it was a
learning press but it was pretty
expensive learning press
and uh this one like i said it was only
it was like 800 bucks you know and it
it kills it in volume it's 20 ton the
plates are bigger way bigger
it's way sturdier way heavier i don't
need to like
babysit it hold it with one hand and
press it with the other hand
so it was just the real lesson there for
me was just like
i always kind of had past things like
going with family owned or going with a
small guy you know
at least first you know if you're just
getting into it
go with the small guy first and check it
out and see if you like what you're
going to do before you
invest on the big big big you know fancy
stuff but
i bought like the name brand thing and
then you know i found this guy and he's
local
close fuck yeah you know he's a guy just
like me trying to
build his name and build the spot you
know throw a seat at the table you know
that's awesome man that's awesome that's
also what i really enjoy about the
solving this thing it's like
representing the farming
representing the quality of the farmer
and it's a teamwork process you know
so that's fucking awesome
100 man 100
it's all about the farmer for me because
i feel like i've lived off the farmer
like most of my life you know and that's
why i really want to
like the solving this wave seems to be
not gonna stop and gonna be like the new
thing and i think it's really going to
change as the industry is becoming this
new
legal conglomerate solveless
is right with it and it's all this is
new the legalization is new and i think
it's going to be a pretty big thing and
a lot of these farmers man they're old
school farmers and they've been growing
for me for a long time and i feel like
it's my duty to help these farmers and
give back and just
and share all my knowledge as i can you
know help them fuck yeah produce their
own solve on this line
you know at least get the basics down
get them started get the wheels moving
and you know they're growers man they
know what to do from there you know what
i'm saying
fuck yeah dude are you a grower
i say i'm a grower i grew i grew up here
and there just for something giggles
like
you know nothing serious though it
wasn't until
i decided to like um you know that this
is
what i want to do i started growing
seriously and then
in growing like in growing and finding
my
style which is like a living soil
method that's the style i put my
preference if i were to grow again would
be that
fuck yeah like once i started growing
and i found my style
i had to move and uh circumstances
changed
and then that's how i found myself on
this you know
window fuck yeah things will happen for
a reason you know
i really want to be a grower never knew
about solving this and now i'm like
super passionate about this like with my
ac
not working right now i haven't brought
washed in about
a week and i've been working having a
little depression with it man and having
to like
remember to refocus my energy that i'm
i'm kind of rebuilding the room
and when it's going again i want to
crush it harder you know so that makes
me happy it's like
it's a weird balance that i'm playing
with myself you know it's like i want to
wash
oh be patient because you're going to
crush you know it's like yeah i'm going
to crush and then
oh fuck i want to wash all this
beautiful shit in the freezer right now
seriously bro no i feel that for sure
what's going on with your ac
uh basic capacitor went out and the
the part at the stores it won't fit in
the compartment so i have to order
direct and
it's like a week out or whatever but
i've been wanting to get an ice machine
so i've ordered the ice machine as well
and that's pretty much almost all i
really need man besides
some new reservoirs and maybe a sink
and this would be a good machine man for
for
a good time coming for for a while but
the ice machines would be nice
oh man you guys oh dude
going on there too we have been
look at that though oh wow that looks
fucking beautiful bud
look oh oh boy
this is a 160 micron wow
cured is that cured i call it yeah for
sure cold carry it's been in the fridge
um oh i'm sorry was the material
cured that you washed no oh no it was
fresh fresh
okay yeah that looks fine that's fire
yeah i've never seen 160 that fire
right usually it's the trashies you know
i usually kind of mostly throw the 160
bag out in the 190 bag out
right or save it if it's clean but
usually it's all
plant plant materials up or something
but this shit was fire man fuck yes
like this is the kind of stuff that you
could do like
a true full spectrum like a two
washing the 220 catching the 45 and
that's it you know this stuff was really
nice maybe double bag
220 just to make sure no plant material
gets in there
but this was a really good nice guy
bros for resin how do you like how that
looks huh you want me to hold your
camera oh it was dang
could you yeah here real fast just film
this let's do a 2x
shoot yourself yes let me just
oh wow that smells beautiful
[Music]
that was a great one
i'm sorry what did you just say i was on
cloud nine for the second there
no i just feel like i've waited i've
waited so long for this hurricane
oh serious bro like a fresh frozen
slurky and i've washed the trim and it's
been
fire and expectations were met for sure
awesome that's awesome and yeah i
experienced it a few times in full melt
form but not in
like whole plant fresh frozen so that's
fucking
that's exciting i remember seeing it and
be like oh
damn yeah oh yeah
oh yeah i got a new a new farmer
that's actually uh that grows in soil
you know i'm super excited to work with
him nice and he's got some pretty cool
flavors too man
fuck yeah so so that's indoor
pandora yeah he has indoor and he grows
in a bunch of soil pots you know
awesome so if do you know any when you
were talking about growing indoor
or i mean growing living soil were you
talking about growing and doing indoor
grow
that's where that's where that's what i
was doing yeah i was indoor and i had
hps at the time
but my goal was to get leds you know but
then
you know that's what that's what my idea
was like
yeah can you can you tell jim about that
situation because basically he knows
more than i do about the actual growing
process but i know a lot of people
and i'm very interested in the living
soil thing so he said a couple things
like it would take a lot of ventilation
and stuff so i'm very curious he had
i'm curious how many lights did you have
in that group oh man no it was a
this is a closet grow you know it's like
experimental i was doing you know
it was it never got to um like
the real deal you know it was like it's
so
hard to do it on a large scale that's
why
to me it's very hard to do on a larger
scale to me
and i'm excited to find out how it can
be done
oh man i've seen um i don't i can't say
i'll have my head but i've seen some
guys
on you know future canvas projects he
did some interviews of
some pretty big facilities in uh in
nevada
oh what's a place called
darn somewhere in nevada close to vegas
and that facility is on point
like he had living soil down in my
opinion like there's something
sometimes
alien labs all those like very well
known
companies that are all from la and yeah
big money and but big advertising and
stuff
a lot of it but but the thing is what's
cool to me is that
nature ended up prevailing it's like
living soil ended up speaking so loud
that that's what's truly represented by
that stuff is that the quality is in the
is in the soil being alive and feeding
it properly and you know not just
feeding it salts or whatever the fucking
you know bullshit so it's very inch it's
extremely interesting to me
but um you know matt rise are you
familiar with matt rises work
uh yo like i not until like i
i wasn't until i started getting into
the game myself you know
and hearing his name more and more but
he wasn't someone i didn't follow
anybody man i just smoked weed loved to
plant
and tried to like grow it and and and
use it for free you know and
i wasn't following nobody trying to get
into it until just like
past couple years but i didn't know of
him for sure
you know and i see him i think he's
viewed as
like a leader in the industry you know i
hear he's an interesting character for
sure with the cat with the hash stuff
i'm just like recently i've just seen
him post a lot of stuff that's all
living soil indoor so i'm like
okay it really is like you know it's the
shit
you can't find it man i mean you you see
like no one can fight it it's weird it's
a living it's like you feed the soil
the soil is going to feed the plant and
it just proves it
and i'm not denying like because i work
with farmers that would grow assaults
and then they crush it as well
and it's pretty clean solvents i know
people kind of some people hate on me
that's really interesting that's awesome
because the reason i asked originally
here
about um about sourcing solventless in
l.a it's just because
straight up i mean you're posting on
fire but we literally like tried to
source on the on the rec market
um you know material out of la and we
found a few good sources but more so we
got stuff that
we weren't able to wash you know like it
didn't come out like and that's just
from the wreck market so i knew already
that
you know obviously people are growing a
lot of material down there and stuff
like that
but i was just curious how it is because
i see you post a lot of fire and stuff
so
it was very it's very intriguing to me
it's all in the grower man because i
worked
and i'm walking throwing the one under
the bus but i worked with his partner
and his ex partner and washed his stuff
from his row
no but this dude his bro it came out
nice you know and this is like
after this they split up and i think
maybe it's the flush
but the salt i haven't i don't know i
don't i don't grow
you know but i am actually
because i i'm working with a a new
farmer that's living soil
and i expected it to like kick its ass
you know i'm like oh man
if the salt hash is fire this guy's just
gonna be great
um and it was great you know but when i
go back and forth i'm like ah
you know it's the salt one's maybe
cleaner but maybe because i'm also
very very familiar with that guy's
interior material
and the living soil material is super
new and
the first round he gave to me it wasn't
um you know his first round
and it wasn't ideal i had a lot of
families in it you know and i had to
tell him to take the van leaf out and
he did it great
we're gonna grow pretty well i think i'm
pretty excited
about this new relationship fuck yeah
dude that's awesome i love that
so much the grower and the hatch maker
that's what i call it so if you
dude if you work with somebody that you
would like to do an interview with and
help and like talk to them and stuff i'd
really like to do that that's
one of my things i want to write
articles about that i've written a few
thus far and that that's one of my goals
is to kind of you know
the the relationship between the farmer
and the person that's making the stuff
into hash
you know it's intense oh yeah everything
it's all in the works right now man but
once like once i get a harmonious
relationship man
for sure we'll get in here and we'll
tell our story for sure fuck yeah
cool man well thank you very much man
it's been fun it's been awesome
appreciate you coming
thank you i appreciate it man cool fuck
yeah
fuck yeah so tim thank you for coming on
too man
oh i was just gonna say i'm doing an
indoor i'll send you a link to the
indoor we're putting together in
oklahoma yeah i figured you would be
able to answer some questions
about the uh indoor and the the living
soil and scaling and stuff like that
yeah you might have something to do
that's it
i was gonna say he's he's on point don't
get me wrong there's a couple of
questions actually a fellow in oklahoma
and i know quite a few they're
doing living so it's just uh there's
two different angles to the you know
every piece has a fit
and not every fit has a piece put it
this way not everybody
you know should do the same thing put it
that way
and the environment there because of the
the weather and different things if
you're going to do an indoor then
you're sealing it up and if you're
sealing it up and you bring in dirt
and you have to have bugs to make your
living soil work
so then you've got to decide what cover
crops you want to grow
to keep the insects happy and not
attacking your pot plants
so they're eating the other things
you're growing rather than your weed
and it's a competition so living soil
takes a couple of
rolls a couple of turns a couple of
grows to get
the soil right then you get into
mode per se and even the bester only is
so good
and that's where the difference is if
you're you know an
indoor the easier quicker and
cleaner operation to keep everything fda
and all that fun stuff is to go
i don't i hate to say it it's true
and the living soil is just more work
and and more attentive so you can do so
there's all kinds of things you can do
but not every operation is set up for
that
so i'm going to look at you know what
are these guys used to doing how they've
been doing
it what do they do normally or have they
even grown me
oh you got a big fight i know i would
stick with your head i think i talked i
don't know if i interrupted you guys i
apologize no
no no no no no yeah he's still on
exactly yeah connected but that's where
living soil is great don't get me wrong
i totally believe in it i
i truly do but it's like anything else
when you're spending like the operation
i'm talking about here
we're spending a quarter million dollars
on led lights
just for lights a half a million in soil
a half a million in soil well you know
that's what i mean it's it's a relative
you know so you've already built a half
million dollar building
and then you've insulated that and you
get it done you know what i mean
and it just keeps adding up so you've
done that
you know you've got to figure out how
you can be
on the market with a competitive product
pretty darn quick and not have to go
through
those getting your soil right hands
maybe
gotta feed those plants they gotta feed
you gotta feed them something
oh yeah yeah we're feeding them food
it'll be a salt base you know what i
mean
five more acres of doing outdoors so i'm
gonna know where he's there i figure i
can
light up the outdoors so i'll be fine
and the
soil's already they grow trees there so
this operation was a tree farm to start
with
and that's what they do already i've
already got the people already got the
equipment already got the land
already got everything else he hired me
and to do the consulting so that's what
i'm doing guys
so that's what i'm doing when i grow up
we all do
even when we grow up you know then back
in march i'll be there to start their uh
outdoor program because you know we got
to get things ready and then
start early and do a couple light deaths
how
how big is the square footage like the
property
oh it's a couple hundred acres over a
hundred hundred and a half 160
something like that so i'm getting a
five acre parcel just for the week
and then i've got the warehouses 20 000
square going up
three quarters building they're going in
australia
the steam tape all the seams there's
totally no right leaks now so now
they're going to go into foam spray the
whole thing
then all the pvc walls go in and
everything else for all the fda
cleanliness and blah blah blah
let's feel the cement about a hundred
thousand dollar freeze dryer coming so
we're gonna do freeze-dried weed
and we'll be able to do the bubble house
but i've already got 9091803 is hooked
up to do all the
bubble hashing so i've hooked him up for
everything we're just going to do the
top buds
his shelf buds that's going to get
freeze dried
that's a great way to do it you know
save the big good buds for the packs
watch the rest you know and the other
thing is there's nobody doing a
good size operation per se and doing any
freeze dry in there yet there's a couple
little ones on the edges
you know doing small stuff but mainly
half so it's like anything else there's
not
there's very few doing weed that's why i
went talked to richard again with cannon
freeze and
and started working with him and can get
new units because i basically ran out of
reconditioned units
[Music]
the markets you know there's no more
they don't make that many
you know when you get to in between a
harvest right and an
industrial there's only a few like the
lava rubber fork
you know that whistler is pushing around
they do they have dealers here too
and it's a very good machine you know if
you're going to buy
two or three pharmaceutics then maybe
you should buy one of those
i think they replaced roughly two they
say three but i think that's pushing the
edge
so have you seen anybody use the harvest
right uh
deal yeah i was i was wrong with tyler
today there with worcester tech and i
feel behind you
a lot of times too where people get
interrupted with freeze dryers is
you got to remember what you're doing
when you're supplementing
bubble hatch you're not supplementing
the water through a tissue
it's not in the trichome it's outside
the tricode
so it's very easy to sublimate water
when it's not going through a tissue or
a material or a cell wall
okay it's simple that's the easiest
thing a freeze dryer could ever do
the trouble with them is their valving
and pressures
and their algorithm is just not made for
what we do
and it's slow not as delicate the plates
only heat on the top and the bottom not
each plate is heated
that's why the the leather bar you know
it's 15 grand
but basically by the time you get
everything right you're going to be
about 20 grand for one of them
right and now you can pair them up
though you could run two of those off
one air air unit tyler was showing that
today
it's a good unit there's nothing wrong
with it in fact it's very good because
you get all the sensors you need and
everything else
goes down to 0.1
atmospheres so yeah it goes down to damn
near
flat zero
so it's really pulling the vacuum and
that's the key and then the
refrigeration units are the right sides
and the temperature probes are in the
right place
that's what matters you know the
algorithm on that and that's where
drying weeds the same way there's been
some issues with wheat and that's where
people have had problems is
harvest rights don't don't evaporate
properly in valving that's they're just
bad you can actually buy
if you want a new weed in a harvest
right there's about a 2500
algorithm and a couple of valving
attacks which you can buy through this
other
lab company that makes them work better
quote unquote but you know if you're
already spinning four grand or five
grand
and now you gotta spend 2500 bucks to
make it work right come on
all right that's kind of it and then and
then if your harvest ride breaks
you shit out of luck you basically
bought a boat anchor if you can't fix it
yourself
yeah that's true no i'm serious i got
i got a guy from canada sent me a deal
today three out of five of the brand new
ones they got in
right the shelves in there weren't even
riveted on one side and like two of the
shelves were just at a
total angle right and that was our brand
new
unpackaged getting ready to go out to a
customer
three out of five so we got two
but like that's just what you can see
visibly
can you imagine what could go wrong
under there
and i i'm not you know don't get me
wrong i get no money from nobody that
makes these other than categories i
worked with them but that's a very large
machine
i mean we're talking hundred grand and
stuff like that you know the little
one's 30 grand
okay those are the ones i told them to
put on the shelves of stock
but it's equal to three harvest rates in
size and volume
and it is a machine that will last you
as long as you live until you die
it's not like that how big is it
physically big is it well the the
size of the smallest unit is roughly
about three not even quite four feet
deep
and maybe a little over two feet wide
maybe three feet tall wow you know
they're not extremely large well
it's on a cart so you got from the floor
up so yeah maybe it's
four foot tall total right and two and a
half wide
and about three or four deep it's not
that big no the right size is here
better and the key to that see those
that yeah
the key to that is its warming system
is not on individual strategies that's
why it takes longer
but what it is is the machine is made
that way that's where
a real smart guy he's been building
these things for 30 years he's working
for everybody
and he's been to all the different
countries where they make them the
factories of mankind
and that's why when he designed these
that he's selling now
he designed it himself and he's having a
built in the factory that he thinks is
the best in the world in england
and they're using all the best parts
that come mainly out of germany and
england
but they've been building them for over
30 years right
and they know what the hell they're
doing so he said okay here's what i want
because the past few years i think
people were kind of pushing them around
as to how they wanted it
rather than how the machine really works
it's like everything you can't
turn a barber's gear you know into a
sheepshear they just don't work the same
right you know you can't make a ferrari
out of a volkswagen i don't care how
many volkswagen parts you bring me
i can't make a ferrari right so it's the
same kind of a thing you've got to
understand the parts so they're making
the best stuff and
there's a warranty you get service you
got a problem bang it's fixed
right that's the big difference there
too because that's one thing with
harvest
it really it's been for years that way i
mean i'm not speaking out of school
i don't think you can find anybody that
hardly that hasn't had a problem with
them if they
had a breakage with their machine or
something go wrong you know what i mean
knock on wood man i know yeah true
i i seriously i i feel i feel for the
people because
i say this guy up in canada he ordered
five
brought in five and only two of them he
can sell the other three now he's got to
return
back to china right i mean come on
and he's a dealer yeah he's a dealer
and they work okay fine for bubble hash
to be honest
i say that's why i tell people you know
for the money and the fact that what
they are
if you're starting out now then yeah
that's probably your best step
because you're just supplementing the
water away you're not pulling it through
the cells
you're not pulling it out of the
trichome so it's a simple operation
so it functions you know what i mean it
works
but you know the trouble is is you're
flipping the dice
whether you're going to get a bad one a
good one hopefully yours lasts
forever you know what i mean but you
never know and i've seen too many of
them fail when you say this guy today
well yeah it was funny it was yesterday
it was like we were talking about it two
days before because he wanted me to do a
zoom up there in canada with him doing a
show
and you know we were talking and we were
talking about this very thing
and it's it's sad because there's not
something to the leather cover
is probably the best in betweener right
now the factor that you can
buy one for roughly 20 000 okay and it's
roughly
three harvest right okay when you get to
that volume that's okay
right then it's equal money more or less
right so then you can also that with
one vacuum pump then buy another machine
for
it's like 13 grand if you buy just the
machine parts without the vacuum pump
and you can hook two two machines up to
one vacuum pump
so you can save a little bit there and
double your volume
right and operate that way but it's
still
you know it's all money now and i hate
to tell people but it's like the morax
gonna pass
while it pass through congress it'll
it'll pass through this next year no
doubt
the trouble is is that's when the
billionaires walk in not the
millionaires now kids
because this is going to be hardball
because now the bankers can get in and
play and we can play stock market and we
can play all kinds of fun games
and it ain't going to be the junior
league millionaires and it's going to be
the billionaires that come in and just
suck shit up i'm not going to like
sucker fish on the bottom man it's
already happened i mean
look at all the companies that have sold
out already general hydroponics should
they sell out too
all right that was that toro who's
general hydroponics
right i mean you know you tell me it's
just going to be that way they're going
to keep eating it up the
thing that people got to really watch
seriously for you guys
is the local laws like right now they're
trying to make it so
if you're say a patient you got a
medical card right well
you're sick and you want to make rso
because you got cancer or something
right you're making an rso for your
patient or yourself
they're making it illegal to do that in
your home kitchen
damn it's in the law read it
in cali even people got to wake up and
not just
i think that the guy over there with the
politicians doing it for us
because they're not dude look around
who's paying all these taxes and they're
they're they're squeezing everyone out
of the middle
there's going to be you might be able to
grow a couple plants at home later
and then the corporate you're gonna have
to buy everything they want you to buy
everything so they get their taxes
period
i'm sorry that's life that's it's the
way reality is
and now they're trying to squeeze out
the middle
and if people don't keep fighting you
know how did this all
start how did how did marijuana become
medically legal in california how
how long ago and why was it
cancer patients and aid patients in san
francisco
we're dying and it was found to be a
remedy for things like
gee you're getting chemo hey smoke some
weed you'll get hungry and it worked
so we we're riding on the backs of
medical patients here but yet
everybody's you know letting the
corporate thing just fly off it's the
old
and it's like the bhl and everything
else i say the same thing that was in
the pharmaceutical industry
stepped into this industry and put their
foot in it just like they did
the pharmaceutical industry that
corporate oil industry
kept petrochemical industry went into
the pharmaceutical market and took it
over we can make sulfur we can make this
we can make that we just mix it together
and hey there you go
all right we're not on homeopathic
medicine or organic medicine no no no
we're we're making it by the barrel full
over here out of synthetic shit
right now what did they do with bho and
and propane and all these other things
now
alcohol is alcohol we've been doing that
for hundreds of years but
you know all of those processes sure
they they're very functional because
you're liquefying the trichomes they
have to
all come because they just got liquefied
right in butane so now we've sucked all
them off and now we're going to bring
them back and we just hope we can get
all the butane out
now granted we test all that stuff here
but you know in reality
you can do anything solventless that you
could do with butane propane and all the
rest of them
they just didn't believe it back then
because they didn't know how
they did not know how it was like making
diamonds you know making diamonds
it's almost hilarious because there's
people doing that and people go oh no no
shatters shatters it man you guys got to
be shattered
some shatter it's no good that was that
yeah it's like
bullshit that's thc crystals they're
like oh no that's not no no no it can't
be better it's too
good it shatters it you know what i mean
it was stupid
and it's now i like to tell people when
you start a bsu or propane operation
like that
you know you're gonna literally need at
least a million
dollars right out the gate just for the
building permits and the bullshit
then you get to buy the equipment all
the rest the crap for the next million
okay well all those guys got all that
money invested in all those buildings
and everything else that they did
and they got to pay it back they got to
pay for it they didn't buy it all with
cash they bought they took loans and
everybody else did whatever they did
and sure enough you know now they've got
to keep them running because they got to
pay for all that crap
but you could you could set up a bubble
hash operation for 200 000 tomorrow
and have a commercial operation going if
you got a permit
is that right i needed to hear that tim
you're the fucking man
is it isn't it true is it i don't know
that
it's that simple cheers buddy seriously
if
you had 200 grand there deal um you know
if you had 200 grand do you think you
could get your small warehouse set up a
wash operation get one of those nice
passion trines i sell you or something
like that no
or whatever a whistler or whatever you
want to buy a delta i don't care get a
frenchie
get an ice checked uh whatever i'm just
saying you can set up a nice little
commercial operation with a nice
hundred thousand dollar freeze dryer
sitting there just
banging yeah now you don't have to go
through all the bullshit that you do
with bho you don't have to have like a
bomb
special yeah
[Music]
plus the permit plus the inspections to
go with it
plus the halon gas plus it is but you
know i mean
it's all more and more all you've got to
do is have ice and water and you want a
big water filter
you know i'd be dumb too but anyway i'm
throwing a couple plugs in here for
fun because it's been a shit day today
we're the only ones in the world that
can do this
and i'm like really well here check this
website because these guys do the same
thing
oh no but they can't do this i said well
maybe you should read the specifications
because they do do that
it does exactly the same thing exactly
the same ionic process exactly the same
you know alkaline process for making
alkaline water done you know
don't get me wrong but science is not
that hard and i got a master's degree in
science so you know i can read that kind
of shit
somewhat and you know like i say then
all of a sudden it's like
you're attacking me you know you're
being rude stop saying
like wait a minute i'm sending you facts
you're saying it's the only one on earth
that can do it you're saying this the
only company that makes it
and i'm sending you links to companies
that make identical equipment and you're
telling me i'm wrong
it's because it's a it's bullshit
corporate like
it's haters cultures we're the best
it's new we're the ones they're cultures
it's a cult you get a company like that
what they do
is they feed you full of all this yeah
they've been doing it for 48 years great
hey the company in south korea has been
doing it over 30. okay fine
they do it for the medical industry
there for the hospitals it's all
approved in south korea they make some
good shit you know what i mean
we buy a lot of it and uh yeah good the
other one's made in italy okay
here's the thing i send you the spec
sheets on them both
right and you tell me if the other one's
worth four
thousand dollars more
okay because i guarantee you they're
identical
and actually the one i'm going to send
you that's cheaper
you don't have to clean it at all you
don't have to stop the machine every
four hours and pour a special solution
in and run it through to clean it every
five for five minutes
and then once a year send it back to the
factory hell no the south korean one
they come up with the new technology and
alter the frequencies and they bounce it
off the plates
and they keep the place from ever
growing anything on them so they sell
clean so you never have to shut it off
and it runs forever
[Music]
which one would you buy right and that's
the point like
you know that oh you you must be working
for them blah blah blah you're
trying to destroy me i'm like hey lady
look i'm sending you facts
you're the one calling cussing me out
using foul language i've never used that
then all of a sudden here comes her
husband now he's saying hey what are you
doing harassing my wife you're you're a
predator
she's at home trying to school her kids
and
and you're a predator attacking her i'm
like dude i sent her links
to check specifications and told her she
was wrong
check the facts and if that's being
a predator then i'm sorry but that's the
trouble with this social media
you guys get all burned up and then you
start using foul language because you
you believe everything's free over here
nobody's going to know who you are or
whatever
and i can call you or whatever and you
know make all these foul accusations
about you
right yeah which i don't do i never do
on any social media and people that not
only know that
no i'll tell you hey look go check the
facts
so that's when she started doing that i
said well held it i went online and yeah
hey
you guys want to know where hydrogen
water where you can get it get it here
you want to know where you can get this
check it here
check the difference check the specs
check the models
check the service check everything you
decide
i never tell people you know unless i
gotta have a paying client
i don't tell them what to buy exactly or
you know give them my opinions because
bottom line there's too many variables
but when you're telling people you're
the only one in the world that does this
and makes that and there's two companies
i sent her two links
there's two companies that make the
exact same product one of them's
identical to theirs
and the other one just makes the
cleaning there's actually it was really
cool just
be good thinking covered and all that
right now right got to clean things
so this comes as like a spray bottle
kind of like one of those
409 bottles right and it's got a little
base on it electronic you plug it in
where you put you put water in you put
salt in like two teaspoons of salt
and then you got a little squirter of
vinegar you squirt a little vinegar in
and it's even
stronger and a better sterilizer and
cleaner than the keg in 2.5
because you don't add vinegar to it but
that when
it comes out you put it on this little
stand in like 30 minutes
it makes that container sterile water to
use anywhere in your you know
house whatever on your hands your
surfaces clean whatever you want
right so it's a home cleaner so you
never buy 409 or
oven cleaner or whatever again just buy
one of those put it on the
sink with this little stand and it's
plugged in and ready to go all the time
i gotta cool this out catalog
i'm sorry i gotta see the tim catalog
i'm curious what the the washing machine
no it's like anything i you know don't
get me wrong it's
there's too much information out there
and i've traveled the world i use those
machines over in asia
and i knew there was a couple of
different makers there's there's always
an
asian maker at least part of asia the
thing is
like when you go to where they sell
motorcycles
there's at least three of them and in
within a
throw a stone's throw of each other they
always do that
if there's a guy with a tire shop next
you know two stores down it'll be
another tire shop
that's just the way it is they group
together i don't know why i don't know
why it's
the way it is but it seems like in asia
it's the same way if somebody's making
something and it's working and it's good
hey we can make that too and they start
making it too now like i say these guys
that are making these have been doing it
over 30 40 years so
they're as good as the guys in italy i
mean i trust them
they got a warranty and everything and
they're good for it they got it actually
in operation in la
so you could actually go and you know
get shit but
the other company does a hospital sales
group
accountants a little uh you remember
shackley vitamins you ever hear them
no okay anyone anyway it's a progressive
system where
you know hey i we're all friends and da
da da and there's a progressive deal
where okay we'll let you have this
area that's your area to sell right and
then you get a percentage off the sales
in that area or the content
fine just don't lie people
just don't lie it's kind of like the
streets
this is mine well then
it cracked me up because tonight i get a
call from my buddy at silly gloves
he's like hey man uh do you know this
lady
i'm like yeah she said what has been she
keeps
telling me i'm harassing her in this and
all i'm doing is say stop responding
but no she wants to bitch me out so now
she's going to talk to you thinking what
you're my boss he goes yeah
you know he laughed he goes he says i
ain't his boss man
i said he said i told him what's what he
goes well i just don't want the name i
said look
you know me i don't attack people i
don't use foul language never have
wouldn't do it right but the bottom line
is
though these people are insulted that i
busted them
okay they're insulted because they
couldn't refute the facts
they just kept coming up with other
excuses that i'm an asshole or i'm a
this or
there's that or oh it's an iso standard
well an iso standard yeah i'm a i'm a
sigma
sigma black belt okay six sigma black
belt you teach iso
i trained iso in africa i know what an
iso
certification is it's a quality control
certification
for the manufacture of the equipment it
has nothing to do with comparing that
thing to anything else
okay ul labs you see the ul labs stamp
on shit right
i've had my products go through ul labs
you know what ul labs does
the ul labs takes whatever you say the
machine or whatever the part will do
whatever it is it'll take this much heat
it'll last this long
it'll wear this much it'll take this
kind of heat it'll taste this guy
whatever it is you say
they test it and if it does what you
said it would
you all snap no problem there's no
comparison of products
so you can't just say oh well you know
this one's better because it has a stamp
on it
well maybe it is maybe it isn't maybe it
makes it safe maybe it makes it so
everything they said is true
so if they take everything they said is
true and i compare it to the other stuff
over there that's all true
and they're both once better than the
other then i can choose right
no problem i got it
so anyway it's just kind of hilarious i
like the way things go
on me and get him to tell me to stop
that's crazy that's really kind of what
my friend said that's
kind of what sean said in colorado he
kind of laughed he goes well you do what
you need to do he says uh
you know some of your silo looking
whatever i said hey sean you know me
i'll send you all the emails i'll send
you all the the instagram bullshit that
they sent me and you see who said what
and who did what
okay that's all i got to say you know me
man i deal on facts
i don't deal with bullshit here you go
this is what i said please check these
facts check the specifications
check this company check that company is
that being rooted obnoxious i don't
think so i think it's like
hey i'm trying to prove a point that
maybe you need to change your verbiage
to say
we're one of the companies in the world
that can make this
how's that that's being stupid
but i knew as well as you know they
wouldn't say that they wanted to believe
because they're in their little cult but
if you name the water something else it
becomes something else no it's alkaline
water
that's all it is it's alkaline water
sorry engine water the cans and water
it's the kangen water right what was it
the candy water
yeah i'm sorry but you know that kagan
thinks that
they came up with you know we call it
pagan and if we call it kagan then
that means it's special okay but it's
really just alkaline water
well but it's kagan well but it's just
alkaline water
but how do you get into the alkalinity
you can get a lot of different ways i
think
i guess it's got to have some well
when you get down you get 2.5 you have
to add salt to it or
you would have to have some salt water
in your water when it makes it because
it goes through an electroplating
and the electroplates then alter the ph
of the water down to two five
but you need a lot of salt in the in the
water and it needs to be fairly cool too
colder than better actually but again on
the other side
when you go to the high side you know if
you're going acid or you're going
you know unsalty so you can use them for
different things but you can
you can be drinking up in the eight
nines
right alkalinity because an alkaline
body cannot grow cancer
cancer cannot grow in an alkaline
environment period won't
can't that's why fish don't have it
at least ocean fish what other kind of
things
you know an alkaline environment kills
itself bottom line you should be
drinking a higher ph
but then again for cleaning you want a
lower ph and of course for your plants
you want something in the middle there
hey tim i get a lot of dms
asking me about the ph in hash and they
ask me if i've noticed
hash in different phs and
talking with you
what was that i said if you want to
waste it tested it go ahead
that's my thought on it don't get me
wrong but first off you'd have to figure
out how to
test the ph in the rosin or in the oil
itself so that way you'd have to at
least get it melted and out of the
trichome right
and then you'd have to actually decarb
it
to get it to be the effect of when
you're actually in taking it when you're
inhaling it doing a
nail or whatever right okay it has to be
decarb at that point
so that's where you need to take the
test right
not the water itself actually that
you're washing the material in
well no no well when you're washing in
the water oh the water you yeah okay you
wash water excuse me wash water should
be somewhere in the neutrals
as i would say and what you can do
though is you see there's some tricks
you can play with water
if you over oxygenate water you're gonna
become an oxidizer
in other words it'll eat bio material so
you want to eat out that
microscopic bile material you have that
everybody has
because it's almost impossible to wash
away well guess what
i've got a water that actually eats that
shit and takes it away it doesn't hurt
the trichome
or the trouble a little bit
yeah there's different ways to do that
i've actually got a test running right
now
where we're just using oxygen because i
found that
a lot of through the testing i was doing
that uh
i was able to take away a lot of the the
negative things that the
arsenics or borons of whatever it may be
up to some of them leads in that are the
toughest but uh
i was able to to remove them with just
oxygen over oxygenated water
you have to get up in the really high
percentages though you got to get up
into 200 percent of normal and better
right there's ways to do that that
aren't that expensive
and then there's ways to do that are
very expensive depending on your volume
period
it's it's all a relative so that's why i
offer that go to grow now because
it's actually an electronic air
oxygen or water oxygenator this is not
really
just like a bubbler okay what it does is
actually have two
plates once again they use electrostatic
ions
so these plates are 25 millimeters or
microns apart microns apart excuse me
and then what that causes is it causes
through the electrostatic
action of the electricity they actually
split the molecule the h2o
the h which is a small one it breaks off
easily and then it escapes through the
top of the tank it goes out of the water
the two oxygen molecules are now small
enough to then be absorbed into the
water
so that's where you get a higher
dissolved oxygen content in your water
and that's something that everybody
should be testing and checking because
if you're using a well actually in the
country it can be very low
you could have very little oxygen in the
in the actual water from a well
where in the study they a lot of times
compare or they use very very large
alkaline systems like we're talking
about here and when i'm talking about
that we're talking about plates that are
the size of four by eight sheets of a
metal or a wood you know what i mean
huge and they do like 5 000 gallons a
minute kind of fucking pumping through
them right and they're just these giant
plates and what they're doing is once
again they're
sending a they're changing it into a
hypochloric acid
the water you actually over ph it and
you
basically chlorinate it but you're not
chlorinating it with the salt
you're connecting it with hydrogen and
oxygen so it's
hypochloric acid so then it's a
sterilizer it's a cleaner
you can use clean surfaces clean
yourself whatever
totally non-poisonous so you got to get
it way down it's got to be hypochloric
to work
properly but you can do that and they
use that in the sewage business for
doing sewage plants and that before
it'll exit
out to the ocean and shit they'll have
one of those giant machines i
saved these plates the size of freaking
48 sheets of plywood
and they'll be running a shitload of
water through it from the from the
operation
and they force it into that exit pipe
and then kind of sterilize the pipe and
that last bit of the water that's going
out
so you're saying to the the ph should be
neutral
and also it needs to be oxygenated like
have oxygen
this is where i like to say there's no
books on this that's why i've been doing
this shit for a couple years now
and i use ozone when we get up into
volumes and i used oxygen
because i found that oxygen over using
ozone and i had oxygen
i found that i could just use the oxygen
and get a certain effect now i'm
working on to see if we can make enough
with these machines
to make it functional so it's a
reasonable price it doesn't cost you an
arm and a leg
to get that right because that's the
trouble with all this like my small
equipment for doing it
properly i guess i'd say that way is uh
starts at 20 grand and goes up right and
you
and it pulls water it's good for a 10
000 square foot indoor
or doing a water remediation right now
we're working i'm working with all the
different
machine makers on remediating the
waste water from from bubble hashing and
returning the water back and filtering
out all the crap
as well as the terpenes some of the
companies want to recover the terpenes
and like i told them i don't want to i'm
not going there because then you've got
to start using chemicals
there's just no two ways to do it out of
water
without using chemicals after it's in
the water the terpenes become liquid
because they'll actually the water will
go through the cell wall of turkey
you know i actually enter the trichome
wall through the champion if you're not
careful
that's how you get that purple hash that
people post and like right
well actually i you know i uh
there's so many you know the the
purpling
i mean back in doing this way too long
but back in the day
no one really knew and then it made
sense that in the fall
they changed color to attract insects to
pollinate and that's really where that
gene
comes from in the plant is they change
color so they get that red spectrum
so that the different you know bees and
different things see it more
because they they attracted to red
spectrums right
so connect to that line they they'll
alter now
some of the strains are that way to keep
them you know keeping bread
basically to get insects to come by and
hopefully follow him
but i see it if you get into the some of
the microscopic shots of triathlons
you'll notice that
a lot of times it's the terpenes that
are actually change the color
the actual trichome itself the actual
resin in the trichome the stuff that
we're really
dealing with more stuff inside the shell
right it doesn't have any color it's
clear as a bell
yeah but it'll be the trichome leafs you
know the daisy pattern on the bottom
of drag or turbine excuse me will have
turned purple
and then you'll notice it starts to go
out because the i don't know french you
agree too
you know and i i i think the same way
it's like
a human body you know we sweat poison
and pretty much the trichomes are
somewhat that they're
the plant is putting off its poison
which is arousing into that trichome
and you know there's a few day window
there
where it actually is it's ripest over
the whole plant
on an average and catching that is tough
but
everybody likes to really clear stuff
now so everybody's picking it a little
early it seems too there's ways to play
that game and
a few of the big companies have been
doing it forever you know they'll pull
it 35 days
that kind of shit right there they're
just going for
you know the clear the white the color
and you know to each his own everybody's
got their process
you know i'm not going to imagine they
have a pretty good production
35 days oh yeah
i mean you know it's like it's like
anything else depends on
every operation is different and that's
why like this one i'm going to go out
there and work with them because
you know when you're setting up
something like that it was one of those
where to be honest with you it was
it was going to be soil pretty much
until all the pieces and parts
you know he already had gotten halfway
there per se
and when i looked at what he had i said
look you know you've spent
you're going to spend a small fortune
here and what you're doing
and i know you've already done half of
that and you're going to make this a
sterile environment
and then you're going to bring dirt in
and we're going to have to allow bugs to
do certain things right
because they're going to be there we
can't kill them off and have a living
soil
right it doesn't work that way
right so then you've got to put in
control
animals and so forth and you've got to
play the game with
keeping them eating the food on the
cover crop you got going and that kind
of stuff and
and play the game with them right well
that's that's a complicated operation to
explain to somebody and have somebody
just start
new at with a 20 000 foot square right
i mean that's some dirt man that's some
property you know what i mean
the simple operation for somebody who
doesn't has never grown weed
is to grow hydroponics because it's more
controllable plus the fact
i'm bringing in all tissue culture
there's i've got a dog's doing all the
tissue culture for us so boom
everything will go in tissue culture so
they're exact replicas
they'll grow the same be you know seed
green perfect
the same height same width same
everything in the plant so
that makes it much easier to grow inside
too and especially hydroponics so we can
roll them quicker like you say
i'm hoping to do it you know 45 days or
so
i'd like to hit 45 50 days and roll and
you know
do it like that we've got a freezer
already bought and going down
so everything will go crowd trimmed
it'll be trimmed right well boxed
trimmed
and then put right in the freezer and
then after it does 24 hours in the
freezer
at minus 20 then it starts to go to the
freeze dryer and we'll
we'll be able to do roughly 30 pounds of
finished dry per run
20 to 30 somewhere in that range per run
and that's every less than 24 hours
roughly
and then i'll have a 24 hour to a 48
hour
rejuvenation time before we'll be able
to send it to the distributor for
packaging
but we'll basically from start from
harvest
to finish will be a week
i need to learn to get on that level
and i don't mean for myself man because
i want to i want to get there i feel
like
we got like the new generation and the
now generation
like the incoming
yeah you guys still using buckets and
canoe paddles right like i was 40 years
ago
okay yeah and this is all new
frank will tell you this i've been
saying this so look man it's 20 20 you
guys
you kids come on now you i know you know
better
all right you got all these electronic
fucking things you guys can beat the
fuck out of me in those
games on tv and shit right i don't play
that my thumbs don't do that crap
right but you guys know all this
computer shit but i don't see any
computer i see a canoe paddle and a
trash can
right okay come on man come on
right that can't be i mean you know and
i
the thing is it does work but then i
look at the equipment that's being made
and people are you know all everybody's
trying to understand how they can
manipulate
the weed in the ice and water and not
hurt the plant
well how about how about i answer that
simple question
you can't it will
injure the plant material how's that it
will
if you've got ice in with plant material
it's gonna run into it they're gonna
smash together
it's gonna cut stuff off on a sharp edge
it's gonna rub
things together or get squeezed between
and chlorophyll is not a tough material
so
you know and yeah you're getting it cold
so it gets tougher as it gets cold and
all that fun stuff but you're still
gonna
have all that that micro biomass
right and just rub off stuff
so you got to learn how to sip it out
and filter it out where that's where
changing the water
and making it an oxidizer or using
different things you know
oh alkali whatever oxygenation whatever
it may be and there's
just depending on the volume again of
your operation
is which one would fit for you because
like you say at a certain level i mean
the
for the machine people i'm talking with
all of them you know that that
that the unit to go on to their machine
is going to start at twenty thousand
okay it probably will end up somewhere
between there and thirty
right and that's gonna be the add-on to
that
hashtag machine that ice machine
whatever it is a
whistler tech whatever it may be because
these people are knocking out you know
some of them doing a thousand gallons of
wastewater a day
right and that ease back east they can't
put it down the rain they won't let them
because after about
24 hours that shit because the terpenes
are mixed into the water
the bacteria is just love that shit and
it starts to wreak and stink
it just starts to smell if you keep it
around if you don't wash it down a drain
or get rid of it somewhere
you leave it around for a day to two
days i'll guarantee you're going to
start smelling it
you know can you water the garden with
it you think
well no the trouble is is the terpenes
have washed off and all the dirt
whatever was on the plant is in that
water
and then there's trichomes too because
you know it's the bottom end and the
top end whatever they clutch so what
they're doing is they're putting a
thousand gallons a day in a tank in the
ground
and then they had a waste company come
in and there's 75 grand a year to haul
away the waste water
all right so now they can buy a water
treatment machine for 50 grand
turn all that water back into water they
can use and the waste they can haul to
the dump themselves because it's not
hazardous anymore
because i can take arsenic 2 and make it
arsenic 3 different things like that
see what is that i was i wasn't insulted
at all
they're facts for facts like i'm
literally just starting this
and you clearly have the experience and
i want to learn that
i mean don't get me wrong
i've been doing this a long time and
like you know
bird says this class i used to say in my
classes what i teach too
i don't i'm not smarter than anybody in
the room
i just work harder at it do you have
anyone like
under you that is like that you're
training to be like you
oh no no and i'm not the hash guy i'm
not
i'm not the ash guy i'm not i know
equipment i know processes i know
chemistry and you know that kind of
stuff and i always try and find that how
can we do it better
how can we make this simpler how can we
make the process
better you know and you know it's like
hand trimming weed
i'll tell you everybody in the world
hand trimming weed is the best way to
trim
as long as you only got 10 pounds okay
but if you're going to do 90 000 pounds
how are you going to do that yes how
many trimmers are you going to bring in
unsustainable yeah you can't it's it's
not scalable as we call it you can't
increase that business you can't make it
go from five employees to a hundred
employees to a thousand employees to
five thousand employees
because i guarantee you it's gonna start
killing people
you know it's too many humans it's just
too many humans in the loop
the more ways you can get humans out of
the loop in production
the better to a point okay a lot of
times and that's where in bubble hashing
i just kind of
laugh because it you know you get into
using trash cans well now you gotta have
two burly guys to haul that shit
well now of course if you're legal oh
boy you gotta worry about workman's comp
did the guy hurt his back
has he got the right leverage just to
wait too much is this that that
is the distance between here and there
right you know it's the floor non-slip
you know i mean it's
it becomes and then i have to tell
people you got to understand these rules
aren't going to get
better they're getting worse and they
will be getting worse
and they don't want you a little guy to
make it
period yeah okay you've got to keep
pushing for the medical you got to keep
pushing
for the medical permitting to be stay
there
it needs to be actually increased and
prop 64 in my opinion needs to be thrown
out but that's me
you know because it never was what they
they turned it over to every thief them
every city and county to to charge their
own little thief and taxes and make
their own rules like they always do
and what have they all done look around
right
you know is it working anywhere is
anybody you know what's happening to the
people in the middle
nothing you know they're getting crushed
just like all the restaurants
in the middle it's really sad but yeah
i hear that i hate to see this because i
think there's these super
secret sessions and all that i totally
believe in them
but on the same side there what really
bothers me
because that's the medical you know
that's the 215 right that's
a you know what i mean that's the one
right
and you go there and nothing there is
tested
generally right
and you go to the dispensary where it's
all tested but it's not medical
right oh well you got medical
dispensaries too i'm sorry
but then you go to the recreational one
and oh yeah anyone can come in here and
buy anything and oh yeah and this is
tested stuff
so it's like wait a minute we started
off trying to help medical patients
because we had cancer
and aids going on wild and everybody
thought
yeah this works but yeah let them be
able to eat after chemotherapy that's
good okay they're dying anyway god damn
it let them eat
right that was good and then what did
that morph into
where are we now right did it get better
for the patients i don't see these
companies that are making millions of
dollars
and millions of dozens i don't see them
going to cancer words and giving
free free whatever that patient wants
you want edibles you
want smoke you want god's what do you
want here you go
boom right there terminal jesus
christ try and help him you know what i
mean it can't be that bad now hopefully
the more act does allow for science
studies and all that
but once you throw the banking in and
allow it
it's going to get really wild and
hopefully the people that have got their
foot in the door and that can keep their
head above water and there's all i can
say because i just don't see it
becoming easier and i know you're doing
great and i'm not putting down
anyone and saying hey start and do
whatever you think you need to do
okay do that and if you can concentrate
and doing it honestly
and doing it respectfully people will
respect that and you will keep doing
business
that's all i gotta say in that respect
but you know if you go out and set
making things and making false claims
and shit
i guarantee you you you're getting
pushed aside people will write you off
[Music]
you know i mean i hate to be it's like
this week it's been a cataclysm of
what the hell you know i was talking to
i i was going through some stuff i
pulled out oh yeah my chalice giant
judges kid
oh yeah i remember this thing we never
had the chalice cup god damn it
right i got the whole thing all the
pipes all everything the
brand fucking knew because hey guess
what i never got to go hear the music
there was
never an event all right got a few
samples you know
not many but yeah i guess time i guess
but it's like
you know now guys going swag right
it's like come on man how about giving
people back money for their booths and
money for their uh judges kid or
whatever you know
that kind of stuff how about uh what
happened there you know you did oh you
didn't get your license so you folded on
everybody sorry
gee it's a tough life i'm really a good
guy but gee
i just lied to everybody and took their
money
yeah i'm sorry i have a hard time with
people like that
yeah i and i'm getting old to the point
now where
you know fuck you i don't give a shit
because guess what
you can't hurt my reputation i'm already
too goddamn old
[Laughter]
i don't know that's how i feel about it
and i know sometimes i come off a little
girl for people people go oh whoa
say look i tell you the truth here it is
facts you know take it or leave it
that's how i am thank you i've gotten
over that for bullshit you know how long
you know that well we've got 25 years
experience between all of us and yeah
okay fine
now can we just get to talking business
and get on with work you know and not
you know having it like
mine's bigger than your contest you know
this is saying
there's a lot of love a lot of hype a
lot of bullshit out there
like i was saying um tim i i would like
to
to uh how can i follow you more
you know i have to get going here but i
want to see him streaming
streaming and consulting but he said
skin thing is when it pops out on
instagram me
no worries and then i have to say
there's every
i work for the client and like yourself
what your needs are completely different
from say what frank's needs are what did
josie's you know what i mean
is your operation is different and every
situation is different so
i try and find the fit for the customer
you know what i mean trying to fit
what fits your best for right now what
you do not what's the most expensive
not what i sell i sell everything in
fact i'm
yeah but just about everybody's
everything to be honest with you
because i tell them all look they you
know i'm blah blah blah i sold this
sell that then they're like okay yeah
fine because i'm gonna fit it to the
customer
i'm not gonna fit it to what i've got
for sale
right it's easier the way i play because
luckily i've been around long enough
where i can do that
you know what i mean there aren't many
salespeople that can probably do that i
don't know
not many people that do what i do i
don't think to be honest in a certain
way but
thank you thank you very much yeah i
know i'm still you guys got to meet
maybe
jump on again and uh we'd talk shop
sometime um and follow up on us
yeah man thank you so much deals thank
you deal gross thank you for joining me
man it was fucking awesome song you're
gonna know your story
and i hope to see you enjoy the past
nerd hang out man thank you so much for
joining