I mean who's gonna be my first time
using it let's heat it up we'll start
low that way he can do a press and we'll
bump the temp up for him
I did bring some material it has I
didn't bring my apologize we've got some
here you can press them of ours because
I'd like let me go those are for a
cottonmouth and they'd work very very
well
they're from See's candy and you know
what this is cool and if users like to
sponsor me at any point I've never seen
impressed my wash I've pressed other
people's washes and I don't I don't
prefer that I don't prefer wash you know
pressing up so this is gonna be fun
because number one I've never used this
machine number one right right using a
new press is like driving somebody's car
else's car it's beyond driving someone
else's yeah so this particular situation
I have feel the same way I'm like okay
how does it ever even provide a plate so
small what makes it move it's a manual
perfect okay yeah manual I love that
it's when it's a hydraulic press is when
I have to dial it because yeah you you
have to learn what it wants to do and
how to control it where now it's your
fingers so that's great so one cuz you
logged I am alright yeah this heater up
yeah
or bringing it back that way light one
or so yeah that's manageable and then
this top and bottom so it's basic simple
yeah it looks like you're just heating
it now we just got to see how it
performs with the material that I have
no no that should be plenty so in the
meantime I'm gonna you have gloves sweet
you can even go a little further if you
want well I gotta break this hash up
now this hash is not in your ideal
environment it's not in a freezer it has
actually already gummed up so more than
likely yes and I'm okay with it good
hash and gonna come out it's all in the
how well did you wash it is what it
comes down to because I I can really
mess up this wash if I don't pay
attention to it so I use a flux rosin
press yeah it's huge I I think I have a
couple of presses my preference okay my
my first press I got was made by CRD Inc
they're out of Ventura and that was like
if you go to like the very bottom of his
page I got like one of the first one or
two that he made and that thing was a
workhorse I pressed a lot of rosin out
of that you'll see a lot of my big
waterfalls were on that press and then
the real I og gifted us the Sasquatch v1
that's what Iraq the it's a v2 but it's
so old that it doesn't have an OPA back
like the back is like plated off
I know over like the v1 it sucks like if
you blow out a bag you almost have to
take it all apart to be able to clean
behind it there was no they're super
gnarly dude they're heavy as hell so and
then with just not wanting to buy the
same presses that I've already got big
plates I decided to go with the Razzak
technologies which is a tiny little like
this is the pup I'll show you this is
the puck you know I do 4 gram pucks so
this is a puck maker alright but I press
4 grams you know that allows me to do a
like you know there's more material
you're pressing them the longer you have
to press it it's just more material to
heat it up don't heat it up on this too
we have parchment paper there's some
paper tada
and it came with it look at it matches
the company we're gonna press some Mac
one by la family farms they're the 90
you whoa we just smoked that was good by
the way it was really good and it's cool
to smoke somebody else's Mac like
they're always very similar but they're
also different because everyone uses a
different rollers you know different
techniques to grow so that guy's saying
this is the night of you it's gummed up
there's a couple of ways to deal with it
no matter what in my opinion it's still
gonna press the same not only just order
to get in the bag to say no just because
you know your material gums up doesn't
mean it's gonna be fired because there
could be contaminants in there you know
so don't want this car know that for you
just hold it
yeah I can hold the camera for you if
you want
that's that great stopper not always the
funnest sorry I normally have all this
work prep but it's gonna take a minute
here I'll prep mine might as well right
yeah
is that cool you really don't mind jump
in there brother let's do that I want to
see as long as you're ok with it
I'm having a little bit like an excited
sergeants participate but the puffs go
peak get a quartz banger and something
that Jolly Roger won't like me to talk
about is get a get the puff Co rebuilt
it's called puff coil repair and your
atomizer will actually burn hotter and
better and use the same amount of
battery life it's the same ohms it's
just a better wiring so it actually just
conducts heat better
[Applause]
you can get online puff coil repair and
it's cheap too it's like 70 bucks and
you get like 10 of them nope
you know what's happening we need it we
gotta weigh on me where's the arm rosin
bag oh yeah what do you need I got 37 I
got 25 25 please
smalls fine okay this yeah I'll just do
a small press about 37 I'll do this is
fine cuz then they have this next yeah
yeah that'll be fine otherwise I have
the screen but it's too small it's gonna
work just all right man I got to pick
from you you got 15 these right here
dude big clock check it out rose and
evolution ah they fold them you don't
fold I like Kobe now I'm inside or
outside bags
oh I flip all my bags outside inside out
I don't need back though that's why Oh
Oh hold yeah no but we're gonna see what
I'm gonna do tonight because I'm gonna
do the folding technique using the rosin
evolution bags because I thought I don't
have Mike my typical press of course
yeah thanks bro thanks for leaving your
fingerprints on there didn't do the rock
drinking drop is all low in there I
can't help you with that dude I make
hash yep you drink a lot of water do you
drink beer I never actually drank a beer
in my life I'm really fussy but I do
drink whiskey like I'm gonna go get
drunk or something but it'll be like
whiskey and coke yeah
I always like something sweet you know
I'm just not all drink socially yeah
yeah I go to the bar with like a friend
or whatever but I don't even have I
don't even have a booze at my house
yeah just fussy that's more like like a
preference
yeah preference thing and that's nothing
to do with like getting drunk or fussy I
just don't think it tastes good I just
think they all taste terrible don't have
to like everything yeah but yeah we're
gonna do a ten grand putt let's do that
I think I could probably get like eight
in here fold it good you have an extra
set of gloves I could steal yeah well
this is not my typical way of doing
things I'll wait by the way we are on
the fly so if you yeah mine would be
like all fluffy and coldest if did but
it's definitely gonna work yeah we're
gonna still do it it's gonna be
different
oh don't mind if I do and I'm most
likely gonna end up going to about three
minutes on this press oh we should
probably you know what we should do we
should turn on the press and a little
tip for the newbies put the plates
together it'll heat up faster and even
so they're both get to the same tent the
same time it's not too tight just
together touch them yep ooh we got
Celsius to girl get the calculator
Google what's it set up in my freezer
okay I made my own cool bot okay I don't
know if you know what the cool bot is
for hash makers cool bot is what makes
your regular wall a/c your mini split
any splits go below 60 degrees you could
take it down to 34 degrees however that
little device is like three four and a
buck so I've made mine for like yeah I
made mine for like thirty bucks
however listen to this folks if he's
giving you information like this you
guys benefit that that controls the on
and off of heating the thermostat to
trick it into thinking that the room is
boundaries and the device that monitors
the temperature my coil to make sure
that the coil doesn't freeze Ami's is in
Celsius
so I hate Celsius only because I don't
understand it that's the only thing
anytime I say I don't like nothing is
because I don't understand it and it's
just being lazy of not taking the time
to learn what Celsius converts to so so
no I just get a cell phone
I just got additional thermostat thermal
copeland with the little line and i just
tap those and those read fahrenheit
right above the celsius but now I got
two temperature sensors ones in Celsius
ones in Fahrenheit the fahrenheits just
for me cuz I'm too damn already you're
just using it as literally like those
are that's an extra 10 bucks
it cost me so I can just look at it and
know what the you know the temperature
is because I I have other equipment that
is in Celsius and I got a cheat sheet of
all the temperature conversions on the
side in the story
learned Celsius you don't need to spend
on extra ten books it goes down pretty
quick just FYI it was set at 200 do you
want me to lower it to 180 oh yeah
please 180 go one eight nine once every
night I do that because it's I don't
know it's not 180 but but when people
say what do you press that I say 180 so
it's weird because it's like too many
little numbers to say so it's like 179
or 180 so but I set it at 179 and it's
you're gonna see it's gonna be 180 181
behringer so like like I set mine to 224
and it's usually always says 225 so
alright it's already at 157 it says but
I would still let it this is what it's
going up to the 35 I have no idea I
think it's like a second thing like a I
don't know what this 35 is I don't have
like a manual for this thing I've never
ran this company
I think it has something to do with this
timer because it says 35s like seconds
is what move it no huh but I didn't hit
the timer yet let's see oh yeah see 34
oh is that a built-in timer okay what is
that doing it felt like it sounded like
something else turned on this little
light came on - do we have an
instruction now my chance no cheatsheet
I think it's just a timer it's just a
time book maybe huh oh yeah check it out
what wow that did heat up pretty quick
that one yep that's it what is the 35s
mean evolution I'm a big fan of a lot of
their material
I like their bags they're affordable
number one number two they work there's
other affordable options out there that
don't work so that's why I like their
bags therefore I use rosin evolution
always I just switched over literally
today I press my first press with rosin
new ink
now I don't have my one ton arbor press
that I would normally close this with to
get a puck so I'm gonna use my 165
pounds or whatever I can to press this
puck makes me want to do the old-school
shoe hash you know like step on it
remember that you guys never should have
put it in your shoe and walk around for
a while hell yeah that should be all
gummy people don't know that back in the
day
it speeds up the process minimize your
mistakes when you're working with hash
it's too it's too precious to make
mistakes oh so that's how I see it I'm
not trying to just waste material you
work so hard yeah it's bullshit it's
very just self-explanatory
it says thank you for purchasing it's
about the same amount of info you get
from rosin or from harvest right yeah I
can just set this time for the amount of
time that he wants to press set the time
35 we're gonna do three I have a timer
you can do it right on here just let's
use their gear then right yeah so when
I'm ready to hit it I just hit it yeah
you literally just hit timer yeah okay
so now it's set to 180 seconds so this
is our little snack puck that we just
made okay so it's still gonna go good
see that's what I'm like it's still good
material you know it's still gonna do
its thing well it's for the top band the
bottom plate yeah I don't know why I
would do that why you would need to but
it's weird yeah it's weird though when
you do click the timer button like watch
like something something something's
clicking I don't know if it's just a
diode in there causing this
what I think you can set each one yeah
the only thing that I don't like about
this is I don't know how hard I'm
pressing but I guess you just kind of
finger you're just as my manual is this
is how I started with the gloves oh yeah
let me just finish this
Emily I'm gonna double bag it with the
37 cuz I don't want to blow it out I'm
gonna put that away
sure thank you I got two of them cool
yeah
I should have posted something that like
like let me know or I should know this
Pete but I should just post you know
before I come here you know hey I'll be
alive on your webpage future cannabis
project well you know what I'm saying
like at least maybe get one or two more
people looking on your YouTube page cuz
I just appreciate you having us here and
taking the time to listen to us idiots
talk about ash that's the thing you get
us talking dude it's it's hard to stop
us you got to tell us okay you got to
tell me to shut up and go home like I
don't have many friends like people that
I that I consider family that there's
not they're few and far between
especially as you get older and all the
relationships like I don't have much to
talk about other than weed so it's
really difficult for me to you know and
and I don't tell people what I do so I
just you know oh it's funny having that
conversation with your grandma for the
first time you know alright you do what
now we're moving alright your stuff you
know I'm ready to go okay you go there
well no I just need the gloves so I can
grab some hash once find right away
that's fine that's fine they're wiping
that don't I know I know what I'm doing
I know but I'll help you I've been I've
been here before
to glove in the house in the house left
method you go backwards yeah you know I
have I have my you know it looks like it
takes I have a lot of prep work that
goes into our assembly lines I'm trying
to recreate what is normally flawless
already ready already ready already
I want to see the cool shit I definitely
do like so much prep before I go live
because I just don't want to hear
someone be like yeah really cool
watching you dump stuff into a bag idiot
this work is though dude this they're
watching the office for two hours just
putting lids on jars or stickers on lids
this one man operations I got one helper
and he's like an absolute sweetheart
thank god he's there he's a he does
stand-up paddling like this specifically
almost a year like specifically but I've
been making hash for 10-15 years growing
for 10-15 years
so making good high-quality hash rosin
and properly with a rosin press and
learning the techniques and figuring
this whole thing out and trying to brand
it and and have people like what I do I
was just making either BHO working in
labs you know making pens no because I
mean I mean I'm doing the best I can
with what I got so but there are people
that are like bothering me for these
massive orders from like up north that I
don't even know who they are I'm like I
can't provide you with like stuff I
first of all don't even have that sort
of quantity on hand I'm very I'm very
small batch and very like by myself I'm
you know so but they're just seeing the
quality that's coming out and it's like
well that's because I am so small you
know if I really tried to do this on a
grand mass scale I believe that the
quality would hinder a bit you know
cause if I feel like I'm not doing it
personally there's there's not too many
people are out there that are gonna be
as anal and and up to my specifications
they could give it up to some of the big
companies like 7/10 labs and stuff like
that that are out there just pumping out
so much consists in quality hash you
like the bro good on you guys you must
have a good crew because it's hard to
trust a lot of people to to be
careful with your product like takes so
much time just to grow the wheat itself
let alone process the hash making like
every time I take on a new farmer it's
it's it's scary and literally like I get
nervous I get concerned that I'm gonna
I'm gonna fuck it up oh yeah that's my
biggest fear is having to explain to
them that I fucked up you know and then
a lot of times I used to think that it
was me
sometimes it's them and they provided
you with a shit product and then it's
another and then another headache that
you have to go talk to that about like I
did not you know and I'm not the kind of
I'm not I'm not the kind of guy that
wants to bring Brad news I don't I know
I want I want I'm sorry I want to come
back and be like look what the stuff you
did I want to polish what you made you
know and and unfortunately the biggest
thing is you know so I'll usually be
like you know what this is gonna be
better off like diamonds or BHO
processed you know that's gonna be make
them straight out I'm like so I was
trying to like you have to have this and
you know how hard it is to get 10 farms
to employee at the farm I'm at yeah yeah
yeah exactly
there hasn't been a farm door I feel
confident that I can do the do the work
at the level that I'm able to do I'm
only able to produce this type of
quality because the way they grow yeah
yeah it's it's all about the starting
material really why it's like what
there's like fine vintages there's like
it's like it's more it's like wine some
some strains and some gears and some
vintages will be better than others and
of course absolutely and that
and it's based on the weather that year
yeah so why it is very similar with
French Canada like Frenchie yes so has a
very special little hatch and I learned
from Frenchie that was my mentor we met
at Frenchy's events like I'm not I'm
just expressing what you did yeah I'm
just polishing what the farmer did I
can't make their product look better
than what it already was I can just sew
oh I'm doing really just makeup up
that'll know so it's like if I'll double
bag it and we'll see what we can do this
is 9.35 I believe just over 9 3 I'm just
trying to make the best square I can you
want me to pucker you yet again I'll
just rock it ok it's good hash I can
tell it's gonna be moldable and work
well yeah I always that I always I
always press and wash and music yeah
like I have to like when I wash I have
to have music when I press like I have
to have music it's it's it's part of
dude you don't need if you guys can see
what I do behind my press when I'm press
I watch a lot of goofy cartoons - I do
I dance bro after impressed I fucking do
oh it's a good when you're by yourself
get you get excited at least I do I'm
ready I don't know if you try to move
the temp though so I'm ready to know
it's at one 180 for you 179 that was ok
have taken me in front of it for heavy
or just some slides over no there we go
I just need to get a kneel down so I can
I bother Oh Oh careful check that out
all right where's our timer now let me
know when you want to start it it
started now it's just gonna go up right
no it's dropping from three minutes 180
seconds oh that's what three minutes is
I believe a 60 times three is 180 unless
I'm not good with math and ask Google
oh that rosin tech dude get get that
dude cheap shameless plug by all means
I look good down sorry guys did
batteries getting low but oh my god
these gloves are so small for my hands
my fingers are turning now you got fat
fingers
so yeah this is a slow process but it's
not it that's three minutes we're gonna
go like this
16 minutes thank you
I normally would like lights in there so
I wouldn't put yeah I have like a big
bright light in here yeah I like to see
what's happening if you take close-up
it's starting it's melting break and
sway break and sweat see that right
there
we're breaking sweat a little better at
least oh yeah anything now and we can
show them I want to get my fingers full
of rosin but we're flowing and now we're
taking so I want to flow I don't want
cake yeah it helps to have a stable
table holding the table for you but this
thing yeah I know I saw that you gotta
hold it as I pull that do it if they
attack there you go get a little flow
here early in two minutes
it's a dramatic picture the three of us
each performing a very specific yes all
important very important everything
matters
it's flown look great color great color
this could get better drop your childís
in up thanks robot like the I always
brand-new present you do another one
great man but it'll get better I want to
pull it for him it's a new press for him
you know what I mean I don't see the
flow much I mean it is flowing but we
can maximize are you yeah we can pull
the best quality so we're pulling
quality right we almost did three
minutes
oh that's annoying yeah buttons alarm
yeah we'll never do that we're doing it
because that's the way this one is well
normally when I press he goes off to the
sides and I don't open it until it's
cooled off so this right now I would
prefer to put it on something cold it's
all we got
yeah sorry apologize because I again
Terk preservation is what we're going
for right the dump it's it's hot so it's
just reeking and it's just everything's
changing right now everything's changing
so I want to stop it that's that's
that's how I make mine he preserves that
heat and allows that heat to create
vacuum which actually creates more heat
because vacuum and heat changes when
you're under vacuum 90 degrees is
equivalent to like a hundred and
something I don't know you gotta look
Google it again so different techniques
for your different textures so just
because he went in at 225 and he vacuums
it he's probably at a higher temperature
for momentarily when he's at 80 he's
potentially at a higher temp what the
melting effect is not affecting it as
much if he had direct 220 degrees versus
vacuum that oh yeah but I don't like to
I prefer not cured yeah like tomorrow or
it tastes the same he's not
smell the same right now yeah it's high
so it so it's almost like when you open
a bottle of red wine you let it breathe
yeah yeah yeah yeah that's like I said
why did balls yeah yeah I do not I do I
make coins my material they he said the
best step of all he ever smoked 13 years
old nice and cured on the inside if that
shell creates a protective layer and
everything on the inside is just like
it's locked and it eats itself up and a
jar tech type of style so that inner
texture is urinated over that's done
properly yeah I'm sure it can happen but
it's not it's like so unlikely yeah so
hurt like for something to happen in
that 13 years it's very likely that
something can go wrong or it can get
smashed or it can get you know
compromised by weather or hot
temperatures whatever texture that's
yeah that matters I personally believe
there's a shelf life on this Ash for
sure like six months I think has a
shorter shelf life
yeah when you're heating it up when you
use a jar tech because you've already
accelerated the decarboxylation process
you have changed the thca the majority
of this material right here in this hash
is THC a majority of the cannabinoids
that are in this hash are acids that's
how it's white as we start the
decarboxylation process the natural
process of nature yes the plant is
already changing those heads as it's
finishing just in the percent ratios or
different so once you cut it that plant
dies that's still continuing its it
intensifies the decarboxylation effect
as it's hanging in drying so during that
process you still have a lot of acids
and that's why it's important to process
fresh material the older it gets you can
freeze it you can put in the
refrigerator you're only going to delay
the inevitable it naturally will do that
so just if you get fresh material just
process it as fast as you can don't
think that your freezers gonna save it
for a year think it's going to change
you know it's gonna I don't I don't
believe it's gonna it's gonna get
screwed up in your freezer the longer
you keep it in there for sure like I I
know running BHO II I've had runs where
that it's been a year later and it still
came out good but I think for this
letting it freeze for that long
something's there's something's
happening to the heads
me I'm like almost immediate I cut it
down and it's like wash within a week of
the cut down the longest that's only if
I have a whole bunch of stuff going on
with it
we are not in the ideal temperature I
like to be under like I like 65 degrees
for my pressing room it allows me to
handle the material without it getting
too cold or the material gets brittle
and like shatter like and just shatters
and if it's too warm you can't
manipulate it with the fingers because
we our hands are 98 degrees so even
though we're wearing gloves in a 65
degree room if I touch this for just 510
seconds you know seconds matter it
starts to stick so and gum and now you
got hats on your fingers and wasted hash
that doesn't get accounted for at the
end of your processing know he's going
to 210 yeah but I'm not gonna use that
stupid loud noise so someone says can
you guys talk about plate sizes versus
bag sizes one pressing bubble also
freeze drying times freeze dryer that
excuse me the new freeze dryers kind of
do it all on itself that pharmaceutical
one is literally set up for almost hash
basically and it it senses it what does
that set it though what do you mean like
what is it automatically said that
what's the hours that it runs like it's
mine is different every time it does a
batch run so it's actually testing all
this different stuff and then once it's
over
yeah the harvest right yeah I was dry
yeah yeah the new pharmaceutical one it
actually says like doing batch test run
so it's doing all these different tests
that I think there's like 24 of them and
then it literally kicks on and gives it
like an automatic time based on how much
hash you have in the freezer because
I've had it where it kicks on and it's
like 36-hour dry time when I had a ton
of hash in there and then I put less
hash in there and it dries a little bit
faster and then they also asked about
plate sites plate sizes are very
important to me yeah very everything
every time your plate sizes change you
have to change your method and you have
to create your own method based on the
plate size for example this plate size I
would not want to press a 20 grand puck
on here it's just it's too small for 20
grand puck so when I looked at it my
first thought I was like 10 grand puck
boom that's why I brought different
pucks because I didn't know what this
guy was going to look like
I brought a foreground puck I got a 20
gram puck and I got a timber that's what
hash makers are craftsmen little figure
now we are craftsmen we then what we got
tool belts we are guys to get our hands
dirty we like to do things with our
hands you know so hundred percent then a
hundred percent even if I see it out
there in the market I'm like I'm gonna
pay you foreigner bucks for that
twenty-five dollar piece of crap
you know what I mean sorry but that's
that's how I look at stuff sometimes
like if I know that I can recreate that
and like why would I spend the money
then there's some times are you just
like you know what just buy it why
because I can't really do that like the
rosin I could not do it it's not as easy
well hell no technologies presses badass
and there's no way
well I can duplicate that so you drop
the money on it is this size there's a
two by three yeah go for it's a two by
three size it's the size of this bottom
right here so I I like small presses I
prefer I can see what's happening with
my rosin I don't like the ability not to
see what's happening on the sides I
don't mean I would like see what we're
doing here we're trying to like look at
what's happening and if I'm only doing
that though because I'm not used to this
press I press I don't have to do it cuz
I've done it so many times that like
mines huge mine's like 16 inches by like
seven or eight
that's massive yeah that's that's a big
one my largest is as 14 inches long four
inches why that's the largest one that I
have that's the one I used started on
pressing flour you might want to get
close in here it looks pretty big she's
gonna dump oh he should have a higher
flow yeah look at that
Wow the fangs for at home and like small
little press this thing's pretty bitchin
yeah but you're not gonna be able to do
a massive workload thank you so much man
yeah and this should be bolted to a
table and like the tables yeah very
sturdy
yes sir like the least ideal conditions
possible you see the whole table
completely full and half like this is
why stoners can't have nice things
that's about good I went for I only went
for like two and a half minutes because
it's such a smaller press like in an
amount that that's still really good
sorry
yeah I'm not happy how you doing there
Tom you okay boy alright alright just
making sure that's why I don't like
these double bags
eh killed my yield we'll see what
happened well I know what this this
material has but the size of your plates
affect the amount of pressure that you
apply the smaller the plate you need
less pressure the larger the plate you
need more pressure and quality plates
really make a difference too because the
if you're not getting even pressure
throughout the entire plate and the
plate will shift or twist you're not
gonna have a good quality press yeah
especially when you're trying to do a
lot at once this like buttered up
immediately and looks so good I want to
smoke this she only got 40% on my yield
which is not good this is this is a
sixty five-plus squirter 60 68 should be
60 so that tells me on my next press I
gotta go a little bit longer possible or
lower I'm like and it's kind of hard to
get a full like yeah this is mind hard
to really get your pressure into that
thing here this is what you want to see
I got it I got it either way it still
gonna tip somebody just has to hold it
tell me now
here should be a little bit more tacky
because of the key it has to get a
little bit easier to handle but that's
why temperatures are so important in my
situation
I'll give you an exact percentage of
what I got back all laying this because
I can just weigh the bags do the math
and then do the math of the nine point
three that I put in that was a total
yeah you weighed the whole thing with
the bags in there and nine points and I
put these inside out yeah seems in right
now
no you seemed out yeah I'm the only one
that does that everyone thinks I'm crazy
but I'd never you look at how flat that
is it looks perfect
let's let's see what I got back you have
two of those 25s two of those small 25s
I can borrow real quick to get a hoe so
lean oh yeah tear it out yeah oh man
you're the best oh yeah twenty-five
hours should be in the bag you need
those knees exactly
yeah the exact same just I'll put two on
there all right oh my bad boom tear and
then we'll see how much this weighs so
there was nine point three now there's
two left so I got like 75 76 % I think
that's that's off the top of my head
that's more in line with what it should
be doing let's see and I noticed that
from past experiences the bigger the
plates the heart of the attempts you
have to go to achieve the higher
percentages so what I attempted to do
was recreate what I normally would do on
my smaller press which is at 180 degrees
and my press is maxed out at 3,000
pounds and I only use 80% of that I
don't even go there without 76 exactly
yeah that's that's that's it
that's where it should be that's now
it's like all right let's do that and
keep doing it that's you know that's
that's and this looks really freaking
good I want to smoke this right now like
dude good job buddy thanks man you -
dude that's nice fucking nothing spit
that was that two minutes like I pressed
for like four but I'm also doing a
little bit bigger of a bag you know
whatever but man what a good getting a
round of applause from every country and
thanks Tom it's all you but yeah and
like I always say I always tend to be
safe on my first I just have it in me
not to over squish not to overheat so
it's like you you don't torture freak
out I mean though that with that like
because I turn it up so hot they're like
it's gonna burn it it's gonna burn it is
that Brown and I used to press my you
know like my big plates so that's where
I was at I was over 200 220 you know to
get a good good squeeze out you need to
to the bigger plates production it's
almost about the same the amount you
know because the squish time I'm only
doing 50 seconds you know per 4 grams so
if you do 4 4 4 it's at 12 grams 3
minutes you do 10 grams or roughly 3
minutes so it's almost about the same
time we're losing using one bag it's all
preference though you know people like
Nikes or adidas right like what do you
like but it what work do drew for the
fact that it looks like butter so crazy
that looks so good dude
good job nice you know YouTube there's
collaboration right there
I've never had anybody press my material
that's what's cool that I've washed have
I mean I can go to me and can't say I've
yeah nobody's ever came in and rest your
stuff where I've pressed other people's
stuff that they've washed and I'm not
always excited about that opportunity
you know I asked for my first time I
actually got asked that they're like hey
I have a bunch that I have a freeze
dryer of everything but I don't have a
press we pressed for me I was like you
put in all that time and effort you grow
and you have the freeze dryer but you
don't have a press I was like yeah no
problem you know some people trip out
but the more you do it it's like it's
like snowboarding you going down the
biggest hill on the first try yeah it
sucks but once you've done it 30 times
it's like cool let's go yeah it is your
experience level you know you either
doing the diamonds or you're doing the
blues
Green was a great return and this is
only that's only that part that was all
right there's a whole another part over
there and that's what you do you play
with temperatures you play with
different things and it'll do different
and it'll look different you're gonna
see his is different from this texture
yeah mine's a little more buttery but
that's just cuz it went hotter but this
stuff looks insane good came out amazing
I'm so surprised like it looks like
butter but you can just grab it and it's
nice and cold in here too yeah so
definitely got a dab on it you
definitely got a DAB on your finger that
all smoke speaking of dabs to smoke I'm
about to try that man I'm not a fresh
pressed person but that looks really
good is that okay George yes please
well III do my cure I do my cure usually
and like he said I believe you get less
taste on the fresh press especially like
directly after pressing but we all do it
we all do it y'all curious you know
you're wondering okay I've had some
stuff that was like it was like oranges
it smelled like oranges it was amazing
and I still have the jar and it's about
two months old and now it smells like
salsa like insane hot spicy Tapatio
salts or something you're like what
happened and it's still when you smoke
it is it delicious
still has that orange taste yeah well no
it took it took that two months like
every time I open it smell like
gorgeous oranges just immediately
oranges and then one day like I probably
didn't open it for two weeks or
something and I opened it and it
literally smelled like salsa and I'm
like how did that happen and it's still
amazing I wish I had brought it with me
so you guys could smell it I feel like
all this stuff it's a lot of acids so
you're good there's there's there's
partial D carbonyl air it's gonna make
me eat much more sticky than its gonna
get you high yeah yeah little turkey huh
get some of those jelly beans in you too
that would be a perfect little mix you
know so there is a difference in what
the textures tip you flatten that out
and might look at this more like very
close like yeah similar texture wise it
not sure I haven't touched it is
actually pretty damn stable I was
surprised pardon me
they're both exactly the same this was
addressed at 180 yeah yeah both yeah
they're exactly the same pressed at 180
yeah and what Bragg's did you use a 25
to 25 and a 37 okay and you use 25 to 25
yeah use 225 correct I did 25 and a 37
and we're used and you're still worried
about you think that you're gonna lose
at at the lower centage at the it's all
about like again like re if we're gonna
talk you know higher temps then you can
actually push that out through your bags
a lot right there because you got hotter
temps it's gonna get higher flow rate
lower a low rate yes
so lower temps you have a slower flow
rate you have more hold back time I owe
this that that when you fold your bags
to and way you placing them in your
parchment you can create channels and
flow and create it to just squeeze out
questions to really pack them in there
too much on it each other they'll tend
to blow out I actually give myself space
in between each bag a little bit and I
and I notice it actually creates those
channels for the the hash to through and
it help
a little bit yeah I'm gonna try it or
what I believe it's just kind of hard to
press that thing in the first place and
then I think what you're doing - yeah
you can't like on one of these you use
your fingers that's all you got you know
and then when you're going down and then
it jerks on things goes off your game
for a minute but again it's like it's
like it's like double dare when you're
you know or something where so you know
the difference of the tools that's what
it comes down to our temperatures is
pretty much what he came down
temperatures you know and and it creates
a different consistency you know I like
to create a single consistent product so
that's what I'm trying to eliminate the
THC a kickin up because that's what
tends to occur at a lower temp at a
higher temperature you tend to melt it a
little better so it tends to come out a
little creamier comes out a little bit
shinier it all comes down to personal
preference and what your in customer
wants to a lot of time that's what it
really comes down to and it's like yeah
somebody wants something to jar tech
then you got to change your game you got
to go up in temps like I know I've lost
customers that have bothered me for for
a full melt and I just don't make full
melt I don't take the time to pull those
mini bags and separate everything out
and then go you know have to call
everything oh it's not really full spec
because I pulled this the the 70 to 90
out on the first wash I just don't even
have time for that I'm giving you like
everything here you go I don't even
smoke full note myself if you want pull
metal head up camera guy's got the bomb
[Laughter]
I am I am more than like three or four
days cured whipped up cold care yeah but
I like I said I it looks so good I want
to try it there's it's not gonna hurt to
to give it a go but but we do know that
it's gonna definitely have less of it
taste yeah it's not gonna look like this
tomorrow depending on the conditions
that it's kept in yeah no it'll get
whiter this is the the end result yeah
it wider it's gonna get wider it would
go in the refrigerator Janna fridge in a
colder air conference yeah yeah that one
will for sure yeah it's gonna end up
looking like this fuck it so that see
the the how the color changes this one
yeah maybe three days now no no no this
has not been down what I carry in my bag
okay no not the reason I don't carry a
mini cooler or keep my Terps cool in my
bag is that I want to see the
degradation of what's gonna happen to my
product when someone doesn't take care
of it I know someone's gonna leave it in
the car I know someone's gonna put it in
their pocket so it's fun to see when you
have like such a good product that it
still stays badass no matter how much
you beat it up but it left in my car out
to the air open being open is not good
we're about every time you smell it and
you just evaporated Terps from here we
lost Turkey because they keep open-close
open-close in it now the reason I like
this texture is temple ball okay we're
talking Temple Bar really it creates a
seal and right that was trim trim run
that's not the bus trim run dude it
tastes it tastes great funny dude tastes
great for trim run dude
good taste were really good for trim run
dude but like again I'm a big believer
in its it's all in the wash it couldn't
love zone that's not true it comes from
the genetics comes from the farmer comes
from the practices comes there's there's
a difference of harvesting flour which
everybody does and harvesting trikes and
flowers so there's a whole different
mindset of harvesting trikes you know
I'm a trike harvester and I love
harvesting flour and guess what trikes
are hauling off every moment just like
Frenchie cannoli was talking about the
analogy he uses is the trikes are like a
ripe apples on a tree and all you got to
do is this shake it and the right
baffles fall that's what's happening
when you're doing a takedown so the way
that people sometimes there it is like
ripping things down here it's our Fox
feeling when you see him clip and then
they're just not you're like no no no be
very careful with what you're doing have
your bag open you know turn your trash
to cash over here no no now we're
turning we're turning extremely high
quality marijuana and it's a dream at
high quality it just has maintained its
shine we're taking high quality in this
bit shine in it because when you see the
flower next to it you're just like damn
that's like a fucking Lamborghini parked
next to a Ferrari now because it's like
they they they they complement each
other it shows off the clean the
cleanliness the the actual practices of
that farmer and then it's the
craftsmanship of the hash maker that
helps guide the farmer and love
trichomes so it's like the farmer
already has a love for the flower so now
you just have to tell him now you have
to start loving the trichomes now so
there's a whole different process of
teaching and going through to produce
quality product out of trim
not everybody's trim can do this no I
guarantee definitely not I've ran trim
that comes out just like his the Mac
usually pumps a very white crystal and
it's very good even in trim and I've ran
other trim where it's so brown you're
just like dude I don't even will I give
it to somebody for edibles
I feel bad even though I know it's
really high-quality hash rosin is
extremely clean it's been sifted it's
been you know processed but it's just so
dark it's very unappealing yeah and
that's what it comes down to
aesthetically exactly that's like it is
focused on everybody is they want the
white rosin though they want the creamy
right didn't you give me a white rosin
they want the creamy rod then you give
me cream they want the jam and the
orange kids in a candy store it's like
no it's like you want to just tell them
what you get but it's like at the same
time it's like you know what it's a
different it's different it's a
challenge never-ending you know love
story so I I like that challenge do I
agree with it no do I do it yes you know
and that's life there's certain things
that we have to do that we just don't
like and we have to do it we want to be
an adult you have to pay your bills do
we like it not really but we do it and
you know what I mean so it's like that's
the same mentality you have to have when
you get criticism I I don't like
criticism it hurts my feelings I'll be
honest but without it I can't learn you
know I mean it hurts my feelings when
someone says dude this is not what I
want you know it only hurts my feelings
because I put so much yeah we're really
trying hard especially when you're like
trying to be honest about it's not
[Music]
that's my point
it's not but the truth of the reality is
it does you know what I mean we all have
a heart and we all get our feelings hurt
but do we expose that no but it's the
truth man if you love what you do and
somebody says this is not what I was
looking for if you really love what you
do it's gonna feel like you accomplished
the task that you were asked to do
absolutely and it's disappointing to
walk away from that and and all I want
to do after that is make up for it like
I need to make up for it I failed and
and there is no failure it only if you
quit so it's like I'm not done like well
you know the shot you know kind of thing
but sometimes it doesn't
that way sometimes they're just
disappointed and that's it you know like
I said I've lost customers just because
I'm not making full milt yeah come on
yeah
like trust me actually smoke my ass I
told me in my opinion I can produce a
beautiful product but that's not the
texture and the consistency that they
want so therefore you know it didn't it
didn't work out for whatever reason you
know so there's a lot of there's a lot
of other stuff that goes on in a hash
makers life that we don't really expose
or talk about it like this
don't don't even get into like personal
issues that everybody has to go through
every single person you know everybody's
fighting some battle you know nothing
about people have loved ones they lose
things all sorts of crazy shit out them
so it's like you never it sucks like you
said when someone talks about about you
but it's really nice to get all the
positive feedback it makes up for one
compliment makes all the time yeah yeah
shit you just like fuck yeah you know
they believe in me and that's what
drives me is anybody that believes in me
like if they're like dude yeah the
people that show me love that don't even
know me it's just it blows me away I'm
like there's no reason you guys should
like like I'm just out there doing what
I love to I were used to work at a bank
for a long time I say I did the office
space life and it's just not for me I
like I like to create a product that
like I can make people happy with and
it's super it's so rewarding so like you
say it's like the amount from the hash
[Applause]
so funny that's that the
anti-inflammatory and the pain wanna try
yeah we'll try yours
now his is easier to work with off the
bat this is the consistency texture
other than the the caking I call this
kicking in my opinion it's very taking
it depending on what you're trying to do
he goes into a jar so that isn't and
that's not I'm robbing the hell out of
it that's all that's probably out of him
I am making a nice solid temple ball
that's flat this stuff is so melty it
can't stay in a temple ball
however it's gonna seep down theory
behind this is based on the temple ball
theory I am a true traditional hash
shishun from the beginning of temple
balls in the traditional dark hashes so
I still a lot of my methods freeze dryer
I run my freeze dry for eight hours I'm
done I'll put six pounds of fucking dry
ash in there and it'll be done in eight
hours why because I don't always do
things the same way you know I can
definitely cut it short I've cut them
short sometimes and they're like
everything's dry I'm like how did it dry
that click and it rocks it sometimes but
I've also ran other stuff where I
noticed usually the the crappie or the
heads are the ones that don't dry like
like if you saw like I'll save my food
grade you know what I mean my 182 to 219
and that stuff won't freeze but I can
put that in the material because that's
all that material do and it's blowing
around it's blows around it's not in my
it's it's on a separate tray by itself
but it's still in the freeze dryer with
everything else and I pull all the other
trays and everything's fine and dry as a
bone and then I pull those and crappier
and rot and there's like yeah little
icebergs of rocks and cuz they're not
heads ya know it's all stock it's all
stocks it's totally awesome it's just
funny figuring that out along the way
then there's no damn book written no
one's telling you nothing I looked at
the harvester I called him up they told
me run it for fucking 36 hours they told
me that though you know the whole
process like 36 hours so we did it you
know and and then it's lying dude with
all that you know I did the scooping
technique because that's what I saw
online you know I mean the Instagram
people were scooping mom was scoop all
right
school and throw it in there and we do
36 hours and you know it's done right
and damn that's a long time yeah and
then it's full of all this ice okay
right let's like take a chunk it up Tim
this is turqu water fell yeah there's a
fucking Turk trap over here this thing's
sucking Turks out oh by the minute this
is good ice you know it's Turk water
yeah yeah we sell this shit like we were
all that water that is oh so gnarly
I'm like why in the hell do I want to
put my product in a Terp trap when all
I'm trying to do is preserve Terps so I
I played with different methods to
minimize the time that it's exposed in
that machine and again I'm not a scooper
because I'm not making water I'm making
hash so I'm trying to just fill my fries
dryer with hash because 50% even my
amount that I put in there squeezed out
has 55 percent or 50 percent my numbers
will usually come in there that's how I
know how I did on my wash that's
important to me I need to know did I do
my job did I did I get distracted and
change the music too long and it's new
did I do my dance to my stupid little
things affect what you do in there so I
like to check my work and and that's the
squeezing out old-school traditional
method you chop it all up and I know
there's a particular layer that I cannot
go over cuz if I don't do my chopping up
and people like dude are you done yet
they say no because it ain't right so we
got to finish it and then you chop it
all up nice and even I know I can get
just over a pound on every tray of
quality dried hash it only has
approximately 50% so I'm like I'm okay
with that you know what I mean but I
don't like sending it in and not having
an idea and I don't like having it in
there for 36 hours or more than eight at
that so again it's just playing with
your product you know having the ability
to process the amount of material that
we we were privileged enough to process
gives us the ability to be more creative
gives us the ability to try new things
because as a as a home person who does
this and makes hash they're gonna get
five grams you know what I mean it's
like of pressable hash
someone posted something I think maybe
earlier today but soluble and
non-soluble turkeys are some I've never
terpenes water-soluble that what they're
asking I mean there's Lysol there's pine
saw all of those are terpene derived
products so they're mixed with water so
they must be water soluble in some form
that's a guess though you know we'd have
to go to google I don't know exactly
what the question is there but soluble
they are cow is that nice right so is
like carry ethylene insoluble Mersin
insoluble limonene slightly soluble
right which is why insoluble humulin
virtually insoluble in a little
installable knurl it all slightly
soluble and that's just what they know
so far but what are you using it for and
what reference is it to and it's like is
that that ice water than the soluble
ones like I said you guys make some Turk
water yeah I don't know exactly how that
works you know and why it smells that
way but I've never noticed like a major
I came out really good dude it's not the
yield that I would have wanted I
probably should have pressed harder and
it still got you killed it though dude
you got what it should be getting up in
the you know hi number you got 70
something new that's the hell of it was
like 76 that's good
that's the one dude I get 90 back on my
GMO damn yeah it's insane this is how I
this is not dirt this is hash guys I
hate showing my bite my nails so much I
don't have any in there
my feet are gonna kill cancer bro these
I got another fucking hash in here to
kill cancer but it's embarrassing
because they're almost like stained like
I can't fucking making things I'd rather
always have gloves on but it's it's it's
it's part of the process you know I I
like you know touching stuff with my
hands and yeah this is this little ball
here
more of consist different different
textures and they're definitely
different textures this is a little bit
stickier it's gonna melt that's why when
I try to make a temple ball it just
slowly
what up what bags are you using in your
my Roger technology never know do you
have a have you seen bolts bags they're
uh they're freeze dryer liners oh they
have some yeah they're sick dude they
worked so good and he was telling me
about him like when we met the last time
and I totally had to try them out and
they they rock dude and it's so nice now
I'm gonna cut parchment for your for
your tray liners and you just like you
pull them out and you just shake it out
and what are you using it's a bolt bag
but it's a train liner it's a trail
evolution make me custom trailer trailer
15 that's all they did that's what I you
that's what he did
they don't sell him I just had another I
was using the so you have that's what I
use but I don't think he hasn't for sale
yet I just had to make him form Oh
nobody old bags people guys does he saw
me that I had to yellow because I was
using the yellow ones right and so he's
like dude you need to use food-grade and
I'm like all right bro he's like what
are your sizes you know so I told him
the sizes might race and so he was
really nice and he sent me the 15 this
quality material basically this is what
I use yeah but it covered my whole tray
yeah and it's even sewn up on the
corners almost it's one this is the same
material that they make their wash bags
out of except this is the 15 year it's
just super low you so the hash isn't
seeping through but it tends to dry them
I see I feel like it dries a little
quicker and I like the parchment paper
wicks especially when you just bring
them it gets all like you know the
humidity in your room will mess up your
batch like that like I was checked I got
there I got temperature gauges all over
like at the doorway on there over here
because there's different temperatures
everywhere so you pull it out and if
your humidity is like 60% you know 50%
it was a rainy day you can't leave your
tray out that was reflect no I mean I'm
on it man you know so there's certain
things that that you you want to pay
attention to so like a lot of people gun
right Waffen solvent was being a block
got the actual edged banger I'm gonna
get this
you got about 15 seconds should I just
go get you one all right here we go
tastes fantastic
that's that new watermelon I pressed
today the one that I found the Turkish
was the the live washing I did now this
one is about I want to say maybe a week
or more whoa that was really really
tasty yeah is this one here did you get
to smell that one I think that's the the
Tropicana cookies so that one naturally
has a different look different texture
different everything about that was my
first time washing real flour fresh
frozen like big fat juicy nugs so I'm
learning about that one now oh no oh
yeah that's Tropicana cookies you can
just taste it immediately it's so good
yeah this I need a bad show it was three
pounds of that okay of Tropicana cookies
one pound of GMO and you could almost
barely taste the Tropicana cookies coz
the GMO took everything over and it was
only 1/4 of that strong yeah this is
strong Juden it's really strong exactly
this I was like I was like dude it's
you're not even gonna taste this GMO Wow
and we were so blown away they mix their
bags um have you heard of Baker farms
he's out of San Diego he's really good
grower San Diego and I think Arizona as
well but yeah he's a great grower really
cool guy too super nice great
businessman and
when I ran his his product like I was so
stoked that like you said you know you
working with somebody new you know
you're and you never know what's gonna
happen and then when it comes out good
and it's a good product and it smells
good you're just like thank God I don't
have to call the sky with bad news he's
a big ass dude he's always like going to
the gym I'm like yeah hey man I got good
news coming to hang out you know yeah
let's do one more
why not let's do it at his big temp
let's go for a twenty Grammer you want
to do a 20 Grammer at 210 yeah or maybe
go up no 210 was actually really good I
think that was a good temp to see vegan
I would squeeze the plates together
right now just making sure they're nice
and hot