[Music]
so I ended up coming up with better ways
of processing what you get like all of
this rosin here is dry material I only
got the one product in here that's fresh
frozen that was the Tropicana cookies
and you're welcome to look at all of
these right here but yeah but my forte
is is dry material you know I like
processing live I like squishing it more
that the squish ability on live is great
you pull like 80% on your squishes means
live is up we're always talking frozen
fresh frozen lives resin right the name
is you know yeah like the last one I did
was the Tropicana cookies it was a hard
wash because the nubs were you know ice
cubes there you had a saturation time
even just soak them up so they can open
up you don't want to over beat them to
make contaminations so it's been only
cool 3% on the water you can't use the
entire the entire plant I use trim all
of this except for the Tropicana is all
trim material dry trim
cured dry cured trim yeah and like I
said I like doing the process you know
but I mean with with the foot with it
with the fresh frozen what about the
entire plant
I cut the whole plant down everything
except for like major stocks maybe some
water leaf yeah didn't like big water
leaf that a purple meal for the price
like the stem on the leave yes you know
that that's just green that's just any
leaf that looks like it has any first
mm-hmm
and you'll notice that on the dry
material when you wash you'll get all
the actual stocks of your heads to like
you won't get those on the fresh frozen
at all it'll all stay on the plant and
it's actually trippy because you hold
these nubs that look like they're still
covered in crystals yeah and there's
nothing on them is there any different
well you guys were all growing inside
when I don't know it's not true no I
mean both yeah but like yeah inside
outside you know but and and two totally
different mediums to outside them in a
greenhouse with soil and you know a
no-till garden and then inside rock wall
and salt
that's all we do is endure Rockwell
Saltz very interesting when I used to go
up north and visit with the farmers up
there where they were being taught how
to harvest their plants for uh for life
present they were being they were being
taught to like harvest like that then
these were they were all outdoor like
then they would be harvest like before
the Sun came up so you say where they're
still cold they were they were like I
mean that just that's just like a
helpful thing because the colder the
plain that's easier it is to cut it down
yeah just just yeah that's like
preferences yeah and then like in all
reality I don't think you're gonna make
much of a difference in that anything is
much more wrong job to be heavier yeah
it might even be heavier because you're
gonna be a little more water more
moisture and it'll be more so I'm gonna
be harder to pull when you got you know
someone who watered the night that they
cut that's gonna have a higher water
content compared to somebody who does a
drive back for two days in cuts yeah
like every single plant that I'm cutting
down and turning to fresh frozen has
been starved for like two or three days
from water at least so I guess my
question is is there any difference in
any way between the different parts of
the plan in yeah of course the bottoms
are gonna come out different than the
tops you're gonna get more I've done
like I've done like a test wash like I
actually brought up the test wash um
that I did recently where I just do like
a mason jar haha ten fresh frozen grams
which would normally be like two two and
a half once dried and then I just shake
the shit out of it in the jar with ice
and water and then I set it on the table
and let's if like a minute I pick it up
and with a bomb and I'd done a plant
that was the same strain but stunted it
didn't grow well and there was no no
yield and then the plant in the back
that was super good and grab a nice Cola
then you shake it into completely
different outcome so of course the
different you know you know tops of the
plant versus a bottom are gonna be a
little different but if you grow proper
you know indoor usually you're not gonna
have too many bottoms or what they call
larf yeah or whatever yeah you know so
it is if the point is to like harvest
like
so you get the like though if the Rebbe
you had get the most residents yeah you
want your resin to be like you because
you just want the head you don't want
the stock yeah and the heads definitely
get to a certain 1-inch solet's yes yeah
but they also explode so you have to be
like careful of that you also don't want
to freeze it too much because sometime
freezing it will allow it to explode but
you lose it when it explodes
no it's just it comes out differently
through the back because you're using
those micron bags can you buy any
purpose your bags get gummed up oh and
that's the worst that's that's how many
bags are the worst and that's what you
call temps make a huge difference I mean
two three degree temperatures you're
gumming up and then I've also had the
other hand where like some house is so
good even in a 65 degree room it's fine
and it's completely fine and then I've
had other hash where it's like 50
degrees in the room and you touch it and
just turns to glue your back watching 38
and stuff melts it's yeah the chemistry
of the resin that makes it it's all the
yeah it's it's how you grow it it's
making sure you thinking care of it
making sure you're not spraying your
plants the more and if you're spraying a
plant you're gonna really ruin some some
heads and yeah and on your almost your
entire product it's not gonna come out
anywhere near as good as someone who
doesn't spray that's the worst
a lot of farmers don't want to be
straightforward yeah and then you don't
find out like oh hey man do me this huge
favor and like let's make all this great
hash together and then they give you a
booth product because in all smelly I'll
smell oh yeah I'll be like oh cool I see
you guys are using plant therapy that's
the the healthy organic spray right I
knew it because I asked you guys are you
guys spraying anything and they'll say
no I'll say because it's organic they
don't think it like I'm like you know I
honestly I don't agree with spraying h2o
or like a high like hydrogen peroxide
even on your plants like any water
anything in my opinion is not good for
the that's why you have the humidity the
control you monitor your humidity your
VPD you have a person that knows how to
do your evaluation is number one so you
guys are on the same page
well when you do it for love you learn
what works like what does
yeah - starts in the nursery the
genetics so the pheno hunting the same
rockin the the networking of trading
cuts and fighting the right genetics
starts in the nursery what happens how
you feed it how you treat it how soon do
you send it off to flower how mature is
your bright are you
mature differently so GMOs seventy days
strength early six you guys would be
perfect to run this by I was talking to
sunshine Johnson once you know she's a
she's uh a dry form or eleven wool and
she supplies for Naja you know
relationship and she had suggested an
article called the the Grover one who's
that that's right sorry the grower in
the hash maker and there's like a lot of
people in this industry where there's
like really close relationships between
the growers I went it has that with the
fish I won't even buy any type or run
any type of flower that I'm not in the
room able to look at so that
relationship they dependably important
yeah I look at it I don't want to get
how my problems
yeah because I operate that's gonna
start to glow well yeah if you're in
here
yeah wait wait wait does it gonna blink
and I understand what you're saying that
we will see this turn orange
I assume that's in are we less me I've
got some cush mints on the flower on I
put macros and my ninety you that I
pressed to dish which even throw the
same that's crazy
I like it this is dope yeah yeah those
are cold
I smoke a lot of flour oh yeah and I
smoke that would uses on my bunk yeah
he'll take long
yeah I think I'm about to go buy one I
think in dementia so yeah we got buddies
over that's where I get my living dirty
girl are you saying joel the old glass
blower yeah that's my home we do so
there's a long doing and Josh indeed all
them girls dude Inge honestly he comes
over and he's my R&amp;D guy I'm like Josh
bro I just pressed some shit dude I need
your opinion come on to those dudes if
now they I mean that what used to be
like the managers and should have
dementia they're all just the growers in
the valley now that are badass and been
doing this for years they're fucking
good we'll sit there we'll find like
mystery strains and we'll bounce it I
think he's taste and he's got a great
palate you know he smoked a lot of
different strains where you can and he
can recall him Oh our mutual friend Joel
he's a glassblower he's also one of the
redzone of Josh D he was big part of
Josh DS legend oh yeah early 90s they
were the ones who brought the OG Kush
yeah oh they brought it to dr.
greenthumb we have the same cup we call
it the Hollywood og everybody calls it
their own thing we all share the same
comes from the stones don't you ever to
call them like ghosts in a dynasty they
were so similar they run him at drops DS
over there in Carpinteria still but
that's what we did you know you find the
fire oh I forgot a whole bunch of crap
that I thought I brought
but say I have the temperature get over
here and I know forgetting a few more
things than I want yeah I was pressing
like shit alright so I can show you the
difference between live oppressed and
you know regular so this is a this was
my live fresh frozen is my first time
running real quality nugs like I don't
get the opportunity to process the fire
nugs where can I go smell that's
Tropicana and I'd only ran a half pound
it was as well as a thousand grams my
buddy was a small garden you know and
he's in grams wet yeah so that's why
he's telling me it's roughly estimated
close to a half pound right fresh frozen
pound should be 2250 2250 so yeah this
one smaller than 450 so one thousand is
smaller then that could help my numbers
because no I still base it on a thousand
so even though I only pulled 30 grams of
pressable hash I don't count my 160 I
don't count yeah I throw that now that's
my choice what is your your full spec
that you're pulling well I bet you like
to if it's new material I'm not gonna
just do what I normally do to my other
material that I know already so I'm
gonna throw all my bags in I'm gonna
throw all my bags in I'm gonna wash one
unit and I want to see what I mean if
it's something you've never done that
for okay so you want to meet ya
everybody talks the 90 you oh are you a
complete opposite hash maker I'm a full
spectrum dude I've all ever did not
respect until like anybody who tells me
different I'm like cool you don't want
to buy my hash that's completely fine I
know I've been doing and I know I make a
great product talking about you what is
what is different from it's an actual
it's actually a very you know good
discussion because not too many people
are talking about it and the ones that
are like it's vague there's nothing set
in stone as to what full-spectrum
actually means right now the guy that I
took most of my stuff from which was
superior salt and list he what he calls
full spectrum is twenty
five all the way up to to 1925 one yeah
okay Micro all the way up to $2.99 a lot
of people would not put those in there
however when I run stuff that is so good
there's nothing in my 219 there's
nothing in my 220 nothing so it doesn't
matter that he is throwing it all in
there in my opinion I understand why
he's like no you pull the whole thing
but it's so little on a good quality
product huh
that it's almost not necess and what
happens with a mediocre quality product
it aside and I like stack a jar of it
and then I'm kind of mix it together
I'll press it and then I'll turn it to
edibles so that's what are you do the
it's the freebie you know and the homies
come over I mean but it's either I
called it a trashy Sh pretty much you
know what I mean if it's not pressable
and like like you said it's all how you
do your wash though because everybody
does their wash is different everybody
says oh you should do you know eight
washes yes I used to do eight washes but
liked every sure he's different
I don't wash lashes on a certain strain
and it's fine now washed for another one
it's already turning green dumps into a
chlorophyll and they're like okay can't
go any further right sure right now the
Keith in my experience working with
material is you're fighting against the
the the agitation the breaking down of
material in the chloroform all those
things are gonna create contamination so
my thought process is do it as fast as
possible hurry up and get your wash done
so with the different techniques and
different analyzation zyv managed to
only have to do two washes and I do -
five minutes five minutes five minutes
and I don't do it in dumps so that is
that's a standard process that's my dry
material I have to treat my dry material
this way because dry material is easier
to fall apart it's easier to the grade
it's easier to not make your watch on
him just dry come out white you know I
mean if you want to have a beautiful you
can't have the contaminations but you
also don't want to lose your yield so my
whole thing is like okay I need to
improve my quality and I want to improve
my yield so and therefore I need to
decrease
my agitation but do certain things to
pull these heads off as fast as you do
what do you use fresh water ice yeah I
used washing machine I I have four RV
washers I have medea big washing it's
equipment like three of the little
washer can have like a better more
sensitive like surface if you're gonna
use dry material there's all of that
matter actually it's not yet that's
great thing so it's not gonna cause more
jamming more or less damage because and
I only washed by hand and I also don't
feed biting me pumps everybody else
usually has like a washer like he does
where there's a pump that feeds the
water somewhere everything that I do is
gravity fed I have pulleys in my room
where I pulled it back to the ceiling so
you build this system myself yeah it use
a deer carcass toys oh yeah I'm gonna
have Amazon well just like what is gonna
hold 300 pounds of water and ice and you
do it differently or did someone teach
you this process no I've just kind of
long it I I evolved over like watching
what was on the internet there's no
freaking information out there no one
wants so good so what does that do other
people use gravity not medicine away
what additional a traditional ways you
hang the bag a little bag and you wash
it by hand can bubble bags is who I
watched in Amsterdam and yet I did the
drill gone oh and he literally held the
bag up and they said tie them off on
poles and let drop drip drip and that's
exactly no that takes forever lost to
the pumps in a bright and I don't know
if there's any oil in a pump that's
being used yeah I don't know your stuff
contamination the only thing on pumping
is my raw water with my RO comes to my
pump because it's a 300 gallon or ro
tank so I have to pump that out so I
have that being pump which is my clean
water and then I have my ways oh you do
you dumb-butt puri but I'm done right
this was washer well this is the most
important quality you're going for like
what do you like what do you mean like
in regards to the preservation like is
it is it like when I walk into a
what am I looking for like if I walk
into a nine product is it the purest and
product my idea you are want an unhappy
sure clean the true essence of the
flower with out the carcinogenic green
material so I want to understand
something backwards intuition it's of
that it's rinsing it all out if we're
doing it right it's already pure unless
you unless you have like cats wandering
around your room with hair everywhere
like this is the only way you're not so
but we're rinsing to show me think about
that again but what you don't you don't
understand yes he's rinsing but then it
goes into another filtration bagging
through another filtration back through
you know and then you have your hash
then you put it in another filtration
bag and then you press it you have no
idea how much effort see yeah it's going
through getting into my job for example
this Cushman's was uh this is my biggest
dumper the mints
it blew my mind on how this one put out
some of the best I've ever made right
there so this is a different texture of
the click here's a version of it now
yeah I thought what we were talking
about are we trying to go with this we
were talking about the rinsing and just
how many filtration Baumann
oh right that's right yeah so on the
Cushman's okay that one right again I I
used to do full spec okay I'm a believer
of this full spec I still believe in
like for my personal consumption but I
am not the person buying my rosin I have
to remember that you know what I mean so
I have to pay attention to what they
want so it's it may be against you know
what I believe and it's a challenge
my definition of full spec would not be
what his would be my full definition of
a full spec would be first run every
single bag the the if we're making
bubble hash
that's a different collection I'm gonna
choose different qualities in that case
yeah Rasen I'm looking for certain
qualities in that hash and there's I
don't want floof I call the stocks floof
yeah so I don't want flu fight if my
puzzle screw up your freeze-drying
too it's it's it's just it's it's not
necessary it doesn't make your end
quality product there straws they're
empty straws yeah you know and their
fluids empty taste any and it takes all
my you get a pile of it put it on bags
and squish it you get like nothing comes
out yes so you know that there's nothing
is freakin flu contamination your yields
go down you know
so this Cushman's best whatever I mean I
generally pull pressable hash my goal
okay as a keeper is 15 to 20 percent
that's I don't want evidence which that
is oh it oh that's see he knows what
number see that's where I have a hard
time process which is a perfect which is
what you want anything more is just
massive icing on the cake where I have
like an outdoor GMO that I run with Al
Gore but greenhouse it's just it's
sunlight driven but it's it has indoor
you know where I'm removing the elements
you know what I mean and that's pumping
like seven and a half percent which is
insane which would be like fresh frozen
yeah which would literally be like 36
percent return which is like impossible
you do that an app in your head you're
like how does this pull this nug right
here 33% of that nug is all crystal how
the fuck is that even possible like
maybe the ruining your head like there's
no way and then it does it and it's
amazing so there's some there's some
strain strain specific very strange
specific and I've also noticed soil and
Sun really have a major factor on it
especially on the time of the year that
you're growing it yeah it is a huge
difference so oh yeah your environmental
conditions completely if you got your
room hot it's just like the Sun is hot
you're gonna have melty heads you're not
gonna have the most peak performing
trikes you know outdoor farmers have a
tougher
Challenge outdoor hashish ins their
process if it's very outdoor we don't
get dust yes there's other processes
that you need to do prior to washing
you've got to wash your material so you
can wash it literally I mean everybody
background it's like great you don't
it's in the air
they can use those so I got my hat's off
to the to the guys who process outdoor
on the trail and bring the fire because
that is a challenge in itself where I'm
fortunate where the indoor material the
doors are closed we're not allowed to
walk in there unless we're supposed to
be doing something in there and that's
how you you know you keep a facility and
the it's called a control environment
control that's exactly right because if
you open that door everything changes
the air evacuate co2 evacuates
temperature rise humidity changes that
hot air come round bump pop boom
everything is off for the next 3-4 hours
so you need to minimize that and people
don't realize that they want to bring
their homies in and I get invited to
other facilities and they're like
Oakland or to come on in and I'm like no
no I'm like you don't know where I've
been
that's what I'm saying like I just came
from the street I didn't even change
like a lot of grow rooms of different
sizes what do you think is the best size
the size that you can Randle depending
on what you can handle the more you have
the more details the more things are
gonna go wrong so it just depends on
what can you handle my opinion for one
person no more than 20 lights 20,000
watts that's for one guy that's what
you're doing any more than that you're
gonna have mistakes you're gonna you're
gonna better be right with you better be
good no vacations no no your homies like
yeah we're gonna go fishing those good
no I have a residue change I have to
learn Amelie you are never ready you are
a slave
that garden yeah that race-off flood
light goes out oh yeah oh shit I left
the RO on mmm hello
you're gonna go now it's turned around
dude my arms still over those so the
stupid thing won't close and it just
slowly drips and finally I piped it to
the drain when you go to trade shows now
what you see are these like cool
automated systems they're selling that
you can use nothing is more reliable
than being there and doing it those
things can because I pull touch we gotta
monitor them yeah they real work as long
as somebody's there to fix them then
they're not because they do the job but
corrosion happens things get caught in
the line you know that's right yes what
about lights lights what about my heaven
what about what do you like to use for
indoor yeah I'm old-school dude or horny
lux's yeah you know everyone's now at
the DeVito's forties is that ready are
we gonna heater up or I gotta use this
thing right I'm gonna try it and just
use that yeah yeah but give it about oh
you're already working on it thank you
sweet yeah it all depends on your
communities garage either ceiling
usually it works a little better yeah
I personally based on who was get to
work Ross I don't even have the desire
to grow at home because the level that
I'm able to see these guys perform at it
just like it's like why even try like in
my eyes because I'm lucky enough to be a
part of this facility every day where I
feel well not only that I might grow fix
by being a part of their facility so I'm
like I don't need a fucking headache at
home so it allows me to dedicate more of
my time to my craft and my growing which
if I weren't in that position then yeah
I'd want to definitely grow like I've
always grown group go yeah
it might be a little whoa you guys have
Meeks yeah it's right there charlie okay
my buddy's dude yeah what do you call
this one
I was watermelon og but that grape
stompers thank you no do something to me
break it without being on the pad there
only the truth how was it taste good
yeah and it hit nice - it didn't I'm not
a big dabber number one I tell you I
only do dabs to test my product you know
and and also to enjoy with friends so
it's like a social thing you know what I
mean but I'm not a I don't have my own
peak I don't have I have my own Gaborik
but again I don't use it to test it so
people can so that way I know if there's
any contaminations in my prodigal so
what's your favorite method of
consumption what we just had I had a
snake in here so I prefer putting my
hash back with the flour
I like that combo I also will top just
about every Bowl I smoked whether it's a
bong or a pipe it gets a little piece of
rosin and that's why I prefer my type of
texture versus the jar tech which
applies heat makes it all gummy it's so
important if you guys could talk about
texture can you speak more on growing
for the melt one of the main one of the
main reasons I follow you all is I'm on
the East Coast where we don't have good
melt knowledge so what's the question
regarding melt I think growing fur melt
like um well just what genetics you like
to grow for it's a very strained
dependent do you know for good melts a
lot of this thick stuff that pumps
is much better with the melt the GMO is
really good the cookies-and-cream stuff
the strong anti stuff is really good but
you have to once you grow it wherever
you're at that's when you have to do
your tests that he's talking about you
have to break down all those bags and
actually do a test of each head to see
which one melts the best where the meet
set like yeah what else that and you
better think oh well the first wash is
always the best well that's not true
sometimes the first wash you're getting
a lot of dirt because you are washing
your plant you're you're cleaning a lot
of crap off that's just been built up
there's dust every room you go in in
every house it builds up doesn't matter
so sometimes I feel the second and third
wash are really good really oh yeah
third you can jump used to be my dumper
when I when I washed three times on a
regular my third was my dumper but my
number two is my dumper I get it number
one number two it's it's it's I mean if
I wouldn't grow four four melt I would
grow for what you desire taste and then
you can figure out your melt you can
figure out which ones you want to choose
to you know go down that path in that
when that happens okay I want this
strain okay I want you know strong Anna
or whatever the case may be but like I
haven't seen there's not much melt out
there there's like oh gee you know
there's no oh geez it's not if there's
not a big deal wash wash got a big
market I have like the old school the og
rascal Wi-Fi cut and this thing pumps
for Wi-Fi for an OG like it actually
smells like OG and does well and it's
white tell ya it's one of the few og
strains that comes through and you're
like okay cool it so gene it's still
half
actually here's an OG I just happened to
have it in there and you got to open it
up you know what I mean like give it the
world yeah my buddy grows oh geez he
gave me a pound of trim and same thing
Washington want to see what I do you
know what comes with oh nice and it's
yeah that was that's like you know you
sometimes you just go into a room and
you're lucky with a strain it's got that
sour bite like make sure your salivary
it just was probably one of the best
terpenes that I've ever had come out you
know like okay the plant smelled like
that and you wash it and it just smells
even better than the plant did and
that's what you're trying to capture
you're trying to capture the essence the
essence of that plant and then when
there's other things sprayed on that
plant it it comes out stronger you know
that extra or you'll get a bad taste in
the back here throat like almost
immediately if someone's sprayed in
their plant and you're gonna turn it
into ash is that the only one that
doesn't die
that's the wife I want it's a Wi-Fi
there's only one that doesn't have a
sticker and that's the alien rock candy
which only pumped like 2%
I like your packaging thank you Matt
it's dope this just a label maker
brothers a secret but it fits your jar /
yeah it's a jar real gold sticker plug
what sticker plug he orders them from
Germany and they're actually then I
wrote the my Ron they're not just
painted glass no it's the real deal
the actual glass is that color they're
more expensive than any jar I use it
sucks my bigger jars my big ball jars
are cheaper than these my big ball jars
with the metal cap and everything are
literally like 60 cents cheaper each
they keep the sunlight out that's the
benefit of those and they're extremely
these are all his yeah the little little
my Ron
these are all different flavors I have
the clear bottom ones so they that's so
they it's kind of burdening I don't buy
them they actually just they come to me
[Music]
I'm not that I'd we'd not that I get up
for free I'm just saying that I don't go
out and get them I could order them but
they're so damn expensive unless you
order 10,000 so he orders the 10k and
then I get a little bit of a cut not
that's five great question washes I
believe and it's all five washes it's
not just first or anything little speck
it's all five washes forty you to 179 is
what you use I use ice extracts that's
that's what I like it because they have
like different numbers that's I'm like
yeah got them nice like and then I can
oh I also even have like a 104 bag and
they're they're really nice and they
hold up really well and I probably
doesn't like 500 washes of them and they
look like the dad mom really so yeah I
really highly recommend the ice extracts
bags are you just doing a natural cold
cure um I I press very hot though people
trip on how hot I press I press it to 24
224 degrees and direct into a jar once I
press direct into a jar I whatever is
left on the paper which isn't much
because I have a pretty good funnel
flows yeah I just throw into the top of
the jar put the lid on and I set it in a
dark room for like three days to three
why does that seem like it would be too
hot because it would have a parade
people think that you're burning it or
it's gonna like we're gonna ruin it but
if you watch any one of my live videos
you can watch one from today if you go
on my yeah on my Instagram I was like I
said I was pressing right before I got
here
I pressed at 225 224 whatever then it
was piss yellow I mean I said why does
you want it what well how many grams are
you going in on your puck like I do like
22 gram bags and then I do like four to
six of them I can
do that goes into one jar yeah and that
all go to one jar I don't I try not to
do more than a hundred grams at a time
because then it won't fit in the jar
it'll actually like start to muffin up
so crazy you kind of gotta like Table
eight now so like 90 is about what you
want to do it the most and then I just
jar it on the lid and I said it in a
dark room that's a little bit warmer
because I for some reason I have this
closet that has my water heater in it so
it stays at about eighty degrees and I
just put it on a wood shelf so it's not
like on metal where it's getting hot and
cold hot and cold
wood on that content wood a thick piece
of wood takes longer to change
temperatures like 60 to 80 grams and
then like two or three days and then
depending on consistency like I have
this gnarly tool that I just beat the
living hell out of it with and I just
twist it up and smash it and go over and
over like two or three days you can sort
of see it start to do like a little bit
of a change and it'll almost like
separate itself from the jar and they'll
be like like white flaky lines towards
the bottom and stuff like that and you
just know okay it's good to go and it'll
usually build up a little pressure and
when you crack them too you know okay
cool it's been doing its thing that's
fermenting it's rotting it's it's eating
ensuring the Turks are literally doing
what it's supposed to it's it's getting
juicier and that's usually where they
call just stolen my stuff anyway so yeah
it's and like you couldn't build that
room that's just something that that
he's done it is lucky you know and it
literally like I bet you figured that
out by just yeah just screwing with it
and I've asked a million people hey how
do you do this and I've tried the other
way where people throw it in the oven at
like 200 degrees and let it cook down in
the oven and then right when they're
supposed to pull it out and whip it and
I'm like screw that I'm not heating my
stuff back up I'm not I'm not putting it
in through anything like that I'm not
even setting it on a heat mat at 100 I'm
just gonna put it in that room let it
sit do it's they make sense and then I
beat the hell out of it to the point
where it becomes like super gooey and
super you know what thing would cook it
it's how it seems like it would be that
other process yet in the other
and a lot of people were all about that
for a minute and they liked that
consistency and like he said sometimes
you have to do what your customers are
asking and I was telling them you're
wrong this is not the way to do it we
shouldn't be putting it in the dam of
and they're like just just do it and
I'll buy it all know it just like turns
it like while we're in like like I don't
know I think by the consistency of mine
right now is the easiest way to dab the
easiest way to get it on add a burden
stays on the battery
would you like to demonstrate sure looks
loose I'm gonna I want to do some of the
grape stomper because I really haven't
seen any or I certainly haven't like
been posting much of this information
literally as soon as I knew as soon as I
made it it was gonna go so but anyway so
you can just kind of get a good job of
it you know you can easily do that you
could break it in half it stays on there
you can even wipe it off with your
finger if you don't want to press it on
to the to the Banger itself I actually
do courts only oh no I just don't like
ceramic I've never been a ceramic fan
that's really good that's just that's
just don't like the way it tastes really
actually I think course tastes the best
first it's for a high quality tab like
this I mean it doesn't would mean it
doesn't have one I don't know that's
it's personal preference like the owner
of puff co would call me crazy come on
they don't yeah yeah yeah he would be
like what are you talking about cuz he
only uses his ceramic one but I'm I'm
course I'm yeah I'm courts only okay
that's just I feel like no I think
courts has virtually no taste is the
purest way to smoke anything on top of
yeah yeah I mean come on I was I was
smoking weed out of a can in high school
well it's not let's not talk about
semantics here you know I always
collected
inside the residence we were making
concentrates in our little metal pipes
and it was literally in the tire and we
would chip it out of the tire and then
crazy Danny would be like lizards in it
smoking all the crazy shit back in the
back in the day yeah let's discharge it
all damn it yeah I thought it was
charging oh you guys want to try one of
these give it a go let's see here let's
start off with the Mack yeah definitely
that's Mack dry trim material the reason
I started pooling the 90 you I started
with the Mack that was my first
experiment because before that before I
started pulling different bags and it's
you know paying closer attention to my
head sizes and things like that my full
spec you asked me earlier would have
been the what is it 144 sorry we just
remember 160 the the basically the 160
is a 159 teen year 45 I don't really get
much in my 25 but all the little broken
plant material that got through
everything else I used to save it and
now it just slows down my draining yeah
it just slows the process so I don't
even have a 25 it's 40 and then go
straight tomorrow
and I all my plants that are my my
greenhouse plants get watered with my
wash oh hell yeah
that's a nutrition right there that
same nutrients that you're feeding yeah
that's what you're washing out that's
what's coming out those anti-science
better so you just recycle that water
and put it down and it's RO water so I
know it's clean it's like I just yeah
and it tastes like weed and smell just
don't pour it in there like immediately
because it's really cold give it a day
to warm up and leave it in a bucket in
the damp it and man that stuff stinks
yeah let me tell you yeah it's loud your
whole backyard on my street like every
other day and there's times where I'm
just like sitting in my house not doing
anything and it smells so bad like as if
the skunk walked into my house and
sprayed my entire house no you don't
even know then you never see anything
and you're just like literally it
smelled like an electrical fire it's so
like potent and insane and like it
smells almost like chemicals it's it's
really crazy so yeah I really
I'm sure it's gotten me off the hook a
couple times right yeah I guess it's
good yeah and my neighbors like this
super cool lady she's like 90 years old
and she's from the Yucatan and she's
like just badass and she feeds the
squirrels and the birds and all the
other neighbors hate her and I love her
to death I'm like yeah bother them all I
don't care no actually the only problems
I have is because she leaves those nuts
and stuff out for the squirrels they go
and bury them in my yard sometimes a
little digging yeah I get a little
digging action going on once in a while
so when I was washing this one I ran all
my bags again and then I was like damn
1090 you is that on this one and the 45
was like smaller than this okay
usually when I do a big wash I'm usually
washing 10 pounds so that's you know 10
12 pounds what he's smoking on right
there no I just hit the gripper but I'm
about to do something about it right
right sorry
that's a Mac one so that's the caps cut
that was gifted to the real iog and the
real iog tissue cultured it and gifted
it to LA family farms and so that's how
that's that is the true tissue cultured
Mac one miracle alien cookies so like I
was saying I ran all the bags and then I
was like wow this thing does have a phat
90 and it had like a you know a big 90
you like this a 45 about that size
73 like that size and so I'm like I'm
okay with leaving that out you know what
I mean yeah it's not gonna hurt me
compared to this so and if it's a really
that much of a difference like it looks
way different there's a different color
by all means please you know you I was a
hash maker you don't want it in there
it'll boost your product way up by
taking it out my buddy's product for
example I do this the first time I ran
it was that that 1,000 grams right I was
telling you about
yeah this is the one and guess where the
meat was did that smell so familiar
guess where the meat was that Mac that's
Tropicana cook oh it is chopped cookies
like I just ran some of this that the
meat was the 45 the 45 that was where
the meat that the heads were smaller
there was and after I did it I realized
I'm like maybe there was you know
done he might not have ran it in the
manner wheel or something told me he cut
it early that's it that's what he did so
there's also probably why I came out
whiter why do you think I've get her fat
her head cuz le family farms they are
not pulling early a lot of times they'll
pushing them to see what the genetics
could actually do different conditions
change the the length you can steer the
plant to finish early or you can steer
the plant to finish longer and and it's
amazing what some of these strains do
some line you could do a lot with like
just what you're feeding it by adding
potassium at a certain time and whatever
there's a guy that I follow named blue a
green tank the guy is so sick he doesn't
even feed his plants any food he makes
these little avocado husks that he cuts
all the meat out and then he adds like
all of his nutrients into like a big mix
in a big bowl and then puts it back in
the avocado house sets it on the ground
and he has so much like so much bacteria
beneficial bacteria and worms and lots
of bugs and he literally just has a
dripper that goes of water that goes on
the avocado and then he's grabbed the
avocados flipped him over and it's just
a giant puddle of red worms and just
like what dude he's the cabin water he's
like I had bananas for potassium I use
barley and pumpkin ground-up pumpkin
seeds you're like dude how do you even
know this shit like what are you talking
about how did you learn to do this he's
like Koreans man they're badass yeah I
can't all right all right
but yeah he was like he and he's very
he's very like open with his info he
posted everything and he's super cool
but it's also testament to how powerful
these plants are you know they they draw
everything out it's crazy how versatile
they are to that one that's the Mac yeah
can I try this yeah please thank you
yeah you know I I'm a believer of
sharing information to a degree 2 degree
B you know there are certain things that
you just those are just your
yeah that's that's what keeps you
different there's also like that I could
tell you some things you can't yeah even
if I told you and I showed you a video
you have to do it 20 times and screw up
five right to really learn it you don't
know how much material and mistakes you
don't know were you just like how I do
sometimes I'm like that was a fail where
I have done a few like first time fail
second time fail 13 and I'm doing
everything that I normally do right and
then I just have to get it and I pull my
hair and I'm like I'm like what the fuck
like everything that I know is not
fucked like I want to blow up and then I
have to tell myself dude
just let go and then awesome you think I
started a lottery sometimes you forgot
something you need to start and do the
alphabet you're forgetting a step and
you're rushing and you're getting
frustrated and it's not it is not this
machine's fault that you want to kick
and throw through the fucking wall it's
you and you just be cool
smoking ball reset come back a B C D eat
all the way through Z and then I nailed
it because you get you get accustomed to
nailing it at times you know especially
when I'm running the same material over
and over and over and over and then you
think I'm gonna do that same thing to
this thing and it just doesn't work it
just doesn't work and so now you have to
recreate a recipe to produce the what
whoever you're really good to keep a
book of screams forget what's happening
and not only that if animate some luck
as to whether chain my cush Mints the
way that I started processing their
Cushman's was not what you see today
it's the ability to continuously process
that material and get to learn about it
like a relationship you've gotta be
around it continue to nurture it look at
it evaluate it be with it be a part of
it
watch the squish
understand that the more you understand
especially you can hold that's that's a
whole nother you can you can't teach
that
oh how long the squire think oh just
because I tell you doesn't mean you know
when to push I squished fifty seconds
you know people are like what I suppose
I squish for four and a half minutes
exactly i squish at one eighty twenty
four there's like thirty four forty five
degree difference and look at the
texture differences there night and day
they don't look like the same hash maker
did it so that's what makes it's your
signature it's really cool I can do
laser logo designs on my textures I
believe this is just my belief okay yeah
I did French cheese you want to try yeah
I want like the hell with the
marketplace I'm doing like you're gonna
like how I do then he gets a very
personalized it's like you're chefs or
something you know you can only do that
to an extent and you're gonna put
yourself in a corner and what I see is
that's another challenge so I love
challenges I'm a puzzle guy so I like to
break down analyze backwards you know
what do they call that when you you know
a read the reverse engineer I'm that
type of my I read instruction manuals
for pleasure
like I don't read books you know what I
mean I I'd read instruction manuals I
like to know how machines work I'm not
the guy that it says oh yeah I'm gonna
make this thing work
yeah I don't like that people don't like
understand how like pumps work or like
you need to understand how a vacuum pump
works before you're running your freeze
dryer understand what you're using
what kind of pump oil goes in there
understand that how vacuum works
understand how when you open a valve
what which way the air is gonna go
through oh you're gonna put it on dude
go slow so you don't think about that
they don't give it to you they don't
tell you there's nothing there isn't
even harvest harvest right they don't
even have they shouldn't hold it fully
don't even happen
we're making hash and we're taking care
of the Machine better than what there's
no no we troubleshooting this guy this
guy's solving must be a bnv he has had
to take his entire machine apart redo
the firmware redo everything and
literally like teach them their mistakes
and what in their and their dude he said
he was like soldering shit I'm like what
uh-huh I'm like dude that you're not
attacked like he's like I had to be they
didn't want to take it back they didn't
want to help they don't want to do
nothing
he said they kept sending him like flash
drives where he'd have to plug in the
flash drive redo everything and I'm like
bro you could give it about ten seconds
maybe maybe fifteen that's the cows cut
too nice such a small world right right
it is it is a small circle it's not a
big it's not as big as you think and
that's where your reputation matters
yeah not being a freaking scumbag not
being a liar not doing videos not
running plants that are freakin sprayed
not you know dude just being good to
your fellow man it's like so hard to
find somebody out there like that
and I spent a breath of fresh air
finding some hash makers that are so
freakin humble and cool and like willing
to share info like that guy Anthony the
solvent must be enemy cannabis cam
Cameron's like one of the nicest people
in the world and like he's given me so
much information and helped me be
confident just to you know just to go
swimming in the deep waters you know
where you like all this weed in the
freaking in the water and I saw we're
not gonna know what's gonna happen you
know so yeah that's the thing about
washing and the process is that I do I'm
not the guy that likes to wait after the
freeze dryer you know cuz that's a whole
fucking nightmare for me to sleep
through that you know what I mean like
you dump it with all the water like I
check numbers I'm a numbers % guy so
after I do my wash I still wash and I
squeeze like the traditional hash
methods and I do my cutting up but again
temperatures play a huge role in my
ability to pull that off but I always
check my numbers I know based on the
pool that I got I got what I needed
and if I didn't then I didn't
damn good wash in and there's and
everything every second counts man like
that's how I count every millisecond
everything if I get distracted
even when I'm pressing because I do
fifty second presses I did it you know
if I get distracted dude I'll lose you
know 0.25 of my yield just like that you
know on an overall picture you know if
you're not focused and looking at it
every moment to maximize it and you know
you and I'm the same way
when you're processing and making the
hash in in the in the in the environment
that you're doing how you're doing it
how you're treating it affects your
whole end result you know so we know
we're tired that's amazing dude that guy
I was doing a live feed and someone's
like hey from UK and I was like bro you
have no idea how much that means to me
like that seriously is like the world
they are true hash connoisseurs and
that's that's where the real hash market
world is America and everything was
coming right there for Morocco's just
like going to well it's the California
it's a California thing it's ER it's our
atmosphere and we walk around started
with it you know Colorado's brought I I
got to give credit to Colorado for
bringing out the rosin but they they
also you know struggled with their
facilities so it was a way hard to grow
pot above 6,000 feet yeah and it's their
way to process early they didn't have to
worry about to take down the dry and all
the humidity spikes and all those things
so that it was it was they were almost
forced into that market like if they
weren't there could have been some
failure you know what I mean I think
that's why they went to rosin because
you know some of the flour was so
lacking just due to the the
environmental conditions you know they
couldn't finish and then they would just
make these amazing hashes that would
come out I'm a big fan rob is almost I
mean there's a lot of great hash makers
that I follow and I analyze as much as I
can
I'm not just looking at the big picture
I'm looking in the back of the round I'm
looking like what's back over there you
know there got you this picture I'm like
over there though you know so that's
that's that's how I am you know so I
there's there's nothing easy I don't
believe anything is easy and you know we
like to make it look easy because you
know it's not fucking it's your it's
your work
it's my portfolio so why would I not
want to put my best work out there yeah
yeah I bothers day will not happen to
make more mistakes than I can produce
beautiful quality I shit the better my
phone died so I'm sorry I am if I'm not
washing I'm pressing so washing and
pressing washing and pressing washing
and pressing I mean yeah I'll take a day
off here and there to go golf that's
about it 6 to 10 hours sometimes and
then look I mean some days are even
longer
I had two or three washes you can get
freaking really deep in the water yeah
let's give it a go dude I mean it's
gonna be my first time using it let's
heat it up we'll start low that way he
can do a press and we'll bump the temp
up for him I did bring some material it
has I didn't bring hard you know we got
some here you can press them of ours
because I'd like let me go those are for
a cottonmouth and they'd work very very
well
they're from See's candy and you know
what this is cool these would like to
sponsor me at any point I've never seen
impress my wash I've pressed other
people's washes and I don't I don't
prefer that I don't prefer Washington
you're pressing up
turn grab the do