exactly so what is this this is uh
a pixie stick
amazing hash
rap
pre-roll with a glass tip with uh
this one is a one gram of
hash and one gram of flour
i believe the flour is a uh it's an
indoor
manzanas from uh deo farms and
the east bay yeah
yeah and are you guessing that it's
gonna be delicious where has champelli
been
where is what where has champelli been
so he he was a grower that um
was growing the
the cassis we just brought so where's he
been hanging out for the last 20 years
great question i think there's a reason
why i sent you that article
no no for rails i want to know where
where's he been just read the damn
article
right now i'm trying to connect you come
on
so have you smoked one of these before
or no i have smoked the
two by two a couple years ago at the
emerald cup okay and it was
is that nice see it can be a different
flavor ridiculous
but because you like already connect to
like
how that first one was taken care of it
doesn't matter what the flower is at
that point you're like oh it's been
loved on
sorry so this is one gram a hash and one
gram of flour
and the other is two grams of hash and
two grams of flour
and you don't think we were deserving of
the two grams
just just joking there's no way i'd
[Laughter]
a half and a half yes
thanks for pointing that out that's
right the two gram right you got it
up and i was like oh no little like i
just saw a little kink and you know
like right and i was all what the frick
this isn't just
this is the so this is the one and one
okay that's the half okay
well tom maybe one day we will be worth
the one-on-one
what's that do you remember your first
hash experience mine were
so i lived in france for a couple years
in uh high school and
college and uh that's kind of what they
smoke so like every time
and i played hockey on a couple
different
traveling hockey teams so we go from
like ren which is the capital of
brittany where we were
to like nance or brest or other cities
and uh all all the french
all the french dudes on the team would
smoke cigarettes
and and put hash in it i mean not all of
them but like everyone smoke chain
smokes
and you'd like get off the bus right
before your game
and everyone would chain smoke a
cigarette between like
first and second period everybody's in
the locker room chain smoking after the
game everyone's chain smoking
which like i'm at like being an athlete
in the u.s you're like uh
what and uh
yeah they smoked a lot of hash there and
and what's interesting is
as an american who smokes flour that
shit knocks you out
like the nicotine hash combo but then
for them when you're like yeah let's
let's rip a tube they're like whoa like
straight marijuana like
don't be crazy and you're like what
um yeah hash would knock me out
i would that happened to me you might
have been at that event do you remember
um there's a place in santa monica they
had some
early cannabis events it was in a music
studio
oh dr norm's guy jeff did you ever go to
any of these things
any stuff jeff from dr norms he had like
a
studio and um i don't think so
um and so i was out back
smoking a joint as everyone was and
there was
you know a couple little ashtrays set up
on the metal poles so right you know
back your car know
like a little area so i remember putting
mine out
going inside for a while come back out
thinking that not pick it up go light up
i lit up
what happened to me you know a nice
little uh
old-school hashish joint
with uh tobacco and immediately my head
starts starts spinning oh yeah i i
remember
sat right in the ground grabbed a bottle
of water and
yeah no joke i just i don't smoke
tobacco so yeah no i
i would uh
crush me crush me absolutely i i
remember going to a club with these
french guys in paris and we smoked hash
in the car
on the way there and we parked the car
and everybody started getting out of the
car to go into this is like like a
midnight to 6 a.m club
this is good and i was like i can't move
so they just left me in the car i slept
in the front seat with it reclined
until they came back out it was like it
was light out
um yeah this is um
and honestly this is done right
right there you go and so that's that's
like