[Music]
you taking me you taking anger I need to
study the Maccabiah life of everyone
spots where I I collect the genetic we
call it a nightclub your life is it's a
second science of this I mean I to a
level I understood like the power of
Zeus my home but I didn't understand
that the little illegally glades yeah
but that's nutrient it's not the
microbes that brags on neutrons you see
what I mean no but the nutrients are
processed by the microbes in the soil
right the microbes are in the soil but
you add to them and then you put in your
compost tea which has the ingredients
that you have and that will be processed
in a way that will change so this is the
you know you told me you you taught me
about the story I say hi Cody according
to science it's and my clubs that do
like when we're in in France when you
say there well there is the terroir the
longer climate genetic and the farmer
but there is a terroir the test the test
of that place and
for a long time they take what couldn't
be pretty like chihuahuas navel proves
at your plant ability to capture a sense
of the other place and then when I
started to look all that stuff Ottawa I
found out that actually they are the
behind the the breaking down further and
they realized that is actually the
Maccabiah life from the soil that define
the cat because if I get soil from under
the redwood trees or soil from over here
out and a thing or soil from under oak
trees it's all different than microbes
not the minerals may be the same but the
micro imagine in Bordeaux you have field
well there is a little der stack in
between
yeah and in between those two well there
is a cell use different in the
characteristic over of the wine and it's
a little micro here inside so see the
microbes break down the nutrients that
you put in whatever and when they break
them down they make them accessible to
the plants right but those are suppose
we call those indigenous microorganisms
they're from the place and so in real
regenerative farming you cultivate those
indigenous my coordinates from your
local farm yeah but you put you cannot
adapt genetic from abode to that you
need you need to have like maybe not
just a microbial life but you need to
have like a bunch of zoos microbes that
are similar so that the plant can really
adapt better well the plant will adapt
over time because of the microbes the
genetics yes but the microbes I agree on
a percent and we're just really finding
out how it actually does that work right
the various kinds of bacterium which are
in there and then the fungi fungi and
then the nematodes you know about the
nematodes have you ever seen those on a
Microsoft
the first person I ever saw that was
talking about my cough like I'm talking
about raising so my realization friend
friend she was that there's an old
saying in in mystical thing as above so
below
right and now I say as above so below
because there's life in that soil in a
way that's not just life it's Jeff
Lowrance house calls it the livings the
soil food web and everything into
relates to everything else so the the
worm dies or cast off itself summon
something eating that shell of the worm
the worm poops out and something eating
that right and then it dies and then
something else eats that and then the
nematode is eating that and they're bad
nematodes and good nematodes right and
then some of the fungi go into the root
system the key thing for me Frenchy was
to realize that the plant roots put out
I always thought the plants to suck up
which they certainly do but they
actually exude they're called eggs as
much as it would on the outside with a
table or a stack everything that move
around the branch is controlled by the
blondie van Hooser protocol whatever
planes are grounded sockets another
story is that you give me this I give
you this ooh girl that but thank you
please
there are everything's dropping from
those fees but nobody turns the soil
kills the soil
nobody water sit nobody feeds it what
happens it falls on the soil 30 years
later it's all decomposed down because
the microbes have done and then what is
the plan - it brings it back up again
and it's a total cycle they call it the
law of return the plant gives to the
soil the soil transforms it through the
microbial life and then the plant and
then reate reacts is again
and so once you have a forest living
like that it's self regenitive it feeds
itself right the sustainable well
actually at the edge of the forest you
have to plan your place as your
permaculture to say how do I fit into
this total landscape right there's land
here that's good for this and there's
other land that's not good for showing
the microbial life in for different type
of plant so you can literally use
Michael to go only what you want on your
own bacteria no no but I mean you can
you can avoid I think weed or any any
plant that you don't want depending on
the microbial life that you have in your
soul right but see if we look at we just
yeah same time yeah
well it's got to be Panama
like eat whatever I did some workshop in
Seattle in and then well a 99% of the
farmer in Washington or Endora me away
before that I had seen like one in Spain
and one year in Canada doing
no chill inside it's pretty I mean I I
want to see the whole world of that guy
in Spain if you go inside like like all
the people out when you see that because
it's alive with life and she was exactly
the opposite of what you wants to do
they want to have a sterile room a
totally controlled environment but but
now you bring in living soil and you've
got a living environment right you see
the thing the reason that the plan
creates
terpenes and and try coal and
cannabinoids is to protect itself right
and if you're out in they're all open in
natural soil there's many things you
have to protect yourself so they produce
a variety of terpenes and many different
kind of cannabinoids to protect
themselves and then we use those for the
same purpose one game you'll making a
cheetah yeah
[Music]
alpenglow Craig's teetsi ball so - too
much - yeah because I don't know
yeah Jacob has some of the best weed and
hash around well I think you won Oh what
recently right for the edge a nod oh the
pink Sunshine's doing a pink Nepali
right now across to the rebel moon it's
giving me
reminiscent of the mountain man swimmy
ad what was that blood well you add its
I have neither you know the field in
mallanna like Zeus field in Milan Azalea
specific smell that you don't find in us
it's all loose food campaign together
here the flower that smelled exactly
like you sleep the first time I smell it
all my ever while back two years back
and I even find the seed that I gave you
my first EP yeah it was it was it was
being is like when I smell it the first
time I was back in the mountain in the
at the end of the valley mallanna in the
middle of the field making Chavez feel
like that exact exact up in profile and
you know I smell can totally hurry don't
taste at all like like what I was making
you know there but I had never come even
when I first came back to the states in
no.3 well no is actually more like 99
and people would say here try this hash
try this hash and I say this is grass
hash you know I mean it's like smelled
like my front lawn you know when I used
to mow it and there's like there was no
concept of how to make true fine hash
right and of course what's that term
mean is it chatter says you know it's
wet all these different ways to make it
now the experimentation is tremendous
between what how many different way
there's resin rosin wax shadow all these
different things it's hard to keep track
but for me I still like the dry sift
from my from my trim train because it's
so different from an extract if you
drink the juice from a foot and you live
beyond the world my takes that create is
the sugar and the juice it's maybe of
the Apple or the the food but it's not
the food anymore
when you take the resin from the resin
head from the matrix that created us
onward 50-plus cannabinoid and Android
50 Pro step and you
behind that matrix that created it when
I make us that matrix is inside the
resume like when you make wine the skin
is inside the juice to be able to make
to share man to do that to add that
chemical reaction if you take the juice
from the of the grape you can make pure
alcohol and well then but you cannot
make wine at all doesn't matter your
take you cannot create the wine if you
don't have the matrix that created the
sugar and the skin of the grape right
there's all these microbes and mist and
so on on the skin of the grape yeah and
so that's why the full plant has all of
that but when you extract you get into a
domain that is so vast and so you can
create so many different projects until
you have something that is so pure that
even Big Pharma I have to to face
reality we can actually extract 99.9
percent Cannavino heed as isolate and
distillate something that they've been
telling us for 50 years you could undo
that's why you needed to do it
chemically you know I mean it's like
there is a that advanced in in the BH to
extraction it's a you teammate mean to
capture and separate all those compound
and then test them for that right as
against when you isolate so far down it
become the Western medicine when you
start extracting you step out of the
entourage effect and you have that world
territory of amazing extract and ash is
that in between is like we don't have
the 450 compound of the plant that you
we have
any whites faked or move but you know I
think I think the cannabis world is big
enough for all of that because those
isolates are gonna have specific medical
use that we're gonna discover right
we're all about the whole planet all
100% all that way but I think that there
are gonna be we're gonna they're gonna
be able to isolate certain things in
pinpoint and I think that's really
exciting and that's what's happening
here
no it's really exciting that way and in
the way they're playing with some things
that is they have to make make it up
literally
so yeah the cannabis plant could use
their friends that everywhere in our not
unique to the plant but that depend
profile of Android plus their pen most
of them you canto cannot quantify that's
unique that you cannot duplicate so
that's why I call it the ensemble not
the entourage because all of them are
playing right all of them are playing
Entourage it's usually one playing
everybody following but the ensemble of
a 500 or an orchestra in America it is
he told me that when it's in the plant
it's the ensemble okay well because in
that sense THC is probably leading THC
would be the dominant most ancient
device that is known basically so we did
a mixture today of a little bit of
tobacco and a hash made from Sun Bowl
farms grown in humble dry farmed
sunshine Johnson yeah so did the rebel
moon for this and then Craig from Alpine
glow to the THC bomb these are both
regenerative farms which for me and my
data topped yield and THC and
cannabinoid content so it's a huge proof
that you don't need inputs you don't
need chemicals and if you just work with
nature you can produce the most fire no
sorry no commercial synthetic and rights
no sunshine she is in a very specific
place where she can do dry farming it's
not the high farming that define quality
she's she's into images with the place
where she is going and she's using that
ability to limit totally the water input
so that
that launch I have to kick into a
defensive system and use a lot of
laziness well but how long has she been
growing there does anyone know this is
the fourth year we're doing on the same
exact spot but also to make people kind
of understand so it's a flood zone that
place yes yeah every 50 years it's under
water
yeah yeah it's also right in between the
Avenue of the Giants which are some of
the biggest plants and the biggest
respiratory they're breathing all the
time and they're blowing they're blowing
so much moisture throughout that valley
in the morning that yes they're doing
your watering for you so it's not like
people say oh how can you grow plants
underneath the ground so when you say
what's average used for cannabis you're
really talking through your head because
there's no average juice from that no it
all depends depends on the long she's
got redwood air where I grow I have Doug
Fir air right Doug for an oak air and so
I think that makes a difference so
you're gonna I love cold air Pollak
they're called una caja like Hara Hara
Mahadeva
Bombo lay it spiritual so and this is a
brand new chill I'm right down blessings
on the children so here we go Thank You
Frenchie Wow
was a big deal in India because when you
did they catch the Chilam to the to the
God there is a lot of awareness that
comes to what you do like that the panel
last night we're talking about making
the tea in India when you smoke it's a
big deal normally the Chilam always goes
to the right and you pass with you right
and you only take with your right hand
son mud Frenchy kind of honor to me past
it this way and then you have to say
Kali Chilam which is the feminine energy
going to the left side but it was all
unsaid but can I be spaced on bone in
Himalayan Plateau next to the big lake
sing like yeah that is like so they find
the birthplace of cannabis when it's
separated from him you lose 28 million
years ago from the herbs six million
years ago it was up to Europe because
there is at cojiro of all the ash
producing country the same climatic only
1 million years ago it went to South
China and only 300 70 South
who jumped in Malaya and became tropical
so that front was a desert plant to
start with that way when you are genetic
that come from anyway a birth a tropical
country you really need a little water
when you have in a place where there is
so much water in the air to start with
you know I mean like new research on
Poland I understand it to you the feet
of the Himalaya or China this is and
it's next to the oldest evidence of
humanity on that continent it's next to
the brows face of cannabis yes 2.1
million years old yeah we've been
working with this plant for a long time
and that's its ethnobotany they call it
the interaction of the human and and
that's to our also the culture of the
people creating it right and so that's
why we value Afghani hash right or we
even say you know Manali right or Kulu
Valley and you know can you tell the
difference you know the difference
between a kulu-manali like I was for a
man seen in the Carew in Manali I didn't
touch a plant until I was in inter
connect and I didn't want to touch any
plant before I was at the place where
they're supposed to be the top of the
dark I see yeah
but Manali before I think nobody thought
it was all white can I be Zander the
more the demands activated common okay
me more Farrell I think it was actually
Farrell not really wild because it had
been cultivated and then Jen because the
Farrell cannabis tends to go 5050
usually CBD THC by men it's like what
does she come from in yeah it's it's not
it's way lower in your CBDs and yeah
yeah I know I gave him the chino Moises
I here look at that stone children from
Funko I don't know the whole lineage of
the chillin thing it was there a Lorenzo
two or not know that tells the guy who
was Renzo random yeah yeah exactly and
anyone still have a Renzo Jim no madman
was all kind of Israel but he was funny
because I took only the first year I was
in a mountain we were lucky to meet a
good friend of my best friend that that
spend some time in Colombia and the
French guys were who is a guy had been
fifteen years in a mountain and he was
buying all the best of the best in
torsion act on so for three weeks I saw
a lot of us come in front of my nose and
the resin I took for me you want jungle
ocean act on you won't captivated
mallanna so the second year I son my
best friend too
get some field as far away from the
village as possible in in Milano Valley
and and I want to do the jungle
interacting for ski weeks alone when I
came down I'd still 19:2 in pooja with
an Italian house and that Italian dude
was burning chillin was burning chillin
in in oven in the morning and I didn't
really understand how special it was to
share my own jungle I didn't get hit
either I didn't understand the value
people put into the chill of quality of
your children and the quality of your
vision that defines the respect that you
receive so because I kicked off my year
jungle all night long with him in the
morning if I can get me a chill um but I
did not know that dude
so when arriving Manny Callum and I walk
my children with a bunch of Italians
they look at me like I had fucking stole
the kiss because that's that guy
literally chants totally what Chilam was
in India I may use a different type of
clay this is a very important part of
any Chilam smoking you want to clean it
right because that's another thing they
look at your children they pull up the
children's this Chilam clean is this
dude clean right isn't that right it's
part of the ritual and so also you look
out our fines the police's inside the
children right it doesn't to be like a
mirror but it's Pawar's so it's gonna
absorb a lot of the tar from it no it's
only it's only orphaned orphaned to see
for different type of claim
yeah episode yeah you won't set
absorption let's see this is the high
art this is the high art of chillin
making see because you can get these
little throwaway chillings all over the
place that are little tiny one to one or
two people chill them so that's true
that sort of status I suppose it's all
about the don't give you that to smoke
when they look at your art they don't
know you you need never touch their
children it's like and when you knew in
India you don't understand that the
world respect that you receive it the
Chilam you have in your on and the
quality of the resin you put in even
15-20 years all people in in India if
you have the goods they're going to give
you respect doesn't matter how long
you've been in India if you don't have
it they don't even give you the time of
the day as well it's not very nice
actually they are not really welcoming
well it's the caste system yeah you
gotta you gotta earn your creds no
question about it but how hardcore is it
to go up into the mountains like I've
got lost there before it's like you live
in a cave for months the closer shop is
like two days walk the closes bus is
today's walk or spraying and you have to
bring all your shit and
it's clay you have to be crazy crazy
crazy about raising quality to put
yourselves with that type of shit then
it's at Z at before the winter if you
get stuck in mallanna with the snow and
there is one pass at 12,000 feet when
you ask that person you have like a snow
up to your your tight and the shitty
basket old and plastic bag to stay you
know I mean it's your you can kill
yourself you have to be now that I think
of it with such a sleeping bag so far
with like I was insane to do shit like
that but it's the best time in my life
the road one point is like
no as @zn and they were moving from me
to take her like the chance my visa I
was going to change my sermons visa I
was supposed to face shortywood here
they wanted Saladin would be I am gonna
come back to go now the first time at
first time I went to Nepal I believe was
70 70 we I was working on a movie called
Sun seed and we were filming various
teachers around so we went and filmed at
the swayambhu we filmed the rinpoche at
swayambhu with the long trumpets like
that woo and they're doing a snapping
thing and they're chanting this an
amazing chanting and pouring tea it's up
on top of the hill there and then I went
back a year later but I went over land
from from Amsterdam all the way up to
Nepal again and then I had a house in
back of swayambhu and I stayed there for
about three months there and every day
around the temple around the hill
swayambhu hill yeah I wasn't really into
the hash at the point it was just there
I wasn't like you I wasn't seeking out
that most rare extreme place I was there
just to be sitting in painting and being
people think that I was going there and
sitting at the feet of the Machine I
wasn't going there to make my own that
basically it is like so it's like I
learned because I you try you walk
alongside with the same tour and stuff
like that and then the loca but when I
came to Indiana the difference was all
my life I work mostly in a winter in
producing country and with bundle of the
high material so for me to be able to
get that one kilo one kilo an Alf two
kilos that I need from a year
consummation I need to I need to move to
do a lot
of sieving so the deal was okay I gonna
make a cheeky low hundred kilo to get
what I want okay everything I drank no
but everything I do I leave behind me to
that local farm me I just want that kilo
of two of the pure him what my price
were how much do I have to pay for
staying with you
so long you have all this almost make
are you gonna make me pay for the
cheetah kilo of creams that I'm taking
that was a deal like melt like something
so melty you it melt when I use quality
of your CV by sieving to a Louisville by
a bay it's like so I take that bangle
in the home where I break down
everything I took all the stock
everything out this my first CD
superlight that's what I keep for myself
aha
everything Oh - what you're doing onto a
screen yeah disorder I see you so you
have a screen like this and you're
breaking it up to get enough of these I
need to have a lot of material material
it's stupid to do it only one time I go
to do ten times all Jews great I'm ready
to give it in the neck change for
hospital and and that they don't kill me
on the price for what I'm making because
that normal is at your stash you know
what I mean so it's like I'm I take your
stash but I give you everything else and
I'm ready to give you a good price
because I'm not spending much money and
I stay long with them you know I mean so
you need to super compensate with your
thumb to be able to get that stuff in
India is different in India you
literally stick libraries in on your
hand like the relation with the plant
doing that in the most remote valley of
the Malaya and shit is like it's
different like that was the first time
where I had that relation with a blonde
I did not understand it it took me a
year to come here to understand genetic
but I had that strong volition for the
first time was that living
oh yeah it's I mean burns like everyday
bounce after months it like it like it
and then what do you do with that you
you you you cover them it's all
caressing so you're sepia light you you
you waste you the jungle the jungle
usually is the season is earlier than
anything cultivated so the jungle is
like early September to end of September
mid September to the first week of
October and then up to end of November
you have cultivated sometime even have I
had a season where it focused snow like
this much but today later it had melted
and we didn't finish our field so we
went back to see it all the plant were
all back up but they were like semi wild
plant we let them every year we didn't
touch them we let them go back to work
to the wild so they were all standard
but they were all burn by the basal snow
so you we had a lot of contaminant you
know and that we couldn't separate bunch
of make us make them survive survival
the species they put out something else
when now you have to is sticky but if
you have water in your hand it's not
gonna stick you don't stick if you have
oily and you don't stick if you break
the plant and there is water from the
plant and clover files that come in your
hand it's not going to stick the same
ASA
it's gonna take a while before I was
always like you just catch the prawns
the first time
you look at your own it's all shiny and
it's cheesy like fucking crazy and then
layer blown by plant layer by layer
every plant you clean up any any little
particulars that stick to it and slowly
slowly player and the color start to
appear and it got from transfer horns to
light on the Ong ahead and then when you
have a secret lair its dark almost black
then when you have enough and you
careful you see that when you carriage
the blonde that is chunk of your ear
from your hand that goes out it's time
to stop and then you take your Sun you
turn it on your hand and you snap it out
and all the ash is gonna be on your Sun
and then you can stick all your hand it
becomes about it's still sticky but it
becomes epi wine the most difficult is
actually to don't feel this to your son
and then there is two way all you do a
finger that means that you hold in your
that piece of art so you kept pure
whatever is left in your arm or Mia I
like better because but the local did
not have plastic in the time I admit I
made likes flat pancake into a sink
plastic so that there is very little air
that can get in contact with the resin
and create more than shit because in any
other problem is Molly's are given when
your resin is perfectly clean so the
mold spore everywhere and they stick to
the resin so you have a bunch of finger
super clean but they put them all
together into a big
but pounder there's a queen you have the
merge that is coming only when you bring
it to the mountain down in South India
right because the temperature change
there's a place when you're when you're
molding a hash where at a certain point
it changes right the texture changes and
the color changes and now it's not it's
like it's light rays in but it does not
have it's not like live reason we got
from with ice water not at all as much
as the high regime - is the same than
ice water dry-cured regime life is in in
your hand is very different and I've
risen from the machine I don't know why
because it's it shouldn't miss the
define never seen new creation in my
life and there is 70% humidity easy you
know I mean yeah it's easy you mean make
like 20 grams a day when T so T or they
can make 5 grams of creme so then to get
them to make creme is very hard you need
you next to you yeah okay you walk like
me you instead of making 20 gram at so
much money you're gonna make only 5 7 10
gram I give you as much money for what
oh I had a one time I Chi I wonder with
with I mean that was pretty amazing in
Marana like it change the perspective
and the deal was a guy say everything
you make I put out that I buy of I
quality on the table and at the end of
the season we go together to New Delhi
and I sell it to the foyer of the same
way that I would sell it for me and
that's your payment for the for what you
are
giving me basically all you have the
local people also that come and and do
the field around you they know what you
want and they know that you're ready to
pay for it so they do generally work for
you and every night when you got starts
they should use their undoing the days I
could stay close but no it's a sad
situation because thank you
before the farmers used to go there and
they had this work word called Cod and
and Cod used to mean goat shit now if
you go to the mountains and ask them
what Cod is they pull out this little
pink bag of salts so like it's been
completely destroyed because so many of
the demand for hash is so high
especially with India as an economic
boom like everybody smokes hash in the
cities so now you have these farmers
pushed and they're growing with salts
and ruining that whole all of those
hills
we need worldwide legal to change
everything if you if you bring foreign
genetic to a place where the genetic is
possibly 1600 and no six hundred and
seventy thousand years old it's like
you're you're polluting pools either
technically speaking it's a national
credit treasure and the Indians they
won't actually they ask father I had
some huge agreement on farm the guy
wanted genetic from here to to bring to
India and I was telling him it's like
you have vast source of amazing and
unique genetic India and you want to
bring something for end that is based
the I know predation or actually long
race and you want to bring that there
and pollute something that is unique to
your present
man you don't get it and they don't it's
because this is a market in Europe they
want to they want to do the same they
want to smoke the same well the Indian
government is now actually trying to do
a landrace catalog and they're about to
start doing that and one of the things
is for that whole thing with the genetic
markers right but they want to make sure
that they get land races that are still
existing not just in him all but in
Orissa and also not time on Andrew but
Andhra Pradesh
there's also traditional cannabis
growing areas right and so right and so
but they're still hung up on the 0.3%
they're still they're only gonna stake
stuff that's 0.3% and then they they
sort of don't get it right about full
plant right is level of THC is like from
the old ash I was smoking when I was
young there is a scientist in Israel
they did a study on ten years of bursts
in his a Moroccan Lebanese an Indian and
it was from the 1992 the 2000 so it's
not too far for my time to be a huge
difference between what I was smoking in
France and and Zeus bursts Lebanese is
basically a one on one CBD THC and it
has a pretty low level of THC they were
seeing only looking only at thecb CBD
and CBN it's like four percent THC so
they're telling me that the fucking red
Lebanese that I remember forty five
years later was only four percent THC is
like it's cracking me up
Malkin two to one is a Malkin - are you
a percentage of THC and CBD and in India
is basically five to one there's a lot
more THC but like from the mountains the
chalice is like fourteen percent THC for
TM so it's like I
but even even even if it's not the
greatest of the greatest it show very
much emerge the entourage effect
actually give power to to the ash with
smog because there is no way I was
smoking a one on one focus on THC and
still be raving about it so many years
later I dream to smoke already bunnies
you know what I mean it's like there is
no way that if he didn't have that
specific depend profile that he's so
unique you cannot even describe it
[Music]
we we only made like three four grams
super nice it's a super nice high and I
don't think there is much we tested it
it was a lot of CBD I made a 52% CBD but
I never tried them until Milan a months
ago when I was a judge I'd sell for the
ash made from I CBD almost 0.3 percent
THC so the first time I smoked false
belief you know in the morning clean
this is science I appreciate your
dedication here come on now wait wait
what tobacco and CBD what yeah is pure
hash okay so I I wake up in the morning
I have a bunch of aches and pain and
shit I had never feels such a really
well beingness bujji release but like
it's like a it's like a curtain that
that comes early sorry Daniel your body
and it's well beingness and you have a
birth but it's a birth of
feeling so good in your body magically
it's not the birds per se but is like on
the budgets gotta let me see well is it
is your cannabinoid system your
endocannabinoid system that the CBD
somehow comes in and like dances with
and it's just that Western science
always wants the isolate it says this
there's only this and there's only that
and you know it's not it's about
everything that's in there at the point
it's fascinating because like before we
were just making us like in in yeah you
just make ash and you don't really know
what's inside then I learned what was at
icon and I learned what actually was the
cannabinoid and how they transform into
each other so now as an ash maker I have
the ability to put a pure CBD ash on the
market because I can transform the THC
in CBN I can manipulate I can manipulate
Canobie know it because I know them and
because there is so much diversity in
the plant instead of having one type of
ash now I have ithc ash and everything
from one on one to fifty to one CBD all
those ashes like it's it's a new
territory for us maker it's like it's
very trippy what what microscope you saw
the trichomes the first time that was
like no seriously this is a revelation
even on hash you see the right the
moment that I did you you know Mila in
Amsterdam right so I'm in her shop right
and she knows me as a and all these
people from Manali and all that said so
I'm with Mila right and she and she says
here you don't know nothing about this
stuff it's not marijuana it's cannabis
she says right and then she says here
look at this and I was like wow
right you have these try cones and to
realize that
the stuff there because that Pollan yeah
yeah it's like and it's like oh can you
understand what you're doing if you
don't understand all the project when
for me all those years in in producing
country it was to make my own basically
so it was it was not a pastime it really
it was very very very special time
dedicated to my well-being as for the
year but it wasn't really serious it
becomes I use when I came here and it
became a craft well there is a project
and the children there is no singers so
I knew the tool a lot but I was totally
ignorant on the project I was actually
walking with it it's like I became
better because I know the project I'm
working with and so now instead of
playing around with a project I have no
idea what it is and tools that are
adapted to a certain level but it's very
local know I could create my own tool
because I'm I know more in depth what
I'm actually working with it's like a
metal were blacksmiths if you give any
blacksmiths titanium to walk and he
doesn't know the property of the new
metal is going to do stuff but he's not
going to he's not going to be able to do
whatever he can do if he knew really old
took place where everybody works with
that metal and then and that's what you
did that's what I did we came here to do
if you ask a local why why do you cure
your flower for three to nine months in
that home the guys make it make good
regime why do you press your resin
because it made good Ashish and every
time it's like that is like they know it
for a fact they invented the game but
they cannot tell you why
everything everything they do there is
something behind
so long worth we're not we're not
getting there we're getting there in
mindo and humble of having enough time
and so on but to really dial it we got
another hundred years here at least of
growing in the finest place because you
have science on your is like imagine a
farmer that can have the ability and the
finance to analyze is sold before a plot
yeah and every month during the world
season not only the salt but the plant
so that you know exactly what the plant
is taking from your soil and you knew
before if it's gonna miss something and
for when you see you know I think you've
really dialed in your soil and so on and
you soil it's become like the edge of
the plant but it's like with a science
you can define why your plant is what
your front is gonna miss because she's
taking a lot of it
you know what I mean it's like it's
fucking huge you can you know when you
first realize that the plant needs all
these minerals right it needs not only
minerals so but it needs all these
different microbes that needs bacteria
and fungi and how do you feed that right
and so you start experimenting with
compost teas and those compost teas
become locally sourced right so the
compost tea you're putting on is from
your compost that you have right and
your worm bin that you have and now so
now the ingredients that are purely
local that you put in do you know
exactly what your compost tea do to your
so no because you need to analyze your
sir you need to use a microscope to look
at well you look at the compost tea with
the microscope before you put yeah no
for sure yeah well first of all I
started doing mineral testing you know
and that's the Nano NPK and all of that
and then you realize wow there's 14
things did you know your plant needs
molybdenum does anybody know what
molybdenum is right and so it needs man
and magnesium and copper and sulfur and
all these sort of things those are all
heavy metals right and normally in
regular commercial agriculture they
delivered as a salt right and so they're
more easily absorbed in the water when
you water it in but now if you want to
do regenerative soil then you don't use
those things you make those ingredients
with your compost tea which is like a
little bit of stay comfrey in there not
come free but alfalfa you might put in
there and you put in some some worm
castings and you put in some compost and
a few other things and alfalfa alfalfa
is like 4 to 1 like that alfalfa it's
got a fair amount of nitrogen all right
and a lot of things what people do with
that because those are more minerals
right then you get what is volcanic ash
azomite something like that which is has
trace minerals and some weeds are
something that thrives in that
environment right and if you can tune
into what it's got they smell something
like hope your G's that tell you that
you don't need to give anything actually
to your plowed everything is in your
soil but you don't have the microbial
life to break it down yeah like Ellen
she's called you all at the living soil
in ambled she's called all the thumb and
only only elk and you can do it because
she's her style and she the worksheet
that we are fucking up your your so
babysitting Zeus plant or your so
pushing what you give to Zeus blown that
it almost ridiculous to a certain level
when she show you table of everything
that is available for you right there
and you just need to put my clog to
break it down so that your you I mean
look at the things that are going
you know everyone's like you love it
actually I have to go and set up
something so adaptogen et tu to the
condition of the place where they live
but for example not putting back the
prolongs matter where the next
generation is going to go like it's done
in Nigeria I think that's a big mistake
not leaving the greater seeds in the
soil during winter I think it's a big
mistake here you have such a devious
city and the planter adapted but they
are still not local local because you
don't give them the chance to become
really heirloom to spend the winter to
to go through the world sidecar real
cycle of a plant life and then you're
gonna create heirloom genetics that
gonna become no no because you have that
first tier of flower that is born and
the ability to get credit for the
biomass that just doesn't go to the
flower market and that biomass it's the
credit of doesn't matter if it could
become a bloody chocolate of a pain bowl
of for me anybody me and you three need
the farmer to strive so that we can get
the stuff we need okay very simple
community that is hiding well the rest
of the rest of the youngest
not going to be nice taping the future
the civilization is built on thriving
agriculture you know the way we have it
and our cultivation artists cannabis
civilization is built on thriving
farmers and you know we came here we
came here in order to you know learn
from each other and a situation which we
had an isolation here so nobody was
bothering us and our seeds came in from
all over the world and people came in
from all over the world and the progress
that has been made in genetics now and I
do have to say we all a lot to the
indoor growers to who really figured out
a lot of the science they had to figure
if there's nothing in that they got they
had to figure out what is this plant
need and so we know how that data and it
turns out to be just about what every
other plant really needs but you can
dial is specific for cannabis but what
we really the whole basis of our
conversation is really about the place
where you grow it and that place about
the product from that place and I
remember your telling me in the past
that every plant that we see on the
planet originated in one particular
place which is its terroir its original
home but now through our interaction
with with plants as humans especially
this cannabis when it's at home in many
many places and so but we're trying to
make it more at home we want to make it
more an expression of every place that
it really is and so that we're now
working on this appellations project to
try and it's very controversial and a
lot of details about it but the idea is
to create areas of recognition that this
is a traditional cannabis area around
the world making fun of me five yeah I
was talking about it 10 years ago but
nobody know what the word meant you know
but when you think about an appellation
for some part of Afghanistan or from
from Manali where you think they will
have protection as the guarantee of this
again what you don't get swingy is like
you cannot use the world abolition the
regime if you don't follow the
of abolition division yes protected
pagination oh that's what we want to do
we want to be those quality standards
who have to choice all you follow to the
later the stone division and the wine
industry didn't do it because they
didn't have an induced fit they didn't
other wines they needed to create those
great wines that you have today you you
have so much greatness that zhuzh
limitation are not the problem at all is
going to it's going to help you define
everything you have but working with the
sale at the moment which has a legal
requirement to create standards for
appellation no no no because zoos
American Standa are not a pollution
division stoned out it's amazing but
because you have to choice oh you do so
a tradition division or you create your
own standards but so all you have some
things that is valid world wild and it
would be a breakthrough for agriculture
in general in America all you need to
create something that is as valid as
that so you can be sure that the rest of
the world is going to follow the
standard of quality you have zoos to
choice but you cannot use the word
appellation the region you're gonna be
sued guys it's like Mendocino they
cannot use that world you have or you
play that game but you don't want to
play it so you you are right now you
need to choose or you create your or
your one it is a great pass don't get me
wrong or you follow the path of what
every country in the world when they use
the word appellation division is because
they have followed to the letter
every stone the every limitations that
give you that ability to not only create
that level of quality but you cannot
birth improve that level of quality you
don't want that you kill you need to
create your own that can be as hope
hasn't achieve as
what the French did for the wine
basically it would be only for cannabis
in that case you would create your own
like the wine industry did their own and
they did a great job even if he doesn't
have the the potential protection of
international protected
name it still very valid worldwide so
you have to do something you hate your
own you need to create something so
fucking valid so that anybody that
legalized is gonna want to follow that
because it's it no there's already
someone in Florida who once used the
word humble right and so Jimmy's fucking
losers using Empire than you ever see a
Mahad square