uh my name is uh daniel morford and
we're at hart rock mountain farm
um this is where i grew up this is where
i was actually born
and we're just gonna be doing some
filming this season to kind of introduce
you to different stages of the farm
we're working with future cannabis
projects and pride of the lion seeds
and
it's beginning april now and the cover
crop is blooming and our nursery is
going along and we're just going to do a
little walk through
of our farm
and we're going to start over here
with some nice hugo cultures
so right behind me we have
hidden somewhere in the mustard and
radish
280 feet of huge cultures
when we buried logs two foot deep and
three foot trenches and piled up
logs and branches five feet high and
covering them with soil
so these are three years old this year
and
it's an exciting year because year three
you get a nice terpene spike
i mean since we've gone no till like
everything's been increasing in
uh
terpenes every year and i guess that you
know goes along like since we got our
dragonfly earth medicine certification
the same strains every year have been
going up you know most of our stuff
testing around three percent terpenes
i'm excited for for this uh to
to see if those trends keep keep
climbing
we have like artichokes we have comfrey
we have a
variety of cover crop
you can see some fava beans here which a
nitrogen fixer
um
and we're just gonna find a little place
here and take a peek
i mean it's been so dry it's hardly
raining
too much
past couple months
yeah
soil's so dry
it's amazing the mustard's
kind of carried on here
but it will be
chopping and dropping and composting
right after to fix as much of this
nutrients as possible you can see the
honeybees are really going for this
we have some nice poppies coming up in
the road
and we'll go up plum tree
we got some little rosemary bushes
planted in front of here
on this side of our farm here we call um
plum tree path
this gets like the late season sun so
this is where we'll probably be growing
the uh original haze this year it's
where we grow like the swazi gold
i think we might be growing some of the
healer one to one from dragonfly earth
medicine
and
and this is our big field here these
plants are on
15 foot centers and you can see the
stalks of the sunflowers from last year
and those are kind of marking our
our flower belts
that we will
uh
be seeding with flowers and veggies
and this is where we'll grow the big
girls
here's one of the potatoes we planted a
few weeks ago
we uh we seeded the whole farm this year
with
potatoes so
in the next couple years we'll have
hundreds of pounds of potatoes in the
bank i mean if there's a rodent they'll
go for a potato over cannabis roots or
stocks
[Music]
but it's just the easy
companion
plant and in this climate when you
harvest the potatoes you can just
scatter them right there in the fall you
don't have to wait till after the winter
because it doesn't get cold enough to
this is a uh
uh
yellow dock
this is good it brings up uh
high-end trace minerals
it's native here
this is holly hawk behind it which is a
good pollinator friendly plant like
beneficials native pollinators and
honeybees like the hollyhocks
i always like to see you know
what
flowers are attracting what pollinators
and you know trying to grow a diversity
of flowers and stuff that'll
that bloom more or less year round and
and seeing what's going on
but yeah my dad bought this place in
or 77 something like that
it's almost hard to see the shape of the
farm with how high the cover crop is but
you know this road we plant all the
wraps away all the all the way around
these are terraces here that we built
which was really fun we had a log deck
up there and just cut and rolled logs
down a couple of us and got them in
place
definitely have some videos of some of
that
here's another set of terraces and these
are probably some of the smaller spacing
on the farm i think these are like six
foot spacing
most things 10 to 12 foot spacing just
to give us the room for airflow
for the polyculture potential around it
and then here we got the the two
sentinel doug fir trees watching over
the farm
and this is sunset garden
and this is this is more of a of a
spiral garden
you know starting here on kuan yin the
it does like two spirals of cannabis
planting and it's got a lot of diversity
that's hidden under this cover crop
we have some
some grapes a lot of different varieties
of flowers and yarrows and
uh we have some young guava trees
which
oh and here's a nice pollinator
you see these blue flowers that are
opening up here
it's uh although there's like eight
plants called this is what nicknamed
bee's friend i forget this actual name
um
and they're
a wildflower that we sewed that just
keeps coming back which is nice
it's a nice little patch of them
i see some beneficial insects i see
over hover flies
honeybees there's at least
three different types of pollinators on
these right now
now we are crossing the threshold
of the
expansion that i've done to the original
heart rock orchard founded or as my dad
calls it the homestead orchard
so my dad planted that jonathan tree
and those two fig trees
and the road used to come up through
here where the apple tree is i've
planted the the younger fruit trees are
mostly planted by me
and
here under the cover crop there's about
40 plots
and i think we'll be doing the um
autoflower hybrid seed production here
if we're successful we'll be making
120 new flavors of autoflowers
yeah this this yellow delicious also has
all kinds of
there's some beetles on it there's a
couple types of winged insects honeybees
that literally looks nice there's a
bumblebee too
and then we have a celestial fig tree
over here
and actually some of my older brothers
ashes are buried under that celestial
fig tree
yeah and then wild elderberry here
behind us
an apple tree behind that
more apple trees and
and of course this is not as open as it
was when like my father was farming here
like here where these fruit trees are
and the raspberries and the apple trees
was all kind of coyote brush with a
little bit of raspberries and up where
those nursery hoops are it's more
that was also kind of brushed and thinly
open space
i think the
before we converted this upper part of
it to uh nursery i think the original
homestead garden
you know could affect like
75 well
spaced big plants
here's our main propagation hoop
and this is just the style that we do we
start in four inch pots
[Music]
these over here will get up potted into
one gallons
we have begun the phase to up pot from
one gallons into five gallons five
gallons into the ground
here's those uh original haze look at
the various thin leaves on those
and at our elevation here
we are in a slight banana belt for the
region you know if you go up 500 feet or
down 500 feet you have to deal with like
earlier frosts in the fall later frost
in the spring
you know we should be able to pull those
november hazes in no problem
then we've got a hoop house full of one
gallons to go up
and then you know now we can do a little
loop oh yeah we can shut then we got the
ones getting into five gallons
i just want to point out that that
where that apple tree is behind me is
approximately where my mom's water broke
and i was born just
up there in the old cabin site
and this slope is going to be fun to
watch
unfold this year we've grown autoflowers
here in the past but we've we've decided
that
this is just going to be a pollinator
garden
so
you know every two foot on this hillside
behind me are plots that are been sewed
with
flower seeds and they are starting to
come up
so that's going to be fun to watch
this unfold
this little section here we called you
know middle earth i originally put in
this flat to build a barn
but um
we added it into the square footage
and we're gonna put a barn in a shady
spot
here we have some parsnips growing from
uh golden figs gardens and cobalt gave
us the seeds we've got a few of them
scattered throughout the farm
that's another really easy plant to
propagate that's like
just a good food bank to like bank the
farm it's actually one of the more tasty
root vegetables like baked or fried
parsnips are amazing
and then the road down below us here
with
uh
we have
i think 13 or 14 varieties of apple
trees that we will grow ganja where the
mustard is
and we have our autoflower soap slopes
that are being prepped to be planted
and you can get a shot there
of the auto slope
and then
that road wraps around to the front
where we started
yeah we'll start making some pathways
here before the snakes come out
hopefully
and then here we are back there's the
hugelkultur's is the main field
and then we have another garden down
below the house so we start at like 2
300 feet and go all the way up to like 2
400 feet a high garden up there is a uh
there's a nursery pattern and
we'll be filming up there later when
there's
something to see it's just mustard right
now
and that's one of the best things about
this office space it's just
the sound of the wind in the trees
well thanks for joining me today on a
little farm tour and i look forward to
showing you guys the season as it
progresses
yeah so um
future cannabis project is carrying our
genetics
planters of the trees is carrying our
genetics pacific north roots
is carrying our genetics
seed cellar
and
i think that's all the ones that are
listed
and then you follow us heart rock
mountain farm on instagram pride of
lighting seeds on instagram or send us
an email
either one of those at gmail
and yeah heart rock mountain farm
when you cultivate love
love grows
and where love grows
so does everything else
[Music]