I think this is a good segue into the
next topic which would be the
environmental component of him you know
we hear a lot towards the twenty five
thousand different uses and I think
however many it is that one of the
things that stands out is that hemp
seems to perform nearly better than any
other option and so that's that's where
some of its usefulness and utility I
think really comes in so in terms of the
environmental aspect we know that it has
great benefits to soil and air quality
and putting carbon back in the earth at
the farming component but also let's
talk a little bit about you know
limiting waste and reusable products
that can come from him and most
importantly I think the environmental
aspect that inspired you to do your
certain businesses today on the farming
aspect of it right now anything that you
find that's you know cannabis or hand it
basically you need to farm it
organically because there's thankfully
nothing no pesticide labeled for
cannabis so in a way I feel that's going
to help move the industry forward into a
norm of farming organically instead of
staying with conventional practices you
know just as far as like the soil
remediation and the you know the
biodegradability the fact that you can
grow you know two to three crops of hemp
a year instead you know who talked about
paper you know takes how many years to
grow an acre of trees and you can have
you know at least two crops of hemp in
this in the same year for you know less
water no pesticides and it's it's just
again there's so much that I could say
but I'll go ahead and yeah it's kind of
a wonder crop in that regard
so I think that the everything that been
said is true and at the same time I
think that it's really important to
recognize that the forces that are
driving not only the in the legalization
of industrial hemp but the growth of the
market are not necessarily you know the
small companies that are here it's it's
big AG the only reason why Mitch
McConnell got on board after decades of
opposing the legalization of industrial
hemp is because his buddies the Kentucky
tobacco farmers were losing money in the
tobacco in in the tobacco world they hit
with a couple of bad years and you know
they figured they'd cut their cut their
losses and invest in an up-and-coming
crop and once they got their
infrastructure together and you know and
was they were able to sort of slow
everything down through the earlier farm
bill and do the research and and make
sure that it was gonna work then they
were saying okay we're now we're ready
and so McConnell let it go through and
pass and and garnered the bipartisan
support which you know had it had had
this happened earlier anyway I don't
want to speculate but the point is that
I went to some of those test fields in
Kentucky and I saw the research that was
happening and a lot it's a lot of the
research has to do with pesticides it's
like well we in this little test patch
we use this pesticide and in this bed
we use this but we're trying to figure
out which pesticide is right for which
so there there is even though you know
the the kind of theory is that hemp
grows so densely that we don't need
pesticides the reality is that Monsanto
is tied in with big tobacco and they've
got their supply chains in their
relationships and everything and they're
gonna figure out a way to justify you
know more pesticides for him that's just
that simple and I think and and not not
just the pesticide part of it but the
the the big AG agricultural practices as
opposed to regenerative regenerative
farming
practices which can not only obviate the
need for pesticides but can actually
contribute to the positive environmental
impacts that we want to see particularly
with respect to global warming so in a
way I think what's unique the unique
opportunity here is that the hemp
consumer is pretty much different than
the tobacco consumer and so the
opportunity is that the hemp consumer
can drive the development of the
industry and therefore affect the
overall environmental impact that we
have and and so there there's it's both
going to come from the top down to some
degree there as long as there are
companies like you know John relax you
know riri botanicals who are gonna get
into every single Whole Foods and
whatever around but they'll still only
be one option there's also going to be
that you know drug CBD company which do
you know the one of Jeannette right and
I mean you look at they'd sent me some
samples at the store and there were
these little fluorescent colored pills
and I'm like wait what are these this is
CBD this is like the new face of CB what
is this company and I was just like no
thank you
in into the trash so so and I'm a
consumer and I but I'm not just a soar
owner I'm a consumer so I made that
decision and I made that decision for me
and for my the people who come to my
store so anyway so that's that's kind of
the opportunity is where we can
influence how this industry develops and
therefore amen and I as far as you know
I'm thinking too with you know paper
I've been in the magazine industry I how
about you know I look forward to the day
when hemp is grown plentifully enough
and the prices drop enough because we
it's very expensive that's why you know
even a lot of people don't have their
business cards printed on hemp paper
because it's it's prohibitive but how
about how about good job
and you know how about the day when you
can pick up a magazine and it's made of
hemp paper instead of you know what an
end it an acre of hemp gives you four
four times as much usable you know
usable content as as an acre of trees so
which probably why it was legalized in
the first place I just want to touch on
a few quick things on the paper side you
know there's there's a few people in the
country making hemp paper on a small
scale one I would want to point out is
Greenfield paper company down in San
Diego they have I think the most
consistent hemp paper on the market
right now that's made domestically but
the pulp that they're using I want to
say is from Spain just because there's
not a consistent enough domestic source
of heaven pulp for them to be using and
then quickly to other things you know
we're talking about big AG earlier you
know cotton accounts for I think twenty
five percent of all you know pesticides
used globally so provides a great
alternative there and then for us
specifically we're always comparing it
to corn because that's what most bio
plastics are made out of and it uses
about a third of the water as corn and
grows in a little more than half the
time I think that that topics really
timely - I just got back from the world
Ag Expo and and you can see that there's
a lot of people still using heavy
machinery
you know just ripping up the earth
rippers and tillers and everything and
the small percentage of the market is
focused on you know organics and
regenerative farming practices and so
it's not just an in hemp but it's also
in the big AG and then that that's kind
of a timely conversation as well because
you have labeling and organizations like
US hemp Authority that they're trying to
put some some self regulations on
labeling and identifying the product and
some of the dialogue within the industry
is about well sourcing you know
are we gonna have to actually identify
where the products coming from because
currently their suggestions are not to
include a country of origin is that is
the CBD actually derived from hemp
because there are people considering you
know deriving CBD from from yeast and
doing it in a GMO fashion so these these
things that are like front and center
considerations not only for the hemp
industry but for AG in general and for
the canvas industry so you know it's
right there it's kind of big industry
versus regenerative and smaller scale
practices I think the biggest thing is
education people need to be educated
that they can farm in a different
practice and they can make the right
decision based upon you know how they
want the world to continue and I think
California could be in one of the four
fronts of that just because everybody
here is very organically minded and you
know closed-loop farming and such but I
think education is the best place to
start and I know with this hemp CBD
versus the versus the cannabis CBD
that's one of the big education points
right now because people don't
understand what the differences are
because it's all kind of been
oh it's CBD is CBD and now there's a lot
of companies going out there and going
out and making the differences of no
there's hemp CBD there's cannabis EVD
these are the benefits this is what they
can bring you so I think education yeah
and education you know again from the
media standpoint and I can see even even
from a few years ago just that you know
people are very slowly it's two steps
forward one step back but you know
they're coming around to being more
approachable I guess I would say with
you know with being open to even
receiving education you know and to you
know non cannabis companies you know
advertising on cannabis platforms saying
you know know that you're not going to
get like Blackwall for this or something
here
well I mean and also
the converse is true I I can't even
believe my eyes still when I see some of
these med men billboards all over town
I'm like oh my gosh there's a giant
billboard in the sky and it says
cannabis am I in some kind of like
alternative reality here because this is
not what I thought the world would be
like when I was you know 15 years old
and I was paranoid all the time so
there's that and then there's the idea
that the the hemp consumer and the
cannabis consumer is the cannabis
consumers coming out of the closet and
the hemp consumer is discovering that
they are that they that they actually
that there's their products out there
that are more effective and better and
better for the planet and line with
their values and so just today I was at
my shop in the morning and these two
older women came by and walking their
dogs and they're like oh look we can get
CBD here I was like wow this is just you
know like one step away from my mom
wanting to take CBD which I'm still
working on her but she loves the hemp
clothing so so I think that that's it's
it's it's education it's hemp dication
and it's also just the mainstreaming of
what was once a vital crop for this
country so it's kind of a rediscovering
of our own history it's it's reclaiming
our plant inheritance you know it's so
weird that that a plant was basically a
plant that was grown in every state and
and all over the world was sort of
erased and you know band and demonized
and taken away from its from the
ecosystems it's terrible but now it's
back then coming back stronger and
stronger
I'd love to add one more thing just on
the topic of education you know it can
be sometimes confusing to look at
industries within their silos but you
know taking a more macro look at the
whole world in the global economy some
of the macro shifts that are happening
and that need to happen are shifting
towards what we would call circular
economy versus a linear economy which is
take make dispose which is how we've
been operating for you know pretty much
you for all the industrial era and
modern era and you know really I think a
lot of what the hemp industry is
perfectly suited for is is furthering
our path towards a circular economy
where we're designing things for
recovery whether it's clothing whether
it's packaging whether it's the products
we put in our body it's doing things for
generatively and and I would encourage
you all to look up the Ellen MacArthur
Foundation and just find out more about
what a circular economy means and then I
think it will make it easier to
understand how hemp and other things
that are happening globally right now
fit into that larger story and that
larger change that needs to be happening
yeah I think I think we're all right
there with you James and it's kind of an
ironic and circular movement itself that
you know this plant that has a 10 to 12
thousand year history with human some
some people theorize that we actually
have a co-evolutionary process with
cannabis like Michael Pollan
and now it's coming back into the
mainstream it's pulling all of these
resources it's giving us resources to to
heal the planet and change our ways and
alternatives to fossil fuels and things
that we've been just doing kind of
blindly and unconsciously so it's an
element of like how do we bring the
educational aspect into our branding how
do we how do we focus products to a
marketplace that is about you know
regenerative practices
natural products and really like
responsible consumerism so maybe talk to
like some of your favorite products on
the market or how you do it within your
brand to like represent those sort of
business ethics to just kind of as part
of that Segway to I like to say I think
that probably the one of the one of the
best things that we can do as people in
the industry is to be authentic about
who you are what you do because I it was
a real eye-opener I started going to
some very professional networking groups
a couple years ago and it was just it
was so funny cuz you know people you
know tell them what you do and about
half the people were like oh cool the
other half were like you know but I
swear of that other of that other 50%
probably 90% of them would come back
around and go well actually you know so
it's just when we when we give ourselves
permission to be authentic it's it's it
has an exponential effect it gives other
people permission to be authentic you
know and that's how change happens so
that's my take on that I think the way
that I in in the vital hemp gets the
word out and sort of markets the the
vitality of this crop is by connecting
it to everyday activities so last year I
don't know at a party I must have said
something which was like it everything's
better in hemp and and then I was like
better in him that's a slogan and so I
came up with a whole marketing kind of
campaign where it was like pictures with
just better in it and it's like you know
Yoga is better in hemp you know men are
better in him New York is better in him
meditation is better in Hampton and so
it's like a wide range of people in
places and things
are better in hemp and if you really
think about it it's true so it's kind of
an arguable thing and if you experience
it so I think the it's so interesting to
me that ten years ago or so there was
maybe one company that I knew knew of
making hemp shampoo and now there must
be 30 at least maybe more maybe 50 I
just read that Barney's is now going to
include CBD cosmetic products and their
storyline yeah there you go yeah they're
opening up a whole little CBD store with
one brand that I can't remember the name
of the brand now which is terrible but
Bebo there we go they're opening that up
in the Beverly Hills Barneys which is
just incredible
I mean that just shows how far things
have come hopefully it's not just like a
fad though available for elite consumers
then right and widespread because the
efficacy is so good for everyone in
different walks of life well then I
think that's what the studies are
showing just even even anecdotal studies
are showing that people who are using
CBD are leaving pharmaceuticals they're
they're you know talk about a cure for
the you know oxycontin crisis this is a
good one I educational marketing that's
all I have to say how'd it go about it I
mean there's so much education that you
have to do with your consumers anyways
in the hemp industry that you should
always just be leading with education
looking towards the future I mean the
last couple of years have been bright
and I don't think they're you know even
what we had in mind so the future of
cannabis and specifically hemp and hemp
in California and even yourselves in
your own ventures if you want to kind of
spiel off that and and we can kind of
close out with some thoughts
I I really hope that we're able to
continue building the the cannabis side
and the hemp side the industries that
you know are the ones that we've been
building towards I hope we're not to
detract by you know big cannabis and big
hem obviously there's a place for that
but I I just you know looking towards
the future I a I hope the infrastructure
comes but with the infrastructure I hope
we're able to hold on to the integrity I
just feel with it being such an amazing
plant that we just need to stay true to
the plant and basically give to it what
it has given to us i I would say one of
my biggest focuses with moving ahead is
to include I hate to use the word
minority but to include populations that
have been kind of left out and have been
marginalized and including obviously
Native Americans and you know because
they're they actually can't federally
grow well marijuana that that side of
the cannabis industry but of course
we're focused on hemp here well they can
but they have to give up their
sovereignty
so with hemp it's it's another story
thankfully and I just want to give a
shout out to Evo hemp they are working
with out with Alex white plume from the
Pine Ridge Reservation and they're in
3,000 locations now and they expect 25%
of their revenue to come from the hemp
from Alex white plume and from white
plume hemp and again I got the chance to
visit that reservation several years ago
and 90% of that reservation lives
beneath the poverty line and there's
literally the middle of you know the
middle of nowhere there's there's the
people aren't not working because they
don't want to they're working
because there's no place to work it's
actually the the poorest County in the
United States yes and you know let's um
you know do what we can to get behind
the the rights of you know these people
who were placed where they are and let's
give them a it was a sustainable
industry well I think that the future of
hemp kind of relates to some things that
were talked about on the last panel
where I heard some guys saying you know
the these these these investors they
come in and they're so excited about
this new industry and he says dude I've
been growing for 20 years or this is not
a new industry and you know in the same
way hemp is there have been people in
this industry a lot longer than me and
I've been doing it 16 years and and
they're a lot of and I'd say a lot of
the people who've been doing it when it
wasn't necessarily the newest hottest
thing that's gonna be in every you know
supermarket those people were in it
because of you know a kind of a love and
a respect for the plant and what it
could do for life on Earth in addition
to wanting to make a living and seeing a
future that we you know we wanted to
manifest so the the challenge is that
some of these people who've been in it
the longest with the best practices and
the best values are getting marginalized
both in cannabis and in him and it's not
some malicious thing necessarily
it's just giant market forces moving in
because they see opportunity they've
managed the legislative landscape to
favor them and they're going to
capitalize on it and so then the
question becomes our hoo-hoos again how
do we somehow effectively educate the
consumer not just to love hemp but to
love certain
humph it has a certain kind of the
supply chain in the same way
that's that consumers now want organic
produce right even at their Walmart they
want organic produce and so you know if
we can can create that kind of an ethic
for our industry both from the consumer
to the highest you know to the biggest
producer which I don't think it's going
to happen easily the only the big boys
only come along when they realize the
little guys are taking away their market
share right because they're so that's
what that's what I think we need to do
is stand by our our best values continue
to educate the consumer with that there
are differences even within our industry
in terms of what's produced and and then
there by hopefully you know get to a
better place with all of this there's
been people in California doing good
work for decades so that the market
could develop and we could get here I
mean Jack Herer Emperor wears no clothes
Richard Davis in the world cannabis
foundation and and John Trudell with
Hempstead project Hart who the namana me
tribe has actually taken over that
operation so there's a lot of nonprofits
and groups along with the future
cannabis project that are helping us to
get the word out as an industry so
appreciate all that so I think we can
shift into Q&amp;A now I'm tethered here
with my microphone but if you want to
join me upfront my question is do you
think it would be prudent to have a
moratorium on production in areas that
are already well known for their
cannabis cultivation outdoors can't
where can they coexist I believe that
they can coexist but it needs to be very
well planned out on how they
exist as long as the hemp farmer is
staying with feminized seeds and the
distance is you know five miles away
from the most of all the cannabis like
when I'm out in Santa Barbara County all
the cannabis has grown in greenhouses so
it's not open fields so if the seeds are
feminized and the distance is set I
think the county would be able to
regulate that and everybody could be
happy yeah that's something at the CDF a
level that's likely like really a topic
that that comes down even to the local
level too so it is the county and I
commissioners the county boards of
Supervisors that are addressing that we
have the opportunity in California that
we actually have 58 counties where is
the county AG commissioner that kind of
sets the rule so there are already
counties that have at least temporary
moratoriums on on hemp pollen or hemp
production Riverside County tell me what
else Santa Barbara County San Bernardino
County so first and foremost if you do
want to cultivate him San Joaquin see
there's they're popping up every day
check with your check with your County
ant commissioner all right that's a wrap
thanks everybody thank you
you
[Music]