[Music]
we have eight separate licenses so the
story of our license we got it back in
2009 um my father purchased it my name
is Adam iary I'm the owner of herbarium
and the way we got our license was back
in 2009 we purchased a pre ICO from one
of our partners who's actually still
with us today and we didn't use the
license until about 2017 when cannabis
first became legal we went through some
legal battles but in the end we won and
herbarium was born when you say legal
battles like yeah the cannabis industry
has always been very messy yeah you know
people claiming that they owned a pre
ICO when they did in people claiming
that they had licenses that they never
had yeah so it's not using ours for a
long time some people thought that they
could use it because it was I said you
know basically Idol there was a lot of
trafficking in licensing yeah yeah I
actually I'm sure there's a ton of
lawsuits going on right now over these
licenses because they're worth so much
more money now and you know a lot of
people that were the pioneers of this
industry they weren't familiar with you
know legal legal rights or the laws or
how to conduct a proper business so all
they did was basically open up these pre
icos and try to run a dispensary and
that's as far as they understood
so these lawsuits are just like in
addition to the lawsuits like against
past
being of the city lawsuit very likely
I'm not familiar with Pasadena but I'm
sure they are I mean I know the city of
Los Angeles yeah same thing is Los
Angeles they were sued by tons of
dispensaries back in 2017 so there's
like a line with people suing them two
three opening is three a third one
opening soon really yeah we're going to
our grow room right and it's locked
no no it's not too
and everything here is on rollers as you
can see sometimes there's issues with a
grow room and you know we go through
them and fix it right now we have we're
using kavita lights we which we just
installed we're on rollers now over here
we're growing
candy-apple cush runs sunset sherbert
grease monkey is back there and we have
a about another month and a half before
harvest they're going at the same time
but we pull once every three months
about a week and a half and then we it
takes about a couple days for trimming
couple days for packaging a couple days
for testing and these go out under your
your your plan yes our brand is called
elevate that's our cannabis line so we
our storefront is called herbarium our
slogan is to educate advocate and
elevate and our cannabis products are
called elevate
right you gotta be light what sort of
issues have you had have you had any
past issues that you're no pest issues
but as you can see this AC broke so
that's getting fixed this
yeah it's this quest dual purifier is
down right now so that needs to be fixed
that's about it
and then now is will you be expand if
this your two here we're actually going
to rebuild this place about really yeah
and turn it into a museum Oh like a
willy wonka factory are you serious yeah
so what we're walking through right now
will actually be much wider
yeah and we're going to offer tours for
customers to be able to walk through
we're hoping to be ready by February
seven thousand square feet that's cash
and this is Amanda yeah this right here
is our where we distribute caviar gold
so caviar gold is one of our brands that
we distribute we're in over a hundred
dispensaries right now they're known as
the world's strongest pre-roll we're
staying at about sixty percent THC yes
sir do you know this is where we
distribute it from and then I'll take
you into where we manufacture
it's our manufacturing room nice high
three rollers breathing yeah hard at
work and you have room for a few more
people about necessarily when you get
business and this is where you train as
well we do not trim there okay actually
I think we do I'm not sure
well me on that they know we've kind of
remodeled these rooms recently it's
going to stay large it's actually going
to be larger off to the remodel and the
way the displays are going to look in
they're going to be much different it's
going to be very like it's going to feel
like you've stepped into a future Art
Show yes here yes no well technically
not here in a separate address but very
close by okay we are not so we still
have to wait for Los Angeles to release
consumption lounges yeah oh yeah
I don't want to be in West Hollywood
okay I prefer to be nulling really okay
what's Hollywood I wouldn't be able to
do all this they're all you only have
retail licenses there which are for
retail and delivery licenses which are
either for recreational or medical well
no on-site grows in West Hollywood
yes yeah absolutely
45 well yes
across distribution many father you sit
here when I was 18 or 19 my father
bought this license under my name and we
didn't touch it 28 so 10 years 10 years
ago I was more focused on fashion I came
from a family that had fashion
businesses and at the time I had a
fashion website after as soon as
cannabis became legal we decided to you
know get back in it and we found out
that someone was using our licence so we
were in court for two years over it we
ended up winning
we found this location with 14 days left
for the deadline yeah this was us a
diamond in the Nova song it was called
herbarium it was it it was a dispensary
that did not have a license so they had
to shut down they were closed for about
a year and before they were dispensary
there was another dispensary it's always
been a dispensary that just kept opening
and closing because of licenses so yeah
so when we first got the store I was
thinking of names to give it and I
didn't know exactly what's what to call
it you know but I didn't want to call it
or bury him and one day while we're you
know just setting things up in the shop
a customer walks in and she's like is
this her barrier
you know I don't know if you guys are
open or not but I just wanted to say
that this place saved my life yeah she's
like I had you know stage 4 cancer and
the edibles I was taking by Korova they
saved my life so I hope you guys come
back I can't wait for you guys to come
back thank you for everything you've
done and I was like you know what this
is more than just a store you know I
thought when I first took over that it
was you know a store and we people would
come if you built it but I realized that
it already had a community you know it
already had a belief behind it that
people knew about and it helped so
everyone was yeah and that was your
relation I still sometimes save the word
patron but yes and as soon as we and
then I I was like you know what let me
do some research and then I just thought
of the name thought of the name and then
I one day I just fell in love with it I
was like you know what it's perfect it's
it's not a little bit hard to pronounce
it's a you know bold name it's a unique
name and no one uses then the definition
behind it is basically a Museum of dried
plants so I was like you know what it's
perfect it works yeah it was perfect and
then everything else came after that so
our other shop is in needles and it's
called herbarium 66 well actually now
that I think about it you've gone whole
hog with the herbarium
everything's branded or berry oh no you
don't pronounce the eighth right and
then say your barium yeah so talk to me
a little bit about like the like retail
right
and the competition and and what's that
like now in in cannabis retail it like
it's specific to Los Angeles right now
because that's where we are like what
are your challenges and you know we've
heard some people are also charging what
they call them a sliding do you know
there's all kinds of things going on
what are you saying what are you saying
so there there's a lot of different
thing channels to this but I would say I
don't believe that I have competition I
think that if you do what you believe in
and that's your Rao and that's your goal
either people love your brand or they
don't love your brand but if people
believe in what you believe in they will
come you know any dispenser you can go
and sell blue dream any dispensary can
go and sell a select cartridge right or
a any edible any any flower anyone can
sell it right but why would they come to
your dispensary to purchase it and
that's where I think is where a lot of
people fall off and a lot of and it's I
think it separates that the beginners
from the believers you know and when
that happens you don't you know if
someone still Shops at another store
good for you I'm happy for you
which brings me to my next thing another
challenge the next challenge is
consistency a lot of these brands and
companies lack consistency so it's a
challenge for all dispensaries to be
able to always have a consistent product
flight some sometimes there's drought
sometimes there's shortages sometimes
people will say they're delivering and
they never deliver some people don't
know how to do accounting so it's all
types of different issues that we're
slowly trying to maneuver through that
you know makes it difficult for yourself
to grow you know so I don't look at
other dispensaries
petition because if someone shops
they're good for them and maybe they
have a product that I don't have that
there they really need and that's the
issue with consistency when you want to
carry a product that you can't
necessarily have so yeah are we yes
that's what I look at it as definitely
getting better yes providing our service
is consistent hours our selection stays
consistent but to have a consistent flow
of a specific product is difficult you
know there will be people that say they
have which is an example blue dreams
right and then they sell out of their
blue dream and they don't have it for a
couple months
this is kiya this is another dog okay
this is a we have a lot of dogs so yeah
that that's one of them now in regards
to slotting fees the way slotting fees
are approached are taken the wrong way
by a lot of brands personally as someone
who also distributes I look at a
slotting fee as I should do it
if I'm a brand and I want to be in a
dispensary I should do it
there's an issue we have a hundred
thousand different brands in the market
but only 180 dispensaries right now
these brands are coming in and their
margins are insane they're charging
twenty five dollars for a full gram
cartridge for a dispensary to sell it to
their custom to our customer for almost
seventy five dollars out the door after
tax you know so their margin what
they're doing is charging a high margin
to a dispensary when the dispensary is
the niche not the distributor there's a
ton of distributors there's only a
hundred and eighty licensed stores right
now more opening but you know there's
there's less stores than there are
distributors right so to be able to put
to be able to price gouge to me as a
distributor is not okay and the way that
we look at it isn't as a shelving fee or
charging to be in the way we look at it
is twenty percent off so to us if you
want to be in our store I don't look at
herbarium as just a retail store I look
at it as a place where people come to
get educated and become culturally aware
of cannabis around them and you know
there's a spotlight on our store all
dispensaries you know come up to they
they look up to us we have employees
come from other dispensaries trying to
work here we have other bud tenders from
Hollywood hi great shopping here so we
have a standard and people come here for
a reason so to us we're looking when
when we have a brand come in we're
looking for the ability to offer our
customers a better deal you know we're
not looking for us to bend it to benefit
more than we are looking for our
customer so first of all you're also a
distributor so what do you distribute we
are close so how many Thompson they're
in over 120 stores right now across
California across California
so you distribute out of you hmm
how long have you been doing that for a
year
I mean so we've had a growing part of
your business yes we're actually looking
to expand it so we've been focusing on
do you think it's essential for a
retailer to survive
different avenues of development and
reading you absolutely you need to find
out what your key performance indicators
are and you need to strike them when
they're when it's hot could you know
absolutely at the end of the day if you
believe if you sell something that you
believe in and people believe with you
you can make it as I was saying you know
there's other stores that sell select
you know or connected but why would they
come here I don't pitch this stores a
place that distributes you know I don't
this is a retail store and face value
it's a retail store but to us and our
customer it's not noticed that you know
first of all it's the brand consistency
is tough in this industry there's anchor
brands that everyone happens right in
their shops there's a few of them maybe
doesn't happen you know maybe it does
maybe it doesn't have to go beyond that
they might have their own flower right
and their own strains you know so it's
sort of like silos and this is
fascinating to me because I'm constantly
interested and you know unlike everyone
else and what I find what I'm looking
for someone doesn't I will constantly
I'm the type of person I say
I love actually you so I'm always
interested in kind of counting it it's
not why not it's hard to get my lash it
might be but it sells
90% of the time Keith he fails to fail
its testicles testing I don't think so I
think they're just put profit margins
out there it's it's it's not that of a
requested product that we have I have I
have people that come in and ask for it
but it's not you know everyone has their
own thing I try to carry everything no I
mean it sucks I think there should be a
lot more research done you know if vapes
actually are dangerous they shouldn't be
in the market well yeah there's so much
to it that we don't know yeah I don't
know I don't know enough to speak about
it I just know that like vitamin E is
being is people are adding vitamin E in
it which is bad for your long I have not
had to deal with anything yet I know
that our bud tenders have oh but they
are very educated you know we won as
soon as it happened I know that there
was a letter that we gave to all of our
bartenders to know the products we sell
and what's in them damage control oh
yeah yeah so yeah I mean we Jackie a
know more come one second so this is
Jackie no Maura
with their there are man they're
actually one of my our longest jackie
has actually been here before I was
so she's also an OG a terrarium yeah
when she came in for an interview
III knew she came with the building and
I mean they can tell you a lot about the
vape issue that's going on this is boo
he's our CFO he's our mascot so are you
saying a smaller dosage smaller medical
setting boy right there
now we'll throw stuff in ten milligrams
right right right yeah but what about
your old time patients who had a high
tolerance who needed those thousand
milligram bars because that's what they
need it are they still around
well there's a loophole in the system
now teachers and go 2,000 milligrams
there's a lot of like companies creating
like sprays grating like liquids that
can get
why I am one of those patients who had
like five milligrams and I find myself
being satisfied with the 400 milligrams
so it depends on like edible of course
why you gotta do a little differently
Ryan but 400 milligrams usually gives me
a satisfying high so so you kind of
you've shifted your method of intake yes
yeah I definitely used as much like less
than I did in the past and you know is
also dabbing rice and trades and right
those are for the heavier people sure
sure man you just do one little tiny dab
yeah yeah well you guys carry like resin
and all that stuff and all the new stuff
- are you into that are you gonna
produce that stuff as well are you
producing concentrate no yeah yeah but
are you gonna add to your to this line
of products absolutely yeah we're gonna
build the full kitchen in here
I mean gummy bears and cookies and so
you're gonna have more SKUs oh yeah