you
[Music]
well here a grown foundation yes
how'd you start it when did it start
what's give me the fourth actually I
actually started giving free cannabis to
veterans in 2010 when I lived in Lake
Tahoe after cannabis saved my life and
then I really hero grown was born early
2014 so it's a charity that gathers
cannabis and gathers and and goodwill
for veterans and first responders that's
the absolutely and we have cultivators
that donate product to us we have CBD
manufacturers who donate product to us
also so and the throwers literally gift
you cannabis product whether it's flour
or oil or anything that's going to have
a therapeutic value for a veteran
absolutely and sometimes it even comes
through dispensaries you know where they
do in most states they can do that for a
penny you know and transfer it just
because satisfy the tax the taxman
so that's awesome so the vet but your
personal experiences with as a veteran
so and with issues that were caused by
your work sure so is that what caused
you to get into it now really what the
the genesis for hero grown was in 2013 I
was training my German Shepherd who was
a young pup at the time and I rented all
these young vets who were telling me
they were taking 20 or 25 different
prescription meds a day and that
cannabis was the only thing that ever
help them with PTSD pain depression
anxiety but if they wanted to buy their
kid a new backpack to start school next
week they couldn't afford to buy the
cannabis so one morning shortly after
that I woke up and decided that's just
outrageous the only reason they're
taking these pills that kill over 50
vets a day now is because they were free
how much how big of a problem is opiate
addiction with with that's it's
horrendous I mean it's a you know it's a
it's it's getting a little bit better in
terms of the prescribing of it but you
know is just pretty much just always a
standard answer not just not just
opiates but a wide variety of
pharmaceuticals and
it's widely understood now that cannabis
therapies are a way to an alternative
way to get off of opiates is that
perhaps you know I really believe that's
the case you know when I talked to
providers at the VA now you know the
providers at that level are much more
receptive to to having their patients
use cannabis you know the the
bureaucrats are the ones that are that
are holding it up because the
politicians of course you know pull the
strings there so you know that's what we
really have to get to you know the
driving force behind this simply's money
you know Big Pharma gives you know
millions adopt billions of dollars to
you know to politicians and then that
kind of trickles downhill when they're
appointing someone to be the head of the
VA hospital or whatever and so the
bureaucrats are still pretty stubborn
when it comes to cannabis so here a
growing foundation operates in how many
states what we operate nationally now we
you know only give away free cannabis in
states where it's legal to do that
obviously but we ship free CBD products
to veterans and first responders in all
50 states now about forty thousand forty
to sixty thousand dollars a month in CBD
products and we've given away over four
million dollars in in actual cannabis
products in the last five years that's
awesome so each state has different
regulations about cannabis and cannabis
products so how do you function I can
how would you function in Marylander how
would you function in New Jersey well in
it back east primarily the way we
function are through veterans who are
members of our organization and it's
kind of like an underground railroad
deal if you will you know and they take
care of other veterans they take you
know we facilitate with our contacts
donations and again it's not always a
you know licensed cultivator sometimes
it's a private grower or whatever we
test everything before we give it out
but in a lot of those eastern states
still you know we don't do public
giveaway events you know we have
veterans helping other veterans so
there's two ends of the pipe line you've
got logistics at the one end where you
have producers that are getting
different products into your hands to be
distributed to veterans in a particular
location and then the other end of the
funnel is your network
of veterans that are connected to the
neighborhood that they're in the
locality that they reside in and they're
bringing the relief to the relief that
you find people can also make cash
donations I'm sure at a website
absolutely yeah just at Hero grown org
orgy they can make donations and you
know that that helps a great deal
especially with with hero grow and
airdrop which is our national program
where we ship as I said free CBD
products to vets and first responders in
all 50 states it's very expensive so you
bring the first responders in New York
around the 9/11 attacks the this first
responder trauma was such a elevated
thing that people had an understanding
of you changed the name of the
foundation from grow for vets to hero
grown to include first responders can
you talk about that and what the impacts
been and sure well you know in addition
to being an Army veteran I also had a
background in law enforcement and it
wasn't the the shootings that we had in
Las Vegas
okay October of 2017 it wasn't really a
driving force I'd already decided that
we'd include include first responders
but that certainly accelerated you know
the process and consequently on January
1st night of 2018 we transitioned or
evolve from grow for vets USA to hero
grown and started helping first
responders we'd helped a lot of first
responders prior to that but we really
didn't make a big deal out of it or
publicize the fact that we were doing
that you know but I've been helping
first responders in Lake Tahoe since
2010 so when I lived there so you know
in a lot of a lot of jurisdictions now
for example you know one of the the
people the persons that we help in Lake
Tahoe is an EMT and you know the his
chief is fine with him using cannabis
you know but if he does uses cannabis
like the night before he tells his cheap
or his captain I mean and then he he
just doesn't drive the you know the rig
that day but other than that I mean you
they understand these guys get a lot of
injuries a lot of physical injuries but
again like you mentioned you know in New
York or shootings here in Vegas
you know I mean it's just but the trauma
those guys went through is horrendous
and it's not just the first responders I
mean the people that were you know
affected thousands of civilians
post-traumatic stress only 30 percent of
the people in the United States we have
post-traumatic stress for veterans so
you know you can have PTSD you know if
you've been involved in any traumatic
situation in your life really appreciate
what you do appreciate you sitting down
and talking to us today and support hero
grown foundation at hero ground org I
appreciate it and I really appreciate
Bovada as well you know bovid o is our
first long-term here or longest sponsor
you know going back you know pretty much
to the beginning you know we couldn't do
what we do without your help and I
appreciate you certainly and the whole
Bovada team so well we appreciate you
thanks Roger
I mean this is this is a this is a
conversation about where you get into
the gray area on all the legalities and
all of the logistics of picking up
product I mean you told me a story about
being in Colorado and and being able to
drive up to a dispensary and have them
give you a significant amount of product
certainly so are you it are you at risk
I mean how should a politician feel if
they're watching this clip about hero
grown and trying to understand all the
good that you're doing for veterans and
what are some of the hassles that you
run into or some of the the liability
that you could face because of these
restrictions in different territories
well we've been very fortunate we've
never had any incidents with law
enforcement you know knock on wood it
helps that your former launch well I
don't I don't know that that's I think
it helps for example in Colorado where
we were well established where law
enforcement knew what we were doing they
knew who we were they knew we weren't
taking you know product and Nebraska
where I grew up or Kansas or something
like that doing you know trafficking
Canada exactly yeah exactly so you know
I think that you know and in the the in
Colorado the process or the it's been
legal for so long now
that for five years that you know
they're pretty much you know it's just
more open for example that it is in
Nevada where I live now
you know in Nevada you know all of the
owners the licensees are very very
concerned about losing their license if
they you know thought of compliance with
the rules exactly you know and some of
the rules here are really otic like most
states the rules were made by people who
knew nothing about cannabis right so you
know for example we get a lot of
donations from California people that
live in California I don't ask them how
it came how the cannabis say donate got
the Nevada but I'm sure that it didn't
just appear in Nevada so you know I mean
there there are some times where you
know we really do our best and I do my
best not to do anything illegal but
there are times for example we're having
giveaway events where certainly I'm in
possession of more than what the legal
limit is because I'm taking it to
distribute right no tens or hundreds of
veterans and so I do that myself because
I don't want to put someone else at risk
great and again we've never had an
incident with law enforcement again I
they know what we're doing with it you
know I think here even by now so let me
go a different direction with this you I
had a dear friend explained to me that
he felt sincerely that California had
sold its soul in the cannabis business
because his whole premise was used to be
patient focused that everything was
about the serving the patient it's
similar because what you're doing with
veterans and and first responders is
about you know medicine for what ails
you but the comment was made that
California had sold its soul from a
regulatory perspective and from a
commercial perspective because the
patient was no longer the center of it
well in that I think that's happened in
every state you know certainly in states
where they had medical first and then
they transitioned into what they call
recreational cannabis which is one of
the stupidest terms to recreational
alcohol or so it sounds like it's going
to be an Olympic sport so the in
Colorado we talk about we talk about the
regulator's we talk they call it Green
crack they're all about the green crack
that's all they care about the money it
generates
creates more jobs for their
infrastructure that's that's forever
growing where they can hire more people
to do it supposedly do enforcement you
know Colorado is a pretty good example
of how silly it is the marijuana
Enforcement Division they're you know
they're they're their business cards
indicate that they are that they're
investigators you know they carry guns
of all nine yards but if you go in there
and and and tell them you know about
some illegal activity that's going on
they refer that the local law
enforcement they don't do investigations
so I mean it's it's pretty stupid the
way they the whole system set up so the
whole sole selling subject the reason
why I bring it up is because there's
redemption in life I mean I think
everybody would agree there's there's
two sides to everything so if we have
collectively sold our souls and taken
our focus off what's good for the
patient there's also an opportunity to
perhaps buy our souls back right what do
you think about and and I think this is
germane to what you're doing because if
patients that were terminally ill had
access to cannabis at no charge that
would really go a long way to buy our
souls back absolutely apps and and and
the same thing applies to veterans I
mean or really anyone that can't get
exactly what they need you know and in
Nevada is a really good example too of
what can go back go really bad you know
when Nevada first went recreationally
legal it really the way they set the
system up it really shut out a lot of
patients and so there were patients who
couldn't get medicine okay that had been
getting medicine for quite some time you
know prior to the recreational you know
going legal so I mean it they don't
think about that you know the the
regulators don't think again they know
nothing to by the regulators defense
they have the best intention I mean
they're not out there trying to ruin
somebody's process they're trying to
make rules about something that they may
not as you had alluded to they may not
personally understand it at a level I
mean if we had growers that we're
figuring out how to create regulations
for growers I think we'd have a lot
better regulations there's comments
you know and and and by and large what
you say is true but on the other hand I
have to tell you that you know I'm
pretty well convinced there are some
states where you know the enforcement
people sit around a you know a round
table every morning trying to figure out
what they can do to you know the hassle
the people that are in the industry you
know which is pretty idiotic because you
know it's almost like they're trying to
they don't understand that if they shut
it down they're gonna lose their they're
gonna eliminate their own jobs do you
have access or has this been considered
to for seized or forfeited property can
you get your hands on cannabis that's
been seized by law enforcement and
redistribute it to you know that's
something that there were that we
they're getting ready to try to do
before that we treat for example in
Nevada a lot of people tourists would
buy cannabis and then they'd have to
throw it away or give it away or
whatever it's a lot of times the rental
car companies a couple years ago when
the first went League or thought about
they had all this stuff left in rental
vehicles you know so I tried to get away
to if people didn't want to take it home
with them well yeah exactly they want to
cut because please understand TSA is not
a Drug Enforcement Agency
you know I carry cannabis Mike cannabis
medicine am i carry on every time I fly
I've had it in my carry-on and I opened
it up and TSA has gone through it and
they've never touched my my cannabis at
all I'm sure if you had you know five
pounds or something in your suitcase
they'd call the police or something but
that's not their job they're looking for
explosives so that's all the repurposing
of instead of destroying it there sue
there's got to be a value or an
opportunity for us to take that cannabis
that's for whatever reason been seized
and to put it back to good use for the
relief of pain and trauma for veterans
and first responders well and and that's
absolutely true you know and that's
something that really you know we
probably need to work hard because $0.20
well that's that's one reason that's the
main thing that holds it up yeah it's
too logical drew so the future for hero
grown dark what's the future what are
your plans where are you going
well you know again we're growing
membership you know very very rapidly
you know and so our hope is just to
continue what we're doing but to touch
more lives you know the last thing I
think about every night before I fall
asleep is you know 50
more veterans and first responders died
today and you know what could I have
done to you know do a better job to save
some of them so you know that that's the
mission we're on now you know really our
goal is to to have veterans and and
pretty much everybody to have safe
access to free cannabis the same way
they have safe access to the drugs that
are killing you know so many people you
know it was over 130 people a day now
- still opiate overdose so I mean it's
just it's a rendus problem you know
people made people and companies made
billions of dollars you know literally
slaughtering Americans you know will
lose more veterans just this year than
we like we've lost in combat and every
war combined Hervey conflict combined
since the end of the Vietnam War
unbelievable so a great cause a great
organization really appreciate what you
do how you do it
you can join become a supporter become a
part of this conversation by going to
hero growing org and memberships free by
the way for veterans and first
responders they can sign up online get
involved and be at stake in the
supporting our vets and first responders
well thanks drew again we couldn't do
what we do without you so really
appreciate you and Brad sure appreciate
you man I get up alright up the good
work go to it Thanks
[Music]