I'm handsome handsome from Germany
Berlin from Germany
yes well I'm working together with
exotic seeds we developed our new
project my strain it's a cross of Larry
OG and Koosh Koosh we named it after me
there are lots of OGIS out there you
know and ocean grown it is actually
right and my name is spelled the same
way h e RZ OG had soaked and we split
that up and made him a perfect health OG
and yeah that's how we call it the
strain it's a cross of two of my
favorites and
it's a strong and happy high the best
ones right best of both words can laugh
your ass off and sweat like a
motherfucker because you think you're
trippin it's a hybrid
you know you get everything like it hits
your head and it hits your body you
really get a full body stone and and I
mean creative file actually and it
tastes like a little bit woody a little
bit earthy with notes of marshmallow and
honey so it can has this little gassy
earthy touch with the sweetness at the
ends so it's really really awesome
delicious my love yes and in their four
years that you have been in a cannabis
world from the way to say um can you
notice have you noticed any big change
or like in the taste of the customer
well there are lots of new
see banks out here everybody is growing
and everybody is developing everybody is
bringing out new strains it's really
progressive business you know everybody
wants to push the frontier we all want
the worldwide legalization so we can
traffic cannabis globally that would be
awesome
I'm actually right now working in Europe
with kilos of CBD you know throughout
Europe because got this medical aspect
which is really important to me also but
it's also important to bring up the
structures from the future when THC is
legal we have already had set up all
those structures you know that was
really important that why we started
with that we are friggin gross in that
is something that happened fast well
everything that has wants to turn out
fine and good has to take its time you
know gotta be patient you've got to be
confident and you got to visualize the
future and the upcoming events which may
be mostly positive
what
much more love in it
now a Gutzon it was put on boys and
we live for the plan we die for the
friends and we're pushing crunches yes
now we have two tickets
you have to of course ever since look
here with so much for your time
it was a pleasure my