lo and behold when the first labs come
out that was steep hill was first and
pure analytics pure Linux comes out
Samantha Millers of brilliant scientists
so I meet her
and she says hey I can do predicated
work and I'm like nice let's look into
predicated work and find out what's
going on we start to take a look at
what's taking place with Lawrence's work
and what we're doing with the canna
tonic line and we start pulling out the
outliers that let us breed these lines
to get a greater stability Lawrence ends
up passing away from Ken's
cancer he gives me this whole collection
I then diffuse it into the cannabis
community so that it's in the hands of
individuals and I put on all these
programs on how to cultivate and then I
put him in touch with extractors that
have the ability to do medical
extraction so that all these patients
would be self-sustaining I I pry wasn't
a medical guy prior I'm a historic
black-market cultivator technician
trafficker and so I take over dispensary
eleven years ago and I get humanized
from the experience because I see real
need for medical stuff and I'm like why
these people are absolutely dying and it
tripped me outside never been around
people don't die before I see people die
from gunshots and I seen you not slow
death and I did not know what it looked
like and I didn't realize that you could
replace so much medicine from cannabis
thank you and so I went on this run so I
I'm involved in the foundation of modern
CVD and I say hey this is gonna be
awesome and then lo and behold they
start to mine Kentucky hemp Chinese hemp
because people say hey we can just use
this and it works and it does work to a
degree but the efficiency isn't the same
and the the overall spectrum of benefits
isn't the same because you're not
receiving they want to give you CBD
alone but CBD has to have some THC
present in order to be optimized for
uptake yeah because the way the
receptors release and recover it you get
a longer recovery rate longest sickle
grade in the body if we have THC present
below point three but it's not that it
doesn't have any THC present it's just
that hemp wasn't selected for smoking
purposes oh sorry
hemp wasn't selected for smoking
purposes fiber purposes only and so what
I realized as just this revelation was
that none of us smoked landrace cannabis
as much as people think it's landrace
it's not
they took landrace populations and they
chose the plants they wanted to use for
their patches propagated it cultivated
it and then they kept the males they
wanted to pollinate the seed for next
year into the females they wanted to use
for next year as soon as man touches
that shit to cultivate a variety Lynne
race is naturally occurring so what they
could do in Afghanistan
Africa is they could go to bat is they
could go into land raise populations and
find the outliers that lived through the
drought that year live through the
locust the ones that lived through the
locusts they could then add to the
genealogical population the ones that
survived this new pathogenic issue added
to the genealogical population so I get
the genealogical information present but
fundamentally that cannabis was used as
medicine and it was used in CVD form if
you're equatorial and I and just because
I got to see so much data I started
going I got you everything that we
consider psychoactive on spiritual use
stuff we want heady weed that all comes
from zero to twenty on the equator
that's what people had incredible
lifestyle where you're plenty of water
you didn't have to worry about freezing
to death in the winter it wasn't over
ninety degrees because it's never that
hot on the equator excites to work on
the equator so something hot it's just
incredible sun intensity and then you
start to get above twenty to forty and
it's in the 30s that we're talking
afghanistan pakistan where you have some
of the most savage weather known to
mankind and no water and so i started
realizing that it breaks down really
pretty well where the easier your life
was is where you cultivated spiritual
cerebral cannabis and the more you moved
away from the zero towards the forty
where basically it ended all normal
cannabis production you started having
CBD
dominant cannabis on one to one ratio
cannabis and nope not Hardy are better
for you to consume Hardy are in a sense
that it works in that environment but
not harder if you bring it down to the
equator because it has to have an
ability to work with all all stuff we're
talking about over the 30 and that range
is high desert
yeah because high desert is is
considered in a definition less than 10
inches of rain a year so I need to have
a different type of root system and I
need to have a different type of leaf
structure to be a more efficient
radiator and I have to have an ability
to control desiccation more so higher
trichome levels because trikes really do
help desiccation the drying out of the
flower and then lo and behold how do you
hold flower in Morocco you can't and so
when I started getting into hash making
probably like we see that would have
been around same 99 2000 I started doing
all my water process back then I had a
lady who had lived in Morocco for about
four years and she was showing us what
we she was what we were doing she goes
you guys are not letting this shit dry
out enough she said you have to take it
to zero and so I started coming up with
my own drying systems in pizza boxes and
then I used big commercial coffee
grinders to do the micro planing so a me
and Brandon hook up from third Jenny was
dying because I was using coffee
grinders to microplane 15 years ago but
what it did was it let me make really
high quality bubble and we had access to
truckloads of shake at the time coming
out all the huge massive endure so it
was a waste product so I had all these
massive operations where we would run
all the the ice water hash through the
systems and then run it through the
filtration and then we would dry it in
the pizza racks in the house and then
micro it and then run it through die
presses that I had welders whip up for
me and then once the material once they
got tired of that varietal I would just
repress it and who died so I would throw
out a brand new die repress it again and
it would come out as a brand new product
as far as the stove was concerned oh my
god that's a much better product same
product in another form it's kind of
like the turkey bag phenomenon you bring
it to me one turkey bag they don't want
it you go back in the house bring it
back in another turkey bag they'll take
it they'll take it exactly they'll take
it they don't know the difference and we
know that so we would deliver a really
high-quality product but you start to
see the new
as a perception but the point was she
was telling me that they have tins the
way they tin up the hash in Morocco
where they're holding it for years with
no mold no hold ability so I started
realizing I got you it's because the
flower degrades so quickly in these very
low humidity environments that they
can't hold flower and that's why hash
production was valuable for these
individuals but if you were to look at
the hash from any of those countries
they would have a way more balanced
keema type you'd see a much more
dominant CVD ratio so not
disproportionate but more like a 1 to 1
or a 1 to 0.5 so when I started getting
all the Pakistani genetics getting
shipped in from the Pakistani hash
fields the first thing I did was propped
it all up and then sent it to the lab so
I could start to take a look at it on
predicated and then it let me understand
what was inside and that's when I
started realizing this hypothesis I
started being put together a lifetime of
doing this and saying whoa the data says
this which makes sense for what we think
therefore that's what it is
so I know that with all these varietals
that came through all the original
Afghan E's if you run all those
originals in like 9% yeah low numbers
man we skewed them and then
unfortunately the store fronts are
obsessed with numerix and it completely
screws up the reality of cannabis it
screws it up as the fruits come in the
fruits are coming in because and that's
about it strip levels now so now it's
skewed syrup levels and I have stuff
that's 2.6 on a total term that's
ungodly quality that's you would say it
has five times the syrup levels of a
five percent because the numbers don't
quantify it it's like saying you know I
always use yeah you're pretty but you're
not a nice person so yeah you can add a
hundred pretty points and you keep
adding pretty points keep bad don't keep
adding them it doesn't change the fact
that you suck to be around so I'm good
now just get the fuck out of the car and
and that's how it is to me with cannabis
weird no there's no reality and it's the
only way to perceive this stuff in real
life is to understand that there's
things that you can use in context to
understand where we're going wrong with
what we're doing now and and as the
reality comes in and people become more
educated it'll be a lot
that's why when I get to mess around
with Abrams where at first you know they
were aggressive when this just like the
wine industry I get all these top wine
execs come in and they attacked me on
judging judging weed because they go we
want to take over the industry and how
Somalia is run it and I said the key
difference between you and I my friend
is that you're judging flavonoids and
ethyl alcohol so no matter what alcohol
you playing with it's the same basic
booze at the lack of all you are you can
put it in your mouth and spit it out you
can't spit out the cannabinoids and it's
the cannabinoids that the effect is
dominated by so you have to be able to
so eventually it traumatize them because
they said you basically have to be a
career weed smoker to be able to do it
and I said yeah because I am yeah
because I'm gonna be able to smoke 40
varieties and tell you that was the one
that worked and and and so when I hang
out with normal individuals they're like
you're a drug addict because they watch
me smoke so much I'm like no I'm not
drug addict it's just that I can
function normally on high levels of
intoxication and I can discern this was
the one that worked and if you put them
all back in the cookie jar I'll still
pull the same one out over and over
again because that's what we do for a
living it's not me it's other people
like me if you're a Korea you're Korea
and the wine guys finally were like
alright alright so then we had a better
relationship because they weren't being
so adversarial because they're very
intelligent most of them are PhD
scientists and in viticulture lists in
Somali a and sort of them there's like
the top of the food chain and how things
are perceived but I can smoke them some
reefer and they're on their hands and
knees begging for me to take them home
so I can put them on into a cot so I'm
just like you're judging anybody so we
we know that to be true and you and you
need to be able to say hey these are the
things that happen in the public is the
same way so when I get academics to come
in each individual that comes into
cannabis wants to disprove what you do
and because you're not one of their
peers you must not be as sharp and so
there for a lifetime of doing this at
every level humanly possible doesn't
mean anything we know this from this and
what they find out is that they're
mistaken
and then you end up building a
relationship so now you can actually
share because I don't pretend to be a
scientist I'm not I am fascinated with
science and I use scientists but I'm a
field operator that's what I'm about I'm
about getting product to the table and
I'm about helping farmers get product to
the table