so why don't we start with High Times
thinks that the the retail game is where
it's at and they're making a big pivot
so who wants to start with that one yeah
I can start it's I told the I think I
said this to Tom the other day I was
like everybody wants to do retail until
they get into retail it sounds fun it
looks you know glamorous but it's you
know I think High Times is import
awakening when they realize that the
amount of money they're there is it
retail is horrible if you know unless
you're gonna try to cut corners and try
to have a certain things here and there
which I'm not gonna lie of third of
retailers are doing that you know
they're not doing things that exactly
the way that they have been supposed to
so you know a and which shocked me
because there's been a few quite a few
retailers that have already been busted
by the BCC legal ones doing things that
they're not supposed to I mean I know of
one that got caught with a hundred
pounds of illicit cannabis selling it
out of the jar from underneath the
register underneath the counter and they
have their license and nothing's
nothing's done so you know that's
another disheartening fact you know off
subject but yeah I think High Times is
in for a rude awakening when they
realize that the retail business is not
all it was meant to be and that they're
not going to be able to get the
evaluation that they want from retail to
sell it or what they eventually plan on
doing well wait a second let's back up a
second where they just slap where they
just let go or there was a slap on the
wrist is that stung
that's not enforcement no it's not
enforcement at all and you know the BCC
has always said oh well II only enforced
and the DCR we only own of course
against legal operators cuz that's
that's that's what we can do that's what
we're allowed to do we're not allowed to
enforce against illegal but they're not
enforcing against legal ones either that
are breaking the laws so and when you do
that now you're creating a completely
missed you
market because now you have legal
operators that are doing illegal stuff
to cut corners isn't quick isn't cushy
punch back to business as usual and
because she punches back the business
hey you know I mean they got caught with
a completely illegal facility running to
location and again I know are you guys
selling cushy punch in your shop
I am NOT but I have been friends with
the owner and I met him I met up with
him the other day and I asked him he
said oh yeah we're gonna be back online
so I don't think they actually have
products back out there yet but you know
it all it is is the brand gets caught
they find another licensee they make a
licensing agreement for the name and
next thing you know that brand is back
online with a new license so you know
and again I I love the guy very nice guy
family guy but you know when when people
are doing things like this and he's not
the worst you know the other retailers
selling you know literally they
confiscated a hundred pounds from his
facility and I know of another incident
where the idiot manager started running
down the back alley with like 20 pounds
and the bcc agents tackled him okay I
mean and they're still operating it
makes no sense and I'm over here worried
about taxes and this and that and I'm
getting you know if I'm late I'll get a
threat letter that I'm gonna even lose
my license
but then the person who completely does
something illegal and gets caught
red-handed
nothing so it just a lot of things just
don't make sense to me you know and and
if you're not going to enforce in areas
where you have complete control to
indoors let alone the ones that you
don't well again you know you're setting
us up for failure and you're rewarding
the people that are doing illegal stuff
to continue doing illegal stuff back to
the question at hand about high times I
don't know if anyone else is as bored as
I am but I actually pulled up the SEC
filing on to look at what assets were
included
purchased so you've got to kind of
unwind it free harvest before harvest
entered the California picture it was
have a heart out of Seattle that was on
you know getting some of the retail
permits in not so coveted jurisdictions
let's say so harvest purchased have a
hearts dispensaries and then they were
also in the process of getting some of
their own licenses so I unpacked just
what it is that High Times allegedly
purchased and I'm saying allegedly
because you still need a stock to go
public and on all of these different
jurisdictions to sign off on this before
this deal could ever go through so
minimum I would say you're looking at a
year before you know any dots would be
the t's would be crossed and and eyes
would be dotted before this would be
completed so we've got a harvest in Palm
Springs and if you're familiar with the
Palm Springs market
Palm Springs is one of two jurisdictions
in the entire state that have an open
process for retail the other being
Lompoc so if you're interested in
getting a retail permit those are the
two jurisdictions that if you can find
property that qualify you can get you
pretty much can get a retail permit
there so you've got a very overcrowded
market in Palm Springs that's one of
them
you've got another one in harvest of
Venice which if my memory serves me
correctly I believe Venice is only a
medical market which is a really tough
way to compete these days we've got
harvest of Merced you've got harvest of
Riverside and I don't think that one is
opened yet you've got harvest of
Handford which isn't open yet you've got
harvest of blithe which is definitely
not open yet and then you've got two
very expensive dispensary permits in San
Francisco you've got another one in San
Bernadino which I don't believe is open
and to in Auckland one in Kalinga and
the final one being in Santa Cruz and
Santa Cruz only allows you to sell off
20% of the business so what they sold
was their 20 percent stake in or no
actually I think it's only 10% so you've
got a lot of less you know desirable
areas to operate you know I know that
the Kalinga store is if it's still open
is doing about a thousand dollars a day
so um these are the types of assets I
want everyone to be aware of that
harvest unload potentially unloaded on
to high times high time still has to go
public and still has to you know take
possession of these and in the midst of
a pandemic when everybody is shifting
from retail to curbside or delivery you
know those business models absolutely do
not make sense in either Oakland or San
Francisco and maybe they could make
sense if you're going to turn all of
those assets into trying to become a
statewide delivery brand is the only
thing that I could think that they would
attempt to do but that would all depend
on how expensive those San Francisco and
Oakland properties really are and how
much those are bleeding them dry until
they actually are up and running and up
and running in a post pandemic world
where we're not wearing masks and were
you know congregating again and so this
to me should be viewed as a Hail Mary by
both harvest who's looking to unload
their less desirable assets and a Hail
Mary by high times hoping that this will
help them go public and that's all this
is and nothing more and just quickly a
show of hands
the panelists who here is getting in on
the high times reggae offering getting
in while the goings hot anybody email
but you know something funny about high
times in that whole situation first of
all it's just whole thing screams Hard
Rock Cafe to me and like this idea of
just these super like commercial just
wonky look in places that have like
cheech's pipe in a glass display or
something but bloody high time story so
you know flow kana we launched this
dirty money campaign on a Monday and we
did an Instagram post it was basically
like encouraging people to contact the
representative and you know we don't
want to have to handle cash great
actually posted it some dude from High
Times who works there commented and was
like all his comment says was your
lobbying wrong or that's not how you do
it or something like that and I was like
okay so we responded and we were like
you know what do you mean we think this
is an issue people would care about
especially since you just purchased 13
dispensaries and this is about not
having to handle cash in a dispensary
and they responded that of course they
care and that they invented grassroots
lobbying so in case folks didn't know
that out there high time invented
grassroots lobbying which actually isn't
even a thing
but they invented it and so you know
they obviously really know what they're
doing and they've got a great team I did
just read that stormy Simon is no longer
the CEO step down she lasted four months
yeah yeah now I I had conversations with
stormy where I told her to get out I
said you do because you know where it
started was when I got the emails and
you know the one from today is coming
you know who sent it high times investor
who sent it Adam Levin and then there
was one that had Stormy's name on it and
I immediately emailed her and said don't
let them put your name I was like and
then I was like don't you do not a
couple years from now once you be
associated with duping little old ladies
who
invested in high times you do not want
your name associated with that and then
we had a long phone call and uh you know
I've been trading emails I'm gonna try
to get her on to do a webcast but just
and being clear for anybody who's
watching cuz I'm gonna cut this is the
high time segment so people don't have
to wait till the end the people who
currently run high times are a bunch of
finance douchebags who have nothing to
do with the grass roots history of high
times from the sick from the 70s and 80s
and any master you know any good grower
does not read high times today ok so
just everybody who is thinking of
investing in high times or who thinks oh
my god that'd be amazing to go to a high
times dispensary so we have a couple
brands on here amanda is Flo kana going
to rush to supply product to high times
retail Shannon is Fiddler's greens is
that gonna be the first phone call you
make when they take over those retail
operations and shame on you
we'll see I blame high times in a lot of
ways for bringing this weird idea of
what quality is to the marketplace and
that's really been hard for sun-grown
because when I was growing up in Chicago
and looking at High Times Magazine they
had be centerfolds of buds that are
supposed to be like the highest-quality
buds like these were the buds and they
were all indoor and they were all grown
like this far from the light and none of
them really looked I always would come
compare it to like the Playboy
centerfold or like you grow up thinking
that that's what like the ideal woman
looks like and then you get out in the
world and you realize that was all
bullshit I kind of feel like that's what
high times did they set it up for people
consumers to think that quality meant
orange hairs and tight nugs well and
that's not true so then I make corn hub
of cannabis no no I kept Kevin I have a
video clip of that I'll play in the end
the on-demand version Kevin Joe jury
said at best which was the article on
the left side of the page which
is that hydro bud its sole purpose was
to sell the product on the right side of
the page which was an HP s light or
whatever it was what you have is you
have information that's used as
basically marketing it's kind of like
reading old high times because I haven't
read this shit in years it's like
reading high times and every article was
basically to sell the material on the
next page so they're not giving you any
information that giving you a marketing
pitch wrapped around some photos yeah
absolutely and and but unfortunately the
impact that it had on the consumer
marketplace was that all these years
later in doors being sold for $65 an
eighth and Sun grown is lucky to get 40
and I do think that High Times played a
huge role in that like I don't think
they'll ever take responsibility for it
but I think they played a huge role in
really leading the consumer or on us
astray when it comes to knowing what a
quality cannabis product is yeah and
it's a double-edged sword right because
for I grew up in Texas and a lot of my
first exposure to cannabis was you know
High Times magazines that we were able
to look out and see so it brought it to
people who weren't in Northern
California weren't part of the community
but like Amanda said it was also
misbranding and misrepresenting it was
you know selling McDonald's hamburgers
like it was filet mignon and so we've
got to undo that at this point I like
that analogy to be rushing to you do
business with high kinds of retail shops
that's not really in line with our
brands and our mission got it okay have
we beaten high times sufficient to
appear
okay