[Music]
greetings greetings greetings and
welcome back guys gather round part 2 of
the history of rosin once again my name
is Nikki T to my right we have Phil of
soil ground solving les
and over here further to the right I'm
introducing you guys to Ben aka show me
Terps show me the church these Instagram
who navels are hard to remember this is
ben mccabe show me the Terps of rosin
tech and rosin techno labs what's up man
thank you for having me
so tell them a little bit about what you
do at rosin tech so we worked for rosin
tech is one of our affiliates so I work
for show labs we have a distribution and
manufacturing license in the state of
California under our manufacturing
license what I've which I directly
oversee is a rosin techlabs we produce
high-end live raisins ice water hashes
one of our main brands is rosin techlabs
so Nick mentions rosin tech rosin tech
products which produces rosin presses
for everything from the home user to
large-scale manufacturing was a company
that we started with and just through
evolution through the cannabis industry
we were finally able to get our
California license to start putting our
product onto the legal market so I head
up the manufacturing and other aspects
of shell labs
so this guys come a long way I actually
you know have watched him do all the
demonstrations since day one with rosin
tech products doing live pressing
demonstrations and it's beautiful to see
where they've come today and see this
guy making moves in the license world in
California they got yourself appreciate
it
and all the way from Barcelona Spain
Barcelona Spain over here to my left we
have my longtime bredrin I do ed who is
a blue ice tech now blue ice tech
California is working out of cookies
Maywood and I do what are you doing over
cookies well hello guys I'm from Spain
and has telling you I'm working at
cookies right now I'm trying to figure
out what we can do there because they
don't have a non-solvent lab they was
doing just some solvent extracts but not
non solvent and they had like tons of
dreams sitting there on the floor just
trying to figure out what to do since
they realized that the solvent market is
going down
they thought that they have to do
something with non solvent with all this
trim so they called me to help them a
little bit so they brought out the big
guns so this is a new blue ice tech this
man's been around for a long time
winning multiple cannabis cups in fact
last year he judged spannabis in Spain
this man has been making hash this is
his passion and big up edu for coming
all the way out from Barcelona Spain
baggage and everytime for real and I
wanted each of these gentlemen on stage
to kind of talk about what rosin means
to them when they first learned about
the term rosin when you first started
pressing rosin some of the difficulties
you encountered what you learned and how
you learned it let's start with Ben over
here you know when did you first hear
about rosin uh so yeah we you know I
grew up on the East Coast
I'm a he's coast guy grew up in
Connecticut everyone had sure like I
might be the youngest person on the
panel here so I might be kind of like
new school right to the to the solvent
less world in cannabis right as we you
know cannabis years are like dog years
like seven years and one really and I
was making BHO just like everybody else
on the East Coast and I had sent a photo
to my friend I had some really nice kind
of like yellow shatter that we had made
which was kind of the in thing at that
point and he had text me a question back
I sent him this photo that was this
beautiful yellow slab and he's like he's
like oh is that rosin hey what the fuck
is rosin I was like you mean resin like
what are you talking about
and from there if you know we obviously
started to have that discussion is where
actually started to hear about Nick and
you know started to dive deep into all
this it was a new thing oh there's like
you know we didn't have to use butane on
my mother's back porch we can use just
heat presses and ice water hash to get
that full melt level and to actually
have it be far superior than abusing in
my opinion you know so to be up here on
the panel is actually I mean really
exciting to come that way from I mean
that may mean it seems like yesterday
but I want to say it was like five years
ago or so when you guys were starting to
blow up with putting rosin on two
different social medias and youtubes and
different forums you can find like
little really like threads of
information that if you knew like resin
and knew making extracts you know things
will start to pop oh shit a hair
straightener you know like there was I
mean the amount of hair straighteners we
went through ridiculous a lot of us
started with oral tradition a lot of
this started with just trying it for
yourself you know the hair straightener
tech you know and I like to bring it
back to Mila Jansen the hash Queen from
pollinator when I first started learning
from Mila back in the early 2000 there
was nothing written about this there
were a few forum posts in 2001 and
really it was about oral tradition it
was about going to these hash makers and
talking to them about their experiences
in Morocco and their experiences in
Europe and their experiences in India
and really just hearing what they had to
say that pushed me to want to learn
further I think that's still what it is
even with like jar tech right now it's
like a simple thing you throw it in the
jar tech but like if you're a hash guy
what solvent list like what you say
we're trying to compete with come come
back with like these butane guys making
sauce it's like you put it in a jar
what that's it just float it into a jar
and seal it for a little bit like it's a
relatively simple advancement but it's
like fascinating and and really not that
simple if you think about it and you
mentioned you know blasting butane tubes
on your backyard we all started there I
feel like you know to be completely
honest I did too you know
a hash 2003-2004 i bought a honeybee
extractor off the back of a High Times
Magazine little plastic looking free
butane cuz I heard it was the best
butane out there and I definitely
blasted butane on the back porch from my
house in Boulder Colorado I'm putting it
out there you know but we all started
somewhere because it tated me it taught
me so much
it was plastic a polymer of some of some
sort I don't know I'm not sure like I
said honey bee extractor I'm giving them
credit back at High Times magazines 2003
2004 but either way you know that's what
pushed me to want to do something else I
actually made that honey oil on the back
of my porch and I started giving it to
all my friends and my friends were
getting goofy like a little too fucked
up you know I was like wait what's in
this what are we doing here and I
started actually trotting to Europe and
I made trips to Amsterdam to learn from
Mila in fact one of the first cafes that
gave me any information as to what was
that product was the Bluebird Cafe
because back then in 2004-2005 is when
they started kind of seeing this butane
product of this honey oil hit the market
started banning it in places and there
were not a lot of people talking about
it there was not a lot of research done
Bluford cafe was one of the only places
that soymilk too hot you know but you
find these Henny little spots and these
people willing to talk about it there
was a scientist there that was doing
some testing and he was finding a ton of
heavy metals in there honey oil that was
on the Shelf being sold so people found
ways around that they started mixing the
honey oil with their bubble hash you
know and calling it jelly so I don't
know if anybody remembers jelly from mid
2000 early 2000s but there were ways
they people start around that's with
morroco hash exactly but we started
learning that the butane at that point
there was not enough education there was
not enough knowledge there were heavy
metals that we were putting into the
product we were concentrating those
heavy metals and that's what pushed me
to try and recreate that color and that
consistency without the use of chemical
solvents you know so there is value to
what we were doing on the back porch
because we were all there so I just
wanted to touch on that that's where
that tangent came from pick up your cell
phone
good yeah I actually used the the the
hottest commodity was a stainless steel
turkey baster and then you'd cut a
screen out of the back porch like you
talked about heavy metals not even
thinking about it could there be holes
out of my screen and I went the wrong
way you know we all came from somewhere
all right we all actually just consumed
some of this gentleman's hash who flew
all the way out here and he's utilizing
dry material we all preach fresh frozen
whole plant material as we were
mentioning and now the man's on stage so
I wanted him to talk a little bit about
what he's doing in the lab specifically
because we really have all preached this
whole plant fresh frozen since I learned
from this gentleman named Joe Petri I'm
actually gonna talk about that a little
bit further right now but Joe Petri kept
yelling at me being like your hash isn't
mine you know you're making it with
butan we were posting pictures on the
forums at this point getting kicked off
of water hash forums because our water
hash started looking like butane hash
oil it was gold and gooey and people
didn't believe us to be completely
honest I went to the legends of hash in
2009 and I almost got kicked out this is
an Amsterdam and skunk man Sam's pulls
me aside he's like this isn't water hash
this is butane hash oil you're not
allowed in this contest is only for dry
seft butane hash oil and tries to kick
me and harold AKA banff extractions out
of legends of hash ease so there was a
lot of like trials and tribulations we
faced with this new technology with
controlling the variables of the ice and
the water and the input material
utilizing fresh frozen but to get back
to joseph Pietra he was like you don't
make real hash because he thought we
were making butane from our photos he's
like I make live hash I was like what is
that what does that mean live hash and
at that point I think I cut the guy off
I was like I'm done with this crazy kook
yelling at me on Facebook this is before
Instagram and I was like but there's
something to his live hash we had a
messed up run in 2010 around that time
when I was running a laboratory in a
place called pink house blooms we had
our own garden on site and at day 40 45
we started noticing some hermaphrodite
plants and these plants started throwing
pistols and throwing things
we didn't want to see that we didn't
want to bring to fruition as flowers and
so the boss was like yeah just do what
you want with that row we're gonna throw
it away it was a little early granted
but it was alive these plants were alive
and I was like oh it's just kook I put
this word live into my head these plants
are live what are we gonna do so I
literally took these plants I took a few
big Leafs off of them but I chopped him
at the root and I grabbed the base of
these plants I put them in my cold water
bucket and just started spinning with my
buddy Stephen Lewis
just two of us for like eight hours and
we took the whole row down we're like
fuck oh they're throwing the shit away
we're gonna just try this and we didn't
this wasn't fresh frozen yet but this
was live plants as far as we were
concerned took him straight from the
root and started mixing them and the
product that came from this was amazing
it started really really looking like
butane at that point it was really
really hard to handle and it became so
hard to handle we were like okay wait
let's pull it back a little bit how do
we handle these live plants and that's
really where fresh frozen came from or
live resin in the butane world live
rosin in our world there's so many
different terms that we like to touch on
and there's still a little time up here
but fresh frozen became a commodity live
whole plant fresh frozen for not only
the live resin guys utilizing butane but
for us solvent lists are live rosin
people we were able to retain a lot more
of the terpenes present in the plant
while it was growing by running it live
so pick up Joseph pietre if you're
listening out there you know it's got
love for a hater because he's the one
that flipped the switch you know and
that's when I started teaching Europe
about processing live or fresh frozen
product I feel like it's where giddy up
and a lot of them got that inspiration
to run their fresh frozen material in
their hydrocarbon units aka live resin
that's all family it all happened around
the same time in Colorado but Eddie over
here is doing magic so without further
ado no he is utilizing dry material and
I just rolled up a spliff I couldn't
even handle it it's still on my hands so
we want to know how you're preserving
the terpenes and you know really what
you've learned coming out here and
experiencing some of the strains that
were running compared to the strains
you've ran in Europe you know give a
little background about what you've been
doing okay um seems all of you know I'm
from Spain sorta for my bank in Spain we
smoked hash for long I think since 726
year when the Arabs came to Spain they
came with hash and also I think the word
hashish in is coming from that because
they was smoking the hash before they
came to the war they were smoking hash
before battle yeah hashish in that's
where that term came from exactly so
he's bringing it back this is his
culture this is where we came from this
is really what we've been mimicking this
entire time is is this culture in this
generation that that came from you know
this man's hometown so bring it back for
us so we've been smoking a hash for long
and there has that we wasn't smoking it
was has mostly from Morocco from Indian
from Pakistan and the quality of that
hash now now we know that it was low
quality but on that moment was the early
only type of highs able to smoke so we
thought that the hash was amazing and on
that time we'll learn from them from the
Moroccan people that we have to smoke
with tobacco's so the way we smoked in
in Spain is with tobacco where all the
highs with the tobacco so people in
Spain they used to use like half gram of
hash in a joint so they smoked four or
five John's a day so two or three grams
a day so people buy hash at five ten
dollars a gram so now we have these
amazing products that we can do as you
say with fresh frozen whole plants but
we all have that market in Spain ready
to pay hundred bucks for a gram so that
make us a little bit difficult to
improve and to grow as a hash maker
doing top-quality six-star pros
so since the beginning I've been doing
highest just with trim and that trim was
trim from plants dry so we know that the
quality is not like when you use fresh
frozen materials because you have
mortars on that because during the dry
process you lose a lot of terms but that
was enough good for us if we compare
with the moroccan highs that we was
smoking before now so that's what I do I
try to do as you say magic with with
trim I try to explain to the growers
that they have to keep the trim fresh
they have to trim when the plan is fresh
and keep that that trim on the freezer
for me but it's a little bit her but
yeah at the beginning people was
throwing away that trim I was asking
them for that trim I was giving back
money or hash to them so they was really
happy now they realized that I'm making
money with that so they charged me they
charge me money for that trim so it's
been a little bit hard for me to do
high-quality product and be able to sell
it at a fair price for me and for the
customers no I think this has been an
issue over generations you know in
reality as I was mentioning you know I
started up in Mendo in humble humble
County where I was collecting trim off
the side of the road it was all dry trim
that the farmers didn't even want on
their property because that was just
more weight that they could possibly get
in trouble for and it's crazy where the
education has come you know we're where
we started where it was just garbage
previously and now we're turning it into
gold and really yeah it's all about
education what are your first
impressions of the LA like the u.s.
slash always
and then kind of globally what you guys
yeah so the question is uh what are your
first impressions on the LA scene versus
like the global scene and it's
interesting that you say that it's
harder for you guys to get $100 a gram I
actually want to touch this real quick
because in Colorado when we first
brought these solvent list products to
market I mean I was stoked if I was
getting 40 a gram so the education and
the slim amount of amazingly protected
and curated material has created an
increase and demand in this product
along with the regulation the
over-regulation and everything else that
comes with the licensing in California
but you know to get back to the question
what is what have you noticed here in LA
or in the United States as the market
compared to the global market I mean
I've been coming to America a few times
during the last five years I used to
came for the expose like high times
seems like that and now that I'm here in
LA I feel like it's a little bit like
Barcelona in a Spain if we compare we
have a Spain that we have all these
cannabis clubs and all this cannabis
culture and we have Barcelona that is
like the center of everything now I feel
like a ladies a little bit the center of
everything here in America there's a lot
of market here and people ready to
invest and ready to spend money on the
that high quality products I agree I
mean especially here in the United
States is what we have seen is a lot of
the hype a lot of the education a lot of
these products start on the coasts
whether we're talking about California
LA San Francisco or New York you know
whether we're talking about style trends
whether we're talking about trends in
hashish trends in food coastal trends
are real as far as what I've experienced
yeah I think that that $100 a gram
hundred twenty allogram that's a very la
or California thing even in Colorado it
seems to be much cheaper than that but I
do have a question - as far as the
the European market one thing you know
I've traveled the spannabis a few times
into Spain Barcelona like you said is
the epicenter it's very much the LA of
Spain in regards to weed for sure but
there's a lot of hype you know over
California strains right there's the
gelato there's the cookies there's these
newer flavors that have come out within
the past ten years that people are
getting excited about and even over in
in Europe because California now with
the legality is a lot of people who do a
lot of Hardy but you rarely in
California see sativa strains there's a
lot of beautiful Hayes's like I'm a I'm
a haze lover at heart right I grew up in
the Northeast we got a lot of haze and
sours which you really don't see anymore
but hey is like I mean it's manageable
its traditional hashish making strains
nobody does it anymore partly because
the flowering time but like what's your
experience with washing and pressing
different types of Hayes's over there do
you or do strictly stick to like is the
American strains the California strains
the hyper in my case it may be is it a
bit particular because since I love high
alert if my highs is clean I like
everything
I like is I like in I like sativas I
like indicus but yeah in Spain haze is
really popular we didn't grow in and
there's a hey super Silver Haze this or
a strange from from Amsterdam that I I
was really love of this specialist range
but people don't like to grow that
strength with 128 that's a rarity that's
like the true Terp lover we only take
him 50 60 days what are you hearing
how are you yielding on him not that
much you know that it was done deal that
bad and they don't look really nice that
they're real city where they don't do
they don't do bats bro they do like
small stamps you know yeah fingers it's
like really special but if you are a
real connoisseur you have to like City
was a thing I do every time I every time
I go to Spain I'm waiting to see some
some different Hayes's in live rosin or
full malformed I mean every time you
know I hate to bring it break it to you
guys but I think one of the reasons that
you guys don't see a lot of it I touched
on the yield but when we're talking
about yield in water hash let's bring it
back to the history of rosin real quick
pieces have a thick waxy cuticle
generally speaking super Silver Haze
Jack any any of those strains uh amnesia
haze what are some of the other Hayes's
that are out there the blue Neville's
haze there's been a few there's there
have been a few outliers to this rule
but most of these Hayes's that I'm
seeing have a very thick waxy cuticle so
even if you're gonna yield almost enough
to make it viable when you make water
hash when you go and then press that
water hash into rosin he was talking
about 91% yields we're lucky if we see
40% yields on Hayes's and that's
something that even if you get a little
something that might be high-quality
that wax also attributes to making
darker colors right you have to heat up
the temperature higher to actually
extrude the oils through the wax so less
the color matter the less terpenes
higher temperatures less terpenes you
know there's a lot of variables that
attribute to haze is being extremely
unpopular to hash makers i feel the high
i understand the haze high but when you
break it down it's very high it's very
hard to find a haze that's gonna be
viable you know if you sell it in flower
form it's extremely viable but when you
break it down and you're seeing one to
five percent yields after rosin it just
doesn't make it viable to send into that
allocated route I mentioned allocations
earlier but there are some outliers and
I do want to bring up an outlier it's
one of my favorite Hayes's to run ghost
train haze there's a few phenotypes that
do combine the haze taste but with that
Ghost power from the ghost OG and the
train wreck to help that trichome
production and we've been seeing things
that are viable we are seeing 15-20
percent yields over 20 percent yields
they were running one called the ghost
train haze number 9 but you know
no numbers at this point are dictated by
the grover themselves so you can't say
run the ghost train nine and you're
gonna do great everyone's got a
different ghost train number huh number
nine but they have been able to breed
Hayes's that that taste and that feeling
in two strains that are viable and those
are the things that I'd look for the
pure Hayes's the Pure Land race Hayes's
are gonna be very very hard to come by
in water hash form or rosin form because
of the structure of the trichome and it
just not wanting to make water hash even
the plan is not worth it because if you
have to wait 128 130 days flowering I
mean it's gonna be more expensive that
with than others
grow your own is what I say without one
lead that haze that 100 30-day haze hi
which I don't I don't discount I see
that there's a lot of people that need
that hi
but it's gonna be really hard to find it
at a shop because it takes a lot of
energy and a lot of dedication yeah I
don't think you'll be seeing strains
like that a lot of what we do focus on
let's bring it back to you know the
positive side of things I actually want
to hear everyone's theory on this is
I've been really focusing on strains
that are yielding viable amounts because
it helps our cultivation see that it's
it's worth it for them to give us that
flower it helps our business model right
so first I'm looking at that you know I
don't want to be generalizing but I do
look at a lot of the yield data but
oftentimes that yield data also
attributes to higher THC a higher THC
numbers in general higher terpene
amounts because if you have a thinner
waxy cuticle you have higher terpenes
generally which is a higher yield
terpenes are heavier than waxes so
there's a lot of things that we look at
that yield helps us attribute to but I
really look at things like the yield
when we're talking about material
starting material to finish product
rosin I look at the potency right that's
the second one and the third one is I
look at that terpene representation and
so those are the three things that I
look for in doing my wash is if it
doesn't hit those three things it's not
something that I generally want
but in those three things I want to have
very specific terpene profiles I want to
have one that's got the limonene I want
to have one that has that gasps the
Piney I want one that's really sugary
and so I have you know my five favorite
hash water hash aka rosin strains
strains that do really well in water
hash and do really well in rosin what
are some of your guys's favorite strains
I'll touch on line after what's your
favorite strain to wash right now your
top two been east coast I have to say
ages Sour Diesel that cut specifically
is like whisper my fresh frozen will
yield like six percent which is which is
beautiful from fresh frozen barbie
Karthus of anything like I mentioned
haze before like I'm a Terp seeker I
don't care like really what it yields I
mean at the end of the day like we all
got into it because it was for what we
wanted to consume so even like you know
I was trying to a five haze the other
day which is I could new one flowing
around had the profile and it was
amazing so that I'll give you three so
that was that was AJ's the a5 is nice
but the peanut butter cup that's been
going around is I got this gas eNOS to
it that I love yields well and again the
Terp I mean Terps are number one for me
like you go Terps are third for you
Terps are number one by far makes it
hard to do business fun ya know and I I
I wholeheartedly love that and I love
that answer
but how many times are you gonna get
more material from that grower you know
when he sees you know if you're doing a
trade you know it all depends on how
you're working but say you're spending a
certain amount of money on a pound of
material you know and you're getting
from that same farm you're getting one
strain that yields that 6% that AJ that
one strain that yields less than 1% it's
a rarity for sure and it's not ideal
every now and then you'll like run
something that that yields you nothing
but the end result is fire you know
shall never ever wash oh yeah how long
how often does it continue to come back
I guess there's two sides to personally
to like a business standard
for sure yields always a question but
gotta grow it yourself with that yeah
you know because the farmers not gonna
keep giving you that strain you know
your boss isn't gonna keep letting you
run that strangely he loses that money
yeah I think you know I think as the
market develops maybe they will I think
that you know price will start to be
dictated on the flowering cycle if it
takes on takes you 120 days for some
mazes to grow with that flower should we
priced more right I think develops those
those things might come to you know we
might be able to see those things
hopefully you know Phil what are some of
your favorite hash strains or rosin
strains okay so my favorite stuff I like
to wash I definitely got to hand it to
strawberry banana that's like my hello
it might go to for R&amp;D as far as like a
very stable strain it's it's it's really
consistent with a lot of things that I
do and a lot of the experimenting I do
and like it's really good for everything
as far as jar tech jams you know making
wet batters like the second press method
solvent lists our mechanical separation
like making the THC a it's very high in
THC a with the greater Keane profile so
definitely got a hand of straw Deana but
right now one I fell in love with was
cement shoes and that's just out to me I
think it's just the terpene for profile
that gets me as well as the just the the
effects from it you know number one for
me as well as I'd have to agree with
then as the terpenes it's number one on
my list and then next is everything else
because I'm gonna do a dab after a dab
after dab anyways so you know it's gonna
do its job but that that terpene profile
really really got me what's the cross on
the cementery there's bread bite
cult-classic seeds correct I'm not a
hundred percent on it and with the
profile man the profile is like a really
gassy funky savory almost like it's
unique it's that's why I like it so much
because it really isn't
comparable to what's popular on the
market you know it's not GMO it's not
papaya it's not strawberry banana it's
it's none of those it's not just gassy
but it's it's super unique and I'm
that's one thing that I really love
about it beautiful beautiful I want to
talk about one of my strains in it and
it does touch on some of what you guys
just mentioned but one of my favorite
terpene profiles for a long time has
been the lemon rind terpene profile like
the outside of a lemon not super Lemon
Haze which has more of like a lemon
orange cleaner type of a smell to me a
little bit more round in fruity I really
wanted like the rind of a lemon and to
me what epitomized the lot of the rind
of a lemon was the strain called lemon G
growing up it was from Ohio it was a
clone only it was really hard to get it
grew like shit it grew those fingers you
know you got it under a little bit too
hot alight I mean really you only have
Fox I really only wanted to grow it
under LEDs I learned eventually but that
thing foxtail like crazy the flowers
weren't good my hash concentrates
yielded less than 1% so I turned a whole
garden into concentrates and I might
have pulled like 30 grams for my head
and like lost maybe $15,000 right so
like I love terpenes right but I started
then looking towards that lemon rind
terpene and that strain called lemon
tree came out right and if you guys are
familiar with the lemon tree some say it
was renamed from some other things you
know but basically it had a very similar
lemon rind terpene profile I started
washing some of it maybe 1 to 3% said of
less than 1% so I was like sweet a
little bit higher right we got something
here so I'm still hunting this lemon
terpene profile this lemon rind and it
was until recently that we started
finding some of these lemon rind terpene
profiles that were actually becoming
viable you know that the farmer would
give to me that we're able to run that
were yielding enough so that we didn't
have to turn that lemon flour into dried
cured flour on the shelf and the hash
maker could actually get some and so I
want a big up man like Brandon third-gen
family and men like Shiloh for breeding
the lemon bean
I know they've gone separate ways since
then but they combine help to create
that string called the lemon bean and
we've been finding specific fee knows
that have that same lemon rind terpene
profile that are actually yielding so
that's one of my top top strains right
now is finding that terpene that
actually does do the work that we need
to do to keep it running through the lab
what's one of your favorite strains to
run right now because I smelled some
fire over I did a little tour of his
place earlier today and I know that they
were taking down a strain that smelled
ridiculous you can talk on that if you
want if you want to but what's your body
rating huh got a beta that Gary pains
for real though but what's your favorite
strange so far that you run over there
at that facility or in in general
because you've ran stuff in Europe
before Nia yeah in Spain I've been
running a lot of those widows I like
that that strain it deals really good at
least the the fennel that we have there
and if I talk about about flavors I like
GMO a lot strawberry one and I love it
and that papaya that it's been popular
for long now I love it bro true I love
that both flavors I like a lot crazy too
you know I love that I actually just
recently followed the the trace of where
that papaya came from because I was so
intrigued by it now you guys you guys
are aware that the papaya strain that's
been going around its won a lot of cups
have you guys seen that recently can I
see the show hands if you guys seen
papaya win a cup I was intrigued by this
because a lot of the strains are new you
know like and a lot of the strains have
been around for a long time I briefly
touched on lemon tree and there's a lot
of people that say the lemon tree has
been around for a long time I remember
smelling that profile in Oregon you know
back in the day but it really really got
popular out of Santa Cruz but this
papaya strain I think that a lot of the
seeds originally were bred by Nirvana am
I correct in saying that Nirvana seeds
out of Europe who is who originally bred
that papaya strain and then Oni seed co
actually got a phyno of papaya
from a facility that I help curate
actually I brought those seeds from
Nirvana from Amsterdam to Colorado and
just recently found out that Oni Seco
got that cut from my facility in
Colorado and has been continuing to
breed it into this couple winning
strains so it's been around for a long
time that stone actually came from your
backyard so you know it all starts
somewhere it's all in how you curate it
how you hold it what you're stabilizing
it with and genetics play a huge role in
what we're doing out there playing with
hash so I have a quick question for each
of you as starting source material do
you prefer indoor/outdoor do you like
both I like depth to be honest with you
indoors always looks great but it's a
little bit of it's like Fugazi weed
sometimes do you can't beat the power of
the Sun like when I first started coming
to California
my family's had farms up north and was
always like that we had this Sour Diesel
that way I like an aftertaste to it that
you could taste I mean for hours after
you smoked but you just can't beat the
flavor on light depth I mean this and
then as far as price-wise from a
business standpoint like it's much more
expensive to grow indoor
I prefer light up every time but light
depth over full Sun what about if it's
light depth during a time of year that
you're having to use a lot of
supplemental that stuff light I've made
a full Sun it can be tough sometimes can
be a little dirtier I just haven't had
in my experience you know hash makers
always good as just as only as good as
your starting material right if you
don't grow your own you're allowing a
lot of variables into there and
unfortunately I haven't I haven't had
been blessed to have a super clean clean
outdoor farm to produce like a like a
light DEP scenario and I you know I come
from when I first came to Cali and like
you said I saw my family had garbage
bags full of trim they were doing
nothing with we were never able to get
that full melt out of the outdoor but
lighten up every time
maybe the environmental control some of
that wind barriers with yeah with the
greenhouses I could always tell if your
farm was next to a road
sure for me I'd say I prefer indoor
fresh frozen I've had a lot of
experience with like outdoor fresh
frozen mostly mostly fresh frozen but
and I just seem to find a lot more
consistency with indoor and you know a
lot of it goes back to like the flower
rose and days and being able to you know
just take a small amount of weed and
press it and and see what a yield is
from there and it kind of gives you an
indicator on whether you know there's a
good resin content and if it's gonna
even be a contender for you know washing
so you know for me I really like indoor
fresh version and mostly because of the
consistency and variables and and also
like the Terp retention without like you
know depths I don't have a lot of
experience with to me I think that's
gonna be the next best thing
as far as all around but indoor you know
you don't really have much of the leaf
matter and it's just more of the turps
and less of the plant taste so that's
really like what's big for me it's hard
for me to talk about whether I prefer
full Sun prefer a greenhouse depth or
prefer indoor it's really about the
environment and whether you can control
that environment so I've actually seen
full Sun grows in desert areas like
Colorado that just happened to be in
this crazy valley where the Sun is
perfectly hitting the plants there's no
wind in this valley there's no dust and
dirt being picked up to hit these trees
and some of the best hash that I've ever
made in my life came from this full Sun
Valley where it was just protected the
environment was perfect the temperature
was right humidity was right they didn't
have a lot of wind because it was
protected by this valley and we got
amazing yields amazing terpene profiles
you know big up Steve down there in the
desert because it was like a one-man
thing you know it was crazy and that was
some of my favorite hash in the world
that I've ever had we do see a lot more
consistency in our in
or operations year and year but you know
it's all about environment and genetics
to me you know I can't really decide
whether I like Depp or outdoor or indoor
more at this point it's more so
controlling your environment control
your genetics and me that if you can
control all the details and you can grow
with the Sun you don't think that the
quality of the trichomes
because y ou is that's why I opened up
with that was my favorite girl that full
Sun that was fully controlled
it's a rare situation and not many
farmers get that availability to have
that valley where no wind's coming in
they've got the perfect Sun but yet I
don't know if the full Sun has been
replicated yet can't beat the power
people are trying every day I see a new
LED mark you know LED light on the
market each and every day I've seen
plenty of outdoor hash that you couldn't
even tell if it was indoor/outdoor
beautiful sometimes with hash I mean
like it's just trichomes and resin right
it's about yields and the the terpene
profile the flavor retention the like
your conditions will allow you to get
you know you guys are all touring
globally so kind of talk about like
different markets and what you're
thinking about for the next year I have
the benefit to go to a lot of places in
South America which is Chile yeah I've
got I got some experience in Colombia
and Uruguay actually not Chile but man
the cups everything competitions down
there different there's some motor oil
getting pressed down there in a lot of
cases that people are extremely happy to
have you know and it's it's interesting
to see you know a lot of the technology
and advancements that have happened in
California
going over to Europe and stuff creating
these higher and ice-water hashes and
live rosin is like pee it's still
foreign to even freeze any product in
South America you bring it down off the
mountain there's no freezing anything
you know so you working with what you
have and
it's interesting to see how far they
come some of the cups down they're
really interesting you get you know
there's no live rosin there's none but
some of the stuff they do with cured
resin you know this is where it all came
from what secured resin and that's what
you're seeing in a lot of South American
countries there's no live resins that
we're so accustomed to to here that's
the like the only thing I smoke is live
chirping profiles I'm really excited
after the show to check out some with
that dried material there but that's
what's really means everybody's working
with cured resin and they're you know
different strains to there's you know
you'd be surprised what a border keeps
out you know there's all you know
there's a lot of strains the papaya
making its way over from Europe but you
know South America is is really isolated
and with the legalities changing in
South America and in Colombia in
particular being poised to be a major
player in the cannabis market I'm really
curious to see the strains that they
produce for outdoor and the hashes that
they produce I think in a lot of senses
it'll be not as superior as the States
or Europe but I think that we're gonna
see some really interesting things come
out of there as far as mass productions
and and you know solvent less cartridges
and stuff which is not necessary to have
extremely great terpene profiles you
know it's more about the process but how
much they're able to do down there is
exciting and you know the u.s. never
stops innovating so one of the things I
wanted to touch on real quick is the the
vastness and maybe it might not be the
highest quality production but let's
just start from the seed what I've seen
happen in Morocco and in Spain in places
like Valencia where a lot of the
breeders are actually doing the bulk of
the breeding for the United States for
Europe is the seed selection is amazing
they're able to pop a lot more seeds in
Fino hunt to a capacity that I haven't
been able to see in the United States
and so that's one of the main advantages
that I've seen from my travels around
the world is the ability to Fino hunt on
a really really specific finite level
because you can pop that many more seeds
in places like valensa
in places like Morocco I'm excited to
see the this ice water hash market in
Europe as you were saying that's the
only thing Europe's ever smoked is ice
water hash and spliffs that'll be the
hugest market for ice water hash which
is my personal favorite of concentrates
its most unadulterated form of trike
heads or resin I think that's gonna be a
huge huge product as far as live and
everything as far as the market develops
really excited for Europe and Spain
Amsterdam we're seeing I mean we have a
lot of corrosion in Spain because as I
told you we have big high school tour
and there's a small amount of people
that they really love top-quality and
they are pushing and helping us to to be
able to do high quality products oh yeah
and also there's a lot of people now
from England that they are introducing
themselves to non-solvent extracts and
they have money and they are ready to
pay for high quality products so for
sure I think the community is gonna grow
in Spain and in Europe a quick question
in the traditional hash producing
countries are they still doing like dry
like traditional methods or they all
like rocking the washing machines and
that's a great question or a mix of the
two and it is there is there a future
for dry so the thing for us it's like
it's been really hard to try to make
them understand about quality because
they've been doing in Morocco for
example they've been doing hash for a
long time okay they've been doing tons
of money every season and when you go
there and you explain them that they
have to do it in a different way to do
it more clean they've realized that at
the end of the season they have 10
tonnes less than last year and they ask
you who is gonna pay for these ten tons
less so they don't really care about
quality they care about money
so of course hash from Morocco becomes
more more pure right now because
European people is going there to train
them but it's gonna be really hard for
them to change what they are doing for
hundreds and hundreds of years extremely
difficult but at the same time we have
seen
friends of ours bring freeze dryers to
Morocco yeah that's true so technology
is changing and they are accepting of
some new technology right and some of
the hash that I've seen come out of
Morocco in the last two years since the
freeze dry our technology is come into
play they're using generators to power
freeze dryers in the middle of Morocco
right like this is real okay
and some of the hash that I've seen is
fucking amazing bro we bring some of my
favorite house barracks freezer freezer
tracks to Morocco from Spain to do a
hygiene side because we might have to
stop the car I think we work at Mountain
Grove nothing so yeah it's crazy that
we're trying to today they've third they
are fighting it we've seen the same
thing in Jamaica when dabbing first
became popular and I went to Jamaica you
know they saw the torch and they were
like nah we don't do crack man no we
don't smoke out a pipe Rasta nom on my
smoked spliff peer spliff well I mean
you know and so the first time we
brought that that technology in that
culture to Jamaica they were scared you
know and I think that the email and
advents like that have have helped and
you know really the education that we
pushed have have helped as well and the
same thing that we're gonna be seeing in
Morocco we started showing them what we
can do with a freeze dryer and what we
can do with their material that they're
going what strains we can bring into
their growing technologies and we are
starting to see some slight changes in
that realm just displaying a little bit
what's going on in Morocco in Morocco
they have few problems the main one is
that they they are growing on the same
land for hundreds and hundreds of years
so the land the soil is dead totally
dead so they've been using chemical
products to feed the plants so that the
soil is dead and full of salts so the
heel of the plant is really low so the
quality becomes from the plan and if
your plans are shitty the Hajj is going
to be shitty
you can clean you can use freeze-dried
machines but when you grow a lamp you
cannot control all these small details
that we control here and as you know has
is something that
you're doing a small batches when you
try to do big batches the quality is
it's going down it's really hard to
control all the small details that you
have to control it that's my opinion so
I hope that everything is gonna change
in Morocco but it's gonna be really slow
really really slow it's happening slowly
all right we have to think about how you
move all these highs from Morocco to
Europe in all this process there's no
temperature your highs it's gonna be
fucked up because the temperature
because the time that you need to move
this hash for more over to Europe so
it's not that easy and Moroccan hash
traditionally is a dry sip - yeah you're
saying they're bringing freeze dryers
there they doing I sell a lot of ice
water hash and things there no moles
ashes has he mentioned I'm really
excited as Peter touched on as far as
dry seft
you know I mean ice water hash and
Rosen's have come a long way for sure
what we've kind of forgot about dry cept
guys like Cuban are making super full
melt type of dry seft which is an even
more unadulterated form of resin head
than even ice water hash to a sense and
with like static and this different
technology I think that that's gonna be
from a commercial production standpoint
which is like California is all about
you know can we scale it is like the
most popular question you get asked
driveshaft is like has enormous
potential yeah I'm like it III like I
like I like parts of it I don't like it
as much as ice water hash I don't quite
think it's there I don't know what but
it's exciting as far as like creating a
new time although as I think we know
that what it is a solvent will lose
something on the water but something
happened on the water process that the
quality that you have at the end I feel
that this bird and the dry season yeah
it's cleaner for sure and I feel like a
lot of this is the strains and the
variables because in reality I think to
get enough of the yield and to collect
those heads those heads have to harden
out when we're talking about dry so the
heads don't have to fully have to harden
when we're talking about water hash so I
think we're able to retain a lot of
those water soluble terpenes
when we're making water hash
compared to dry sift which those
terpenes are falling off in the air to
the environment because to enable to
make to make sift you do have to harden
out those heads now we've seen some some
frozen sift some fresh sift but I don't
know if the yields are gonna make it
past that hash maker that's that's about
you I've seen freeze-dried sift like
freeze-dried flowers and sift and I've
heard of people doing that I'm just not
too sure on the yield and stuff like
that this is what we wanted to get into
in the history of rosin we were gonna
explain what we've seen in the past and
we want it's up to you guys to keep
educating and keep trying these
different things play with some frozen
sift post some freeze dryer sift you
know keep playing so you guys were
mentioning the terpenes and yield are
very important to you when choosing
which strains to press but I was
wondering also how important in terms of
terpenes are the medical aspects or the
medical benefits of each strain going
into that and what they will be useful
for in terms of when deciding what to
make well a lot of this is unknown you
know and a lot of this is just us
playing with these different things and
doing R&amp;D because for the longest time
we haven't been able to do research on
paper this is still a federally illegal
product that we're talking about but we
actually do mention terpenes because I
personally highly believe that terpenes
have a huge benefit in the actual
interaction how they make you feel you
know I go back to the analogy of an
orange when you crack an orange
generally most people are gonna smile
when you open an orange and that's a
terpene that's present that's making you
feel that specific way I think there's a
lot of value in the terpenes combined
with the specific cannabinoids to make
you feel a certain way or help or
benefit a specific effect do you guys
want to touch on some of the things you
guys have witnessed yeah you know THC
cannabis is actually classified as like
a psychedelic right and it does have
psychedelic qualities
and anybody who's experienced with
psychedelics you're set in setting right
and how you experience the power of THC
is pure is is very much dictated on your
mindset going into it and a little bit
of some what aromatherapy and and how
that strains smelled you just like you
like certain foods that make you happy
and certain foods don't the terpenes
have a big aspect on your set and
setting on creating a positive
experience to start where the
psychoactive components of cannabis
start to affect you you're you're in a
better place subconsciously almost yeah
no I agree I mean I think I mean the way
I look at it is THC is the the road and
terpenes are the driver you know so and
you know we're all not gonna feel the
same off of each strain or the terpene
profiles but I think it's it's like Ben
was saying it really does have a lot to
do with your mindset going into it you
know and just you know your overall
feeling you know I think it's just we're
all gonna find what strains we like in
the way we feel and you know it's
getting to a point where with with the
extraction and stuff you know we're
separating the terpenes from the THC so
you know now we're able to concentrate
the terpene profiles and the THC
profiles so you know it's definitely
changing and I think that's gonna be a
lot of R&amp;D and observation with you know
us trying it and figuring out you know
how we like it like for me for instance
you know when we remove the terpenes and
you just have THCA
I had fun with it you know I dabbed it
I'm not a big fan of it I don't really
like the way it makes me feel you know I
get really high yeah but I just don't
like the overall high from it you know
but you know if I do a hit up THC a and
then I do like a nice herpe dab maybe
two and it's definitely you know it's
it's way more relaxing and it's just
more of a direction you know rather than
an anxiety or you know just stuck in
your mind thinking crap you don't want
her you know I think terpenes give you a
feeling you know you when you want to
relax you buy things with lavender and
you know like it's it's it's Terps
definitely are they dictate the way we
feel and I think THC just boosts us up
there so a combination of all of those
cannabinoids is really important one
more thing to briefly touch on the
medicinal aspect and why we all talk
about terpenes so much is a good example
is most of these strains that we're
finding extremely high in CBD aka
strains that are classified as hemp or
drug variety hemp strains like ac/dc
strains like Harlequin strains like the
cherry or cherry wine and all these
cherry crosses that we're seeing now in
the CBD world canna tonic
those strains all have a very high beta
Carol awfully no file that's the terpene
that's extremely present in that series
of strains in all these CBD strains
we're seeing now we're starting to see a
fused outliers we're seeing the bubba
pushes that are testing is hemp which in
reality hemp is just anything that's 0.3
THC and less or less THC that's what's
being classified as hemp but what we're
seeing in most of these heme strains
like I said there are outliers we are
finding CBD and strains that don't have
this terpene profile but for the longest
time those strains had that cherry or
that cherry cough syrup flavor which was
associated with bethe Kerala flame beta
care Laughlin is also the smell you're
finding in anise and black pepper and
some black pepper if you look in the
history and what those things can do
those smells those the terpenes that
come from an ism black pepper are
they're good for anti-inflammation the
same thing that we're seeing CBD is good
for so I think that there's a lot of
analogies and things that we're gonna
find and amazing combinations between
the terpenes and their counterplay
cannabinoids that do some amazing things
for the medicinal aspect I was going to
say I think that cherry taste is the CBD
in my opinion I got to agree with that
actually you know when you isolated like
I played around with isolated CBT too
and smoking and
and just find that heavy cherry taste
with it I think that's where the the
name was coined 100% yeah what's that
terpene I don't think there's terpenes
at that point yeah it tastes like cherry
that out that exhale you taste a
predominant cherry I still think that
it's terpenes that are left in there
what else provides a flavor because I
don't think a molecule is gonna have a
flavor at that point but I could be
wrong you know it's just what I've
noticed over over generations whenever
I've tried CBD when we extracted CBD
from Ryan Laughlin farm in Colorado we
got that same flavor and what I've been
seeing in history is that flavor is
associated with you know that black
pepper anise type flavor the anise is
very cherry like that black pepper anise
beta-carotene which has been known for
anti-inflammation I just think that
there's going to be a lot of
correlations between the terpenes and
the cannabinoids and that's what we're
gonna be fine-tuning as we move into the
future and what rosin holds for us
there's a few then out there nice but
it's definitely not as exciting that's
for sure we've done some awesome
demonstrations that appear like we're
running cannabis THC heavy strains we're
washing it it's turning out to be a pure
gold color we're pressing it live we did
one at the endo Expo that people were
like how are you guys running weed out
here you know like live you know it's
it's hemp however said have I think
we're actually gonna be doing one
together at the dabba-doo around Miami
I'm doing some things out there with
some hemp that looks like cannabis as
I'm saying there's a lot of cush
varieties coming out that are washing
well it's smell amazing that smelled
like your bubba kush that you're seeing
at the dispensary shelf so there's
things changing everyday I'm excited
it's late but I to start soon I think to
get specific with that question with the
tens of thousands of acres of flavorful
smelling hemp farm flour do you think
there's gonna be a market for just like
there's a market for smokeable flour
some farmers are growing for those
varieties some
farmers are still running a bunch of
seed crops trying to figure it out but I
think it's definitely going towards
running for specific allocations whether
you're growing for smokeable varieties
where they're growing for topical or
they're growing for extraction purposes
well also I mean talk about allocations
when you have a lot of hemp farms out
there you're talking a KERS and acres
and acres of cannabis at the end of the
day hemp is cannabis right a hard time
calling it HAP it's the same thing just
no THC you like Nick said but who's
gonna have I mean you have 20 acres of
hemp who wants to freeze all of that you
know what I mean they're dried in barns
and and and dried with much less care
than THC is so to get high-quality
solvent less at the end of the day is a
little bit harder you can save part of
that crop if you wanted to to make a
live rosin CBD and I'm sure it would
come out amazing but the amount of
people doing that are very very minimal
if anybody I hope to see that in the
future and I think we I think we
absolutely will again as the markets
tend to mature we will see that but
right now I don't know if anybody's
doing that thanks for changing because
we went from growing average of 7% CBD
hemp crops when AG first certified hemp
facilities in Colorado and now we're
Fino selecting for putting clones out
and putting seeds out of over 20 30 %
CBD crops and those are going out there
to produce CBD isolate which is
concentrate you know and CBD distillate
so I think it's definitely out there now
we're seeing the smokeable varieties
people pulling public push and the cush
varieties coming out of Southern Oregon
right now are pretty spectacular so just
to bring it back like Ben said hemp is
cannabis it's just testing below 0.3
percent THC people are breeding now for
trichome production of CBD we're
breeding for THC production since
hundreds of years ago right really going
after it since what the 50s or 60s
that's just starting to happen now with
CBD so I mean and give it five ten years
we'll see some really cool stuff we
almost lost CBD because people are like
oh this stuff's not getting me high
we're not gonna get that one you know so
we almost lost it
for regulation so we do have to give
thanks to regulation and some
over-regulation for allowing us to test
all these products we literally almost
lost CBD because lack of testing and
lack of the ability to you know
protected while testing so so I kind of
have a two-part question and you kind of
touched on it earlier how important are
the smoking devices consumption devices
to the expansion of your market and
bringing new people in to enjoy these
types of concentrates nude a Briggs ear
IG's opening up the market to people how
important is that and for each one of
you do you have a device that you feel
perfectly expresses the concentrate the
experience for you are there devices
that are inferior what is the best
method for each one of you maybe I'm not
the best to us to answer that question
because I mixed with tobacco I've been
trying to find another way to smoke
without tobacco probably because that
heat that comes from the tobacco I don't
quit and I like that I don't smoke
cigarettes I just smoke tobacco with my
joints but I've been trying a lot of
device and finally the only one that I
like is the puff copic in my opinion it
works really good I used to smoke rose
in on on the Pascoe Peaks and I'm not
gonna join and I think that that's my
favorite I love hearing that I love
hearing that you know like I mentioned
one of the scariest things about
promoting dabs when they first came to
the industry into the community to the
world was the torch you know in reality
in explaining to a lot of folks we are
in a different generation that this
torch is for healthy purposes
you know inhaling something via
vaporization rather than combusting it
there were a lot of things that it were
really really hard to explain so I do
agree with that
I believe that devices like the puff
coke peak and there's so many other
devices coming out now the cart GPN just
put out a new device there's a ton of
electronic dabbing devices that are
coming out to market that are a lot
safer than utilizing a torch for dabbing
and that are a lot easier to travel with
a lot more portable much more
approachable I've taken to answer your
question I prefer a rig a quartz nail
and a torch every time there's nothing
really that you you really cannot to
implicate that what I actually think one
of the coolest tools and I wasn't into
it at first is the turbo meter that came
out to measure the actual temperature of
the nail I took it
dab dude a little while ago that was
really like never do it without that now
because you get the exact time but I
think one of the most instrumental
things and making dabbing more
approachable
I've dabbed with my grandmother on the
electrical devices you know who's she's
almost 80 years old she like sweet but
well I only ever smoke joints and I get
to tell her you know the new
appreciation you know we all have for
for hash and rosin now which has come I
mean many you know it's come a long way
let's say since her time was smoking ash
but a puffs go or a Carta you know for
to put that in front of her was so much
more approachable and to take this
generation who you know sees a torsion
thinks you know really hardcore drugs
that's really been the biggest
revelation and leap in the industry but
I don't think that as far as flavor wise
and what we're searching for on extracts
particularly solvent this is is it's not
matched with a nail and a torch I want
to touch on that real quick just because
he mentioned something and you mentioned
something that's it's been coming up a
lot recently you mentioned that your
favorite thing is a torch with a timer
and for me this whole time earthing has
been interesting because all nails are
different all environments are different
so you take that same nail in your same
dag rib that you're normally torching at
minute and 20 seconds but you take it
outside in your backyard and that time
were completely changes right minute 20
to 50 seconds right so so there's been
some variables there that have confused
me a little bit what you just mentioned
this new device this Terp timer turbo
motor it actually puts a laser on your
nail itself and gives you a recoil to it
laser touches a straight up coil to it
to get used to have to be skilled but
now there's a new one out there that's
actually I think that can talk about
these things because there are a lot of
variables when it comes to this and you
know he mentioned the puff Co peak it's
all personal preference for me and
judging a lot of these cups I couldn't
deal with the variables of the timers I
mean I took the punch because I was able
to put it on a very specific temperature
each and every time yeah yeah
the consistency so that I was able to
give an even platform to everything that
I was judging was was key to me now I'm
not saying that it was the best dab you
know so these guys might actually have
more experience with you know their
favorite favorite dad but I think it can
be subjective I think for judging I mean
most people are probably just gonna have
access to a torch and a nail you know so
I think that's where most people are
going to experience it you know like a
peaks great I love a peak don't get me
wrong like on the go I'd still rather
have a torch in it you know with me but
a peak is great you know for travels or
things you know and it's just just
convenient like Ben was saying you know
to approach like my father-in-law with
that you know doesn't really smoke but
we're at a wedding
hey he's interested it looks cool hit it
boom he hits it so it's like you know
the experience is that I've come across
what the peak is great because of how
sleek it is it takes away the whole
stigma of a torch and well what are you
doing smoking crack like it's it's
definitely a whole better approach but I
think being at home you know we all
figure out our ways you know
we got our glass for our beer a specific
glass we got our specific rig we got our
you know the time that we hit it at and
and that's also gonna change there's so
many variables cuz if you're doing a fad
dab obviously you're gonna go in a
little bit hotter you know so there's a
like area will solve that but it's just
being a connoisseur about it you know if
you love it love it you know I love it
to the fullest and I love it the way you
love it I've seen I've seen your judge
comes rolling hash into spliffs out of
my what the hell but it's it's to
experience taste like the actual resin
in a bong and there they use that as
their platform you know they can
actually they can't taste it they just
taste the weed some people need a blunt
they need to back on the outside it's
weird to taste the weed inside and I
don't condone it you know I don't
condone utilizing the tobacco but for
some reason it's like that standard you
know for them it might be the taste of
the titanium nail or the torch maybe a
little bit of the butane from the torch
you know has that standard effect you
know it tastes like that every time you
know I'm not saying that's the reason by
any means but I think it's just a
subjective answer I'm loving a lot of
the handheld stuff I feel like one of
the first things that puff coke came out
the really revolutionized things was
their puff coke Plus which was the first
ceramic insert portable pen that you
could load your own you know it wasn't a
cartridge where you had to rely on going
to your dispensary to purchase that
cartridge you could make your hash at
your home you can make sure make your
oil load it into that puff co+ I think
that was a really cool referred over the
really pretty cool one as well so lots
of devices out there from your hash
spliff to the peak to the dabber with
the nail and the torch if that answers
your question sir
hey I was just wondering if you guys had
heard of CBG of course the the mother of
all cannabinoids that's what every other
commie Neustadt every every cannabinoid
for the most part that we see THC CBG
starts as I mean CBD or THC starts as
CPG and once the plant matures turns
into the other cannabinoids that we
value so much so where is that are you
seeing that if you taken a plant down
early and just seen CBG if you cut a
plant early you'll still see like the
ratio of THC that you have but the if
you cut it early you will see extremely
high levels of CBG my experience we had
we cut a harvest early at a facility in
Connecticut
for various reasons and it had
predominantly CB gene we got extremely
high yields from our extraction and I
was think we were seeing like 50% CBG in
there but this was a like of just a
almost a vegetative plant at that point
so will the CBD you know as it oxidizes
will it basically transform or cross
over to whatever it's supposed to like
for instance you know if THC a start
says CB GA does CB GA at some point
oxidize whether it's in concentrate for
him because you know like THC a will
degrade to THC and then THC degrades the
CB n so like this CB g will do the same
word I would assume so but we never had
it around long enough to do that we've
always been infused it and put it out to
market into topicals I think capsules
and different and different things like
that from I remember some research that
we were that we were into at the time CB
g was supposed to be a great cannabinoid
for cancer patients and stuff like that
so we pushed it out in capsules and
stuff like that so we didn't have the
time to let it sit around or try to
decarboxylate it into the cannabinoids
that follow i personally don't have a
nice experience with it
why do you ask the question why is it
three times more expensive expect more
expensive than what it's three times
falsified already I don't have a lot of
knowledge on it so it's going for ten to
fifteen thousand a liter in Oregon
versus that might be some hype because
in all honesty I think the reason oh
you're seeing a lot of CBG stuff might
possibly do be due to what Ben saying is
we're seeing higher concentration of it
if you pull early Organa had a huge
freezing issue this year a lot of water
you know and a lot of those farmers
pulled early and they had to do
something with that product I was seeing
a lot of CBG distillate CBG kilos on the
market in my forums actually just in the
last three months and that might be the
reason there might be trying to create a
market for it I mean CBG in my opinion
is easy to get
I mean it's hype like who's creating CBG
nobody wants CPG they want THC or CBD so
CBG just because it's like what'swhat's
that acronym let me get some of that you
know THC V is super expensive too has a
little bit more value in my opinion but
CBG is I mean everywhere cut a plant
early you got CPG it's easy to get but
you know there's a lot there's a lot
that we don't know about all of these
cannabinoids their interactions with
other cannabinoids their interactions
with the terpenes so really you know I
think that it's all gonna have to do
with more testing more education freeing
up the plan on a federal level to really
really dig into these you know the
entourage effect really the interaction
of the different cannabinoids with the
different terpenes I personally don't
know enough about CBG and its effects
alone to give an answer on that one
thank you
there it has anti-inflammatory
properties anti-inflammatory properties
yeah okay okay anyone have a comment
over there
what about the like whistler tech kind
of closed systems that they're coming
out for bubble hashing i do i was i was
gonna ask you about this to other kind
of projects along those lines and what
that might do to just like the
production of hash maker i think that we
cannot be run in a lab that we have
equipment really expensive and be using
plastic bubble machines so since I found
that that company's creating a big
machine stainless steel with high grade
medical grade everything proper I
thought that that was the Machine I had
to say that the price is two hundred
fifty thousand that is important to know
nobody kind of for there's quarter
million dollars exactly oh and I know
that part Eddie was actually gone and
visited the facility right yeah you've
gone and seen the machine yeah what'd
you guys get to wash there how was the
we do it in a random facility that they
just bought the machine because the
wizard company if they don't have a way
to show you how the machine works if
they don't buy width so they don't buy
width they do machine so every time that
they sell one machine they use that
client to show to other clients how the
machine works on that facility the
people working on the lab they was just
people from lab not from hashas world
you know so they don't know they don't
know nothing about how they was just
running fresh frozen plants but I don't
know why the quality became really low
so I'm not really sure if that machine
is it's been created to do formal hash
it's been created to do massive
production probably with have always
always weighed but not to do like formal
it's not for that so I love the question
though and it's something that a lot of
us have been working on for a long time
there are a few units out there that are
100% stainless steel and there's been
other companies discussing it the I I do
see a lot of value in the fully closed
loop version you know having stainless
steel as your agitation but I still to
this day have not seen anybody bring it
to fruition and have the agitation
coupled with the separation in one unit
you know bubble bags ice water
extraction bags essential bags ice
extract bags bolt bags you name it the
pollinator bags you know these bags have
been around for a long time and it's
what we use coupled with whatever
agitation we're using whether we use in
hand agitation with wooden doors or
paddles whether we're utilizing a
washing machine I said it was mentioning
these plastic washing machines that have
been used in our little space and
industry for the last 10 years or
whether using one of the brand new
Brutus stainless steel barrels from pure
penetration there is a huge need right
now to couple that agitation whatever it
may be whether it's magnetic or
electronic or mechanical agitation with
separation because in reality when we
first went to states like Nevada and
talk to them about water extraction bags
they were not for it the health
department didn't like it there were a
lot of nose that came with reusing nylon
bags over and over again so as we move
forward there is a huge need for some
type of closed-loop unit I for one have
been working on a unit I've got five
seven prototypes at this point still
haven't found the exact thing that I'm
looking for I'm flying up next week to a
place that we're working on but I hope
to be another final one but I think a
lot of us are working on it Ben looks
like he's itching to talk about his
newest product coming out of rosin tech
products but you know there's a lot of
people working on this and to be honest
whoever comes out with it first I'm
gonna support me to like say for sure
I'm excited for it
things that I think all of us are like
drooling to get you know agitation is
one thing collection is total something
totally different I think with Whistler
tech and a lot of the other machines
I've seen or trying to utilize the
stainless steel mesh is utilizing a
totally straight flat stainless steel
and to collect the trichomes off that
it's not as easy as like a bag a bag is
easy to to put a spoon in there and
scoop it out nice and generally and not
disturb those heads where if you try to
collect it from a straight up stainless
steel flat screen you're just pushing
smashing heads these things that we've
done delicate harvest with to put all
this energy to grow and they're just
smashing them against the stainless
steel screen is quite an issue so I mean
not that we you know have anything to
announce but you know it's I'm excited
to see you know and I don't know where
you have been playing with a lot of
people trying for these columns that the
shaker columns you know they're used to
separate paint or used to separate
different settlement types and sizes
these shaker columns for years for dry
sift but Eddie you mentioned that you
know even with those units we've seen a
lot more raw or crude end products that
then have to be cleaned further so there
is value to getting a lot of a crude
product and then cleaning further down
the line and I think we're all going
towards that same goal of finding a
closed loop unit that doesn't just
produce crude but produce the craft that
we're looking for I think there's always
gonna be there's always gonna be a
market for handmade ash and I really
don't think that handmade hashes is
going anywhere I think that even with
these developments of larger machines
whether it be even the marketing of
handmade hash it's always gonna be
slightly higher quality I think how can
you get I made handmade hash that
smelled like mildew and was black and
pliable that about commander casinos so
you know there is value to changing up
what we've known from the past and you
know being open to what's coming in the
future for sure I think I think the
Whistler tech I mean the closed-loop
systems are gonna be great for rosin
extraction for sure I mean especially if
we're going for like full-spectrum and
you know I think it's gonna take a lot
of us getting in there
really testing these machines and and
tweaking them and putting our little
techniques and really understanding what
it's doing and what we can do to change
it and adjust it you know like any
machines just a base you know but then
you start putting the people who don't
know what to tweak and what to add you
know add this do this my feeling when I
was there it was that that they are just
people that they they do machines they
don't do hash so there's few points that
they do they don't understand how they
have to do it because they don't do hash
so they need people like us going there
and telling them a that machine is good
but you have to change these and that or
I need these or that on your machine so
we have to like do it together there's
there's a lot of chemistry going into it
whereas chemistry and hash making are
two different things in my opinion were
separating heads were mechanically
separating oil and a lot of people
developing these products are from a
chemistry background was a science
background that is extremely valuable
but doesn't always translate it's really
hard to say that there's a science to
extraction because in reality you make a
rosin press for example where you can
create you know a certain pressure for a
certain amount of time at a certain
temperature and right and you call it
Sour Diesel so right you you think that
you're coming into your lab and you're
like okay perfect I got a bunch of Sour
Diesel I'm gonna press the button that
says Sour Diesel and everything's gonna
be good because it's all programmed for
the Sour Diesel temperature and pressure
and everything else but not all Sour
Diesel is the same you know and not all
rounds of Sour Diesel the same maybe
it's the same phenotype from the same
grow but this round it was you know that
he had too much magnesium or too much
fossil load or something he added to
that round and the pressure and the
temperature changes up so it's really
really hard to just say that you know
you're gonna press one button and you're
gonna be good to go
cannabis is a different plant and it has
a lot of variables associated with it
I think I think it really matters I
think we can all agree that us up here I
have a true passion for it I think that
part of what makes like a hash maker
or somebody is is to be able to define
what is a good product what is the real
Sour Diesel cut what is you know a good
development of that cut you know what I
mean there's different hues different
levels to the terpenes that you can hit
and a little bit comes with the with
experience and knowing what a good
cannabis product is or hash or a good
strain a good profile definitely
definitely I agree for sure I've been
doing highs for a long time and I've
been losing money a lot bro just trying
to find the best product so if you have
passion on doing high as you are not
doing hydro wrong we're all consumers
first right like the passion is what
keeps us dedicated and pushing forward
in innovation and it's what so why we've
evolved so quickly as Saul says you know
all of us on stage want to smoke I
actually I actually loved hearing Nick
you and Phil talk about the origins of
hash you know I still I still nerd out
on that on that stuff where you don't
get to you don't forget to hear to guys
like Phillip Nick you know talk about
you know putting it to an email you know
and doing a five times that's you know
that's cool stuff and I think that you
know a lot of us really appreciate and
nerd out on those types of stories the
old genetic stories and the beef in the
cannabis industry is like it's the juice
this is real oral tradition this is what
happened now a lot of this is written
down but we're gonna tell it to you
straight here today give thanks for
coming out
[Applause]