[Music]
we're live rosin history greetings
greetings and welcome to the town house
here in Venice give thanks to bud gasm
over here for bringing us all together
my name is Nick Atia of essential
extracts I'm joined by Phil Salazar of
soil grown solvent list we got some
other family over here give thanks to
everyone who's shown up and come out
shown support and is here to talk to
about the history of rosin we wanted to
provide a little education and throw it
back to some of the people that have
been involved since day one that have
got us to where we're at today so
Phillip did you want to say a little
something about yourself before we get
started I'm just here to talk about the
history of rosin I'm super excited about
it I like where it's gone where it
started and where we're pushing towards
so I'm just stoked to talk about it I
don't well I'm gonna break into it I
love giving credit where credit's due
and I'm extremely blessed to have been
here from basically day one from when
this term was coined basically so a lot
of this started before Instagram and
before Facebook we had a lot of
underground forums and the forums were
where a lot of us growers and hash
makers gained a lot of our knowledge so
there was this gentleman named
confession compassion Co mph a s o n I
believe yes h o n but I also you know
his his name is out there freely his
name is chadwick Bastardo and i really
like to give credit to this gentleman
because back in the day there were a few
forums that that I was on along with
this gentleman compassion and he was
really the one who started using this
term the term rosin has actually been
around for centuries it's been around
for a long time in the adhesive and in
that world the adhesive world just for a
gummy substance
you know sermons to like violins yeah
rosin that term has been around for a
long time it really was brought into the
cannabis industry when confession
started utilizing a stainless steel bowl
with the stainless steel spoon heating
up that bowl heating up that spoon and
literally mechanically pressing his
bubble hash into that bowl and stirring
it around and he started noticing this
ring of oil on the outside of that
bubble hash and he was like huh that's
interesting there's this separation and
so he started pulling that ring of oil
with his dab or tool off of there and
back then it was knife hits and he
started taking that oil off and taking
knife hits and noticing that there was a
lot less residue and back then the term
full melt clear dome FM CD was a very
popular term for when we got bubble hash
or water hash so good and so clean that
it would bubble up and make these clear
domes and basically burn to very little
if not no residue
it wasn't until Chadwick compassion
actually started playing with this
technology of utilizing hot stainless
steel instruments and mechanically
separating the oils from the waxes that
he took this knife hit saw these clear
domes and saw zero residue and I really
want to say that that's where rosin
started but at that time there was no
way to make that technology
commercialized or scalable you know a
lot of people in this industry talked
about how is it scalable how do you
scale this technology and that's where a
lot of things are going and so you know
back then it was the hash makers treat
rosin started spreading that term you
know this is back I want to say 2005
maybe 2007 2007 I'm really bad with the
actual date but this is pre dabbing you
know so back then it was the hash maker
that got to keep that ring of oil for
themselves you know rosin really wasn't
able to get out to the masses until
people like this gentleman came along
and I want to talk and I want him to
talk to you guys about
what really pushed rosin to be scalable
initially what was the term that you
came up with and what were you doing
well I think I called it like solving
this hash sha sha
something like that but the way it
started I was just really really into
making hash and you know all my melts
and stuff and smoking it and then like
it got to a point where I ran solo on
what I had I didn't have any more of my
harvest and I got solo on my melts I was
like literally trying to smoke like four
star three-and-a-half star like
low-quality melt hash so and I have to
give thanks to you because I remember
seeing a tip on your page back then
where I would take Milo my like my
low-grade melts and put them between
parchment I'd use a hair straightener
just to thin it out and it actually
helped I was able to get a better dab
off low quality hash and you know I got
tired of that and so I'm trying to
remember like exactly but
fast-forwarding you know past like
flattening my hash out and like just
dabbing it like that getting to the
point where I'm running out of my dabs
so something went off in my head I
remember just thinking like back okay
okay
going back again okay I remember I
messed up doing that I pressed it too
hard not in the hair straightener and I
see it would be real shiny on the
outside and dry in the middle and I
wouldn't think anything of it I'd fold
it up do it again phone I used to do
that like I'd fold it up like three
times so it'd be nice and like
homogenized a nice good melt off of a
low-quality hash you know what I mean
the best you'd get off of it so light
bulb goes off in my head I'm thinking
back I remember that shininess I
remember the dry so I didn't have a hair
straightener laying there this is the
longest story possible of it but didn't
have a hair straightener laying there so
I actually took a chunk of hash between
a piece of parchment shoved it up
against the email with my finger and I'd
try not to burn myself or burn the paper
on the side of the coil and sure enough
I pulled it off and there was oil like I
was hoping that would happen very little
not enough to dab so I kept doing it
doing it doing it took me like five ten
minutes
to get one dab hit it and sure enough my
father-in-law family was there nothing
it melted to nothing and it we were just
amazed so from there it would that's
where it started that's where the Hat I
would say that's where the rosin for me
started you know it started by a mistake
that came back to me later on as an idea
and I took it from there you know and so
I was I was pressing hash so it all
started with hash for me no screen
screen wasn't any part of it at all so I
was making low quality rosin still could
still small contaminants in it for the
most part it melted to nothing and so I
ran out of all my hash and we got to a
point you know we're just smoking bud so
Bing light bulb and I took a bud and I
did the same oh and actually when I was
pressing the hash my wife had come out
and she brought me a hair straightener
cuz I had been using her hair curler and
so she swapped that out for me so boom I
get back to the out of the hash now I'm
at the weed I pressed a but I think it's
like 400 degrees super freakin hot so I
pressed it on the parchment and crazy
amount of oil came out of it like three
of us got a dab off of like a little
half gram bud so we were just amazed and
they just went non-stop from there like
nights of just pressing out eighths
taking like five six hours just to press
out an eighth on a hair straightener and
that's where it took off and really I
think that's where are all of our light
bulbs turned on because we're like
that's where it's scalable this guy is
pressing flowers you know because before
we you know us hash makers we didn't
want to press the best-quality hash you
know we've we got amazing quality hash
and we wanted to keep it as that you
know we might have started playing with
a hair straightener to press it so that
we could dab it but we weren't anywhere
in the mindset of actually removing that
waxy cuticle until I feel like flour
rosin came about in that term I really
want to give credit to Phil over here
because I think that's what changed game
for a lot of people especially on the
mast level because kids all over the
world had flour it was a lot harder for
them to come by amazing water hash but
they had flour and they had a hair
straightener and that's what change game
at that time is when I really believe
we're pushing
towards you know safe extraction you
know everybody wanted to make oil we're
all dabbers you know and when at a time
when when solvent list was scarce and
when you'd get hash and it wouldn't melt
it's just a disappointment it was hard
to come by six star five star even good
hash to even know what it was so I lost
my thought that hash split right before
[Music]
but yeah going back to it you know we
came from somewhere and I'm just gonna
give you guys a little recap right now
we came from somewhere where we were
watching forums of this guy named
compassion taking bubble hash and
pushing it on some stainless steel bowl
to then playing with hair straighteners
to then pressing flour itself into flour
rosin and now look look where we've come
you know there's been so many different
advances in technology since then this
man helped put out one of the very first
rosin presses on the market there's been
so many other rosin presses since and
the technology just keeps changing and
evolving and you know it's it's I think
it's thanks to the education that we
started the open forum education style
that can fashion was pushing it on
originally that we've continued that
trend of really pushing education to our
peers to our community and it just
continues to evolve into something that
I had never even imagined I grew up
making bubble hash in my uncle's barn in
a hot barn and now we're actually
separating THC their THC a you know on a
scientific level really we're seeing
99.9% THC a without the use of any
chemical solvent so it's really really
really come a long way pickup everyone
that's involved in that movement we can
talk about you know where it's going now
so are you guys familiar with some of
the new consistencies that we're seeing
out there
how many show hands out there in the
crowd how many of you guys have tried
rosin just rosin alright so when we
first started making rosin was really
when the consistency of earwax was
popular in the BHO world so I'm gonna
bring it back to like
2008/2009 and Pho had really just hit
the market
pho was called earwax back then so as us
hash makers started to make water hash
on a more controlled level a higher
level we wanted to mimic what was
happening in the BHO world so this is
pre rosin but we started making hash on
a higher level where the hash was coming
out gold rather than brown and it was
coming out smelling really like the
flour that it was come from because we
were controlling the variables of the
water the temperature of the water our
environment that we were making the hash
in and that starting material we started
really really paying attention to the
starting material rather than using
stuff at uncle's farm that had been
sitting on the side of the road that he
didn't want on his property because that
was more weight on his property that's
what we were making bubble hash out of
initially up in Mendocino Humboldt
County we started making bubble hash out
of close trim and not just the close
term mixed with all the fan leaf and
everything else they were throwing away
then we started making water hash out of
fresh frozen material you know I think
2008-2009 was when I first did my first
wash with fresh frozen material and at
this point we're making water hash with
whole plant fresh frozen material later
on we're gonna talk about some of the
amazing magicians in the crowd over here
that can make fire with dry trim it's
been sitting around but right now you
know the pinnacle of water hash is using
whole plant fresh frozen I'm jumping
around a little bit here but throw it
back to that 2008-2009 generation when
earwax was popular we start learning a
little bit more and then chatter becomes
extremely popular 2009 Colorado
California 2010 and Shatter is the
consistency so we started wanting to
recreate that consistency of shatter so
we started heating up our hair
straighteners a little bit hotter
you know pressing in between parchment
paper just our water hash at a higher
temperature to create more stability
more of a clear see-through shatter
consistency and I think that's another
one of the variables that pushed us as
hash makers to find out what rosin was
we wanted more stability we're trying to
create these consist
we were seeing in the BHO world but we
weren't seeing as much stability if you
just press hash at you know 200 250
degrees you're gonna see it turn into
shatter but eventually you're gonna see
it start to degrade turn darker butter
up some of those issues and it wasn't
until rosin came along and rosin the
actual art of rosin is removing the rest
of that waxy cuticle if you look at
cannabis cannabis you know is a plant
that has a lot of these shiny trichomes
on the outside the crystals if you will
all plants have different structures of
these crystals and as hash makers and
specifically rosin makers we're learning
about this structure even more with
every strain that we run some strains
have that longer stalk with a very small
head with a thick waxy cuticle and they
may not run as well in water hash they
may not press as well in rosin you start
seeing some strains that have a thick
stalk in a really bulbous head with a
thin waxy cuticle and you're seeing them
run better in water hash you're seeing
the waxy cuticle effect the rosin less
and you're seeing higher yields higher
potencies and so you know moving forward
we started seeing these different
consistencies like shatter like the ear
wax and then as we move we started
seeing this sauce consistency in the
butane world where we were seeing a
layer of terpenes on the outside and
it's pushed us rosin makers to continue
this movement and to continue trying to
create a higher echelon for our industry
by pushing education and I think we've
taught each other at this point that we
can now separate THC a via different
temperatures and different pressures to
pull those terpenes and pull those the
THC a separate that and now as we see
these saucy and jammy consistencies in
the BHO world we've been playing with
pressure just like butane hash oil is
utilizing these columns
basically to pull pressure and then keep
the butane and the trichomes under
pressure creating separation we're now
seeing the same thing in the solvent
list world some are calling it rosin jam
some are calling it solvent list sauce
but we're seeing these consistencies now
via
ultimately means and rosin so rosin
history just continues as we see
different consistencies as we see I feel
like as we see now hydrocarbon guys
starting to separate delta-9 and CBG and
THC v that's all with pressure and
columns and temperature and so I think
as we continue that might be some of
what we see in the future as far as what
rosin can really do you don't need a
column
you don't need heavy chemicals you don't
need to possibly bro up blow up your
neighbor's house we're seeing all of
these different consistencies via
solving this means
thanks to rosin through the use of heat
pressure and force right on I think that
really kind of concludes it do we have
any questions from the audience or
anything else anybody think that rosin
is going in another direction anybody
disagree what what we talked about as
far as the history of rosin it's a trip
how far we've come really this started
what 10 12 years ago and now it's on the
commercial market heavy I just actually
came from cookies in Maywood and there
was a ton of different rosin brands on
the shelf and it was amazing to see it
started 10 years ago but I'd say
realistically it took off about five
years ago when when the masses started
to learn and do it themselves at home
and the more Minds that are able to
focus and work on it and share the
knowledge that they find that's why I
think that's why we've quickly evolved
this technique you know compared to has
been around forever and it's taken so
long to get to where it is but you know
with the butane extraction and with
everybody hands-on trying to do you know
learn two new techniques and do the next
best thing with solvent lists or with
rosin I think that's where we're
breaking through and and I think you're
right we're gonna find you know all
these different components we're going
to be able to separate you know we're
already at the point where we're
separating THC and fats and terpenes so
I think we're there it's pretty crazy to
see some of the hydrocarbon companies
switching over to solving this you know
that's that's where I feel like that's
when we made it you know like this
education really did something we got
the guys that have been known for making
butane making solvent list now that's
one of the cool things you know as of
January 1st 2019
a lot of the new regulations came into
California and it was very difficult to
just set up a closed-loop system get the
fire department out there go through all
those regulations people are able to get
to the end goal of a concentrate and a
nice healthy alternative right one
regulations hit and some of the first
companies to come to shelf were rosin
companies or solving those companies
because it was a little bit easier to
get manufacturing going licensing for
type six via type seven was a little bit
easier to push through she didn't have
to deal with the fire burn nearly as
much still do but a lot of factors have
really really changed game I feel like
when we started putting solvent list
products or water hash products on the
shelves in Colorado back in 2009 we were
maybe 1 to 3% of the concentrate market
was water hash and at this point I think
we're definitely pushing 20% of the
concentrates especially in places like
California and Colorado so big up
ourselves appreciate all the support and
keep pushing education for real that's
what puts the products on the shelves
that are healthy that's what puts the
quality on the shelves and that's what
helps the consumer understand what's
good well I mean the perfect example is
the diamonds you know we kind of touched
on it but I'll back it up a little bit
just in case anybody didn't catch that
one but in the hydrocarbon world right
when we learned about roz in a year or
two into learning really about
commercializing and scaling up the
creation of rosin we started seeing the
butane guys make diamonds and we're like
oh we got to learn we got to step up our
game over here we're on shadow right now
you know we're starting to make this
butter and these lighter consistencies
but diamonds oh how do we make this in
the lab how do we compete and really you
know it was all in playing with
different temperatures different
pressures different separations I feel
like the first diamonds were not
actually grown we're now seeing on the
solvent side of things growing diamonds
with pressure
but the first diamonds to come to the
industry were actually mechanically
separated amorphous solids morphus solid
crystalline yeah and you know I was
gonna bring it up a little earlier I
might have touched on the gentleman but
I have too big up a man named Jeff or
the cannabis Reverend this revenue
because of church
Jeff church cannabis Reverend was one of
the first gentlemen to bring in the
actual micron screen to separate the
oils from the waxes or what we later
found out to be a lot of that THC a you
know so that bag
not only contained a lot of the waxes
but it also contained a lot of the THC a
so eventually we learned that pressing
at higher temperatures would completely
remove the rest of the the terpenes and
actually are a lot of the rest of the
cannabinoids and at those higher
temperatures we were just retaining THC
a right and eventually we learned that
that white powdery substance was the THC
a that we are seeing some of these
hydrocarbon companies put out we started
testing some of those that white powdery
substance and hitting anywhere from 94
to 99% THC a in our regulated licensed
labs in Colorado and then we were like
whoa how do we turn this white powder
into what looks like the diamonds more
heat and pressure so we brought the
temperature right back up to around 250
degrees people do it at different
temperatures but basically to melt that
white powder back down into a solid form
and then you can mold that that form
into whatever shape you want I think
when we first started doing it we were
just making very very thick slabs so we
started with the white powder we heated
it up into these thicker slabs and we
were smashing it in the lab and in our
parchment paper and it was basically
just making all different shapes and
sizes of crystal and we started getting
that tested and even with that slight
temperature up crease upwards at 250
degrees we were not seeing any THC a
turn into THC which was interesting and
our labs were telling us that it was
pure 99.9 percent THC in fact some of
the labs that we were using not to put
anybody on blast some of the labs that
we were using for giving us test results
back at one
one hundred and eight point four percent
THC a so we had to step back and say
okay we can't put this on the shelf that
doesn't make any sense you can't have
over a hundred percent what's happening
here and we contacted the lab they're
like well we've never seen anything that
high you know what's going on and we
started looking at the standards and you
know this is gonna be an ongoing issue
in newly regulated environments but one
of the standards came from res Tech and
there's another standard that's put out
with another company there's a few more
companies that are putting out cannabis
standards now but res Tech Stander's
range from like ninety seven to ninety
eight point nine percent their THC a
standard and when we turned in our THC a
sample is higher than that so we bumped
the scale and I feel like they have to
create some new standards at this point
but we started leveling it out the lab
started learning and we were
mechanically separating THC a so to get
back to the original question
mimicking these hydrocarbon guys you
know it started with the earwax we
created solvent less wax now the rosin
has really really given us the advantage
to recreate different consistencies
we're seeing in the hydrocarbon world we
saw diamonds become instantly popular
with butane extraction and propane
extraction few other methods to create
diamonds and we had to find a way so we
utilized heat pressure and mechanical
separation how much a did you throw away
before you figured out that's the
craziest thing yeah well luckily we were
actually using a lot of it in other
products topicals edibles and other
things of that nature because we were
seeing the test results in our coconut
oil and other things but we just didn't
put two and two together it's crazy to
think back on it but yeah we definitely
threw a lot away we definitely use some
for purposes that we shouldn't have been
using it for you know in mechanical
separation I always like to talk about
allocations and this is maybe something
we can take a little break on but
allocations are extremely important and
that was one of those allocations we
were throwing away something that had a
lot of value another allocation I talked
about is when we're especially when
we're talking about butane versus
solvent list I used the strain blue
dream for the perfect example you get a
full indoor operation of blue dream you
bring it into your lab and you've got
the hydrocarbon guys next door butane
extract
guys and they're yielding 18 to 24
percent on this blue dream you bring
that same exact blue dream into the
water hash lab we might be yielding
three to five percent on that blue dream
and originally I just started this
discussion about the trichomes structure
whether it has a thick waxy cuticle or a
longer trichome stalk but blue dream is
one of those ones that has a long stalk
a very small head and a thick waxy
cuticle it does not yield well in water
hash and this is just an example you may
find the very specific cut that does do
well in water hash but for general
purposes aloft in times the blue dream
that we see is just not good for
allocating towards water hash it's great
for hydro carbon and so the same thing
goes with allocations on the back end we
found that that white powdery substance
that we were taking away in our bags and
keeping the clean clear beautiful gold
rosin you know we were throwing that
away as Phil mentioned and we've now
learned to allocate that and utilize
that THCA that we're thrown away any
other questions we got lit up here so I
don't all right so we're used to you
know the full spectrum like 45min 160th
you guys to play with like the 1/16 plus
for separation because you know I I
found some light goods you know find
some good heads in the ones
bigger heads who beat our dicks have you
guys tried explored that so you're
saying you know do we basically isolate
the 160-180 micron and you know press
that out and see the quality of that
rosin and do stuff like that or separate
or keep it like yeah I mean personally
yeah I've actually just recently I mean
it was some indoor but it was isolated
180 micron from an OG which is to me not
a common thing to find for ice water
hash a 180 you and it was incredible it
actually put out about 91% return on the
rosin so it was the most most impressive
180 I've ever seen when he talked about
that return on the rosies talking about
the actual trichome head being pressed
into rosin and when you're talking about
a 91% return that means there's barely
any waxy cuticle it means you're barely
losing anything you start with 5 grams
and you're yielding about four point two
four point five or four point six grams
now I'm horrible with mass start with
the gram and you know you're getting 0.9
one bag there you go but but yeah I mean
for the most part a lot of strains I do
I like the 180 I like the 150 I think it
really depends on your methods
you know gentle agitation depending on
strains and knowing what you're working
with the environment you're working in
and controlling all your variables
I think the 180 and the 150 are really
good because for the most part I usually
isolate everything depending on what I'm
doing but I find in the end a lot of
things end up just making it into the
same batch because what I'll do is I'll
isolate and then you know I'll press
everything out and I'll separate
everything by quality you know so not
quality just by color but call you by
terpene profile always have to dab it
taste
I noticed the 40 the 40 micron is
usually not my favorite I like to keep
that little separate because I don't
know if it's more fats and lipids that
are in it that's giving it a certain
taste but I mean it's still great oil
but to me I think keeping the 40
separated is better than keeping the 180
and the 150 separated because to me the
180 and the 150 have a high terpene
profile to me those have like my
favorite terms you know like if you
never catch 150 or 180 those are just
man lucky and to really you know
summarize that it's so strained
dependent you know I was actually
speaking of your og cush that you'll did
amazing in your 180 bag we ran some
lemon cush Himalayan lemon cush it was a
strain that was brought back by a
soldier friend of ours that we ran in
Colorado for a long time this one round
that one of my growers grew wielded over
two ounces of full melt in the 220 bag
okay
so anything's possible and to go back on
what Phil said I really like to
emphasize that we actually do the same
thing we separate all of the microns
I run a couple 220 bags we actually run
a couple there and in the washing
machine just to make sure we've gotten
all that plant material I then run a 185
a 160 a 120 you know sometimes the
hundred the 90 that you know sometimes
to run a strain that we've never ran
before I'll put all my bags in there
I'll try and separate as many as I can
because each strain each grower each
medium is gonna be a little different
even from one row you know you might be
running the same strain in a grow house
but have LEDs in one row have your HPS
and another you're gonna see differences
even there's differences from the top of
your plant to the bottom of the plant as
far as the trichome formation the amount
of oils in them the size of the trichome
head so we really like to especially
when we're running a strain that we
haven't run before is run all of those
different micron sizes you can combine
them in the end I can't combine them you
know if you've started with only three
three microns you can't separate them
sorry beforehand so we like to start out
with as many bags as we can see where
the heads are lying and then eventually
on that next run when you're running
that same material from that same garden
you can remove some bags you don't have
to use all those bags and I think right
there I think what that is in my opinion
is every strain has a different head and
tell you know so it's like the heads the
cream and the tail is gonna be your butt
end it might be it's lower quality you
know but for the most part when you see
the head and tail together like a
full-spectrum hash oil
something it's a good product but when
you actually pull that tail end out of
like let's just say for instance a
headband we're running and that you know
you can run seven eight spins you know
30-minute spins and you're still pulling
and you know five spins in it was just
quality but you can see it's getting
darker more contaminants but then you
get to the rosin and you're pressing
everything out and everything's just
coming out gold regardless of the hash
you know and and you know it's all about
the yield so you got a hundred grams of
high-quality and 10 grams of just some
darker oil other strains you know you'll
notice regardless of the yield you might
got the same yield off that strain as
far as hash but it comes to pressing you
know you have more wax membrane to those
heads so therefore you're getting more
more tail in with that head so you know
you're get looking at like let's just
say you get 80 grams and 30 grams of
tail in because that's the darker oil
yeah and that's that's more when you're
looking for like when people are
separating their Roslin's you know
having like you know their their heads -
and then just the edible grade for me I
kind of I'm more of a full spec guy I
kind of like to keep everything together
as long I like to keep the tail end out
and I think that's an important part of
extraction is the head and tell
regardless of what we're doing rosin ice
water extraction ahead and tell it's all
about knowing when to poll and what to
keep separated a mature grower as
anybody here ever explored with
ultrasonic cleaning for washing hash
like definitely actually we've yeah the
question is has anybody utilized
ultrasonic cleaning with hash or
ultrasonic technology and we've used on
actually a number of scales and people
companies that I know right now are
utilizing that technology in a number of
ways as well I'll touch on a few things
we had a company come in to our facility
we were one of the first licensed
facility blessed to be one of the first
licensed facility in the world in
Colorado and so a lot of companies from
the cold brew industry from the wine
industry beer industry started
contacting us because we were able to do
license protected R&amp;D and an ultrasonic
agitation company or cavitation company
similar technology contacted us from the
cold brew industry and brought in
machinery into our facility and we
started playing around with it
unfortunately cannabis is a lot
different than coffee and hops etc and
we just kept having clogging issues with
that machine but I saw value in it so
what we did use utilize that cavitation
or that ultrasonic technology not to
separate the heads from the material
like we initially wanted to and I still
do think that there's value there and I
think that there is viability and I
think that you could do that but instead
we ended up because it costs so much
money for the machinery and to keep
making these diodes bigger and these
passageways bigger because the cannabis
had to flow but we wanted to get an
exact temperature there were a lot of
variables that cost a lot millions of
dollars really in R&amp;D that this
cavitation company didn't want to just
keep shelling out but we ended up
finding out that on a very high level
turning up that cavitation device that
ultrasonic device we're able to actually
fully homogenize the oil into the
solution so for edible products for
topical products there's a lot of value
in ultrasonic agitation and cavitation I
still do think there's value in
separating the oil via this technology
if you guys aren't familiar basically
ultrasonic agitation is a wave that is
so intense that it can actually separate
oil from wall
they've used it in actually separating
rivers and things of that nature on a
larger scale ie cavitation but we saw
this value because we started turning it
up and actually breaking the trichome
heads in water which would be our
solution and now we have oil and water
in one solution we started going back to
okay how do they get oil out of water
and you know we started playing with
some of the technology that they're
using in the oceans to get you know
spills out of the oceans these polymer
tubes basically that run on the bottom
of the ocean that are pulling the oil
out of the ocean and we played with that
but we weren't seeing the yields we
wanted to see I still do think that
there's a lot to do there and there is a
future for it so keep playing that's
what it's all about I didn't get to it I
didn't get there yet myself but I think
one of y'all could
share share share with everyone put it
up on the forums throw it up on
Instagram tag these guys they'll put it
out there that's what it's about man
that's what it's about we found each
other somehow we found compassion both
both of us found compassion so keep
spreading knowledge for real and stick
around today because I think we
definitely have some more discussions a
little roundtable with a few more hash
makers in the building but we're gonna
take a little split break I think right
about now