[Music]
so tell me about the competition that's
coming up tomorrow
yeah so I just picked up the entries I'm
truly truly blessed to have this
opportunity to judge the og competition
put on by hitman glass bredrin Dougie
always doing it right and doing it
properly for the community I really
appreciate what he's done since day one
you know there's a lot of back-and-forth
on the internet but all in all all in
all I just I love what Doug he's done
for our community he's been there since
day one
along side you know and I love what he's
doing so this oh gee competition is
gonna be super super cool especially for
me I grew up smoking oh gee cush and for
I feel like eight and nine years
straight that's all I smoked that's all
I wanted to smoke pure clone only og
cush so his Dougie's kind of broad
working together I grew up in the Bay
Area grew up in Bay Area California up
in NorCal I lived in Colorado for the
last 18 years or so and now I'm back in
California just kind of traveling right
now I'm on tour for the next two or
three months so just free-floating yeah
there's a lot of stories and actually
that's that's one of the guys that I
look up to Josh D I really respect his
opinion and I follow that trend in that
story to be honest there's a lot of
different stories about OG Kush I
believe that Oh G stands for original
you know there's a lot of people that
thought that it stood for ocean grown or
original gangsta and things of that
nature I was always told from day one
that the OG and OG Kush stood for
original and then talking to a lot of my
friends from that generation the cush
part was due to the the cushy nature the
squishy nature of it and that's really
what's stuck as far as I've been told
about OG Kush and you know the lineage
is all over the place because nobody
created
cush I think that some of the first og
you know that true true clone only
strain came out of Florida migrated to
LA I really gained its popularity and
its hype in Southern California and then
dispersed from there one cut went out to
ghost OGE out in Oregon you know and
things spread like that but some some
cool studies are coming out with the
genealogy and following the actual
origins of strings like this that's a
great question you know through and
through since day one
the hi of OG Kush has always been
extremely strong but clear-headed for me
and the taste is just something almost
undescribable I always say it's got a
citrus gas and tennis ball funk and I
say tennis ball because if you've ever
cracked a brand-new can of tennis balls
smell that smell and smell a jar of OG
Kush there's some similarities there
oddly enough so citrus gas and tennis
ball funk is what I consider a G and
then there's also a lot of G's and
especially some of the original ones
that do have a hint of anise on the
backend and on the top of the tongue so
a little bit of all those flavors citrus
gas anise and tennis ball funk a G Kush
and it might not have been the same
exact strain they might not all have
grown oh gee clone only oh geez and I'm
actually I haven't even fully dove into
this just got it late last night and
just starting to dig in today yeah yeah
yeah yeah I always like to start out
with number one I like to make a big
list for myself write everything down
and put things into the app but uh yeah
I always start just sequentially yeah
this is number one
[Music]
yeah first I want to smell it
take the sunglasses off for this first I
smell it take it out I want to see what
the nug structure looks like I want to
make sure that there's no you know no
issues that are blatant to the to the
eye to the naked eye just make sure that
there's no you know PM or might damage
and things like that which generally
speaking in most of these cups recently
you're not gonna see too much of it
because it's gonna get pushed aside or
not actually fully entered due to
failing of microbial or other issues
yeah I go for the smell I want to break
one of the nugs I want to really get
deep inside there smell it from there I
basically break one up and I roll a
spliff because I can't really tell
anything you know fully from just the
smell and the appearance it's about the
smoke ability it's about how it burns
it's about the flavor fully through so I
actually will smoke every single entry
from start to finish
certain entries you know you get halfway
through the spliff and it's just really
not good and we'll set those down and
you'll kind of notice in my ashtray that
some of the spliffs are burned to the
crotch some of them definitely have a
big spliff tail as we call it left
behind because I didn't like it as much
so what's what's the initial reactions
entry number one smells great it's got a
great structure big calyxes you know
often times I'll look to to see if the
bud looks like it was machine trimmed
and this does not appear so you know
I'll see if the calyxes have been
knocked off with some scissors and
things like that if people weren't as
particular with the trim but it's a nice
tight trim big calyx structure beautiful
trichome coverage for an OG and it's got
a great cure on it too good Oh Geno's
it's got a little something else on the
on the tip of my tongue here
but I'm gonna have to taste it to really
really fully see what I think about this
one yeah number one
so generally I'll go through them all
and just do a visual and smell
inspection take some notes and then from
there I'll start at the very beginning
again do the same visual and smell
inspection and then smoke a spliff of it
I smoke spliffs so I want to really see
a constant and that's something that I
do you know differently than a lot of
the judges but I know the flavor that
I'm really looking for when I blend my
grabba in with it it's like a base some
people use a blunt some people use a
bong when I smoke out of a bong all I
taste is resin you know and the people
that are used to smoking bongs they're
using that resin taste that's kind of
always on the back end of their tongue
and they're able to taste the flavor of
the gum cannabis that much clearer
because they're balancing it off of
something that's a standard for me that
standard is an unbleached paper and some
grabba so that's really what I base my
judging off of I'll roll a spliff
because I smoke spliffs daily and so I
mean how many for this one we have 10
entries 10 passing entries okay so how
long will it take you to go through all
ten to give each one you know I'm you
know maybe it's that I'm blessed to
smoke really good but I've been judging
so many cups I've got a pretty healthy
habit of smoking upwards of an ounce
ounce and a half a day so I do get high
and some strains definitely hit me a lot
stronger I try and space them out at
least a couple hours but I can knock out
ten entries in a day yeah yeah I've had
upwards of 75 entries in four days
you know yeah so now let's talk about
passing verses family because people
were throwing he that dug for
not-so-humble sunglasses back home hey
what's up what's the question
a couple entrance failed the testing and
very in my mind very openly let people
know that on histogram I think is pretty
transparent with the process then he got
a lot of shit for it because he wasn't
calling those people out by name what
I've seen from an outside perspective
because I've judged fuck a thousand cups
at this point to be honest I've judged a
lot of cannabis cups and I love the
transparency but you can only really be
transparent to a point we have a lot of
friends and you know community in this
that it's such a hard situation
putting your friends on blast and things
of that nature is not what we're trying
to do you know we're trying to promote
positivity
some of some of the time these guys are
getting cuts from they're from you know
outside sources that have systemic
problems with them and that's how a lot
of these things are coming in it's not
that they're spraying with Michael
butanol still and things of that nature
but in reality it's not really my place
to speak on it it's one of the reasons I
don't throw competitions because of that
I've got too many friends in this
industry and you know it's it's it's a
balancing act
[Music]