yeah please it is absolutely absolutely
so anyone who brings so we have we have
our nursery which is a commercial
nursery we sell plants mostly b2b
licensed the license to licensed
cultivators we occasionally do like
clone drops at festivals and at
dispensaries as well but we also have
services that we offer to other private
individuals and that's all done through
what we call our non propagation
agreement and that's ultimately spelled
out by the client if they can spell
exactly who they want to have access to
the genetic materials and most of the
time we propagate stuff for people we
can't even grow it ourselves you know
it's all contract based absolutely
absolutely so yeah I mean the only buddy
and they kind of screwed them over they
were totally dying they were mutating
they were covered in past and he brought
us like the saddest-looking slips like I
had never seen and he was desperate and
we did we on a handshake deal it was
like look we'll take an animal take care
of you you mean we took in his pink
panties as acai
his original sunset sherbert all of this
parent material to you know love the
pipe shit that people are talking about
right now again sorry pardon my language
but the so yeah that was the first time
and luckily it worked out well we did
eventually put a contract in place over
time but it was a handshake deal that we
did with him and now we're providing for
a lot of his farms that are contracted
grow his products were providing all the
clones to those so
[Music]
so is it that depends it ultimately
depends on how much so it depends on how
many plants you have that you want a
bank it depends on what your so I'm
sorry let me back up to clarify your
question are you saying is it economical
to use us as a germ plasm is a genetic
banking of material or is it economical
for us to be a propagator for you
[Music]
I'd say the the latter must much more
likely the germ plasm process again the
initiation like what we because it takes
a it takes a lot of time to when a plant
comes into culture to our India to
figure out what media grows healthily on
there's a big rnd expense that we incur
bringing in new varieties in the culture
we're trying to shorten that process up
and streamline that process by starting
to do genetic screening and being able
to look and see hey this new variety
that we're bringing in how does it look
genetically similar to other varieties
that we have does it have some of the
same genetic markers that this other
cultivar has so if it does let's try it
on this media first and save ourselves
three months of having plants not grow
and die on the wrong media to back up
for a second that was one of the things
that we were really really surprised
about is there was a huge variance in
cultivar to cultivar to how they
performed and grew on media much more so
than other agricultural crops like
there's a there's a great media and
there's a banana media and there's an
orchid media and you can grow cymbidiums
and Phalaenopsis and lady slippers all
in the same orchid media we didn't find
that with cannabis which was pretty
interesting each cultivar really seemed
to want a specific media
to grow on so the the initiation process
is expensive I'm not gonna sugarcoat it
for you it's expensive you know I mean
it's thousands of dollars to take one of
your varieties and come in you know so
banking that material yeah absolutely
yeah and we have insurance as well so
this is the and backup facilities all of
that you know I mean we keep multiple
copies not all on the same site you know
I mean but um yeah I mean it is it is
certainly what we've found at least for
economical even for smaller people
within the ten thousand square foot
range who either don't want to don't
want to mess around with propagation
anymore it's like dude you can devote
all your square footage to all the other
production you don't need a team to do
propagation you don't need to keep moms
that are out anymore either use choose
from our genetic library which is over
120 cultivars or we'll take your your
genetics in and we'll propagate them
from you in next season we'll give you
all the plants you need you know I mean
exactly exactly
absolutely yeah yeah yeah exactly I mean
and you it's volume it's obviously a
sliding scale volume independent you
know I mean but yes no we should we sell
the clones back so I just got the word
that we've got five minutes left I'm
just gonna look real quick to see if
there's anything that I didn't hit and
if I mean yeah the one thing that I did
want to say like being back up in here I
think it's just a really it's a really
good time for the kind of communities to
come together I really really hope that
through my work with finance and my work
in the industry that I can try to be a
bridge between the scientific community
and the grassroots cannabis community
because that's where I came from and I
think it's really important that these
two communities work together to
preserve this industry and put it on the
right track the track that we all want
to see it on and with that said I'll
I'll open it up if there is any more
questions that people have that we can
hopefully be able to answer
no good awesome
ball thank you all guys
you