and then this blank client will spend
about 21 days 14 of which at almost 100%
humidity before it establishes roots and
we can start acclimating it to lower and
lower humidity and higher and higher
light levels so that's a little bit of
kind of the outline of like so we have
stage one initiation stage two is shoot
proliferation which is basically
figuring out the media that the plant is
actually growing on getting more biomass
that we can multiply it multiply off of
stage three is multiplication and then
stage four is this hardening off and
routing phase that we do the which
process the whole process so this is I'm
glad you asked that question because
this brings me to kind of one of the
next points that I wanted to talk about
which was just the pros and cons of
tissue culture and there are definite
pros but there are definite cons it's a
more expensive way to produce the plant
no question asked you know it's a lot
easy it's if you've ever done breeding
before it's really cheap to produce seed
how how much do you need consistency
across your across your production
system because obviously with seeds you
get a huge amount of varying genotypes
and phenotypes so hey I need consistency
in my production system I need to grow
the same plant so you go to asexual
propagation as opposed to sexual
propagation and that's cloning you know
cloning asexual propagation we've all
been doing it for years it's not rocket
science
keep it pretty clean keep the
environment right give it a little bit
of hormone 14 to 18 days you got a new
plan so one of the cons is this process
does take a long time you can do we say
so we work with a lot of clients
throughout the states and we've brought
their genetics and under contract with
you know specific language saying who if
anyone besides them has access to these
genetics but we tell people it takes
usually 8 to 12 months before when from
when you give me a plant that I can
induce into tissue culture from when I
can sell you a thousand clones a week up
off of it's going to be 8 to 10 months
and you know there's different processes
and there's different types of tissue
culture but one of the big cons is that
it does take a while and that's one of
the things that we've struggled with
especially with how the market can be
very trend driven so it's like you've
got the hot strain hey I want fucking I
want 10,000 a month fucking clean ass
tissue culture clone sorry my part my
language on and I'm like awesome I'll be
able to give them to you a year from now
when the new hot strain is trending and
that doesn't sell anymore no so this is
one of the challenges that we face you
know and
so but yeah I mean so that is definitely
one of the cons and there's different
processes there different message we can
do something called a quick clean you
know where we take the plant in we do a
generation or two in vitro or in culture
and we can give you 50 or 100 plants
back you know that you can then grow out
and then what most people do with tissue
culture is they tissue culture their
plants and they grow up mom plants of
them and then they take traditional
clones off of those and then we provide
them new tissue cultured plants on a
regular basis
so they're always cutting off of clean
stock it's it's the same as what we do
traditionally so we do and I'll cut back
a little bit and if I get it if I get
too granular at any point stop me if
you're like I don't know understand what
the fuck you're saying but we do
different types of and there's multiple
types of different tissue culture you
have noddle propagation you have micro
propagation you have meristem
propagation you have callus cell
propagation and you have embryo Genesis
all these different types depending on
what section or amount of cells or
tissues you take to reproduce kind of
defines what we do we do what's called
nodal propagation so we're only taking
the lateral nodes and propagating off of
those we've found that you have you the
lowest rate of mutation through that
type of tissue culture because other
types of tissue culture work really well
for other things like removing systemic
viruses or producing a large volume of
plants in a very small area but you run
a higher risk of mutation on the plant
which is a reality of it's a reality of
clone
we talked about genetic drift which is a
mutation you can see mutation and seed
production where you have intersex
traits from a frenetic trace diploid
triploid traits so mutation is a risk
that you always run with group
reproduction whether it's sexual or
asexual or in beach or ex vitro but it
is a risk of tissue culture and so
through nodal propagation we see again
the lowest we see the lowest rate of
mutation now I think there's a decent
way to segue into like one of the big
advantages of the tissue culture process
is this this reinvigoration that you see
of the plant and again I am I have not
spent nearly as long working in tissue
culture as some of our partners have but
even talking with them I've tried to
press them to understand why does a
plant regenerate when it goes through
tissue culture process process why can I
take a 20 year old og cush clone that is
just not performing like it used to it's
way more susceptible diseases and pests
than it used to be why can I take that
through the tissue culture process and
it comes out healthier and stronger and
growing like a seedling again I don't
think we're screwing it up and yeah it's
party screening so the thing that we
really see in this is I had like a
double doctorate tell me this they me
when I first asked this question he was
like the plant forgets how old it is and
I was like what the hell does that mean
you know but it is there is somehow your
the cells have a genetic memory the
plant has an age we all age senescence
is a natural process of all biological
organisms and plants have this as well
and somehow through this tissue culture
process the plant is resetting itself
and it's resetting its genetic age so
you'll take a plant that's been growing
and again has all these what we maybe
call undesirable traits after a long
time
of traditional asexual propagation its
since eight months in tissue culture
generation after generation after
generation getting micro propagated in
vitro with zero biotic stress no
bacteria fuckin was it no pest fuckin
with it the perfect climate the perfect
temperature everything all the right mix
of nutrients hormones sugars vitamins
everything we grow those plants out and
they do equal opposite branching again
the way a seed does and it's like holy
shit this is there is something going on
here the plant is in I will say one
caveat we haven't seen that across the
board
I'd say 70% of the strains that were
showing symptoms of degradation we can
take through the tissue culture process
and within eight months to a year of
being in tissue culture they come out
growing better than they did before but
not every single strain and ultimately
we think it is just it's the amount of
time that it spends in vitro so this
quick clean process that we have done we
really now only do four meristem tissue
culture which is what I'll talk about
now is taking a different set of cells
and in propagating and multiplying from
that the advantage of meristem culture
raising has do we know what the marathon
is on a plant so meristem is a region of
the plant there's multiple you have a
meristem in the growing tips you have a
meristem in the roots you have a
meristem actually in the stem region as
well it's an area of rapid cell division
that's happening in the plant the
interesting thing about this these
regions in the plant is that if the
plant say has you guys been hearing
anything about hemp latent virus
recently so if there is a systemic virus
in the plant systemic meaning that it is
not a pathogen that's external and
affecting the plant from the outside
that it's actually a pathogen that's
reproducing inside of the plant viruses
are this way and it's very prevalent
other agricultural crops this
meristematic region of the plant the
cell division is happening so fast that
you can have new healthy cells that
contain all the genomic mature
grow a new plant that is not yet
connected to the vascular tissue of the
plant the vascular tissue being what
transports all the water and all the
sugar through the plant and so you can
take this cell cluster from the meristem
and produce a genetically identical
perfectly healthy plant that's outgrown
the virus that is not yet been infected
by the virus that's running through the
xylem and the phloem the vascular tissue
of the plant so I worked briefly with
Driscoll's right out of college I'm sure
no big berry growers and all of their
plants are produced through meristem
tissue culture so they're taking again
the very very very growing tip of the
plant and this is something you have to
do in a microscope you pull that growing
tip you scrape off all the Leafs all the
leaf primordia and you get this
meristematic dome it's this area of
rapid cell division again all the
genetic material to grow an identical
plant but it's not connected to the
vascular tissue and you can culture that
meristem and grow a virus free plant so
Driscoll's at their facility up in Red
Bluff that's what they do for all their
berries and then what they do is they
grow that tissue culture meristem
strawberry plant into a mother plant and
they take traditional clones off of that
and that's what they provide to all
their growers disease free virus free
pest free plants that's what we're
trying to do at finest candidates so
this meristem process is the only like
quick clean process that what we do now
and meristem takes longer than
traditional noddle propagation so when I
say click quick lean you're still
looking at probably six months till I
could give you a flat of meristem
regenerated disease-free plants back so
yeah please
yep it's a good question I think so we
haven't had that positive intentions
obviously yet if we do I'll definitely
be the first to tell you know most of
the mutations that we see are increased
intersex traits so we evaluate every
plant that we take through tissue
culture we evaluate in-house in our
facility before we release it to the
public we grow it out to make sure that
there is a mutation I mean I don't think
it's I don't think I'm speaking out of
line and I say like a lot of the
cannabis cultivars that are widely
circulated and grown and loved have
intersex or hermaphroditic traits this
is the result of like extremely rapid
and somewhat unmonitored breeding that's
happened in the cannabis community and
so a lot of traits that maybe weren't
noticed or documented are getting passed
along and passed along to the gene pool
you know cannabis is pretty unique in
the angiosperm family that it's it's
deiicious it has male and female plants
that have flowers that have totally
different reproductive organs and it's
one of the challenges there are not
cannabis is right now one of the only
plants except papaya that is dioecious
and as being tissue cultured so it's
something that we're we're really
looking at pretty actively is what what
do we see yeah what do we see with with
with dioecious plants and intersex
traits when we start to do the tissue
culture process especially when we start
to talk about things like embryo Genesis
which is another type of plant tissue
culture where you're you guys familiar
with like stem cells so it's basically
stem cell growth for plants we take
plant material in and you can put it in
the media and it grows what's called a
callous and callus is just
undifferentiated
and sell it can doubt those cells
depending on what biotic or abiotic
stimulus they get they can become a leaf
they can become a root they can become a
chute they can become a flower
embryogenesis is a way to produce a huge
number of plants in a small area you can
take a piece of callus the size of a
pinhead and get it to grow 75 plants out
of it
embryogenesis is something that's not
done in a lot of crops again because of
the mutation rate we're currently doing
trials as embryogenesis right now to see
if it's something that's even viable so
again I don't want to get I don't want
to get too too granular one of the other
one of the other things at least for me
that has been really interesting about
the tissue culture process and learning
as the just the idea of germ plasm the
idea of start being able to store a vast
amount of genetic material I mean anyone
who's ever tried to do a breeding
program or done breeding in-house or
even tried to keep mother stock around
knows that it can be problematic it can
be challenging to keep mother stock
around and not to mention if you want to
have 10 20 100 300 cultivars that you
can be able to cycle through so German
just the genetic banking part is a is a
really big advantage of tissue culture
so we we offer that program to actually
a handful of breeders as well who they
have a a library of genetic material
that they don't want to have to keep
alive and potentially lose or have
potentially get infected with with pests
you