hey here's an update on the gorilla glue
and the five by nine tent
it's coming down here um got the cuts
from a buddy
um this is the second run i had with
them the first run i had in the four by
four tent um
they're kind of a trickier strain to
grow for me at least
they were really heavy feeders
i smashed them because the first run you
know
i noticed that so i tried to correct for
that on this run
so i smashed them with some foliars from
uh organics alive
and nature's pride green aminos so but
still
these these uh three beds on the right
started showing deficiencies there uh
pretty early even though i kept on the
the foliars and even up the
dosage too um
but this bad i think um when i was going
through my notes
i saw that because these two beds
weren't set up initially it was just
these two so when i set this one up i
didn't have enough soil in it and i
started growing cover crops
so i let them grow for a little bit i
chopped them down
and then covered it with uh some compost
and some more soil
and then that's when i planted these
girls in them so uh
i think all that active decomposition
and stuff because this plant just blew
up leafs everywhere you know just
huge compared to everything else fox
tails and everything
so i think that had something to do with
it but um
yeah overall man they're just uh heavy
feeders
um oh yeah what i learned
not every strain is the same some
strains are going to eat more than
others you know some are going to be you
know prefer a different environment than
others prefer more water less water
you know that's why we use these tools
that we like to buy from the grill store
and stuff
to monitor those things but um oh yeah
another thing i learned keep the trellis
on point
i didn't know the gorilla glue would
stretch this much
so when i put the trellis up um they
didn't stop i mean i flowered them when
they were like at the first trellis you
know and
that's how big they got even with me
stretching them all over the place
trying to keep them keep them down so i
guess just try to know how much your the
string you're growing
stretches um
because that that's that was an issue
for me with the trellis and keeping the
trellis on point is uh is huge it's
really huge
um ipm always ipm didn't have any
problems this run thank god but
i did um listen to brandon russ talk
on the future cannabis project and he
was talking about the bavaria basiana
and i had already been looking into that
about a year ago i just never got it
and when he mentioned it i i went out i
ordered it so i got some of that coming
um the dr zymes you know and then the
extract sprays
and stuff
uh yeah i would have used different
cover crops
like a more diverse blend as well
we just want that diversity all those
different cover crops would be released
in different exit dates waking up
different sets of microbes in the soil
getting that
that cycling going on but the rye just
kind of went out of control
um
oh my grill media so in all the beds i
use
coasta maine the stonington blend and i
also added some malibu compost
to some of them um
and to others i'm pretty sure i added
um the lobster compost from coastal
maine as well even though it was already
in the stonington blend i just i really
like that stuff it smells great um
my lights i'm using the next light
course
i've really loved them so far they don't
put out a lot of heat at all
um yeah i mean i can leave them like six
inches above
the plant i just like them because the
heat because i'm growing intense
that's that's what matters to me
i got a six inch phantom filter
describe the smell because my girl
doesn't really like it in the house you
know
so got to take care of that that seems
to work
um also if you're growing intense
something big
is uh controlling the environment of the
room that you're in
so i got that dehu over there um
that's big like positioning that you
know so where i got it
the heat is blowing out towards that
wall right there so these two tents tend
to get hotter
and drier than this tank so
i gotta finagle it around um and then
you know
check the readings in all the tents and
then adjust that
dehumidifier accordingly um
that's huge controlling the temp because
then that you know
when you're sucking trying to get it dry
in the tents you're also jacking the
heat up in the room which is going to
increase the
heat and the tents but i don't like to
ever let the tents get over
60 percent humidity at night
but it's pretty hard growing intense
it's a big challenge if you can't just
get
one big tent or i mean throwing
multiple ones is is pretty difficult to
keep your environment on point
oh yeah i got these fans i need to get a
new oscillating fan i think sucks
but um the oscillating fans for
above the canopy for air movement and
this box fan down here i didn't like uh
no air movement down here at all so i
just keep it on low
and blow it through through down there
but i think that's why i stopped getting
mushrooms popping up
um oh yeah mark your beds
that's something i didn't do initially
if i could go back i would you know
definitely would and mark them all which
they now are
so that i can keep like meticulous notes
so now you know everything i've done to
here
i have to go through all these
handwritten notes and like some
uh like saved videos and stuff i have
so it's kind of a pain in the butt but
yeah i mean i talked about the gorilla
glue a little bit already but
they stretch a lot a lot a lot they're
heavy feeders
but i mean it's beautiful they're
they're super frosty especially this one
super frosty has the classic gorilla
glue smell
to me it's it's kind of like an og
undertone
which i love i love the ogs but um
some gnarly looking nugs over here
but you can see that i've been
de-fanning because they're coming down
here in a couple days but
you can see the deficiencies they had
um yeah like i said i would have hit him
with more
um like extracts i would have had a
different cover crop in there i got blue
mats going
you can see the line coming in from
there
that comes in splits and then the
eight millimeter tube is run in a circle
around
where it meets back here
i got a purge so i can purge out
um you know any air bubbles or anything
i run that
you know for like 30 seconds like once
or twice or
about once a week or once every two
weeks
um oh they're on the distribution
drippers
i think the soil kind of swallowed
everything but i usually leave them in
because if i take them out i don't
remember to hand water them and then
while the crops drying in here
so are the the beds because you know
when i chop it down i just hang them in
here to dry
so if i leave the blue mats in the
plants are gone they're in the dark so
they're not really drinking any water
but if i didn't have the blue mats they
wouldn't be kept topped off and they dry
out and
i don't want my soils to dry out for the
micro life and also for the worms and
stuff um
i don't think really two weeks of no
water they really dry out that much but
just to be safe i leave it in there
but this time i will be taking them out
just so i can get out this rye grass
because it's
a son of a bitch to kill
[Music]
but yeah real glue it was fun
getting rid of it i don't have anything
behind it
any clones of it or anything i got about
six packs of seeds i gotta go through
that i'm pretty excited for
yeah thanks