[Music]
hello everyone my name is John Wilson
I am Tribune of the stakeholders for
Seattle City Lights lighting design lab
I'm gonna set the table very quickly and
make up some time by talking about you
know what why do you Tillett ease care
about this conversation why are they
actually in it beyond the sort of
platitudes that we often hear like I'm
just trying to get some energy
efficiency and hit these targets right
there's really three reasons that
utilities are making this investment and
their their business models are evolving
and I'm just gonna touch on that quickly
and the rest of my colleagues are really
gonna take it home the three topics
really are yes there's reliable energy
savings that's kind of like the first
generation like we all understand
utilities want to get cost-effective
savings especially where there's targets
or regulations in place
you know requiring them to do so the
next really big topic is what a lot of
utilities are describing generically as
like customer service plus utilities are
rapidly waking up to the fact that they
need to be part of the solution for
technology transfer and not a hindrance
or you know somebody who is slow in that
process down and to deliver you know to
technical professional services to
utilities is something that's going to
reinforce the utility business model and
allow them to sustain what they're doing
and then the last one is just kind of
funny because it's it's back in vogue
after like since like the 1940s but it's
next generation electrification and this
really has to do with our current
climate around carbon reduction in the
fact that electrification now leads to
hopefully a reduction in um you know
harmful greenhouse gases and all that so
if you are a utility it's not any one of
these things it's all three of these
things and for the utility community
members in the room I encourage you to
think about putting your business plan
together and addressing all three of
these things to make a comprehensive
plan for why your utility should make a
sustained investment in the CEA market
so what is different now then like I
don't know the last five or ten years
and you know what why are we at you know
what many people are kind of describing
as an inflection point or a real growth
opportunity well I
described for you what has changed on
the utility landscape it's no longer
just about energy savings
it's about load growth it's about
delivering a level of customer service
that makes you know that gives the
utility a chance to have a positive
interaction with customers beyond just
billing you once a month right but what
is happening is it's really how those
things are starting to align with the
Horticultural lighting market and where
things you know where the alignment is
starting to come together so 5-10 years
ago we didn't have great reliable
product that was trusted by consumers
the time wasn't right for utilities to
push that as a kWh saving mechanism
similarly utilities were less interested
in load growth than electrification ten
years ago than they are now and that's
reflected in any utility conference that
you go to that's the big buzzword and
then last but not least cultivators are
hungry for information and although
utilities might be strange bedfellows as
far as a resource where you would go to
get that people are hungry for
information and utilities in just about
every other CNI market and with
residential consumers have played a
helpful role in the past delivering that
service and good information and so you
can see these things are aligning in
such a way that give me a lot of
optimism that we're going to be able to
team up and really make a positive
impact everybody is familiar with this
basic technology diffusion curve invest
on the Left cash out on the right when
Matt was talking about making LED lights
in his basement that's so far off the
left that like it's not even on this
chart but it takes people like that to
get this whole thing going right so
we're familiar with this what is so cool
again it's reinforced in because I'm a
visual learner
we now have organizations like the DLC
Leora's gonna be up here taking this
that'll help propping this up we have
our III what a phenomenal resource and
then it's really like in my mind those
two organizations are like two of the
most critical pillars that needed to be
in place in order for utilities to come
behind and like do the stuff that is our
bread and butter work in the traditional
CNI markets before we could be effective
in this market we needed to
we know we needed the resources and the
tools that are brought by those other
you know DLC and ri-ight so it's just
terrific that these are in place because
it gives us something as a utility
personnel to work from you know
information a balance people are so
hungry for information out there and
where do you go when you're hungry for
information you go to the YouTube right
and a quick search about grow lights or
growing cannabis you know you could
spend all day looking at the science
stuff you can spend all day looking at
this stuff online and while you might
get some good nuggets of information
it's nothing is as good it's coming here
to this conference and the information
that you're getting listening to these
bonafide speakers get up and really open
up and share in the cross-pollination
we're getting with utilities and the
cultivation community coming together
outside this cultivation space we have a
really positive track record working
with industry and my favorite thing the
first efficient yields workshop I went
to I did not know it was a utility
function and tell somebody like pointed
that out to me they did the utility
energy trust I got to give him props
they did so good getting out of the way
and letting there be a really healthy
peer-to-peer information exchange that
it was unlike any other utility
experience I'd ever gone to and I really
believe as we think about utilities how
can we work better with the cultivation
community that's going to be a big key
you know support good information who to
do to do if you are a utility continue
to support the good information that's
about that that is out there consider
becoming a member of organizations like
RI I support or at least engage with the
work DL C is doing in this horticultural
space because it's gonna be a way to
right-size your utility investment so
you can be effective and participate in
this market even if you don't have a
huge customer base underneath you that
you know allows you to have a dedicated
person amplify trusted information and
my last one to sign out on my little
daughter think about the children water
in the crops the next generation coming
up so that's it for me thanks y'all and
my next speaker what I'm going to be
talking about is some industry trends
that we've seen as far as what's going
on in the global market for
horticultural lighting
but then also some terminology and
baselines so first again I'm creme
Wilder with fluence bioengineering we've
been we were a startup back in 2015 and
now we're owned by osram which is a 4.5
billion dollar lighting company globally
so we've got over 350 commercial
cannabis installations and over 80
commercial AG installations right now
and we've learned a ton over that whole
time period so it's one of those things
that as we get into looking at what is
going on globally we really have to pay
attention to what's coming the next 7 10
15 years and beyond so when we really
look at we were kind of in as far as the
whole global lighting market sorry
excuse me
is the greenhouse era and then going
into vertical and city farming era so
that's more indoor cultivation that's
more looking at rnd vertical farming and
such and the industry is just going to
continue to grow as we find more and
more pressures environmentally and
population wise so hopefully everyone in
this room has read the 2018 cannabis
energy report that REI and new frontier
data published two years ago which
really took a very very hard look I
think it was 25 plus pages of
information about just the cannabis
energy sector really the key highlight
there is that 70 times more energy
offense intensive than other commercial
lighting applications right now because
of the amount of light that's required
I'm going to step into that a little bit
more but also looking at the u.s. just
u.s. cannabis market trajectory here
we've got medical and adult use that's
projected here through the year 2025 but
also you can see the huge amount of the
illicit market which is predominantly
using HPS technology right now the
impacts on the energy sector because of
that are just going to continue to scale
up as we go so I wanted to touch quickly
about segments because there's a lot of
people in this room that absolutely know
this information hands down back and
forward but there's some people in this
room we've got a very diverse crowd that
is just brand new to the industry so we
really want to look at what does green
house means sometimes these are multi
acre multi hectare sites that require in
through lighting and in HVAC and reheat
etc to make sure that their crop
production is going to continue
there's also indoor cultivation it can
be very small multi level two tiers
lighting racks whatever but it's also a
very energy intensive environment when
you look at it and our current legacy
install base as far as indoor versus
greenhouse a very important factor that
you have to understand when you're
looking at energy modeling or producing
rebates for these potentially is that
when you're talking indoor cultivation
you're talking sole source lighting so
unless you're using something like sola
tube the only lighting that you're going
to get is from the fixtures that you're
using in your environment however when
you go to greenhouse and you're looking
at the supplemental lighting is what you
have to look at this is where you're
using the existing DLI from the Sun plus
whatever supplemental lighting years
you're using so for a cannabis operation
if you're installing 900 ppfd in this
indoor environment here on the what is
that right on the left you may only be
installing somewhere between 3 4 500
ppfd depending on where you are if your
DL is low or high there's vertical
farming as well that we have to pay
attention to Sam was talking about his
farm earlier and then there's also
research environment which are usually
very tightly honed environments and
require a lot of controls so terms and
baselines and ecosystem let's talk a bit
about this so Nadia was talking about
yesterday how we haven't really touched
on D Li we haven't really touched on
some of these terms let's just go
through some of them really quickly
there's par which is photosynthetic
active radiation this is really just the
light the visible wavelength between 4
and 700 nanometers that is part that is
the light photosynthetic photon flux PPF
is the amount of light that's coming out
of the fixtures so amount of photons
actually that are coming out of the
fixture so this is kind of like the
total number of lumens that are coming
out of the fixtures for the commercial
lighting people ppfd photosynthetic
photon flux density that is how many
photons are actually hitting that plant
canopy or whatever canopy or
so that's what we call ppfd it's kind of
like foot tank put candles think about
that and then there's DLI which is daily
light integral again this is the amount
of light that is hitting over a course
of time so it's a measurement of how
much you're gonna get over 6 hours 8
hours 10 12 18 whatever the time period
is that you need to measure so a quick
little segue for lighting to commercial
or commercial lighting to horticulture
if you've got an office space I want to
really look at the first category which
is ppfd on this chart in a typical
office space you'll have about 37 to 65
foot candles which is equivalent to 6 to
10 ppfd that you will see in an office
space if anybody's got a apogee or a
like or light meter take it into your
office and you'll see 10 or 11 ppfd
for cannabis I mean you can go 7 900
1,500 2,000 and you can see how much
more energy and since of that is I used
to I like to use the little analogy that
you think about all of the lights that
are used in the Yankee Stadium and then
you take those and you condense them
into a large CVS and that's about the
equivalent to what a cannabis grow
operation is and we have to remember
always that our true customer is
actually the plant so we go back to
maybe third maybe fifth grade science
class and just remembering that chemical
reaction behind photosynthesis and what
that means
so our true customer is actually the
plant so we have to pay attention to the
whole environment it's not just lighting
and with that there's different growth
stages so in each of these growth stages
you're going to require a different ppfd
as well so from germination propagation
through veg and bulking going into
flowering and fruiting and finishing you
can have a range of anywhere from 6 10
50 ppfd
up to 900 and beyond environmental
conditions these are really important to
call out as well because again when you
change one thing you're going to
influence another and that's something
about the ecosystem that we really
always have to pay attention
we actually did a study with smut a
couple years ago where we looked at all
of the different systems together and a
straight HP s2 LED conversion for over
to led the first round reduced eighteen
percent overall and the second round
they were able to capture twenty five
percent savings so kc actually touched
on this and the lighting breakout
section the other day but it's always
important to test measure verify and
repeat and then continue to do this over
and over again so you can make
incremental improvements as you go
there's baseline fixture crosses so this
is very important again to the utilities
in the room to understand when you're
going from propagation to vegetative
flower there are definitely certain
technologies that are used a lot in
these different areas and so when you've
got propagation and this isn't like a
complete full list the cannabis cannabis
Energy Report has some and then also the
best practices guide call some of these
out too but you can have some fixture
classes that are quite reasonable now
going from t58 show all the way to
thousand watt high pressure sodium some
more trends are just really quickly
we've got more and more best practices
guides and publications coming out every
day so whether this is something that's
to do with getting grow rooms right led
HVAC something about energy it's a it's
really aggravating sometimes to hear
that oh there's just not enough data out
there it's it's it's coming there's
definitely some data and so just to say
and turn a blind eye that we don't have
the data
Colorado's got some really fantastic
publications and so does California so I
would say please go verify before
there's the idea that there's not data
out there again program trends we've got
state-level programs that we've talked
about already California has this
awesome mix tier lighting for
greenhouses which is six watts and below
or six to twenty five Watts depending on
what kind of tier you have for your
greenhouse and then as far as program
levels efficiency Vermont which is
Lauren it's going to have a nice rebate
program hydro-quebec also has a
prescriptive rebate program right now in
energy trust of Oregon
Doug is in the room they've rolled out a
program through their retail locations
as well and then finally what do
customers want I mean really we have
seen a very very dedicated trend between
lighting sales and where rebates are the
better the rebates the bigger the market
conversion I mean it's just it's been
shown year after year after year and
it's absolutely true the better
incentives that we can get the more
market adoption we absolutely get for
customers and they really appreciate
that that is it for me hi everyone I am
from the design lights consortium and if
you are a utility or have worked with
commercial lighting you're familiar with
who we are we are interested in market
transformation and we promote
high-quality energy-efficient lighting
and we work with utilities manufacturers
energy efficiency programs in order to
transform the market our guideposts are
energy quality and controllability and
that's whether we're talking about
horticultural lighting or network
lighting controls or our major qpl our
big list about solid-state lighting
controls which has half a million
products these are always our guideposts
we are a nonprofit organization we're
located in Boston Massachusetts we have
about 20 full-time staff located across
the United States
our main mode of operation is that we
create performance standards and
standards for utilities in order to use
for incentives we work with federal
local and state organizations in order
to have test methods that can then
inform qualified product lists that help
utilities provide incentives one of our
big outcomes is our qualified products
list we have an emerging one for
horticulture lighting I'm going to talk
about today but we also have many tools
and fact sheets and information that we
provide to utilities so that they
understand what's happening in the
market and of course our goal is to
accelerate energy efficient adoption and
right now that's mostly a
led because it is the most efficacious
light source that we have it's the one
that promises the longest life and the
largest maintenance savings one of the
things I want to tell you about is that
we very much are part of a rulemaking
type of process we're not legislated or
required to have rulemaking but every
single time that we have a draft of our
technical specifications we have a four
to six week comment period we encourage
you to provide your comments to us in
writing or by contacting us and then we
go through those comments we work with
our utility members to revise a
specification then we put it out to a
final draft so please be involved in our
rulemaking process um there will be a
new draft for a horticultural lighting
specification in April so the dlc is a
member organization we're supported by
74 member utilities across the United
States and Canada this is a list of our
utilities there are many of them in the
room so thank you Lauren thank you
seattle City Light very appreciative
this is some new data I wanted to share
with you so one of the things that we
hope to do with our horticultural
lighting specification and our qualified
products list is show the relationship
between the spec and the list and
incentives so this is data from Bob gun
from synergy and basically it shows that
out of the hundred and twenty-two top
utilities United States including DLC
members that about 40% of them are
either referencing the specification or
are requiring the list about another 50%
don't use our list at all but we are
seeing that change quickly and about 10%
of them don't have horticultural
lighting rebates at all so this is
something that we are keeping track of
and are hoping to see change in the next
year so why are you Atilla t's concerned
about rebates why are they concerned
about controlling lighting that's
because when you look at the power
demand the electrical power demand that
occurs in CEA whether it's in
greenhouses for flower or veg or
cannabis or indoor facilities lighting
is the dominant use of electricity in
these facilities and if we can use more
efficient lighting more efficacious
lighting and he'll still have the same
light levels the same DLI that we can
really reduce our power demand so
regulators are of course are concerned
you look at the do a report from 2017 it
predicts that horticultural lighting and
CEA will grow by 15 to 25 percent year
over year and this is concerning the
states that have requirements for energy
efficiency or carbon mitigation and so
they want to keep track of what's going
on so we're seeing some variation in the
rollout of regulations across the u.s.
across the u.s. I know Kate Oil spoke
about this yesterday so what we're
seeing in the market is either lighting
power density limits so basically this
sets the top light level for your light
levels in your facility or a minimum
requirement for efficacy so this is PPF
per watt right light for what in
Illinois we see that Illinois allows you
to use the dlc qpl and you're
automatically able to comply or you can
use an LPD requirement Massachusetts is
similar they also have the ability for
you to give them data about products
that aren't on the DL C qpl and they'll
evaluate them for quality control
California we had a wonderful code
session yesterday is going through its
rulemaking for CEA they're trending
towards using efficacy instead of
lighting power density we're seeing it
in building codes city of Denver is an
example that has a brand new building
code that's gonna go into effect in
April 1st that basically says you have a
PPE threshold or you can use the DLC ppl
that's different for lamps versus
fixtures and IECC the International
Energy Conservation code just passed
through voting a new mandatory
requirement for CEA that will have a
minimum efficacy for these types of
facilities along with a coverage area
for that cultivation space so it's the
Wild West right this is early days in
CEA and horticultural lighting
especially we're trying to bring some
trusted information to growers and
utilities and code bodies and regulators
with a qpl so again we go through a
rulemaking type of process public
comment process where we're asking for
information from lots of stakeholders
but really not only is the qpl about
efficacy but it's about high quality and
what we mean by high quality is a life
in terms of par flux of 36,000 hours or
longer a life for drivers or fans of
50,000 hours or longer and a five-year
warranty and a horticultural safety
certification and if you don't have all
of that stuff you can't be on the qpl so
we worked with DNR Rose is one of the
amazing reviewers for our applications
that looks at the horticultural lighting
products we are very appreciative of
them so we work together to make sure
that only high quality products are on
the list again there's a value
proposition for the qpl for everyone
whether you're a grower and you're
looking for trusted third-party
information objective information you
can look at the qpl to sort by efficacy
or power demand or light or flux if you
are a manufacturer you can differentiate
yourself from other manufacturers by
having this trusted verified data
there's bad actors in every organization
in every field and we are seeing some of
that in horticultural lighting so it's
really good that we're all sharing the
same type of information and of course
my code bodies and utilities or giving
them trusted verified information as
well
the current specification that we've had
since October is version 1.2 the mean
minimum performance spec for DLC is
efficacy and in this case our efficacy
is 1.9 micromoles per Joule we have a 5%
lower tolerance so that products can
comply but any product that's less than
1.9 micromoles per Joule is not going to
be on the qpl our standards so when we
have a technical requirement we are
using is standards and asabi standards
and where to some extent limited by
those standards so for example liquid
cooled fixtures which we would like to
see on the QP l we don't have a standard
from a Saab yet that tells us how to
test and measure those fixtures so that
we know how to look at that reporting
we're waiting for a sabi to complete
that process so that we can have liquid
cool fixtures on the QP l you can see
our technical requirements below we have
almost 70 products on the QP L which is
amazing considering that this has been
live for less than a year one of the
market actors as I mentioned before is
regulations from States so we have a
state compliance filter if you click on
the state compliance menu on the left
side you can actually filter the list by
either the Illinois regulations or the
Massachusetts regulations so for example
this is a screenshot from last week we
had 68 products on Thursday 52 of them
would comply with the Massachusetts
regulations for examples it's a very
easy way to see what works I want to
share some information about the data
with you this is the most current data
again 68 products as of last week there
is no relationship between efficacy and
light output so if you want high light
output products that are for example
equal 2000 watt HPS you can find them on
the qpl same f at the same or better
efficacy if you want low light output
products that are very close to the crop
that you would use for example and
vertical farming you can find those
products with high efficacy as well and
we have easily can see one for one
replacements in all the categories for
fixtures that are currently available
right now our average efficacy is 38%
higher than the most effective HP HP s
double ended products so you're seeing a
big jump and efficacy from commercial
products that are available now as I
said before the efficacy is higher than
HP s again it's it's 2.36 compared to
1.7 but it's only increasing slowly so
sometimes we hear claims about efficacy
increasing rapidly in terms of the
products that we see on the QP l we're
not seeing big improvements yet perhaps
we'll see them in a year
right now it's 24% higher than our
threshold of 1.9 if you filter the QP l
for these state regulations for example
Massachusetts you will find that that
regulation PPE is 16% higher than our
threshold 16% higher than 1.9 but what
happens is there are about a third of
the products fourth of the products on
our QP l that aren't compliant with
those regulations so you would
essentially filter out the products
which means for those manufacturers
there's reason to improve what they're
offering um one of the things that we
used to see a lot is sort of this
blurple yes heard of the term blurple or
pinkish light that you would see in
greenhouses a lot of the early LEDs only
had blue and red LEDs in them we're
seeing that change we're seeing a lot of
phosphor converted white LEDs with red
so you can see among the mix there's
lots of green content
is available among the fixtures about 30
on average the fixtures that we see on
the qpl have about a 35 percent green
component and have about 3% far red
components so there's very few of those
blurple fixtures on the qpl right now
there's no requirement that they have
Fox were converted white or white light
but that's the way the markets trending
and we're seeing that in the products
that are available and that is me my
contact information awesome so I'm
Lauren I mean emergent emerging
technologies and services manager at
efficiency Vermont so I test new
emerging technologies and services not
just in the indoor AG space but in a lot
of different spaces I pilot those
technologies in Vermont with Vermont
customers and then if those pilots go
well then we implement those programs
across the state at a much larger scale
and in some cases in other jurisdictions
as well so this is more or less my
agenda I'll go through why we're seeing
current market increases in Vermont and
future market increases expected and
then I'll talk a little bit about some
programs we have as my colleagues
mentioned indoor grows greenhouses and
hemp are a really big reason for these
increases and we definitely see all of
those applications in Vermont so this is
where normally I'm presenting to a group
that's a little less interested in this
area and so this is where I say let's
get the elephant out of the room
cannabis legalization is becoming really
big about a third of Americans are now
living under fully recreation alized
cannabis and there's an urbanization
movement happening as well typically
younger more liberal folks are moving
from the Northeast across the US to get
cheaper housing and and a lot of and
better jobs so we're seeing this
this phenomenon really move across the
u.s. into states like Illinois as this
mentions another big thing for Vermont
was actually the farm bill in 2020 18
through the USDA we saw a bunch of hemp
come into the state since then and
actually Vermont's in a very unique
scenario where this is not a ballot
initiative it's a legislature initiative
so the legislature has kicked around the
idea of doing commercial legalization
with dispensaries and commercial grows
for about five years in a row and
they've never been able to pass it
they're actually debating it right now
in the Statehouse at this very moment so
it may pass this year and so we'll see
those commercials size grows come online
but it's been a really interesting
market to study because with the absence
of that large cannabis grow we're still
seeing a lot of CEA pop up in a lot of
different areas so it's been really
interesting to watch this kind of
fragmented market still move into the
CEI space even without that main cash
crop driver so some folks got into this
earlier but basically I use this case
study to describe to people that we
really need to scale up our food
production farmers need to harvest in
the next four decades the same amount of
food as the last eight thousand years
that means that we will be increasing
our greenhouse size greenhouses are
about are growing at about 20% year over
year across the US and in about 10%
Inlet area and I would venture to guess
that in Vermont it might even be faster
than this so this is Westland there was
another slide on it earlier but this is
just showing the scale at which we might
need to ramp up in order to keep this
food production going so in Vermont we
also have a big farm-to-table movement
people love out of season produce and
greens in the middle of the winter so
we're seeing a lot of folks use local
greens this is a case study from Peru
Vermont in southern Vermont this woman
grows microgreens
and ornamental flowers in her basement
we see a lot of these small medium
businesses popping up in addition to a
lot of the large cannabis grows that you
all have been talking about so this
woman sells her microgreens to a local
restaurant it's won a bunch of awards
for using local sustainable produce and
that's very common in our state so this
is actually upstate New York customer
right over the border but we also see a
lot of dairy farmers moving to hemp
historically they've had really low
margins or even negative margins in
recent years so moving to hemp is
actually a really great option for them
even if they don't make it they might
make more money than they did in dairy
which is a highly subsidized industry
dairy farmers at the most maybe make 3%
margin so these margins on hemp are much
much better if they do it right
the other thing is they have a lot of
lands we are really scarcely populated
State so a lot of these farmers have
hundreds of acres of land they have
growing experience they have facilities
that they haven't used for a while like
barns that they can dry the hemp in so
we see a lot of them transitioning also
climate resilience so this is the
droughts in California the fires in
California the deep freeze in Chicago
this is a picture of some new Americans
going back to their plots after we had
Hurricane Irene a couple years ago that
flooded most of the state of Vermont and
I hear from these customers all the time
I can't predict the winters like I used
to I can't follow the Almanac anymore I
get random Frost's in the middle of May
that I never had to worry about before
so they're actively looking into
spending more energy in these
greenhouses or or usually greenhouses in
order to maintain their crop they can't
afford to lose a crop in the middle of
May due to a random frost and they never
really had that issue before so we're
hearing more about people trying to be
resilient with their with their grows
and really have backup systems so that
they can they can keep growing
regardless of what's happening outside
John touched on this a little bit as
well but in the utility space we have
been addicted to screw based lighting
for a long time it's been an easy market
it has given us a lot of great savings
per unit large volumes that are
residential and commercial scale but now
that that's over and baselines are
creeping on that we need to find a new
area to get savings and this indoor AG
market is a really great one we also see
that we're serving a lot of markets that
we normally wouldn't have touched people
like low income customers and renters
are some of the biggest home growers and
home grow is legal in Vermont so we do
see a lot of like small-scale
residential stuff happening and it's
really nice to be able to get your foot
in the door with a renter who obviously
who can't really do other anything other
than screw based lighting in their space
so it's nice to be able to connect with
them and perhaps create more
relationships for a future state as I
mentioned we have creeping baselines so
as codes get more and more efficient
we're required to meet those codes and
give incentives on things above code so
this is getting harder and harder for us
as well and then this last one is really
important but utilities are moving from
reducing energy to being really creative
about when we use energy so it's often
about overall grid health now and carbon
in comparison to reduction of overall
use so we're doing a lot of pilots
around flexible load management carbon
impacts things like natural refrigerants
that have really intense carbon
applications and for our distribution
utility partners the people who supply
the power because we're responsible for
saving the power as an efficiency
utility they really care about this they
want sustainable load growth and they
want people to be using energy during
off-peak times because that's the
cleanest form of energy in the Northeast
we have a really really clean grid and
it's getting cleaner in Vermont we
actually buy a lot of power from
hydro-qubec so that is completely
renewable and then we see
dirtier fuels come on to the market and
the distribution utilities are required
to buy things like coal when there is a
peak so we're really trying to avoid
those peaks and be creative with these
customers to understand how we keep them
off peak as they're growing with you
know thousand watt lights every couple
feet so now I'll talk about some
programs this is the first residential
indoor prescriptive program in the
country we developed it alongside
Burlington electric and it's available
for all Vermonters for residential grow
operations it can be any any type of
plant this is what our website looks
like it's a hundred dollars off an LED
grow light and it needs to meet the DLC
specifications we were also finding that
we were basically selling out of read a
I'm selling out of dehumidifiers in the
state so we're also really pushing the
dehumidifier rebates on energy star
dehumidifier because we know that people
are using those for gross so this is
what our rebate form looks like we'll
probably make it a lot more streamlined
in the future but we needed to start
somewhere so we offer $100 we get
minimal information back from the
customer so things like what wattage
were you replacing this with how many
growth cycles per year do you have do
you have cooling in your gross space
like do you use a window air conditioner
and our savings are related to those
things we're getting this information so
that we can hone our savings more and
create better solutions for customers in
the future you'll notice what we don't
ask is what are you growing we don't
care they're using energy it doesn't
matter we don't necessarily want that
information in our books of what they're
growing and this is really open to any
type of residential growers so this is
our savings calculations on what we
assumed for lighting and cooling savings
in the residential space and then these
are the assumptions of what we did for
baseline versus
new wattages so everything on the right
is products that are on our qpl and
actual wattages and on the left you can
see what we kind of assumed they were
replacing in those scenarios this is
something that we'll look back at once
we get more data from customers using
the rebate program to see are we correct
are they actually replacing a 600 watt
light with 345 and then I am super
excited to announce that we just came up
with a guide for greenhouse greenhouse
customers along with an initiative for
rebates around greenhouses right now
they're all custom basically what we'll
be doing is we'll be working with each
greenhouse customer to model their space
to understand the interactive effects of
lighting and HVAC and pumps and watering
and everything that's in that space we
have rebates for thermal currents
coverings like double polyethylene
heating systems both the system itself
and if you're using a efficient
distribution system like radiant
flooring LED grow lights greenhouse
controls ventilation motors and VFDs and
we will probably end up making some of
these prescriptive that was my original
goal with this but it's really hard to
make these things prescriptive we
started to go into these greenhouse
customers and they all had different
square footages different heating
systems different plans they were
growing different things so it was
really impossible at this stage to
create a prescriptive rebate program but
it's absolutely something that we're
interested in doing for this group
I could see thermal curtains VFD uses
more or less already prescriptive and
then LED grow lights as future
prescriptive offerings other things that
we'll be doing is looking into cryogenic
freezers that happened in processing and
whether we can do one for one
replacements with those as well as
drying recommendations we have a lot of
people who are drying hemp themselves on
their
and they use a lot of propane and oil
and electricity to do that this is just
a case study that I'm gonna go past but
um thank you
[Applause]