[Music]
hey everybody this is jason wilson with
the curious about cannabis podcast
thanks so much for tuning in once again
today i'm joined by somebody i've been
wanting to talk to
for quite a while dr ethan rousseau uh
thank you ethan for being willing to
take the time to sit down with me today
thank you
yeah so um and i
i almost struggle to
figure out how to introduce you because
there's so many different angles i could
take
you were um involved at one point in
um getting side effects going and
approved is that right
sure yeah for 11 years i worked for gw
pharmaceuticals
as senior medical advisor and uh
medical monitor study physician in
development of sativex and epidialex
yeah and then you also on the side are
involved in a lot of
um different types of broader research
and education
sure i've been involved in cannabis and
cannabinoid research for 23 years
yeah quite a quite a record and some of
the some of the review papers that
you've
written um have been critical tools in
the education work that i do
like taming thc is now pretty much a
classic
and there was a recent one you did to
the no strain no gain
review paper about you know
the the complex you know what we call
the entourage effects some people call
matrix effects
you know whatever but um
in my opinion you've done some really
good work summarizing relatively complex
ideas that are digestible to a broader
audience well i hope so
one of the big issues right now is
trying to sort out
whether uh people should have single
compounds like single cannabinoids
versus
whole plant extracts and i'm clearly in
the latter camp
yeah for the synergy the boosting effect
that
uh these provide over and above the
kinds of effects that we can get with
single compounds
yeah a lot of doctors and nurses that
i've spoken to
that are doing clinical work with
cannabis products in the united states
a lot of them um it's been a pretty
consistent message
that they've said at this point they
tend to only want to work
with what they term broader spectrum
extracts of cannabis usually like
ethanol sourced
that maintain a wide diversity of
phytochemistry and what they tell me
and what i mentioned to talk to you
about is what research data we have to
to kind of support it but um
they're able to get better outcomes
at lower dosages with fewer side effects
sure
well we can illustrate this by going
back a little bit historically
in 1985 synthetic thc as marinol was
approved by the fda
the thought among certain people at the
time was
this would obviate the need for
cannabis treatment for medical
conditions
instead what we got was a drug that
is very poorly tolerated
and gained no traction in the
marketplace
thc by itself is a very disorienting
drug people tend to be dysphoric
unhappy rather than euphoric
even people who are accustomed to
cannabis
find thc in pure form
a very difficult drug to tolerate and
very few people
remain on it for any length of time and
when people have had the opportunity to
compare almost invariably they prefer
herbal forms of cannabis yeah that's
um that's been my experience too i have
a good friend of mine that
funny enough to treat schizophrenia got
approved for marinol
which is sort of strange
in one in one sense to me but um
he uh reported similarly that he
had some success with herbal cannabis
controlling certain uh positive symptoms
right that he was dealing with and um
the marinol just didn't do
anything that the herbal canvas did
other than making him feel uncomfortable
like physically
um unsettled as is what he reported and
that's the only person that i personally
know that has
been on a marinol prescription sure uh
beyond that
we have now a lot of evidence both
laboratory and clinical
that uh much better results accrue
when we're dealing with complex mixtures
from
cannabis extracts as opposed to pure
compounds
a recent illustration was saw
a an article from spain blasco benitez
at all
in which they were looking effects at
effects
on cancer both in cell culture and in
animals
comparing pure thc with which worked to
some extent
on treating the cancers but in
comparison to a cannabis extract there
was
much much greater activity with very
salient
statistically significant differences
right yeah
i i remember there was some paper i read
that was looking at was it
tnf alpha levels in mice
that was looking at
i don't remember the actual type of
botanical extract that they used from
cannabis
but they were trying to compare to
isolate and look at dose response curves
sure essentially yeah another good
example um
was there was a paper by pamplona in
that compared pure cbd
uh as would be an epidiolex
to the results that people got with
uh cbd predominant cannabis extracts
what they found was equal efficacy but
with the uh cannabis extracts the doses
were about
in on average 22
of what was required with pure cbd
so instead of 1500 milligrams a day
perhaps 300 milligrams saw would be
enough
of the corresponding extract
so this can represent a substantial
savings and cost additionally with the
high doses of pure cbd
there is the possibility of drug drug
interaction
particularly sedation with some of the
drugs that are used in epilepsy
treatment
yeah and i know there's some concern
lately too
and there's controversy of controversy
over some of it but about the liver
toxicity of
high doses of cbd as well well i
i think that's a blind ally to be
truthful obviously
lower dose would be better but um
the liver issues are mainly related to
elevations of liver function tests and
this is
in uh generally children uh
who are in polypharmacy with a number of
drugs
particularly of valporic acid which is
well known for being a bad actor in
terms of
lft elevation um so
my strong suspicion is that's related to
polypharmacy
multiple drugs rather than a specific
effect
of cannabidiol yeah that's a that's an
extremely
good point to make um that the
the risks contraindications and
everything are
very different circumstance circumstance
depending on what a patient is
is taking and i would assume not just
the
other medicines they're taking but even
possibly their diets i know there are
different
dietary elements that can influence yeah
i would just add the point that i've
seen a lot of people
conflate even in presentations at
conferences
conflate the side effect profile of pure
cbd
at high dosage to cbd in general and
that's not a fair comparison um
i would say that cannabidiol
despite its many complex
mechanisms of action as an extremely
safe drug with very few adverse events
yeah and what uh
i mean there's a tidal wave of research
kind of coming out now
now that um i mean especially now that
the farm bill's passed there are a lot
of universities now ramping up to study
cbd and hemp extracts and
um and and in general with legalization
movements happening across
the world there are more researchers
feeling more comfortable
taking on this work but in your opinion
where does the research particularly
around cbd and cbd extracts
need to go um i guess to
[Music]
elucidate some of those nuances that can
help
particularly physicians understand uh
what they're dealing with and if they
have patients that are coming them
telling them they're using
different types of cbd products yeah
well first and foremost as an
issue of the preparation right now it's
sort of the wild west out there
with online cannabidiol products
i can't vouch for the utility or safety
of any preparation
without a certificate of analysis and i
want to know
exactly what's in it not just the
cannabidiol
content but other cannabinoids the
terpene terpenoid content
i want to see evidence that it's safe
that there's no pesticide residue
microbiological contamination or heavy
metal
contamination and beyond that i just
won't comment
and i would urge consumers to be
extremely
diligent in trying to require that
information
my bias is that that information should
be available for every product
rather than whether medical or
recreational at point of sale
so that's first and foremost beyond that
um it really is a matter of what's in it
so we can have cannabidiol but
there's almost nothing that cannabidiol
does
that will not be enhanced by having at
least
a tiny amount of thc on board at all
really synergizes uh these
normally occur together in the plant
uh it sounds corny but that's the way
nature intended it
and that's what usually works best
medically
the effects of a given preparation are
going to depend on those components and
we really can fine-tune things in terms
of applicability
to produce synergies towards
treatment of specific disorders what i
mean is for example
if we want to treat a mood disorder such
as anxiety
we can look for possible synergy between
cannabidiol which
has a proven effect at a certain dosage
plus an additional component such as
linoleul
which is a common component
terpenoid that's also in lavender for
example and it's well known
traditionally
as something that produces a calming
anti-anxiety effect so that's just one
illustration
you know what i'd like to see is that uh
there's a greater appreciation of these
nuances
uh of how cannabis can be tuned to the
individual need
yeah and something i'm interested in too
that
segues into another thing i wanted to
talk to you about which is the
endocannabinoid system is
um i'm interested to see research that
goes into how to
characterize the endocannabinoid system
tone more i think that's really
fascinating sure
well it's a tough one yeah first let's
define some terms
yeah uh the endocannabinoid system is
the master
homeostatic regulator of physiology what
does that mean
well physiology is how things work in
the body
on generally you need a certain level of
activity neither too high nor too low
and that's precisely what the
endocannabinoid system does is try and
keep things
in happy balance so if a system is
overactive it tends to bring it down if
it's
under active to bring it up this works
through
complex mechanisms we have
endogenous chemicals within called
endocannabinoids
specifically two arachidoglycerol
2a g for short and anandamide
anandamide in particular closely
resembles thc
both are partial agonists at
the cb1 receptor the mean psychoactive
receptor in the brain and elsewhere
throughout the body
and what this does at the brain level
is actually reduce the release of
neurotransmitters
so if we have a glutamate
neuron that's stimulatory
the reduction in the release of
glutamate will lower that
activity good example of why that's
important is
we'll give two glutamate
activity tends to be excessive in
neuropathic pain
nerve-based pain so if we have a person
with chronic neuropathic pain
on we can either raise their anamide
level
or supply exogenous thc
and bring that glutamate level down and
that's going to help with pain similarly
in
brain injury whether it be trauma
stroke or things of that sort we get an
excessive release of glutamate
it can be so bad there can be so much
glutamate
that it produces an excitotoxicity
that the cells actually stimulate
themselves to death
we have situations in which people
suffer a head injury
they might seem okay briefly and then
rapidly deteriorate over 48 hours
and some of that effect is from this
excitotoxicity from glutamate
if we're able to supply drugs like
cannabidiol or thc
early enough some of that can be
prevented
and have a much better result clinically
so those would be examples going back to
endocannabinoid tone
endocannabinoid tone is an important
concept but we don't have good ways of
measuring it right
the three important aspects are how much
of the endocannabinoids are present
second is what's the activity of the
receptors
if someone is using thc at high doses
recreationally
the receptor number will actually go
down
it's the brain and body's way of trying
to keep things
on an even keel so the receptors become
inactive when they stop they'll
reactivate
um so there is the number and status of
the receptors
there is the amount of the
endocannabinoids and the third
part is what is the activity of the
enzymes that make
the endocannabinoids and break them down
so unfortunately we don't have ways of
measuring this directly
except with invasive techniques such as
doing a lumbar puncture or spinal tap to
measure anandamide levels but that's
invasive
it's not something you can do on
experimental basis
with most ethics committees for example
ideally in the future we would have
scans
non-invasive methods of trying to assess
endocannabinoid tone but that's a
dream for the future right now right
yeah and
measuring the endocannabinoids isn't it
a little complicated too because they're
produced on demand it's not like they're
stored in vesicles like
a lot of neurotransmitters are yeah
that's exactly right so
these are in a constant state of flux
they're just not there
for any period of time similarly they're
very hard
thing to study um anandamite is rapidly
broken down in the
the bloodstream um so when we are
looking at serum levels which may or may
not reflect what's going on in the brain
the samples often have to be frozen and
liquid nitrogen
and then be transported to a specialty
lab this is not something where you can
go into your local hospital and get your
blood drawn and see what your status is
right
uh we're talking some very sophisticated
science here
yeah and another thing that
comes to mind when i think about the
complexities of trying to measure the
endocannabinoid system tone is that
the endocannabinoid system is not just
cb1 receptors and cb2 receptors it's
it's a really complicated system that
overlaps with a lot of other
[Music]
physiological systems and other
different types of receptors that would
normally
be associated with other other systems
in the body right
well yeah no it's a broadening concept
i asked my friend and colleague vincenzo
de marzo
whether he now would consider the
serotonin one e receptor part of the
endocannabinoid system
and his he didn't hesitate he said yes
how this comes into play is cannabidiol
was shown by my team
at the university of montana back in
2005.
cannabidiol is a serotonin 1a
agonist and we're finding that that
mechanism explains a lot of activity of
cannabidiol
as well as its effect on nausea
prevention of brain damage from
ammonia levels in hepatic failure and a
lot of other mechanisms
another example would be cannabidiol is
also an agonist
a stimulant on the trip v1 receptor
the same place where capsaicin works and
again
most experts consider that part of the
broad concept
of the endocannabinoid system so
what's amazing to me at this point is
for a system that's so
fundamental to how our bodies work
this is not in general taught in medical
school
yeah uh you know somebody can go through
medical school and learn nothing about
cannabis or
accept perhaps it's a alleged addiction
potential
but unfortunately it's highly likely
they won't learn anything about
the endocannabinoid system despite the
fact that cb1 is the most abundant
g-protein-coupled receptor in the brain
exceeding
uh the number of all the
neurotransmitter receptors put together
uh so obviously it's really fundamental
to how
humans work yeah it's it's
um ignoring that system is like having
severe tunnel vision
when trying to think about physiology
considering how
how big of a role it is and when i've
talked to
um other doctors that are not because
i'm originally from mississippi so
very conservative um and
much much uh more of a deficit of
understanding than you know you would
find out here on the west coast and
when i've talked to doctors about it
i've tried to use terms that they might
that might help them put that into
perspective talk about icosinoids
and g protein coupled receptors without
getting into some of the
vocabulary that we have and they they
can start to wrap their mind around that
and around
how the body processes fatty acids and
how important those are for signaling
and everything but it
it's true and i haven't talked to
anybody that's close to it recently
about whether that's still the case if
medical schools are still
ignoring um you know whether
intentionally or not
um a lot of information about the ecs
yeah i'm afraid that's still the case
um yeah there's a quite a deficit there
that i'd like to see rectified
um it is myopic uh
it's intellectually dishonest and i
wonder how much of it is
born from prejudices against uh cannabis
yeah yeah and the
you know i know part of it coming from
where i come from
there's just so much still taboo around
the idea of cannabis and a lot of um
feeling that you're putting your
professional reputation on the line
in order to talk about it in a
in a serious way um that's
one advantage of age i no longer care
about that
yeah yeah what are uh
so i've got two things that came to mind
when we were talking about that
one is i wanted to come back around to
the serotonin receptor concept because
it's been shown that
um some serotonin receptors and maybe
it's it's the one you mentioned because
sometimes i get them confused but
they're often
heteromers with cb1 receptors they often
appear side by side at times and
influence each other
uh yeah that that has been noted in a
number of experiments and to be honest
i don't always know what the
ramifications of that
are yeah yeah um but um
it's always tough uh for me i'm 67
so you know my basic uh science
training was like 45 years ago and
things change radically yeah so
you know i i'm like a lot of people and
[Music]
when i've got a new journal article i
think has
pertinence to what i'm investigating i
may need to read it three times to try
and get it straight
so none of this stuff is simple
there's a problem trying to translate
this into late terms because
the foundation is so broad uh in the
endocannabinoid system and the details
uh can be so extensive
it really defies simple explanations and
to be fair that makes it very tough for
the average physician to be able to grab
a hold of this
when their schedule has them seeing a
patient every 15 minutes
it's just not amenable to providing
a good education to the patient about
anything let alone something so complex
as medical treatment with cannabis or
the
the endocannabinoid system yeah yeah no
exactly they have
everybody has such little amount of time
and mental bandwidth
um to wrestle with much of anything that
to
try to tackle all this is is definitely
complicated and something that i
i teach about is
try to urge people to be cautious
when reading research and trying to
project the clinical value of that
because so much of
cannabinoid research um you know is
cell culture models and rodent models
and a little bit of human clinical data
and it's all interesting
and it there's wisdom to be gleaned from
all these
these different studies but it's you've
got to be really careful
well yeah let's use an example and i
want to go back to the hepatic damage
from cbd
issue there was uh an
article that came out recently it was a
rodent study
the doses of cannabidiol that they were
using
purportedly producing liver damage
would be impossible to attain uh
in a human and somehow this
travesty passed peer review and was
widely reported by the media
it has no correspondence to reality i
just wish that had been sent to me
and i would have done my best to ensure
that it didn't deserve publication
and um this kind of thing
unfortunately this kind of material is
often produced
with uh taxpayer money yeah
and it's more than intellectually
dishonest it's downright dangerous
and unethical yeah and it just
perpetuates
more misunderstanding among um
not just a lay audience but um
physicians and other health care
providers that are working
with patients that are reporting use and
trying to conceptualize what that means
well i know that i got
10 personal queries about it that i had
to address and
dispel what are just furious rumors and
um basically propaganda yeah
um what
what would you say would be some of the
more real risks limitations
contraindications
of herbal cannabis use
and extracts depending however you want
to go with that that you think people
should know about
well we've got a public health crisis
out there right now with
um additives in vape pens yeah yeah
um so i've got to mention that uh
it is important that people
again apply critical thought
uh to any development like this that
actually has nothing to do with cannabis
yeah it has everything to
to do with additives that are toxic
that are put in these devices and so it
can happen
with nicotine vape pens it could happen
with
cannabis vape pens or whatever
but i i i'll put the finger on the
government
um you wouldn't have this situation if
we had
legal commerce federally
in cannabis and had standards applied to
any of these products because this is a
hundred percent preventable
um if these things were available and
regulated properly there would be no
need for kids to be going to a street
corner to purchase
black market vape pens with dangerous
ingredients
so that's first and foremost
very briefly um i'm not a proponent of
smoking anything particularly in a
medical setting
uh vaporization potentially is
a safer approach but when we're talking
about medical uses of cannabis
we're almost always uh talking about
chronic conditions and in that situation
best approaches are for oral agents or
tinctures say in the mouth uh even
and there are reasons for that when that
type of preparation is used it's got a
much longer half-life
basically the need for more frequent
dosing is limited
often people can treat their condition
with dosing two or three times a day
this offers other advantages in that
there are fewer
peaks and valleys of activity you avoid
what can happen with inhalation where
there's a rapid
increase in blood and brain levels that
is
going to uh make a person prone to
psychoactive side effects
specifically anxiety paranoia
things of this sort that are much less
likely
with a slow titration slow raising of
dose
with an oral agent and therefore
the risks of intoxication reinforcement
withdrawal and all these other effects
can be minimized
again the ingredients are key
people need to know and that can only
come through regulation because
it is a situation i can say without a
lot of fear
of contradiction that companies are not
going to
produce lab results unless it's mandated
yeah yeah
no it's all about the bottom line and if
something isn't required
companies are not going to spend the
money
but there's a happy balance there it has
to come
on the side of safety yeah yeah i
totally agree and that's that's a
an area of things i've directly
associated with spend a lot of time
working analytical labs
helping them get accredited and onboard
methods and
i've seen the response from producers
that you know complain about you know
the testing that they're required to do
and the cost of it and you know i'm
always thinking about like
what's that total cost of you know the
few hundred dollars to a thousand
dollars you might be spending on testing
versus the value of the whole
batch of material you have and
everything but um
it is a struggle um and even producers
that say they value
product quality and consumer safety and
everything i
see a lot of that go out the door really
quickly
when they're allowed to kind of skirt by
it's
unfortunate but it is what it is um
what are going back to the
endocannabinoid system a bit and we
talked
about a couple of things but what are
some misconceptions that you think
that people commonly have
about the endocannabinoid system um
i'm sure you have a few in mind
well the main problem again is ignorance
just lack of awareness and this is
across the board it
really man on the street
probably doesn't know anything about it
but again
his physician won't likely either
so a big part of my mission over the 23
years i've been
doing this work has been education
but i think the message i'd like to
impart
is this is an important aspect of how we
work
what can we do um even apart from
drugs to improve
our endocannabinoid tone and there's
actually a lot
the paramount lifestyle approaches
that would affect the system would be
first
aerobic exercise we've got good
data especially from animals and limited
in humans that show that
you improve your endocannabinoid tone
and
overall well-being through aerobic
activity
uh humans weren't designed to be
sedentary as
is prevalent in modern society and the
other one
which seems to be taking on more and
more importance is the microbiome
the bacterial content of the gut
a lot of the ills of modern society
or nutritional and origin we're seeing a
huge increase
in things such as the metabolic syndrome
type 2 diabetes associated with obesity
again this is not normal in human
populations
in contrast um
we're seeing a situation in which
the american diet in particular is
pro-inflammatory yeah
as well as having an improper
balance of nutrients generally too much
but a lot of this can be counteracted by
having a better bacterial balance in the
gut and that can be attained
through eating more vegetables more
fiber
and particularly use of probiotics
and prebiotics and this
can make a tremendous difference in
health and
regulating the endocannabinoid system
and i was going to ask is there any
specific research that you're aware of
that is
currently looking at those links between
the gut microbiome
and cannabinoid receptor expression or
endocannabinoid
production yeah it's a developing area
um there was a very interesting study
that was done in canada clooney at all
that showed uh
that thc didn't uh
uh produces uh
a better balance in the microbiome we
don't see
development of obesity in animals that
are administered thc rather they remain
lean even in the face of
a high fat diet and a genetic
predisposition
to that kind of problem uh so it is a
real
developing area um you know i see that
as really key
and a key lifestyle yeah approach
uh some people can
use this kind of dietary approach and
hopefully not even need cannabis quite
so much
yeah and one thing that's exciting to me
is newer research coming out that's
showing how
different flavonoids interact with the
endocannabinoid system because it
it then opens this discussion up uh
much more broadly um to talk about
i mean and there are multiple reasons
for that flavonoids are one but
to talk about um diet and consumption of
different types of
plants and everything that are also
going to be affecting
cannabinoid receptor signaling and
endocannabinoid production that sort of
thing
and something that excites me about
cannabis in general
as a natural products guy because that's
really my background doesn't come from
cannabis but i've
adopted the realm of cannabis given
what's
going on these days is i like that it's
kind of a springboard for people
learning about other plants and
you know other concepts and
rediscovering that oh maybe we should be
exercising and
eating better and maybe that will help
medically
more so than a lot of other approaches
um one of the last things i'd like to
get into
check our time here we've got a little
bit more time um
going back around to your work with
sativex and looping around i'm sure a
lot of people are thinking
okay cannabis has therapeutic value
there's research going on it's
becoming more and more accepted
there's also a major push by a lot of
companies right now to get cannabinoid
pharmaceuticals developed
so can you and i know it can be kind of
complicated but as
briefly as you feel comfortable kind of
describe to listeners
what it actually takes to get a cannabis
based pharmaceutical or cannabinoid
pharmaceutical
actually developed trialled and approved
because i think that process is a little
more complicated than than folks give it
credit for
ah yeah it sure is um
in most respects the development of a
cannabis-based medicine as a
pharmaceutical is the same for anything
else
but cannabis is a botanical a
plant-based medicine
there's still a common misconception out
there that you can't make a
pharmaceutical from a plant
but it has been done
and even though sativex isn't available
uh in this country it is approved in 30
other countries and it passed
the chemistry manufacturing control and
the safety
signals but basically what's involved
is you have to take your preparation and
show that it's safe through toxicology
this means giving large amounts
unfortunately
to rats and dogs and seeing what happens
then it's put through phase one in which
normal people get are exposed to the
drug in varying amounts
and you see how long it lasts in the the
body in the blood
and what the reactions of people are
monitoring the
side effects if any then
uh it goes to phase two in this moderate
numbers
of patients with a specific disease or
given the drug
and again you're looking for sick
efficacy
safety and then the other factor is
consistency
can you show that your drug if it's a
botanical it's going to
contain many ingredients you have to
show
consistency of each component within
very tight tolerances over the duration
of the drug development program the
final step is phase three in which
large numbers of people with the disease
are given
the medicine again to show safety
efficacy and consistency at a point
where a drug is passed all those steps
it's fda approved and then it takes
about a year
to designate a
schedule you know if it's a drug that
has psychoactive effects it has to be
put in a schedule
that describes what its drug abuse
liability is
whether it has addictive potential how
often
a physician can prescribe it etc etc
and then label is developed and it goes
on the market
so we're talking about generally from
start to finish a seven to ten year
proposition
that will cost anywhere between 700
million and 1.2 billion dollars
easy right right yes yeah no problem but
um so that's one aspect of cannabis
as medicine however as we're seeing now
in this country cannabidiol has been
available in
various preparations
on another level where people can access
it without
a prescription so in the future they're
going to be other cannabis based
supplements
these should be also subject to safety
and efficacy
issues as well as labeling and we've got
a final
uh level or echelon of activity which
would be
someone grows cannabis and may use it in
a medical context
so uh there are these three different
ways
of getting cannabis medicine i think
people make a mistake when they think
that
one level can eliminate the others
much as the government thought that
marinol thc would uh
reduce or eliminate the issue of medical
cannabis uh it never happened it never
will happen
similarly we've got some counterculture
people that
would just like to free the herb so to
speak
and forget about these other areas of
commerce god forbid
a company would make money uh
on something that uh is god-given
um but again those are extremes
of philosophy i think yeah yeah
i agree um completely and um there are
some
you know like you alluded to already
examples of how botanicals can be
treated
in a highly controlled manner um i mean
one example is looking internationally
at how how drugs are handled differently
but even in the united states i mean you
can get
you know like a standardized ginkgo
biloba extract absolutely
and get a prescription for it um right
when i'm advising
patients you know i i indicate just that
um the best ginkgo biloba extracts or
egb61
these are developed in germany where
they have a thing called commission e
which is
analogous to food and drug
administration for herbal
products so these things
can be uh as safe and
effective or even more so uh than
new chemical entities and prescription
drugs
yeah i guess we'll just see how how the
fda decides to
to wrap their minds around all this well
i can
guarantee it'll be a slow process
because the level of understanding is
not there
and it's hampered greatly by residual
prejudices
yeah yeah i think there was there was an
assumption when the farm bill passed
that all of a sudden
cbd was legal and we're going to be able
to make dietary supplements
well yeah i mean there's friction in the
law congress said it's legal
uh uh the fda and the dea
still consider all forms of cannabidiol
apart from epidialxia schedule one
forbidden compounds
yeah yeah and and the last thing that
i've heard
privately from folks that are trying to
interact with the work working groups
with the fda and cbd is that they're not
they're not very optimistic that the fda
is going to
um provide much allowance for
cbd and dietary supplements and and
foods and that sort of thing
now we've seen this in europe already
they have a novel foods regulation
that basically is eliminated most
cbd containing products from the shelves
yeah yeah so we'll see how it goes
um uh before we sign off here i want to
make sure to
to get you going we have a conference to
get to and everything
um is there anything um we haven't
talked about that in the
the last two or three minutes here you
want to
make sure to share with anybody or even
just
bringing up some of the work you're
doing um people can learn more
sure well a big focus of my attention
right now
is um trying to educate and i like to
use the catch term making cannabis safer
and better
and that encompasses a lot of different
approaches
but again i think we need better
genetics
for cannabis this is a very um malleable
plant we can make it do anything
that we want there is not the need in my
opinion
for a genetic modification of cannabis
or to make it from yeast
the full entourage of compounds in
cannabis can
be optimized by selective breeding
without resorting to those other
approaches
and the future is very bright in terms
of
what can be done again i'd emphasize
safety standards should be paramount
consumers need to be asking hard
questions
not just of their doctors but of the
purveyors of these products
and i think marshalling our forces
together
we can greatly improve the situation as
well as the public health
yeah i i totally agree i i know we still
have a long road ahead
as far as education goes and everything
but there's progress being made all the
time and i greatly appreciate the work
you're doing i hope our paths cross
again
and perhaps you know maybe sometime in
the future we'll be able to do some
educating together
um thanks so much for being willing to
to spend the
time this morning to get together and
and talk with me i've
really enjoyed it as i knew i would and
i look forward to catching up with you
again
sometime my pleasure all right thanks
everybody for listening if you want to
learn more you can go to cacpodcast.com
or you can connect with us on social
media just search for curious about
cannabis and you'll find us
thanks so much and have a great day take
it easy
you