so we're the founders of nose botanicals
and we founded our company on a set of
core values so the first thing we did is
we incorporated as a benefit corporation
so that we can never be forced by a
Board of Directors or some situation
like that to change any of our core
principles which is you know to focus on
the sustainability of the ingredients
and the packaging as soon as it's
possible to him child resistance it's a
highlight sustainability but ultimately
to actually use what we're doing with
our products with our company to create
real change in the agricultural space
because when you integrate a lot of the
botanical ingredients that we grow into
us into a conventional agriculture
system like on a hemp farm on a cannabis
farm you not only increase the health of
the plot you also build soil you attract
beneficial insects that fight off
credits or that fight off you know
insects that per day on your plants and
then you increase the value of your crop
because now you're not just pulling
cannabis or hemp out of it you're
pulling calendula extract extract these
can be a high-value essential oils and
at the end of the day if we can create a
very high value high price tag end-user
product that supports systems of
regenerative agriculture that's the
ultimate goal definitely I can't I can't
really say it any better I mean being
able to make doing good work profitable
has been one of the things that have
made me stick in this fight that we can
actually do good works and actually earn
a living doing it is really something
that that sparks my heart that we can
move it forward and I have to say glad I
found a partner that actually believes
in that ideal because
it's out here on the struggle we beans
arise more than a few tips just make it
to trying to make it ends me and so
slowly but surely kind of feel like that
cat hanging in there until this industry
settles down and can actually be an
adult industry where it functions like
regular businesses rather than this
little fledge in the industry that has
regulatory hurdles that cause problems
for us to stay in business but I have to
say a shout out for my friends that are
developing vertically integrated silos
their own cooperatives farms
manufacturers distribution centers we
need to start building our own
vertically integrated silos proper to
living amongst ourselves you know
something like a blue diamond almond or
Ocean Spray as far as like getting a lot
of small farmers to be competitive
against these large large large
conglomerates that are coming after our
lunch we built this industry we we
should not be allowing people that just
can capitalize baked the cake they're
eating it
yeah we're taking our cake back and
we're we're willing to work with anybody
who wants to work collaborate with us if
you want to be competitive then
hopefully we'll see in the rearview
mirror
you know collaborative works moving for
helping the planet helping our fellow
man building up you know equitable pay
you know for people that work in the
trimming industry and these uh we're
trying to make that possible and big
industry just wants to turn it into a
you know cash cow and that means you
know the people that work in those
communities are gonna be undercut rather
than
the good high-paying job it used to be
in these communities we want to keep it
that way that hey and over the last 12
months that's really been something we
cared about a lot so when we were on
stage accepting our award last year it
was like every person who came up to
take their award gave their acceptance
speech followed by their retirement
speech it was like thank you for this
wonderful award it's a great thing to go
out on piece it's like wait ever you're
all giving up and so by the time we got
up there it was like you know maybe if
we all work together we're all here so
we've actually spent the last 12 months
doing something very very non businessí
and very counterintuitive we've been
actively giving a hand up to our
competitors whenever we find them if I
if I run into one of my competitors and
they need a manufacturing space they
need a connection to a distributor they
need a connection to a lab or a piece of
inventory source material
I always always there bro definitely
corporate corporate carpetbaggers
them but you could be my bro and be my
competitor and I will help you out
because you're here you're part of the
real industry and I'd rather work with
someone who I have to compete with in
the market if they're real because at
least we're establishing what the market
is that that true core what the markets
supposed to be oh gosh
I think it was Churchill that said we
can either hang together or fall apart
and that's not seriously what we need to
do we need to build and work together or
we're gonna fall apart they're gonna
take take us and I ain't down for that
and there's still enough market space
left for all of us little guys to have
our brands out there we don't have to
compete with each other we do have to
compete with overly capitalized low
value products that are just kind of
being pumped out there to steal market
share ultimately I think we're seeing in
general in the world that that market
tactic is not gonna fly anymore people
want good and we will never
equivocate on that point we will always
make the best product that we can
[Music]
you