[Music]
I've rolled a few Jewett's
I know you've rolled many joints
I've never rolled a joint on board the
Queen Mary before I'm excited for that
Swami
you're a legend of cannabis cultivation
but you're also got a very specific
joint rolling technique do you think you
can share it with us yeah it's called a
Swami joint that we roll but first of
all like I never started be giving a
seminar and rolling a joint least of all
on the Queen Mary but here we are so
anyway you need a certain number of
things that first of all the rolling
tray is nice and a nice nice piece of
wood is very good and to keep that and
then you I like to use a grinder some
people like scissors or something like
that but with you know really good flour
you need something to really break it up
because actually the quality of the
grind is also very much part of that the
quality of the joint you roll right and
then I have a special tamper that I use
to tamp to join us I'll show you about
that later and then if I don't have this
is my traveling tamper right so I don't
someone doesn't lift this one all right
so this is my it's just a golf pencil
right and of course the lighter and
papers and the papers I do want to put
in a plug elements papers for as far as
I'm concerned are far and away the best
papers they're just beautiful papers
they hardly leave any ash and they're
also very easy to work with so yeah so
then the first thing you want to do is
pick your flower and of course I would
always suggest Swami select right and in
these jars these jars are special
ultraviolet jars that only let
ultraviolet light in so it preserves
your cannabis in a much better way than
it than anyone else right any other way
of doing it
then of course you have your tube to
carry once you got the pre-rolls so now
we're gonna break this up into little
little pieces to go into the grinder and
this will take a little while and sort
of what I think I found is people kind
of lose patience watching me roll a
joint
you know if you really you're not
rolling your joint you're crafting a
smoking experience right and so the
whole thing about the smoking experience
we were talking about earlier right
about how the the joint is the most
efficient way to deliver everything that
the cannabis plant has because so say
for imagine for more of that but this is
your joint and later and the top of it
now has a cinder which is combusting but
before that it's actually you're getting
at room temperature what you just right
so as the combustion goes down what's
back here on your mouthpiece is rising
up one degree at a time one degree at a
time so every different cannabinoid
vaporizes at a different temperature so
when you smoke a joint
you start from room temperature and
eventually you get the combustion so
everything in between is delivered to
you by smoking from a joint and I think
it's the only actual method that really
does that because vaporizers got one or
two temperature ranges only right even a
bowl you're flashing it with your life
yeah you hit it with that lighter and it
all goes at once but with with a joint
you get cannabis that's off gassing at
room temperature and then all the way on
a continuous scale up to the combustion
so I think there's also like there's a
ritual to it that should be embrace
alright now we're getting the philosophy
things on a deeper level because what I
think about cannabis is that one of
these cannabis does is stimulate all
your sensory perceptions right heighten
them and make them deeper but the
rolling a joint itself is really
celebrating the cannabis cannabis
because you have the tactile right you
have the olfactory right and then when
you actually smoke it that's called the
gustatory right the the flavor right but
you also get the sound all right this is
the joint and to clean it out right in
the rinder to clean it out you have to
clap it and so that's like telling
everybody in the room that you're in the
process of rolling a joint now that'll
bring people in from the hills yeah yeah
we call it the Mendocino matingcall
so that's to clean up the joint so and
so the whole idea now is you want to get
a good grind right now if you're making
coffee the best way to do it is grind it
just before and get exactly the grind
you want for weather using a filter or
French press or so on so once again for
cannabis the grind is perhaps one of the
most important things about the quality
of the smoke that you're gonna get with
your joint right so I'm trying to hurry
up here because this takes it what
manufacturing is right now the other
thing about the joint is that the paper
to cannabis ratio wants to be favorable
to cannabis so exec you know the New
York pitter yeah you can pick your teeth
with the New York alright now I have a
good paper I will say however that to
really be able to grow a Swami joint you
almost have to be a grower because
they're gonna be almost innate right and
that's that could be a pretty expensive
joining right but we always share so
that's the thing we always share with
people and so it gets passed around so
on see that so now we're getting the you
do one smell that I do that's what we
call pine angel yeah and that's a cross
of in the pines with I think it's a
turban and what's the consistency you're
looking for on the grind well actually
since every every kind of every cultivar
as we're saying these days not strain
every cultivar of cannabis has its own
kind of textural quality but also how is
it cured is it too dry is it too damp
and so on and so each one is a little
bit different and sometimes if it's
really kind of sticky and lumpy I'll
grind it twice to really get that proper
texture because
and I said before it's a smoking
experience right it's not just you're
getting high you're gonna know you're
engaging all your senses and then when
you do finally smoke it's really you
know you want to really smoke it like a
cigar you ever smoke cigars uh once or
twice once or twice
mostly I cut them open and III think
that coffee analogy is a really good one
yeah because when if you buy pre-ground
coffee yeah it just cannot be of the
same quality as crimes at yourself so
much is released in the first 30 seconds
of the grind
I don't allow more than 30 seconds maybe
45 seconds between grinding and pouring
the water right and it's all those
volatile organic compounds again which
are vaporizing out just like cannabis
same thing if you want to get a really
good sense of the aroma of cannabis that
moment after you grind it is yes well
actually sometimes not always the best
it's curious and the cup we found I'll
break open a bud and I'll get a really
really wonderful thing but then when I
grind it somehow it doesn't mean
everything is unique in cannabis all
right it's not yeah it's always so
unique about now one of the little
tricks about rolling with the paper is I
don't know if you can see that but the
you don't roll a square you'd forget
about the line that they fold and make
your own fold slightly on an angle like
that so you get a little taper close to
the mouthpiece right and it kind of
holds it together just a little what do
they call those trade secret kind of
thing secrets out
oh another now about terpenes you were
exclaiming about the terpenes with the
flowers here and I was reading a a long
time ago I was reading one of Ed
Rosenthal's books and he's got a little
graph there that shows that the peak of
terpene saturation on this graph it goes
like this so just before dawn just
before first light terpene saturation is
maximum it's at its least at sunset
so at a certain point I said okay let's
harvest in the dark so that's when I
harvest the cannabis and I found out
that's what wine people do - you're
harvesting grapes because that's maximum
sugar and actually people going to
farmers market they're gonna harvest
their lettuce early in the morning
because that's when everything at its
peak so when I started harvesting my
cannabis in the dark in the morning my
terpene profile just went right through
the roof well nothing is about in the in
wherever but yeah so that's a oh this is
a little sticky this stuff see there's
two kinds of sticky also they're sticky
because it's not dry enough that's gonna
you'll find some now in November October
and then they're sticky that this is
this is a year old this cannabis and
because it's been in those jars right it
still got that terpene saturation and so
on I'll get you all right so now people
think you're finished ah you're not
finished this is what you now you've
created your tube or your cylinder which
are gonna proceed to stuff full that's
why there's all this stuff left on the
tray your grower yeah some people have
complained I see when I said how come
there's got dirty fingernails Swamy well
there because I'm a farmer for a few
days but yeah so now this is what you do
carefully you tamp it in and then you
squeeze and this is what's great about
these elements papers as long as they're
dry you can really mistreat them right
you like this so I'm squeezing it down
to get all the air about go bubbles out
and so on do it from the other end nice
is gonna take a little while so and I'll
do it from this end right so okay now
this is what gets kind of tedious I'm
just putting this in so what else you
want to talk about while we're do
well how was how was the this year on
the farm well this year our our plants
are gorgeous they're really I've got
with the county and they're allowing us
to do a few more so I've got a few more
plans so I'm slowly expanding which is
difficult to scale up without well on it
right so yeah we've got our plants and
they're they're really gorgeous in green
and big and they're starting to put out
those fragrances and the aromas that
sort of just bring you into the garden
from a long way away yeah it's beautiful
and we're looking forward to a good good
harvest and then we're also looking
forward to the Emerald cup which is
happening this year and I'm you know
kind of a new context with the new
legalization so we're working out a lot
of the details for that but Nicky and I
are still be judging the flowers there
so anybody wants to enter the Emerald
cup please do so look that seems like a
peek joint rolling opportunity judging
the Emerald cup no see what I would do
for them are couples they give us a gram
in an unmarked jar just a number on it
so it's a totally blind contest it's the
only one that's really blind like that
and then we have a couple of weeks to
test it usually and so we test it on we
test it on the look and the fragrance
aroma and the flavor and then finally
the the effects the effects get double
the points right so the look is ten
points maximum the Bliss of a grinntech
Samand flavor ten point maximum when
you're smoking and the effects gets 20s
but one of the one of the results of
that kind of scoring is that the winner
of the Emerald cup has never had the
highest THC because the experience of
looking at it and and smelling it and so
on summoning scores really high
and so we're looking at the total
experience of the cannabis as a smoking
event for the flowers right how does it
roll up you know it's it really dusty on
the tray or something like that while
you want you after you grind it up or is
it super sticky because it's not quite
dry yet because you know the contest is
in December and maybe they harvest in
November right so all those little
things so you know to be perfectly
honest we don't actually smoke all the
entries because not all of our smoking
right it's a shaggy trim it's really
scruffy or something like that that
can't be a winning but in the display
case okay it has no smell no terpenes
well I kind of missed something you know
it's like so I don't even smoke those
too right then I'll get one oh the
terpenes are good looks like a nice bud
it's got some crystal on it though the
the trichomes are kind of golden amber
and all those little signs right and so
you roll it up and then you smoke it and
then all of a sudden I look at Nicky and
I'll see and so you take two hits off
this thing and say okay that's it then
you get one that's really really really
good all right and you say yeah and then
the really good ones you smoke all the
way down to the bottom because that's
sometimes where the best hit yes because
it's kind of accumulation summation of
everything that's come before now see
we're almost there right we're almost
got it's got a little bit more at the
bottom right and it's still it's a
pretty solid joint see it's got that
taper a little bit all right helps it
together so now the other thing is
you'll notice I didn't put a filter in
all right now it's a lot of people
consider a filter necessary kind of a
courtesy or something like that because
the little bits of you know cannabis can
get in your mouth or what have you
so that's that can be an issue for
people but yours at the end woke up I
found I can taste the cardboard in the
filter and if I'm trying to judge
someone's cannabis purely for that it's
not fair to them right and so that's why
I never use a filter because I can I can
said even though unbleached filters and
so on even the white ones you can taste
the bleach excellent yeah so what I do
is I have a I have a roach clip and
that's what I like to do at the end of
the joint is to put it on to the roach
clip you know about these right a little
alligator clip alright you can put a bow
a feather on the end of it if you want
or you know anything like that oh I have
to tell you a little story when I had
originally Alan
anyway the roach clip makes it easy to
pass and the joint doesn't fall apart
and so it's yeah I am until that story
years and years ago I had a roach clip
like this and I had a gold chain
attached to it and on the end of it I
put my Phi Beta Kappa key all right you
know what if I Beta Kappa key is well
tell me well you get its an award you
getting when you graduate from college
because you had I know straight A's or
something so I'm I have this roach clip
I'm a hippie in San Francisco and at a
certain point somebody steals it alright
so I just had to let it go right but it
was sort of something like well not just
stoners not just whatever that you know
I got a Phi Beta Kappa key here and I'm
using it to pass you a roach and let's
share this and let's let's get down to
it right so anyway that's a I'll be on
the DVD extra alright so we're just
about done but apparently because of
various other situations we're not
allowed to smoke it in here you know
there's still a stigma to cannabis and
the smell and so on people people don't
like that so we have to honor that
so on but we can't go outside and smoke
this so is there anything else we need
to tell people because this is your
Swami join um I think there's only one
thing left to do all right
you read my mind let's go to the
starboard thanks for that
[Music]