[Music]
one of the things that I've really
noticed about this industry is moving
from kind of the shadows into the
corporate world is not an easy walk and
some of you have difficulty in really
understanding the kind of regulations
the laws that you are now bound by
because it's legal congratulations and
I'm sorry
so it's it's a double-edged sword
so you know when I talked to you the
owner of a cannabis company and I say
you can't call every single one of your
employees contractors or you can't give
everyone a salary and call it a day you
just can't do that anymore because of
wage and hour laws I get a little
pushback and what I hear most is well
that's the way I've always done it and I
get it totally get it totally understand
and and really it's my job to to help
you understand to very gently help you
understand why now that you are legal
you're in a legal industry you really
have to start paying attention to some
of this stuff and it's not it's not
interesting it is not sexy it's not fun
it's it's the law and we'll have Rocco
go into that into more detail but really
my purpose in helping out the cannabis
industry is to really look at the little
guy the up-and-comer that has a small
company has you know maybe a couple
three ten employees and we need to get
you poised to really to grow and to grow
in a way that you're going to be
protected because there's a lot of
little nuances out there that you have
to be aware of you know now you're
looking at wage and hour laws now you're
looking at you know employee versus
versus consultant you're looking at a
lot of things now that you didn't have
to look at before you know I'm not
physically May
you money but in the long run we save
you money you know by making sure that
you're compliant I'm a labor and
employment lawyer by trade and I'm
geeking out in sort of a nerdy way that
there is an event like this happening in
the cannabis space I came to cannabis
through labor employment law with a lot
of my traditional clients outside
cannabis saying hey somebody who came to
work and they tested positive for
cannabis I heard it's legal in
California can we still screen them out
from employment standpoint a lot of our
clients were doing business with the
cannabis industry selling them bags or
glass or other materials and saying how
do we how do we work with this industry
so coming into it several years ago and
and then launching a cannabis practice
group and being really focused on the
front end with regulatory reforms and
licensing and whispering in people's
ears for the last five years hey you
probably should pay attention to labor
and employment law at some point it's
it's exciting that we're actually there
and people are getting past the
licensing point and and now starting to
look at these issues in addition to
being a labor employment lawyer and a
partner and a firm here in Los Angeles I
also serve as the HR committee chair for
the California cannabis Industry
Association and if there's anybody here
who works in HR or who wears the HR hat
for their organization I would plead
with you beg you
please come see me so that we can get
you wrapped into that group there's some
very good people some very sophisticated
some very smart people on that committee
but the thing that I have trouble with
is reaching out and getting a lot of
industry participants to come and share
sort of their headaches and what's going
on and as a as a CCI a chair we're
really trying to deliver information and
practical advice to the the industry so
I can tell you what I think is important
but if it doesn't really land for you
guys
it's it's a waste of time in those
discussions with the CCIA the work that
I'm being asked to do for clients inside
the cannabis industry my number one
concern is as Lynn alluded to is the way
people are paying people in cannabis and
I get why it happened it's a banking
issue and people came out of a cash
based system with with no ability to
bank and a lot of cash sitting around
and it's just easier to start calling
people paid volunteers which is sort of
an oxymoron or a contractor or or
whatever you want to call them and pay
them cash and quite frankly a lot of
times pay them very well in cash but no
good deed goes unpunished to businesses
in a regulated market and I will tell
you without going too deep in the weeds
if you're not if you have employees that
are working for you people that are
doing what it is you do as a business
people that don't work for companies
outside of you
those people are employees if you're not
treating them as employees if you're not
calling them employees and if you're not
paying them the right way
today it's okay but the statute of
limitations on a wage and hour claim is
for years and it's not unheard of for us
to settle class actions for wage and
hour liability in the millions of
dollars they will kill your business and
it's little things along the way in
terms of the way that you classify them
the way that you track their hours if
they're they're eligible for overtime
wages the way that you pay them those
little things can be set up on the front
end for you to be successful in the long
run and for those of you that think well
Dean I can't get a banking relationship
or I have difficulty with the payroll
solution I will tell you that it's an
increasingly problem of the past so come
find me come find some of the other
people that are out here we can help you
solve that sort of a problem so the wage
and hour piece is a very very big
problem for the industry I see a
receptiveness to changing but but we
have to get better there and the other
part beyond the way we pay people the
way that companies are set up from an HR
standpoint in terms of onboarding people
having policies and procedures dealing
with issues as they come up
quite frankly a lot of small cannabis
companies were started on a handshake
with a couple of friends who knew each
other from past business dealings the
more sophisticated you get the more
money you take in from private
investment the bigger you grow the more
employees are going to have that no
longer went to college with you that
were no longer or referral from your
relatives and family members and if god
forbid there's a downturn in the market
and you have to start laying people off
or firing them the tide will come out
and if you're not doing things right in
terms of the way that you manage people
as employees talk to them about their
performance issues when you go to fire
them if it's a surprise you're going to
get wrongful termination discrimination
retaliation claims and so there's a lot
of again very simple things that you can
do on the front end to build your HR
function to have policies and procedures
in place to teach your managers how to
deal with people on performance issues
that can really manage a lot of that so
those are really the two big things that
I see on the front end is we come out of
licensing and everybody's cheerful that
we got that license that we've been
struggling to get for the last year now
that you go back to running your
business and trying to move at a profit
those are the main two things that I
would encourage everybody in this room
to focus on in a short time and I would
also like to add that in through my
years of experience one of the saddest
things that I've seen you know in in
businesses just any kind of business is
the people that you're closest to
building it are the people that
sometimes you have a really severe
falling out with I've seen so many
managers that have had one employee and
they're just the best best of friends
and then something in the in the
business changes maybe financially
you're having to make cutbacks maybe
you're having to decrease pay because
financially you're just it's either
decrease pay or lay people off and I've
seen really strong relationships go sour
quickly and it's so hurtful to everybody
involved so in order to protect that
it's it's really a good thing to put
policies and procedures in place and and
the one the one word that I encourage
you to stay away from for your entire
career is special it's a special deal
he's a special case that word will get
you in more trouble because everyone in
the company will want to be special so
it's really good to put policies and
procedures in place and I don't live and
die by policies I don't care what
policies you put in place but once you
put them there you know you really need
to try and adhere to them and it's
really it's it's Italy it's give a
spirit of fairness to your staff and you
know if you're fair to your staff
company-wide
you kind of alleviate a lot of issues
throughout your entire you know
experience in a company so the one word
you want to stay away from is special no
special treatment no special people
those are the those are the issues that
will you will see yourself in so many
meetings with other employees because
you you treated somebody else better or
you know you can tell them don't tell
how much you make
they're gonna tell they're gonna talk
they're going to tell so just try and be
fair and equal to your staff and it will
it will actually help you in the long
run yes so karen is our next speaker and
she's going to talk about the
requirements for food safety and the
regulations and the core principles
Thank You Lynn my name is Karen Clark
and I'm the lead California trainer for
cannabis trainers and thank you Courtney
for having us here tonight and Peter so
how many of you guys are manufacturers
of cannabis Goods and how many of you
are dispensary owners the state requires
that anybody that manufactures cannabis
products have to have has to have a ANSI
certified food safety program in place
within 90 days for any one of their
employees who is part of the process of
creating your cannabis manufactured
goods as of today in the state of
California we have certified
approximately 11 manufacturers of
cannabis Goods that number sucks so I
know that there's at least 11 of you
here and I've only seen one person in
this audience that I've actually given
the serf safety certification class to
how many of you guys have 30 is how many
of you guys have had your employees do
the serve sake certification class oh
come on so you guys are talking about HR
we have been providing these surf safe
certification classes for decades it's
the traditional service aid class we
customized it completely for cannabis
and it's a traditional three and a half
hour class it's good for three years
your employees can take that
certification to any manufacturing
facility that they go to and we also
have for the dispensary owners we
provide a class that is a similar to
responsible alcohol program it's a
responsible vendor program and we teach
your employees your main
and sometimes owners of dispensaries
invert in regards to the state
regulations for safety checking IDs
security what the law is about selling
cannabis so we basically have a
responsible vendor program that helps
you keep your employees trained at the
state level it does not require or say
anything in specifics about what the
training needs to be but the local level
is where the requirements are for a
responsible vendor program we actually
have had several counties reach out to
us because in their local jurisdiction
in their cannabis regulations at the
local level they have a responsive ended
program written into their local
regulations that requires the employees
to be trained at a local level excuse me
of a budtender level or even manager
level before that employee starts
working on the floor so we have had
those counties reach out to us we've
provided them our curriculum they've
approved it and we have gone all the way
out to Mono County in Mammoth Mountain
and done responsible vendor programs to
two of the dispensaries out there
there's several more of them that are
coming on board the reason why training
your employees is a value is that it
creates a retention for you as an
employer so if you train your employees
and they know what's expected of them
they're more than likely to stay you
have provided camp key performance
indicators for them to know what's
expected of them when they arrive at
work and also what the law is what the
regulations are and what the
requirements are for what they need to
do to do their job like I said at the
surf safe requirement for the food
safety class that's a requirement of the
California Department of Public Health
and you have 90 days to have your
employees trained in that servsafe
certification and when the regulator's
walk in to do a certification of your
facility and they give you a pass at the
Department of Public Health level and
they see a whole bunch of servsafe
certifications all over your kitchen
they smile because they know that this
this manufacturer has taken the
necessary steps to certify their
employees for food
I mean I've walked into some food safety
into some manufacturers and there's been
barrels of acetone with no lids on them
in the kitchen and I'm like what are you
guys doing you can't have this in your
kitchen this is like completely
prohibitive and they're like what like
what right back get it out you can't
have this in your kitchen so her
question was it does an individual have
to be part of a company or a
manufacturer of cannabis goods to take
the serve safe certification class and
the answer is no they do not have to be
part of a manufacturer a cannabis
manufacturer they can come take the
class anytime my name is Jacqueline
shuttin I'm a researcher with UFCW Local
770 we're in labor union that represents
retail and food workers along with
pharmacists in LA County Ventura County
Santa Barbara and San Luis Obispo County
we've been fighting for legalization
marijuana legalization since 2011 so
we've been very invested in this fight
we do currently represent cannabis
workers and I think I imagined a lot of
people want to know about the LPA
requirement is that what you were about
to ask as you probably all know you have
to have a signed labor peace agreement
with a bonafide
labor union in order to get your your
annual license what that means is you
have to sign an agreement preferably
with us to UFCW that says that in the
event that we organize your facility you
have to remain neutral
you can't talk bad about the union you
can't you know managers can't try to
influence both in exchange we want
strike we want boycott we want in
your business this is a requirement for
anyone in the city of Los Angeles to
have 10 or more employees and in the
state of California it's 20 or more and
San Francisco is also 10 or more I doubt
anyone's here from there though oh okay
well there you go
so so this signing this labor peace
agreement does not say that we're gonna
come into your facility the next week or
the next day to organize your workers
it's safe you know this is an agreement
that lasts three years of the week and
so you know we we have a team of about
six that's not enough to go in and
organize every every dispensary or
manufacturer even this year really you
know our goal is to have a strong Union
workforce in cannabis from seed to
retail location to set you know good
wages to set the standard you know to
make sure that the people that are doing
the work in this industry are taken
cared for are you know that no one's
violating labor law which you know
there's hopefully there's other people
that are involved that are trying to
make sure that doesn't happen and
essentially just to make sure that the
workers who in a lot of ways have been
with this industry for years you know
continue to grow in it and continue to
it's a it's an industry where you can
raise a family you can have a dependable
paycheck that you can you know get paid
by a payroll company that if you do get
laid off you can collect unemployment
just you know things like that to make
sure that there is a standard in the
industry so that's that's kind of the
basis for it I think a lot of you are
probably I don't know if anyone's
applying in phase two in LA but that
would be you would have to you know
either sign that labor peace agreement
before submitting your application or
essentially make a promise to sign one
if you know your business isn't up and
running yet
I just want to maybe have deemed touch
on the ability now to get a bank account
to to pay your taxes to pay your
employees through a payroll company and
you said that there's been a lot of
strides and making it more accessible to
the cannabis industry can you talk about
that a little please I'm sorry
you can make yeah you want to sign a
labor peace agreement with a union we
you know then fighting for legal is date
we're the only union that's been
fighting for legalization it makes the
most sense we already represent workers
you know we have no union is dedicated a
team to cannabis like us we think it
makes the most sense not just you know
for us but for our you for the workers I
mean so but yes you could choose any
union you want it's about a six page
agreement that states you know it lists
out particulars if we send a letter of
intent to organize for example you would
have to send us an employee list within
10 days it states that you know if we if
we if basically it outlines what happens
if we if we submit an intent to organize
so it just lays out that process it lays
out you know within how many days we you
you know both the company and the union
has to provide each other with certain
information it just it's really and
normally we don't have to actually even
refer to the labor peace agreement we
have good relationships with cannabis
business owners we've been working
alongside each other so this is really
in the case that things you know get
really ugly but it's really just kind of
a lot of common sense things that we
would get you know an hour of time to
talk to the employees about the union at
some point so just you know some
particulars like that and I'm happy to
forward an example of the labor peace
to anyone to any business owners who are
interested come talk to me at the break
and I'm happy to share information and
share the share the agreement just to
piggyback off that so if you're a member
of CCI a we can reach out to the CCI a
HR committee and there's a model
agreement that CCA's or has sort of
blessed and we can talk with you about
that there are certain just answer your
question there are certain things that
the law says have to be considered and a
number of other things that are sort of
open to negotiation between the Union
and cannabis business so but yeah there
are some forms floating around it so the
question is whether our goal is to is to
organize all the workers in the industry
or just essentially workers who need it
the most who have been victim of labor
law violations we would like to organize
the whole industry we want to set the
standards we want to make sure that
every workers you know getting paid more
than minimum wage getting paid overtime
you know doesn't have to deal with
sexual harassment you know eventually
you know you have to sign the labor
piece if you have ten or more but if you
have fewer workers that doesn't mean
that you're you were never gonna try to
organize your shop it just means that
process won't be we won't have you know
we won't be bound by the process of the
LPA but you know it's our I mean that's
you know labor unions as a goal that's
you know that's what they they're
looking to organize an industry to make
sure that there aren't certain bad
actors who get away with taking
advantage of their workers and you know
it's really to set a floor for for
everyone and again just to sort of echo
that I I think if you are sitting in the
room and you're worried about being
unionized or you're not sure about it
the easiest way to get unionized is to
not pay your employees the right way
have dangerous working conditions don't
carry workers comp have somebody get
injured at work it's very easy for a
union to come in and address all the
things that you just laid out to say
they're not taking care of it so we'll
take care of it for you
as an employee group so there is a
there's definitely a balance real
quickly if you could just touch on the
banking and peril in taxes yeah so one
of the things that the federal
government has kept in place
notwithstanding the revocation of the
Cole memo is the Department of Treasury
is still requiring banks who bank
cannabis money to file marijuana and
Limited suspicious activity reports and
they're actually encouraging banks to
bank it so that there is some certainty
and people aren't sort of hiding loads
of cash under mattresses if you look
that the fencing department that is
involved in receiving and outlining what
those reports look like publishes
statistics on how many banking
institutions are actually filing
marijuana suspicious activity reports
and contrary to the news that you're
hearing that nobody's banking marijuana
hundreds of banks are filing suspicious
activity reports right now so the
banking has happening and even if you
can't go into your current bank there
are probably other banks that if you're
out in the open about it and you tell
them what you're doing will bank it I
know for example with the unions if
that's a solution and a partnership that
you want to make some of the unions will
allow you to use the unions banking
facilities to do the payroll for their
unionized employees so there's a lot of
solutions that are out there
my without endorsing any single one of
them my message to everyone in this room
is just go find one
so that you understand if you're not
paying you can pay people cash by the
way and still give them a pay stub it's
complicated as hell it's a pain in the
ass and you'll probably go through an HR
director every three weeks because
they're having to do payroll on killing
them so right okay she's she's for
hire she's right but you can still do
that at least give them a pay stub but
if you set up a pay roll relationship it
will give you the ability to track
people's hours and then pay people based
on the hours that they actually work and
if they work over eight a day or work
over 40 in a week your payroll system
will be set up in a way that it'll
automatically calculate the overtime
hours and all of the deductions and
state payroll taxes will be set up and
we'll go through that bosses all of that
is going to give you documentation of
what you're doing you'll be able to show
that you're paying your employees the
right way and so if people leave and
they're jaded or they're there they're
upset with you and they go to see a
labor attorney or they go downtown to
Los Angeles and they file a claim with
the DL SC and they go in and talk to an
agent and the agents first question is
going to be let me see your payroll
records and if you're doing some of
these basic things this is not
complicated stuff if you're doing some
of those basic things the DL se is not
going to take that claim that that
plaintiff lawyer down the street is
going to tell them it looks like they're
doing things right but if they walk into
the DL se or they walk into a lawyer's
office and they say well they pay me in
cash and I don't get a pay stub and they
don't record the hours that I work that
lawyers once you start drooling and
you're going to see a multi plaintiff
case land on your doorstep and they're
gonna say pay up or we're gonna take you
to court and put you to put this out
into the public
maybe expose your business that maybe is
not fully licensed yet the government
scrutiny I'm a lawyer but I can I guess
that means I can tell a bad lawyer jokes
lawyers are not very nice people
sometimes and this is not by the way
always for the benefit of your employees
it's for those lawyers to get lawyers
fees out of it right they're trying to
collect money
you're paying so if you give them a
low-hanging fruit piece of a piece of
fruit case where they can just go this
is a slam-dunk winner they're going to
take you and they're gonna extort
they're going to maximum settlement
ality so those are the sort of things
that a banking relationship a payroll
relationship just naturally will blossom
those those sort of compliance issues
another thing to take that just a little
bit further is forget about the lawsuit
that the employee is going to put on you
but the state of California payroll tax
is going to come after you and the state
of California when you are not paying
payroll taxes on your employee they look
at that as you're stealing money not
just from the state of California but
also the employee and they're far more
ruthless than the IRS in the state of
California if you owe them money from
the federal government of the state so
not paying your employees appropriately
not just gets you in trouble with a
lawsuit from your employee but the state
of California is going to definitely
come after you for that
I've spoken with several of them some of
the some of the the EDD officers and
they sit in the they used to sit in the
parking lots of dispensaries and count
how many people walk in go in as a
patient count how many employees there
are go back to their office look up the
address and see how much payroll tax has
been paid and file right then so this is
a this is not a joke this is something
that's very serious and I know all about
that stuff so please you know take this
stuff very seriously
again piggyback off of that I've sat in
so many conference rooms across the
attorneys like him and he's going to ask
for every document every the first thing
he's going to ask for is your handbook
the next thing he's going to ask you for
is your payroll records so you know even
though it's a pain in the butt
and again it's not fun it's something
that you really as an employer need to
have I've talked to several of the very
large payroll companies out there and
asked them if they would take on
cannabis clients and they say yeah
they're not really excited about it yet
they say they can take on a cannabis
company as long as they don't have a
conspicuous name so it has to be
something that has nothing to do with
cannabis itself which I don't know how
they determine that but I know that
there is one company and if you ever
want to get in touch with me that that
does handle cannabis industry but it
really is better
to to to just get this taken care of get
somebody in who knows how to do it knows
how to handle it and just get it taken
care of I promise you in the long run
when you do get sued because these
employees have just as much access to
the law
and they research and if you make them
mad they're going to start coming at you
so you want to protect yourself
you
[Music]