all right well we're here with hallie
and micah from humboldt seed company hi
guys how's it going hi how's it going
man doing great thanks for having us
today thanks exciting to finally all get
to meet up again and who's this little
guy this is milo he's basically the team
mascot
makes sense makes sense looking forward
to it um okay so what makes this
interview slightly different than the
other ones we've been doing is that
we've been interviewing farmers and
they've been showing casing their
flowers but you guys are a seed company
yeah so if there's humboldt seed company
and can you tell us a little bit about
how that got started you know like the
background from your dad and what he did
to get that going yeah i mean honestly
when it comes down to it our creation
kind of happened organically basically
what you know started was my dad had a
need for reliable seed back in the day
he you know he had had a kid very young
and he was working for the local
fisheries department but we all know
government jobs don't really pay enough
for a family of three so he had his
little crop going and he you know
started getting seeds from his buddies
and sometimes they'd work out great and
sometimes it would basically just come
out like mexi ditch weeded there was no
way of knowing at the time
and you know this is when straight four
thousand dollars a pound
but you know then it was like strains
almost didn't even really have a name
like there was like you know probably 10
different things floating around getting
called salmon creek big bud right and so
he basically just started kind of
holding on to the things that he liked
and actually saving males and then doing
breeding for his own personal use and it
went from that to neighbors suddenly
being like wait why do all your plants
look uniform and like
you know
solid they all smell the same and he's
like well that's selective breeding for
you and so next thing you know the
neighbors all wanted seeds and then they
started sending their friends to get
seeds and eventually my stepmom at the
time was like
you can't keep asking folks to bring you
a six pack of beer and you know come
pick out their seeds you're getting fat
and we're broke
is what it came down to and so that was
honestly the turning point where he was
like maybe i should start charging for
these things that's amazing and that was
way back in like you know i think we
probably didn't ever start charging for
seeds until like 2004 2005 but that's a
long stretch though he's been breeding
since 1998. yeah that's amazing so yeah
i mean from going from that and being
able to you know kind of launch into the
recreational market having an arsenal of
like very stabilized seedlings i think
has been a major advantage to us tonight
our goal has always of course just been
like to expose quality sun-grown flower
to consumers that haven't experienced
that before yeah so to be able to kind
of have our foot in the door already and
to be able to just launch and be ready
to go doing that yeah it seems like you
guys hit the ground running for sure you
know we've we've been
gathering and breeding and hoarding
seeds for decades now so speaking of all
that i mean what are some of the like
management practices like i know mike is
on the farm yeah like what goes into
some of that well we're doing mainly a
lot of feminized breeding so we're doing
we get our dads and we're keeping our
dads and we're switching them and then
we're putting them in these cloths that
protect the pollen
and keep it from cross-pollinating it
just kind of keeps everything like
steady
and then we um it's amazing yeah we just
we go and we do our thing in there yeah
bring the dads in there one thing that i
have to say is like big kudos to all
these guys who take care of our farm
because obviously micah has had years
and years of experience cultivating but
what we do yeah we used to work together
scientific and so much more dialed in to
the point where we're keeping track of
every single plant and what it's doing
in a field of 10 000 plants yeah the
female the great pinot hunt exactly when
we do a lot of selective breeding and so
you know micah is one of the people
that's responsible for you know say a
specific chamber like hella jelly
chamber he's responsible for keeping an
eye on the potential selections that
we're going to save for breeding all
year long yeah walking by them every day
and you're like kind of just looking
like that one's the best one
like right no it's fun yeah no it's so
yeah it's it's fun and i know you're
definitely like a rabbit hole nat does a
lot of
genetic testing he does a lot of testing
and then he's also got these outsourcing
projects where he's like you know these
huge female hunts are going down so
genomics is really interesting been
really important to us and you know
there's a lot of people out there
not to shame like any kind of breeding
because i think it's all with a purpose
and you know it's all interesting but
when it comes down to it if you're just
throwing pollen on something that really
is just pollen checking it's not
breeding selective breeding and focusing
on genomics is a whole different level
yeah back crossing it and getting it to
s1 and like super just straightforward
you know that's the main goal really
pretty much interesting yeah it's
fascinating stuff it's always been an
interest of mine so it's cool having you
guys here didn't talk about it no i mean
i think it'll it'll stay fascinating for
a long time in my opinion because you
know this industry as new as it is i
mean obviously it's not new to us but
it's new to a lot of people and we
haven't had the opportunities to do such
intense genomic testings to work with
labs like uc berkeley in the past
because what we were doing at the time
was illegal and so now it's opened a lot
of doors as far as advancement and
learning about the streams and you know
learning about the effects of different
cannabinoids and terpenes and so i think
you know the more that we dive into this
the more our minds are going to keep
being blown because this plant it's like
it's amazing yeah it's never ending
wonders i know right i was talking about
finding the unicorn you know i know it
leads me into so many different lines of
questioning about that like you know i
mean what do you guys see in the future
you guys obviously you're working hard
and and trying to develop new products
like do you see anything interesting in
the future like you have future
developments you know we've kind of
learned to not get like too excited by
you know the new crazy thing
like back in the day i think the first
thing was like cbd and we did do like a
few cbd lines and we got kind of into
that and we're like is this going to be
like the next huge thing is this going
to take over like what we've learned is
like following hype trains really never
works out for us
and so like we kind of just like follow
our heart
yeah
what we think is going to be bomb
because like i'm sure you know like when
you walk through the field and you find
one of those unicorns you fucking know
what you want yeah excuse my language
but like
you know you're in a field of 5 000
plants and you think it's impossible to
pick that one winner but when you find
it you really do know it's just like you
see it and it you know blows your mind
you smell it and it blows your mind
too you know it's like
when you take a clone and you you know
you take it back and then you kind of
get to run it you can have that forever
you know once you turn it to a seed yeah
and we've been doing that a lot with our
r d process now for when we you know we
go and we do our phenohunts and we have
our winter selections we will propagate
enough cuts of that to at least run it
one full sun one light depth and you
know one indoor mix light as well
so you know we want to see what it
represents in any environment but really
like
we breed for soul full sun product
because i mean you know in my opinion
and
it's honestly one of the things that
like i've had to really like teach
myself that not everyone knows it's not
logic for everyone but to me i'm like
sun grand flower is what it's all about
i love that
the widest expression of the plants yeah
full potential
potential yeah yeah for sure well
speaking of sun grown what do you guys
uh what's your favorite
you know what what are your favorite
seeds that you like to smoke like out of
the seedline what's your favorite
that's always a really tough question
for me but this year i think i'm i'm
really rooting for the farmer's daughter
strain not only because it was a little
bit of a homage to myself
but you know i think that overall that
one definitely has potential for full
sun cultivar cultivators to be getting
you know higher yields higher thc but
also still having that bag appeal that
we're all looking for what is the uh
what did the genetic
the the cross you know the cross is um
that one was our humble pound cake times
what was the rest of it was it wedding
train i think it was wedding
oh wow so it's definitely super cakey
kind of purple big chunky nugs nice yeah
amazing what about you michael what do
you like
like i'd say my all-time favorite so i
have
definitely an all-time favorite and then
a new favorite you know my all-time
favorite probably the blueberry muffin
oh yeah i smelled some of that dave it's
so good yeah yeah i could make it like
literally smells like blueberries but i
think my new favorite would probably be
the potty mouth potty mouth yeah it's a
weird crazy cross we did of uh
is it
was it humble pound cake times mountain
top mint
yes i think that's what that was yeah
and that one's just it looks like we had
it grow in full sun and it looked like
indoor was the amount of leaf to nug you
know oh yeah crazy yeah yeah no that
one's a really unique one honestly that
was another one where like i won't ever
forget the day where we really like
fully we were out there taking cuts and
it came from our own farm actually which
is good
but we went up to it and we were like no
this one's the one it just has like
these crazy you know trichome covered
potty bracks basically it's like a
structure it has a great bag appeal to
look at that i keep hearing about it but
i haven't looked
um and then obviously you guys got a big
autoflower line yeah we've been we've
been putting a lot of focus into our
auto lines to be honest like even
personally when they first kind of
started to come around and i you know
did our first little r d batches of the
ones that we'd gathered from you know
corners of all over the world where like
we don't know about these they're like
you know kind of larfy kind of small
kind of
but like as the years have gone on like
man i have to say i never thought i'd
say this but some of them are really
like standing up to photo period lines
for sure they're testing high they're
getting chunky they're getting dense and
they're like frosty yeah they have those
gorgeous frosty representation one thing
is like you know they don't really have
nearly as many environmental factors
that they have to deal with because it's
such a short flowering time and because
they're just kind of doing their own
thing it's like if you plant them in the
optimal timing you're not dealing with
like rain you're not dealing with they
don't really care about sun
oh i know they're hearty i yeah your
dad's been kind to me and he's helped
over the last few years i've been using
some of his autos in the spring and it's
been really interesting watching the
evolution of the quality yeah and then
also just the potential of the plant you
know planting in may or ape actually
april
end of april and then watching the plant
grow
not having to do anything with spraying
at all they don't have they're just like
the heart i don't know something happens
with it yeah they go i think the plants
like are shifting so rapidly they're not
releasing the same hormones during
flowering or something's weird's
happening it's kind of crazy how they
they're not attracting veg at the same
tests as much yeah i've noticed that too
actually and i mean that's something
that you know we should definitely look
into a little bit more from a scientific
stance but if i was going to guess i
would say that it's probably something
similar like you know the the hormones
or even
it's maybe you know it's just something
in the root or alice trait itself where
it's just not as susceptible or the
secondary metabolism yeah the router
allows might have some other secondary
metabolites that it's producing that
we're not quite
tuned into but yeah it's really cool
it's really fascinating watching it so
they've been a huge advantage to like
honestly a lot of growers these days
especially when you know i i highly
recommend people who are doing full term
do an interplanting project where you
kind of just put an auto right in
between oh yeah yeah yeah
you're paying for every square foot you
might as well try to get as much out of
it as possible yep yep it's so
interesting yeah it feels like the way
humboldt seats heading it's like pretty
soon the autos are going to be you're
just going to have
whatever variety you want eventually
it's just going to be like the photo
period variety but in autofocus
basically
yeah well micah helped a lot like this
year with uh
with that we did our caramel cream
autoflower and that one was a
photoperiod strain for quite a few years
before that and so taking it from you
know that
photo period line and then making sure
that it carries all of those traits
while also introducing the ruder alice
is definitely true it's a big
undertaking it doesn't like to split a
lot
and the crazy thing about the
autoflowers is you can't take clones off
of them i know you have to just breathe
i know i was talking with that about it
it's like you just in it when they're
flipping you're having to reverse that's
what it is deal with a large scale
population so yeah it's fascinating yeah
really cool um all right well i think
we've covered pretty much everything
that we would normally would with the
flower guys um
if there's let's see we could end it on
if there's anything that you'd like to
see change with the regulations or
education in the industry what would
what would that one thing be
um you know right now something i've
been really thinking about is how absurd
it is that the tax that people are
paying per pound is not based off of the
price they're getting for said pound
i think that first you know it's just a
brick set exactly well and i think you
know for
sun grown cultivators to actually be
able to have like a winning shot it's
not really fair to be putting them in
the same exact tack
160 dollars although to me yeah
independently
so much more than indoor it's the fact
that we have a lot of uneducated
consumers out there and they don't know
what to ask for when they go into
dispensary and
like realistically that should have been
based off of the price you're receiving
for your pounds in the first place in my
opinion
so that's something i would really like
to see change i like it i like that what
about you do you have any
taxes on the square footage and stuff is
just outrageous right now it's kind of
crazy it's a hard market to get into if
you don't have a lot of money and you
know you wouldn't survive a lot of
people aren't surviving right now yeah
it kind of sucks you know micah micah
and his family have been in the area for
so long micah is you know a native
tribal member and
you know for people in those cultures to
even be able to get their foot in the
door in the cannabis industry it's now
like nearly impossible because if you
don't have
hundreds of thousands of dollars to put
up front for licensing and taxes and for
employment yeah all the upfront costs
like starting a tomato the startup is
just like so different you could start a
tomato farm these people don't want to
grow
normalized a little bit yeah definitely
needs to be normalized for sure
hopefully we'll get some change going as
i think if we come together as a
community in these like groups like this
and start pushing regulators we'll
hopefully make some change so thanks for
your time yeah this has been really
awesome i appreciate coming by and
hanging out so thanks a lot