it is redistribution for you where we
have our own distribution license we use
so we started with I've been friends
with Rhys for a long time but then they
changed like everybody else just don't
have control over what they're doing but
there are fulfillment partner so they do
all the last miles table so our real
focus is to besides cultivators just to
make sure that we do our own like
testing and packaging and all that stuff
and then we have a sales team so we keep
the relationships with the clubs because
we add them you know didn't want to give
them away to some you know the drill
[Music]
well you know what I can't speak to this
cultivar as much as the people that
farmed it so this is an example son
roots farm cultivation and this is a
great example for us because we're
always talking about son grow versus
endure and now that dates are on on
labeling everything all except that was
produced in October and it's July it's
like if the Sun grown and people in
Southern California starting to
understand the cycle of Sun grown and
the seasons of it all so this is a great
example of a flower that I can put in
front of a pyro couldn't be like bitches
in door and they're like oh that's great
and they're like essentially last year's
outdoor
so it's a great it's a really good
strain like the velvet perks it's a good
one
they've been rocking it for a while and
it's just it's still resonance and it
hold it's like it's got that sappiness
to it super high terpenes he's got that
SAP to it the kind of suspense it in
time nice yeah it's a good one it smokes
and fermium you know I could be like
opportunity to have a more anxious
feeling and so for like I got to be
careful about coffee and things like
guys so it's cannabis I'm pretty
sensitive to and this is such a it just
is very calming for me it makes me feel
good yeah it's a great example the Sun
good nose kind of reminds me sweetheart
yeah it's super circular we control his
roll a joint yeah see
[Music]
yeah
your own farm can also work
exactly exactly yeah uh only thing that
I call debate on is the 2500 square-foot
license
I ended Mendocino in the community over
the last like really over the last like
five years there's been a big push to
other people trying to sell their
flowers through us and we'll get to
retail yeah for sure yeah we have Ingrid
over there absolutely that's a good
example of one that was in the Sun way
too long today and I'm like it's not
exactly how I want to look it's a
beautiful strain but yeah so really one
of my I think one of my strengths more
than cultivation it was was going out
and being the voice of a group of us
that were cultivating rather than
someone coming in and saying yeah I
gotta sell your herb for you it's like
hey guys I'll do it I'll fucking get out
there and do it so that's gonna shop we
cultivate a little bit but really it's
an aggregation of a lot of small farms
Wow and we took in a little bit of a
different approach like talking trees we
just it's all single source but there's
also that need to help out other
community too so we're gonna develop
another brand so that what like this
mountain is brand and then we can like
co-brand other farms but the talking
tree it's like we know if we oh it's
just we grew it we know everything about
it if it sucks we're gonna take yeah
it's our farm la seems to me to be the
hardest to tap and the smallest volumes
we like we see compared to some Bay Area
stores tend to go deeper
I think la there's so much so if you do
get in a store maybe they'll order sizes
at least to our experience so far the
volume of the orders aren't as big let's
say norcal or in our own backyard
there's so many more players and more
competition I guess it's so different
it's so different than the Northern
California market - as far as like you
get a lot of like the like and get in
door 417 you know
there's a lot of indoor being cultivated
in Los Angeles and I think there's still
a lot of education needs to go in and
sun-grown
to get more momentum than that in the
market down here it's it's a lot I mean
just just our experience down here over
the last year or cycads it is incredible
how many people are unaware of the
agricultural cycle of the seasons of
cannabis and when something they want
something full Sun and in it and it was
harvested in December and they're
getting adjourned I could see it's like
oh wow you didn't know that this was
harvested because that's when that's the
end of it yeah we do make some pretty
rolls for sure probably rather had
someone start with like flour and make
their own
fireproof oh I I go to I would go in my
store and get a free roll first thing
just cuz like if I'm traveling or moving
around it's easy just to grab a pre roll
and I'm a flower guy I'd rather smoke a
joint than a bowl or yeah I'm totally a
flower guy that's where a flower flower
to the end and the pre-roll market is so
like people are really in timid
fortunate like there's a lot of product
today people don't know what to do with
the natural makes it into a pre-roll but
I'm sure like these guys like we
basically we take our flowers and we
grade them there all of the a buds and
things that we decide not to put into
1/8 jars what a pre-roll it's turned
into so it's not like you're taking trim
and they're taking random things you
know they gotta go quick you know cuz
once you break it down and starts to
degrade so I mean we tried to go for a
model of like packed or you know packed
to order pre-rolled order which you
can't do anymore
because the testing change but we just
can't keep up so it's like we're just
constantly really really rolls and
they're out the door and feel good about
that I hate this even sit around for a
month and then go out
what's your best-selling
like which was like probably the budget
flower like a nine $10 eight
[Music]
we've got a little bit I mean the live
markets a little hard to crack there's
so many players and prices are low and
we've done really well at bubble ash
we're doing really well with my wife we
just do full spectrum 70 you good old
bubble hash ten dollars a gram wholesale
so hits the customers about 20-25 and
yeah all that and then we use it for all
our edibles our ice water hash and fused
as well yeah this is still funny how it
all like full-circle BHO okay gonna
bubble hash I mean I always straight
away from the solvent world and just ugh
I all make bubble hash when we go ash
and then we use it for like Space Jam
and the tea is and stuff so and then it
just returns like oh well bubble ash
what we sell more than anything
I mean us
if you were making this in Europe people
would be like we have European people
hitting us up trying to buy it it's
crazy it's like mobile guys or and
they're like oh we're coming to the
United States and we love Sour Diesel
and want to buy a lie-down my well we
can't tell it to you sorry
bill days good it's great
I mean I've always rather smoking
sun-grown over in door myself you guys
do indoor - yeah you guys as far as the
um so you guys are cultivating yourself
well permis you guys out what purpose do
you guys have I have five outdoor
permits one under five thousand into our
permit and a micro business permit that
includes cultivation nursery specialty
indoor distribution and retail I have
nine permits
yeah Humboldt County man there's
definitely like that's always the
balance between small farmers being able
to scale up a little bit to be able to
actually throwing up to penetrate the
market it's easy to aggregate when
you're acting like a 2500 square foot in
the 5000 square foot and a 2500 square
foot you actually end up being maybe the
canopy that's similar to what you have
with the fiber material CDFA is like the
word CDMA is the worse than getting per
mass yeah yeah getting permits is not
easy at all still no BCC is much easier
than CDF a CDF age it's like really
difficult and taking forever and moving
slow or as if you have a micro business
or retail or their distribution or CD pH
manufacturing permits I seem to all be
so much easier than getting a
cultivation for a minute
[Music]
well I work with three different local
municipalities city of Eureka city of
Arcadia and then Humboldt County the
county has always been the hardest
Eureka was the last to come on but is
like the easiest they they did they
actually hosted the best campus mixer
I've ever been to like a week or two ago
so they've issued 59 permits in the last
year give or take in the city of Eureka
City of Eureka and so they brought in
like a half a million in permit fees
that they like they gave us all these
statistics it's created this many jobs
it's bringing this much money into the
economy
we love cannabis there's one building
that was empty for 14 years until the
cannabis business moved in so it's like
even the city sees a great economic
story and it's good to see ya yeah so
they're getting easier the locals are
getting easier I think unless you're
dealing with cdfw is also the nightmare
when it comes to cultivation dealing
with fish and wildlife is very hard
July 1st there's a new waterboard
regulation I I diffused that stuff to
other people I don't remember the
details but a new waterboard enrollment
and here at ready that's gross has to be
enrolled with the waterboard and so
they're rolling out a whole new program
they have to be signed on a lot of a lot
of cultivators that a lot of friends
people that I know with perfect sir
they're in scientific review right now
so they're waiting on their provisional
license and they're fairness like
suspended state waiting around CDMA yeah
so I can see
yeah so hopefully they'll start to turn
on when do you decide what you're gonna
grow for the coming season well the form
that we have is supposed to the coast
so we Rock genetics out there that we've
been doing just because they work well
in those environments and conditions
when you go closer to the coast you
definitely have to be thinking as far as
like folds and things like that so
watermelon ranchers really really great
it's been a great strain the a.k is
another strain that I don't know exactly
why it works so well out there but this
particular cut works so well something a
little school classic okay it's big
fucking resinous buds but they don't
mold out and we rock this Ellie's gift
out there and that's what we're doing
again so that's what you know that's
what we've been doing and then everybody
else in the group would kind of like you
it's like people have been cultivating
the same genetics for a long time first
up breeding and trying to do different
things but a lot of people just setting
up the same thing that they did they
knocked out last year mark and she'll be
registering the grapefruit like he's
doing the Viper cookies gabe is doing
the ingrid so people go with what they
know it's definitely once you change it
up it's it can be a rabbit hole and
fives you know I mean finding a cure
genetic is it's not easy to come by it's
a lot of fucking work so yeah we do a
little bit of both you know there's a
few staples like for now that could
change with like skittles through the
huckleberry buddy work we're trying to
get like over a year ahead and work on
new genetics and trying to just come out
with new strains every year but that's
like a work in progress
well we did a lot of crosses last year
and we've got this really good pink
lemonade nail and so we just back crop
we've just crossed that with skittles
like Tahoe cookies candy land a bunch of
stuff golden lemons so we just popped
all those seeds so now we're gonna you
know be no Hunnam flower all indoor and
just kind of pick the winners and then
try and build those up for next season
and try and just at least have something
in our profile it's always just brand
new and hopefully of the next big strain
you never know so when you from the time
like we start the process to the time
you find something to the time it's
actually ready in the market at least
two years right people that people know
yeah yeah yeah it takes a long time yeah
breeding in getting a stable good
genetic outage is a definitely a process
so everything you're doing is wasn't it
started last month as we've been working
on for almost a year already by growing
in picking the selections the male's
were grown last year we cloned or kept
the pollen ideal we try to keep the
pollen in the clones so they do the
initial cross with the with the pollen
that we save and then we can keep the
clones going and produce more of that
same falling well first off do you think
that people should have the ability to
patent their strains
I don't really have an whole question
yeah yeah sure so I guess I'm just gonna
say I wouldn't you know I would say that
the key the key play is just to keep it
really tight and get win a couple cuffs
enter it into things negative
recognition let people know work with
the people that you got the genetics
from if they're breeders as well give
them the recognition and just make it on
the string yeah I think like so it's
like you don't have to trademark
something if you are the one that's
known for doing it and if you decide if
you build it up and then you decide to
give it to somebody else to do it then
it's like they can do it because you've
given it to them but it's not talking
trees so the brain goes a long way to
protect the genetic itself I'm I see why
people would do it but it's just not my
thing I'd rather share something great
with everybody and let them play with it
and see what they do with it I think
that's I think that's art you know
that's cool yeah breeding and like plant
patents and and all that has been a huge
like huge conversation and cannabis
community these days with everything
that's been happening with Pylos
bioscience and all that stuff so 20
times what do you want
what do you feel like smoke really good
any flower madam just a chunk rough yeah
flower for sure see what we got here
that's all we have is indoor right now
try the huckleberry what's up with you
guys this much distribution working for
you guys okay we do I do all my own
distribution through high grade
distribution and I mean it's going
pretty good it's a lot of work but we're
in probably over 120 stores now so
moving I mean we sold out of flour so
and I mean I did try like you know
putting getting some of the homies I'm
like oh I know you're you know a good
grower haven't seen your crop in a few
years but and people notice and so it's
like my reps were getting upset I'm like
well dude you're the one that's not
making any money if we're not selling
flour so we're gonna we already
developed a brand and then it'll be like
alright we can you know showcase other
farms through that brand and just kind
of run this branding a single source and
when we run out it's out that's kind of
like it's seasonal product yeah
[Music]
and a current volume of cannon just
learned in the last season is that
probably have enough this is like you
know last year it was like making moves
where every had to make moves but we
have the cultivation campy that can
probably get us through about a year
supply as we're growing and that's good
it's part of it as well you guys when
you got the end or but you've been
harvesting already my end or I'm only at
1200 square feet built out right now
justice I have the permits but not the
money for the build outs but we have
forty nine thousand square foot outdoor
you know thirty low thirty thousand of
its mostly mixed green house alone tarps
so we start harvesting first second week
in July
a little little bit a little bit behind
this year I like to harvest on like
fourth of July I'll be about a week late
because I mean where I'm at and just in
my light depths in general almost
everything finishes about a week earlier
well I mean right now we're not
harvesting anything and on the outdoor
scale from you know October through July
and then July it'll be non-stop until
October always harvesting
[Music]
yeah yeah I'm not selling any bull so if
I sell bulk I'm gonna help friends out
and sell their product is bull and only
do package for my my flowers today I
mean right now we're still in in the
growth phase and could've sold a lot
more weed if I had it but we made it to
like May what some still having flower
and we're planning to produce you know
more this year every year we add more
fans we added this that you know like
it's always getting better the
infrastructures so yeah the huckleberry
is a strain that actually got from a
father-in-law of mine that was bred I
think out in Trinity and so Trinity
County so we got seeds of it and grew it
for two different seasons to just be no
hunted what we call we label the
huckleberry but it's the huckleberry
three is the pheno so it's really nice
like fruity uplifting tasty bud so we
can roll join attack
[Music]
I think that's true but I think they
have smaller limits on like canopy and
stuff but probably easier to deal with
in terms of the grading and stuff like
that but when you're dealing with cdfw
there's cdfw and their state widening
they're not county and and they're gonna
be your biggest nightmare yeah as an
outdoor grill were in the Hills CD I
mean they have been for me maybe other
people's are different stories are
different but most people I know in the
Hills are humble that's been their
biggest hurdle to get a permit to cdfw
and advise the farmer and that's doubly
the case for sure all the local AG
department and the Cal Fire and naval
Water Board like state inspectors but
Fish and Wildlife simply have some
serious business
don't give a fuck about cannabis and
their job is to protect Fish and
Wildlife you know so but it's been good
you know but yeah a lot of hurdles
do I not necessarily not not so much
yeah I mean I think everybody has the
right to cultivate and their quality is
quality so I think Appalachian I think
like I don't know I think that yeah
we'll see how it all rose I mean I
believe there's definitely something to
it because even the girl office a great
example of it you can give ten growers
the same exact cutting and even on
indoor I mean you give ten growers the
same indoor cut it's all gonna come out
different so I just kind of speaks to
like yeah there's something to
Appalachia and I mean nothing against
Salinas or Santa Barbara or anywhere
that's growing but elevation definitely
can play a key and a lot of men Dohan
below Trinity here between that six
hundred two thousand foot elevation is
pretty prime cannabis growing weather
plumbing it's just you have to you
definitely have to have earlybird
strange I've never stuck that comes down
earlier
unless you're pulling tarps but for us
we're doing a full season crop out on
the coast so you know we don't want
strains that are going to be going to
too far into you know late September
ideally they're all coming down just
strange to do well strains that are Airy
you're no stranger to luck you know that
are going to grow and there allow good
light to come through and air play the
program and the trick is just like not
you know giving them exactly what they
need and building the soil out there for
a while and it's it's a I think one of
the biggest things out in the coast is
just not over watering when you're in
the valley and you have like super high
temperatures it's a whole different
animal but on the coast just less is
more more oxygens good
okay guys smells good
amazing that is amazing I wish I could
do that dry farm is definitely because
you're really close to the water source
on the riverbed stuff you gotta grow the
right strains because you're gonna deal
with a lot of moisture similar to
growing on the coast but that mean it's
amazing I've been I visit a couple dry
farms it's like wow you never water
these plants you plant them they're like
yeah they droop like the first week and
then they just come back up and do their
thing pretty cool
wish I could do that but I'd say in
general a lot of a lot of farmers
typically historically do overwater
that's super juicy
so yeah we try to conserve as much water
as possible
what are you like
[Music]
[Applause]
ya know we're always experimenting and
nothing really through the methodology I
mean there's like some hot strains out
there or some breeders that are putting
out new new genetics so we're trying to
play with it all I don't know it's quite
it's part of the fun of it for me it's
just seeing all the varieties of
cannabis one strain I've been liking a
lot lately that I could enjoy the
breeder off the top of my head is the
lemon Royale it's a really nice really
nice
it's that lemony let me not let me just
scent and he's got a little bit of a
doji cushy lemon just yumminess to it
[Music]
it's a good one it's been my favorite
lately - yeah well honestly now there's
another criterias like we go ahead and
like oh this is awesome
let's do the potency test because
unfortunately we're dealing with that
bias and we'd rather have stuff that's
gonna be like oh it's over 25% okay yeah
like yeah if it's amazing but and tests
at 14 15 percent it's like well we'll
keep it around but unfortunately people
bye-bye that we actually Terp test all
our smokeable so we have with you know
Terps are important and where there's
more just beyond Terps and THC can
happen but there's more going on - like
synergies of it because even some of the
better strains that get me really high
I've low turfs in low cannabinoids
sometime so there's obviously something
else there's all kinds of factors
that's super bummed super tasty it's all
our indoors soil grown te organic yeah
just smaller amount
[Music]
I mean we I think it just produces a
better tasting product growing in I've
personally never done anything beside
soil but I've seen and been around a lot
of different systems and I know like the
flood drain systems work really well
all the grodan systems I mean there's
those are more efficient and tend to be
higher yield so from a business
standpoint it does make more sense to go
and more hydro cents even though they're
growing great quality cannabis - I mean
I smoke something's really good but I've
just always preferred soil just a
preference and I think the Terps come
out a little stronger and I've heard of
extractors that extract with product say
that they get a better extract out of
the same strain if it was soil grown
versus say salt grown hydro style
No we blend like you know products we
get thankfully we work with this company
called still escape solutions that Sam's
great yeah yeah he's great so he's
actually developed this folio I've
always been kind of an anti foliar
person but he's like just you gotta try
you gotta try it so we've been trying it
and it's amazing it's like all these
micro minerals I mean I think there's
like 18 ingredients in it but it's true
you use like three mils to like a
hundred gallons or something like don't
quote me on the ratios and stuff but
it's extremely low amount and it's a
very effective very very effective yeah
he helps us develop the right program to
keep plants really healthy all
organically I'm not a soil scientist or
a Bobby so we got to rely on time
not so much I mean I've been doing it a
long time I mean I used to buy my own
nutrients and lime and dolomite and
blend it all together the back Juana's
and stuff but when someone else could
just do that and we're balanced ratio
based off like testing the soil and
develop a program and get you know I'm
just like tossing it in like this really
you know it's what I've learned so
nothing that was like amazed like my
that necessarily but just like the
specific knowledge of the balance of
what to be giving it pretty much yeah
but it was always working I'm good
actually are you like the person like
I've never done by fraud
or you like bring someone in like
whatever it is well I tried to only
focus on non solve it you know solving
list solving free products but we have
started making live resins as well but
we don't we outsource that with her
actually we partner with a guy named
half hash so he does all our high end
hash productions
yeah yeah so he manufactures all our
hash you know we try to work with people
that you know bring value to each other
by working together we can't just do it
all it's good to develop good
partnerships and that's what kind of
what space gems is is she had an amazing
product and brand and we started working
together and so now we collab more like
right now we're using kavita's I must
say I really like the controller's the
system where they all you can control
them light dim them and temperature
settings but we'll be looking into as we
remodel we're still not built up to
scale for the permit so we'll be looking
at other options
try it there's always something new to
learn and this is in this game you're
killing about testing coming up
are you feel about testing and all that
shit oh man testing is such a burden
yeah it's so expensive especially
they're just like the most organic
farmer ever can you know it's like it's
gonna trip eat the table too thick heavy
metals to shit like that that's kind of
why we went with this foliar program and
we hadn't we hadn't failed anything for
heavy metals yet when we started testing
at the end of last year but uh what we
did fail before was Aspergillus and so
there's Sam soil escape as I go that's
coming from an over ripened fungal class
so we were making fungal flats you know
try to get the fungal biology going but
there's like such a short window and if
you're not microscope and if it blooms
then that somehow Boston or that does
that created them fungus Aspergillus so
yeah trivia we've had any issues with
the heavy metals don't wait hopefully
things change the name
like bees enough of some of that but
probably gonna Rd everything just to be
safe just to be safe because there's
some just shift it into another source
know where we have our own nursery but
it's between four different facilities
but it's all in how
[Music]
do I do everything
right I mean I think you got allocated
about 25 to 30 percent of your total
space and most most municipalities don't
charge for nursery space so tack that on
and they usually just give you that as
you needed that and I mean usually you
need about to propagate I'd say for
indoor you can get away with 25% that
moms and self-sufficient clone
production and keep 75% flowering
I would like to I don't really have the
source or the funds to pay someone to do
that right now but I'd like to tissue
culture everything and start fresh as we
move into like a new facilities just to
make sure get rid of pathogens and stuff
I mean just to revive your the genetics
that you're working with but I haven't
got it done yet
you know a lot of farmers who would love
to fish you culture their genetics
getting back to Ground Zero is a good
way to preserve them save for later you
don't take up space like God it's not
good right now but I don't want to lose
it just catalog it in tissue culture I
[Music]
do have a story yeah yeah
the retail stores yeah
the retail stores definitely helped a
lot because it brings in cash flow every
day and it's been pretty successful so
on my model with the store is that way
you know a nice clean environment but
also just to support everybody anyone
has a good product we give a chance so
we have a lot of different broader did
McKinley bill which is in northern
Humboldt the clientele is super diverse
so I would say our clientele averages
probably between thirty to sixty and a
lot more frequently we're seeing a lot
of more elder older folks coming in a
lot of people new people yeah even in
humble choosing so a lot of new people a
lot of curious people younger people
they know what they want
coming in
I can't say that we've seen much demand
for that but like we have brought in
products from lemon tree and say alien
labs and editor at a really premium
price like like how are we gonna sell a
$70 a thin humble and the product sells
that sold I don't think it was an issue
you know I don't work in the store
monitor too much but I know we brought
in some very high-end product I was like
wow how's this gonna fly and humble
people we're still buying it so I think
there's such a diverse consumer out
there so as a store it's like we like to
offer something for everybody I mean
like a cheap ten to twenty dollar eight
is actually the highest volume selling
product when we have a good stock of
them where we live but then there's also
people that come in for the super
high-end live resins and rosin Stu
not so much not so much who think
whatever we do is gonna have some niche
somewhere market immunities no one can
ever get tired of having new strains of
cannabis to try just gotta find good
ones and yeah totally exactly a lot of
that a lot of people interested in CBD
products or have tried it and are
looking for another accomplice because
it's working
oh yeah we have a definitely yeah a lot
of CBD infused product yeah yeah I'm
probably getting into some pure hemp CBD
products as well so non cannabis not in
the store but focusing on that on an
adjacent building and then started
loosing right next exactly I was gonna
make it a consumption cafe but I feel
like it might be better to just half a
CVD product store there instead and do
we could do some manufacturing of
products there too
[Music]
you know it's because you wouldn't be
able to split the unit cannabis versus
non cannabis because it's not split like
that yeah I mean consumption on site
would be cool but yeah and it's not sure
if it's gonna be a lot more to monitor
[Music]
it's allowed you can get a permit for a
consumption
we were going for it and we still are in
the permit process so depending on how
difficult it becomes we might just drop
it and go into CVD but we've already
paid a pretty good permit fee and it's
been five six months now we're just kind
of trucking along in the progress not
necessarily ready to outfit it and get
all that done so it's no rush not yet
not in Humble I don't think so mando
definitely I think a lot of I think yeah
that's um so there is one there's one in
Mendocino
it's the Ingrid lounge is right next to
Allen
and it's it's a private sub membership
base kind of situation and honestly I
don't really understand or know how the
regulations go as far as conception
lodges and let you know I know that
they're really working on and tourism
I think consumption might be a little
bit of a gray
there was
when I was later
there's fuckin rock and roll bar that's
fine you got some Edelman's
she loved F gone but should have got to
see your head land for my vacation
vacation guys like me