[Music]
I robbed Addison with inspire hi I'm Sam
burger and crop scientists I'm Nadia
Saba the president of dr. greenhouse all
right let's talk HVAC that's awesome
yeah so I got into this business about
eight years ago just kind of stumbled
into it and then for the last three
years I've been doing HVAC for
agriculture typically indoor some
greenhouse and it's been a race to
understand the plant science along with
the HVAC challenges that go along with
it you know you start by using
commercial equipment and stubbing your
toe again and again and again and not
really understanding why the plants
aren't yielding what they're supposed to
and thinking maybe we shouldn't be
slapping a leaf weed leaf sticker on the
side of a commercial air conditioning
unit right and so that led us to develop
you know better products use
tried-and-true dehumidification
technologies and you know start really
reading the papers and the latest
understandings of how it's particularly
cannabis reacts to the nine cardinal
principles you never talk to doctor
Bugbee about this kind of stuff you find
out what's in our control that's you
know wind speed temperature humidity and
co2 delivery right as HVAC people we
don't control the lights the growers
gonna pick a light that they think is
gonna give them the best result we don't
control the root condition directly I
mean we can do underfloor heating and
things like that in greenhouses and that
kind of thing and the room temperature
does affect the route temperature but
yeah those are those are the four
cardinal things that we play with so I
would add air quality to that we also
have control over the constituents in
the air such as mold spores biosecurity
tests and things like that through air
filtration and purification yeah
absolutely yeah and in your presentation
earlier you made a very good point
people are blasting money away in Merve
Merve 15 or better like hepa type filter
ation systems which are complete
overkill
you know merv 13 is like it's a very
readily available filter
the pressure drops are much better since
they became like a lead standard as well
the filter designs have gotten better
and that's you know that's basically
where we stopped our units don't use any
of that stuff so anything happened
beyond it's just kind of overkill but
yeah I don't know we see these
challenges all the time one of the
things I would say is that you know we
see this VPD term being thrown around
constantly by growers who are picking a
number and they are using it as gospel
and that drives me nuts it probably
drives you nuts too and there so there's
a lot of adaptations the plants have to
deal with changes in VPD just a model
control they have active uptake of water
through their root systems so like if
the humidity levels too high during the
night period you'll see water actually
coming out of the tips of the leaves I
think it's called good tation they'll
start to just build up a ton of pressure
inside themselves even when the VPD is
totally maxed out or sorry the humidity
is totally maxed out yeah so again
that's is that so as that is that
happening because there's another
mechanism driving water out of the plant
yeah the roots or the roots can actively
take up water to build up a root
pressure West Drive which also helps
drive water through the plant as well
got it yeah
and there's also aquaporins that are
just like active open channels that are
constantly drawing in water okay yeah
yeah it also has to do with solute
gradients inside between the actual
rhizosphere and the root itself as well
so giving the you know keeping your
humidity levels in check in the room is
giving the water a place to go yes yeah
yeah otherwise it the plan just like
yeah I think one of the reasons that
high VPD numbers you know obviously very
low VP DS when you draw a VP D chart at
a hundred percent relative humidity in
the room it's zero and that's a red zone
on every chart because you're not
getting any carbon dioxide in because
the water molecules that would be
leaving due to vapor pressure are not
exiting the stomata and therefore co2
can't get in on the opposite side if
it's too dry you have so much water
leaving that's such a rate that co2
can't get in but you know I just looked
at some research from last year that
indicated you know as long as you have a
high enough level of co2
VPD was not so much a factor all the
things being equal VPT wasn't
necessarily a factor for photosynthetic
rate or carbon synthesis or an
integration simulation inside the plant
so if you can keep your co2 levels high
enough you can have a high VP D or a low
V PD and still have decent
photosynthesis again you have to be
mindful of how you get water through the
plant and whatever nutrients and how
that affects nutrients exactly because
there's you're gonna get different
transpiration rates out of different
leaves at different you know levels of
the plan going from the newest growth
down to the older growth where the leaf
is very mature it's very large you can
get such a high transpiration rate out
of these large leaves just not
necessarily like per area but there's
just so much of that leaf at that point
it's very developed a vascular system
it's gonna draw nutrients into that
larger leaf the nutrients that are
dependent on water flow through the
plant at least some are more mobile and
can be moved around or phloem dependent
but the ones that are really based on
movement and the water tubes throughout
the plant are gonna end up getting drawn
to that larger leaf and that's why you
see a lot of the tip burn issues like in
lettuce plants it's because there's no
calcium making it to the actual new
growth because there's so much water
movement coming out of the larger leaves
that you just start to get these
crinkled edges where and when the leaf
actually expands it's like pinched on
the edges because there was no calcium
movement into it so you know I
definitely can see that a very high V PD
can be very risky just in terms of that
because you're not getting an even
movement of nutrition through the plant
yeah VPD also affects how much water the
plant uses i mean if you just think
about it right so if you just think in
terms of water efficiency and water
utilization when you have a higher VPD
the plant has a greater demand for water
and so you're going to have to irrigate
your plant more to keep it well watered
so that you know it can keep growing and
it's gonna not wilt and all these things
and at a lower VPD the plant has less
pressure on it to use that water and
like I mentioned in my talk earlier that
you can we can actually control VPD when
the plant is very young to turn it into
a
tolerant plan so that when it grows up
and it's an older plant it requires less
water right those plants have more
smaller stomata so just like in terms of
controllability like right like you have
you know variable speed compressors
almost it's like you have all these
stomata that when they're all open it's
like three big stomata right with thirty
tiny stomata I mean it's always
mimicking its environment or at least
like it's it's a reciprocity between the
environment of how its gonna develop a
leaf even down to just like the
chloroplast level where the chloroplasts
are positioned inside of the Mesa fill
cells inside the leaf is going to be
dictated by the type of light source the
intensity of the light source the
thickness of the leaf will change as
well
so when you're in that type of light
setting and then you go to another light
setting you know now the plant has built
itself for this light source at this
intensity and it has to totally change
there's a tremendous amount of energy
that's why you'll see these like long
lag lagging acclimation times going from
one environment to another and it's the
same thing with VPD because it's built
that it's built that way it's I mean
it's intense to say that you could build
a drought tolerant plant but I get what
you're saying for sure that it's like
it's it's adapted itself to that can do
those conditions and now it has to
change it's still model density or you
know if the quantity per area or the
size like to adapt to that change one of
the things I'd like to see because again
this strict adherence to a VPD chart
that they took off the High Times
magazine website article whatever it's
like we're gonna use this chart as
gospel and they've circled whatever
number you know the better charts they
are their temperature specific to leaf
temperature and our you know relative to
the atmosphere because you have to
redraw the chart based on the radiation
source but even to that end like you
said within a gradient of canopy which
leaf are you going to measure to get
your VPD from it it's more an argument
against using VPD without understanding
all the variables right and
understanding that when you say I want
this VPD in my room that you've taken an
average leaf temperature and
and a good estimated guess of what the
leaf temperature is and understand that
that's the VPD for those leaves at that
temperature so what is an average leaf
temperature and how do you get that what
what exactly does that mean well it
depends on the radiation source so a
radiation source is going to have a lot
of infrared or no infrared and depending
on whether it's one or the other the
transpiration through the leaf is going
to cool that leaf and if I have a high
infrared and you know hid in light like
an HP s system leading heating my plant
leaves I need to keep the room a couple
degrees colder than where I'd like the
leaf temperature so a couple three four
degrees Fahrenheit below the leaf
temperature temperature I'm trying to
maintain in an LED system I still have
transpiration even though I've got
mostly photosynthetically active
radiation hitting the leaf I'm gonna
keep that room warmer because I don't
have I'm not cooking the leaves with my
light source but I'm still transpiring I
need to get heat into that leaf to get
the water to turn into vapor so I've got
to keep that lieth at room temperature
warmer hella d rooms 82 to 85 degrees in
the flowering stage for cannabis HTTP
rooms 75 degrees you have to play with
those numbers because we're shooting for
a leaf temperature we're shooting for a
temperature where the metabolism when
you give it enough carbon and all the
other right elements is gonna be in that
optimum band too hot and that band falls
off too cold that band falls off they
like to play within you know between 20
and 25 degrees which is probably too
large a number for what we're talking
about if you guys have better arranges
or you know an optimum for a cultivar
for leaf temperature I'd love to hear no
pressure probably 80 degrees for
something like tomato in cannabis I'm
sorry for mixing up Celsius and
Fahrenheit it's fine so that's 27 or 28
degrees Celsius and for a lettuce plant
we're probably looking closer to 70
degrees Fahrenheit so 21 degrees Celsius
is
is you know the the target but you know
route temperature also has a play in
this you know I mean we could have an
excessive air temperature and leaf
temperature but if we can also control
the root zone temperature then maybe we
can compensate for some of the high
temperatures at the leaf but the thing
is is that there unless you're doing
true like hydroponics where you have you
know deep water culture or something and
you can really control the water
temperature to control the root
temperature I mean you're really
controlling the plant with the air most
people are most people are dependent on
just where their water storage is that's
the temperature of it with it's inside
maybe it's a conditioned space and they
can have a little more control that way
but I've seen some people where they
have it outside and so the water is
coming in at like 50 degrees Fahrenheit
like as it's been sitting out there
during the winter and then you water the
plants with that and that is detrimental
vice versa I've been in a greenhouse
where they had their water storage tank
outside it was in Nevada and so as you
know 110 degree water algae actually
because it was a clear tank so can I can
I ask the play outside just something
why does the VPD chart have a band of
green a band of yellow and two bands of
red typically and those bands extend all
the way up to these temperatures where
you'd never want to grow a plant in the
high range into a very very low
temperature in the low end where you'd
never want to grow a plant anyways why
is that green band there why is the
yellow band there what are the why did
those colors come about I mean it's just
different research that's happened with
different crops and like extension
services trying to actually create
something to give a reference to it's
largely just like it's it's just
physical values presented in that way
and those have those have been shown
with various crops to like to have high
productivity cannabis it's the only one
that's really just brought in like a
different practice historically okay I
mean I would say I mean when we look at
the vbe chart and when we create them
for different crops I mean we will try
to trim off the edges depending on what
the plant is so if you look at our
lettuce chart it's very small compared
to say the Cannabis chart but also I
mean if you think about with cannabis
and tomatoes and and let's say we're
growing in a greenhouse and you know we
didn't oversize the system for the peak
load or whatever and so we know that
there's gonna be days that it might be
90 degrees in that greenhouse okay
that's not ideal but if it is 90 degrees
in there what is it's only about water
movement the VPD charge so it's it's
these it's it's fairly theoretical with
some some experimental information put
in there but it's some of that some of
the ends of that chart are kind of
irrelevant because it's only about
whatever them
yeah the VPD gosh sure yes so I mean so
when we're talking about Rubisco
activity which is the it's the 50%
protein of plant leaves is what's being
used to actually fix carbon that has its
own temperature limits as well so
whereas like your VPD may be okay at
this like high range on that graph which
is it's still in that green zone still
around 1.0 you know but now you're
Rubisco activity is starting to fall off
right or you're having leaky cells
because the membranes cancer membranes
are made of fats and they'll they'll
change out the types of fats to make
sure they're keeping the contents inside
of the cell so that you know they'll put
in more liquid fats or more solid fats
and based on what the temperature is so
like if it's a really hot day you want
more or is it unsaturated fats in that
place that are gonna actually like have
more fluidity and build withstand higher
temperatures you know I'm sorry
saturated fats and then in the other
direction if it's really cold you don't
want fast that are gonna harden in cold
temperatures and separate and create
pockets where there can be things
leaking out of the cells so there's
other things related to temperature that
are not related to VPD or transpiration
got it yeah well the one thing one thing
I would say about that is as soon as you
get out of the temperature band and you
start moving the humidity's around your
leaf temperature changes right so the
same room with even if you played along
and went to a green part on the VBA
chart in the same room it's not gonna be
a two degree temperature leaf difference
and you have to redraw your chart for
whatever the new leaf temperature is so
I think what I'd like to see
the building control world at the
building automation world is a good
leave temperature sensor that will help
you redraw the leaf temperature help you
redraw the VPD chart and let you play in
the new numbers when you get to those
spots I think it's less important in
Indore because we have very tight
control over the room temperature but if
you're going to have different cultivars
and play in different temperatures and
humidity you have to be able to
understand that belief temperature has
changed and your adherence to an old DPD
chart needs to be revisited like for
sure and in you know to that and I would
also say if you're not getting airflow
into the canopy in a consistent way no
matter what you do with your air
conditioning system which is doing bulk
removal of moisture and ten changing the
temperature to keep the temperature of
the room
somewhat accurate if I can't get that
dry air into the canopy or that
conditioned air into the canopy along
with co2 it really doesn't matter you
know air flow inside the rooms is as
important as anything else yeah and and
the old ways of doing oscillating fans
inside the rooms that has got to go
especially as we go to two and three
tier type systems you just you're not
going to get that consistency of product
yeah you're gonna end up with pockets of
very bad pathogen growth higher higher
resolution air flow more locations yeah
we're all three of you in the HVAC
session I was I was asleep
you were speaking yeah all right were
you there you your key takeaways from
his presentation okay it was a very
intense discussion of plant physiology
and how it pertains to HVAC very you
know it was I felt it was very well
spoken but also there was some like new
information presented that no one's
really paying attention to yet it was
talking about comparing different BPD's
at different co2 levels which is
important you said some stuff just about
demonstrating that you're getting the
same photosynthetic rates at different
VP DS but you're also getting different
transpiration rates so you know you can
it's demonstrating you can get similar
productivity
even at a much lower energy cost because
you're not having deal with so much
transpiration but then that also that
also introduces some more like pest
issues because not you know if you don't
if you don't have clean starting
material coming into the gross space
like a lot of people are dependent on
nurseries to get clones and those
nurseries aren't always clean they don't
sometimes they're already coming in with
spores all over them or they're coming
in with bugs on them and so you don't
have an opportunity to defend yourself
against that so that's why traditionally
a lot of people have just worked with
the higher VPD low humidity values but
yeah
I also think it was important - it
wasn't necessarily highlighted in the
discussion I think it's just because of
what we're there to talk about was
mostly about water and energy and
productivity but the effects of co2 are
also there they're affecting the
transpiration rate as well as they're
affecting how the system how the stomata
operate which is affecting how water
moving water is moving through the plant
and so we didn't really get a chance to
go into maybe some of the effects of co2
levels on VPD as much as I really wanted
to so B for another we have a camera and
microphones I feel like he put the ball
on the tee for you so now can you
reinforce the like give us the give us
the juicy key points that you made and
you wanted people to walk away from and
then elaborate on the thing that he
wished yeah so the the takeaway is we
have those four cardinal points that you
know biosecurity is the fifth
temperature humidity wind speed in co2
plants are very reactive they are
smarter than most people give them
credit for they will react to their
environment and do their best to
increase their metabolism in the most
efficient possible way given the
materials they need to get by if you
give them more co2 enough co2 to
increase their photosynthetic rate they
understand that they no longer need to
keep their stomata so open and they can
start to close them off and along with
that closing of the stomata comes a
reduction in the transpiration rate
which means it needs to move less water
through the plant to maintain the Turner
in the plant to maintain
take of the nutrients and it's just it's
better all around for the plant the
plant is gonna grow typically at a much
higher rate and have much higher
photosynthetic activity correct yeah
there you go
so the talk yesterday was very similar
to what you talked about today which is
your VPD line your vbd
is the difference between the vapor
pressure at whatever leaf temperature
you're at minus whatever the room
condition is and you can draw that chart
and adhere to that chart as much as
you'd like but your chart has everything
to do with where you put the leaf
temperature and every time you change
that leaf temperature you have to redraw
the chart to know where you are on the
VPD you know with your VPD and to that
end wind speed affects leaf temperature
relative to the room temperature the
humidity changes the leaf temperature
relative to the room temperature there's
all sorts of other things like stomatal
conductance these things affect and and
lighting intensity on the plants affect
leaf temperature relative to the room
temperature but now that we know those
things that we're starting to understand
those things better we have a better way
to figure out what that leaf temperature
is with all these other sensors we have
in the room without actually having to
go and take the temperature of all the
leaves in the plant in the room and that
is you know it's a surrogate for
actually doing that to know all those
other components we don't have to go and
take the measurement of every leaf and
we can do a better job of producing
plant matter out of a room using the
sensors we already have you know we've
got rooms with 16 sensors in them
2-tier co2 temperature and humidity each
sensor has got those built into it we
can pull that data out and and make some
assumptions on wind speed because we're
doing static tests and those fans are on
24/7
running all the time inside the racks we
can come up with a leaf temperature at
whatever condition we're in and we're
gonna see we're doing the test right now
right we're running those rooms and
we're gonna figure out which conditions
are better for the environment we're
sending all that data to the cloud
amazon's analytics or
through millions of points of data I'm
gonna tell us hey this cultivar in this
room is going to give you 2% more THC
right
you know we if we feed the data back in
then we'll have something to work with
here
we'll do some real good interesting
research yeah kind of the way I wanted
to express what you guys are doing is
like you know you're you're maintaining
the architecture of the plant like
because it's basically it wants to have
its leaves upright fully expanded so it
can constantly be harvesting sunlight
and if the conditions are not
appropriate for it to be able to control
its its water content if it's just
getting water ripped out of it there's
too much it's not able to keep itself in
a perfect position to harvest sunlight
if the temperature is off it's not able
to put actually like performance
enzymatic activity at the proper rate I
just recently saw for the first time
I've seen a lighting company advertising
that it's set on their site like
activate your Rubisco content of your
plants like I was like that's deep you
guys are really make because if you look
at some of the like they'll have like
co2 assimilation co2 assimilation rate
against like different temperatures you
know often you'll see like a peak of
activity at like you know 30 degrees
Celsius or higher and that's mostly just
because of the Rubisco activity so it
has it has its own thresholds to deal
with but it's there's also to consider
you know we talked a lot of other stuff
but long-term adaptations to these
different conditions are very different
than a short-term measurement that we
could take as well how does the plant
respond to that when it's endured it for
two months yeah so one of the things
that we we're doing with the data that's
you know paying back immediately is you
know you mentioned I think someone asked
the question in the previous talk how do
you measure transpiration rate right
what's the standard testing you measure
the plant over time you see how much
water's gone through it we can in a well
fill the room the sensors we put on our
air conditioning units we care so much
about it because with so much more
efficient we're trying to prove it to
the market we're using our sensors to
tell us how much water we take out of
the air every single minute of every
single day and we can see when the
emitters in a room get clogged or the
solenoids didn't fire to water the
and because the watering rate changed so
drastically from one day to the next we
can immediately fire an alarm right and
in one day if someone didn't notice that
the plants were wilting they can go in
there and fix that problem so so you
know we do have the ability to do
transpiration rate measurement which is
you know it's just one of those metrics
that is going to help us indicate plant
health and plant vitality and increase
our yields it helps a lot for planing
girl rooms too to have that data I have
a question you had spoken about training
plants when they're young to need less
water if you're successful at doing that
when they get older
are they tougher is or is the VPD less
of an issue is the leaf temperature less
of a factor because they've been trained
properly
I've actually been sitting here thinking
that same question I don't know the
answer to that but I feel like the
answer has to be yes
I mean if we've conditioned them to be
drought tolerant and to be acclimated to
a certain environment where there's not
you know I don't know just a lush source
of water all the time then why wouldn't
there leaf temperature be different than
a different plant that wasn't
conditioned to be drought tolerant why
wouldn't there Rebeca levels be
different I don't know I actually don't
know the answer to that question I guess
it would depend on what environment it's
moved into after that you know if you're
doing it because these plants are going
into it a drought a drought type
environment after being conditioned that
way then it's you know it's probably
gonna stay pretty similar to what they
were already existing in but if it's
going into something else I mean they're
constantly just adapting to their
environment and trying to reflect their
environment so I would think it would
change well why would you take a plant
that had been trained to be sort of
drought resistant and put it into a and
and then a smother it with water like
you know wouldn't you drown it will you
do whatever it took to get the most
productivity out of the plants so you if
it meant that that's how you got the
most part
to be out of it sure but it is
drug-tolerant resistant and but I guess
the whole point of this would the whole
point was that these younger plants that
have been trained this way are those
yeah and are still productive oh yeah
not necessarily for cannabis yeah so we
don't know we just take it we grow it
[Music]
talking about energy resource
I'm een we're all talking about energy
but when it comes to agriculture and
farming really the question we should be
asking is about water the liquid gold
that's used to irrigate our farms you
know 65 to 70 percent of all the fresh
water on earth are used for irrigation
so ultimately when we solve the problem
about energy the next big question and
the question we should already start
asking ourselves is about water use
efficiency and you know being able to
collect the water that's condensed on
these air conditioning systems is a huge
opportunity and is probably one of the
something that we should be screaming to
the rafters that hey yeah we use a lot
of energy but we're recycling between 65
to 95 percent of the water that we
initially charged these facilities with
it's never leaving it is almost a closed
system
you know that's why we you know we're
not proponents of desiccant or
economizer cycle type systems that are
just blasting the water out to the
atmosphere you know we use an energy
recovery system around our cooling coils
which makes it way more efficient but
also we get to collect all that water
none of that water leaves the facility
it comes out of the condensate drain so
as you treat it appropriately don't just
feed it back into your plants you know
make sure it's clean and everything else
and then you can feed it back in but
yeah we capture all that water a gallon
in 99% of that gallon comes
of that pot so I don't know if it's
relevant to this discussion but I've
been on a couple of dry farms cannabis
dry farms in southern Humboldt are kind
of scattered along the eel River and
they're really amazing extremely
productive were you high I was not at
the point I was I was just doing well
well well III have been high from the
produce from those farms really great
flower and the plants it's so like at
the base of the plant it's like
literally like desert it's as dry as
desert and yet the plants themselves
were thick and luscious like you can't
believe now that's obviously very unique
you know you have to have the ground
water at there at the right place but
but it's real I mean these are these are
thriving and and I'm just wondering if
there's if anything to be learned its
outdoor obviously it's not an indoor
environment that sounds like an
application for a drought conditioned
plant you know it's it's that's produced
produced and produced in a controlled
facility yeah to be handled that way and
then well you know it's very interesting
I didn't or sunshine Johnson is the name
of the grower I did an article and it
was titled they are the the art of doing
nothing because you know I and she's a
wonderful grower she's a traditional
grower and she's only been doing dry
farming for a couple of years but she
literally let's kind of nature do all of
the work and and I get one of the
lessons is just how Hardy and how
powerful the cannabis plant is in
drawing the water and the nutrients that
it needs from the soil again I don't
know if there's any applications here
other than you know your training your
plant to be drought resistant to an
indoor more controlled environment but
maybe there is I would you know there's
so many there's so many considerations
to take it I could even say if it's the
right thing or not because how many
cycles a year could you get from that
plant right she does want to eat one she
does one harvest a year when I was here
and it might take so long because this
drought resistant to get to that spot
but even if you brought it indoors
you're not gonna be able to go through
the flowering stage in the same amount
of time
I think that though all those factors
need to be considered because growing
cannabis indoors is a business right
people are trying to save the energy and
balance that with get the yield and also
maintain consistent quality because they
have contracts to fulfill so all these
things need to be balanced with how to
be doing the most energy efficient way
also I mean we're talking a lot about
productivity and photosynthesis but you
know there's also quality considerations
and you know when we have flowering
fruiting plants they're flowering and
fruiting because they're stressed and
think they're gonna die right I mean
they're like oh my god you know winter
is coming I'm about to die so I better
start the propagation process so that I
can send out my seed I can send out my
pollen I can accept the pollen from a
male plant and so stressing them through
you know through drought conditions
through you know not giving them
nitrogen in the last week of their life
by dropping the temperature making them
think that the weather is changes these
are all techniques that they're using
and what they're doing is they're
inducing a stress response they are
making the plant think that it's going
to die I mean it is gonna die don't get
me wrong exactly and so keeping things
from it and creating not a good
environment or not a great condition for
productivity is actually going to
improve the quality of what it is that
we want to consume unless it's a lettuce
okay I mean unless ya controlled stress
exactly it's controlled controlled
stress and steering in the plant that's
a really excellent point I think because
that speaks to really what it's all
about you know and what a lot of these
growers all about that's what they're
going for especially the small ones the
Kraft ones where it's all about quality
or they're out of business they're just
not mass producing to generate some oils
right you know a gummy bear or something
I shouldn't say that for a gummy
some sort of gummies shaped animal
creature delicious so um what else can
we talk about HVAC wise
what do you anything else you guys want
to cover any new Jimmy to get on a
soapbox sure no you do a soapbox or
absolutely you can plug it a little bit
or that's usually best done in terms of
any sort of new technologies or
innovations that are on the horizon fair
enough yeah we see data every single day
of brute-force dehumidification systems
or miss applied dehumidification systems
that create either microclimates or huge
energy bills and the technologies exist
now there's no excuse for people not to
be using these new technologies they
involve those energy recovery systems
around the cooling coils which is you
know a primary way to do this or liquid
desiccant systems these technologies are
out there and until people come to
realize that there is a better way to do
it and still get the precision you need
inside the room look at the airflow you
need inside the room but also understand
that airflow is such a big deal you
can't just buy an air conditioner and
strap it to a room and expect it to do
the work so we don't like fans we don't
like air conditioners ideal all air flow
is natural no you what we need two air
conditioning and dehumidification if
we're gonna do an indoor grow we're
supplementing co2 to such a level that
if I just try to use outside air and
pump in a lot of co2 I'm gonna lose all
that co2 as the outside air comes in and
gets exhausted back out so I think air
conditioning and dehumidifying should be
done we should be doing it with more
efficient technologies so that's my one
rant and rave so buy a fish more
efficient mean more just simply more
energy efficient machine ologies
technologies yeah
such as such as so one way to dehumanize
more efficiently is to run an energy
exchange system around the primary
dehumidification mechanism so like you
said in your talk mechanical
dehumidification means I'm gonna cool
the air down to or below the dew point
which is the temper
which do we'll form I'm gonna do that
with a cooling coil and before I get
that air to the cooling coil I can
exchange energy from both sides of that
coil so that the air that reaches the
cooling coil is already saturated I take
away all the sensible temperature based
cooling I needed to do using the energy
exchange from behind the coil to the
front of it so the effect is I get to
reduce the amount of compressors I use
inside my air-conditioning unit by about
50% somewhere between 35 to 50 percent
so that's a technological solution
absolutely that has been done people
like you would would do we've already
implemented all of our lives and we've
been the industry has done it probably
for about 40 or 50 years you know in
places where you know we're in San Diego
many many engineering firms out here are
not familiar with the challenges of
dehumidification if this was Florida
we'd be having a different set of
engineers who can jump right in and say
yes we all do this yeah
up north I'm sorry go ahead go ahead I
was just gonna say I mean one thing also
is that conventional HVAC equipment has
been you know over the course of 20 30
40 years has been set to a higher
standard to meet certain energy
efficiency ratings and in order to meet
an ER and se ER and ier certain things
have certain changes in the design of
the HVAC system have occurred to reduce
compressor energy to reduce fan power
energy and the bummer part about that is
those things that have been done to
improve energy efficiency have have
resulted in less dehumidification
capacity of those equipments so I love
talking to mechanical engineers in the
south because they really understand the
challenges that energy efficient
equipment put on dehumidification
potential so it's fun I mean it's not
funny but it not funny ha ha funny but
you know you talk to a mechanical
engineer and
giorgia you just designed the
super-tight apartment building right and
they're using 17 or 18 seer vrf systems
and they can't control humidity so what
are they doing in these buildings
they're installing standalone
dehumidifiers
Wow exactly so they're the same pains an
apartment building yeah in residential
building even commercial buildings but
I'm just giving this one example I mean
I have this image of an article in my
head where they're literally installing
like in the wall standalone
dehumidifiers that look like like those
old radiant heaters that you would see
in like an old-school apartment they
make the same type of model but for a
dehumidifier and so structure - yeah
build the HVAC such that it took care of
both right and an ashtray is not
tackling this issue it's like this
elephant in the room and it's such a
bummer like there should be different
standards different codes based on your
climate zone I mean there are for a lot
of different things but for whatever
reason energy efficiency is God yes no
well they've started come up with MRE
ash MRE and some other like heart load
MREs but as it applies to the cannabis
or indoor grow in general those
standalone dehumidifiers are the bane of
many growers existence I mean we go into
grows where they have a graveyard of
spare parts because they've all broken
down and they've got new ones in and
they're mixing and matching components
and then they go and install them inside
their rooms stuff as many between the
lights as they can and the condensates
fill up and drip dirty condensate water
on top of their plant right we're
proponents of get everything out of the
room use one or maybe two units per room
that are both temperature and
dehumidification control systems have
them like outside have them outside and
duct it in and use that ductwork to
deliver the air in a consistent way to
circulate the air through the room
properly get it to the in rack fans and
distribution systems you need to just
that whole model boggles my mind and
that's that's really essentially
where we had our first kind of victory
it was going up against one of the
larger manufacturers who was first to
market in the cannabis specific HVAC
space and sitting at a table with them
and having them justify their decisions
and how they designed equipment and once
you lay out every single aspect of that
design versus a more holistic well
thought out and well engineered design
it's a no-brainer really it is and part
of it comes down to having the tools
I mean it's 2020 right we model every
single room there's no excuse for us not
to we have very expensive bottling
software we're going to use it we're
gonna model every single room to make
sure that I get the air where I need to
inside the canopy it's just whether it's
a greenhouse or indoor proper yeah
that's has to do that too it's critical
also with these types of systems that
enables you to actually it reduces the
differential you have between the air
coming into the space and the air
conditions you want to maintain within
that space as opposed to the redundancy
brute-force methods that are traditional
to the industry so far which is just you
know commercial air conditioning
equipment standalone dehumidifiers
exactly what you guys have been talking
about in that case all of your air
mixing is happening in the room instead
of supplying this like pretty close to
what you actually want it to be supply
air to the space you know you've got hot
dry air you've got cold saturated air
inside the space so then you have this
little climate around the plants and all
that's mixing on the plants yeah short
cycling air back to themselves right you
know they stopped a humidifying five
hours ago
yeah so like audience say Desert Hot
Springs in it where it's desert and it's
dry so that's a different problem in
solution isn't it you don't have a lot
of humidity out there so you have to put
moisture in are you talking about inside
a greenhouse in an indoor farm typically
we don't bring in a lot of outside air
were recirculating the majority of the
air co2 levels right so the outside air
has less of an impact on what's going on
inside the farm but in a greenhouse
environment that in a greenhouse
environment sure I mean in that case we
want to humidify your greenhouse so we
want to use evaporative cooling we want
to use high pressure fog system and add
moisture because the VPD will be too
high in there which is great I mean in
terms of cooling efficiency evaporative
cooling doesn't get more much more
efficient when it comes to energy the
problem is is that it uses a lot of
water yeah so for my PhD I actually
looked at water use efficiency of
evaporative cooling systems for
greenhouses and when I included that to
the entire water balance of the
hydroponic system all of a sudden it
looked like growing tomatoes in a field
in terms of water use efficiency okay
yeah of course I would say that there's
a lot of benefits to growing in a
greenhouse I mean just the quality of
the product the control of the
environment year-round production you
know t OVI me and it's gonna ripen right
there and be as nutritious of a tomato
as possible the altitude of the
greenhouse impact these factors the
environment yeah sure so there's a
reason why you see green houses being
built at higher altitudes because the
high maximum high daily temperature is
lower also
there's less obstruction to sunlight
just through you know the particles in
the air so I mean really you're closer
to the Sun so you get better light
transmission so it's cooler better light
transmission
yeah there's absolutely I mean from an
HVAC perspective if you're designing a
piece of equipment yeah absolutely
altitude changes everything but we have
calculations to solve that problem and
it's it's not a hero there I think it's
a bigger deal for greenhouses for sure
are your machines geared for certain
size grows or do you work with all
different size you know just in terms of
our bandwidth as a company we're trying
to focus on 10,000 square-foot Ciotti in
a facility or you know of but are we go
into rooms that are about a thousand of
1500 feet up to you nee
that there's no top limit on that so my
kind of general takeaway from this is
that there's still a lot of conversation
to be had with the cultivators you know
and education in order to get all of
this right that there's still some
misunderstanding and there's so many
factors to consider and you know despite
the fact that so many of them have been
grow you know growing for a long time
the learning curve is still you know
there and straight up and that's just
kind of my takeaway it's not the growers
it's the science it's everything about
this it's still so news right so there's
yes so in general we just we need better
communication education across the
aisles if I can you know I mean
manufacturers and engineers and
technical people really need to
understand the plant better they need to
understand the grower better they need
to understand that farming is a business
you know and just the complexity that
we've all been talking about in terms of
growing a plant it's not just throwing a
seed in the ground and then you know
watering it and it's just gonna poof
grow into you know the beautiful plant
that you want it to be and then we need
growers to understand the engineering to
understand the implications of their
choice of vapor pressure deficit you
know also needs to understand this is
home growers yeah sure you know because
home grow is a really important part of
this industry and hopefully will be
allowed throughout this country you know
there some states they don't want to
allow it but that would be a really big
mistake well they especially need to if
they don't want to ruin their homes you
go into any room that's how to grow in
it and go looking for mold and you don't
need to look too far right you put a
high humidity room in a cold environment
that wasn't meant to have a high
humidity room in it I'm so sorry if you
have other people living there besides
yourself but you've made a mistake is
hugely problematic it's probably the
reason that we have grocery stores today
the fact is
the production quality you can get from
a craft grower is most likely gonna
eclipse what most people can do at home
right and look there's a novelty to it
my parents are Italian my dad every year
we harvested all the tomatoes and
lettuce we know that we wanted to eat
from our own backyard so I get the
homegrown approach but if you're gonna
put it indoors we're talking about
indoor AG I think is an efficiency thing
just be very careful are there any like
little grow rooms that work have you
ever seen them work but I know that they
exist the girl attends and they have
like cute really cool-looking
architectural boxes with the lights
inside and HVAC included and they do all
the things but I've never seen them work
they seem to be a novelty I'm sure they
do well with the problem be that there
but porous or there they don't they
don't maintain the correct environment I
just haven't seen them work but they
look very cool very cool looking for
sure I really really enjoyed listening
to this conversation I'm just curious to
know about the the best way to price
HVAC is it dollars per ton is it is it
pounds of moisture removal per kilowatt
and is there are there ways to specify
it by square footage of grow or other
are the challenges and pitfalls doing
doing it that way I mean if we're
talking about conventional equipment
where a ton of cooling is includes both
the temperature heat removal and the
latent moisture removal then you know we
can use kind of our typical HVAC rules
of thumb which ranges you know from a
thousand to three thousand dollars per
ton let's just call it that
however because of dehumidification
because it's not so II I mean you can
convert you know pounds per hour to BTUs
per hour to a ton
but really if we're talking about a
dehumidification or moisture removal
efficiency then basing a price on
tonnage might not make as much sense
it's dependent on room conditions as
well correct yeah yeah well your set
points are oh so I agree with dollars
per ton from our perspective because we
have that energy efficiency mechanism
inside of our unit which reduces tons by
thirty five to fifty percent we use way
less tons but we moved as much air and
we have as many components in there the
dollar per ton doesn't make sense so
we're looking we are striving for that
metric dollar per pound per hour is a
good metric for us because the numbers
work out to be you know not astronomical
and not too small they're just kind of
enough how do you figure this out how do
you figure out ahead of time before you
have to buy it how much you're gonna
need what how much you're not gonna need
to remove from the environment so before
you purchase the thing or yeah so we
have a most most manufacturers will have
a project input form and that project
input form is going to look at well what
they're trying to get is what are the
inputs of energy over the course of 24
hours of the highest load of that room
both in electricity and in water so
remembering that transpiration is 99% of
the water you put into the plant is
going to end up out of the plant we need
and into the air that we have to remove
we're gonna look for the number of
plants and the water per plant per day
at the peak time of transpiration to
determine and that's that's not
necessarily the same thing as how much
water I put in the root zone and how
much water stays in the root zone in the
course of that 24 hours I need to be
able to remove that with my
dehumidification and temperature
controls can you determine that while
there while they're under construction
we do it before they're under people
okay yeah so there's usually a grower
who's on board with the development team
that grower will say I did this before
and this is what we're gonna do here and
then we look at those numbers and say
well those numbers are wrong because
they are not accounting for
you know they're not accounting for
drainage or those numbers are right
because they seem to fit a set of ranges
that we've run into time and time again
or they're right because they fit the
data we get out of rooms that are
similarly designed to this with the same
lighting technology in the plant density
things like that so we can advise and
say your weed we think you might want to
revisit this or we think your bang on
and then give them a size of equipment
that they can then go and take to the
market have you dealt with any and I
know that several grows have hired
growers from the Netherlands to come
over because they've worked at scale
have you dealt with any of them and is
this stuff are they are late queued into
all of this because they're so
experienced some of them are amazing yes
so at the Canadian greenhouse conference
I ran into a number of them who had such
an incredible understanding of
temperature and humidity control it was
almost unmatched and I was very happy to
be talking to them there were others who
were 50 years in the greenhouse industry
looking at newcomers like ourselves who
come from the commercial and indoor AG
space saying you don't know what you're
doing this is a huge mistake
and you know this you know these things
well these ideas will never work
those same growers those sorry those
same greenhouse manufacturers you know
had their facility shut down because it
wasn't a Canada fybel cannabis facility
you know two up two months after it was
bought they pulled all the plants out
had to destroy them all because the
powdery mildew outbreak and it turns out
that cut flower greenhouses are not
ideal for cannabis so when people you
know what we have to take what people
say and their experience with a maybe a
grain of salt sometimes they have a firm
belief that they are the best right
we've been doing this in the Netherlands
for so long how could dare you question
us and then well look it's a it's a
whole new world so what happens when the
day comes and we've solved the mildew
problem in cannabis if that day could
ever comment below they're working on
share the Sun is expanded in the or or
genetically
new strangers say that we're done what
does that change everything here does
that change it's not just about powdery
mildew or mold yeah it's about plant
health and but its nature of the more
that causes growers to behave in a
certain way so their behavior might
change that well it takes away one of
the many variables they're concerned
about okay yeah there are so many other
pests and pathogens to worry about for
sure right waterborne yeah okay thank
you
this was really wonderful right question
well what you guys