[Music]
we were talking and you you said oh I
you know one of my beds or one of my
rooms has 919 cycles on it
I started trying to kind of crank out
the math on on what that is and I was
like well I don't know he's doing this
of three four years five years that
you're putting into this medium and we
see that out here outside all the time
but in the indoor environment that's not
common and they you know come on any
kind of scale it's it's it's even more
round there's a couple of people you
know they're doing this small-scale but
like what's well what kind of inspired
you to jump into that I mean it was
really a number of things getting
introduced to permaculture was like
getting introduced to cannabis but for
like different reasons the same reasons
ways cameras helped me I feel like
permaculture would help the planet so
then when we were putting these
obstacles in front of us with our state
regulations versus trying to you know
bump our heads against them we try to
work with them the best we can and adapt
you know how we operate how we do things
and Indore was one of the biggest
challenges we had to face with the
microbial testing they weren't really
allowing us to really even entertain
outdoor even greenhouse for the most
part so really forced us to put our
focus on indoors and just being the most
sustainable regenerative as possible
indoor facility on the planet was kind
of our goal how do I help was it didn't
do a solo but it was definitely a
journey and we're still learning till
the day yeah so when you kind of when
all this culminate and you actually get
in a facility and running it was that
you more coming from the permaculture
farming gardening background or the
indoor cultivation background or neither
so so for me know as I was a medical
marijuana patient I hate to use M word
other than
side of that if that's what they call it
but yeah so I was ahead I was on the
patient program so I was strictly just
growing cannabis oh my god I've grown
food as a kid I grew up in a berry the
farming community people like to farm
where I'm from everybody has a little
vegetable butter in the backyard so that
that's kind of the culture I came from
but for the most part I came as a
patient into the industry so my thing
was more as a medicine plant medicine
and then when I was introduced to
permaculture I saw that as again a
medicine for the planet you know it's
kind of thought putting the two together
that's like okay we got this gateway
drug on gateway drug let's make it a
gateway drug to sustainability and
permaculture agenda they're farming so
we try to put those two together and
really and use cannabis as this you know
this this lead to introduce people to
this this save the world method
methodologies you know there's a lot of
research out there I follow I try to
follow more lean when some of I think
she said in try to adapt as she says to
to endure situations but there's a lot
of things an example as far as I'm sorry
like something Elaine an idea she had
that you then like translated
we'll just to soil food web in general I
had managed embeds so a lot of the
things that she does outdoors dealing
with the seasons and the seasonal
changes and just a lot of the things
that she's incorporated we could
incorporate those indoors just put a
little spin on it you know yeah so
that's kind of what I've been tripping
off of as we kind of start talking about
an actual soil food web and a living
soil system indoors is whether it be
pollen ator crops or whatever outdoors
we can bring we can bring things we can
attract things in a way it's a little
bit difficult indoors do you do you
achieve that really by by bringing these
things into your garden so it's and we
could bring anything into our garden you
know we can we could buy any bug on the
planet and bring it to my garden and
that's not really a sustainable model
you know the idea is if we do inoculate
our facility whether it be with a
microorganism or an orthopod or some
type of predator that that we can keep
it around and sustain it and potentially
even finish its lifecycle so that we
don't have to keep purchasing them so
that's been kind of my goal is is is to
not just focus on on what's in nature
but how do i replicate it to where I can
finish not just a plant's life cycle but
all the beneficial microorganisms and
organisms life cycles that are also
involved in this process yeah I mean I
see that very much in my own garden
spaces I'm I'm gonna purchase something
I don't want it to be kind of a one-time
thing and if it thrives then great and
if it doesn't that I need to reassess
the situation so you guys kind of just
see a similar thing in terms of how how
you build these systems and I I guess
you're fortunate on the one hand that
that endure for cultivation probably
maybe afford to certain flexibilities
first pest management yes certain
control mechanisms we're able to do
indoors so we run a lot of the same
strategies but again we were able to
catch to track better data indoors
because we all have so many variables as
the outdoor people do so we've actually
covered a lot of ground again just using
the same exact techniques just on the
indoor model but yeah my biggest thing
right now is again is just not having
too
inoculate because again that's not
sustainable if I have to have a bug
truck show up every week and drop up
bugs from God knows where they came from
you know so our thing right now is just
to keep things alive I feel like
everybody's real pumped on living soils
and living systems but the truth of
matter is we're all growing in dying
soils and dying systems because we're so
focused on the lifecycle or the plant
that we're forgetting that there's
organisms in our soil organisms below
our crop our canopy that also have a
life cycle that needs to be finished and
how do we highly keep them and take them
into consideration and still maintain a
profitable business you know so that's
one thing I've done is just really try
to map out a good a good system that
models nature so we can allow all those
things to happen the strong survive and
then they have a place in our system and
but everything has a place in system at
the end of the day so it was kind of as
I've been wrapping my head around this
idea and how deep embeds kind of roughly
are we talking in moisture systems so we
have our facility right now in proper
our flagship facility my buddy Matt
Davenport actually back in the day when
did when designing the beds we actually
went extra deep we wanted big we were
like me and we're this is still so so
new like the last soil that the better
like the less the less cushion we have
so we basically I think I believe there
are 18 or 20-inch beds deep so so there
it's way more soils and I technically
need but again I'm not that good of a
gardener so it allows me to have some
flexibility so I don't have to be so so
so on point you know no absolutely and
so so then the reason I asked that
question is now I'm sore anything of all
you miss or like way higher and like for
your size of your facility a much higher
amount of medium grant and Kranti you're
not switching that media all the time so
it's like it's not that it's a big deal
on that end but you're LED right and so
how do you feel that have you raised
your room's temperatures to compensate
for that yes that's a great question by
the way you know people catch that yeah
so we run a warmer air temp to back in
the day using the hid we typically run
you know
seventy-five our 78 to 80 degrees and
now I get to leave surface temperature
right about where you want to 81 83 kind
of range both LEDs they run so much
cooler you have to raise your air
temperature to achieve a good leaf
surface temperature so yes we typically
run our rooms anywhere from eighty one
to eighty three depending on season but
yeah that's that's kind of our sweet
spot yeah and you know it's it's only an
ID it's it's my like only positive I
really could throw out there for pot
seem like a greenhouse setting it was
really when we're talking about more
uncontrolled spaces is that allows
greater sides in terms of surface area
so we're getting a little bit faster
warming up in the media
and so in the indoor setting and LED do
you guys feel like your media just kind
of holds a fairly consistent temperature
it doesn't get cold or you know indoors
we haven't seen much change because our
beds are off the ground I feel like it's
like we're doing a greenhouse project
right now well we plan on slamming the
beds on the ground so we're gonna do
some radiant floor so radiant bed
heating in the beds just to maintain
soil temperature in the winter time but
indoors we haven't seen a problem we
were again we run the same cycle over
and over again so they really don't see
much change on the indoors the the
radiant heat definitely had changed the
whole dynamic for me as far as growing
in beds to like to put like it's really
exciting and it just seems so much more
efficient to actually heat this this
giant sink you know heat sink that can
let off that that heat slowly is
supposed to but yeah that's that's
awesome to hear it is just about making
it work because I know that for like for
some of my people that are trying to go
with more regenerative approaches and
endure as they catch a certain flak
sometimes they're like well you're
growing indoors it's like but people got
work in their confined and so it's it's
so interesting to talk to somebody
that's kind of that that's doing
something and like this is how we can
meld these worlds and work from there
yeah I could go outdoors I would you
know so I was kind of pushed to the
indoors and you know it's really the end
of the day it's what are your intentions
I'm not growing indoors because I think
it caused a better crop I'm not growing
no-till cuz I think it has marketable
I'm doing the best I can with what I
have so my intentions aren't I would
have grown a lesser quality product the
same way and still been just as happy
but just I also happens to turn out that
this process provide creates a superior
a superior quality product so that's
just more of a byproduct to the whole
point of why we do this you know I mean
that's also spot-on I really I see that
and it's I think it's a lot more
commonplace for people to wrap their
mind around outdoor being grown in that
fashion
indoors just it's it's my two separate
worlds coming together in a way that
they like they haven't for me and they
are for other people you know I've
transitioned from the indoor to organic
living bed through and herb but I didn't
like transition Matt right into an
indoor my mind was still on fucking pots
and indoors now I'm big fan of beds oh I
do I do like beds indoors I think it's a
huge crucial I don't pot as well I'm
just too much to manage to micro climb
or micro environments
hey buddy I was warned not to pet this
cat but he seems like he's friendly yeah
they said they attacked if you touch it
back in 75 see how people pet him I'm
still nervous
bring herb Larry Lawrence you got herbes
what do you got what do you got you got
something you got something some some
outdoor mesh what do you what do you got
this is you guys yeah yeah this is I can
smell that
that's my garlic food and that's some
some seed crop that some friend of our
super lemon kindness to it yeah it's
it's really enjoyable for me like super
not not marketable but unlike all the
marketable stuff I've been like that's
already a few times to talk about that
talk about the marketable versus the
stuff you like to smoke so how you gonna
say where's this mimosa
you got so
oh it's far as Oh what I I guess a
little wrong yeah about so I realized
this certain hypocrisy that I got going
on recently where I like the the strains
that I that I grow that I sell the most
of I don't really smoke and then I have
these other varieties that I love and I
think are wonderful like that but
because they have they're less
photogenic or whatever their name isn't
hot and I'm the Wright family like they
don't they don't have market play and as
such I'm like speaking about how awesome
these these strains are and how more
people should consume them but I'm not
really putting them out to the market
because I got to go through these
channels to get distribution and all
that stuff and they're saying no that
won't work that'll just sit there what
do you see for yourself yeah it's very
similar I mean I remember we first
opened up I tried to grow everything
that I like and it to be honest it it's
it's it's always changing you know
saying bacon I thought it was gonna be
more of a sativa dominant City because
it's just the the CEO goes all night you
know so I came out with a bunch of
sativas but everybody wanted to get
knocked out with oh geez so then so then
we switched up our catalog and started
growing a bunch of heavy indicas and
then everybody kind of came around was
tired of falling asleep at eight o'clock
I was asking first además so it's like
you're constantly gonna be behind the
ball so that what I found is it's always
have your finger on at least a little
bit of the height just just to stay
relevant just get people's attention but
it's also to try to create your own
height you know I mean a fights not a
fight unless you can create hype and you
can sell it
so it's like strange that I like I'll
try to pre hype them knowing that you
know the market might not response him
well but I'll pre hype it just so they
get excited about it for a minute just
so I have something to smoke that I want
to smoke yeah so you guys so saying that
if you got hyping you can sell for at
least a minute you know hopefully they
catch on sometimes I don't know but I
mean that word it's like it's like
anything else so where I was time or
something about about hype hype what was
the other one wasn't just hype it was
hustle hustle so so a hustler is a bad
thing but hustling is good it's all just
fucking semantics and so height or
personal brand versus reputation it was
just when that term people are using
personal brand and so I feel that way
with with hype is that if something's
good then it's good and I'll stand on
its merit but still it needs some kind
of what else do you call high I'm kind
of pushing out there so to me it doesn't
mean automatically that it's like some
some falsehood some fakeness yeah not
necessarily I think I think it more from
a from a from a prizefighting standpoint
you know can't sell fight unless you
hypo fight
but do you feel like I mean in the
California market basically I need a
strip here I talked to they got 20%
threshold if it's under 20% THC that's
they claim it's not moving needs to be
pennies on the dollar all that yeah
that's the way that the market is being
run right now there because it's so
focused on test results
you can't touch feel smoke taste so you
has it then look at the test results
that piece of paper and you have to put
all your trust into that piece of paper
that's why focusing on your branding
helps kind of break through that a
little bit but even us in Vegas and you
know we're pretty reputable brand and
yeah we try to keep everything above 20%
at least total cannabinoids if not THC
it just helps move it just helps me tell
it better on their standpoint you
understand from somebody who knows
nothing that walks in again can't touch
feel smoke they look at the results is
and they don't want to have to sit there
and actually work to sell it and they
have to educate somebody that doesn't
know something so yeah it's very test
results based it still is Tuesday what I
like is originally really did spark
education everybody had learned about
terpenes and cannabinoids chemo chemo
VARs and and all these different things
and and
it sparked a huge huge just knowledge
sharing of everybody just kind of
sharing what they were learning it was
pretty cool but I don't like is that you
know it's gone corporate you know and
it's only gonna get worse when things go
federal it's not going to get better
Stephanie gonna get worse so it's just
it's trying to have an organic company
in the corporate industry is can be
challenging at times you know
what do you think this is beautiful yeah
no this is it checks off the boxes man
it's got definitely got the bag appeal
it's got the nose it just just can't
taste it
you can't feel it yet but looking
forward to it well I think touching on
that point how the distribution and
retail model is so broke and that I want
to be moving forward in life and when I
see like I don't really like my herb
trims before I spoke it but that's what
whatever that's a reality but at least
when it was congregated together on the
traditional market or on the medical
market that's how we always saw it is
you got your Ethan it was pulled out
fresh and it had been hanging out with
its friends now it's all lonely in this
little jar and I feel like oxidation all
these things are sped up and I was
looking at some of my product that was
dated that it was packaged in September
and I was really disappointed and I've
pulled out the same herb when he was
over and it would just it was fine it
was great and then I looked at this
jarred thing that he had sent me to show
me the jar and what was inside I was
like oh just not super stuff that's
definitely that's always part of a
problem and I can understand point we
packaged everything before we sell in
the eights no less so we do a lot of
packaging and it's really crucial that
we make sure that it's at its highest
quality when it goes out so we have our
packaging room is environmentally
controlled so we're not packaging wet or
we're not starting off with cured good
flour and then packaging dry dust so so
we definitely control the environment in
that aspect I'm just trying to make sure
that selling it in smaller sizes as well
makes people burn through it we spread
ourselves out so it's not sitting on the
shelves for too long so we try to have
fast turnover that also helps with that
if you serve somebody up too deep they
have to sit on you know several packs
for six months and then somebody's
getting signals laners but sitting in a
room at 110 degrees in the desert you
then get some freaking complaints Manan
sucks we've had them is it again it's
not our fault always but we always try
to just do our best that we can to make
sure that it goes out the best that we
can send it
you know we try putting glass
immediately that's a big thing too is I
think a lot of people in our situation
put in plastic bags and things like that
then it just dries out and and it just
turns into crap yes you can more than
anything in the whole world it's it's
they shut down the licensing system for
five years that was the first time they
gave him out my wife I know the answer
that I would be wrong to fight I mean
there's gotta be over 100 yeah they just
gave out another 66 licenses for the
first time in about five there was four
years of the time was last year around
this time they gave him out but there
were some issues with it as far as the
the judging process was was found to be
corrupt and there were some some weird
stuff going on there so everything's
tight at the court right now so they
have 66 licenses they're just pending
until they figure this legal battle out
but it's definitely it's a very hard
license to acquire you gotta I don't
know who you got to know or how much
money you got to have I don't know but
it's it's it's not an easy one to get
and say that I know for sure I hear you
say that your your package unit so do
you have a manufacturing license to do
that or is that just part of your
cultivation rights so in the state of
Nevada they have I think it's like five
million licenses now it's cultivation
which allows us to package our own
products and then it's a production
which is like making oils and edibles
and things of that nature
right testing and then dispensing and
then now they have distribution and we
also have a distribution license which
was really excited about and which I
think a lot of people here's to really
be focusing on except could be that one
connecting factor where a good organic
distribution company like that's how the
alcohol come lose their they have
distribution companies that they sell
all this shit through them sure yeah
I mean is tricky because it seems like
it really is split up in the back that
we as cultivators can't package unless
we have somehow a manufacturing license
we really yeah most of us don't so like
do they make it a challenge to get both
I haven't delved into it enough to like
tell you how hard it would be like I I
think it's a lot of 88 compliance
stuff which for us in the mountains
becomes tricky sometimes like I was I
was like like you know an existing
cultivator I was able to work around
some of those issues on the cultivation
zyv but I'd imagine if I brought in
packaging would the co manufacturing
like then all of a sudden I would be in
a new place they want to see that happen
more in cities do you realize that
that's that's a challenge man that's
doesn't really make sense either in any
way shape or form I can see how they
could justify their you know end up
being a little bit at the mercy like if
we can go and get set
separate packaging done but like a lot
of times it's done with a destro and
then they're tagging on old sin that's
kind of their label with yours on the
side and that's just kind of how it
becomes as like slippery slope into the
whole white label it's definitely
causing a problem for branding is a
hundred percent I can see that being an
issue
that was a big like shift for us to
realize like okay we need to do more of
our own jarring and marketing even
though it costs us it's a we make more
money if we just sell the flour to
somebody who's going to put their label
on it
but that doesn't that doesn't work out
well in the long term now is our thing
is early on we had a lot push back
everyone to run like more like a
Starbucks model in the bag at first
where nobody knows where the beans come
from you're at Starbucks showed up at
Starbucks and that was kind of what they
were going for but we get in pushback
like no we really need you just to put
it in our glass jar and not just to
preserve the quality of it but just to
protect our brand and I want to do my
life what's that they wanted to do bags
oh yeah at the time everybody was bags
yeah but no one's even thinking about
doing drugs but yeah that was a big
thing was was hey we really had a fight
to have our own brand and not just be
selling beans to Starbucks and they
protect us because if people don't if
people weren't asking specifically for
GOP these days we wouldn't be in shops
you know it means so it didn't really
help her help us at that time but it's
definitely we're benefiting it from of
today for sure really that's really cool
and it's just gonna have this this reach
because it has that truth in the way
that people know it is buy I got a lot
of people that I think do a really good
job they all kind of seem to share so
many similarities in the indoor world
like I've kind of seen this focus on
certain tiles of salt growing and all
the models kind of is is the same in
these facilities that I visit and sort
of think about like your facility where
maybe some of the technical aspects are
similar but like that you're bringing
more yeah most most outdoor guys only
kind of my farm they they they they geek
out way harder than they thought they
would they think maybe they go thinking
and be like are they kind of you know
suspects and they going like oh my god
this is like this is this is dope this
is this is on point with everything you
know III heard but didn't think was
possible
life extreme weather like instead of
keeping everything perfectly with
advance two legs stress attack I don't
have to test it because it'll happen
eventually
something's gonna break yeah anything I
can't have it will happen so yeah
example today I just got news that our
power shut off and we lost power which
is very weird for the position voice is
rare yeah it's rare for us because we're
located between two power lines so
typically one goes out there the one
picks up so I still haven't got a call
back but they got fixed I know
everything's good but you never know
wasn't happy got be prepared for
everything I'd be able again just be
able to be flexible be able to adapt and
just respond creatively to change you
know so we started five years ago or
four and a half years ago five ish with
an older light Lumet X they really did
better quality light back then but it
was have that blue bold purple pink
stuff but it was a good light man we got
really good using it and we had everyone
two rooms a lot warm with that light
with the to avoid photo bleaching I was
making probably how's that light and
running cooler temperatures but we got
really good with it and then just
recently I've been looking for a couple
years to replace him took on up datum
because technology and how it is you
know it's next year the LEDs maybe 10
times in this year's are these and so on
and so forth so who knows but I recently
found a company that I'm really
confident with post they they out build
their CFO say I'll build their LEDs that
they make the most gnarly fo HSE and
they just out build these LEDs like
they're just gnarly
they're like the the biggest strongest
powerfullest most well-built LED I've
seen on the market they're they
overpower them in my situation overpower
me a little bit which is good for me
because they don't have to run a full
full bore and I can always turn them up
later years if they do start to lose
their abilities so yeah we're harnessing
LED right now have been from day one
what
the guy there's a guy I think from like
Oregon God like his price per pound dad
like indoors price per pound way down
and he was like speaking at events
what do you measure stuff and like what
you're getting your price per pound down
yeah I mean but we're always evolving so
that there's no real we know for the
most part money I don't want to say it
wrong
with my wife list here to answer this
question she's the one that has all the
books and all that stuff but yeah I know
it's it's you gotta you gotta have a
have a competitive bottom price and in
no-till indoors LEDs our facility I
guarantee is is efficient as anything on
the planet so I know our costs are
extremely low not just on just
electricity and but also employment like
I'm really efficient with my with my
employees I have two women that run a
12,000 square foot grow on the
cultivation side they don't tell the
trimming but there's two women run three
huge rooms and just being a super
efficient able to execute proper tasks
at the proper time and not waste time in
the wrong areas is then really key for
us to maximize honestly just we've been
in for five years now we're gonna try
the same thing every time makes my new
adjustments every cycle the for the
better and we just kind of worked out
all the kinks just made as efficient as
possible that's really how you save
money too is if I had I could do the
same thing I did five years ago I had
six people running the exact same three
grow rooms that I have two women running
now so it's it's it's unbelievable
we use air conditioners yeah it's indoor
so just traditional their business
that's uh definitely something that I
changed a little bit the future that I
think there's more efficient ways to
cool rooms but you know fact what are
you well right now are 2.0 in our
greenhouse that's kind of our two point
of it actually our we have a future
build out like water-cooled systems
what's the one I found came in with even
coming right now but other generator
driven systems the natural gas
generating systems are really efficient
and actually kind of a cleaner more
greener way to cool a building so we
kind of look into those looked into one
of those for a project in Michigan well
honestly with LEDs in the amount of
Brewster first place we have I really
think with a le I'm sorry our solar
panels in future we can take a big dent
of our power usage I mean the only thing
we don't have a lot of his water I mean
so what type what type of greenhouse are
you so the state kind of made us jump
through some hoops they made us attach
our greenhouse compound to our existing
indoors so we have to enter our indoor
dress out its into it into our
greenhouse the corridors yeah it's
pretty pretty crazy but at the end of
the day it's it's actually I keep our
greenhouse safer and cleaner I guess you
know then people just walking in from
the outside so I can't hate too much
it's a hoop they may have drunk through
that it's ultimately they keep more bugs
out I guess but we end up going with the
Agrotech greenhouse we just did for work
four days but there's a thing should I
say positive pressure Agrotech
greenhouse oh yeah yeah I've you've been
inside one yes yes right now so we did
three separate Bay's so there's three
separate burrows owns and then positive
pressure and wanted to keep pests pests
out but also pollen we got a lot of hemp
in our area a lot of people don't open
pollination males females not Poland not
calling their males so for us it's just
one way to reduce the potential of you
know cross contamination was hemp pollen
[Music]
yeah we did it won't be done for we're
hopefully we'll be done by summer it
will help me be done by something we
already broke ground