[Music]
little secular we spend a lot of time as
engineers using this tool this device
which discusses the properties of air
and the water in the air and we use it
to figure out how to condition that air
whether it's meeting cooling humidifying
dehumidifier this chart comes from many
many hundreds of thousands of points of
data that are collected in the field to
generate this chart and it all has to do
with how much air is in the water and
how we go from one temperature of air or
one humidification point of air to
another so let's talk about the chart
you know you should all have a
handy-dandy inspire psychometric chart
in your hands let's talk about some of
the different axes so this is our chart
along the bottom you're gonna find the
dry bulb temperature dry bulb
temperature you're gonna find the wet
bulb temperature in a diagonal from the
bottom right hand corner of the chart to
the top left-hand corner of the chart in
green lines you're gonna find the dew
point temperature as an axis here along
the y axis of the chart on the right
hand side you're gonna find relative
humidity as swooping lines starting from
100 which is the very top of this chart
along this swooping line to 0 percent
relative humidity along with this flat
line and the swooping lines that are
connected in between are all the
relative Commedia lines and then allows
me to find is the humidity ratio so
humidity ratio also runs along this axis
here it's this axis right here is the
humidity ratio it deals with the amount
of water in air
alright let's talk about what Elly's
done with all these different terms me a
dry bulb thermometer is the thermometer
you might be used to when someone took
your temperature as a kid this is a
thermometer that when waved around in
the air it is dry on the outside this
bulb right here is dry and it is
measuring what we call the sensible
energy of the air it is the dry bulb
temperature of the air any time you want
to use this chart you can use one of
these thermometers to measure the air
you're trying to put on the chart wave
it around the in that air and it'll tell
you where you should be along this axis
the next couple of tools will help us
figure out how far up we go on this axis
to find our place on the chart so we've
got dry bulb now we have a wet bulb
thermometer very similar device in fact
it's the exact same device except there
is a sock at the end of it that is
soaking wet okay
why do we do that well the wet bulb
thermometer is going to find another
point on this chart and it's gonna tell
us the rate at which the water is
evaporating off of the sock and in doing
so bring down the temperature of the
bulb which is encased in that wet sock
so I want to find out the wet bulb
temperature of some air I need to
measure I'm gonna take this wet sock
sling it around inside my room that I'm
trying to measure and the temperature I
read on this chart will give us the
second point along the wet bulb lines
and between the two points I now know
where we are on the chart that is
because of the evaporative cooling
effect of water same reason that we
sweat and we get hot the same reason
that plants transpire when they're
exposed to radiation okay so let's talk
about why the dew points relevant we
have this dew point on the chart right
here this is something you'll see every
day on the nightly news they'll talk
about the dew point temperature
as we go into our overnight condition
what they're really concerned about is
if the temperature of the air gets below
this number that we call the dew point
we are going to have condensation come
out of the air and on to the surface
that is at or below that - so when you
repeat that the dew point is the
temperature at which condensation will
occur so if I take a can of coke out of
a fridge and it's below the dew point of
the air that we've plotted using our dry
bulb and wet ball thermometers that can
of coke being below the dew point will
condense moisture on its surface this is
the principle by which most mechanical
cooling is done and most mechanical
dehumidification is done as well yes
question
great question a dewpoint is a measure
of absolute humidity any line that goes
directly up and down here any access
that is on the y axis of this chart is a
measure or reference for absolute
humidity but one of the things you
should note is that it is a it is a
useful tool rather than an absolute
measure of a physical property so for
example and I probably did more that
right but then right next time so as an
example we're about to talk about the
humidity ratio which is an actual
measurement of the amount of water in
the air if we could collect it all
inside of a pound of air which takes up
about 13 cubic square feet if we take
all the water in that and measure it out
and plot whatever point we're at on that
humidity ratio we'll find out exactly
how many grains of water which are of
course out of 7,000 pound we'll find out
how many grains of what are inside okay
so do occurs when surfaces reach the dew
point temperature inside fog occurs when
the air is saturated so if we happen to
hit that magical condition in Santa Cruz
all summer long when the temperature is
60 degrees Fahrenheit and the air coming
in off the ocean has been cooled down to
60 degrees the moisture being at a
hundred percent doesn't pick up all that
water off the ocean rolls in his father
so fog is air which is saturated with
water and can no longer hold anywhere
water if I try to mist water into it
that water would beat up form raindrops
and fall out
so that one other measure we want to
talk about is the relative humidity so
let's talk about what motive humidity is
we see these swooping lines this bottom
one here is zero and then they start
swooping up from zero all the way to a
hundred it's very important to know that
the relative humidity is the amount of
moisture that's in a given amount of air
over the amount of moisture that the
given amount of air can hold it is not a
measure of how much of the air is water
if you take a look at the humidity ratio
which will describe shortly you'll find
out very quickly that at a hundred
percent relative humidity we're not
talking more than a percent or two of
actual water molecules versus the rest
of the air molecules around it so a
hundred percent relative humidity is
only one or two percent of water in the
air does that word follow that 100
percent relative humidity is a measure
of the humidity carrying the water
carrying capacity of air not of the
amount of water that makes up the air
okay
so if I have a given volume of air and I
put in 50% of what it can hold I have a
50% relative humidity
if I have saturated in air if I go into
a cloud and take a measure of how much
water is in that volume of air I will
find that I could not put any more water
into that air this is what clouds are
this is what fog is this is what a
misting system creates it creates a
hundred percent Bills of humidity so now
let's talk about the humidity ratio so
let's say I was gonna take that and
follow you of air which was that 50 or
100 percent relative humidity and
squeeze out the cloud squeeze out all
the water from that particular volume
and then weigh the water
versus the weight of the air the
humidity ratio is a weight divided by a
weight the humidity ratio is grains
which is a unit of measure for weight
grades of water divided by pounds water
it is grains per pound grains of water
per pound of air does everyone follow
there's other numbers that exist for
this as well anytime you see humidity
ratio you can expect it to be a mass
over a mass or a weight over a week so
you may have grams per kilogram you may
have pounds per pound you know pounds
per pound well you've got very very very
small numbers so the humidity ratio that
we work with which is greens / pounds
just happens to give us some numbers
that are in our tangible reach they're
not 5 6 decimal places they're not in
the hundreds of thousands or millions
they just exist in a very small number
that is useful for us to use okay we've
talked about this entire chart you know
everything there is to know about
finding your way around this chart
except to say that things change air
changes temperature changes humidity
so let's talk a little bit about what we
can do with this information to figure
out where we're gonna go and apply it in
our growers let's start by finding our
way onto a specific point on the turf so
let's say we've got our dry bulb
thermometer and we've got our wet bulb
thermometer we go outside on a hot humid
day in Atlanta we measure 95 degrees
Fahrenheit dry ball and we measure 78
degrees Fahrenheit wet bulb so take a
moment to look at your second bunch of
charts and let's play plot the point so
on the x-axis down here you're gonna
find 95 degrees Fahrenheit between 99
then you're gonna look at the wet bulb
lines and you're gonna take the 95
degree fahrenheit line all the way up
until it crosses through the 78 degrees
Fahrenheit wet Bob line and you should
put with your pen a little dot there and
that's where we are now what else do we
know about this point
let's all tell me what is the relative
humidity at this point
okay so 95 degrees Fahrenheit it's 95
degrees Fahrenheit and 78 degrees wet
ball Jessie what do you have
okay so along the x-axis on the bottom
of this chart ya go to 95 degrees dorita
now look at the green lines which are
the wet bulb temperature that run in
this direction okay now find the one
that's at 78 so 75 76 77 78 okay now run
over until those two points me 95 and 78
and put a circle there put a dot
perfect
so tell me Jesse what relative humidity
are we at
so the way to find this out is by
starting at the bottom and saying this
is zero percent relative humidity ten is
the next line up twenty thirty forty
fifty where are we
just below fifty we're out about 48
percent notes if you look good okay
great Brian you got it on it
Brian without looking at that board
don't look down I have what is the dew
point at this condition
remembering the dew point is along the
right side of your chart it's what are
the axes that goes straight up and down
the right side of your chart 72 who
agrees with that
that's all do you agree with that no
what do you say but song okay Jessie
what do you say okay we have a consensus
formed 72 72 that's right
perfect there we go ladies and gentlemen
we found it
so to reiterate it's 72 degrees if we
take the same condition here and drop it
to 72 degrees that's correct if we took
any surface also that's below 72 degrees
into 95 degree air at 48 percent
relative humidity water is going to
condense on anything 72 degrees in below
right as the air hits that surface the
air gets closer and closer to the
temperature of the thing that is 72
degrees or less and that is where
moisture so at night where the
temperature drops
what happens most often when we find do
on our cars is that the radiative effect
of losing all the energy out into space
cools the surfaces on the ground
including your metallic surfaces under
car so they do on your car is because
the surface of the car got below the dew
point of the air
make sense okay
okay so
where did this chart come from right
like who's like okay we get a chart that
looks like this because this will be
easy to work with all right what are the
places you can start is not at air with
zero water in it
water is molecules and getting rid of
molecules is actually a challenge but
what we can do is make saturated air
very easily I can spray moisture into
the air and come up with a saturated
condition and almost any temperature I
spray water inside of a box and I slowly
heat the box up until it gets to
whatever temperature I want to measure
it at and then I can take a look at the
amount of water inside that box and say
okay this box at this temperature holds
this much moisture so they did this for
a number of different temperatures of
air and they came up with a humidity
ratio which said for every pound of air
that I got inside this box I end up with
nineteen point four grains per pound a
full saturated conditions at forty
degrees at fifty-five you don't notice
as the temperatures go up it's not a
five degree increase five degree or five
grains per pound increase it starts
there it doesn't end there
so what happens we take these points and
put them on a chart and that chart is
temperature in one direction and grains
per pound of moisture in the y-direction
they start here I say this is my
humidity ratio I have no moisture in the
air at this point I have 20 40 60 it's
just an arbitrary scale of grains per
pound of moisture on the left side and
then I say this is my temperature 25
1,200 degrees Fahrenheit in the
x-direction so I want these are 100%
saturated air conditions if I plot them
they look like this so what well this is
our 100% relative humidity curve they
start with this line because that's very
easy to generate those conditions
experimental right if you don't know
where you are if you don't know where
you are on the psychometric chart when
you go to do an experiment and set up a
chart like this you have to go in one
direction of the other you can take all
the water out you can put all the water
you know you can't get by constantly
misting the air that's what they did
here and that's how they discovered this
whatever percent humidity from there
it's pretty easy from there to take the
distance from here to here at any one
point from the curve to zero along this
line and I divide it into tenths and
this is where I get my relative humidity
curves so my relative humidity curves on
this chart if I go in it looks like
they're all very curved but if I go in a
straight line down there's an equal
distance between each temperature line
crossing the relative humidity curves
then follow so this is where we get the
term relative humidity fur it is a
fraction of the humidity of the air
relative to the total amount of air a
total amount of moisture of the air
controlled when I get to a hundred
percent conditions I know that I can no
longer hold any more water in the air it
is saturated okay so what does it have
to do with dry bulb light bulb dewpoint
relative humidity we can have the exact
same amount of moisture inside the air
at a number of different conditions what
changes when we go to map these points
well in this case the only absolute
measure of moisture in the air is the
dew point everything else will change as
we move along this line so at saturated
conditions let's say we're at 60 degrees
Fahrenheit right here we're at a 60
degree to point our wet bulb temperature
if you look at your chart is also 60
degrees I'm swinging around a wet sock
in the air hoping it'll cool off the
bulb through the evaporative cooling
effect but I have all the moisture in
the air that the air could handle
there's no water coming off the ball the
temperature of the air sensibly is the
temperature of the air from a latent or
moisture Laden perspective so 100%
saturation gives us the dry bulb
temperature the wet bulb temperature and
the dew point temperature
let's say I want to take a box of air at
these conditions and I'm not gonna add
any water to it
I'm gonna take the box it's already got
all the water it has it it's saturated
and I start to heat up the box okay and
I let it expand as I start to move away
I'm not adding water energy I'm adding
temperature energy many the heat of
sensible heat energy I'm gonna start
moving along this line I haven't added
any absolute more moisture into my
balloon so instead we keep the amount of
water in that volume constant we
increase the dry bulb temperature from
60 to 62 well now if I swung my wet bulb
thermometer in there it's going to be
some temperature less than less than 62
degrees right so 62 degrees is a dry
bulb I put it in the wet sock and now
I'm spinning it around instead of being
62 degrees it's gonna come down from 62
because some of that water can evaporate
off the sock the bulb gets cooler and
now we're at sixty point eight but the
dew point still 60 but where are we
other boats if humidity curve we're no
longer in saturation conditions we're at
92% relative okay
we're moving along the line we heat up
the air even more we hit 275 degrees
Fahrenheit dry bowl
75 degrees Fahrenheit dry ball equates
to sixty five point two on the wet-bulb
scale but we're still at 60 degrees on
the dew point the dew point hasn't
changed we have no more or less moisture
going into our volume of air all we've
done is heat it with sensible energy so
now the temperature goes up we go to 75
degrees the wet bulb has changed because
now if I slung the butt sock inside of
it it would cool a bulb off
significantly from 75 degrees a relative
humidity line where only 60% of the way
over this water that's sorry this is
this volume of air at this condition
could hold a lot more water now that
we've added temperature energy to them
and then finally our last point we get
to 90 degrees Fahrenheit the wet bulb is
70 and dew point 60 and run through a
relative humidity perspective really 37%
of the way of this theoretical line
until we hit the saturation if this line
continual go pretty far
quite quite so let's talk about what
happens when we had since we we started
a condition that saturation we're adding
sensible only heat which is temperature
only temperature based heat it has
nothing to do with moisture addition
into the space this is in a grow room
what happens when we turn the lights on
and there are no plants in the room no
people in the room it is a dry box with
hot electric toasters that make it light
this is sensible addition of heat these
relative humidity curves like I said
before they indicate as we go up in a
very exponential way how much water the
air could hold at saturation and any
place on here how much more water could
hold if we wanted to get the properties
of air such that this humidity ratio
here also could be referred to as the
dew point matches a dry bulb and matches
the relative humidity we can use any one
of these points to find a way around
this term earlier today we talked about
well I don't really have the conditions
for the room all I have is dry bulb and
wet bulb we have a number of different
ways to play on this chart to figure out
exactly which way we can go it's
actually exactly where we'll find
ourselves on the chart so people need to
understand that humidity ratios dew
points relative humidities wet bulbs and
dry bulb temperatures really need two
out of the seven or eight different ways
that we measure errors properties to
find our way onto the chart moving on
okay we've talked about travel we've
talked about with we've talked about
dewpoint absolute humidity numbers
relative
right wet bulbs dry bulbs dew points
also humidity ratio okay these are the
properties of air there's one more when
you talk about which is as you heat air
up it occupies more cubic feet per pound
so if I took air and I'm moving air
through a fan at a certain temperature
and then I cool that air down and I want
to move the exact same volume of air
through a fan I'm going to be moving
heavier air relatives respected to the
volume if I change the temperature in
one direction so keep that in mind the
other thing you'll find on these lines
are specific volume cubic feet of air
for every pound of air that you want to
move okay and this comes into play when
we start talking about the we start
talking about moving air around the fan
laws fan energy and actually we're
really talking about is how much
moisture we can fit into air at higher
than higher temperatures you'll notice
that as we move along this line here the
cubic feet increases that expansion
means there is more room in a pound of
there that needs to get taken up as the
molecules push each other apart all that
extra energy allows for more water to
get into that air and that's why the
holding capacity of the air is much
higher
which respect amongst you okay so all
has to do with it everything else I
don't think there's a many other lines
we want to look at except for some oil
cooling lines but let's talk about
adding energy and taking energy away we
talked about adding the sensible energy
right we're gonna go in the right
direction sensible energy is dry energy
temperature based energy is not moisture
energy so we call it sensible heat I'm
going to go from left to right when we
add it to a volume of there so the air
of this room if there were no people in
it there was no moisture emitting
sources
it would just be lights in the grow room
without plans for people okay if we want
to take that away we go the opposite
direction I'm gonna cool the air down in
a sensible only manner I'm not taking
any moisture away I don't go in this
direction I'll go in this direction I
don't change the humidity ratio I don't
change the to point I'm just changing
where I am with respect to trouble I can
add moisture dragged into a space now
this actually a lot harder than you
might think it is to go from the air in
this room temperature and humidity to a
level straight up on this chart towards
the intersection of the dry ball and the
dew point in the window actually quite
hard to do that because as I had voiced
her into the air what happens he gets
colder why
because
what happened we suspect what happens
was that a pretty grueling so does that
mean by adding moisture to the air okay
so that admission in the air so what
there's some physical property there
it's exactly right I mean there's no
really better answer than that a droplet
of air as it evaporates is absorbing
temperature sensible energy from the
space and those water molecules shed off
of that droplet until it is all water
molecules in the air we call it dry air
okay so that energy absorption releases
the water molecules and now although all
the molecules at a very homogeneous way
have the same amount of energy that
energy temperature wise is lower even
though the moisture content has gone up
but if I want to go from here to here I
can do a couple of things I can heat up
the water as I am shooting it into the
air these are what this is what steaming
minifiers do for the most part if they
did it perfectly they would add no more
heat than was required to take those
molecules and turn them water into vapor
we always end up with some amount of
some huge amount of humidification and a
small amount of temperature increase
when we talk about steam generating
human fires I'm talking about taking
kettle elements putting them in a box
heating up the water to boiling and
shooting that steam into a room and
that's the effector than have very
little temperature increase but a very
high humidity okay if I want to take
moisture away
well in general I have to go down in
this direction to go from here to here
in a straight line also not one of those
things that's really physically possible
there's no media on earth far as I know
and there's definitely none available
commercially for the work that we do in
greenhouses and
grow that we'll take a room at this
condition and just pull moisture
straight out of it without affecting the
temperature of the air as it's doing it
we may end up taking this air and
cooling it or putting it through a
desiccant or putting it through any
which way we can be may end up here at
the end of the day which is what we do
in a lot of our applications but there's
no way to go straight from there there
but the net effect is if I take a point
on this chart I apply some processes to
it from where I begin to where I end
these arrows are our cardinal directions
as to what that process ended up doing
if I start here and I end up here i
humidified even if I went this way in
this way or this way in this way this
doesn't matter if I start here and up
here I dehumidifier and I start here and
they end up here like we do in so many
of our roadmap occasions we have heated
and dehumidifier
but to get from here to here you'll find
out we went all the way here so you can
go in any which direction any
combination of directions following
these lines cooling and dehumidifying is
the one that typically most mechanically
air-conditioning systems to not
including distance systems so what
happens we remove sensible heat we see
that the temperature goes down well
let's say that we're cooling the air by
introducing it to a surface that's
colder than the dew point well we're
going to end up cooling the air in a way
that cools it below the temperature at
which condensation will form the
condensation forms on that surface that
we're cooling it with and then we end up
doing some sensible and then latent
cooling as well we're not going in this
direction what does that look like in an
actual space why do we need to do that
with an air conditioning system well
let's talk about a grow room we're gonna
take air from an air conditioning system
and put it into a grow the supplier
comes from an air conditioning unit it
falls into the room and spins around and
it's mixed inside the room that air is
going to pick up the sensible heat from
for example the lights the motors the
fans spinning inside the room to mix the
air around this is all dry sensible
energy introduction to that air but it's
also gonna pick up late again this is
not the same type of dry temperature
it's moisture that moisture comes from
the plants the plants are transpiring
constant
now there's an equilibrium you're going
to get if you want to make sure that the
room temperature stays the same and
we'll talk about how we get there later
but basically supplier in well pick up
sensible heat and latent heat and be
returned back to the air-conditioner so
we can do something to it all right so
if we can't match the amount of sensible
heat and latent heat added to the air as
it passes through a room we're going to
end up unable to control our room
conditions so we need to quote be able
to remove both sensible and latent heat
to ensure that we don't stray away from
that condition that's going to provide
the planet's maximum vitality so how do
we do that a couple ways to think about
it the way that we were taught was you
have a bucket I'm heating up that bucket
and I need to balance the water I'm
putting into that bucket to maintain a
certain temperature as I remove some of
that hot water as it all mixes inside
that bucket what is the fraction of cool
fresh water I need to bring in to keep
the temperature up a bucket exactly
where I wanted so I've got a bucket a
certain temperature I light a fire
underneath it it's getting too hot okay
I'm going to add some more cool water
I'm going to balance the flow of cool
water and the temperature of that water
so I can maintain the temperature of the
bucket at one okay
the way that engineers use to talk about
the balance of both sensible energy
removal and latent energy removal is
called the sensible heat ratio is by
picking apart the total amount of energy
we take out of the air in both forms and
saying what fraction of that is done on
the temperature side versus the latent
side so I put air into a room and it
goes up ten degrees Fahrenheit on my dry
bulb and it goes up fifteen grades per
pound on my sensible heat ratio I'm
going to put those numbers into a common
unit I'm gonna take that common unit add
it together and knowing what I know from
the temperature in to the room the
temperature leaving the room of that
error I'm gonna take that sensible heat
gain and divided by the total heat gain
going through that space now these
numbers here this since well he came and
the latent heat gain are dictated by
equations called the sensible and latent
heat equations we're not gonna go over
those right now the fact of the matter
is there is a way that we can take both
types of energy addition and make them
into the same common unit and in doing
so we can come up with a ratio of how
much of the energy we have to remove is
sensible and how much is latent so let's
talk about that you're going to look at
your chart and you're gonna notice that
there is this sensible heat ratio around
the outside around the outside
it is all referenced to an index point
that index point you'll find a little
dot in the middle here where's that dot
J see give me that temperature and the
wet ball with that dot the dry bulb and
wet ball temperatures of that dog
mmm-hmm where we looking and we looking
at the wet-bulb chart right here in the
green take this dot and follow the green
line all the way over to the web oh yeah
you know how we got there all right I
what's the relative humidity there Brian
it's 50/50
all right let me see make sure 1 2 3 4
50 Jesse's at 50 percent relative
humidity yes yeah Mike we got it
okay if I take a volume of air and do
something to it and they end up from
going from this point to some other
point here the angle between those two
points can be lined up with an angle
between our index point and a sensible
heat ratio that's why we have this chart
I don't need to know necessarily what
the ratio is going into the thing I can
look at a process and saying hey we
start here we end up here well what
percentage of the energy being added is
sensibly paced and what it is
lately based how much is sensible on how
much is labeled I can use this chart by
taking the two points and the angle
between them and then corresponding them
to group this index point and the angle
informs with this indices on the outside
and that will tell me how much sensible
energy is added or taken away
how much late energies
the sequester they weren't interesting
things here okay if I have if I have all
right so
if I have some amount of temperature
being taken away that is a hundred
percent sensible and certainly what is
my sensible heat ratio okay so I'm gonna
start at this point right here and I'm
going to go in a sensible driving to
take away a sensible energy I'm gonna go
directly in the leftward direction okay
what angle am i making with innocence
that's why
and then I correlate that to my sensible
heat ratio number here it's a 1
okay
you're gonna hear the sensible heat
ratio term get thrown around a lot and
it's not certainly used every single day
it's almost like a inside some
relic but it's it's definitely not terms
that we use in the HVAC industry every
day and you're more prone to hear vapor
pressure deficit which is a much more
complex eternal than the sensible heat
ratio but if you really want to know
what your air conditioners are doing you
could take a temperature and humidity
sensor at two points and go oh this is
how much sensible energy is being taken
out versus how much water energy is
being taken the steeper I go the smaller
the number it gets okay so if I start
here and I go here at the end of my
process I've got a very small sensible
heat ratio why is that well it turns out
that going in this direction from here
down it corresponds to 0.15 or point -
well the sensible heat ratio that means
of the energy that's been removed going
in this direction a small fraction of it
15% or 20% of it is temperature or the
rest is humidity 80% is humidity right
it is very hard and the numbers getting
very small very quick it is very hard it
takes a lot of energy to take water over
there that's gonna take so by sensible
heat ratio so quickly anytime you get
below 0.8 or 0.75 in this direction
you've basically moved outside of
comfort cooling and the world that we
live in in commercial air conditioning
okay
now we start getting into greenhouse and
all right steep curves so we're looking
for we're gonna take a lot of water away
and mostly not a lot of temperature
absolutely
so we're gonna talk about how to get
there you can you can follow this one
there's an interesting thing about this
I know if I if I also happen to
calculate this many lights in the room
and this one's water coming up I can
also determine how much my sensible heat
ratio has to be for me to adequately
keep this face at the right temperature
basically I know the ratio I can take
the point of trying to maintain and draw
a line and this rate away from it as I'm
taking energy away from this point and
as I do it the further I get the less of
the air I need to process in the room to
maintain this condition okay I could
take all the air in this room and I want
to make it I wanna keep it 70 degrees
whatever it is it here and 50 percent
relative humidity if I blast air through
this room like a tornado and I take away
just a little bit of energy with each
passing second I'm just gonna change the
temperature and the humidity of the air
a small fraction before I reintroduce it
back in I don't need I don't need to
make much temperature humidity change to
the space if all I did was put a tiny
tube and suck a little bit of air out
condition it and then send it back in
well I would need to make that air very
cold and very dry to get rid of all the
heat and the humidity that's being
generated in this space something about
what the implications are for our
greenhouses plants love
consistent temperatures if I take small
tubes of highly conditioned air and drop
very cool air into the room at different
spots before the air gets a chance to
mix there will be a microclimate created
everywhere I dropped that cold air in
and just like whoever is complaining at
the reception desk because it's so cold
and why can't we adjust the thermostat
right if I create that drop of air cold
air dropping over the plant that plant
is gonna suffer what I'd rather do
instead is keep the air coming in as
close to the room temperature as
possible and this is the reason in
commercial air conditioning we do four
three five air changes per hour which is
how many times I take the air in the
room and pass it through an air
conditioning system in an hour in Ag so
we do this kind of cooling and delivery
of hair in commercial comfort air
conditioning systems we do this
we're going to move 20 to 30 times the
air 20 or 30 times in an hour we're
gonna change it out and replace it with
conditioned air now I save a place it's
just the same air being cycled back
we're taking co2 late in the air rather
bringing outside air replace it it's the
same and we're gonna take it out and
condition it and send it back in and the
conditions and we send it back in at
have better be close to the room
condition so that we don't cause those
micro climates wherever we're dropping
the air back in space okay done totally
makes sense anyways it's you know it's
constant cavities like maybe think about
for a while but I could either send in
very cold air and a small amount of it
in different spots or I can move a lot
of air and not send it back in at a
temperature that is so far from where it
started there's a number of reasons for
that and they have to do with compressor
dynamics and the heat of you know the
heat of compressive compression of
refrigerant gases and where you go with
that all that excess energy that's one
of those reasons that yet definitely you
don't want the pockets of hot air
sitting around the greenhouse or inside
your bank space there's so many more
reasons than that
hot air comes out of the diamond a fire
it floats
that hot air that's been cooled so
that's been heated and dehumidified is
hot and it's staying up there unless you
have another fan to blow it down so now
instead of how you can just my team in a
fire are gonna do you in a fire I've got
a fan a fan has to blow it down has to
do it a distributed way that's where if
you hit it hit that hot air straight
down yeah you're going to have a problem
where one plant is probably in an ideal
addition and rape aside the other plates
gone right that plate is very highly
stressed and is prone to pathogen
okay temperature although there are
types of humidity densities of air
changing as we go hot and cold we're
talking about how we how we process air
now okay how we change temperatures
cooling heating humidification
dehumidification okay if I was at any
other starting point and I knew my
sensible and latent balance I could go
to my new starting point using the ratio
line that I drew the 60% the point six
sensible Eurasian translated and know
that I had to deliver air somewhere
along this line here to counteract the
energy balance in my room this is a
well-engineered room I know exactly what
the lights are doing where the moisture
is coming from everything else I can use
this line to tell me boy I need to
liberate our here and a little bit of it
I need to deliver air here and a lot
here's the tricky part I don't cool air
in straight lines and follow the
sensible community ratio instead I cool
air by going through four inch to 12
inch cooling coils the cooling coil is a
big metal box with fins and I'm passing
through those fins a coil of chilled
water or boiling refrigerator that makes
the fins very cold my air comes through
as it's coming through let's say I was
at this point as I put air through a
cooling coil the radiator on your car
except with cold stuff as the air passes
through the cooling coil we start to
drop temperature very quickly well we
don't drop humidity that air hasn't
gotten to the saturation we haven't gone
to that wet bulb temperature as I get to
the wet bulb temperature the moisture
starts to fall out as I approach it and
how does it starts to fall out and get
colder and now now my sensible heat
ratios been there but I want an air on
this line and I wanted in this air here
but I have to go all the way here to get
it and then heat it back up sense of me
so I determined that I need this point
of error and this amount of air changes
through a room I can't get from here to
here directly I have to cool the air
first and then heat it back up my
friends this is brute-force
dehumidification we say brute force
dehumidification
I am using a source of cold which is
very hard to generate and I'm gonna cool
my air well past the temperature I need
it right Aladin and you only be there
right here under need air at 65 16
degrees but I needed that a humidity
ratio of 60 well to get from here which
is 70 down to here which is 16 degrees
Fahrenheit and 16 grains per pound I
have to go all the way down cool that
air down to 52 degrees and then reheat
it all the way back up to 60 this is
illegal if we're using new forms of
energy to do that reading so in the
industry what we do is we use a
compressor to compress refrigerants the
heat of that compression is used to
drive the reheating effect we needed the
compressors to run anyways because we
had to get them to expand refrigerant
gases to make the cold surface on the
coil to dehumidified in the first place
we're not really wasting all that much
energy but we are using a lot of energy
going from this point to this point
because my compressor is responsible for
going all the way down here making the
air all the way this cold and then
reheating Abeka the reheating is free as
far as we're concerned we were gonna run
the compressors anyways to dry them it's
not like we're adding toasters in the
Airstream or electric resistance heaters
we're not adding natural gas burgers
we're just using the compressor energy
we were going to send to the environment
anyways cool the reheat is free but the
cooling is not
and not only that the designer
refrigerant systems means that I can
basically only reheat to about 10
degrees below what my starting condition
was traditional reheat systems just
don't make the air any harder but there
are conditions will talk about in later
parts of this video series that will
show you we need to go not just to 68
degrees not to 75 we have to get to 85
maybe even 90 degrees if you want to
keep the room at the same temperature
the same VPD the same everything that
we're trying to maintain so the plants
have a consistent environment