i'm steve campbell with greenlight
productions um we're here to walk around
liberty talk shop
retro facility here in pahrump nevada
and it's amazing we haven't even really
cracked the the real secrets or that
yeah so uh well actually maybe we have
because we're
starting to talk about the compost and
what makes the the plants grow so yeah
so we're
about to step into that area are you
guys good over here this is the
greenhouse project future greenhouse
project by the startup again
well um i can see it because we've been
talking
but we're talking next year three years
out
so we've actually been planning this for
about two years um
we really were gonna hit hard early this
year but then the covet thing hit
so we pumped the brakes um now that that
hype is kind of settling down
we're confident to start this project
back up again
uh so we're hoping to start getting
things ordered here the next several
weeks
oh excellent yeah hopefully yeah it
looks like you guys already
prepared the slab so it's just pouring
steel structure
like the rest so that goes up quick yeah
it's it'll be really relatively quick i
think about six months time period from
start to finish
uh so by next summer we should be um if
everything goes right we should be
having our first sun ground crop by late
next summer
perfect timing it'd be nice
uh this uh all right so this is
basically this is the the
we're currently operating again it's
about 12 thousand square foot
uh indoor space and then over here to
the right this is just our storage space
this is where we just kind of store all
of our amendments
um i have a little pad over here where
we do most of our compost not most we do
all our composting
is your compost over here can we take a
look i don't have any compost right now
because we just got through
well i have some indoors but we're not
composting right now because the summer
time the summer heat
so talk a little bit about your compost
what you were talking about the timing
of it when you do do it and what your
process
is so over here it looks like you have
some of your feedstock uh
probably some biochar some alfalfa looks
like some straw
yep i'm not sure what's in the other um
so that's a couple totes that peat moss
left over from when we did that big soil
mix and then we have a couple totes or a
couple of soil bags of a pumice
from that same soil mix but then you're
right we have uh both alfalfa and straw
uh and then uh yeah just trying to store
distorted various amendments dry and
you're right biochar is a great black
one great
space like honestly you've got to have
space because when you need it
that's that bulk 100 yeah yeah
uh i mean it's a little messed up here
now i got to clean up a little bit we've
got a
looks like trim which is being dried so
you can add to the compost as well so
yeah so this is our
official composting area this is where
we start we store all our dry amendments
um so any of our cannabis leaf stem
uh we actually get a little bit of
manure we store dry
oak um for for our brown um
and then we basically store it all here
and then you see some of our pallets
with meshes
um some of our compost fences uh our
cages and then uh yeah
do you it looks like uh these are
movable you got a forklift
do you utilize that in the composting
process the turning or is it just in
finish no we don't really use a forklift
form to be honest we just use that to
get them off the ground so we just build
our little pallets
yeah for the bottom yeah uh
but yeah this is our leaf system at
least we've been storing and drying all
summer
um again we're about to fire up the
composting process so about to burn
through all these
and this uh how much are we looking at
this this is the product i mean this is
not much is it or and what are we
looking at um this is the the water leaf
uh i couldn't tell you
uh you got a little swarovski pack yeah
uh yeah i couldn't tell you but we had
the paperwork that i pointed to though
so you have to are you gonna put it in
the compost you don't have to destroy it
you have to
so this is just drying out this is about
to get all scooped up and put in a bag
like this
and if you look at this this is
so we store everything dry just like
elaine it teaches in her classes
um so now this is just like the leaves
and the fall right you collect them you
have them stored dried
they're prepped and waiting to be then
utilized in your compost when you're
ready to build it
pretty much and then here yeah again
usually this corner back here would be
filled with oak or some type of brown
material
inside those trash bags just unused
cannabis stem
a lot of this stuff gets chopped and
dropped on our beds but our beds can
only take so much at once
without smothering them so that's why we
have to take some of this stuff out here
and dry it out here and incorporate it
in the composting process
um but overall this is where this is
probably one of my funner places of the
whole facility
especially this time of year when it's
starting to cool off we can actually get
going out here
with composting you'll see me out here
quite a bit so when you are flipping
your
your pillars is it more of a uh
aggro style or is it more
like here you go floppy over my
my first couple piles i was more
crossfit in my
in my methods uh it definitely went a
little hardcore
uh hurt my shoulder at one point yeah i
blew out my freaking rotator cuff yeah
you have your uh your bandages off yeah
and i'm gonna air out today
yeah yeah that hair out um but now i i
i actually have a style of flipping it
now inside out top to bottom
that really turns it nice you got to
take her too it's a flow
yeah um i noticed too that there's a
down pressure like when you're going in
so it doesn't just fall apart yeah like
you come in and you push
down not just lift yeah and so
because you're really just trying to
you're not making a mess
you know you're literally just creating
oxygen and aeration
and i'm real big on getting that outside
in the inside out
you know so i'm always trying to
separate the pile when i re-flip it
but yeah smart you got to work it all in
working
dude this looks great and uh excellent
work area looks like some river rock and
this is probably for the new beds coming
in so you boil this access river rock
in all my beds inside i have uh we throw
various piles of rock
in in the corners or the middle of the
beds just to create like a rock mulch
environment
um the the the consistency the moisture
consistency under the rock stays the
same
it doesn't dry out as fast it doesn't
get as wet um so you tend to see more
worms and just more biology right into
the rocks but
they're diverse ecosystems within within
an isolated island yeah have their
little rock mole show yeah it just gives
a different environment for things
and because it's not organic it doesn't
actually contribute to
like pill bugs or you know something
like that yeah
so which we have which i love i don't
think that it lasts for years
they're here well you just got to feed
them enough yeah you know or or they'll
start eating other things yeah yeah
so excellent man well thank you so much
for sharing outside let's go inside
you got it
so you guys are going to have to uh you
guys got your ids yep
now we will figure out the whole process
yeah
so what's your uh process um you guys
gonna put booties on
and then i'm gonna go in here and hang
out for me and i'll get you guys some
scrubs and i'll get you guys all
scrubbed up
so i can feel the air coming out this is
part of
your hvac but we were talking about you
you don't actually use much
like you're very efficient system uh
you'll see
how how use this is its own unit in here
everything has controlled air no we
don't share air in any of our rooms
so yeah this is just the office space so
the big thing here is just make sure you
have
clean filters obviously high grade
filters
and then purification so have to some
type of ubc light in your duct work
make sure that you're cleaning the air
all right so this
this is the uh basically the kind of the
beginning of a tour i guess this is our
open locker room
um so we kind of did like an open locker
room to try to avoid theft and
and uh things like that so open locker
room with clear lockers really
makes that kind of hard to no pushback
by anybody
no that was just dressing room so open
locker room was with private dressing
rooms was it
was the idea here employee break room
down there some offices from
for my wife um nothing too fancy then we
got our security booth right here
uh he has access
food very nice break room by the way and
you have pastries there
for your saturday crew which is like
really so nice
so it's usually they take care of some
will bring them and take care of each
other
uh but in a security booth here he's all
behind ballistic glass
um ballistic walls access to all the
cameras uh
requirements he's all he's all legit um
over here is our sally port we're just
pretty much just saw our materials
nothing really to see there um
i know uh this is our trim room uh we'll
we'll go to the sink right here and
we'll wash up
hey everybody what's up guys
hi good morning
i'm just wash up right here
so talk to you about your trimming
everything's hand trimmed yeah all hand
trimmed um in a nice
environmentally controlled room so we're
not
we're not deteriorating our product as
we're trying to clean it up so
are they like do you have trim days are
they busy is it like every day
no we typically run five days a week um
then if we're backed up we'll have a
an excess of strain or something like
that we'll offer overtime on the
weekends
i think it looks like we had a crew take
us up on the offer this weekend so we
got the whole crew showed up
or at least a lot of them um
yes this is it sounds like a real quick
turnover from your processing
um from pulling down the flour to in the
jar
not not pulling down the flour but out
of cure
like how long before it's on this shelf
um typically for us
uh i would say roughly four weeks four
or five weeks
so it really it's a 14 day drive period
uh then we trim it up
takes about a week to trim it up before
it gets tested then a week for testing
uh so that puts us in about four weeks
before we can package it and then on the
fifth week it's packaged and sold
uh yeah so and depending on strains some
trains you hold back on
i mean they need more time some training
to try to put out in a hurry because you
know those chirps don't last as long
so fruity stuff goes out first it's kind
of the rule of thumb
fruity goes first there you go
yeah that that sweet tone is lost and
then it gets that tartness yeah which i
kind of like sometimes and spicy they
taste a little spicy sometimes too
so so one thing we had to recently do is
we actually expanded our trim room um
where you see that wall cut out that was
actually a wall at one point
uh and then and then we have another
four thousand square foot beyond that
wall that we're gonna expand into for
more dry space
um with our future greenhouse and our
future uh flower room indoor flower
rooms
but for now we just did this little pop
out um what happened was
we changed our lights out got some new
leds some new focus leds and we had
almost
a 50 to 100 increase on some strains so
basically we had to build a whole new
dry room and hold more trim space
just to be able to handle the extra
weight so now weight
in bud set or weight in like biomass
growth
overall bud set and and just overall
pre-roll
all every every part of the plants
volume when that both are pre-raw
material our durable material
so yeah we had we had uh like i said a
100 increase on some trains um
minimum 50 increase across the board uh
but anyway so yeah we did that and we
have our little trial hash station over
there that we're building out right now
just got all our final little
tools in tell us about the next
adventure yeah you guys can go check it
out
take it by real quick guys hey jason my
name is real quick
sorry
so this is uh this is just a temporary
little area this isn't a hash
lab that we're content with but you're
gonna transition
or at least use some of your your
produce right
and turn it into hash so the idea is
right now we don't have a very big
volume to work with for to launch a hash
line
but what we're going to use the little
bit of volume we do have with is to do
the r
d in preparation for our greenhouse
project and the rest of our indoor so
when that time does come
now we have some experience we know how
to make it the most efficient
the best hash we can with what we had to
work with
and scale up from there perfect so
that's what this is we went with the
bruteless
washing vessels we got the the
sasquatch ross and press with the
harvest right freeze dryer
so we got all the cool tools got some
big freezers in the sally port um so we
should be able to make some
some nice stuff here here we got another
dry room check this out
that looks new yeah this is none of this
has been used yet this is all
just installed fresh fresh
toys pretty much this oh you got it
so do you do your like the pre-rolls in
here you have a pre-roll day and then
everything that type of stuff is done
yeah right now we just have a handful of
people trimming
um but usually usually during the week
we have a full staff out here we have
trimmers pre-rollers
packagers uh we'll have 20-plus people
in here so this is like your
production room for that yeah this this
was just a weekend crew who wanted it
who wanted the overtime kind of thing
uh you know so uh typically there's a
lot more people in here though usually
there's
a there's an ask in every seat uh this
is our new dry room that we just built
out we've yet to use it
um but to give you guys an idea what
we've got going on
okay yeah
so completely all controlled through our
iponics
um we have uh intake we've got
our fans not on there but we have an
intake fan exhaust fan
through us through a carbon filter ozone
generator
when needed carbon filters in here to
filter out any contaminants um
ac unit humidifier dehumidifier
um so we can keep all those parameters
that we're aiming at
the green lights green lights help help
keep down the uh
the degradation of the plant so that way
when we put the plant in here it's it
stays sleek enough to not
degrade yeah uh 14 days
that's our desired time and this will
clear out
is this for each bay like like a cycle
so basically um there's two dry rooms
per bay
um so i'll fill this is each one of
these i have two dry rooms they each
represent a week
so i fill one one week i feel one the
next week and then the third week this
one's empty again
and this room looks like it's super easy
to
reset to to sterilize and break down is
a huge part of the design
um the only real issue that we had that
i didn't like was where the car the
placement of this fan filter is
but the reason we had to do that the
reason it's upside down like that is
because
the other side of this wall is the ac
unit so we had to work around it
so that that's the only pain in the butt
in this room that's going to be able to
clean it and change
that filter up there uh but other than
that uh it's meant to just be able to be
sprayed down and washed down easily
oh you gotta agree degrees are cool
agreed
so um so does the whole place close down
by
by five is that like typically we run
five days a week i try to we try to run
this place like a regular business give
people their lives we were talking about
the light cycle
that that was yeah yeah because of the
light bulb okay but that was just
the yeah that's just the driving room so
our flowering rooms are typically
our lights are off to five that's why
you guys are limited yesterday
uh actually one of my rooms is off at
four um it's a little further in the
cycle so we
knock another hour off
oh this is this is just a light eagle 20
avid mix just to make sure we kill
anything that you guys could be bringing
in
uh just to be safe you know safety
tasted first
it's just a dr bronner's and essential
oil from build a soil so it says
pretty much in a smell lemongrass and
i'm mainly spraying
i'm just spraying your legs just in case
you walked in with anything
uh because you guys usually have same
shoes on
um let's just do a quick rinse right
here or
we're supposed to wash our hands again
so i'd use the alcohol
so for your sops it's
enter every room wash your hands usually
we'll skip the vent
the the trim room so my growers will
skip that and just come right to here
but we walked the trim room so we had to
wash there and wash here so examination
vector yeah this is listen i really
appreciate this this is actually amazing
so tell me about the little ones oh yeah
welcome to our bedroom
uh so yeah these are just planted a
couple days ago out the clone dome so
they're just kind of working through
their stress of
of getting into their new environment
uh this is just one round this is
actually in preparation for one of our
we have a slightly smaller room out of
our three rotation rooms
so this is for one of our smaller rooms
so let's talk about what's in the in the
pot
these are a transition from clone are
you you're not growing out
would you like to no okay you're not
growing out of rockwool
are you no um we do unfortunately
currently use that's one of the only
limiting factors that
are not limiting factors but then one of
the variables we have is that we're
using um
uh riot router type plugs
so we were using which is a peat moss
base with some type of adhesive
um so it still breaks down in the system
not very fast and it's not something i
want to use but
they it implies a lot quicker yeah i
actually have some that i'm testing like
literally just
put into worm bins where there's so much
life it's crazy
and they're still there the best thing
i've seen to break them down
is the bird's nest mushrooms so if you
ever see birds nest mushrooms collect
those little seeds
and put those in your beds they love
riot rooters dude see how
beautiful thank you all right so we have
those
put into a living soil or uh so what
these are is basically
when we when we plant our beds the
little bit of soil that we take out of
our beds to make room for these
we take back and then those go back into
the pots so and we just rotate our holes
every cycle so
we never dig we never pull the root ball
we plant right we dig right next to it
and then we let the root ball break down
then the next cycle that's what we take
um but yeah so these plug then is used
to
foster the growth and then it allows you
that transition back into
so this is the same soil that's in our
bed so this is 20 second cycle living
soil
um this is off the top of the soil so
this is a high concentration of
of uh worm castings in this in this mix
here which is nice at this
because these are still shocked they
they that helps with the shock stress
are you seeing the shock stress
right this is about it right now you
again they're planted
three days ago so this is we're
literally in the heat of the stress
right now
uh so in about three days they should
start coming back to normal and start
showing some growth
um right now they're just adjusting to
their new environment um and like you
said
that's totally i'm talking about when it
transitions to the beds oh
because this ecosystem is so similar to
what they're going into because it's
just been removed for a short time yeah
are you seeing the heat the transition
stress is there um and you'll always see
some because you're
cutting off the root hair yeah there's
there's there's other variables that
we've we've ran across
um like recently we changed our lights
up so we planted into rooms
with that new variable that we had to
adjust to like oh too much light too
little light because it's a whole new
system
um so we've had to adapt that fine
we're refined tuning now after after uh
five plus years we just
changed the biggest uh input the whole
facility the lights
so now we have to kind of re-figure
things out again and kind of refine tune
but for the most part yeah we love in
every part of it
uh and these beds here uh from my
understanding this is part of what
you're using for your cloning process
yes sir all right so tell us tell us
what's happening so yeah so we try to
we try to not or try to grow as much of
the inputs that we use as possible
so aloe is one of the things that we use
the most um
as you guys know as high in salicylic
acid um good sapping
so it's uh it's just a good thing to
both feed the
the plant get yeah you're fine yeah and
it's good for foliar feed it's good for
the cloning process
uh so it's just a good plant to have
around super easy to grow so
the fact that it's good for the people
too yes it's good yeah uh honestly as
it should be in everybody's garden if
someone was fair skin to get sunburned i
definitely had my fair share of aloe
rubbed on me
uh so what is happening with these beds
are plants going in here so this is a
mother bed that we just cleared out
we're about to plant another cycle of
basically this is kind of our our worm
bin really
all of our excess organic material that
our beds can't take that we don't feel
like taking outside
um kind of gets thrown right here and
the worms just devour it
so this is kind of our it's really our
mother bed slash worm bin
right um it's hard to describe sometimes
and and this because it's an ecosystem
like this is a perpetuation of the
nourishment that is
like if you needed something well where
do you go get it
right here right and so in my garden the
whole garden
ecosystem like you literally go into the
trail
and pull up your material for your
potting plank
right so and that's what this allows you
to do too what this did one thing i've
been doing with this motherbed that's
been i haven't really talked much about
online yet
but i've been seeing really good results
with is when i'm done with the mom
i'm pulling that root and i'm putting in
a tea brew
immediately and i i'm getting much
shorter brew times because i'm working
with active microbes now it's an
extraction
yeah they're not dormant so the whole
rhizosphere boom
boom right there so i'm not wasting
these moms at all now
um so i've been doing that for the last
i would say almost this last year really
and i've been really enjoying that
because i'm really getting i'm getting
something out of this bed now as well it
also allows you to really
i do that as well and that allows me to
see the
the root growth like especially in a
no-till situation i
never dig up the whole root system to
see what it looks like
but if i can shift that out and go
this is what i'm really working with
underground it's really kind of a cool
perspective yeah it can open your eyes
to you to some of those
the problems problems or successes yeah
good point like where's your root depth
going
yep this is something cool i saw him
look at this is something beautiful
this this is from home this is a it's an
african boa bab tree this is the
madagascar trees that's the
the tree of life uh some of the oldest
trees on the planet um i had one but
dude it's a tropical tree and it gets
cold out here so i didn't want to plant
it outside
so i bonsaied it um several months ago
and brought it to geo to hear the glp
and it's blowing up it grows like a half
an inch a day
uh i actually broke a branch off at one
time and had a mirror trip back i i
wrapped it up with some aloe
um re-healed it what does it mean when
you bonsai um basically you
you can you cut the root and you stunt
its growth you stifle its growth
so why is it still growing because you
didn't kill it because i didn't kill it
and
it's that gop and it's getting the best
compost teas and the best extracts
because it's grown with this life
does that mean it just doesn't get as
big as it would yeah
you're holding it back um once a year
what i'll end up doing is
there's wires that are actually holding
it down to that pot
um once a year i'll cut those wires i'm
going to um
pot it cut the roots and then repot it
in the same pot is that how they get the
bonsais to bend with those wires that's
just manipulation over time
the the real bonsai is what how you deal
with the roots
most people only think of how the little
tree is shaped but the real shaping goes
as above as below uh so you got you got
up down below
it's just like you would the top um and
the bonsai is actually more important
is the root zone so anyway so this is my
mom man it's about to get freshly
planted again
with a new run of moms so let's talk
about what we're seeing a different kind
of aloe smaller
um but what else is happening lifewise
in the bed
and by lifewise we'll talk about the
microbes and the worms and stuff but
also
the green you know the other than
cannabis life uh so
we use various companion plants um
they're getting they're breaking it down
uh
but for the most part um the the most
two that we use
um we use them for ground cover purposes
is just dichondra
uh and then uh chickweed i'm a personal
fan of chickweed it actually helps with
the peel bugs
uh i feel like uh our beds that have
high concentration of chickweed
um have the lowest population of peel
bugs so this right here is a dichondra
it's just
it sure is a really good ground cover we
don't have to reseed it it grows back
all on its own
i've never seen it go to flower
unfortunately but it's a super low
maintenance all you got to do in the
beds if it gets out of hand
it's just got to chop and drop it um
before it gets too bad
the the the mealy the peel bugs
and it doesn't have such an aggressive
root like a mint
like that you know that penetrates and
spreads how's the root system on this
if you over seed it it's a nightmare um
and that's the big thing people have
problem with with dicondra is they'll
either overseed it or under manage it
uh and or both they'll oversee it and
under manage it and then they'll just
have this jungle mess of
a of a cover companion plant growing um
but so if you don't overseed it and you
and you maintain it and you keep it down
um you're it's fine it's 100 manageable
um
and you know again you don't have to
waste energy and time reseeding it
uh it's just not pop back up on its own
i like this over clover
we started the facility off the clover
um clover had this place in some places
sub-alpine or not white dutch or
more crimson clover um than anything uh
and then uh it was a mix of some other
things red clover crimson clover
large yeah they again you gotta maintain
them um but the problem with the clover
is those high-end
uh plants those those legumes is that
they attract past
a lot of uh pests so a lot of thrifts
uh aphids uh anything you can imagine
that like high-end
uh they're just they're just a breeding
ground for them so it kind of became a
problem after the years of just kind of
having to re-deal with that um i mean
there's also plus side certain things
like the clover more than the cannabis
so having the clover
would keep things off your cannabis as
well so i mean there's really some pros
and cons and ways to look at it but
we got rid of the clover your variables
is where you go this one works for us
super low maintenance it does its
purpose
it's adding exudates into the soil
structure i don't need nitrogen is an
easy
building block to replace i can always
top dress with some alfalfa
so so it's not something i need to grow
in the beds if it's causing that much of
a problem like what like the alpha like
a clover does
so that conju what's that how old is it
this bed um this this big we didn't
start with this bed so this bed's a
little newer but it's old potting soil
dumped in um
i want to say this one's like two or
three years old i would say yeah
uh but yeah so chickweed and dichondra
are the most um
popular ones we use but we have other
companion plants we use different i use
a lot of trap planting
so i'll plant specific plants just to
attract a pest i use clover for a trap
plant actually
um and then another thing i do is uh we
plant a lot of
banker plants like pepper plants um so a
lot of sweet sweet peppers purple
sweet purple flash peppers um things
like that you'll see in various
throughout the rooms so what about your
choice of uh container
is uh was that uh what is this the
grassroots
yeah yeah so i love the guys over at
grassroots we started off before i think
they were actually open though so in my
rooms we actually have old geo planters
um the older style fabric beds but what
do you like about the fabric
um this is more breathable they're just
they're really good easy affordable
setup
nowadays they make the no-till one which
i kind of help inspire
uh with the the less penetratable sides
so you can actually sink the water
i played a really big role in the
development of that um
so even though you don't see it here
what you're gonna see here is
old beds wrapped with saran wrap that
basically uh ushered out fired the next
next generation but no what i like about
grassroots is they're they're an awesome
team
their product speaks for itself um they
beefed up their piping um so you don't
have this
flimsy weak piping and fittings are
breaking uh they went with the tan so
it's not attracting heat
uh especially when you're in the outdoor
environment and you'll be able to
maintain this environment
in this bed for as long as you want as
well
we're testing that theory out right now
seeing how far we can push it right
22 cycles um deep and uh and going
strong
we were thinking about that we thought
that would be like 40 years or something
but it not but it's
yeah five minutes and change um so so i
basically get four and some change at
four and a third cycles a year
uh at each room i have three rooms so i
get roughly 13
13 um harvests a year
when when some people hear that they say
oh
he's almost burned out of his newts he's
gonna have to flip
you know it's a five year cycle or soil
you're saying this is how far we've run
but we're continuing to run we're going
for
yeah i know my news is quite the
opposite man honestly the only problem i
have right now at my soil is that it's
too rich
uh so now i can't top-dress anything
just maybe a little bit of alfalfa for
the
to make up for the for the nitrogen
there's a weird bounce where the
beautiful worm activity in nature that
would be separated and moved around and
you know but in a bed
it gets really concentrated super rich
and it's hard to like
bump the carbon up without it being a
sink at that point
yeah it's tough it's tricky you're right
uh
but anyways so yeah this is veg this is
kind of where you get everything big
before loading into the rooms
uh you see some of our extra clones that
we didn't plant yet just backups
that's our other little cloning area
right here they're getting burped out
right now
um uh let's go and check out your
t-brewer
and uh this looks like how you move it
around and then disperse
this is kind of a mess right now we
don't have to see it
liquid is the difficult thing to move
and so
have an efficient yeah and yet still not
killing the organisms because the liquid
is really the transport medium
right yeah and so well then you use a
pump that kills everything what the heck
have you been doing you know it makes no
sense
we have diaphragm pumps so it's exactly
perfect it
kills less we test the t both in the
brew
and out of the hose to see the
difference um you see a little bit
different you might not see as big as
strands of fungi but they're still there
they might get beat up a little bit but
they're still there um
this is exactly just two little t-birds
compost tea brewer
yeah that's why i turned it but the
important part that he shared was
actually the diaphragm pump
instead of it being a propeller impeller
that's spinning and chopping and
forcing it's just
doing this motion and so you you're not
shredding
the life yeah that you're just blending
it you're not putting it through a
blender
yeah these are some of our so one cool
thing is uh we designed this facility uh
i was real big into permaculture and
capturing and storing energy and whatnot
um so we actually designed the whole
every single room
this pipe right here that recycle water
that's the feed line off of all of our
dehumidifiers from each room
and then it goes into a catch tank and
then from that catch tank we put it
through a uv
light and through heavy sediment
filtration no no ro we're not wasting
so it goes into the tank and in the
process it gets ultraviolet
then then from that tank it gets pumped
out of that tank through an ultraviolet
and heavy heavy sediment filters carbon
filtration
and then it gets put to our storage
tanks that feeds the rooms
um so we're basically catching at this
point i would say up to like 67 of our
water
the only water that we're losing is
through our ac units which we're going
to eventually catch as well
uh and and do the same thing so if you
ever tested before you ultraviolet it
no you ever have uh it could be fun to
look at though because you're actually
pulling right
the moisture the micro literally stuff
in the air
i'd be curious to see where it's more
it's not it's more it's not or is it off
the machine
it's not so much the air chemicals or
the air um pulling that we're worried
about in the water which we are
but also the the shit that's in the
pipes algae and all that stuff growing
in the pipes
um that we also want to kill water
to see what that looks like too because
that's where a lot of people end up with
a cerium issue or
so this uh these are light controllers
pretty sweet
compost um this room was just planted so
plants are a little small a little
stressed out don't freak out
it's crazy to be going into an led room
and not have it be purple either way
not be purple oh yeah yeah this place
was purple for a long time like
for for reals like so this it was just
planted uh
make them look green but they already
looked green it was planted last
last week so we're about seven no
actually eight days into planting in
this room
so they just got through their stress
they're actually just starting to grow
yeah keep going
i mean we're still cleaning this room
still breaking it down so fast i just
want to look out because we're talking
about where the rock placements and how
these ecosystems are set up
yeah or if we can do that in another
investment too oh you're doing this for
fine i mean
you're in that room i'm not sure uh yes
but this room was just planted this is a
20 second cycle
how many plants in there it depends on
strain
so light barrier on the exterior of the
door
yeah we still we still seal them but
this is just fool proof
that way if one of these pops off or
something happens we don't we don't see
the whole fucking room
what's happening all right guys uh
welcome to our 30 our
second cycle sorry
so this is a this is a part of your 22nd
site yep first this is our first room
our 22nd cycle
they're looking great man uh this whole
row right here is all black
triangle um in the middle there's some
potted plants just from thailand
uh to our right we have some grape pie
number five
um this isn't our this isn't the winning
phenotype this is actually the thino
that i breed with
it's super grapey um so i use it because
it's the grape that i want the breeding
project the other female we have is
higher testing
still grapey not nearly as grapey as
this now when you're talking grapey are
we talking like a
grape bubble gum grapey are we talking
great candy
yeah like i showed up grape candy um
delicious
absolutely the the smell and the flavor
um bait
are translates very well
overall though this one is my favorite
finger to smoke just for flavor that's
why i'm using the breeding
um but the other one is gonna sell
better because it has a higher testing
in this market
tell them how better this one is this is
part of shifting that
conversation because we smoked some
great flour last night
but i'm but it's about what you're
growing
you know and when you say this one holds
a note
that it cuts through that has value
well until and where the thing is too
though is that
the people don't value terpenes as much
as cannabinoids yet even though this one
has a higher chirping profile on paper
yes okay and oh and they don't test for
flavonoids yet so like
this might have that like i don't see
the grape in the terpene profile i
the grape must be a flavonoid in my
opinion um because this terpene profile
doesn't differentiate between other
profiles that don't have grape i know
it's all word of mouth at that point and
so if you can't smell the product you
can't touch the product you can't
you know anything the product before you
pay for it
you have to see it on a piece of paper
or
beautiful labeling or jars or yeah that
helps yeah attractive
pretty flowers
this is fire angel this is cbd strain
right here um
it's 50 i think uh two to one
they're my sativas they're they're
blowing up a little yellow leaves on the
bottom nothing too bad
a little yellow
uh so so this is actually
one of the great things of the living
soil bed is that process
makes sense if you don't have the
roly-polies and the pill bugs
to eat that it makes no sense because
that's now a vector for bacteria and
fungi and other things to break it down
you got to have the breakdown processed
or it's a problem
and that's why that's why the
relationship with mealybugs is it's a
love hate man i i
love them gotta feed them but you just
gotta feed them man
and tom if if it's okay i don't know how
you mess with your beds like i usually
am just hands in and looking
but i'd like to roll the stone over just
see and you can take a video
yeah describe a bigger one yeah yeah
find one that usually is active
we don't have to this is this is a small
basement
we'll we'll find a big flat one but this
this is that importance of showing that
life too
steve have you water in here where's
your watering system
is there is it what about your water
you're watering
a hand water you had water and water
yeah
i have uh three rooms like this um
they're all hand watered um and i have
two two growers on schedule on schedule
yeah the schedule changes throughout
this one cycle
um but yeah we have a a very very strict
watering schedule that we follow
um obviously depending on what the
plants are telling us as well as telling
us but um
hey if you see this
yeah they eat that better than this no
no that's a chipmunk we have a chipmunk
or a rat that got in we've been hunting
we've been hunting up for six months
he loves he loves our uh our predator
packs
yeah what are these they're predator
packs they're swarovski mites
so it's a beneficial insect
there is little pops
yep we've been hunting for a minute
let's go to the other side
hey you know what elaine would say throw
a bird in here and you have the complete
soil food web
he actually um eats the cover crop the
the we'll come in here and see how the
the the the sides
he mows it down like we've actually done
less cover crop management since it's
been in here though
in the weirdest of ways i kind of want
to eventually get to the fact that
you bring your rabbit to work with you
and then you put him in the bed
he mows he poops because it's cold
compost it's not even hot
yeah that would be cool that would be
cool you take your little support animal
home
so that's just another row um
yeah basically just this is all happy
praying plants this is our miss x right
here
this x right here is uh one of our
highest testing highest yielding strains
she's won all the awards for the best
sativa in the state uh
she's uh even though she's expressing
more of a
indicator she's a uh half of her as ac
dc cbd and doesn't even show up
um so she's a weird one man it's when we
say sativa
we're more associating we're not we're
not and that's the thing about the old
style so back in the day if you said
indica sativa and you it depends who you
ask if you ask a grower
they're going to talk about how tall or
short or stout or how quick it finished
or how long it finished
um but nowadays if you have something
indica sativa they're strictly
asking you about the effects is it going
to make me sleep or is going to make me
up or down
um so that when i said sativa i was more
or less referring to
the uh the effect okay
this is why there's so much confusion on
the customer base
because well what are you talking about
and there's no time to explain
yeah but the effect
is often confused by other like flavor
profiles and
and what are you looking at it's a uh
ice wing barber just
needing some love yeah
there you go
anyway i mean that's pretty much oh this
is the other great pie female right here
this is the winner great pie fino
technically this is a
mid 30s total cannabinoid um it does
have the great profile
the grape just isn't as loud as the
other one the number five this was the
number uh
i came here my number this one i think
it was number nine uh
yeah number nine uh no number twelve
that's number twelve
uh the other one's number five the
number twelve is the third mid thirty
percent the number five
is a twenty percenter um but holds the
stronger the stronger now yeah
yeah this is this is pretty much our
rooms man this is a 20-second cycle
three rooms so we've done this at this
point 65 times now
i'm so impressed with how you keep the
consistency of your plants
i just it's so i don't know i don't know
how you do it
this is a and multiple strains yeah oh
no multiple strains
i mean so this is a good example of
where this was
last cycle yes which was left in place
just harvested that next to it
in the void that's where the new plant
goes and you'll see it in every single
one here there's already this one's
already been broken
down so this is the natural progression
right here
broken down and falling apart but if you
look they're in every single bed
right there yeah exactly right there and
so this is
how you can still maintain the system
while using
pots to transfer in because you're
you're only disturbing it as little as
oh so so these are in pots that you
transplanted no these were this was
where our last plant was last cycle
right it was planted right here then the
plant got cut down harvested and then
when it was time to replant
we went right next to it because what we
didn't want to do is that's where
all the active biology was last cycle
was right there in their rhizosphere
right there in their root zone
and if we harvest that we what we end up
doing is harvesting 90
of our worms and all the biology out of
the bed so leave that in place let that
start the next cycle off um and then
just move over
move over right next to it you get the
benefit of all that biology
anyway don't you yeah now we're tapping
into it the other way
so basically we just shift grid every
single cycle
so but i mean they're they're planted
and you transplanted they're not like
you didn't
yeah okay yeah well we were in the room
now let me ask you one question were all
of these in this room
transplanted over at the same time or
were different strains brought over at
different times this room gets cut
they get harvested at different times
but they all get planted the same day so
they're
all at the same stage in their
development
but just expressing it differently it's
so fascinating i love it
great um and then you design
everything specifically to them these
are the ones
these are the sativas that i'm rotating
from room to room so were they trying to
get 20 weeks out of these
remember last night these are the plants
that take longer but his rooms are on a
10-week cycle
so he's got to move these plants yeah
well let's take a look at these beauties
what can you tell it these are the top
these are this is an authentic original
thai sea out of thai sea right yep it's
a
a land raised seed brought indoors
and this is uh it looks like some
marigolds or
um here yes yeah i love marigold did a
terpes
and they actually we did a study on root
feeding nematodes
and the marigolds create a biotoxin that
appears to
deter or kill the root feeding nematode
we did different control methods in
several different pots and we studied
over several cycles
and at the end of it the marigolds had
the best results
after three cycles they're multiple
species and this is french yep
yeah but those thailands i i do believe
they are a wild
um variety um i don't think it was bread
i i do think it was whatever is floating
around
out there still they're exotic
yeah i don't think there's a
selection that was what i'm getting at
those are peppers i know i think they're
purple flash or those might be the spicy
joes
oh no those are the new mexico uh joe
parker yeah can we talk about
this this environment is it the same how
i
what is the plans for so what's the
question
yeah uh lifespan like what can you like
no it's a creature that as long as he
feeds it and loves it could grow forever
and and that's what we're trying to
prove yeah is that hey
done correctly we're gonna hit 100
cycles plus out of this
and and i really want to show that that
works has it been done yet no i
this is five there's 20 cycles we'll say
20 is five years 20 is five
and so a hundred cycles is longer than
most businesses
right with the same consistency and
maturity
is the expectation as a grower that the
cannabis you grow in the 100
cycle environment will be the same as
that that was grown
in the 22nd how will that have changed
technically it's supposed to get better
with each cycle as that soil matures as
as as that soil gets broken down and
worked and
the fungi ratio changes
some of these fungi take years to
literally just be like okay there's
their environment
yeah well remember everything in this
ecosystem is all about
it has to be conducive for growth and
the bacteria grow fastest
boom after a while no no like literally
it can take
years for a fungal spore to be like okay
this environment is healthy long enough
that i feel safe enough
comfortable enough to now do my job
because it's part of that relationship
with whoever's on this
above and below part so
15 20 years from now you know
what a crazy thought i mean i don't know
anybody who's gone
this far with a living soil indoors um
but we definitely want to push the
envelope see how far we can take it
i mean it's already paid for itself 10
times over um so i mean there's no
reason let's talk about that because
most people
it's always the the price tag which is
why they don't want to
do new things but there is an initial
price egg but it's actually not that
much
mostly in the fact that you've got to do
more than just fill a bed with
bulk peat filler right you that costs
more
but after that it it's not the same
nutrition cycle
because the life is actually utilizing
what's in that
pot a lot it's it's more it's similar to
leds
it's a more upfront purchase when you're
getting into a soil system
it can be but that's it it's a one-time
purchase
you're not using as well as the hands-on
requirement
you know you're out there making compost
you got to commit to making a compost
though yeah
it can be there are some aspects of it
that require work
no doubt um uh obviously it's more
farming than
than uh than playing video games um but
uh
it's definitely it's not as labor
intensive
as people think once you really
streamline it make it efficient process
like again i have three rooms like this
i run with two growers
um three three of these rooms so every
plant you see
at this scale at this scale with two
people with two people and a harvester
so i guess three people
but that's all that's a different part
of the cycle right that's that's
two weeks out of the month i have a
harvester come in and harvest um but for
the most part
two people grow plant clones i didn't
all blue maps i didn't see irrigation
run everywhere all hand watered
which for most people is like oh you
never get the consistency so how do you
train your staff to not just stand there
and gossip and flood your bed
no they're they're water ninjas man they
know water they know what to do
uh we have we have uh
hey while we're here are these your new
lights yes these are the
my opinion and i'll fight anybody who
says otherwise uh these are definitely
the best lights on the market i feel
um they're the fos a3i it's their
flagship light
uh it's the most over built
awesome piece of grow equipment on the
market it's
super solid they're 1500 watt led
they're spectrum controllable
they have a program where you can do a
sunrise sunset
uh they're just a trick and slice on the
market they did a really good job
engineering them
and then thinking this light through
example if i get a diode out or a bar
out i don't gotta change the whole
fixture
they come in they swap a bar out uh just
little things like that are just super
efficient for me as
a cultivator thing i'm noticing is like
unlike
some other brands where there's kind of
you really have to have a
place them really specifically you have
to have a bridge to place your life
these are pretty
it's like pretty straight forward so
what these direct
angles yeah they they had they can
direct an angle but what's really
important is the beam angle that they
went with
some people go too wide like a lot of
the newer led lights like the the
non-tortoni brands and the underbust
but a lot of the newer leading led
companies they use a really
wide beam angle which which forces you
to throw the plants
or the lights um six six inches to a
foot above your plants
um which doesn't leave space for air to
move uh which is
which crates in my opinion less
consistency
and with these lights they have the
power and the beam angle
to where you can set them and forget
them which is great for commercial
applications there's so much space
between the lights and the plants
there's easily outside but it's really
good for commercial applications because
i don't have to chase the stretch now
with the beam angle i'm not throwing
light on that wall over there
unless i want to uh so i'm actually what
i was wondering because people would say
the side of the plant's not getting
light so that's why they're reflecting
so what i did with these lights is if
you look i put the outside um
bar on the row across from it i forced
it out so i'm getting that to penetrate
and slice underneath the leaves
um so we're getting we're getting tons
of penetration with these lights
well yeah and you can see that in your
other plant growth too
you wouldn't have the the cover crop or
understory
you know penetrating as well it's it's
very well done
your your soil is going to outlive your
your
your beds all right it is 100 we have to
figure that out
it's it's on the network yeah because
that's the reality of going no no if you
really do this
that that's temporary you understand so
far that's that's to be a testament
ultimately is that so far our soil is
out
outrun our lights are all our first
original fans
okay tom did you hear that because when
we talk about return and
investment we talk about costs and
expenses
most people see it as when do i have to
replace right
and what he's just said is that what is
actually growing his plant
has been consistent longer than the
lights because you've changed those out
even the type
right sap right like every all the
consistency
of that the most important point here
this may look
like you know any grow room you've seen
this it doesn't mean
this looks way better this is unlike
most almost
almost any other group that you will
find
and that is really unique that's so
true at this scale this is
continue to reap like financial benefits
from working with this type of
environment and that's how you
become a successful farmer yeah no i
mean we're highly successful businessman
we really want to be able to to take our
success and share with
with with good product to the customers
with good jobs for our employees
with a good business for the community
uh we really want to fire on all
cylinders um
well no i don't that's all great you got
your big you know you have a great
product so
thank god you have a great product you
know out there but i mean when you go
apply you're like wait a second man i'm
not gonna have to invest as much in it
because i'm working with this
you know so and that's the big thing is
people look at how much can they get per
pound
the question i ask myself a lot is how
much am i putting in per pound
uh and that's a lot of people that's a
question they don't ask themselves one
of the things that
that we that keeps us so competitive is
how little money we spend
turning these rooms over so when i come
in i clean this room i replant
i probably spend fifty dollars in
materials to restart this room
a hundred dollars in materials to
restart this room yep
i mean if you include compost if i hit a
heavy compost yeah that might compost
but i make it in house so technically
it's free
but it would cost about 500 bucks a yard
so yeah and even then you're looking at
hours versus days or weeks of labor also
requirements
so i mean it cost me a thousand bucks to
flip this room per cycle
not including the power bill but yeah so
i mean that's a huge cost savings that
keeps us
competitive um that we couldn't do
without the living soil system
and you and that competitive is not just
on the market with with
other products it's also with the
customer base you're trying to actually
interact with
if if you're just having to cover your
costs and you've out
costed most of the people who would
really appreciate your product
just because you're being inefficient
right
we're penalizing the people who are so
grateful to us like a park
down here you want to go have a picnic
down here
that's where the fairies have the picnic
so yeah i mean the idea is to drive it
to drive the cost down
uh how much to put into the plant to
drive the quality up
uh and to drive the yields up um and so
like so far we've done it our quality is
is
has always been top shelf um our we've
we've actually just this last year broke
into
those dream number yields that we've
been striving for for the last five
years
so what's the downside man there's got
to be something
no i mean we it's we're in a regulated
market so i mean
we could fail at any minute for anything
we could uh
ac could go down there's there's always
a risk there's always
there's always rainy days you know i'm
saying we still have our issues it's not
uh
it's not all smiles able to tap into the
local power grid or you have generator
backup
we have a generator backup right now
that handles our security system
um but not that wouldn't run our lights
um
but we are currently looking at a
generator that will run our hvac and
lights
um if needed well that's a great
question because there have been rolling
block out
but luckily our placement we're in
between two power grids so usually when
one shuts down
they transfer power from the other so
we're actually one of the best locations
um to have a grow
i don't think we've we've only actually
known we had one for i think less than
an hour
uh blackout uh how much do you pay for
it
yeah i don't know like quite things on
the top of my head that is well you know
yeah hey be respectful tom
it shouldn't be an embarrassing question
but it's really important when we have
costs
you think of the costs differently
because it's part of what keeps it
everything
fed right when you go at that point
you're like actually it's not a cost i
just have to
take care of my people right i went to a
massive grow in
eastern washington state where they the
energy is like
two cents a kilowatt i mean they pay
nothing because there's
that's where they produce like all the
energy for the country and so they're so
lucky
but they're you know so yeah but that
often breeds in efficiency
because it's so cheap they're like oh
don't worry about it it's just 20 bucks
but the reality is is the one thing that
we have good here going for us though is
that we don't pay
uh i just torched that the other day i
brought it in here no no i'm looking at
the worms already caught up and say hi
is that we don't have um peak hours so
we have a private uh power company and
and they don't do peak hours so during
the day like in vegas during the day
mid-day
you're paying more for power um then we
don't do that out here and so that's
nice
that forces people in vegas to make
their their crews work at night
and all these ridiculous things to try
to save pennies uh so it's kind of yeah
the road crews are out at one o'clock in
the morning just be
yeah it there's weird little things
because
the infrastructure doesn't support what
everybody has to do to get done
can let's pull that pot i'll just lift
the pot over and so these have just
don't don't do it yet
so tom why don't you get the camera just
close enough
and all we want to do is just a reality
that the soil in here is actually
already so close to what's in here that
the life just transfers between them
right and you can see worms literally
hanging out the bottom
these are different various mites you
see some springtails
uh you see some snails
that's the only pot flipping you do
you guys want to talk i think we should
probably have a little bit of
conversation outside the rooms too just
in case the fans become a problem
and it's exciting oh real quick check
this out though check these lights out
yeah so just to give you guys an example
spring look at this little row right
here
so that's all balloona there you go
summer bring it back to the the
spectrum's arrested room
boom if i wanted to i can go autumn and
it really hit the heart they're heavy
red
so that's pretty cool light man
and then they have this feature here
where you can do a scheduling sunrise
sunset so basically the lights they
don't start off at a hundred percent
they'll start off at
at the minimum yep and they'll let the
plant wake up before they hit him with
that ppfd
on the tail end you know resting yeah
you start to think you're god or
something
but they're really they're really nice
hissing man i highly recommend folks
if you guys know anybody who's
interested in lifetime hit me up y'all
hook them up with the 18 from post and
get them dialed in
uh and i like that you're a combination
of technology and old school
yeah that's good definitely yeah i can't
go wrong with those uh
it's one of our original things i was
trying to accomplish kind of says it all
we're going for old growth for us
anyways that's a different perspective
right of what a cannabis grow is
that that's what i'm going for today
that's our that's our mission
cycles any other question before we take
off we got i mean
you gotta have more no well i was just
saying we'd get out of the fans
no i don't have any questions my basic
feeling is
first it's really
it's clean it's organized so nicely
and i can see how you have complete
control over
everything and it's like coming along
and i just asked myself it's like it's
like you were saying it's like you can't
be everywhere at once and
because you you know you do want to get
bigger so
it's like it's so nice at this size
and uh it's so nice you know i know when
we do expand i'm gonna miss it
i know i know that i know your expansion
is
a different type of growth with the
greenhouse part
so there's that but are you going to put
more bays like this as well
so the 35 square foot building in front
the goodwill that you guys saw
that will all be built out for more
indoor so we'll have
we'll have six more rooms the green
light goodwill
and i do want to talk about this maybe
we could talk about it in the other room
but we were talking about do
relatively smaller businesses right now
in cannabis
have an advantage because not they're
not over leveraged
they don't have too many things and so
you know it's sort of like what's wrong
with running a small business
in the scheme of things why does
everyone have to go huge so maybe we can
talk about that a little bit i mean
i got caught up in the rat race at first
i thought i wanted a 100 000 square foot
we get through the science most people
that's intimidating
right we've talked about finances most
people that's too intimidating we talked
about
dude i'm not a farmer i just grow plant
you know that's intimidating
how how do you deal with going but i'm
still going to try
something that no one else is doing
when when you're really just trying to
meet the medical needs of a community
too
you know what i mean there's a different
agenda where
the quality is the focus and guess how
much our yield is
versus no no we don't care we just got a
push to get this number
i was kind of personally i was kind of
blessed with the fearless nature
so to me it was challenge accepted
you know it kind of state of mind but
for the most part
when you know what you're doing is so
right it's hard for anybody to tell you
you're wrong
and that's just something that you just
gotta and the confirmations are
literally the plants
they're all about the worm the the
finance book
the satisfaction of your employees the
efficiency of your your
the flow like when you go to work people
like to go to work
versus a drudgery because of all the
managed problems they have to deal with
i've never said this is a living system
that we just walked in i'm not sure if
you guys felt it but
there's energy in these rooms there's a
living energy and when you walk into
them
the air is fresh it's not stale it
doesn't smell like water
it smells like like air
like supposed to smell so it's just
it's a good clean energetic environment
like when i come here
i i i drink coffee in the morning don't
get me wrong but just walking through
those doors that door right there
gives wakes me up gives me energy makes
me feel alive so i
i'm thankful for that and that right
there
should give the person who feels like
crap some courage
right to try something a little
different that
actually helps lift you up like the
plant reaching out to lift you up
because it's
it's a nurturing environment you know
you can talk about this a little bit
more when it's quieter there are so many
arguments to transform over to a living
soil
and if you can say to someone and you
should really really
nail this one down with people you would
have to replace your system every year
yeah
it's like i don't understand why that
really would not resonate with someone i
really don't know what i've heard
what i've heard and and i think this is
what we should talk about the house is
actually what i've heard so i agree
there are actual reasons why i want to
get to what like
someone's starting a business they're
doing is the thing that should matter to
them
yeah it's costs
no matter what
dude i think we'll make it that picture
come on yeah it'll be happen
it'll get there once i get those
hand-caught sharks in it
you gotta make the grotto see so you're
gonna that's how you'll end up changing
you'll be
we'll get some some jade from the
california coast and we'll put it in
there too
some abalone shells mother of pearl you
see that
[Laughter]
i am so grateful to be here who are you
steve campbell with green life
productions
steve campbell i've heard that name in a
lot of different places but guess what
i'm really happy to hear it right now
because today we went to his facility
which total grow footage
what's that what's the facility's total
growth space currently because i know
you're expanding but
uh currently we're operating about
twelve thousand square foot okay
uh with the potential to grow out to
about another forty thousand plus
greenhouse
twenty thousand foot greenhouse the next
phase is
um it is
it's really great to have been to a
facility that sees how the life
translates through its process
and this is what i want to talk about
it's not only part of
the bed it's part of the cloning process
it's part of the up potting process it's
part of the
composting post growth process
it's part of your r d process
i'm not talking about structure facility
which by the way the efficiency is
amazing
and and the lighting i'm specifically
talking about soil
that that life
process is a complete cycle and because
of that
there's no misuse of the resource
in nurturing your plants yeah
which is loss either found in the plant
growth
yield the accountant right
your wallet like that's that's where
that cycle
of waste or misuse starts kicking out
and you're like oh i feel it in this
area
time you know because i got all these
messes to clean up
i didn't see one mess in the entire
place keep a clean shot
no i okay good it wasn't yeah
it's a clean shop but you didn't say it
wasn't it's not an unmessy shop
right mess is is the projects that are
half finished
that you step over that ruin the flow
all right it's a shit you gotta clean up
yep
and there was no messes and even the
messy room
was really because you had to move them
like hold on once again it's so messy in
here
like three feet of adjustment on
something on wheels
is not a mess right true okay
so most places
there's a mess somewhere and that's what
is taking all the energy
you know we uh we definitely run a tight
ship uh
early on one of the things that we
didn't really have a lot of experience
in was a cul-de-sac
there was no other cult-based facilities
so what we tried to model after was
either a restaurant and or a hospital
try to keep it clean try to keep it
sterile try because that's who was
inspecting our facility was restaurant
people
yep um so their rule set so we had to
keep in mind that people who were coming
in that were gonna write us a ticket
what's their
favorite what was their pass where they
were coming from restaurant the majority
of them so that's why we are so uptight
with our
clean walls clean every day we clean our
floors every
every cycle we break our rooms down and
clean our rooms from top to bottom
um our trim room gets broken down once a
month i drive them to get broken down
every cycle
or every every harvest um so i mean the
whole place is just
we're really at the end of the day every
single position is a glorified janitor
uh but you know it's it's it's what we
got to do
what do you mean by janitor because i
know you're not just meaning toilet
cleaner
no i just mean we clean that messes you
know and we but we don't step over them
our job is to clean them up and to to
make sure the place is
is looking sharp and that at any one
point in time
someone a state official could walk
through it a patient can walk through it
and feel comfortable a state official
can walk through it not be writing up
tickets
this wasn't a surprise but i have no
doubt if i showed up
next whatever at whatever time during
legal business hours a week
like honestly it would look exactly the
same i don't do tours
and you've been here so yeah
did you just do all this yesterday and
just show up
but you never know honestly usually i
see but that's why it's done in a day
you don't leave it to tomorrow you don't
j yeah and it stacks
yes it's it's not you guys that i'm
always in preparation for it exactly
okay it's it's honestly the state they
have their regulation their rules
you you're playing the game um so
it's not worth it i want to keep them
happy they come to make a recommendation
whether i have to it or not i'm going to
listen i'm going to do it because
it shows that i listen um and part of
that is
part of the effect of listening that you
did for them the understandings
two ways is that and that second way
back and forth
allowed you when i got there to go hold
on different rule set
new state different facility license
here are our rules and structures this
is what i'm expecting of you
no negatives no weird lala hey man can
we just
this is the rules the role right
and if very clear-cut
and so having that knowledge walking
into it
we didn't have one issue the whole day
versus
right going on a tour and somebody doing
this and somebody doing that messing
stuff up here and oh what are you doing
i
was supposed to do that yesterday you
know it's like yeah that's
the messes and so i really appreciate
that it's rare to actually have somebody
so clear
like this is how you can best experience
what i've
worked so hard at you know again it's a
we're on our 22nd cycle so times three
we've done it 60 we're on our 66th time
now
uh around the led 66 times
but when we were looking at the bed it's
over here
and then over here right yeah then over
here
but to be honest over here
yes but even that though that wasn't a
technique that we learned until several
cycles in that we noticed
so how did that cycle shift like you in
in working with these creatures these
beds right
you were like oh there's a better way
there's more efficiency we used to
remove the root ball and what we what we
did was over time what we learned was
we're harvesting our worms when we do
that
and not only worms but all the other
biology behind them the entire arousal
yeah the whole plants actually
everything you've been building pretty
much or the plant's been building i
guess
you could say so that's true we're
really
doing a uh not doing a service to the
soil by doing that we were taking the
most valuable part out of it every time
so that the soil wasn't advancing
uh and we were actually seeing less and
less warm population in our soil
um so then all we did was we just moved
over 60 that's where you're going to
have a higher concentrations of your
cocoons and egg casings
which proportionately everything is
exponentially going the wrong direction
so we just shifted whole over we created
this great pattern style where we just
go north hole let's hole
our north hole south hole um between
cycles um
and uh yeah it allows the root ball to
to break down and
it allows that that biology to transfer
to other parts of the soil
uh because at the time needed to spread
and uh yeah we're not harvesting the
biology we're
we're just taking the soil needed to to
plant the next corn
you're you're not even harvesting the bi
or
when when your clones transition and are
up potted
it's the same ecosystem on a smaller
scale so there's a little bit of
isolation a little bit of
you know decrease of the diversity
because of that smaller scale
but the reality is is the transition
there's always stressors you can add to
the transition but
on the soil micro you know rhizosphere
level
is as seamless as possible yeah even the
moisture content like you know
i don't see you taking that ecosystem
and then having to really drench it in
good because you're going to saturate
the whole medium
it's not it literally is going it's a
transition
you're just moving it from one equation
one group to yeah it's a tourist
and like you said it's less shock to
plant it's the same yeah it's on a
smaller in a smaller pot but it's the
same soil so
it's relatively same ph same micro same
biology
board worms literally in the clone pod
there's already established fully mature
ecosystems on
on that trophic level we just got to
make sure that the environmental changes
are the same so that i'm not coming from
a humid veg to a dry flower room so
right on the operator side of things you
got to make sure to make the proper
adjustments right away
um because there's a day or two of like
an example the end of flower i'm running
my rooms on the dry side so
when i go to plant a room i want to be
on the humid side if i if i forget to
switch my humidity set point
and i plant into a dry room i just
create a huge stress factor yeah
see and this is where the management is
so important and understanding
how that one
i hear is it worth it that's what i hear
people is it worth i just don't see
how you know what's it worth right you
go wait
that five seconds to turn around and do
it because you know you
should right what's it worth well you
just paid some guy thirty thousand
dollars to fix up the plumbing
issue and this and you lost your entire
crop because it flood you know
it's like that's where the worth is so
that you're not actually paying
the money you know that's where the
farmer
keeps go transitions from thriving
because the real worth isn't thriving
you know the survival mindset that we
were talking about versus surviving
versus thriving yeah
so we re we lifted some of those rocks
we forgot to lift more of them though we
should
yeah but the nice part is we still did
and what the point was
is that when you lift the rock um
that's how you it's a window it's a
portal
and you can do it if you have plexiglas
and you just put plexiglas
down and then you cover it with uh
cardboard and then put something over
top of it so it doesn't move
they'll just turn that like like the
underside of the rocket so you'll see
the worm channels and the insect paths
and it's really great for outdoor
growers to do that as like what's going
on under here we got to put in a window
there you go that's good it's kind of
fun how do i get on my beds now
yeah and so when you remove that rock we
did get the video of us
lifting or just leaning over yeah that
was cool
and literally the bridge what was the
bridge the body of a worm
like coming through
now the rock mulch has been a great idea
man it just creates that the more
consistent moisture so in between waters
if the soil does tend to dry
too much or whatever the the worms
always have that it's a good
base to run to that moisture zone to run
too
it also creates these almost like little
windows
where you're not getting that same green
growth
um from your cover crop yep yep almost
you know
little snorkels because those roof mats
can get real thick
yep but in the flowering room the
consistency of coloring and everything
was
really something to behold to me it
looked really
nice thank you great yeah
we're uh we pretty much i mean we rarely
see unhealthy plants in our facility
um just recently with these new lights
pushing the beds as hard as we can
um now we've actually seen until we've
actually reached our limitations finally
um before lights are the big were the
biggest limiting factor and we couldn't
even push our system hard enough to ever
see the limitations so now you're seeing
where's the limitation with the soil
okay i was never able to reach that
before
okay and so how are you seeing the
limitation
no i i could just see where or where it
potentially your deficiency is yes
it's hard to see these efficiencies not
that it is a problem but you can see
that because of this extra demand
you're going to see like it's hard to
see the trends that we're going from
sorry i can start something
tending to mining right so so this is
really fascinating because i look at
this i go you know we talk all the time
about the living soil how like paramount
that is but here's a technology
that's made like a huge positive
difference so it's the marriage of the
two
that you know because that is not
negligible
the difference that these lights have
made it's not it doesn't sound like it
would you i don't need to know the price
but would you say it's a
double what a high-end price
light already is like you're talking
about it's a more cost but that's fine
because
the benefits are we're talking about
folks right now the lights wow okay if
you want to oh
no by the way a good led now that we are
uh they're face lights post lights led
led a3i is their mothership light but
they make
several models of lights that are all
extremely spectacular i've worked with
all pretty much all of them at this
point
um no it's a really good led company
they make really high-end led fixtures
that are just super well built the
reason i like them is because
in the last five years the trend that
i've seen in the led industry
is that the biggest hang up for
purchasers
was the price point so what led
companies did was they did they
they solely went to uh
lower the price point they try to yeah
attend to that
so versus focusing on building the best
light
they just try to build the cheapest
light so they all try to build a cheaper
price point light
and they all ended up building cheaper
lights
um folks did not froze exactly so folks
did not do that they were the first id
coming we were trying all these new
lights out
that brought a light it was like whoa
this isn't a tin foil
it's a tool like when you look at it
you're like this thing is fully
adjustable
and i'm looking at it and you literally
just allen rich okay that whole thing
just comes off and snaps back in it's
like
this is a functional tool it's like a
multi-tool right
like i need it to be over here and yet
it's not just a plastic snap
that's gonna eventually snap right now
they shouldn't be well built so that
that's one of the things they've really
um sold me on on the company um and just
the way they future built them um
they're extremely versatile from
spectrum to
to the ramp up ramp down mode you
totally played with that how long until
you found you're like hey look this is
like sunrise and sunset
and here we go no it's fun and uh
i noticed the plant's less stressed out
though by doing that so
to transition into those rooms and when
it's hard to increase the ppfd on the
plants
i'm not just hitting them all at once so
we're just seeing happier plants in
general
i think i think this is almost shifting
the um
role of a bud tender right
it's like when you're walking then the
person's watering and they're just going
you know they're not a janitor
they're the actual bud tenders right the
actual bud tenders
yeah and the whole facility was hand
watered yeah we can't water
and it didn't look like you guys were
running anything but water
um the only thing we run primarily would
just be our compost extracts teas
um do the occasional protozoa infusion
can i can i talk about that for a second
the reason for that is this is an
ecosystem
that is populated but that population
has to come to something called a quorum
okay and a quorum is what takes place
in like the bioluminescent fish have you
ever seen that on some year yes yeah
right
that's actually a bacteria inside the
fish that the fish can figure out how to
turn on with an
enzyme and all at the same time
trillions of these independent organisms
go okay cool
and light right like it's really trippy
it's the same thing of like you eat some
food and then you're like
instantaneously you get like a film over
your teeth the biofilm
okay that's a quorum right like your
compost teas brewing and then all of a
sudden
right you get the foam and the thick and
the crust
right that's one population hit its
quorum and then went
ape shit and it shifted the ecology
right and so that's why t's are so
volatile in comparison to an extract
you're just
adding more teammates into that
ecosystem because
everything's eating each other and
trying to create
the most nurtured balance and so it's a
really cool thing to add those
extracts without having to add nutrients
to it
because you're adding there's they're
called amino sugars and that's why your
in
requirements change because
when your plant is pulling the nutrition
out of the actual microbiology it's like
eating a steak so but on that scale
the creature meat is called an amino you
know
uh sugar an amino sugar and which is all
because of the carbon the photosynthesis
sugar is going into it like that's the
meat
and your plant wants to be a carnivore
and eat these biology sugars
instead of in and even the in that's
processed through the air is through the
biology of that bacteria we were talking
about on the clovers yep
yeah yeah and so you're just adding
more livestock into the into the grow
and for us like but as far as the teas
and extracts go
it's a process that we at times really
don't even need like when you look at
the microscope all my players are there
but to some degree i have to use compost
because it's part of our waste
management program
um so like at some point i'm just top
dressing just
because i don't want to have 10 yards of
compost building up um
so does this state have a requirement
that it has to stay on site after it's
been
thermophilic so that that's something
you sell it
i i've sold compost when i can't give it
away
i've given it away in small bits to to
friends well
these are all variables but if the law
says it has to stay on site which
in some places i don't want to make a
business model out of it because
maybe there is one day but for the most
part i know
damn well if i make a cannabis compost
and the state finds out that i'm making
compost out of cannabis cannabis
instantaneously and i'm making money off
of it forty percent we want
forty percent of your compost money
somehow so it's that's why i don't want
to try to sell anything right this is
literally the absolute
waste waste stream so we want 40
of your waste yeah 30 tax on compost
we want your 40 of your poo so right now
we just put it all back
in the system um wow okay but that
actually is part of
we were talking earlier about it can get
too rich
and this is where the biology gets
almost clay
right like it it'll really thicken up
because it's missing that other scale
because it's still in a pot and this is
where the gopher would come and take
raw minerals from the bottom of the
earth you know dump it on the surface
right
this is where vice versa then once up
here it takes organic material
drives it down into the earth like it
had a role and a purpose
it still does and so do we and they call
it hugel cultures
that's what we do on our scale we take
the trees and put it into the ground
right
biochar right we're just working at
different scales
for sure uh yeah there's definitely
certain uh aspects of the living soil
system that we can't incorporate indoors
some of the macro features like ground
squirrels and
rabbits no rodents aren't welcome
they're not we've been there we got a
rodent we got one
well and this is any business right and
so your model of the
restaurant or the the hospital
they still got to deal with that too
yeah
but i will say
you got to know who you call and what
they use
because if you're trying to get rid of
something and
they're leaving stuff around your place
making messes
and it has any form of decon rat killer
bait all this stuff
because most often what happens is you
tell someone who has
time which is usually someone who
doesn't have anything better to do
to go deal with a problem right at which
point they go to the store and say hey i
need some help
what kills rats and then someone who has
less training than any of them
sells them something and then you get a
contamination violation
so it's there's a whole process of going
no no
the whole facility runs on this
perspective
yeah 100 you gotta be uh really try to
take an organic approach through and
through
as much as you possibly can um obviously
you get a rodent
you get a bird a pigeon there's there's
certain times you got to eradicate
certain things
bb gun is organic yeah
it's an acute amount of lead put into
the ecosystem
and it fully composted it's just fine
what about the dogs they were actually
uh our originals
no but we said when we first opened up
we actually lived across the street in
the apartments
um for about a little over a year and we
take the dogs at working day they run
the property
um so there they they ran the property
for i want to say
really closer to a year and a half
but the thing is that that's when we
first opened up everybody saw us and uh
the pictures were taken of them at the
front gate and whatnot
with barbed wire like it's a horrible
image with rottweilers
you're a big dude kind of scared beat
people up for a living right but
you're through with mike there's like
four years and people have been dating
a big teddy bear look at you you never
get that side out i mean they're like
you know you don't
primal until this day people think that
they run that property
uh hold up i'm not gonna wasn't here
well you wanna go there with invitation
see that's part of community too you you
work with each other and you welcome
but you have good boundaries or a lot of
dogs
which are good boundaries and now we uh
they're definitely they're more of a
liability as a security guard than uh
well i actually think you're giving a
job to human beings is good too
he's a very nice guy i've met two of
them team team humans
people team human see it's important
but yeah the security factor is always a
big deal though
at the at these facilities
it is also a deterrent to have a pile of
composting material
outside the front door really short it's
a lot of robbers
they're confused there's strange smells
barbed wire we're at a farm there's a
goddamn cow sound over here
i've been to they are kind of out of
town and so then they do have their
perimeters and they have security
you're like in town yeah we're playing
neighbors here so that is that a good
thing that might
it's a beautiful community yeah i mean
but you still have
like security concerns well i mean
there's really i guess there's two ways
to look at it um
yeah we're surrounded by a lot of
traffic but we're also surrounded by a
lot of cops
uh so if we're in some rural out in the
boonies out in the middle of nowhere
it's gonna be a lot longer for cops to
get there wherever the radio goes a lot
faster than uh so being a center town
like that is kind of safer
position to be in and it's a smaller
town so they'll react
faster probably and one of the weird
things is that they let us do uh
razor wire fencing out here uh you can't
do that in las vegas
oh so there's an actual deterrent versus
yeah so
people we've never had a random person
walking on our property
and in all the years do you have the
whistling over there too
no but we have much better security
cameras
that move and track and trace what's the
surrounding businesses appreciate
there there's this a security that also
has a presence no there is a shop next
to us the tattoo shop
next to that is a shop called threads um
they were robbed one day
and the dudes ran across our security
cameras and uh the cops came
and took our surveillance camera and
we're actually yeah able to help with
that
yeah yeah yeah they use dispensary
cameras a lot yeah for traveling another
service of the cannabis
community i think i think it's happened
for us once if not twice already that
that's what they've been able to use our
cameras to to help excellent
so yeah so we got five minutes you guys
want to wrap it up and uh anything um i
would like to say thank you
for the time and um and sharing what you
guys are
all you guys are doing just kind of in
there anything you want to talk about
that i i'd like to say that i
no matter what if seals intact right uh
would happily share and partake in your
flower
total trusted thank you thank you like
like i'd give it to grandma type of
thing right you know what i mean like
trust yeah
and everyone has a grandma so he's got a
ground here he'd like he'd give it to
everyone's grandma
there you go there you go yeah i'm just
waiting for this new building though
what's coming up next i mean for us
right now we got two things in motion
um we're doing some r d some small skill
um hash
uh rosin that's right uh bubble yeah
some just playing with some different
techniques there
all all solventless um so we'll be
playing with some things there coming
out some different products
uh and that's just a lead up into our
greenhouse project our sungrown line
so we'll be having a completely
different stream a completely different
line of gop
still living root soil um still done
with our standards
um just using the sun uh in a state of
our greenhouse versus indoor building
uh so that'll be coming up hopefully
next year we postponed it this year
because of covid but we're hitting it
hard again and i hope to have it next
year nice
look forward to it man you're well on
the way it's looking great
thank you so much for your time and
back to you peter
thanks ryan