systems that have been adapted from
other industries that are not designed
for cultivation
are like fitting a square peg into a
round hole
the fact is cannabis is a living
organism that has different
environmental requirements based on its
stage of life
it's not a it's not a static load
requirement like human centric comfort
cooling or an indoor pool facility
the 10 cardinal parameters work
synergistically and all of them need to
be optimized to ensure crucial kpis are
met such as grams per square foot and
price per pound
hvacd tells the full story of what
environmental control for cannabis
should do
sure there's heat load from the lights
it needs to be accounted for
but it takes about twice as much work to
dehumidify than it does to remove heat
and through the process of transpiration
plants act as perfect little humidifiers
in cultivation rooms and without proper
modulating dehumidification humidity
rates and vpd simply cannot be
maintained
but we have a huge challenge here how
can you determine what a proper hvac d
system looks like how much should it
cost how do you compare competing
systems on a true apples-to-apples basis
we're going to help answer these
questions over the next 30 minutes as
adrienne and rob walk us through the
concepts of a coordinated design process
the performance and cost differences of
conventional non-integrated and
integrated hvac d systems
and a crash course on leveling bids and
important kpis
with that i'll pass it off to adrian to
get us started
thank you brian indoor cannabis and
horticulture projects are extremely
complex
and in a way we're constructing an
entire campus
in a near in nearly every building
that's purpose built or retrofitted for
indoor cultivation
and looking at this process map courtesy
of anderson porter architects
you can see why they're so complex
labor is one of the largest operational
costs so employee workflow is central to
an optimized facility
in addition to that you have lighting
strategies canopy area
cultivation methods and technologies
building envelope design
energy consumption building management
systems for data collection
and control maybe even on-site renewable
energy and microgrid controls
all of which need to come together in
harmony to meet your product
output goals and meet your business
metrics and kpis
that we will talk about later on the use
of a coordinated design process
allows you the ability to assign
resources according to the limited
capital
available to any project now let us dig
in a bit into the two typical types of
project delivery methods
as well as the type of team members that
comprise
an indoor horticulture project plan spec
build on the top on the left is a more
traditional approach
that typically doesn't allow for as much
collaboration between the design and
construction teams
but it doesn't have to be that way you
as the owner get to
set the tone and the expectations for
your project
you want collaboration and want to work
through an architect as the quarterback
it is very possible but needs to be set
up that way from the start
and the architect needs to be selected
appropriately
an alternative method is design build
this method allows for the whole design
and construction team to be brought
under one
contract and work collaboratively from
the beginning
this is a true one throat to choke
scenario which works well
for complex and fast paced projects
regardless of the path you choose it is
imperative to ensure that each project
team member has the requisite cannabis
and horticulture
intimacy to avoid costly and common
mistakes
these professionals are somewhat rare in
the wild but they do exist
regardless of where the recommendations
come from be sure to fully vet
all project partners to the best of your
ability
by having the right professionals in
place as shown on the right side of the
screen with the owner in the middle
owner's representative surrounding them
or construction manager role
followed by the architect and the other
engineers and sub consultants and
ultimately contractors
all coordinated together allows you to
lock in a guaranteed maximum price
when possible allows you to limit your
risk
allows you to avoid change orders that
can be very costly
allows you to avoid work that needs to
be redone
there can be huge challenges with
projects moving so fast as these do
and making sure that all the bases are
covered up front so budgets and
timelines don't get inflated
is extremely important your project does
not have to cost more money
to execute in a coordinated fashion and
have it be sustainable in design
if desired get things done right the
first time
and it will pay off
now make sure you target the business
metrics and kpis that will drive
your business profitability be sure you
have selected the best site that you
have sufficient power available
you can get the appropriate licensing at
that location have the right amount
budgeted for the project
on and on and on before you jump in this
process is truly a delicate balance
between risk and reward
the rewards can be massive and the risks
can be crushing
our mission is to bring our experience
and ecosystem
to work together to maximize the rewards
and minimize the risks with that i'm
going to hand it off to robbie to talk
you through different hvacd system types
and why some systems outperform others
when using kpis of business
profitability
so we've spent about a decade walking
into indoor cannabis facilities of all
types
and like you'd expect no two rooms are
100 identical
but because we're putting a webinar
together that has to compare different
system types we've had to generalize
different systems and we did that based
on certain key features so we're going
to suggest
that those three major system types and
that each of them represents an
incrementally better approach
as we move through the generations of
designs
so let's start with the conventional
non-integrated design approach
just by looking at this picture you can
recognize this system type because it
has a pretty glaring feature
hanging from the ceilings are
dehumidifiers the primary hpc system
that you don't see
in the room is most likely a commercial
system really designed for regular
commercial
or office building type loads we're
using mini splits or
off-the-shelf package rooftop units
serving these rooms this is why we call
it a conventional system
i think it just can't handle the
humidity levels required
for a cultivation space alone and hence
we have all these d-hums installed in
between the lights
now the air coming off those d-hums is
probably about 110 120
in that range of temperature or higher
and now how is that now dehumidified hot
air going to float down to the plants
well it really isn't and that's why when
we take a deep look at the temperatures
and humidities in the spaces
we see incredibly inconsistent numbers
and conditions at the canopy are
rarely where the cultivator would like
them to be the fact is
it's almost impossible to tie all the
systems together
to achieve room consistency most of
these rooms have separate thermometers
for each of the different equipment
pieces and this is why we call it
non-integrated
so there we have it conventional air
conditioning paired with disparate
dehumidification equipment
each piece controlling separate set
points in a non-integrated family
now there's other problematic things you
might notice about the room looking
closely you see these concept drains
hanging off the side of the d-hums
we've found that these condoms clog
frequently and the result is dirty
condensate water
dripping into your canopy causing all
sorts of ipm problems that require extra
management
putting equipment in the room like this
is also a maintenance nightmare
sending maintenance people into a live
room to change filters or fix equipment
the biosecurity nightmare for sure and
cleaning all the services you see
is almost impossible so it's just extra
hard to keep cross-contamination
happening from one crop to the next
so why is all this a problem the fact is
it's a problem because it costs you
money now don't get me wrong
i'll be very clear people will grow
cannabis in these rooms
and a sharp cultivator can do it very
successfully to this day this is
probably the most popular setup for
indoor growing
some people have become millionaires
doing it these people did amazing work
with equipment that was commercially
available or even just available at the
local home depot
we congratulate them for everything
they've done in pioneering this industry
but now only in hindsight we know that
cultivators
could have been so much more profitable
if we could have addressed the items i
just mentioned
so as the industry evolved we ended up
seeing dehumidification specific
equipment providing temperature and
humidity control for the growing rooms
how do i know this based on the picture
on the screen
well where are the dehumidifiers they're
gone
this is an indication that another
off-the-shelf piece of equipment most
likely
a system designed for pool room
dehumidification for example
is serving the space now the best thing
about this approach
is that the temperature and humidity
control are integrated so this is an
integrated system one piece is doing
both jobs
and that means the hvac has a much
better chance of getting the things
right inside the room but the fact is
this is still a conventional system
it's conventional because the equipment
we're using
may have been designed for
dehumidification but it was designed for
human
centric dehumidification pool room
dehumidifiers are just not intended for
the cultivation industry
i want to take a minute to stress this
difference serving a space with a pool
in it
versus a space with plants in it is so
very very different
the biggest difference is if i'm
swimming in a pool i want all that water
a nice warm 80 degrees plus fahrenheit
temperature
frankly to keep that pool at that
temperature it takes a lot of energy
the people who make pool room
dehumidifiers know this and they take
every last bit of energy from the
compression cycle
and they put it into the water using
special heat exchangers
now because the pools need so much heat
they literally have no incentive to make
their dehumidification process more
efficient
the more compressor tonnage they use the
more energy they can dump into the pool
why
fight it look the hvac industry has
better ways to dehumidify air
but none of those waves make sense to
someone building a dehumidifier for
natatoriums
now if you're asking yourself so what
the answer that question is
these rooms are still costing you so
much money and this isn't just about
energy consumption costs
yes running all those compressors all
the time leads to huge energy bills and
that stinks
but in an industry where cash flow and
time to harvest are so critically
important
ask yourself this how much more
electricity do you need to bring to a
building
where all the hvacd has 30 to 40 more
compressors than it needs
how long is your project going to get
delayed because the utility has to do
a huge infrastructure upgrade in your
part of the city
this isn't just big picture stuff either
think about what we see literally in
this picture
they're still running propeller fans
inside the room because the people who
shoehorn a pool room dehumidifier into
these facilities
maybe don't have the plant nvc they
should have they haven't focused on
getting the air where it's needed in the
room
this is a room filled with plants not an
empty room with a small lake at the
bottom of it
here's another challenge the conditions
in a pool room are about as constant as
you can imagine
but a proper cultivation hvac-d system
needs to perform optimally throughout a
vast range of conditions
think about the change in load when the
lights are on versus when the lights are
off
a flower room or a veg room isn't about
lowering the humidity as much as you can
all the time it's about keeping the
right level at the right time to bring
out the best of your plants
the bottom line is both integrated and
non-integrated and conventional systems
will lead to compromises
diseases show up in rooms because of the
interplay of a pathogen
a host and the environmental conditions
i'm not just trying to pick on pool room
dehumidifiers
we see server room hvac or 100 outside
air units
being applied and they have their own
whole host of challenges
but philosophically this is why the
starting point of integrated pest
management is cultural control
cultural control is environmental
control and if your environment is set
up correctly
you'll spend less time and less money
with physical biological and chemical
interventions
you're going to pull more and better
pounds out of your room
and so we land on the not so humbly
named inspire integrated hvac
system this is a system designed from
the ground up
with plan-centric environments in mind
the system is integrated i mean properly
integrated
control of the temperature and the
humidity control of the lights the co2
levels
even the room pressure for biosecurity
purposes
see this is a symphony controlled by a
brain that is married to equipment
designed specifically for the purpose of
enabling plant transpiration
now i could probably spend 20 minutes
telling you about how the run around
loop around our cooling coil
and inspire system will cut your power
bill by 30 or 40 percent
and if you're someone who's with utility
that's probably a big deal
but what's important if you're the one
responsible for actually growing plants
in a room
and what's important if you're actually
the one cutting a check for a project to
move forward
well maybe then the important part of
the story is
there's a good chance you can install
the hvacd
without needing that costly utility
upgrade maybe the important part is that
we can modulate
every one of the components responsible
for dehumidification and temperature
control
this means you can make sure your
temperatures and humidities are at the
level you want throughout the growing
cycle and day or night
not too hot not too cold not too wet not
too dry
how about if the important part isn't
the box outside the room
serving the air into the space what if
it's the forethought of a cfd model
before construction
to make sure the air you're sending into
the room actually makes it into the
canopy
the important part of the story might
not even be that it might be that every
minute
hundreds of data points from each room
cultivation to drying
are securely making it into the cloud
where you the owner or you the grower
can watch your rooms with one eye on
real-time performance
and another eye on historical trends
this isn't about a box moving in air
about a box moving air this is about
intimacy with plan
it's about intimacy with the
construction industry it's about taking
the process of transpiration so
seriously
you put in your company name so if you
do all these things right
you end up with a very different
triangle you end up
with a facility that actually lives up
to the promise
and you end up not using as many swear
words when talking about the air
conditioning system
it's the reason that hvacd as we do it
is obviously not a four-letter word when
the environment around the canopy is
conducive to plant vitality
without microclimates or in-room risk
factors like leaky condensate trains
you end up taking more pounds out of
that room than you otherwise could have
and every one of those pounds is
consistent enough to keep the top spot
on the shelves at the dispensary
where you've earned the trust to deliver
products you want now i'm not trying to
tell you that hvacd by inspire is going
to naturally earn you money
what i'm saying is that if you have a
room designed by people that have
cannabis intimacy
it's going to give you the ability to
grow a product that people will buy
and not just grow a bit of product i
mean you're going to be able to fill
that room
with healthy high demand plants was the
last time you saw a room with three
tiers of trays
layered into a 13 foot high space
so the heart of this into me starts
intimacy starts with data
and sizing your equipment right you need
to have real data from real rooms
that can help you with the task here's
an example of some of that data and the
simple formula we use to figure out the
point the peak
moisture removal capacity we need for
equipment serving space
quite simply we need to figure out the
peak pounds per hour of moisture removal
the hvac system has to provide so we sit
down with the project team and get the
master grower to give us the total daily
watering rate that is
gallons of water that are going to be
pumped into a room on a given day
we multiply that by the percentage of
moisture that comes out during the
periods
highest transpiration which is when the
lights are on then we divide that number
by the
number of hours of the photo period and
of course because we're
looking for a total because we're giving
a total daily watering rate in gallons
we multiply everything by 8.33 to
convert from gallons to pounds because
we're looking for pounds per hour
and obviously this number changes for
our international metric loving friends
who use liters
instead of gallons but i think you get
the point
the key to this whole equation is the
percentage of moisture removed during
the day
and to this day we invest a lot of
resources to get the data from live
rooms
this is a snapshot from one of those
rooms the blue bars represent water
transpired during the photo period
the red bars represent water transpired
or evaporated during the dark period
add them together and we can see the
total daily plant water consumption for
that room
but more importantly we see the ratio of
lights on versus 24 hour moisture
consumption
and this ratio is the percentage of
moisture removal
i referenced in the previous slide this
is the kind of knowledge that is going
to make sure you're not scrambling to
buy portable d hums that you have to
wheel into a room
three weeks before harvest but fair
warning look every room is different
different lighting technologies
different growing styles they're going
to have different ratios don't treat
this as gospel it'll bite you in the
butt
um feel free to give us a call we'll
talk about what it means to right-size
the equipment
for the facility you're picturing
okay look i've gone into a deep dive i
spent a lot of time highlighting the
features you get when you work with
inspire
but it's not exactly a sales pitch
you're going to hear from adrian
about how to make sure you've got all
your bases covered as you realize that
dream of a successful cultivation
facility
the features i've just mentioned bring
real value and most of them are
requirements you need to account for
your bids you're going to try and
compare multiple vendors
i hope you understand the limitations
that come along with purchasing a
variable truckload of mini splits and
dehumidifiers for a streaming price
and how that decision will ultimately
prevent you from optimizing the facility
you absolutely can compare apples and
oranges and grapes and pears
adrian why don't you take it from here
and show them how
thank you rob i hope what robbie just
went through resonated
and you can begin to understand why it's
not an easy task to compare multiple
bids against each other and it seems
easy to have a plan
of calling up you know one three five
different companies that offer
environmental control systems
ask for a bid review them in a couple
days and make a direct decision
around your design in the indoor
cannabis and horticulture business since
nearly every manufacturer approaches
this challenge differently this scenario
couldn't be further from the truth
now let's dive in and see if we can help
unmask
some of the details that it takes to get
to a point of a true
apples to apples comparison robbie just
walked us through the process to define
how to set expectations for your room
conditions temperature
and relative humidity and how generally
size your hvacd systems based on
moisture removal capacity
this is a process that needs to be born
from a collaboration between the
cultivation team
and the business team these decisions
have huge impacts on the type of
cultivation setup that you end up using
the lighting type you choose strain
choices
on and on and this is why we call this
step one
of a bid leveling process
once these key decisions are made you'll
be ready to complete a form like the one
you see on the screen
which is used to convey the design
criteria along to the manufacturer
mechanical engineer
and other project stakeholders
as discussed in my opening section there
are many different ways to go about your
project
but hopefully sooner rather than later
you're going to engage in mep engineer
to design your facility and when you do
so we come to step number two
ideally this is in conjunction with
hiring the other project team members so
that a true collaborative design process
can happen the coordination items can
get worked out early
and you can have your best chance at
bringing your project in on time
on budget and with the right parts and
pieces to allow you to be profitable
your mep engineer who has indoor
horticulture experience
does way more than just create the
drawing on the far right for
construction permit process purposes
they are an integral part of
coordinating the design elements of the
hvcd systems
between the other design consultants on
the project such as structural
electrical plumbing controls
fire protection these guys and gals are
problem solvers
just like us and as a team it is so much
more seamless to get complex decisions
made
like the ducting challenge as an example
shown on the screen
that's drawn with 3d cad to detail out
the all the pro
all the appropriate ductwork fittings
and insulation
that were required to get the air to and
from the cultivation room
and not lose any or gain any heat from
an ambient condition that can be
110 120 degrees in different conditions
in locations on a design day
since just about every design decision
has a technical fit or function
as well as a cost implication having the
rest of the construction team
involved early helps streamline the
process significantly
and true value engineering can be done
where the overall value of the project
to the owner
can be integrated into the design and
done so
for the minimum amount of overall cost
slightly different take on the way that
you normally hear value engineering used
but it's an it's an important way to to
approach these projects
now i say overall cost because the raw
hvac d
equipment or system costs that you get
from the manufacturers
only tell part of the story the
installation costs play a huge factor in
determining your total cost of ownership
for your project
and without the ability to quickly
determine what the installation cost
impact on a design decision will be
there is no true way to know your total
budget
going into construction and confirming
that you have enough funds available
now this brings us to step number three
which
while we know that all of these steps
are important this one may be the most
important of the bunch
how do you now compare multiple bids
that you've solicited
when it may be one of them may be a
chilled water hot water four pipe system
one of them might be an air cooled
package unit system
one of them might be a water cooled dx
system one of them could be a liquid
desiccant system
and how do you know which bid to select
all the numbers are different
do i take the lowest price do i take the
highest price what do you know do i take
something in the middle
uh well you really you don't have any
idea how to make that decision
until you consider the installation cost
impacts of each of these systems
in order to get a total capex budget
that's required
for your project we approach this
challenge with what can be called a bid
form and it's hard to read because
there's a lot of detailed information
crammed into one spreadsheet but we need
to know
a lot of this detail about the hvcd
system some of which
robbie touched on but many others
to be sure that the systems serving the
cultivation and curing rooms have all
the appropriate options required to
perform the duty
of proper environmental control now this
might be the right type of filtration
and air cleaning
included this might be the right type of
redundancies in different parts of the
system
and units maybe it's a room control
system that allows the cultivator to
focus on cultivation
and not monkeying with a thermostat or
feedback loop all day
maybe it's the right type of startup
processes commissioning
training spare parts sops associated
with mechanical part
failures is is the air cooled condenser
going to run at negative 40
in the alberta winter or 120 degrees
fahrenheit in the california desert
summer
the list is long detailed and honestly
pretty dull
unless you're an hvac d nerd like us
but every one of these items is
imperative for your facility
to operate in a way that allows your
plants to thrive
in your business to be profitable this
is why we're here for you
and why we work together with your
design and construction team to be sure
that all of the appropriate items are
included in the material bids
the installation bids and are
coordinated together with the design
team
if all three of those plates are not
spinning in the same rhythm
you are sure to encounter unforeseen
costs schedule delays
or both and although it is not normally
top of mind when selecting these systems
today
let's not forget operating costs and
potential utility incentives available
when deploying a more energy efficient
system
these may not be as impactful on
profitability in the short term
but will become much more important as
the market develops
and since we know that efficient and
sustainable facilities
do not need to cost more than standard
facilities
to build when working together with a
collaborative design and construction
team
why not be ready for that when the time
comes
this whole process takes intimacy acumen
and integrity to perform the
comprehensive apples to apples bid
leveling
in an ethical manner you might be
surprised that when you compare a
conventional non-integrated system with
an inspire integrated system
that the project costs are neutral or
very close
we look forward to exploring this
together now let's take a quick recap of
where we're at
we've set our expectations for how the
facility will operate in step one
we've brought in the right design
construction team members
and we've successfully leveled all of
those hvacd bids to determine which
partner to choose
let's make sure to note that the hvac
system is not the only
part of the puzzle that needs this level
of evaluation
choosing the right lights fertigation
system racks or tables
wall materials epoxy floor coverings
you get the long list here for your
business model
are all equally important however
nothing takes the place of investing
in the building blocks of your cultural
and environmental control
now that all those numbers are rolled up
into a total budget how did we do
against the estimated budget that was
said at the outset of the project
are we within the budget great and let's
move to step four
if not let's talk about some financing
options
we see three typical forms of financing
used in the cannabis space currently
with a possible fourth as a newcomer the
three that are most widely used
are equity financing where you offer
part of your business in exchange for
capital
traditional financing which may come
directly from a bank or indirectly from
a private source
based upon creditworthiness or equipment
leasing
these backs are a model that have been
around a long time in other market
segments and are making an entry into
the cannabis business space but are
really yet to be seen if they'll be
successful
we don't have a horse in this race
except to say that we can help connect
you with some different ecosystem
partners who we know
offer a fair exchange of value in the
end it is up to your team to evaluate
all your options carefully
read the fine print and make sure it is
a sound business decision
for you and your partners to enter into
keep in mind that in the cannabis
business most manufacturers require
significant funds up front and that you
will need your funds to be liquid at the
appropriate time
to be sure you don't delay your schedule
let's look at a slightly different
alternative to financing
and that is phasing your project there
are a lot of reasons why you might want
to phase your project
it allows for proof of concept the whole
measure twice
cut once saying really offers the
ability to gain
invaluable experience and reduce your
risk by biting off smaller pieces of the
dream
while you learn the systems that will
allow you to scale into the future
but most importantly this measure twice
cut once approach
allows you to preserve more equity and
reduce the capital raise
requirements ultimately you can maintain
more control over your future
by not having to raise 10 million
dollars to build out the whole facility
as an example
when you could start with three million
dollars get operational become
profitable
and then scale up you don't know what
you don't know
at the beginning of the journey and this
allows for failure
but not spectacular business crippling
failure
you know it could also be said and
called start smart
so you can scale fast
now that you have all of this out of the
way let's get on with awarding that bid
that you chose back on step three if
your project is fast track like many are
and since you chose a coordinated design
and build process with the appropriate
team members already involved
you easily have the ability to release
the long lead hvcd equipment
into production which can range from
three to five months from
time of order to the time that it's
installed started up and commissioned
depending on the particular system type
chosen
the design team can get you to the point
where enough coordination has been done
to minimize any impact that completing
the engineering
work quote on the fly might have
otherwise negatively influenced
now all that is left is executing on the
construction
which with the right team involved is
some pretty straightforward blocking and
tackling
but don't be so naive to think that
issues won't come up
they will you're just prepared to fix
them quickly
because the team can look within within
themselves brainstorm the best possible
solutions to the problem
and make sure it has minimal impact to
cost and schedule
easy right if only if it was that simple
challenges always come up on complex
projects
it's how your team approaches and fixes
them that will decide whether you come
out on the other side with the ability
to be more profitable
or less profitable based on what happens
no reason to dwell on negative
situations use them as opportunities
to look within lean on the team and come
out stronger
on the other side
now how do you know whether you have
built a profitable facility for your
business to operate
i'm glad that you asked the first step
is to harness
that data take your data and turn it
into metrics that you can use to
benchmark your business
and processes the most important of
these metrics will become the
kpis or key performance indicators that
your leadership team
will be tracking on a regular basis
increased plant productivity
and expression equals increased
financial metrics
in most cases it's important to focus on
the kpis that drive
business profitability things here like
grams per square foot
dollars per gram active compounds per
square foot
harvest cycles per year reduced crop
loss per room
operating cost per pound are all metrics
that will help
shape your business success also
important are other ways to offset
you offset capex via things like utility
incentives
and benchmarking your subsystems like
hvacd
and lighting as you see with pounds per
hour of moisture removal per kw
of energy or micro moles per joule on
the lighting sign
and as it turns out that these need to
be top of mind from the beginning of the
design
and construction process so that all the
decisions that are made along the way
have these goals in mind in addition to
these metrics and kpis
pursuing ways to reduce risk throughout
the whole process
will pay dividends for years to come
we talk about these metrics every day
with clients because they're so
important to focus on
if our hvac d systems can't make you
more money
why spend the money on the right system
we look at things like how does your
grams per square foot and dollar per
gram get impacted
as a result of better environmental
control homogeneous airflow and removing
unnecessary mechanical equipment from
inside a cultivation room
talk about reduction in ipm costs as a
result of better
cultural and environmental control
once your operational the race car has
been built so to speak
and now we're racing and it at that
point it's
what can be done to make that car faster
stronger
more agile what are the five or ten more
plant you know
what are five or ten more plants per
room worth over the course of a year
if it's determined your hvacd systems
and space planting can allow you to
stuff more plants in the room than you
originally planned
and still maintain stable room control
this is where the fun really starts i'd
like to wrap up with a few key takeaways
environmental control via hvacd
is key to any ipm or integrated pest
management
strategy different hvacd
system types provide varying results
it's very important to understand the
limitations and risk
of each type of system balance revenue
and risk with capex and speed to market
phasing and scalability and this goes
back to leveling the bids
using that bid form that we talked about
i want to mention it's very important to
engage your utility
early to evaluate potential incentives
this is a step that's often overlooked
and when it's when they're engaged it's
too late
to to have an impact on your project
you want to choose your partners with
care
and at the end of the day know that
cultural control
is the foundation of success all right
thanks adrian thanks rob
all right well let's go ahead and jump
into the q a now
let's see the first question i'm seeing
here are
what are the common pitfalls you see
with inexperienced construction teams
what are the pitfalls we see with
inexperience because i guess
uh you know from my perspective it's not
having a good understanding
of the peak moisture removal rate
that needs to come out of the rooms and
especially
different cultivation facilities um we
see them often
undersized as well there isn't
much um there's much forethought to the
different states of a room so a room
isn't always
full with peak transpiration happening
and you need to be able to deliver
hot air cold air dehumidified and not so
dehumidified air
at various different times so you know
that's that's from my perspective it's a
very
um you know technical engineering
challenge that we see
but i think there's also operational
issues too we see a lot of people just
dive in and they're trying to do 40 000
square foot boom
canopy uh right off the bat and this may
be their first time doing it at scale
and a construction team may be able to
execute that
but have you thought it through from a
people management side
giving up people to man those many
different rooms
and keep them operating at you know even
peak operational
capacity so or anything close to peak
you know really
since age you probably have other other
things to happen
i think those you got a lot of them i
mean it's
it's understanding you know having that
intimacy right and understanding
what it takes to to get the systems you
know the rooms designed properly
and then be able to execute on it
yeah yeah it makes sense it's a growing
cannabis is such a complex
multidisciplinary challenge
it's uh trying to try to bridge those
knowledge gaps
is is super important uh yeah
like the financing perspective right
even if you've got the construction
team to execute it and you've got the
the resources to design your rooms right
are you really going to want to outlay
all that capital
and uh not be able to turn turn prop
you know proper cash flow numbers um
with rooms that are operating
inefficiently you know why not start
small and go big
it's that phasing question or the
phasing topic you brought up age
now that's what that's an ex when we see
experience teams doing this they're
always phasing they never just
jump right in so um
yeah seems like it'll be it'll become
more and more important as uh
as the industry grows and more
competition comes in
and price compression sets in you really
it's
very important to make sure your your
cost structure is in check and
you're able to produce good product yeah
i'll throw in there just the sort of the
concept of trust but verify and
and the partners and really spending
time i mean i i talked through it
quickly in the presentation but um the
amount of time and care that should be
take taken in
choosing these team members is really
should be significant you know you're
you're pairing yourself with them for
six months a year two years three years
um mean
you really want to make sure that you've
got the right team from the beginning
to help preserve that capital as best as
possible
yeah fair enough uh
thank you guys another question uh
are there significant differences in
hvac d considerations between a closed
greenhouse and indoor facility
yeah absolutely you know in the
greenhouse space
you have different things you have to
manage lights and
lights especially so you have blackout
curtains and other technologies that you
have to take in consideration
you know the thermal load from the sun
is a huge
huge challenge so managing that um
you know most people may not most people
don't have the electrical
capacity or want to put in the
electrical infrastructure to do that
with closed
greenhouse species so um
i mean that's a webinar in and of itself
and it's a 40-minute discussion and all
the technical nuances
but one of the interesting things that
we saw at the last conference we were at
was the except for you know certain
parts of the united states where there
is a consistent amount of daylight
every single day throughout the year as
soon as you start getting into northern
climes
greenhouses start to become more and
more of a challenge there's a challenge
of putting heat into the rooms
because greenhouses are very inefficient
insulators so all this heat gets
radiated out through
the top of the building out into space
and so you have a whole different set of
challenges for heating at night than you
have
got it do your systems require
humidification in the beginning of the
flower cycle
uh no no but that's a great question
we've seen that happen before i mean
plants are
beautiful little humidifiers in and of
themselves
when you start to apply these brute
force or non-modulating compression or
dehumidifying technologies
or even you know try trying to use the
economizer cycle and bring outside air
in for that purpose
you can end up over drying the space and
that becomes like a spider mite
challenge it's a balance of
making sure you're cooling the air down
where it needs to and won't any further
so you don't have that dehumidification
problem it's a balance of airflow
and temperature and humidity control
that you know with a little bit of
forethought
you can you can get around that problem
and not have to go back
you see that happen all the time though
they're pretty cheap to install but it
becomes another thing you have to manage
you know you've got this this system
spraying water into
a room if the sprays nozzles aren't
perfectly maintained
droplets into our plants and now you've
got a challenge
just like condensate draining uh
condensates draining onto your canopy
yeah there's a lot of challenges luckily
we don't have that
with our systems the importance of
modulation
all right um
another one here are both the temp and
humidity controlled by one air handling
unit
i think that's a mean with one system um
yes we can use one air handling unit per
room we can do multiple per room it
depends on what the tolerance is for
uh redundancy um yes but
that's the point of an integrated hvac
so this is integrated because
temperature and humidity control
buy one piece of equipment uh typically
we're talking about bringing the air
below the dew point or sorry to the dew
point you need to maintain room humidity
and then reheating the air back up
before it gets back into the room
so that you can maintain the temperature
because often going all the way
that low on the dew point means that
you'd over cool the space
especially when you know the lights turn
off and you go into the dark period
because someone flips a switch
you have to have all those process in
place but yes our units do both
temperature and humidity control from
one piece
great another question here from david
can you touch briefly on the concept of
reheat coils for dehumidification
sure age do you mind if i take this one
absolutely either way go ahead
uh so reheat coils are
recoils come from the hvac industry
because
about i think it's 20 or 30 years ago
most energy codes around the world
mandated you could not use
new energy to reheat air after you've
brought the temperature down to get to
the dew point you need for
dehumidification
and so to get around this they were
using the energy from the compression
cycle and taking
hot compressed gas from compressors and
putting it through a coil in the air
stream and we call that
the hot gas coil and it saved you from
using an electric reheat coil
basically a toaster in the airstream
using new energy
um it's just more efficient you were
going to otherwise take that hot
compressed gas
[Music]
so that's what the typical reheat coil
is that we think of it comes in
different forms
if you're using a chilled water system
you might have a four pipe system and
you're taking
chilled water to get the
dehumidification done
and temperature brought down on the air
coming through the air handler
the reheat happens using the cons
conventional loop
so if you've got a chiller making
chilled water on one side
you'll be making hot water on the other
that you can use
as the reheat energy it's the same
philosophy you're not taking the energy
you have to reject anyways
the compression cycle correctly you're
putting it back into the airstream to do
reading
another one here from our friend
christopher lacey
how was peak transpiration measured and
how would you account for pruning and
canopy training
so many ways to do it if you've got a
grower with experience peak
transpiration is measured by
watching the level of water in your
tanks as you water from one day to the
next
and figuring out how much water you've
had to refill back into your tanks for
fertigation
and capturing as well anything that
you've trained and sent out to the
sewers so if you can watch that that's
probably
you know the most accurate way to figure
out how much water is going into a room
that ends up in the media and stays in
the media and is
transpired you do that for enough days
and you can figure it out
the more scientific approach the way
that i think the
guys with lab coats do it is they have a
transpiration test so they'll water a
plant
one plant out of a room or they'll take
the samples parts of the room
and they'll weigh the plant put water in
watch the run out
watch how much water stays inside the
root media
weigh that and then every hour they'll
come back and weigh that plant again so
they'll catch
the weight of the plant as it changes
over time and account for the water
going in and out
um that is a very granular and
scientific way to do it
um it's also very expensive i mean
there's a lot of people you're putting
into and out of rooms
there's a lot of measurements to be
taken we use a sensor system inside of
our units to figure out how much
condensate is coming out of our units so
um that's kind of an equivalent that we
found to be very effective and we can
using our particular setup we're within
5-10
in our rooms of what the growers tell us
they're actually putting in
through the fertigation system so it's a
pretty good number
um it took a lot of time to develop it
and it's it's not
exactly intuitive the way that we do it
um but we've been able to come up with a
pretty solid system and so every room
that we're in we know how much water is
being transpired
and so i it was it was in relation to uh
pre-construction
and so i think it's it's about the
question is more specific to
to pre-planning the uh the facility
and um so maybe you can talk a little
bit about about
a little more about the scientific
studies that we've done and the data
that we
that we collect from from the control
systems that we have deployed in the in
the field
for sure so i mentioned in my part i was
talking about
you know maybe one of the important
things is sending hundreds of points of
data every minute to the cloud
um the data we're collecting gives us
back from every room that we're in
with all the different types of lighting
and all the different types of growing
styles
it gives us a reference point for
whatever new project we're walking into
um i would say we've got it all 100
figured out i'm sure we'll run into a
growing system we don't know
um or we haven't seen before but we'll
come up with a good estimate
and they'll tell us based on a plant
canopy square footage number
how much transpiration we can expect
from that canopy
um it's it's funny but it's not about a
square footage it's actually about the
volumes but the volume of the canopy
some people grow high and wide they're
using lights that penetrate all the way
through these hps systems
those are different than the low
penetration we normally see
with led systems where you know maybe
the diodes are all angled straight down
and so we've got to trellis out the
systems and spread it out but the canopy
volume is a lot smaller
all these things add up and um we use
that we take that into account
as we come up with the transpiration p
transpiration rate we've gotta
maintain oh great and just just one more
um piggyback on that on that question um
how does how does uh pruning removing
leaves affect transpiration
you're taking stomata out of the room so
you're taking out
those pores those wet surfaces inside
the leaf
and it'll typically drop the
transpiration rate significantly
um but because we're watching the rooms
every minute
we know when we've got some really
interesting
uh things on a graph that we see we say
oh they just trimmed today
because the room won't go through and
the transpiration rate drops and we're
like oh they must just trim
and we'll see it climb back up as the
plants redevelop in different ways
and start to flower so it's really
interesting
uh data spray events right i can tell by
looking at a graph oh they sprayed today
in this room
because the lights turned off in the
middle of the day and the hvac system
worked to compensate and fix that
so um yeah it's it's basically
pruning leaves takes out the stomata
that are um you know that are directly
tied to the transpiration rate of the
plant
yeah awesome okay so on the
concept of transpiration and and water
um maybe uh there's a question here
about
what are the best methods to drain
humidity from a dehumidifying unit from
your grow
um maybe touched a little bit on
condensate capture
either way but i thought that would be a
great segue because there's another
question about
desiccant based systems and and uh
geothermal was mentioned in the question
um
but uh yeah i mean the ability to
have the condense you know we can not
only measure the condensate
and the water that's flowing out of the
units um but we're able to reuse that
and recapture that
the grower can and reuse for irrigation
if they desire
um and that's that's a benefit of a
system that has a condensate drain
and a you know a coil on it such that we
can
you can not only measure that amount of
moisture that's being removed
through that but you're also able to to
reuse it
which is if we were to want to use that
as a as a
point of differentiation against the
desiccant-based systems that are that
are out there
for the most part um where you're you're
really in effect blasting
out that um that hum that
moisture out of the space back into the
atmosphere um
and that's one of it's it's one of the
in our opinion it's one of the potential
negatives of a desiccant based system
um but there's there's a lot of great
positives of desiccant-based systems
from an efficiency perspective and an
air cleaning perspective and things
um very they're they're more complex
um and they you need to have all of the
parts and pieces appropriately designed
and constructed
and there's not a lot of good players um
out there that
know this really in the way
to fully control the rooms there's a lot
of sort of spot type units that are used
particularly in the greenhouse
environment um and in other in other
locations and really
in some of the some of the standalone
dehumidifiers that you see on the
marketplace
you may not even know that you have a
desiccant-based system um
in in your facility currently um if you
have one of those
um but it's uh you know we really
we see there we see pros and cons with
the different types of systems and
the ability to capture condensate reuse
that water to us is a big
big benefit um geothermal was mentioned
and i think it was
um i think what i mentioned was water
cooled dx systems so there's sort of
you there's so many different hvac
system types out there
and different ways to and this is sort
of a
a detailed question on the type of heat
rejection
mechanism that you would be using um
on the other side of the equation from
you know from the air handling unit
serving the space so
a water cooled dx system is typically
going to be connected to
a hybrid adiabatic cooler plant with
pumping skid
or a cooling tower plant or dry coolers
or some sort of
system like that whereas
a geothermal system you're actually
using either water
or the earth that ground to use as the
heat exchange mechanism
or heat exchange medium that you're
that you're using um and so
it's we can go into you know geothermal
in general is a much longer discussion
topic really and we can go into more
more about that um
together directly but um in general
i don't know that i've seen a geothermal
project um
personally in the in the cannabis or
horticultural space
um to date but it def i'm sure that it
can be done
it's just going to take a lot more
engineering to get there rob i don't
know if you have others to
add yeah so you know geothermal system
when i think about geothermal i think
about um
the whole point of geothermal is i'm
going to store
heat in the ground in the summertime i'm
going to take it out in the winter
and vice versa i'm going to take heat
out
in the winter i'm going to use the cool
water ground the ground effect
in the summertime and it just makes the
systems much more efficient
i don't know i haven't done the analysis
but if that really makes sense here
because the indoor conditions don't
change
in a well-sealed well-defined world so
we're always using that we're always
standing over the ground with our
loops so i just i don't
you know i i just don't know if they're
the right answer or not
it's a pretty involved design that we'd
have to look at
but uh welcome to challenge let's let's
figure it out yeah
it would take a detailed engineering
analysis really to figure out if that
if that's the right the right way to go
but site conditions
you know you know it's very interesting
in some cases you're able to
able to use resources around you that
could allow for it
another question that came in here is i
noticed a plastic
duct sock running through the tray of
one of your pictures
what's your opinion on the options
available for in-room airflow
i mean i think i said this at the in the
q a of another webinar we did maybe the
first one or the second one i'm not sure
i mean you just have to you have to get
air into the canopy
um oscillating fans on the wall
propeller fans they don't do a very good
job
and they're going to cause a lot of
stress wherever that direct blast is
hitting the canopy
so it becomes really challenging i think
the best system out there
is vertical air solutions it's you know
very consistent
it is well thought out and they put a
lot of time and effort into it
that plastic tube that we use i mean
we've we spent some effort
and resources figuring out the right
tube to use because we needed
some way to get that airflow through a
room because it is so important
and we would just have to come up with
the cheapest way to do it so
is it as consistent or is it as solid as
a
you know rack mounted duct i
don't i don't know um we have to we
haven't done a side by side comparison
yet but i do know that
our system works pretty well too and it
might be more cost effective if there
isn't a plan to use anything then go and
find something
i mean really it's it's a one to two
percent cost of the total project
to put those systems in but it makes a
huge difference
that's what i'd say about that yeah and
you can see it in the cfd modeling when
we run
when we run those models you can you can
in the model turn
on and off those in-rack fans um
and just see the path of air just going
you know
finding its way around the canopy rather
than through it
yeah i always think about thermostats on
the wall and humidistats on the wall and
how the conditions could be drastically
different between the those sensors and
what's actually inside of the canopy
that's right yeah we're huge advocates
of having the sensors right down in the
canopy right next to the plants
um you're really going to get you know
if that's that's what we're trying to
control to then that's where the sit
where those sensors should be
yep yep makes good sense
okay uh do you guys have a ballpark
price per ton for an inspire system you
can give us
age takes away
um i mean in general you know so first
off dollar per ton is a really hard
thing to
baseline around and we didn't hit it
quite as hard as we normally do earlier
on
uh in the prepared remarks but um
you know this is really a moisture
removal challenge
not an air conditioning challenge right
and tons of
tons of air conditioning in the way that
it's typically
typically thought of you know the funny
thing about it
you know in a refrigeration world tons
means almost
you know something a bit different i
mean you have a connection to horsepower
of compressor
um and things but um it really
there's so many different types of
systems that are out there and different
types of technologies that are used to
do the moisture removal
it almost really doesn't matter what the
tonnage is
that it takes any given manufacturer um
to you know require them in order to do
the dehumidification
at that given room condition and that
dew point
a combination of temperature and
relative humidity that you're trying to
maintain inside your space
so we we we like to assert that we use
pounds per hour
a dollar per pounds per hour of moisture
removed at that given condition
rather than dollar per ton um but we get
the question all the time
and it's important to know what it is um
you know
ours is typically in the five to six
thousand dollars range
per ton um but we're using the important
thing to note is that
we're typically using forty percent
of the tons compared to another brand
and so our dollar per ton may sound
really expensive
but when you baseline it against what
it's really going to cost
for that room on a dollar per pound per
hour basis
or just at the end of the day when you
get down to the bottom and look at the
total price
we're gonna be right there neck and neck
with another system that's
2500 bucks a ton or three thousand
dollars a ton
and we're talking about when i say that
we're talking about the entire
the cost for the entire system for that
room
right i mean we're not just providing an
air conditioning unit
shipping it out to you and saying good
luck go to it you know find a controls
contractor to locally to do it or
you know go find go find some in room uh
in
airflow devices and you know buy this by
and by that
this is a full complete system for that
room
um and so i think that's something
that's also overlooked um when you just
ask for a dollar per ton it's typically
referring to
oh just you know i'm just going to buy
that package unit and throw it up there
and
you know it's 1500 bucks a ton or two 2
000 bucks a ton
i was like well no at the end of the day
once you add in all these other things
you didn't have the right air cleaning
and the right filtration available in
there
you didn't have the right type of reheat
available and all these other things you
start to add up and that's
the importance of that bid form that we
talked about um but you start adding all
the rest of that stuff up and you're
going to get
close to or or above what we've just
shared
and we like to approach it with our
clients just from an eyes wide open
this is what it's going to cost total
full
you know for the entire system so that
your room's up and running
you've got pressure control in your room
the right type of odor
control for the exhaust um the the co2
life safety
purge that's required by code and for
for life safety purposes
you know all of those things are so
important why just like
leave those to to hope that they're
going to get uh
those holes are going to get filled on
the project um
when you can really can can scope it all
together
yeah i mean if you want to do dollars
per ton go to home depot and buy a 510
split system right i mean that is going
to be your cheapest dollar per ton
but it's the i mean it's the difference
between
non-integrated conventional integrated
conventional
and inspire integrated um i hope that i
made that comparison
clear enough i mean that that is really
the difference are you getting a unit
that's intended
for cultivation systems and cultivation
facilities
and has all those other features that
are going to make you so much more
efficient
and profitable
yeah yeah great seems like sometimes the
the cheapest option up front maybe
you're most expensive in the long run
iceberg right the ice cream iceberg
analogy
yeah everybody's doing shit right
right i got one coming in from amy brown
here
are there any specific state compliance
regulations that you've come across that
hinder the operational planning for
cultivation facilities
um she's asking from illinois this is
this is a great
a really great question um and it's it's
a moving target really i mean
you know we're just we're in the last
week or so reviewing the
california title 24 um
draft case report about the projected
2022 code
updates for california um which for for
anybody
involved in the building in construction
world
knows that most fairly progressive
states will take california's title 24
um and apply that as their energy code
and building standard
um as a sort of easy way to piggyback on
somebody that's already gone through and
done it
[Music]
and there's a lot we're very involved in
this i mean
so in general there's really almost no
codes and standards
saved for a handful around the country
massachusetts has a few
illinois has a few as amy's mentioned um
in the way that they've written it
but more and more jurisdictions need to
want to
get this done and so there's a bit of a
race right now i think going on
around industry with within industry
organizations
um and other stakeholders you know both
on the utilities side and the
you know public util public utility
commissions of the states
the utilities themselves the design and
construction professionals people that
are involved
from a cultivation perspective i mean
they're getting a lot of input from all
the different stakeholders which is
great
um but amy's somewhat specifically
referring to a code
that came out in illinois that wasn't
even part of their
building code from my understanding it's
part of their cannabis code
that basically specifies and stipulates
that you should be using mini splits
for your system smaller facilities and
vrf systems for your larger facilities
um you know and it's and it says or you
know
kind of in as an afterthought or more
efficient alternatives
um it's so challenging to see
uh jurisdiction take on a a particular
system type into their code you know it
should be a performance based type
metric
not a here you must use this type of
system type of an approach
because like we talked about we didn't
we didn't specifically mention vrf
variable refrigerant flow
systems earlier on in the different
system types but they're
they're there in that you know that
non-uh
non-integrated conventional type type of
scenario where
you're needing standalone dehumidifiers
so
in effect what illinois has done with
that scenario is they've
said this is the best way to do it and
when i think
in general we all know that yeah there's
a lot of like legacy growers that have
had great success
with that but that's coupled with really
robust
you know strategies around ipm
you know pest management control and and
the rest of the
other ways that they're able to to
mitigate their environmental challenges
um that ended up rearing their heads
through those
through those types of systems so it's
just really important i think for
for jurisdictions to understand as they
go into through this process that they
need to find
real world and performance-based um
things that you know that are that are
practical in the space um
we're involved in some projects in
illinois right now where um
you know our system is just going to
absolutely smash the performance
of that vrf system that they call for in
the code
um yet provide them like with a
significantly better
environment to work with inside of those
spaces and so it's
you know it's a bit of a win-win in that
perspective and hopefully we'll be able
to garner some
some utility incentives as a result of
it but um i do feel like that's somewhat
leading
many cultivators down the wrong path by
by
forcing that on them
thanks adrian got a got a nice controls
question here from
andy do you typically see all wired
sensors inside the canopy
or are wireless options available to
provide future flexibility in sensor
location
yeah absolutely we see a lot of wireless
options coming on the market
all of our sensors at this point in time
are wired but we're
talking to people and we can integrate
with anyone except we've got a sensor
array deployed by
one company that can communicate through
the modbus or the bacnet or some sort of
internet protocol we can pull that data
out and use it effectively
i have a bad taste in them all for
wireless sensors especially wireless
with sensors in a
industrial process type setting
we find that a lot of these rooms are
very busy they're noisy electrically
they get hit with spray from time to
time
and there's all sorts of challenges
there and so
i've seen them used and i've seen them
not work
and so to this day you know our systems
we send them out with wired sensors
i look forward to the day where we can
just use a wireless sensor and know it's
going to get
all the things it needs to from just
being wireless
i'll tell you one of the challenges is
we put all of our sensors in an
aspirated box for us
it is the most reliable way to get data
from the canon
i need to power a fan on a box that
sucks air through
so i don't expose the sensor to those
nasty industrial conditions
that power has to come from somewhere
now i don't have a solar panel robbing
lights from the plants
i have to run a power line to it anyway
to power the fans it just is either easy
to bring
multiple conductors over and get the
sensor data out
so i don't know that really answers your
questions there are options available
i can't i can't speak to any of them
right now about their efficacy
or whether i'd want to use them
okay well let's do one final question
and um and bring this presentation to a
close guys
um is there any chance we can get a copy
of your bid form
all day sure
yeah absolutely i mean it's um it
probably
would uh you would appreciate some
conversation along with it so that you
understand
um how how it really comes
you know comes together make sure that
you don't miss anything uh
through that process so yeah we would be
happy to talk you through that
um if you get in touch with us that's no
problem can i
just throw in there too um look it's a
big form that we've built
and we're hvac environment centric and
i'm sure that there are people in the
lighting industry who have
as much expertise and knowledge on their
specific field
that could highlight and include more
items in there you know we're looking at
the conventional integrated system
and we see all sorts of things in that
picture that we don't like like
you know there's a wiring hanging out
all over the building
you know that adds costs are probably
not captured in our bid form properly or
appropriately
but someone else with a little more
expertise in those areas for
you know wiring the lights we'll be able
to show you how you can save money up
uh save money up front in your
installation costs and end up with a
more robust
in the long run and tap us for that
network as adrian mentioned we have a
network that's
that's wide and deep and work with some
best brains in the industry so
i'm happy to share that too along with
that
fantastic fantastic great well
i hope that this last hour was
informative for everybody
and um really appreciate everybody
joining us again today
um if there are specific questions that
uh you have
uh or ones we didn't answer or answer
well enough
please feel free to reach out anytime
we're available
to to talk and and help answer questions
uh at any point so on that unless adrian
and rob have anything else
uh call it closed i think we're good
be safe wash your hands wear a mask as
applicable
and uh we look forward to seeing
everybody soon
absolutely all right thanks again