there seems to be a disconnect in this
industry um we have we seem to have a
weird line that's going down the middle
of this industry we seem to have people
that are fighting the fight working on
the rags working on the policy working
on the ordinances spending time with
State County City officials trying to
make sure that we all have Fair
Equitable and inclusive cannabis policy
going forward because let's remember
this is the first and only time Cali
will do this the first time so it's
really up to us to make sure that we get
it right as right as we possibly can
given the limitations and circumstances
that may happen um in in you know with
everything going on and and for how many
people in the room let's just quick do
show hands how many people in the room
keep up as much as they possibly can on
all of the rags and everything that's
going on right so it's about a third of
the room now the rest of you do are you
nervous are you scared are you is it too
overwhelming uh it's overwhelming CU I I
can understand that right so we have an
over how many people feel it's
overwhelming there we go that's about
the same amount of people some of the
same people that are fighting feel it's
overwhelming um so good okay so what I
wanted to try to do tonight is sort of
shine a light on The Advocates and the
nonprofits because here's the deal those
are the people who are making all this
happen those are the people who are
working hard with all of the the the
government at to make sure that there is
a solid foundation for businesses to sit
on top of and actually make money we the
other side of the coin is those people
who are in it for the money only or
they're in it for their own
self-interests and they're not
contributing back so we have a problem I
think we need to talk about it it really
hasn't been talked about that much I
really just want to commend everybody in
this room for showing up tonight because
I'm going to tell you I'm going to be
totally completely honest with you this
was a hard topic to get people in the
room for and it breaks my heart because
there's all kinds of people in this room
that fight every single day and yet we
couldn't get people here for this topic
we were joking about it that if we said
hey here's a way to make money in the
Cannabis industry we'd pack the room but
here we are saying no here's a way to
support the industry so we can all make
money hopefully one day as well and we
had we're pulling teeth to get people
here so thank you all for being here you
guys are the ones that we happy
about so I want to get I want to drill
down into that topic tonight because we
we have so many amazing people and
organizations that are out there every
single day making sure that there's good
policy that's it really simple and so a
whole bunch of them are going to talk to
us tonight we're going to we're going to
go through a whole bunch of speakers
you're going to get a really wide
picture of what this is all about if you
don't know you're going to learn a lot
and if you do know you're still going to
learn and so that's just really where we
want to go and I wanted to like stress
that that when you're talking to your
friends and you're talking to other
businesses Canabis businesses encourage
them after tonight after you listen to
what's happening encourage them to get
out there and support encourage them to
get out there and volunteer encourage
them to get out there and go speak to a
city council encourage them to get out
there and put money in if they have
money in to support some of these fun
these foundations I mean MPP is here in
the house tonight marijuana policy
project drug policy Alliance is here
tonight I know that these organizations
who are really doing some of the heavy
lifting they're struggling for financing
they're struggling for funding why is
that these are the people who helped
carry the the Baton over the line and
get us to legalization and yet we can't
seem to get them funded so and it's not
just them there's a lot of people who
work in this industry every day who get
no dollars zero dollars but they're
still going and doing it because they
believe that it's the right thing to do
so that's what we're going to talk about
tonight so I want to start with a couple
of quotes uh from some people that are
not here tonight and also one that I'm
going to read to you right
now so there's this amazing woman her
name is Susan Burton some of you may or
may not know her okay got becoming Miss
Burton I know some people in the room
know who this is um so Susan has this
amazing book she does a a re-entry for
uh women that have been in incarc ated
and are trying to go back into their
real lives she has a quote in this book
that I want to
read so so she's actually quoting
somebody else telling her this story
long time ago and here's the quote she
said they they said there was this book
I read as a child it was called The
Little Red Hen where a hen finds a grain
of wheat and goes around asking all the
other farm animals to help make get into
bread but no one will help finally when
the hen manages all on her own to make
the bread everyone who wouldn't help
shows up to eat the
bread welcome to the Cannabis
industry