[Music]
we'll just get started
okay hey everybody how's everybody doing
out there today
can you hear me in the back
all right y'all my name is joey berger
and uh we're gonna teach you two natural
farming inputs today
and this is from a system of farming
called jadam the book was up here
earlier it's not here anymore
but if you've heard of korean natural
farming this is a farming system
developed by the son of master cho the
founder of korean natural farming young
sencho and he took his dad's teachings
which are all about empowering the
farmer making farming simple
uh farming the way nature farms the way
nature builds soil and using plants to
make our own inputs our own fertilizers
our own pesticides and basically a way
to make the farmer
sufficient
empower them
give them their power back
these fertilizer companies they want to
make you feel dumb they want to make you
feel like you have to be a soil
scientist or you have to go to the
university you don't our ancestors
farmed very simply for eons
using plant plants and using human
manure and using animal manures very
simple ways of farming and
so
we love this jadom's type of farming
because it's very simple
the inputs we're going to teach you
today are so easy you're going to say i
can't believe i sat there and listened
to these guys talk about this so easy
and we like these inputs because they're
basically free
and
so what i'm going to teach you today is
called jms jadom microbial solution
and this is the one of the most
important inputs in this jadom natural
farming system because this is the way
to build the biology in the soil
the difference between dead dirt and
alive soil is the microbiology in the
soil microbes these are the invisible
workers there are billions of them under
there some are shredders and decomposers
a lot of them are are fixing nitrogen in
the soil making it available for plants
a lot of them are being uh eaten by
larger uh larger
critters of the soil and
they're they're being turned into
nitrogen as they go through their their
own gut microbiome
so
more than anything more than making
fertilizers more than making pesticides
the most important thing in natural
farming you should be looking at is how
to put the biology in your soil
and the different ways to do this are
this genome microbial solution
compost teas aerated compost teas and
compost tea extracts are another great
way to get that biology into your soil
and and you guys covered the imo process
a little bit in the last panel the
ferment cipher group talked about the
imo these are your indigenous
microorganisms this is a way to culture
microbes in the traditional korean
natural farming method
so
this jms we love it because it's easy it
can be made with water
a little bit of salt
a potato
and and a handful of microbes which is
this leaf mold soil that we're going to
gather deep in the forest i'm going to
take you guys deep into the untouched
forest here
where's my little pot
come with me
deep into the forest you have to get up
stay there
stay there i'm going deep
deep into the forest
picture that i'm going to the untouched
parts of the forest here oh look at this
oak trees over here so you're going to
want to pull back the
non-decomposed leaves
get get through that non-decomposed
layer of leaves you want to go to the
untouched areas of the forest where i
live the land's really steep it looks
like this so you go to a tree and you go
to that uphill side of the tree and the
leaves have been building up there for a
long time that's going to be the
thickest leaf mold so you're going to
pull back the non-decomposed leaves
and you're going to find those leaves
those breaking down leaves that are on
top of the soil we call this leaf mold
soil and the microbes from the soil are
starting to break that down a lot of
them are shredders and decomposers and
they're literally in there breaking that
down
and and to find the best stuff you want
to look for these white strands of
mycelium oh this is a jackpot you guys
you would have thought i planted this
over here for this demo but you want to
look for the white that white
that white mycelium
and these are huge colonies of fungi and
bacteria these strands of mycelium they
connect these plants these trees
underground and they can share nutrients
they can warn each other of pests and
passions pathogens so they can prepare
their defenses
so i'm gonna i'm gonna bring this out
here and show it to anybody that wants
to see this
the white stuff you know about this
right these are your decomposers your
shredders
your fungi and your bacteria right here
and so we're going to use this these are
our indigenous microorganisms we just
collected them they thrive here at this
temperature at this elevation this is
their home they know how to turn that
leaf into soil
that's their job so we're going to use
just a little tiny bit of that
i got i'd like to introduce you to my
friend r2d2 right here
this is a five gallon bucket it's maybe
a little bigger is this a seven gallon
bucket
this is the bucket that we use at home
to make jms and uh the jedom liquid
fertilizer and we do our feedings
through this bucket with a dosatron
so you've got your five gallons of water
i already filled it up because ain't
nobody got time for that
and we're going to
take
three ingredients salt potatoes and this
leaf mold
the first ingredient is going to be 25
grams of salt
i weighed this out already i hope i
didn't mix these jars for the weekend up
but we'll see
we're going to pour this in here now
you can use sea salt
or you can go to the ocean and gather
sea water
we're going to dissolve this in here
stirring it with a wooden stick you
don't want to use metal when you're
working with microbes they don't like
they don't react well with microbes so
i'm just dissolving this this sea this
sea salt in there when we go to the
ocean to gather the sea water we'll take
a bucket we'll wade out into the ocean
and you want to gather from those top
three inches so we'll just skim from the
top of the water that's where the most
uh diversity of aquatic microorganisms
are
is is where that uh that where that
water meets the air wherever you've got
an edge you've got the most diversity
you also want to gather that water near
the brackish waters where the river
enters the ocean you're going to get
even more diversity of microbes if you
can gather that water
so if you bring that salt water home
open that bucket up or that container
let it breathe overnight some of that
salt to burn off
and then you can use that sea water to
mix it in here did anybody
download the sop this week
we usually we bring them with and hand
them out but we didn't want to do all
the paper you did good job okay
these guys did okay good job then you
get to follow along the rest of you guys
are out of luck you should have followed
my instagram download the sop man we're
trying here trying to save paper
so
if you had the sop you'd see the
material list here five gallon food
grade bucket
we're going to skip the dilution tank
because we're not going to cover that
right now
50 grams of boiled potato
there it is right there
that little that little tiny potato
let's see what that weighs
96 grams
you can i'm going to use this whole
potato you can use more potato than you
want basically this potato is going to
be a food source for these microbes
they're going to be multiplying in this
water
and this water is going to tell us when
it's all done it's going to tell us when
these microbes are at their peak growth
so i'm going to take this potato
and i'm going to take this salt
i'm going to stuff this potato in this
sock you guys
it's kind of erotic
this is the erotic part of the show
right there
uh and then
i'm gonna put a couple tiny sharp rocks
in here that's just gonna make it a
little easier to bust up this uh
this uh
this potato anybody got a sharp rock
there this is the
part of the show where you guys
participate
there's not a rock on this property
you know what i really boiled the hell
out of this potato earlier i'm just
gonna mash it by hand
that's also kind of erotic if you've
ever squeezed a boiled potato it feels
great feels great
no we're good
so anyways we've got our 25 grams of sea
salt went in there we're stirring it up
here we go
yeah my man that's good that's good one
more boom
three sharp rocks just went in the sock
we're about to lose our sop we're all
over the place guys bear with us
good thing they're not filming this oh
oh i need that
okay
50 grams of boiled potato we went over
but the easy way to remember is 50 grams
of potato 25 grams of sea salt 25 grams
of leaf mold which is very little
so i've got my sock i'm going to show
you how little that leaf mold is
that's 16 grams
that's
21. use very little you're going to see
we're using just a small handful of this
there's our 20
25 grams
that's 26.8
so you can see it's a handful that's it
we're gonna use that's that's the whole
thing we're gonna use for this five
gallons right here
give it up for my lovely assistant here
she's gonna stuff this leaf mold in this
sock
it's in there already
oh this is a two two-man job okay this
is the erotic part
don't don't watch you guys don't watch
this part
okay
you wanna tie that off for me please
get it out of your hair please okay
okay so now
we've got
our sock
with our potato
with our leaf mold in it
and if we were going to culture crop
specific microbes say for like cannabis
at this point we would go and grab a
couple of leaves off of that cannabis
plant we'd throw them in this sock also
because you're now you're going to
encourage microbes that like cannabis to
get in there and start cultivating to
start inoculating this so
if you're growing if you're growing
tomatoes throw a couple little leaves of
the tomato plant in there if you're
growing potatoes grow a couple little
leaves of the potato in there if you're
growing cannabis throw a handful of
ganja in there just the leaf just the
veg leaf will be fine
um
so i got my sock
and we've got
our bamboo stick we already
we already watered this in
what's nice about the jms too is like
once you do it enough that you'll get
those measurements in your head and then
you don't even have there's no need
after a while to measure like especially
your leaf mold just go grab a handful
and it's not like and then if you get
too much if that's okay it's no big deal
the same thing with the potato if you
get too much it's okay the one thing to
be really um consistent with is your
salt water your either your sea water or
your salt to make sure that that is like
really exact but the rest
it's okay
yeah seawater has 93 uh micro
micronutrients in it minerals so
seawater is very good for your garden
you want to work that into your garden
where you can it's a free input not that
close to the ocean here but it's worth
the drive to the coast
so we've got our sock in there now what
i'm going to do is i'm going to massage
this into this water i'm going to
massage that potato remember we put
those sharp rocks in there that's going
to help break that potato up i'm going
to massage the leaf mold i'm going to
massage the microbes out of that sock
into the water
and tomorrow's going to hold the
microphone for me
work it yeah do it
so
the one thing you got to make sure is
you need warmer water when you're doing
this this won't work if your temps are
under 64 degrees i've made three of
these this spring already my first two
were great slam dunk but we were having
hot weather and my last one that i made
about a week ago during that cold snap
total fail i even started it in the
greenhouse where it'd be a little warmer
it wasn't warm enough
if your water is really cold and it's
underground fill up your back fill up
your bucket the day before so that water
will sit out be a little warmer
sometimes i will cheat and use the warm
water from the hose that's been sitting
in the sun if i know this water's really
cold i'll heat it up you know put a
little bit of that in there
in hot warm weather this is going to be
done in 24 hours we're in lake county
it's hot there in the summer
it can be done really fast cold weather
those first ones i made in february and
march they took about a week they could
take up to five days seven days
when you make this in hot weather
you're going to get a lot of big bubbles
and when you make this in cold weather
you're going to get small bubbles and
what i'm talking about there is how we
know this is done how we know this is at
its peak microbial
growth uh
i'm going to massage this in here
i can feel this potato getting all
broken up i can feel the leaf mold this
water's looking a little grayer
i've rigged i rigged this up with a
bamboo steak so this will uh sit right
in the middle this this uh
this bucket
and the vortex of microbes that you want
to hang in the middle because there's a
whole vortex of microbes that happens
there and they're able to multiply
faster if this is in the center and also
the way you know this is done is you're
going to get tiny bubbles are going to
start coming up around the edges that's
where you're first going to notice them
and then these bubbles are going to get
bigger they're get more vigorous and
when this is at its peak growth is when
the whole top of this is covered with
bubbles a solid pizza is what we like to
say
and um
and you have about a 12-hour window when
it's at its peak growth so in hot
weather you'll check it in the morning
be like oh it's not done and then it's
you didn't check it in the evening it's
done it's over the hill the next morning
the way you know it's over the hill is
the bubbles will have started to break
up they'll start pulling away from the
sides of the bucket and those bubbles
will start breaking up those are your
microbes starting to die off they've
reached their peak growth and they're
dying off you can still use this as a
liquid fertilizer at that point you
could still dilute it and use it but
it's not going to have the the diversity
of microbial life in there that we're
really looking for
so yeah when this is at full pizza shell
i know when it's done that's why we
prefer this over doing an aerated
compost tea where you have to brew it at
a certain temperature in a certain
length of time and you need to scope it
to make sure it has the life in it this
is telling me when it's at its peak
growth that's why we like it that's why
it's this is so available for any farmer
to do this on their farm you saw what we
used here today anybody got a five
gallon bucket at their farm
okay you guys are well on your way to be
natural farmers you already got the
basics you know the essentials
um
so yeah we massaged that in there i'm
just going to run through the sop for
you guys a little bit
um
at this point you're going to loosely
cover this with your lid and just leave
it in the center of your garden in the
sun and this is you want it in the
garden where you're going to use it
because the microbes that are there that
are present are going to start culturing
they're going to start multiplying you
know these are your indigenous
microorganisms you want to capture them
use those ones
yeah if your water temperatures get too
low you can put a water heater in this a
little like aquarium water heater and
heat it up that's all easy way to do
these in the winter time
um
when we go to feed this
we will dilute this if we're if we're
feeding empty beds that aren't planted
no plants in them we'll dilute this 10
times into into water so this will make
50 gallons this five gallons i put into
a 50 gallon drum of water and then feed
that if i'm pumping it through drip
systems or hoses i flush those lines for
a good five minutes with clean water
afterwards you'll get microbial buildup
in there and things can get gross so
flush those lines
if we're if i'm watering beds that are
planted or nursery plants stuffed with
the gongz in it right now i'm diluting
it at 20 to 1.
no no nothing no um no plants in the
soil 10 to 1. so this would make 100
gallons i fill up that 50 gallon barrel
twice with it
if you're going to
move this with a pump
low pressure pumps are better
diaphragm pumps are best and if you
start pumping anything with high
pressure it's going to shred your
bacteria and your fungi and start
beating your microbes up and kill them
so
pumping them one time through a low
pressure pump in your drip system or
into your dilution tank not a big deal
don't use those pumps to aerate these
things you're just going to shred them
get it get a low pressure diaphragm pump
if you can
um
when we go to feed this this also mixes
well with the jadom liquid fertilizers
that tamara is going to teach you next
so i will i will combine the liquid
fertilizers into a feeding at the same
time that i'm doing these microbes but
really this is the most important thing
in our system if we have enough biology
and good microbes in our soil we don't
need to feed as much we don't need to
fertilize as much we don't need to water
as much
this is why the forest functions the
forest doesn't need to be watered it
doesn't be fertilized this soil is full
of microbial life that's performing its
functions and when that's vacant is when
you need to is when you start having the
pests and the pathogens come in
when there's good biology in the soil we
say there is no good and bad you just
have a healthy balance it's only when
things get out of balance that do any of
these things become a pest or a pathogen
they're all present all the time but we
need them in balance so when we do
farming that mimics nature these natural
practices a lot easier to stay in
balance with everything
so
uh when i'm done i'll also wash out my
sock i rinse out my sock i use a 100
cotton sock because the microbes will
actually break this stuff down so don't
use like a a
synthetic sock or anything
it's best to apply this in the evening
to your soil this way your soil will
stay moist longer you want those
microbes to be able to get a foothold so
water in the evening or even better
water before a rain and then the rain
will water it down in the soil take it
deep down into the soil that's what you
want
this stuff is so safe and so beneficial
you could do it with every watering
every single watering if you did at
those dilution rates
we try to do it at least once a week or
at least every other week and when we do
that we're alternating the other week
with a compost tea ex with a compost
extract which you'll probably talk about
that to you
and it that's a very simple easy way to
get some biology in your soil so we're
just making sure that every week we're
adding a different set of biology our
soil diversity you hear us talk about
diversity a lot we want a diverse set of
microbes so
uh you guys just just heard the biochar
talk over here we've used this jms to
charge biochar also once you make that
biochar you need to get the microbes up
into it to establish jms is a great way
to do that we've made big windrows five
you know six feet wide five feet tall
i did this at a farm last year we got 80
yards of biochar that we had to charge
and we used jms and we used pond water
that was full of aquatic microorganisms
and we used the compost tea and we used
genome liquid fertilizers but
at the very least you guys you should
apply this to your to your soil three
times a year
once in the springtime before you plant
which should be at that ten to one
dilution
once uh before you go into flowering
during transition time as you're going
from veg into flower if you're going
full term that's you know end of july
somewhere in there
uh at least over by us probably same
here
and then once again before you put your
beds away for the season once again
before the winter rains come or right
before that winter rain comes so
i hope you guys learned some things here
this stuff is very simple
uh when we make this in a 50 gallon drum
we do a pound of potatoes a half pound
of sea salt and a half pound of leaf
mold i mean those are some really easy
numbers to remember
you can still go online on my patreon at
the link on my bio at the humboldt local
2.0 on instagram there's a link there to
my patreon you can download these sops
for free there so please go grab those
and let us know yeah anybody got any
questions
say again
i live over in lake county
oh yeah yeah we live in middletown
come to the farmers market
what's up
cold water is the biggest one a lot of
people are messaging me right now
they're trying to make them in this
springtime weather it's just too cold um
yeah that water needs to be 64 68.
i would either either fill this bucket
up ahead of time the day before let it
sit out
black plastic could be good
oh yeah so this is why this looks like
r2d2 i wrapped this reflective
insulation around this you guys could
wrap a blanket around it would help
anything like that would help insulate
this bucket bring it in your greenhouse
if you got really cold weather you know
that's what we did for a few days
um yeah great question trent yeah
anybody else before i turn this over to
tomorrow
tomorrow's going to talk a little bit
about this as well because these two
inputs really tie in well together so
i'd like to introduce tamara thorne
owner of heal thyself gardens a dem pure
certified farmer
and my sweetheart
and she's going to talk to you about
jadam liquid fertilizer give it up for
tomorrow y'all
awesome thank you
joey um yeah so a couple things i want
to mention on the jms is like because
you all over here in grass valley north
san juan are very similar to our growing
environment that we have in lake county
it's really hot so
we said 24 hours sometimes i've noticed
on 100 degree days 104 degree days it's
like 12 hours so
check it because i have had that happen
before and that's those are really like
it's kind of rare but that's like it has
happened so just kind of check them on
those really hot days
um
and this is i don't know if any of y'all
know what sea green is y'all remember
y'all know that stuff
yeah well this would replace your sea
green like this is what like when i
first found out about this i kind of
like blew my mind because i was paying
800 a bucket for sea green and i was
understanding what they was trying to do
like this microbial life
but then i started understanding like
once i learned how to do this
then i realized that probably all that
stuff i've been feeding my plants out of
that bottle really wasn't alive
and probably had already died because if
you're taking microbes from another
environment especially from the sea and
stuff and you're bringing into your
dry environment it's not the same
microbes so they're going to die off
really fast and if they don't they could
start attacking your your ones that are
there and that's not what you want you
want your native um indigenous
microorganisms to be in your garden
because that's how your garden's gonna
thrive
so those are some things to be aware of
and how like when i found out about this
like it was pennies compared to those
buckets i was buying i mean it was it
was yeah i couldn't even believe it
but we love this stuff it's amazing and
you just do it you know once you do it
over and over it becomes really routine
and it's super easy and then you get the
hang of it and you start realizing your
temperatures and how to you know you
just do it more practice makes perfect
but they're really simple
um the one i'm going to talk about is
the jadom liquid fertilizer
and this is your liquid fertilizer that
you can make with plant material animal
wastes
um
also it when just water and leaf mold
so your first thing that you're going to
do like what i've got in this bucket is
your five gallon bucket
you need some plant material we're going
to talk about plant material first and
then i'll go into the animal manures
um
and so you get your plant material
you're going to harvest a bucket full
and i didn't finish the bucket because i
wanted to show y'all what i like to do
um so some of these pieces too like when
i'm harvesting you see how these are
dried i just kind of take those out
because you know we're looking for
nutrients so that's something when
you're looking for your plant material
to harvest
you want it to be alive and fresh and
look really you know healthy
um
so we're gonna take off some of that
right there
and then you're just gonna cut like your
plant material into about like i'd
do two to four inches
and
yeah sure
just doing two to four inches here
just cut and so i usually just harvest
and then if that's anything that's dried
i'll just cut off
and just do it directly into the bucket
i really like to not have so many steps
so if i can just harvest and then just
put it directly into the bucket makes it
easier
and so then you want to fill your bucket
up to where like i've tried to fill this
all the way full and then where when i
press my hand down it's still hot like
it's still there you know there's not
much give
and so after this is filled then you
just fill it with water
and
leaf mold
and that's it
so we're going to put this leaf mold
over the top
now
if i had some water over here then we'd
put water over it put a lid on it and
boom you just put that in your garden
and that's it that is your liquid
fertilizer and so on the plant material
i know we have it on our on the sops if
you downloaded there's a few different
things about the plants
um
not too much on here though
but like right now what i went and did
is i did a grass jlf
yeah and the grass jlf is going to be
for your veg
and so what i went and harvested is
anything that was still vegging like
anything that was like already flowering
these grasses over here i kind of had to
go search because some of these are all
flowering
about to go to seed and so those would
be really good during transition or
flowering fruiting times
so the grasses i went and got i had to
um hunt down some miners lettuce and
just some of the other taller grasses
which is nice because you want stuff
that's like have a lot of growth
hormones
so i wouldn't got the taller grasses
nothing that's gone to seed
and then this jlf if we make this now
we'll be ready in about 10 days
and that that's going to be filled with
nitrogen it's also going to be filled
with any of these micronutrients from
the soil that's here
um but this is a really basic one we can
get a little bit like more in depth like
you start knowing your plants you know
your nettle your nettle has a lot it's
very high in nitrogen you also have
calcium iron magnesium it has a lot of
nutrients in it so
every year i like to get like a 50
gallon
barrel of it made and just do all nettle
because that nettle is really good
during veg
and then also
you're comfrey comfrey's another high
one in nitrogen so all comfrey one
borage borage is i think it's potassium
for that one
so
they're in transition they're so it's
like you know in your plants
what
is in those plants and kind of do some
research into that because like borage
and mugwort high in potassium
that's really good during transition
time
then we have like anything that's
fruiting or flowering is really good
during of course flowering and fruiting
time so any of your apples coming out
any of your fruit trees blackberries
um
you know just anything that's fruit and
flowering we do a lot of sunflowers
sunflowers are really high in phosphorus
so when they're all like in their flower
set about to go to seed to harvest them
and put them in your
buckets or barrels
that's a really good one
um
other pla at all parts really like the
the veg time it's gonna be just anything
that's veggie but it's the whole plant
except for the roots we leave the roots
so it can kind of come back
um
but like if it but then once it's
flowering you're wanting to take it like
if these all these grasses start
flowering like i'm saying here right
here now this is good because it's not
seeded yet so this would be good during
transition once it's seeded then it's
really good during flowering and
fruiting time and so any of your flowers
you can start gathering spring flowers
now too that can go in for your um
flower teas
so let's see
and
i'm thinking about some others yes
cannabis of course we
prune i prove like one of our big prunes
we do is during transition and so of
course it's the best tea during
transition we immediately you know we go
inside and clean out those girls
and you have at least a 50 gallon bag it
depends on how many plants you got at
least a five gallon bucket of all that
and then that's we just turn that into a
jlf you know fill that up with water put
the leaf mold on it and ten to 10 days
it's ready to go
um anything and it's like that with any
of your anything that you are growing if
that's tomatoes if that's peas it's
squash that plant is gonna be the best
thing to feed it so squash is great to
feedback to squash
cannabis back to cannabis you know it
just goes like that because that plant
has everything the nutritional needs
that that plant needs to grow
um
horsetail horsetail just went and
harvested really high in silica that's
really good for structural support of
your plants so i like to add that in
like pretty much through at owl and it's
another one too that that's another
thing we teach to make is a um
herbal solution that we make out of the
horsetail which is really good for pm
so horsetail is amazing like if you can
find a good horsetail spot go harvest
because it's also good for you too
nettle and horsetail are two of the best
things for our plants but also to the
best things for us also because it's had
so many minerals and vitamins and silica
it's just like packed full of nutrients
that we need as well
so that's the thing with the plants i
mean it's really you can use your
intuition with if you see something
flowering like um milk thistle is really
nice right now before it flowers use it
for veg it's just filled with nutrients
plus it has growth hormones that stuff
is powerful you know you look at those
plants see like how fast does it grow if
it's growing really fast take that
that's growth like hormones in there
um the milk thistle once it starts
flowering great for flower tea
um let's see and then with your animal
manures those of course we're really
great for nitrogen i like to do my
strike i tell like a nitrogen shot is
what i do with the chicken manure so
i'll fill either a 50 gallon barrel up
or a five gallon bucket depending on how
much i have
and i love to start the year with like a
50 gallon barrel of chicken manure
and then we just fill that up and i'm
not and
you don't need to fill it all the way up
for the manures the manures you're gonna
do about like i do about a third of the
bucket for the manures
and sometimes that's a little much
sometimes you can do about a fourth but
a third i feel like it gets a good
strength on there and the same thing
fill it up with water put your leaf mold
and
then wait for about 10 days
and one thing to know if your jlfs are
really stinky because they will they'll
become smelly and you're like oh my god
is this thing rancid yes it is
but it's okay it's supposed to be that
way um but if it gets too smelly for you
we're just like i can't take this put
some more leaf mold in it or some
mushrooms i've even used mushrooms that
have gone bad out of the fridge and just
stuck mushrooms in it and it seems to
like really start breaking it down
faster and the smell goes away
so that's just a little tidbit i found
out
um trial and error
and uh
let's see and so you can also use some
of your stuff you'd use for top
dressings like kelp or oyster shell
and you would do the same thing you'd do
with the animal manures do about a third
to fourth down the bucket and then same
thing again fill up with water in your
leaf mold
and you're gonna want those to be in the
same temperature like with your jms you
want that right by your garden where it
all the microbes everything's breaking
down at the same temperature that your
garden's at so we're brewing all those
microbes that we want
and um
yeah i mean we go through this to make
sure another oh another really good one
is blackberry go get that blackberry you
know it's overtaking all of our places
and it's really good it's another growth
stimulant like that stuff is powerful it
can break through anything and it grits
it's strong
so put feed that to your plants that
right there when it's vegging that's a
great veg it also when it is fruiting
but not ready yet
take that for transition so any of your
fruits that are unripe that's another
thing to use during transition
and then of course the blackberry you
can use when it's all the way fruited so
that one's really nice you can kind of
use it through all stages and it's
really helpful
and we're going to take these and we
usually use these at about a 30 to a 1.
this one's our the grass we usually do
about a 20 to a 1 just depends on how
much nutrients are in the things you're
doing but usually my gauge is about a 30
to a 1 on everything
and the things with these
liquid fertilizers is that they don't go
bad they'll just get stronger
so if you've had one and it's over a
year then you're going to instead of
doing a 30 to 1 you're going to do 60 to
1 because it's going to be stronger and
so every year you're going to cut it
down a little bit more depending on how
long they've been brewing
um
what else am i missing anything
in natural farming we have what is
called the nutritive cycle theory and
that's what tomorrow is talking about
fast growing leafy green shoots for veg
unripe fruits and flowers for transition
and ripe fruits flowers and buds for
fruiting and flowering it's very simple
so these inputs are important to make
seasonally we go out right now while
things are in veg we go out and gather
the miners lettuce we go out and gather
the dead nettle that was only out for a
little while the horsetail is just now
starting to pop get out in the forest
and start to know your land start to
know what these plants are seasonally
they're going to tell you what should be
feeding these things this time of year
that blackberry every farm we go out on
to consult they have blackberry that's
the easiest ferment we could all be
making right now those fast growing
green shoots
make fill up a 50 gallon barrel throw
again throw a couple gallons of leaf
mold in there that's all you need
through these others like you can use
your urine oh yes go ahead
we'll talk about that in a bit
what was that
no anything that's like already um dead
you would you can use that for compost
or mulch it's really good for that but
because you're wanting the life out of
that anything that you know whatever
that you are um putting in here you're
taking the life out the mycelium you
know is like kind of liquefying it for
you and then you're gonna strain that a
really good um
220 micron um what else is some good mic
some good microns i use some of my old
hash bags
or there's just a bunch of really good
um filter bags i found on amazon even
that kind of go over your whole five
gallon bucket kind of do a little fun
research on that
and then that just makes it really easy
for you to strain because you can strain
it enough where it can go through your
fertilizer injectors and all of your
irrigation and this like you said after
where we do it through the irrigation we
do rinse it you know through which is
straight water because this can get
really stinky
and we do add these two together a lot
is the jms and the jlf the jlf is like
what you would use instead of like your
feeds you know when you're doing bloom
veg all that kind of stuff instead of
having to buy those at the grocery store
you're making your own that's what this
is replacements of this is what this is
for
and this is a really old technique like
i've even found it in my herbalist books
like really old texts where they're just
like grab the plant material fill it
with water put in some um like i think
mushrooms and i was like i held in a
couple books and i was like wow that's
really cool and some of them didn't even
stay put my ceiling was just like a
bucket and
plant material so this jadam liquid
fertilizer this is just an ancient
technique that we're you know we're
taking from indigenous people and from
our ancient our ancestors
um
oh okay so i was going into our urine we
can also like pee in these buckets as
well and then you can put leaf mold on
it and after six months you can use this
and that is just straight nitrogen
that'll just give a good shot you're
going to want to give other things too
but that night that will be a straight
nitrogen shot for those plants
um
we haven't done any humanure at lunch
yet but they're half but people do
but we have done horse manure uh chicken
manure goats you know all of these
others that i love rabbit i love rabbit
manure that is one thing that we um our
main animal that we're having on our
farm because it's also high in
phosphorus potassium the nitrogen it's
it's a really good one you can use all
the time and you can put it directly
onto the soil you don't have to wait for
it to compost
so that one's a really good one
but yeah this is our our some of our
things that we do at the farm the jadam
liquid fertilizer we have 50 gallon
barrels like a ball by our gardens and
then we have tons of different buckets
because sometimes we'll like go on a
little um
mission to the ocean and go vet and find
fish like at the old fish cleaning
stations and they'll have like just a
bunch of bones and just grossness and we
get excited we'll go fill some five
gallon buckets with that fill it up with
water and put some leaf mold on it and
then put it and some place that we don't
have to walk by very often for three
months and then it's ready that's like
your fish emulsion
and then we've also done kelp we've gone
and harvested stuff at the ocean and
done the same thing with and also oyster
the mussel shells
we've done oyster shell
um
yeah
oh
yeah so the dilution rates on this it
kind of depends it's just about like you
want to start
at about a 20 to one depends on how long
it's gone for so the least amount of
time is usually about 10 days and then
you kind of check it and see if it looks
like it's it's kind of done its thing
but usually about 10 days
is you can start to use it but the
longer it goes the stronger it gets so
at 10 at 10 days do it out at 20 to 1
and then like i said as it gets stronger
i usually do everything at about a 30 to
one but they've usually been gone going
for at least a month
or more
and
so if you look at your your sheet you
can kind of see we have some different
things like urine you want it to go for
six months for at a 50 to one your fish
wastes at a hundred to one
you can use quartz horsetail is a twenty
to one most of your plants start out at
a twenty to one
and um
the manure the chicken manure is also
another one that
i have done it like we have it right
here where you want it to go for a month
but i have done it and like 10 days it's
just not as strong
but i've had to use it and it works okay
but the month it makes it really strong
if you can let it go for that long and
that's at a hundred to one
and then after the buckets or the
50-gallon barrels are emptied after
we're done with that we don't clean it
out or empty them you just leave that
old plant material in there and let it
just keep breaking down and then you're
just gonna pile on more material and
then fill it up with water again and
leaf mold and you can continuously keep
doing that because eventually that old
stuff completely liquefies and then it
just
keeps happening so we never clean like
these buckets out when they've like been
designated as our jlfs
and we don't have to
um
yeah okay is there any questions on this
any more questions yes
warhound
i haven't used horror hounds for the
jlfs just only because i haven't found
that as much of it and when i find it i
usually use it for my smoking blends i
love whorehound it's a really good
expectorant
oh that's awesome good to know
i'm thinking horror
yeah in horror hound it's like a it's in
the mint family and it's more of a it's
a smellier herb
and so it would be good as a jadom
herbal solution it could be good as a
pesticide because we're going to
concentrate that and then it would go
into the plants and i think that would
be a really good jhs that's what i would
use that one for
yeah
um there's a lot of different plants you
just look around your grasses your
miners lettuce your cleavers um like i
said the net any of these spring grasses
that just came out we're now kind of in
the late spring so now i like to look
around for like the flowers and the
flower and the other spring flowers that
are blooming and summer flowers and i'm
starting to start making the bloom and
fruiting ones
and then transitions will come soon too
as the fruits on the trees are just
starting to come out
and so we'll start on those after we
start pruning the trees a little bit
and so what's really nice about this is
it's like you follow the growing season
like it's very organic it's not like
okay this is what we're doing today and
we've got to get it all done you can't
you have to really follow nature oh it's
springtime now it's time to get the
grasses for veg okay oh now we're going
in transition oh now we're going into
fruiting and so you just kind of follow
with nature
and it's just a very organic system of
working with it so
okay
yes
actually yeah we've known some people a
a friend of mine did a rat
i was like okay yeah yeah just same
thing but i would put a lot of leaf mold
in um but in water and put it somewhere
you didn't have to smell but yeah you
definitely can
[Music]
all right shaw yes what was so beautiful
about these two things we love showing
them because they're so easy like i
literally just went out and harvested
the grasses the horsetail and you just
the water and you can see the leaf mold
the leaf mold here is incredible
and some of your drier regions of course
where we don't have as many oak trees
out where we are and it's like you said
we kind of have to go up on the upper
side behind the trees we kind of have to
get down far in there
but i've also seen two in really dry
places you don't always see the white
striations but you know that they are
actually there because like you kind of
just as long as you get past the top
leaf level
layer then you will find some even if
it's just a little white on par of the
leaf then it's there
so yeah
all right love that's great any more
questions
yes
yeah definitely
i usually i'll just fill a bucket up
with the um unripe fruit the same thing
within the water and the leaf mold
mm-hmm
yep
yeah um i will do separate sometimes
depending on what the nutritional needs
of the plants are and also if we got to
go to the ocean and harvest something or
if we found something but i also create
we also create
like multiple plant ones like i have um
barrels set aside that are veg
transition and flowering
and those are 50 gallons i have 250
gallons of each
um actually more at this time but then
um
those are all multi and so like the veg
i'll go and take from we went and did
mala we had a bunch of mala we harvested
a bunch of nettle and then a bunch of
just spring grasses we had alfalfa from
the straw we had late or hey we had laid
down before
and so we were able to harvest all that
and put it together i think some milk
thistle was in there
and so it's kind of like whatever you
got
and that's what i do for our veg and
then i'll do um
certain ones like i said just little
specific ones
depending on what i'm able to harvest
and the same thing for
transition and fruiting different kinds
of fruits and flowers all together
um
yeah yeah just a mixture and i like to
do that for like their main feeds
and then add in a little mistletoe for
some phosphorus
or some you know an extra little here or
there of the other buckets that you have
laying around
so just kind of keno gets to be fun you
get to be like the cook in the kitchen
you could just do them all out of your
50 gallon barrels that you mixed all
those herbs and that's just fine i did
that actually when i first started and
it worked great
and then it just became fun you know i'm
like oh i could go get this oh i could
get this oh you have horsetail oh okay
so and it's just being able to go and
harvest what you can and um
use
and share resources with friends like
we've had a lot of fun doing input
making parties
and then also um connecting with our
neighbors and seeing what like more
plants that they have on their land
compared to ours and so you can you know
kind of come together and work together
for these and for your nutrient needs
yeah
all right y'all well thank you all so
much for coming and listening to our
talks
give it up for tomorrow thorn you guys
you can reach tomorrow on instagram at
heal underscore thyself gardens and at
heal.thyselfgardens.com
and you can reach me at the humboldt
local 2.0 on instagram