okay so so it's commonly known that that
in in in full variables that there's
approximately a hundred and thirty six
original landraces
from around the world and within about
four hundred years that tripled because
of cross-pollination due to you know
regions that they were growing in and so
on and so forth and that's why you get
some of your breakdowns of the different
types of Afghani or the different you
know your your base sativas and so on
and so forth
one of the one of the pure strains that
I was able to locate was called la
Juanita lacrimosa Jane the tearful
maiden I went over to Spain I spent 90
days over there I worked with a
cultivator just outside of Barcelona he
actually gave me the entire history of
that strain and it dates back to the
plague first first getting to Spain and
nun in a cloister had been growing the
la Juanita they they used it as natural
medicine it was it grew inside the I
don't know what you call the courtyard
of of that of that convent there and
when she saw the signs of the plague in
the fishermen's village she went up
there and stripped all the leaves off
the plant boiled them in water and went
down and served that tea to everyone
okay
only people who died from the plague
during that period and of infestation
were the people who did not drink the
tea who refused to drink it they thought
it was a devil's you know thing okay so
and and the preservation of that was
actually carried on through the
religious sect not so much as the common
farmer you know having it available to
them and when villagers got sick they
would go to see the nuns the nuns would
take care of them but the name of the
strain actually came because of the
woman she was beheaded you know by the
king of Spain
for for healing those people there was a
land deal involved and they needed the
villages cleared out so that they could
build a French port and Isabella would
have married the king of Spain at that
time and it was at that time that they
found out that this woman altered their
plans and there's a famous painting that
it was done of the woman hanging upside
to her body upside down in the form of a
cross and her head in the spike right
next to it but did koi stir is in the
background of the painting and in the
window you will see the hundred percent
sativa leaf yeah it was tripled tripled
quadrupled so so in from well that would
be from today we're talking about four
hundred years because you have to
remember hump was in huge production
back at the beginning and the
establishment of this country so we had
seeds coming in from all over all the
European continents you know between
Spain God you know and Ireland Scotland
every place that they you know even Rome
Italy Italy was known for some of the
best highest grade hemp available for
making you know for clothing and for
sales so you think about a lot of the
strains that that were crossed into the
original land races were hemp that were
crossed into it and that's where you'll
find variations when you do a hundred
seeds you can find a variation of a seed
that gives you a higher CBD value to it
so it's important that when you get the
plant to this tall that you take a cut
of it grow it out you know do it do a
quick flower of it and get a CBD value
on it get your THC values find out what
your CBG values are you know with having
the laboratories available through those
that we have today we should be able to
break down all of the individual
cannabinoids to a point where there's
not an illness on this planet that we
can't fix
you know I think when the creator
reached his finger down and touched a
spot and the first cannabis plant grew
he knew exactly what he was doing okay
and up until man got in the way in 1928
man got in the way okay I don't think
our federal government should collect
any taxes I don't think our states
should collect any taxes I don't think
our Police Department should be using
any money raised from this okay because
they lied to you for 75 years they lied
to you they took this out of a doctors
hands okay so that they could push a
pharmaceutical industry that has done
nothing but cause harm and cause macular
degeneration to the human genetic that
is today and we need to take it back ah
my Panama red came out like Panama red
and I'm talking 1974-1975 Panama red and
if you came out to the farm I would
smoke some with you and you'd be you'd
be happy you met Panama red okay it said
this is the one thing you know the the
the the difference between okay when you
put a plant outside for the first time
okay generally within seven to nine days
it starts to you know you're starting to
get your boost growth and everything but
it can take you up to 30 days to finally
get a sex on that plant unless you're
using something like Philo's okay but I
can't recommend laboratories for sexy
okay there was a point that I thought I
could but I cannot do that I had an 80%
you know success you know rate no is 80%
success rate with getting females out of
the seeds that we were you know that we
were that we were germinating for the
first two years but as soon as the
recreational kicked in and everybody was
doing it I think time became a
constraint again it boils down to profit
last year's test results
were 90% inaccurate 90% okay now you
think about that I grow 423 patients
that we have cards for everybody else
gets their medicine for free all the XS
that we grow on our farm
I sell plants that's what I do I don't
sell buds you will never see my buds
you'll see my strings in the dispensary
any of if any of you've ever smoked or
consumed the Strawberry express that was
designed for adult seizures it works
I created it it's I worked my ass off in
order to do it and I don't care who
takes credit for it but the original
name was strawberry - - but they
wouldn't let me use - - it was a it's
mazar-i-sharif
that's the land race of Saudi Arabia
crossed with the time wreck from
Southern California that's a natural
grown mountain side plant okay and then
infused what Kyle kushman Strawberry
Cough okay I went from having 18
seizures a day to maybe two maybe three
and that's it and now after continued
use I'd make an RSO from it I do a
quarter gram of it every morning and I
haven't had a seizure you know well I
haven't one periodically you know and
it's generally due to stress when I get
overexcited but