[Music]
so it's now 2015 and today fortunately
we see a number of states that require
testing it is mandatory all the hard
work in talking to State regulators and
other lawmakers that they've required
this element inside of the new programs
that have come about um but
unfortunately it's still frustrating
from the lab perspective being mandatory
and required has brought other types of
players into the space but no one has
certified that they actually do their
scientific process the right way that
they're getting accurate reproducible
and valid numbers and the frustration is
I have a bunch of unsophisticated people
who thought being a lab was a great idea
from a business s stance it certainly is
but technically it's exceptionally
complex it takes a great deal of uh
scientific Acumen to run this type of
process the right way to make sure your
uh tests are accurate valid and it
requires a certain amount of cost to do
that in the best possible fashion the
frustration that we have is that other
labs who don't understand those
scientific uh principles or cutting
Corners are happy to give High values
for cannaboid Content passing all the
mold and microbiological contaminations
have never found one in their you know
existence they're gaining market share
and having all the clients go towards
them because they know that they're
going to get a big number and be tested
and be passed they're never going to
have to reject their lot they're never
going to find out what's actually there
that's exceptionally frustrating so we
are working with regul especially in
Washington to form proficiency testing
protocols Colorado has also added that
to their regulations at my insistence we
have to be able to say these labs are
doing the right job or it's really
pointless you're just paying someone to
do something and give you a false sense
of security an inaccurate number no one
should pay for any of that in my opinion
so we have to continue to to work hard
and and really demonstrate that there's
the right way to do this and I think
through that the quality will continue
to improve it's always difficult to be
the ones at the very top but we're
trying to bring everyone else up to that
same level and make sure all the labs
are operating at the the utmost highest
regard
[Music]