[Music]
I have become a little bit more
politically active and interested and
have had a chance to talk to State
regulators and other lawmakers so former
lawmakers uh had come across my path
they were interested in what labs were
doing saw that this could be a place
where they might be able to help Uh
current lawmakers craft laws and
regulations and understanding local
state level politics is what they were
an expert at and they were the ones that
kind of first got me out there and
saying you need to talk to a state
regulator you need to go talk to the
Department of Consumer Protection in in
Connecticut their legislature just said
they need to Define pharmaceutical grade
medical cannabis and no one knows what
that would be so definition is certainly
an exceptionally important part of the
law and it's really an exceptionally
important part of all the conversations
we have and why many arguments really
happen certainly the same in legal
context so when I hear that someone has
to be tasked with pharmaceutical grade
what does pharmaceutical grade represent
well it really goes towards label
integrity and accuracy and how you go
about building up that label so that's
testing and I think a lot of people
think well testing is to see what's
there but really testing is to build an
accurate label into understanding all of
the pieces and content that goes into
that label being a representation of
what the product is and assurance that
it's clean and the same quality so my
first goal was talk to different state
Regulators there were some that were
asking me to explain
how testing's done where in the supply
chain it should be done and some of them
were very you know very astute very good
questions very informed already about I
can't set a limit to zero because
analytical equipment is so sensitive it
will find something at per per trillion
level and then it's not zero that showed
that they were definitely very
interested in understanding the details
they they were learning the types of
questions to ask so when someone that
has you know Real World experience and
has been doing it in a very unregulated
system we've seen all the different
types of products that everyone's tried
to shove cannabis into we have an
appreciation for what types of things
The Regulators should look to control
where they can allow things how labels
should be built up and most of the time
it's been questions along the lines of
where do I test what am I testing for
what should be required on the label um
how often should you test how is
sampling accurate how is this testing
accurate and how do I protect public
health and safety it's a consumer
protection standpoint another good
example was in the state of Illinois I
had friends that were there that were
interested in working with the lab said
I can get into the regulators and talk
to the the Department of Agriculture is
where that one was at um and they
they've created a bureau of medicinal
plants I couldn't have been more excited
to hear that I thought that was very
forward looking beautiful type of
approach they were very interesting as a
group they lined eight different people
up in the room and said can you talk to
us for about an hour hour and a half and
just tell us you know what you know give
me a presentation about cannabis from a
scientific perspective perspective we're
interested in testing and we just have a
lot of questions at the end of that they
were like thankfully you were here we
had gone to Colorado and thought the
whole world was THC we thought that's
all that there is in this plant you've
really opened our eyes and understanding
of there's a lot of other compounds of
Interest there's a lot of other non-
psychoactive uses of this plant if we
were to regulate this in the wrong way
we won't allow it to reach all of its
full medicinal potential and that
understanding and education was very
beneficial in how we can craft our
regulations where a Testing Lab should
sit what its function should be and
throughout their process of developing
the regulations lots of emails and other
calls were back um and we do that as a
free service I mean it's just a
community service that has to go out
there to give the right information to
the right people so typically it's been
either there's an event where The
Regulators ask people to show up they'll
ask for labs to come around the State of
Washington's Liquor Control Board did
that while they were crafting the rules
let's get anyone who's a lab and tell me
if there's someone that we're missing
who should be here around the table to
talk about how do we establish limits
what types of quantities are required
for testing and how do we go about
setting these regulations up the right
way what you quickly learned though is
regulations can only be written if the
law was written in the right fashion and
there's always a little bit of a rub of
what is in the law cannot be changed
very easily it's very difficult and
timec consuming to change that
regulations are a little bit more
fluidic and and dynamic and you can
change those on a quicker basis it's a
little easier to go back and change some
of those things lawmakers need to set up
a really good Broad based framework and
then Regulators can tighten that up and
control that and make sure it's going in
the direction everybody wants in the
best interest of society with the best
interest of the consumer protection in
mind lawmakers that say well wait a
minute I'm going to try and write half
of the regulations into the laws if they
miss something or get it wrong you end
up with this horrifying scenario that's
like why did you make it in this fashion
now I can't change that until I get
another legislative session someone's
got to approve it it can go through all
these committees until it has to get
there this part should not be included
inside of the actual law it should say
regulator go do something like this and
the regulator can Define exactly what
that should be so it's interesting to
see different states take different
approaches different lawmakers have
different interests in terms of how much
control they might want to exert over
the regulator um and it's a very complex
picture and it's different in each and
every state what we're benefiting from
now is that we've see all these
different states look at each other
figure out which ones have learned which
lessons and as new ones come on online
you can see them kind of formalizing
sophisticating themselves and benefiting
from the experience of others they're
they're also understanding hey I can go
talk to these people there are a lot of
people in the community willing to try
and get these things done right people
like ourselves have been screaming for
regulations tell us exactly what to do
have us help you tell us what should be
done and we'll just go do that so that
your shorts being done the right way we
know exactly where the rules are and
where the lanes are and we can stay
inside of those too to do that though is
really a a whole community effort we
have to help them understand the
principles they need to know they have
to ask the right questions from that and
then they can craft regulations and be
willing to know they might need to
change those over time and we are seeing
Colorado and Washington and other states
change them currently California is
talking about changing laws so that they
can appoint a regulatory body um and
then have The Regulators actually go out
and write the right rules so that
everyone can follow them the right way
the new law laws being proposed in
California are definitely in a positive
direction they probably are a little
overreaching and that they shouldn't
have all of that in the law some of that
should be left to the regulator it might
make it very difficult to change later
down the road I mean let's look at past
history right it's taken about 19 years
to get here since they said they were
supposed to do these types of things um
what happens when it's wrong or we found
a flaw inside of that in the law how
long will it take us to get the
legislative body to change that it'd be
better if they took a little bit of a
step back and said let's make
regulations along these lines um then
the regulator can change in a much more
fluidic fashion as opposed to lawmakers
saying I make all the all the grand
rules of the land it's a little bit of a
an ego thing in my opinion it's kind of
entertaining to watch so it seems like
the laws are sort of like the broad
picture and the regulations are sort of
the the fine tuning and nuts and bolts
of the interpretation exactly you could
say like the laws are we're going to
play a soccer game and then The
Regulators are here's all the rules
here's the timing here's the size of the
field here's the number of players that
you've got um and here's the you know
all the things we're not going to allow
you use your hands unless you're this
one guy that would be what the regulator
does and then they're like well we need
10 people out there plus one guy with
hands and because of the Field's so big
so um but if the lawmaker said we're
going to play soccer with five people
per side and the field is going to be
you know this large it wouldn't work
that well and it would take a while to
go back and change
[Music]
it