[Music]
I've always been a scientist and an
entrepreneur kind of both that had a
little bit of the lemonade stand uh but
in college actually started an internet
service provider and was always
interested in being on The Cutting Edge
of technology and and making change that
would be positive for society went on to
graduate school out here in Los Angeles
California because it was a big place
for opportunity the uh adviser that was
doing research at USC was doing some
really interesting things in an
environmentally and friendly fashion
making non-natural amino acids and other
types of building blocks that could be
useful in the pharmaceutical industry I
was trained to think about
environmentally friendly methods of
production trained to think of you know
how you can do things to better improve
Society um making molecules do kind of
more of what you would like turn them
into materials turn them into uh food
ingredients turn them into
Pharmaceuticals or fine chemical
building blocks for things that we use
as fuels and and other stuff like that
so I'd always thought you know chemistry
could use those types of skill sets and
understandings to be an entrepreneur and
make a big positive impact um and I
thought yeah that was a great place to
to start i' always had an interest in
working towards helping people medically
so I had always had that type of mindset
to go out there and be uh involved in
research and help make medicines and try
and change people for the better what
can we understand what can we learn and
how can we produce things at low cost
for people graduate school taught me
environmentally friendly methods how to
think about your economic and
environmental impacts of the processes
that you perform to produce these things
at scale how do you scale them up in a
safe fashioned way that we won't hurt
the people that are performing those
processes how do you not leave residues
in the products and how do you become
really good at making things in a an
efficient and effective manner for both
yourself and the environment um I was
working as a as an entrepreneur I was
working in a lot of different areas find
chemical manuf facturing ways of
producing chemicals and different means
when my brother came to me and said he
was at a construction company and he was
asked to build out a storefront
dispensary um and that was around the
end of 2008 so building a dispensary I
said dispensary for what I have no idea
what you're talking about and he told me
it was for medicinal cannabis my first
impression was is that legal I can't
believe that that would be legal in any
way shape or form but turns out I moved
out here in 1997 and in 1996 is when the
voters passed the initia
was not very politically interested or
activated in any way shape or form I was
focused on school science and getting my
degree and doing my thing um but this
kind of woke me up to say wow there's
you know voter initiatives there's laws
that can be put in place by the people
and they think things should be done in
certain Fashions um and sure enough prop
215 existed sb420 was already enacted at
that point since the end of 208 in the
beginning of 2009 when President Obama
said you know patience I'm not going to
come after you you guys I'm really
worried about drug dealers and cartels I
thought well maybe there's an
opportunity um I certainly was going
through my own physical ailments as well
I had had bouts with an irritable bowel
they had given me lots of antibiotics to
the point where my face swelled up and I
had adverse reactions from that nothing
seemed to be working they kind of get to
that definition when they've tried
everything else done all the tests and
still don't know exactly what's going on
well it's a really large nervous system
and when my brother said this stuff can
be used as medicinal means I started to
look at cannabis uh from a very
medicinal standpoint um had understood
that it was around and certainly was you
know aware of the topic in a
recreational type of sense which I think
medicinal and recreational are two
different labels for tax purposes at
this point it's all for physiological
impact um look at those studies that
have been done kind of take an approach
like the schaer commission and really
start to look how safe is this molecule
or sets of molecules what makes this
very medically beneficial to so many
people and how harmful might it be and
when you look at all the research that
have been done even up to that point
it's pretty pretty easy for me to see as
a scientist this is one of the most
effective types of compounds we can find
it's very uh benign to the human body
because it's offered in a whole plant
type fashion and we really don't know a
great deal about all the therapeutic
benefits but all of these early studies
are saying it has benefits for any numer
like numerous number of ailments or
physiological responses and you come to
find out that the endo can aboid system
was really only discovered in the early
'90s natural molecules anandamide and
endoc canabo were only found in the
early '90s and we haven't really gotten
a good handle on being able to research
understand and fully appreciate that
whole type of system we now know it's a
good system for regulating balance
within the body and it seems like that
is key to so many different things that
are causing the root problems of the
ailments from inflammation to all sorts
of other you know irritations and how
can I sleep better my mood could be
improved and then fundamental
physiological processes like cell growth
blood cell growth and things of that
type so when I looked at this and said
wow there's like this enormous amount of
opportunity and potential Botanical
offer this ability to be very friendly
and healthy um and very easy on the body
it's not a single molecule where you see
a lot of people with hands fulls of
pharmaceuticals and that's because well
one solved the problem that I thought
you had but caused side effects and I
needed to give you three other things to
mitigate some of the side effects
they're trying to mimic a plant in some
respects like if I can give you four or
five or 10 different things you can find
your state of balance so cannabis
impacting with the endoc canabo system
and the body's homeostasis and balance
looking at this body of science I just
thought to myself this is really going
to be good for me CBD canabidol other
types of you know non- psychoactive
cannabinoids could be very beneficial
irritations of the bowel things like
Crohn's disease I had talked to other
people that were benefiting from the use
of THC and CBD was you know very very
rare to find so in the beginning of 2009
the idea was wow like you could really
make a very positive impact with
cannabis how would you do that and when
you start to go to dispensaries you
would see no one understands their
supply chain no one knows which products
they have and are they possibly
contaminated so plant has been bred a
lot for high THC how do we find the
other cultivars like CBD or CBG thcv and
other things only when a laboratory
exists could you start to direct
cultivation efforts and breeding efforts
to other types of plants only when
you're there could you start to protect
against pesticide exposures
microbiological contaminations and
really protect public health and safety
so our thought was there's not a lot of
scientists out here in the game I'm
seemingly getting some somewhat of a a
green light to say if you think you can
help people and really do this the right
way and Usher this into society in a
safe effective fashion um that would be
of interest and we will kind of tolerate
that and let that let that go at that
point so the calculation was this is an
enormous risk uh probably throwing away
a career path uh down the pharmaceutical
path not really sure what this means but
I I think that there's enough of an
opportunity to help so many people to be
a good scientist and really make a
positive impact in an environmentally
and ecologically friendly way that it
was worth that potential risk that we
could go out there people would want to
hear from educated intelligent
sophisticated scientists um and make
sure that we were able to do what we
wanted to do and and inform and educate
many people so without understanding
formal education or formal knowledge
base about what's in the products what's
going on with the products what people
are actually being benefited by which
products we can't really further um
develop and utilize this plant to the
best of it best of all of our abilities
and to the maximum utility that it has
to offer and when lawmakers uh State
Regulators or other people have to make
decisions about what the people want and
what they voted on they need to be
informed and and they can't go to school
for seven years and find an education
that's going to help them understand
each of those sections I mean they just
don't have that kind of time so they
have to look towards informed uh experts
in that kind of sense and we thought
that would be a great part of our
service would be to provide educational
information to anyone that would want it
whether it's a lawmaker regulator law
enforcement type people individual
patients doctors and just the general
public at large how can we help most
people understand what's going on with
this plan or science in general and
really start to introduce people to
things that I hear now they're like well
I really kind of didn't pay that much
attention to science in school but I
wish I would have because it's really
interesting to me now and I really have
a great interest in seeing how this is
impacting things and we're not going to
understand things until the scientists
get involved so we thought at that point
if we're going to help catalyze change
in the best possible Direction it would
be good to go ahead and start some sort
of service entity that provided at least
testing to begin with and that was kind
of how we got
[Music]