[Music]
now you have this great idea about I
want to be an entrepreneur and start a
company and then it's a scientific
company which requires expensive
analytical equipment and things that uh
like a laboratory fum Hood safety shower
and there's definitely a capital need
I'm going to have to find someone that's
either a high net worth individual all
of the uh I put a business plan together
started talking to people and a lot of
um professional funders Angel Investors
or investment bankers were like that
sounds like a great idea I would never
touch it like back in 2009 their uh
their risk appetite or you know
willingness to enter into this space was
definitely very different than what we
hear about today um and still today A
lot of people are still hesitant but are
quite curious and I really you know took
a long period of time it was a number of
months with the idea and the plan in
place and understanding how you could
get it going um and the first plan I
wrote required a significant amount of
money and the millions of dollars to go
ahead and do it right and all I could
raise was
$150,000 so as every good entrepreneur
will have to do you have to figure out
how to make do with what you have you
have to be determined and persistent and
if that's my opportunity I'm going to
make the most of it I'll rework my plan
and figure out how to bootstrap from
there it was the biggest blessing in
disguise I ever got so I didn't outspend
ourselves we went very carefully slowly
methodically we bought one hlc and got
our you know equipment in the right
building a very well suited lab for that
kind of activity and started working
really hard from there um and didn't
understand that when we started other
labs would start with quite a different
model uh in terms of what equipment they
were using what types of costs they
would charge for their testing that the
market wasn't quite ready for testing
they weren't sure what that really meant
um and you really have to try and and
continuously Invent Yourself and
reinvent yourself just to adapt to the
conditions and the market Place what's
out there so I didn't understand
initially how much education would need
to be given and how timec consuming and
challenging that really is our first
choice of analytical equipment was a an
hplc a liquid chromatograph everyone
else was using gas chromatographs so
people thought that's the only way you
can do it why would I want to do
something different and then when you do
something different you get more
information but that actually ends up
being somewhat confusing it doesn't test
for just THC but THC acid which is what
the plant makes if I'm making wait a
minute I thought we all were talking
about THC now you're mentioning another
canabo then you say I have to heat it to
form this one all of a sudden you start
to lose people's uh you know willingness
to try and test or understand what's
really going on it took a long period of
time for people to even accept that it
has to be a liquid chromatograph to get
started that was the tool that was the
stuff that all of us had thought about
and um my scientific friends and I
bantered back and forth why do you want
to choose this equipment over the other
ones the other ones are cheaper it's
easier and the assessment at the end was
this is the only tool that can look at
all of the broad-base of products so
every type of product that I'm going to
use this is the one I need to to work on
and it it was half the capital that we
raised was going towards this decision
it was the biggest decision we could
imagine the other decision of not paying
yourself was a little bit easier that's
typically what most entrepreneurs have
to do um years worth of no salary or
working very hard out of the garage they
they often call it um it's hard work
dedication many days worth up till 2: in
the morning 3: in the morning to try and
get the rapid turnaround times we had
promised driving around to collect
samples to make sure they were
scientifically valid and accurate um and
was just fortunate to convince a very
you know very nice and kind friend of a
friend individual to take that risk on
us um that we were going to do whatever
it took to be successful we were going
to do it all right completely
legitimately um above board and really
be standing pillars of scientific
excellence and professionalism and that
took a number of months to convince that
individual and if it wasn't for a
wonderful Christmas gift my father gave
me at the end of that year I probably
wouldn't have had the funds to survive
until um that individual made his
decision and said okay I'll hand over
you know my significant funds to get you
guys started um but fortunately we did
that we got there and it um to every
entrepreneur out there just keep trying
and just don't let don't let anyone tell
you no you just uh if you believe in
yourself and what you're doing and you
know it's right that determination is
what's going to take you through the
really long days the hard pieces of
effort it is never a get-rich quick type
idea it is a labor of love and a lot of
hard work that will get you there it's
not this you know oh I have an idea and
tomorrow all of a sudden it's a big
success it's a lot more complicated than
that and I think many entrepreneurs
don't understand that they see this is
really good and I can have a lot of
benefits from that but they kind of miss
the part that's all the hard work
towards getting there um and in this
realm with cannabis it's exceptionally
difficult I thought I like a challenge
myself no greater challenge of being an
entrepreneur than this one because
you've got an extra layer of legal
complexity other things that might cause
barriers to entry for others and you
need competitive Advantage if you can
figure it all out before others can
being at the utmost uh responsible level
though and operating transparently
operating to be a very professional and
respected member of the community and
Society in general and doing things that
are not you know looked at as favorable
by everyone causes unique challenges too
it's definitely difficult to deal with
everyone in that fashion but that's the
only way that we wanted to operate
raises unique challenges that you didn't
quite think about in your business plan
um but it's a testament of well that's
that's what I'm having to deal with
that's what we're going to go figure out
um but I I would say every entrepreneur
just keep trying that's the best
[Music]
thing