[Music]
how do we preserve true Medical in an
adult use Market it's a very big
challenge I would say and there are some
that really want to be dedicated and are
passionate towards producing medical
products
um I think the standards of Purity for
both of those products today certainly
look to be the same which is a good
thing everyone is entitled to good clean
pure products so I don't think that that
you know bifurcating that in some way
may make a little sense but it uh in my
opinion it's it's good to have clean
things for everybody um we shouldn't
have a different type of Purity limits
for all of our products out there I
think the medical minded operator might
find it challenging to find shelf space
they might find it difficult to reach
all the patients that thereafter we may
see more of a delivery Network being set
up where you can have patients come into
a dispensary uh they may need to travel
further away we're not sure where all
the licensed dispensaries are going to
end up geographically speaking how many
there might be Los Angeles is still
going through the process of creating
their new ordinance um they haven't
decided or discussed really if they're
going to have limitations or not I think
you're seeing a great resistance to
accept acting a large number of
dispensaries there's a lot of Southern
California locals that have said ban it
all we're going to wait to try and see
what this looks like before we start
permitting these things in any fashion
you have to be locally permitted before
you get a state permit so I think we're
going to see this unfortunate time where
patients today are accessing things in
today's current Medical Market as that
one gets forced into the regulated one
you'll see different operators show up
you'll see locations move you'll see
different product types show up and
today's patient that's finally found
what's working for them may
unfortunately be disconnected from that
product um and that's a huge Challenge
and not fair to any patient and I don't
know if there's a great answer other
than you know try to make sure the
product that you're relying on the
brands that you're relying on are moving
towards adopting the regulations are
finding some sort of way that they don't
get their supply disrupted in the new
system which is where do I manufacture
where do I have it distributed how do I
get distribution hooked up how do I make
sure I'm compliant with all the testing
how do I know that my product type is
actually compliant with the new
regulations um just a few things that
you have to deal with on top of you know
new business practices and other
problems the level of requirements for
operating in this space based on
manufacturing regulations are rather
stringent they are extremely um detailed
you have to absolutely write every
single thing down um be redundant in
what you're adding to your batches so
that someone's signing off on what some
some other operator actually added to it
and weighed out and the requirements for
that are I think unfortunately going to
push up the price a little bit when you
add tax when you add testing when you
add um things such as operating
conditions that require tons and tons of
paperwor and lots of diligence in that
regard it inherently adds cost more over
add to cities that are trying to tax on
top of it they're adding you know square
footage or gross receipt taxes on top of
that it's going to raise the cost and
today's Medical patients are not
reimbursed by healthcare for their cost
of this medicine um we may see the
market balance that with people that say
I'll push down towards commodity pricing
I I know we all have to compete with the
black market pricing which are guys who
are not paying taxes or doing any of the
regular regulatory standards so there's
got to be a little bit of a give and
take but there's only so much that will
actually be able to be given um because
your costs of doing business are simply
going to go up to be able to comply um
how that whole piece of the pie
basically today gets split um between
taxes local taxes regulations and uh new
requirements for operating how much will
be left for the businesses that are
there I think the longer term minded
ones the ones that are going to invest
in the future are probably going to be a
lot better off um and able to weather
those storms and make it in a long sense
but are today's patients you know
acquiring medicine from people who are
operating in that fashion it very well
might be a no and it might be very
difficult for every patient to not be
disconnected from their medicine as
regulations roll out I think there will
be a significant challenge in finding
new access points or the number of
access points the retail outlets um or
Delivery Systems that are going to be
set up from through the retail outlets
um to getting medicine into a patient's
hands today the the numbers of estimates
are hundreds to a thousand or more
different dispensary points inside of
California um um and I think that number
is going to significantly shrink we
don't see many locals trying to rush to
permit uh a large number of dispensaries
if they're even willing to do one or two
uh and some are saying let's just keep
them all closed off and make them
delivery only um we will see those
distribution points Limited in number it
will be harder for patients to get
access to their medicine I think one of
the only solutions around that will be
who's driving that and delivering it to
them but again there will be increased
cost by having that happen um but I I
think it's definitely going to be a lot
less than what we see today
[Music]