[Music]
some of the difficulties of building up
the sales Avenues of the business and
really getting the business started once
we had secured the the funding the
equipment in the place um were it was a
big challenge so how do you find
cultivators when they're all you know
hiding and they don't want to be found
well the the only place you can really
find them is that that M Mutual meetings
bought the dispensaries those are public
they're out there everyone can find them
online or in other places so we thought
that would be the first Target for us
was we're just going to find a list of
dispensaries in Southern California
we're going to go start knocking on
doors we're going to put our you know
the press the flesh they say or put our
boots on the ground and really just go
out there and start talking to everybody
and you you get a quick sense of wow
there's a very insignificant
understanding about what testing is and
what it really means most people hate
the idea of a test usually means it's
something you're probably going to fail
uh you know no one likes to test at the
DMV no one likes to test at the schools
no one likes to be tested for anything
so quickly you come to well I shouldn't
go in there and say I'm a tester and I'm
going to test all your stuff that's
probably not going to lend towards
continuing the conversation and really
helping you go forward so it was how do
you frame the approach and you say look
I'm here to help you find the best
things for your patients we're here to
help you screen the quality of products
that you've got and help everyone
understand that you know there is
quality control and assurance and that
your supply chain is really what you're
hoping it would be and that they can
start to understand the dosing that
they're using and can effectively use
the medicine that's cost effective for
them and the cost that we're going to
add to you coming in here to do this
service is very nominal so if I can come
into your dispensary location I would
like to select samples out of every bag
that you hold and I can show up once a
week or on a regular basis uh to your
liking and offer these battery of tests
that you guys could start with that was
how the whole conversation had began and
after hundreds of I'm not interested in
doing that I don't feel like I have to
I'm afraid I get a lower number and
people won't understand that this is
still good medicine it might be
effective for them um mindsets of like
why are you using the equipment you're
using how do you interpret these results
this makes it more complicated for me to
make my sale to patients I'm not sure I
want to do that there's literally a risk
of holding the bag that can be
contaminated as a dispensary operator um
others eventually started to Fe here
these guys are around they're very good
they're very professional and had some
that said you guys are fantastic from
what I hear but until I'm forced to do
it by law or by regulation I'm just not
going to do it I don't feel like paying
for that the beginning of 2010 is when
we started uh opening our doors for
service and offered testing to the
industry and in the early part of 2010
there was one other prominent lab Steep
Hill Laboratories that operated up in
Oakland California northern part of
California they used gas chromatographs
at that time and we were using liquid
chromatograph so in 2010 there was very
little bit of an understanding of okay
this stuff may be able to be tested I
had a lot of people ask oh you can test
this plant I'm like it's still a plant
own dispensary owners um State
Regulators other people but I mean even
cultivators patients like you what what
are you going to test what are you
trying to test for how does this testing
really work um in the beginning of 2010
there was definitely a really grave lack
of understanding that you could even
approach this plant and test it in in
some sort of fashion it's still just a
plant like any other plant um the people
that we were interacting with
predominantly at that point were mostly
dispensary owners operators or managers
of the dispensary so those are the ones
trying to make the financial decisions
understanding what may be best for
patients how to understand product
quality was certainly of interest if
there's a way I can kind of check the
quality of my cultivators that would be
good patients seem to be very
appreciative of the type of testing that
was being offered at the few places in
Southern California that were doing it
um and that was kind of the idea there
had been just a little bit there if you
if you build it they will come and over
time you'll be able to educate and
explain why you're doing these things
and how that formalizes this product and
treats it just like every other product
out there so all the eonia all the St
John's wart all the pharmaceutical
products your food all of those things
are tested we eventually changed our
pitch to be like you realize your dog's
medicine is tested do you think that
this is you know of lower quality or
people are not is important and you
wouldn't test this type of medicine that
caused a dispensary owner to come right
outside of of his you know little back
office and was like oh was really
interesting I hadn't really thought of
it that way and I'll consider using your
service they didn't they uh but that you
know kind of at least got the thought
process going and I think that kind of
shows how many people were thinking
about it at the time it was a very
difficult cell I mean it was definitely
days of tens to you know eventually over
a week like I swear we hit a 100 places
and no one wanted to use this service um
but we did find a few and eventually
found a few dispensaries that said I I
really want to demonstrate I am a
legitimate operator I'm a professional
operator I care about the people that
were providing these medicinal products
to and I want to also do what we were
saying like let's formalize these things
let's understand them better and let's
show everybody that this is just another
Botanical product and something that
everyone can benefit from we should
treat it like every other product so a
few dispensaries started to test on a
consistent basis and we asked them you
know would you also do microbiological
testing would you do pesticide testing
and they said yeah if you get the
equipment we'll make the commitment to
you you can show up every week and we'll
screen for these types of things too so
the next piece we got was
microbiological testing so we found a a
technology that would allow us to test
for mold in 48 hours and realizing that
turnaround time is exceptionally
important nobody wants to sit on the
products it's important to keep it fresh
you know how do I you know tell somebody
I have to take seven days to do your
testing and get back to you by then it's
all gone and it was pointless you that
was never going to work so 2 days was as
fast as we could find technology to do
it and that seemed to generate enough
interest like all right I can wait a day
or two or I can kind of package it get
it ready while you guys are going and
then we can put it on to um you know
onto the shelf so I think that was you
know a big piece in our development The
Next Step was Where Do We Go From Here
canabo profiling was first
microbiological testing was second along
that we went to a couple trade shows and
we found um we put up our here's the
label that we think should be there we
have a little logo that says we were the
ones that tested it you can trust the
numbers were done in an accurate fashion
um a little bit of the Integrity that
goes with that is the people behind
doing the testing and what their
certification program would mean how
we're doing this so this is on display
to the consumer and then eventually
consumers say oh it's yeah you know
Workshop tested I trust you know seen
them testing other stuff so we put that
there for consumers so they could
understand we advertised that at trade
shows for dispensary owners other
producers cultivators could then say Oh
wait I can take my stuff to the
dispensary so that they already know
I've done that type of responsible
portion that actually gives me a way of
you know marketing myself and saying I'm
a responsible operator I've checked
these things this lab has verified my
work product for this you know this
Harvest you it made their conversations
I think easier with dispensaries at
least the first round did now if you
come back and your numbers are very
different the second time uhoh okay I
think I'm done with that testing thing
I'll just tell everybody that I'm always
this good that's great right and that
was why we use tested on dates so I mean
we've seen that in other markets but we
thought that's the only way to say when
were these numbers you know acquired
when might they be able to change if
they're stored over longer periods of
time how might the product be slightly
different from that or was this some
sort of test that can't be valid because
it was done two years ago on an edible
product that's obviously being
manufactured more frequently than that
um that was one of the elements that we
had added and at this trade show we had
our our label up there and another
individual came up and said I'd be
really interested in investing in your
business I see that this is where things
should actually go and where they should
head in the end you seem like very
responsible group of individuals
professional I don't see anything else
like this out here let's talk further um
and fortunately that did lead to the
next step in our development after
months of convincing him and his family
that this was a very good decision
um that he said okay I'll take the risk
and give you guys a little bit more
money that allowed us to acquire
pesticide testing and tpine profiling uh
and along with that we were able to uh
bring in the house a Dutch scientist
wonderful individual named CA elzinga
who actually had eight years of
experience in the the Dutch national
system and his uh Graduate Studies he
really understood things we had spoke
and met each other at a conference
together down in lagona woods and
immediately the two of us were like you
know oh my goodness you understand the
bigger words I'm saying you understand
the technical complexities of what we're
doing let's go have dinner let's talk
about what we could do together um and I
was able to formalize his position with
us upon securing the other investment
which was about a year after we had
gotten started that led to what I think
we're known for a lot today which is
tarpine profiling and looking at all the
other products that are present in
cannabis most people say it's just
canabo THC or CBD now um most people
don't even know what CBD was when we
first started testing so that was the
goal showing people the other molecules
that are present starting to breed in
different directions Labs will enable
that and start to drift away from only
THC or only one type of use of the plant
if you can breed it for that you have to
be able to breed it for other things
when we first started testing for tpin
the rationale and reason was you could
see I test three different products they
all smell different they look very
different physiologically feel different
but they have the same exact tht number
they have the same exact canab profile I
don't see anything different on my
machine yet I know they're very very
different so I have to start looking at
other molecules and other things to
start to see what these differences are
when we first offered tpine testing
other labs said they're trying to just
charge you for another test I can't see
where there's any value and that they
just want to get more money from the
dispensary guys today everyone's like oh
I offer tpine testing we're trying to do
more of those things you see TP
festivals now there are you know that's
a very big trendy word on social media
media and all sorts of Sling terms
around it now and most people didn't
even know what a tpine was when we
started doing that still today A lot of
people are like tpin I haven't heard of
those um and you have to educate them
about it's related to the smell the
aroma but really causes the
physiological effects that make cannabis
unique that has been you know a big part
of what we've been working on that
started back in 2011 um so we got
different equipment we were able to
continue to bootstrap we got a couple
other clients that said you offer
broader testing um the clients we did
have and started with they wanted to do
more testing so we became a little bit
more efficient getting the same number
of samples but being able to do more
tests and get more dollar value for that
driving around Southern California for
50,000 mil a year uh to go anywhere and
everywhere whether it was Palm Springs
Bakersfield San Diego you know we live
in Pasadena or Los Angeles all those
places are quite a ways away from where
we're at every week we were going to
those places to hand select samples and
make sure that they were collected
properly and building up our reputation
for being um responsible that allowed a
lot of discussion and a lot of
interaction so it really was a good
thing for us and the community we could
explain last week's results we could
explain what else was going on we could
answer technical questions while we were
there and started to then also offer
educational seminars if people were
testing I would show up and give them a
little PowerPoint presentation to the
staff so that they could understand some
asked if we would do it for their
patients and certainly we would um um
and I recognized we really have to get
out there more so and start talking to
more and more people so in addition to
talking to dispensary operators
cultivators eventually doctors more so
um I made an effort to go out and talk
to State Regulators other types of
individuals and explain how you could do
testing why testing was important and
where we really need to see this done in
a a regulatory fashion so that the
supply chain is controlled so upon
testing for dispensaries you've got a
couple months of operating time with
them things are going pretty well you're
seeing them on a a weekly basis on a
regular basis and the feedback that we
received from that were patients love
the information they're very happy to
see that someone has checked the quality
control that they feel better knowing
it's past the microbiological screen
knowing that they weren't pesticides
that were screen for that were found
inside of the products and really
appreciating some of the the cannaboid
numbers when tpine values came in
addition to that and we expanded the
label that was a whole new realm that
they could then look at you know I don't
know if I trust the name but I can at
least trust these values if they're on
here and if these are the types of
things that I've used before and I like
then I know as a patient that that's
some sort of product that would work for
me and our our feedback from the
dispensary operators were you know our
patients really really like the testing
they really see the value in this type
of thing um and we're glad that we can
offer it to them it was a huge
competitive Advantage for dispensaries
who opted to offer tested products as
opposed to those who didn't so when you
have a large cluster of them and a very
small area how do you differentiate
yourself how do you offer different
things to the patients and other
information this was a great tool for
that kind of thing and certain
dispensary owners really recognized that
right away some that were um in other
areas actually used it posted every
result and said look I even grabbed uh
tested samples from other dispensaries
and they found pesticides in them our
supply chain is clean we're very
diligent it's a very different type of
offering to the consumer or the patient
consumer that wants to understand what
what they're putting in their body who
may be immuno compromised or really
under you know sick or other types of
issues they don't want to ingest
anything that could cause harm so
pesticides and molds could be worse we
definitely don't want to do that um and
the feedback was patients really enjoy
the service and really appreciate that
and found it to be very very beneficial
to them so every entrepreneur builds
their business plan with the hockey
stick in mind and it was definitely not
the hockey stick it was a very very slow
hard work effort type thing and and more
Grassroots type Word of Mouth gets
around the way that we when we look back
at all of the clients that we've tested
for and the people that we've been doing
business with there are very few that
have still continued to test from the
first days that we started so we've got
a couple they started with us and have
tested all the time every single time
and keep doing it there are others who
tried it for a little while then dropped
off and it was a constant effort of
finding new clients constantly going out
there to try and build the business but
that really just kept you able to
maintain and sustain it was never really
where that all of a sudden everybody
decided to go ahead and start testing um
we now test we've opened a laboratory in
the state of Washington where it is
mandatory to test for the recreational
market so it's been required to test and
what you see there are there's a couple
Labs that offer services the one who
gives the highest THC value and the ones
who charge the lowest price are the labs
that get the best amount of the market
so it's not even that all of a sudden
regulations change and you're a
successful lab there's all sorts of
other ways that you have to
differentiate yourself and it's still
difficult because they're not checking
the scientific Integrity or validity of
all the tests we now have Labs that are
giving Gravely inflated numbers on
flowers I won't even repeat the number
for fear people think that that's
possible um but it's difficult to say
hey regulator you've certified that
these Labs should operate but you
haven't checked that they do their
operations properly there's no
proficiency testing there's no you know
accuracy checking on what exactly the
lab is doing now you've given everybody
this false sense of that's an okay lab
but really they're giving them
thisinformation and to me when people
told us as we were building up I don't
want to test I'd rather see you not test
than test wrong and get the wrong values
so if I have Mis leading information on
Doses and I thought I was taking 25
milligrams when really I was only
consuming 10 and the next time I go and
actually get something that's 25 and
that could be very detrimental to the
patient that could be exceptionally
harmful if you told them they never new
they'd probably always start you know at
a slower regime and work their way up
and that's a lot more safe from their
perspective we see lots of benefits for
testing I think people out there are
still saying well it cost me more
patients are starting to say they really
want it and that's why we started to go
out to more and more of the trade shows
to educate patients and say this is why
you want to ask your dispensary for
[Music]
testing