[Music]
when Dr pmell called me weeks ago about
this potential conference uh and the
involvement of the law school here at
UCI he told me it was going to be on
Friday
afternoon uh in uh May 5th at 4:00 in
the afternoon CCO deile
I literally said to Dr py are you crazy
doctor I really didn't believe him that
we would draw this audience so a big
round for yourself for being here this
afternoon I also have to share a comment
uh about the congressman uh Dana and I
have known each other for probably 20 25
years uh I'm the flip side of Dana uh
Conservative Republican he is of course
uh I'm the progressive Democrat that
served in the state senate uh from here
in of all places Orange County 1998 to
06 County was a little more conservative
at that time I share that because uh
we're an interesting Dynamic on this
issue we disagree on most major policy
issues it's the nature of the Beast uh
but on this particular issue he's been a
leader his entire elected life I
struggled with these issues as a
progressive Democrat in Sacramento
at that time some of you may remember uh
now unfortunately he's no longer with us
Senator John vasconcelos who was one of
the leading advocates for both uh
medicinal marijuana as well as the
legalization of recreational uh
marijuana back at a time when everyone
scoffed at him in Sacramento uh but he
really through his own determination his
own passion really opened the door to
where we are today he sat right behind
me on the senate floor he talked to me a
lot as a progressive Democrat uh and
kept needling me of course about Orange
County uh so it's interesting that Dana
has been as a Conservative Republican a
passionate leader in this area for many
many years I a progressive Democrat
struggled with this issue but I have to
confess uh where I am today as uh one of
many who share the same views as some of
the folks who have already spoken I know
Dr uh uh Pali has focused solely on the
science uh but I'm a strong supporter
and I have to credit my daughter uh who
actually did that it's amazing how
daughters can affect dads uh and get
them to change their mind and my
daughter in fact did that I know some of
you in this room know her uh and I have
to credit her because she started uh
dad's Evolution uh as I was taught by a
younger generation I'm only going to
share a couple comments I know we're a
little behind and I want to turn the
podium over over to some of our
remaining speakers for a little extra
time uh but I am going to share another
part of this that it we feel here at UCI
is now necessary in the
evolution of all issues surrounding the
use of cannabis whether recreational Med
or medicinal um and that's something new
is as follows every time there's a major
industry that emerges on the scene and
grows
exponentially and everyone who observes
it uh Advocate or Foe knows that it will
be uh in due time a massive industry
involving so many different elements in
society um and you know with cannabis
when we now have Venture Capital funds
that invest in the industry you have
major law firms uh uh that practice in
this area you have many of the very
established organizations in society
grav gravitating to this growing
industry what we feel at UCI is a
missing but
critical part of all of that puzzle and
you'll like this particularly Lori given
what you're doing um and that is to
create the nation's first academic based
interdisciplinary cannabis Research
Institute
I have to note uh as the congressman was
walking back up he and I have worked on
a lot of issues over the years that's
the way politics should work we'll
disagree on major issues but on those we
agree on we work together uh and he was
applauding uh the creation of that as
well we're in the early stages but I I
want to be very specific with everyone
about what that means because it may be
different than some of the Advocates
that may be here today there's something
very unique about an academic based
disciplinary Institute academic based is
critical it means it's tied to no
ideology it's tied to no specific
position in science or business or law
or art or communication
psychology it bases its positions solely
on academic
research that is critical it has always
been critical in mature societies to
ensure that we move forward based upon
independent research that is as free as
humanly
possible of outside
influence second I said
interdisciplinary there are a number of
centers around the country in uh
research institutions that focus in on
one area of
cannabis it may be the medic medicinal
impact such as Dr Pell's great work that
is known around the world
but for a new and growing industry it
needs interdisciplinary analysis it
means the law must grow in complement
with the science it means the theories
of business must adjust to the new
reality of a new industry it means the
financial industry must adjust with it
and adjust to an industry that is only
growing and is only going to grow bigger
and more established as we move forward
as a society the academic based
interdisciplinary Institute is frankly
the only way to fill that void so we
already have the involvement in setting
up this institute at UCI of course LED
and frankly it was his concept by the
great Dr pelli and now the law
school and there were some who advised
me when I went to ardan I think some of
you in the room have heard of him before
uh Dean Irwin chiminski uh that there
might be some concern and I sat down
with the dean and I said here's the
concept and he said well that's long
overdue thank you Dean chiminski we have
already been in Communications with a
number of the other schools on campus
from the business side to the
engineering side to the information
computer science side to the art side to
the communication side you name it we've
touched upon as many as possible with
more to go Go including for those who
are familiar with uh UCI the applied
Innovation Center which is on the back
side of the campus and that really is
designed to bring the scientific uh and
other research here on campus out into
the marketplace in a far easier fashion
than in the past when it comes to an
academic uh University setting uh so you
bring all those pieces together and it
will be the first in the nation that is
again I stress academic based
interdisciplinary Institute
and I want to share one out last thing
our hope is to do many Symposium and
Conference in addition to the great
research develop model policies The
Institute will never Advocate others can
take its work and Advocate but it can't
Advocate it would compromise its
independence we are in the process of
creating a large and diverse Advisory
board but I also want to stress it's an
Advisory board for those who are
unfamiliar with academic based Institute
it can only be governed by the academics
because that's the only way to protect
its independence on the research that it
does but The Advisory Board certainly
will be made up of experts uh throughout
and different perspectives of this
growing industry so that the academics
have that input can consider that input
but again all research will be
independent more to come stay tuned uh
and I will be by the way at the
reception later that's not a UCI related
uh reception but I know there'll be some
folks in the back of the room and out in
the hallway as we end today that we'll
have the invites and the maps I will be
there I believe the congressman will be
there as well we're happy to answer
questions uh at the reception as well
thanks everybody
[Music]