[Music]
today we're rolling I'm gonna roll up
some gelato 33 yeah you know I don't
know exactly where this one came from I
was grown by some good friends of mine
my hands here and so you are about to
release a pre-roll line yeah we're
actually about to release a pre-roll
collaboration right now yeah we're about
to release a pre-roll collaboration with
the Moana brand essential extracts alien
labs and Kali kosher alien labs is
providing the baklava flour gelato 41
times kosher Kush so we're using dried
cured baklava flour and then we're using
Cali kosher x' fresh frozen friddle's
string friddle's and this is whole plant
fresh frozen friddle's is forbidden
fruit I'm skittles has this amazing
candy citrus flavor and we hand selected
the material we are hand-washing that
fresh frozen and hand rolling these
joints and really proud of the
collaboration the joint tastes amazing
it's one gram of flour 23 full melt hash
yeah
really properly hand rolled by myself
just like this but with gloves on and
yeah that should be releasing this June
and so just quickly so you have a little
European style going on here to talk
about so first of all you're using I'm
using a doubled up crutch I like the
left east crutch because I like a long
crutch here helps cool down the smoke
helps keep the weed out of my mouth and
just helps support a longer spliff as
well so i like that longer crush
basically doubled up rode up
I we call it a crutch or a filter - this
is the part I don't condone but since I
was a youth I grew up with European
foreign exchange doing European friends
traveled all over the world and this
unfortunately has stuck with me the
blending of the tobacco or the gravel
into this spliff here this is a smoking
brown unbleached roll so build your own
size basically smoking brown you know
there's a few unbleached papers out
there on the market right now and I just
really prefer everything that smoking
has done over the years I started with
smoking blacks and move actually I think
smoking EKOS which was the hemp one with
the dehydrated honey glue moved on to
smoking blacks and then smoking masters
which is the silver pack which is a real
thin paper and now I've kind of just
been stuck on these smoking Browns and I
just like how they burn they taste a
little bit less almost woody or
cellulose II than the raw papers to me
so it's important that I get a real
tight against the crutch there to me
it's about a folding it's not really a
rolling technique so we fold that paper
right there we get the conical shape
here tuck and a fold the lick part won't
be happening in our pre-roll
collaboration either we're using a
paintbrush sponges not an auth box cuz I
really want the homogenate homogeneous
Asian of the hash so we're actually
mixing the hash and the flours in a cold
room and I'm rolling this up in a cold
room with the hash in it so we have full
homogenization the hash remains a powder
that way we can completely homogenize it
with the flowers
and then once it reaches room
temperature kind of melts out yeah so
there's the nicotine style spliff right
there this is a little bit longer a
little bit larger than the size but it
is a little bit large and larger than a
king size paper
oh it's whatever pretty rule is so talk
about it I mean you just rolled your own
joined with amazing flour obviously with
a pre roll it gets a little stale so can
you talk about how you reconcile it like
you're coming out with a brand of
pre-rolls I don't think yeah and first
of all you know we're really trying to
stick away from the term pre-roll
because I think a lot of the pre rolls
out there on the market are that knock
box dried stale trim things of that
nature so we're using hold buds cured
buds from alien labs we're mixing that
in the cold room like I said with our
hash packing it into the joints like
this then we're actually putting these
into a sauna tube which is a hemp
plastic tube we're wrapping that with a
heat shield shrink wrap and then that
goes into the box so I think the heat
sealed shrink wrap is how I'm trying to
avoid a lot of that stale that stale
flower situation mixing the hash in
there just I don't know it's it's
keeping the consistency we're seeing a
nice shelf stability on it for sure and
you're environmentally conscious with
the son of plastic yeah there's so much
waste out there and we really you know
we really tried to do everything we
could to avoid the waste situation with
a pre-roll though I do want the shrink
wrap I do want as much of the you know
keeping that flavor in there as possible
but yeah you know with the compliance
and all the regulation aspects of our
industry there is a lot of waste that
you just have to do and it's unfortunate
but we're trying to go every route we
can
hemp to recycle
[Music]