Josh Gordon got spent ten times or
something like that Ricky Williams took
a year off to go on sabbatical to smoke
and he knew something we didn't know was
like okay my body's getting beat down I
need you gonna fix it and repair it and
I didn't realize the benefits of its
allies myself startup are taking it and
I realized that you know staying calm
being able to sleep being able to eat
you know sometimes when you're nervous
or you're frustrated or you're injured
you're you're depressed something you
don't have the same eating habits and
you eat bad or you're impulsively eating
but now like when you you get the
munchies I know if you've had much
before
but you eat I'm not sure I have healthy
food in my house but you know I'm eating
properly and eating eating more than
what I would if I was stressed out I'm
curious to find out what they do in the
NFL if you are caught smoking you hit a
little bit on with Gordon but what do
they do what are the protocols and what
are the protocols in place to protect
the player and house that'll go down or
you get fined
first offense you get fined you then
they put you in the substance abuse
program so you have to pee in a cup
every week probably three times a week
it's um
I've seen people go through it they hate
it's the worst but um yeah you get fine
and then second offense you get a
four-game suspension and then you get
put into the program and you have to you
know meet with the psychologist and
whatnot and then um third offense I
think it's a eight-game suspension and a
fine and you could possibly get conduct
detrimental so it escalates each time
you do it but I mean Josh Gordon was
continually getting in trouble for
smoking weed and I mean he was just
always ready to play every game he was
there and ready to play and I think that
cannabis was a huge part of his ability
to be relaxed and comfortable and he
just he moved effortlessly and I swear
to God it's because of cannabis but uh
yeah I mean he just they don't really
want to get rid of you because you smoke
weed but they have their rules that they
have in place that they have to adhere
to which is kind of to me it shows that
that they want to allow it but they
can't allow it because the backpressure
they get from the Jenner plug I think
but they'll prescribe opioids quickly
yeah in a heartbeat here take this tour
tall get in there how can that be change
or how do you see that changing in the
future I think it's just going to have a
the NFL Players Union has to rally
together behind the people who have the
lawsuits against NFL for the damage has
been done
so there's walking evidence of people in
the community now that are former
players their walk around with pain that
have problems with their body because of
all the opiates they've taken and all
the stuff they put in their body I mean
I was a time where I was playing a game
and it was a really good year we were 14
and 2 but we were just playing at a high
level and I was putting DMSO and
ketoprofen on my body and DMS though
it's not clear by the FDA it's not good
for your body I don't know what the side
effects are probably in another 20 years
all right I have another leg growing out
of my body I don't know but um whatever
it took to be on the field that's what
everybody's mentalities I can't lose my
job I'll do whatever so if you got this
I'll take you give it to me I want to
feel better I want to I want to be able
to work and players are not gonna stand
up for themselves they're so focused on
trying to survive that they're not
focused on what the bodies
what damage is being done and the
long-term effects of it so I think the
the alumni has to jump back in and say
you know what look at my body I'm 55
years old and people are dying from
heart attacks and do they don't know why
but it's because of all the stuff they
put in their body people are going to
having dementia at 60 Alzheimer's it's a
high prevalence of people who have brain
issues and they're just now sort of
rolling out packages to help with that
disability plan but there's a lot of
lawsuits still against the NFL because
of that and I think that they would just
look at the books and say if we start
allowing people to take CBD start
allowing people to use cannabis there's
a lot of money that saves us in the long
run so I mean from a business
perspective I would just look at the
brass tacks of the numbers and just say
you know what it's probably more
profitable for us to do this and they
say oh well you know they're smoking
weed and they're promoting weed and it's
promoting it to the kids well say well
what about all the beer commercials you
have out here we're all other damn Coors
Light you passed down in the stadium
they see daddy drink all the time and
daddy gets mad selling yeah mommy that's
a problem but you don't see daddy smoke
weed and going yell at mommy
I'm not just being advocate in that on
that fashion but I mean just from from
plain and simple just looking at what's
going on I think this need to step up
and say you know what this is the
problem let's fix it I mean it's just
it's going to come from the community
that people who are actually live
like living in the pain that are using
it they had to use the proper language
and their speaking and sort of convince
people that this is the right way to go