[Music]
home and medical has its own home and
there's proper funding an infrastructure
in place to produce medical cannabis and
there's companies that are producing
high-grade products that are doable and
and pure and repeatable and you know the
studies can be done that the product can
be delivered you know when it's proven
successful you know these are these are
the steps that have to happen
I agree Patrick but but I don't think
you didn't separate some well here's
worry where it has to be is you know for
example right now the competition to get
a manufacturers license is dominated by
the recreational market yeah right so
how does how do how do people who want
to make real medicine who how do they
get the manufacturers license when
there's already so much interest and so
much money and so much value to those
licenses well this is what I think that
you can't separate them because we are
what we do is we do within the cities
and counties that we work
that's all that we do is we speak to the
City Council and the County Supervisors
about separating this because you have
to understand the do between what would
be they don't understand they don't
reducing their they're falling for the
new stigma which is that they see all
these people buying cannabis from a
dispensary under the under the guise of
it being medical when they recognize
that it's clearly is this is primarily a
recreational consumer and so there are
our own culture current culture is
devaluing the credibility of the man
obviously right this is why in the
Arcana conference which really gave a
front row seat to real herbalists who've
been doing this for ages and I said to
them I don't know how we're gonna
operationalize that in terms of policy
or the economy of the market I have
always argued politically speaking we
gotta keep them separate you're
absolutely right that's a tactic we have
to keep them separate I know every
herbalist every true cannabis person
worth their salt knows that it's all
medical it's all medical because people
self-soothe and self treat for all kinds
of reasons and it's not harmful to do
that but if we if we if we make that if
we try to make that point that it's all
medical don't do it and again we can't
use them yes it's too could use all
you're right it's too confusing and
we're playing around with you know
lifestyles just between you and me and
the microphone okay my friend my friend
who has that Parkinson's now for about
10 years yeah and has resisted cannabis
for all ten years
and I had it readily available for him
in in the right forms and the right
doses and the right excessive
consumption and everything in place but
the state and and he actually his mother
produced cannabis medicine when he was a
child and when I first met him 40 years
ago he used to have this alcohol this
black alcohol that he saw that his mom
has soaked believes in to treat her
arthritis and at that point I was just
becoming a cannabis grower and I kind of
thought that was BS really it was a real
remedy and it it gave her everything
that she needed to treat her arthritis
and this may have a very normal life and
so he saw that but he was still afraid
of it because he grew up with the other
side being enforced you know it's bad
it's medicine as dangerous a dope you
know it's also a Hispanic family so I
think he knew it was best to stay clear
of it and so he did but most recently he
did finally decide that you would try
CBD yes and I don't know that this was
just like a week ago and I don't know
that it has benefited him I think he
waited a lot longer than he should
for effective treatment hey and I don't
know if he's taking enough you may need
to so he'll titrate up and see if it if
he keeps the keep going who knows how
many people change your minds if they
try cannabis and it is or isn't for them
sometimes and that's okay but I couldn't
agree with you more though we have to as
a political strategy we have to keep
them separate
yeah because otherwise we play right
into everybody's prejudices yeah well
then what he said to me says you know he
says gosh you know now that I'm taking
the cannabis and he says now that I
think about it everybody that he knows
who he's known throughout his life used
cannabis that was like they're all in
better health than the people who didn't
use cannabis yeah and I didn't even have
to you know okay no it's absolutely
share some truth to that
you know I've seen that I think maybe it
lowers the stress level keeps the
homeostasis yep helps you know create
let's create yeah no I totally agree I
totally agree it's it's but you wind
down with you know when you need to
which we all do the difference between
us and like when they're at the ended
alcohol prohibition was the alcohol
prohibition didn't have decades and
decades of disinformation campaign
really you know we've got an awful lot
to overcome in terms of those embedded
messages in people's minds
I mean we all make jokes about what's
the movie that you know reefer madness
yeah
and then we make jokes about that but
that's only the extreme you know I've
had patients who actually believe that
it is the devil's drug it's not an herb
it's a drug that weaves you directly to
heroin and crack cocaine they believed
it perfectly so that stuff's not dead
but I think what's far more pervasive
it's just a sphere just as feared
because it's so embedded in us and that
you know people don't like the idea of
losing control of their they think that
they'll somehow come unglued yeah no
it's true but I think there's also the
the disappointing you know it's a every
oppressed group racial minorities women
and immigrants every oppressed people
with disabilities every oppressed group
has a certain amount of internalized
oppression and what we've talked a lot
about in the last four years in the
activist cannabis community in Mendocino
cake is how much of those messages
people have internalized
and feel bad about themselves and feel
guilty and feel like they don't deserve
to get the honor and recognition that we
think they really should have as members
of a cannabis community that produce
this wonderful medicine beating down for
some hope they feel bad so there's an
answer light up exactly so we're talking
about social change after four decades
of prohibition that's not going to
happen overnight
this transition out of prohibition is
going to take we have a very active
social media they can't they can move
information very quickly yeah and
they're they're already becoming
uncomfortable with the pharmaceuticals
you know I know you know I remember the
first time that I saw a pharmaceutical
ad on TV and I haven't had a TV for 30
years so I just catch moments sometimes
it could be a year before or it's in a
bar or a restaurant but even restaurants
didn't always have a TV in them known I
stopped watching TV so there were
periods of years where I may not even
have seen a TV me too yeah and all of a
sudden I would see a TV course then I
would have a pharmaceutical suicide but
over the depression usually sitting with
my parents house yes because that's
where I would end up going to have
dinner yeah getting stuck in front of a
TV set and I and I couldn't believe that
they were watching this yeah and not
alarmed it was just I mean they clicked
through those commercials just like the
other commercials if they remember to
click through them so the so the answer
has always been and everybody says it's
education education so I write an
article where I try to take the science
that we've learned a little bit from the
research studies the the huge Oxford
study about how THC reverses amyloid
plaques reverses Alzheimer's and
dementia the Salk study that from last
summer that substantiates the same thing
and I said okay there's all these new
scientific studies that we didn't know
about before I mean in 1860 Queen
Victoria's person
wrote in his diary using the hemp plant
as they called it back then for older
people with softening of the brain as he
put it has every single time been a
factor in reversing that softening of
the brain it works all the time so you
know we're getting some modern
statements of fact about you know using
people to treat so I was I wrote this
article and it's in the blog if you go
to qu fara dot-com all my blogs are
there it's like what if we started
earlier because all of the studies are
being done with people who already show
signs of dementia what if we started
micro dosing THC at age 50 and just did
it every day routinely don't you think
we might prevent so this is I think
where we can start to bridge that gap
you know and and and what that means is
well on the industry side what it means
is we got to come to terms with micro
dosing THC and not using it as a get
high and on the the medical
practitioners side and the patient side
we've got to start looking at herbal
medicine as a real choice for people to
be allowed to make and you've got I've
got so many patients who say when they
come in to
dragonflay on their like third or fourth
stage cancer and they talking to their
doctors about I'm gonna use cannabis for
to try to get on top of this and the
doctors lean into them and say I'm not
supposed to tell you this but you just
go ahead and do it I cannot tell you how
many times my own primary care physician
I said you know I want to tell you
something about what I'm doing and I
don't want you to type this up on your
computer so you takes his hands off the
keyboard turn sideways to be user
director of the clinic and Castro
mission clinic in San Francisco and I
said I use CBD for my arthritis they
were talking generally about using
cannabis I mean some of them are doctors
of my cat by cancer patients who tell
them they're gonna be using THC oil to
try to treat those cannabis those tumors
I had a 26 year old glioblastoma patient
she had a fourth stage she had of this
huge grill blastoma the
anyway I could tell you so many stories
and we could go on and on and on but
these are doctors who are recognizing
the effects why do we think we hope this
to reduce tumour and kill cancer reduce
tumors and kill cancer absolutely and
and heal other disease I mean this the
zme conference I went to in Columbus
Ohio a month ago this is all doctors and
nurses who are getting continuing
medical education credits to learn about
cannabis as medicine
Wow is that a step forward or what now I
was sitting around a big table of
doctors and nurses who are asking me to
sort of help help them understand what
the ether Rousseau's and the Dustin
Sulak you know they were like big pretty
high-end stuff and talking about how
that has worked with my patients in
practical application and they're
they're just like furious they're just
furious that they were not told a bit of
this in nursing school or medical school
yeah it's a sin and a crime
it is so I don't know two steps forward
three steps back I don't know
so Patrick will just keep doing what
we're doing huh that's right that's
exactly right and doing the education
that I'm really passionate about the
education
[Music]