but now that we're looking at eight
months into the legalized regulated
market and I know from the bureau's
perspective for each part of the supply
chain we've had our own challenges in
regulating so I wanted to get your
perspective on how it has been for you
the last eight months and being in this
regulated market and especially how have
you continued to deal with the changes
that come down because we always talk
about the regulator's you know we keep
changing things on you and so I'm
curious how you've dealt with that you
know you have to stay nimble and you
have to be on top of it I think the
worst thing you can do is refer to
lawyers to interpret the regulations for
you instead of as a business operator
being engaged in them in a line-by-line
fashion and I think that's where some
people have been caught unawares at
times where they're relying on others to
interpret for them rather than as I say
as operators actually being fully
engaged in the text of the regulations
but I think some of the biggest
challenges have been to on the lab side
is the the marketing right of the
regulations is is to help guide people
through things they feel are
unreasonable are things they don't feel
like they should have to do and help
explain and understand to them that this
path forward represents one where we're
taking some extraordinary measures
around the protection of consumer safety
because we lack a certain body of data
so I think one of the biggest challenges
has been to communicate to the people
who are the users of lab testing in this
current market maybe why some of the
things that are in place are there in
terms of being able to react to the
changing regulations mostly you have to
anticipate when you get an initial draft
of regulations you need to take them
almost as if that's what's going to be
because if you wait until the end of a
comment period implementation then
you'll find yourself probably too far
behind
so I think one of the struggles that
people have had is well I don't want to
spend money I don't have to write in
case this thing changes let's say
there's no heavy metals requirement for
example right I don't want to buy an
icp-ms if I don't have to so I think
making those decisions in anticipation
of what could be while trying to manage
cash flow and and and capital is been
challenging as a business owner yeah
absolutely all those points
the I think probably the top level thing
I would say is the ultimate goal was to
transition people from the black market
to the regulated market and for as a
whole supply chain Enterprise such as
group of floor it's frustrating talking
for example to dispensary owners
explaining to them that the packaging we
have actually does comply with the law
and then getting into fights with them
about why it does or does not that that
gets very tiresome so there's a lot of
unknown
I was actually mentioning to you Laurie
before the event there's a lot of
distrust politically there's also a lot
of distrust in our industry towards the
politicians and I think that the more we
can you know connect and demystify a lot
of both ends of that being really useful
for us I think the to see a larger
rollout I think this has been less you
know explosive rollout than we had
anticipated so a lot of people spend a
lot of money and a lot of energy to gear
up for not a lot and so that's been very
frustrating and I hope to see that
evolve well interesting you mentioned
the packaging relationship with
retailers but before I get to that I
would say a sort of on an overall 30,000
foot view of this has been the educating
and talking to both the vendors and the
public because we have both basically to
deal with and the public has been very
frustrated with the rising prices and
the taxes and a lot of that sort of the
education around that component and then
also talking to the vendors and and like
some of us we're talking about before
everybody sort of has their own
interpretation on what's compliant and
what's not and it kind of comes down to
you know sort of making a determination
of within the business of where you know
where you're gonna draw the line and and
what you believe is going to be the
right thing because ultimately I think
if if the intent is there and you're
trying your best to be as compliant as
you can in your own capacity then you're
doing as well as you can but yeah so
it's sort of just been
balancing act and making sure I think
the July first transition was
fascinating it was it was yeah you know
it was it was inevitable and I think
that it were really we're in a really
interesting place in California being
the largest cannabis market in the world
and you know having just one chief
overseeing the the largest cannabis
market and trying to fit all the supply
chains and together and and having
everybody talk to each other and making
sure that that it's working and that we
all are on the basically the same page
so it is a heavy lift but I'm really
glad that it's happening and I think it
if it's done right if people stay
diligent then it can be done oh it's not
entirely impossible but there's always
going to be challenges and always going
to be issues and then there's also the
working with the local jurisdiction I
think has also been a challenge and that
seemed to bring out a lot of players
that had never traditionally come out to
challenge anything regarding cannabis
BPG has been around for almost 20 years
and most of the community members seemed
fine with it and then all of a sudden
January 1st
there was this outpour of interest
groups that were completely opposed and
it was shocking because I nothing really
changed other than who we let in the
door and tweaking security measures so
that was kind of a challenge I agree
with much as much that has been said
already and you know to not repeat any
of that I would say that it really does
feel like we are all you know we've all
got our map on how to try to succeed and
were each interpreting those words
slightly differently as we make our way
through this dark forest because it's
not there's no path it's follow the map
and that's been the challenge is my
impression or my understanding of what
these words say is a little bit
different than maybe somebody else's and
we've got to do business together and
and that creates complexities and at the
same time to make a separate different
I think that we're all able to
understand and measure the success of
this growing regulated market but we're
not able to measure the health and
wellness of the illicit market that
we're trying to deconstruct and that
presents a challenge to me because I can
only understand whether we're making
progress as a regulated market but not
whether or not we are gaining ground on
the illicit market and so I think that's
a lot of really good lead into what
cultivators are facing especially
existing cultivators right we have a
cultivation system that breaks
cultivators in two sizes and scales them
right so you're 2,500 square feet or
you're below 5,000 or you're below 10 or
22 or if you're outdoor you can have up
to an anchor and so California has a 20
year old cannabis industry that's trying
to wrap regulations around a very robust
existing industry this has not been done
before right in most states statute has
passed regulations happen in an industry
is burst right so here in California we
have a whole new paradigm where these
regulators are trying to figure out how
to fit a multi-billion dollar industry
into a linear regulated box so to say so
for existing cultivators were were
having a lot of struggles we didn't we
didn't build our cultivation based on
you know five hundred square foot
increments or 5,000 square foot
increments we built them a lot of times
where they fit in the landscape and so
what we're really struggling with there
are these challenges around how to have
12,000 square feet when the licenses are
ten thousand or twenty two right
economically you don't fit into twenty
two thousand square-foot license and you
don't really fit into ten thousand
because you have twelve thousand so a
lot of our members and the existing
cultivator
especially the seasonal cultivators I
find are really struggling with how to
fit their existing operations into a
regulated model that doesn't have
flexibility right it's really linear and
the issues around shared facilities if I
have to have two licenses because I'm
twelve thousand square feet I now can't
share a processing or a propagation area
so we have lots of providers that have
been working diligently to provide
medicine for patients over the last 20
years that don't necessarily have the
funding to build new facilities nor do
they have the space or necessarily the
land use opportunities because of being
located rural E and they're on a glans
and not on commercial lands or
industrial lands so you know work we're
kind of constantly trying to figure out
how to fit into a system after years and
years of engaging and being involved in
proposition 215 and SB 420 and feeling
kind of really pulled in a multitude of
ways so it's a little bit of a kind of
quicksand scenario for a lot of our
stakeholders and members
[Music]