what's up what's up guys my name is
brandon i'm with athena one of the
founders
um we're gonna be bringing on jungle
boys
pretty quick here um what we're gonna be
doing is
um we're gonna be we had to post a week
ago
that went over the difference between
vdc
and um media ec so
what i did was i called ivan and he had
a lot to say about it and i wanted to
bring him in
and here he is what's up guys
so obviously we did that post last week
uh the difference between vdc
and um maintaining ec in your media and
that's why we kind of got this whole
thing started
um but i wanted to start off and talk
about your guys's
new facility that you got coming online
i think it's cudahy
yep what uh like how many lights
like how many rooms like what do you how
did you guys set it up do you guys feel
comfortable talking about it
sure i'll uh i'll let roach give the run
down uh since he's our project manager
over there
uh that'll give you a little bit of a
rundown of cudahy and where we're at on
it right now
yes basically two-story facility
uh it's got eight flowering rooms
ranging from about 70 to 80 lights
um and a 260 light veg
and genetic holding area mother area
um so full recirculating
uh runoff we take all the one off
clean it sanitize it and then re-feed it
back in through the netaflex
um it's definitely the most
technological facility we've built yet
excited to put plants in it for sure
so is that recirculating new for
california is that active yet or is that
it's not active yet i think it's 2021
i believe where uh it's
department of fish and wildlife or the
water board or both of those two or
requiring
all cannabis facilities to be
uh recycling their runoff and not just
dumping everything down the drain
yeah 2021 no it's got eight rooms how
many lights in each room
70 to 80. okay is there
no now i i go through a lot of your
facilities you know
through the factory and different
different facilities like that they seem
to have a similar amount of rooms um
based on how many weeks right do you so
you guys plan on taking one room down a
week
yeah that's kind of the goal uh with the
eight rooms basically you'll pull down a
room every week
be kind of a smooth smooth kind of
schedule
transition nice cool man well good job
on that i saw
what two weeks ago i haven't posted that
nutrient room is probably the
prettiest nutrient room i've ever seen
so good job roach
thank you thank you so let's let's get
into the questions
um the first question you know we want
to go over that post that athena did
a week ago um what the difference
between
feed ec and ec in your media
um as far as that would be your runoff
as well can you talk about and give us
some insight on how you guys
your sops on that and what you guys do
yeah so there's two different ways to
look at it you can look at it
i'm trying to make it into i'm trying to
when i speak i'm trying to speak in
growers terms i'm not trying to make it
too complicated for everybody
um so if you look at there's two ways to
water your plants right let's say you
have a rockwool cube right let's take a
six inch cube for example
you can you can water it and each time
you water it you can get runoff right
so think of it every time that you're
watering that cube you're resetting that
cube
right so if i'm doing a 3.0 ec and i'm
getting runoff
that cube that the ec inside the cube
is not building as much right
now the way that we do it
going to say this is the right way
because we've done it both ways and both
ways work really great and have a really
good result with it right
is you can stack that cube so imagine
you take little tiny waterings
throughout the day and you're giving
them
short tiny bursts of watering eight ml
10 miles seven ml whatever your drippers
rating is is what we do right so
imagine uh in a twelve hour flowering
the lights come on the first hour now
every hour we're giving them tiny little
bursts of water
but what's happening is now we're
stacking that nutrient inside the cube
so now that 2.0 we see that we
originally fed
now a couple weeks later that 3.0 ac is
a 5.0 ec
of 6.0 ec right but the thing
that you have to be careful with is now
when you start hitting those dry backs
right
and the plant starts drying out right
there's not any water and there's not a
lot of water inside that cube
right so now you're now competing on
that really fine line of burning your
plants
right and
not having enough water for your plants
to pick up
but you also get amazing results doing
that right you can really sit there you
can stress the plan out you can see
you can see things happen that you've
never seen happen before
you know we feel
that not one way is better than the
other necessarily
right i feel like if you have people
that are not as experienced and not
there every single day and watching
everything and have monitoring on every
single cube
and and you know you're you have someone
at your facility 24 hours a day
feeding with a little bit of runoff is a
lot safer you know i don't want people
to take this and everybody go run out
and start putting you know a 7.0 ec
inside their cube because the jungle
boys told us to do it
you know we're not telling people to run
out do this we're just sharing what we
do
so what ends up happening is that we put
a feeding chart out there
and we say hey start out at a 2.0 ec
right and they almost start feeding a
2.0 ec and they have a bunch of runoff
and then they come to us they're like
hey it's not enough food for our plants
right
you guys are set that's what we've been
seeing yeah
you guys are setting us up for failure
our plants are turning yellow
there's i hate feeding charts you know
you know
i've always said this you know what i
mean because it's one well first off
it's all strange specific
you know some strains eat a lot more
than others from somebody very little
nutrients some you're sitting
you know so for us we try to give a
general guideline
and if you're if you're giving your
plants a bunch of runoff
you know and you have a heavy eating
strain a 3.0 vc a plant can take all day
long
no 300 35 ec with a high amount of
runoff
because that's what your media is
maintaining exactly
yeah all day no problems you know but
then
there's also the flip side of that right
let's take a strain like strawberry
shortcake right
strawberry shortcake we would never feed
a 3.0 ec2
it just doesn't it does it won't take it
up it won't eat it you know so there's
always that
small amount of strains that no matter
what you tell someone to feed it's going
to be too much and then there you take
something like topanga
or wi-fi 43 or strain that eats a lot
and you tell someone to give it a 2.00
they're going to come to you and be like
it wasn't enough i didn't give my plants
enough
you know so that's why when nutrient
companies put out the
char it's just a baseline it's to get
you to where you need to be
but depending on your runoff and
depending on how you're stacking your
your cubes in your watering
that's what tells you whether or not you
should be feeding high or low you know
and of course we don't want to go down a
whole another rabbit hole
but then there's there's a whole other
uh
there's some other stuff that we're
playing with feeding way higher than
that
and doing a lot more drybacks but you
really have to be on your game
you know it's like i always tell people
you know you go to the batting cage and
someone throws a softball at you you hit
it you're like i'm a man
you know someone throws a fastball yeah
you're like
let me get the fuck out of here i suck
you know and that's what happens when
you're
stacking these feedings and you start
pulling back waterings you know you can
easily
destroy your crust you can easily fry a
crop
you know but if you're off the game and
you know what you're doing
you know you're going to hit numbers and
you're going to you're going to see
things that you're going to see
you know thc levels and tribal levels
you're going to see that stuff just
let's go through the roof you know
but it's a very funny moment we don't
want to go and put some cruiser card out
there
and say hey guys start expecting these
moves with a 3.0 led
you know and getting too much build up
and locking everything out
yeah 100 because they're because their
runoff is not sufficient
you know i was over at the factory what
a week ago roach
and i saw that all your tanks were at a
2ec
now understanding that the genetics are
getting affected by
the ec value differently are your
water shot volumes changing
based on genetic to build ec higher or
lower based on genetics in that room
while you're feeding a 2ec
does that make sense yeah so usually
we're not really changing the run time
to alter the in the block we'll adjust
it just
how long the dry down period is okay
simple answer you could if you wanted to
lower the ec inside the block you could
use a longer run time and that would
therefore give the plant more runoff and
then lower the ec
or you could do the shorter run time if
you're really trying to stack that ec
to where you get no runoff and then that
goes back to the stacking technique
but you got yeah you guys aren't
changing your run times
you're just changing the frequencies
yeah the time is between frequency
now now given that the factory was
wanted to
running at a 2ec baseline for pretty
much all its flower rooms
though depending on genetic of that room
is depending on how
you're going to monitor that how high
that ec value
goes in that block depending on that
genetic
while using a 2ec you know because
that's the thing
you're not feeding a genetic more you're
just monitoring
that raise inside the cube
verse giving it you know full blown
three four
you know three and a half ec yeah that's
really the only
real reason we're able to do that is
because of the substrate monitoring that
we have
you know if we didn't have the rockwell
monitoring and the ec
and the water content it would be you
know a full-time job for several people
to be checking runoffs on all these uh
on all these rooms and strengths
but having it in like a half where you
can kind of see
water content right there on all the
rooms
now do you like do you have an optimum
root zone temperature
and does that equate to relative
temperature of the room at all based on
that root zone temperature
or what you know what what's your
thoughts on that
oh i mean root's not temperatures for
stir relative to what the room is
you know and if the room's warmer i mean
your meatball is going to be warmer but
it also goes into what your
uh what your what your feet is what your
feed temperatures what your nutrients
are coming into the planet you know if
you have like a really long run
and it's up in your crawl space and it's
120 degrees in your crawl space
and then your pvc is therefore heated up
and your nutrients are there for you
you're going to raise your root
temperature you know yeah so
all that stuff is kind of taken into
account like on these build-outs that we
do as well
do you try to watch it or what i mean
what do you do you like to see a certain
number do you like to see it not go over
a certain number
you're just kind of you know anything
over 80 definitely isn't good
yeah get out but um we're not
we're we air condition our uh
our irrigation room so our water stays
about like
67 degrees anyways
yeah 73 74 75
um so our water's not really getting too
ever i personally realize it's
i don't really focus on water temp that
much at my grows
i don't like to see it go over 78 yeah
but other than that you know it's it's
pretty but that was one of the questions
that we had gotten
um now yeah i mean if you're if you're
on a small scale and you can you know
really dial in your water temperature
i'm sure you'd see a little bit of a
difference you know but the biggest
difference you're going to see is not
letting it get too warm you know i've
seen large facilities i know a couple
people that just had this issue recently
or like roach was saying they ran all
their pipes up in the attic
and now their attic gets 120 degrees
during the summer time and they're
having all these issues and they're like
oh it's good you know
all this hot water sitting there
yeah i've done that before uh
so when we're talking about blended
compared to pro
i know you guys were flowering some
rooms over at 58 on blended
um and then i definitely i know that the
the the nursery is all using blended
right what is
what's your thoughts about the
comparison i mean when would you use
blended
as far as you know uh compared to pro on
on a grow
yeah i mean it honestly just comes down
to what our employees are comfortable
using
right so we have we have so food for
both of them
right and some guys like mixing
you know a two part right out of the bag
and some guys just feel more comfortable
mixing a bottle
you know yeah for us
if the guys are really good at what they
do and they've been doing it for a
really long time
you know and they've worked on growth
for years you know guys been with us 10
plus years
you know we have a grower that grows
amazing cannabis says listen
i feel comfortable with this and i like
what i do and i'm used to it
and this is my rhythm and this is my
routine that's what i like to do
you know go ahead you know
i think that uh it just comes down to
the grower
you know and what they want what they
prefer you know
budget wise too you know i know they're
not there's not a lot of difference
money-wise you know
one might be a little bit cheaper than
the other one you know um
yeah that's all it really comes down to
you know
now this is a question that we get all
the time you know
um do you ever sometimes i'll be talking
to people
like yeah you know this is how ivan's
running this is how roach runs it
you know um and they're like come on bro
like
they're adding other shit in there like
i know they're adding something they've
got to be adding some
sweet or or or organic input
or this or that what like what's the
real deal like what are you guys adding
i mean to be honest we spent years and
years and years
um adding a lot of shit to the to the
reservoirs
you know i mean there was there was one
time we were adding
and he was
all liquids all liquids you know we've
been through it all
you know we've no one has done more side
by side
comparisons and i'm talking real side by
side i'm talking taking thousands of
and taking multiple rooms and doing
multiple side-by-side devices with the
same cranes under the same lights
you know what i mean same room same
everything you know this is in some one
row
you know things might look a little bit
better because it gets a little bit like
light you know i'm fucking taking full
60 light runes and doing full
side-by-side you know multiple times
over and over and over
yeah and every time we would take
something out
and we would take something out and we
would take something out
and then we would get to the very end to
the real base of it what we really
needed we'd always have the best results
sure there was one time that we had a
great run and you know that was this
mythical one that everything
lined up and all the stars lined up you
know but at the end of the day
you know what i mean yeah i mean i just
think they just brought some dosy killer
in there right now that was blue that i
was just like this is fucking
unbelievable
you know what i mean there's a fucking
fire
you know and that was you know there's
one thing
you know nothing at it you know we had
to claim
we have clinton and that's it
you know there's we really do try to
keep it simple
you know well we really do try to
eliminate all those questions and errors
and did this get out at the right time
did they add too much of this
we've kind of eliminated all that you
know i think
i think seems like you guys are focusing
more on your dry backs
and your dr you know your dry backs to
increase that
that terpene content and that thc verse
thinking that an organic input of some
sort is going to do it for you because
if you had to talk to me three years ago
and
knowing what i thought i knew back then
i would say hey
you have to add an organic input to get
the container
yes and but the more that i had kind of
adjusted to
just going with core girl or core bloom
cleanse the more i was like whoa like
this is where it's at
so um my ghost do you guys use any
micros with your clones anymore i knew
that
you know a few years ago you did are you
guys using anything yeah we
we did for a really long time you know
what i mean it it might shave off a day
or two
you know it's just being real you know
what i mean like anyone made really good
stuff
you know jordan yeah that michael jordan
stuff was fire
you know um but at the end of the day
shaving off a day or two
you know what i mean we weren't really
seeing the
a day or two you know what i mean just
hit the drive back perfectly right you
know we're not seeing that
we're not going from 14 days to seven
days because if it was 14 days or seven
days we'd be using that shit
yeah yeah you know but at the end of the
day
you know if someone's using something
and they like it we're not going to tell
them not to use it
you know what i mean like i used i used
caps venues for years it was my go-to
you know
i'll still pull it out to this day if
we're having issues and do a four-year
sprint
yeah you know it's like it's like magic
in a bottle you know but do i lose
anything
yeah would you want more for sure yeah
but do i use it every single day on my
grow
you know do i soak every single cube
with it no i don't
you know but if i see some
something going on that i don't like
will i hit it with the foot absolutely
you know yeah that's good you know
so um this is a big one you know
um ipm so what's the sop
what's the secret look i mean you got
how many facilities you have eight
uh nine nine nine facilities
how many lights right now thousands
yeah i don't even i can't i can't i
don't even really
i succeed yeah close to 4 000 lights i
mean you
most people you got to be like bro you
got to be using botana guard max vinner
a fucking
you got to use this you got to use that
you know what's what's your ipm regiment
what's your program
what is that yeah i mean ipm is our
go-to
you know that's our go-to it's what it's
what we've used for a long time
you know and we've been trying to get it
out to the to the public for a long do
you know this brandon we've been telling
you like dude
we need to get this out we need to get
this out we need to get this out
yeah you know um
but it's it it just comes down to it it
goes to the same thing you know i tell
people if you're using something that
works for you and you've used it for a
really long time you don't
have issues stick to what works for you
you know
all we can tell you is what works for us
you know all we can say is hey listen we
run almost 4 000 lights
in la where we have to deal with a
a bunch of issues you know what i mean
we got homeless people right outside the
door
you know and we'll we'll also we'll also
do we'll also fog the rooms we we uh we
play around with with uh heating the
rooms a lot
you know after each run we'll keep the
room as hot as we can get them
you know and when i say as hot as we can
get them 150 degrees plus
yeah you know because because because
that temperature matters you know if you
if you really look at the chart and what
actually starts killing things you know
you got to get the rooms
really hot you know i mean we've gotten
the room so hot before that we broke the
sprinkler bags before
you know that so you got to be careful
you know
and i'm not talking getting your room to
100 degrees i'm talking about getting
your room to 150 degrees
what's the hottest we've ever gotten
into uh it was like 150 on the floor 165
on the ceiling
yeah yeah so what we do for that
and this is a really good tip for any
grower without plants that was with not
without
there was no plants
yeah yeah there was no plants in there
that was after we tore it out
so you teared them in your room and now
all the plants are out right so anything
that was airborne any spores or anything
that that could have
could have uh gotten into your room at
that point is the time to heat treat
your room as fast as you get the plants
out of there as fast as you can heat
treat that room
that's what you want to do and when i
say heat treat 150 degrees there's a
there's a number
i'll i'll i'll come back and edit this
and get the exact number
but we shoot for as high as possible
because you gotta remember at 120
it does like powdery mildew even if we
don't
you know if we never have an issue we do
this
we do this religiously at all of our
facilities
and the way we get this is we cut off
our air conditioners
we turn on our dehumidifiers because the
dehumidifiers make heat
and we turn our lights up all of our
lights up to 100
and we let the room bake how long yeah
how how long usually three hours three
hours
yeah yeah and the key is is not doing it
and going home and then coming back the
next day
when you're when you're i mean we've
literally had schedule 80
melt on the wall because the room is so
hot
yeah yeah so
on using the athena ipm
look are you using are you using
anything else
then other than athena ipm to spray
no not currently you you know i mean
well uh
in our in our nursery we'll hit it we'll
uh hit uh the moms with regalia every
once in a while
okay you know as if not as a drench as a
full year but our main
go-to spray is ipm that's that's our
go-to that's our
you know we you gotta remember it's a
drench you have to drench the plants you
you can't just go in the room and open
the door up and spray a few plants
like okay i sprayed my room you have to
saturate the plants top to bottom
we get it we get the stems we get those
plants should be dripping
uh yeah two times a week i mean minimum
is two times a week
you know three times if you have a
problem or whatever just
exactly i mean if you have i mean to be
honest if you have a problem you know if
you're battling something like pm or
mites or something
i'd hit it as often as possible we'd hit
it sometimes twice
you know twice in the same day you know
morning and later on in the day i mean
this is if you're battling something bad
you know
we haven't battled anything in years you
know what i mean we keep really clean
and sterile facilities but
if i came in here and i seen i mean i i
don't remember the last time i seen a
spider mite you know i mean but if
someone was like hey we've seen some
lights or something you know what i mean
i go i go to war with them you know and
i'd hit them apart
you know but e-treating with
ipm i mean really killer combo right
there
okay um cool yeah that's not very often
when you talk to somebody at that scale
and they say hey i use one thing
so people are just probably like how's
you know and that's
i had the reason why is because i had
the same reaction
you know when when we were when we were
developing it and going over all that
stuff
you're like bro i use one thing this is
it yeah i'm just saying yeah
i mean we'll we'll bust out uh sanitate
2.0 oxidate 2.0 you know what i mean
we'll bust it out and we'll we'll rotate
every once in a while you know what i
mean
just for peace of mind so we're not
using the same thing over and over again
you know what i mean uh like i said
we'll use we'll use some regalia on the
moms just to boost their immune system
early on
you know what i mean um but are we
spraying regalia in all the rooms
all the time like we're doing ipm no you
know what i mean
um i think that it just comes
down to like i said if you're spraying
something in your facility and you're
not having any issues
stick to it just keep going with it yep
keep going
you know all right sop for cloning
you know that's probably you know
maybe what ec value you know what cubes
are you using
what do you like to feed ec value in
your cubes what do you like to maintain
maybe possibly a drench initial drench
ec
and yeah what do you use yeah so
uh we have a what we call the nursery
right
so we have a nursery crew that handles
all of our cuttings and our moms and all
that stuff
and this is all stuff that we've done
over the years and we've kind of refined
it
and we're all we all do the same thing
right so we have one
major hub that puts out all of our
cuttings for us and all of our moms but
each facility also does their own moms
and cuttings so
imagine you need ten thousand cuts a
week right
seven thousand of those cuttings come
from our nursery and then you're
responsible for your other three
thousand cuttings
right for every spot every location yeah
and that's how we run our locations
right wow so what's happening
behind that um because all of our
genetics aren't in one building so if we
ever have an issue
right everything is protected so each
facility houses genetics
right let's say we had a fire or god
forbid anything happened you know what i
mean
we somebody broke in and installed our
genetics you know which would be
impossible to do because you're talking
about thousands of likes you know
but at least we know we have them backed
up somewhere and they're not with some
other random person that we don't know
or some tissue culture lab that we don't
know what they do behind the scenes you
know what i mean
so we kind of protect all of our
genetics in-house you know
that's why that makes sense yeah so uh
right so when you when i knew this
question was going to come up so
uh i wrote it all down so uh 3mls
of uh grow a b right
200 ml of calmac that gives you an ec
of 0.7
okay ph of 5.5 5.7
so this is taking your initial preso
right you get your clone tray you get
your individual cubes they're on a map
right we take that in that right
three mls eight three mls of b right
two mls calmag right
ph of 5.5 5.7 we do 5.7 but i always say
5. but listen if it's 5.4 to
5.8 you're fine yeah yeah but everyone
likes to know what we do we do it at 5.7
and grow down
lower ph's higher ph's
we've had great results with all of them
5.7 5.5 puts us right where we want to
be at
right so now you've you've done your
initial soaking you plugged your
cuttings now
it's time to water them right now
they're starting to bust through this
time to watering
how long do you weigh how many days you
usually i know it's all different right
but
you know usually unusual two weeks to 20
12 to 10 days to 20 days yeah
10 to 20 days depending on the the
strength
first water oh first watering uh
five to ten five to ten five to ten all
right yeah
depending if you know these ones dried
out quick they're busting roots fast you
could
see them start coming out you can't pull
them out you know
okay you know but also we grow
so many different varieties right yeah
i mean you're talking hundreds and
hundreds of different strains right
some of them are five days some of them
are or
you know tending you know yeah
so clone feed is four to four and a half
ml per gallon right
2.5 cal mag right that gets you an ec
of 1.1 and then same thing pa
5.7 okay okay
cool no cleanse
say that again no cleanse is there a
reason why i'm not using
uh yeah so we'll use plans as a dunk
you know we'll dunk the cuttings and
cleanse you know we use it as a full
year
right and then after after they start
busting their roots then we'll add the
cleanse to it
okay you know uh and that's just like i
said that's what the nursery feels
comfortable doing
you know and then from there on out it
gets plans all the moms get clams added
to it
but that's you know that's the guys this
is what we do this is what we feel
comfortable doing
hey i'm not going to tell you with the
results that we get
these guys are popping up i'm talking
you know 6 000
cuts a week 10 000 cuts you know what i
mean yeah
per facility you know i'm not going to
tell them hey
do something a little bit different try
to tweak this just leave it alone it's
not broken
i tell that to a lot of people just yeah
but we we
we failure with plans all the time you
know well that was another thing i guess
that would be part of our ipm too
you know we'll the only thing is you do
have to
you do have to use a lot of it that's
the only downfall it's like
how many amount do you have off the top
300 and something ml
it's like 300 something in miles per
gallon which is a lot
yeah you know so but it's also if you're
having an issue or you see something
that you don't like
it's a go-to you know start hitting
things with it you know
yeah and it doesn't have any it's not
harsh on the plants
yeah real real quick on uh when people
are asking questions in the comment
we'll try to get to some of the
questions in the comments
we gotta tell you right here she's
writing them down cool
cool if there's a bunch of spam then not
even
yeah if you see any good ones shout them
out and then we'll just go over
real quick so we got slp for cloning you
got the ec value on that
um co2 controllers and regulators i mean
you feel comfortable talking about what
you're using in your rooms and
yeah sure so um we use big giant
uh co2 tanks liquid co2 uh
and we have a company that comes and
they fill our
co2 so like we're at the factory right
now for here we have like eight or nine
giant co2 tanks and that feeds
each room we're required to have a high
co2 monitor in every single room
and from there all we're doing is a
simple co2
regulator was it a
you know uh cheap titan regulator you
know
uh turning the co2 on and off you know
okay um but but yeah liquid co2 we don't
we used to use gas
and we had issues with propane and then
natural gas and then
you know bottles are really hard to fill
so we use a service that does big huge
baths of liquid co2
what about controller-wise what are you
guys
on the controller well we used to use
sentinels which
they made the best controller but they
stopped making them for some reason out
of the blue they just stopped making
them
uh most of our facilities are signals
they've been running for years and we
haven't had any issues
um but since we've been able to
it's not something that we've done in
the past so cudahy will be all ahead of
him
okay um
now any so you guys are using groceries
right now
yes and then uh so we've used grow
stands at all of our facilities
and then cudahy we're gonna go with the
yeah full full climate full full
monitoring
is there a reason is there a reason why
you're looking at doing that or
looking at making that transistor was it
is more available more
info what do you i mean just the
flexibility we have at that facility we
can pretty much
have every single solenoid in the
building
get it different nutrient and or feed
and or
time per day like uh just the
full flexibility that we have at that
location compared to some of our other
ones we've basically taken like
everything we've learned at these past
eight facilities that we built nine
facilities that we built we put it
all in the cut hey so uh definitely kind
of like the top
technological one that we have
with kind of the most uh
kind of tech fancy stuff you could say
short short forms you know full
monitoring
full recirculation um
yeah everything on floats yeah it's the
masterpiece
it's it's rosh's master plan yeah you
know
um awesome no cool yeah i think that's
going to be big
you know and then uh i get a lot of this
all the time
cal mag with the pro line everyone's
trying to add cal mag to the pro line do
you guys
ever ever add cal mag while using
proline
no that's insane no i don't know why no
don't do it i don't i don't understand
why someone would do that
you know i get it you know what i mean
cow may count my cow mate you know
people are trained and
they get it instilled in their head you
know but all that stuff is built into
the line
you know we spent a lot of years testing
and sending shit off the labs and r
being it going over and over and over
with it
that line is figured out when you can
ask brandon
i don't let anything get by me yeah
nothing got by these facilities that
wasn't tested 100
and we went through everything a million
times and
and and trialed and narrowed it over and
over again before we took this is the
one and release it
yeah no one has spent more money than r
d than we have i promise you that
yeah i could have retired a long time
ago
yeah yeah so no i'm glad we got that out
of the way because you're
we're getting guys all the time trying
to add calmac to the pro line i'm like
just
don't ruin it like it's perfect you know
the ratios are perfect you got to pay
attention to your shop volumes and your
ec and your media
and how you're going to do that but as
far as
what it is just don't add anything to it
and mess it up
yeah that's kind of my my philosophy
still work
so we're clear with everyone there's
there's two lines there's a liquid line
and there's a powder line
the liquid line yes you add helmet
the pro line the powder line you do not
add cow make it's already built in
yeah 100 um did you take down some
questions there are some good ones you
want to
i'm finishing one more all right so this
is some uh
questions that just come up temp plus
vpd in um flour
what uh timpin which what do you like to
run your your temp in humidity and fire
for vpd
i mean we we kind of just follow that
bbd chart right as long as we can we
push it we push the vpd chart as long as
we can
right so if you look at that chart you
know
it it the way everybody builds their
facility is a little bit different
right so if you look at that chart and
78 degrees
and 69 humidity puts you right in that
sweet spot
that's that number you should stick for
you know for us
our temperatures are a little bit warmer
you know we run our
we run our rooms more warmer and more
humid
earlier on veg and flower you know
but you also you see other people and
they have all these humidifiers in their
room and they're trying to get as much
humidity in their room as possible
the way we build them and we design our
rooms is we don't need to do that
because we built it within the air
conditioning system within the walls we
make it so our rooms can get humid when
we want them to be humid
and when we want to pull out that
humidity we can pull all that humidity
out
you know so if i tell somebody hey we
run our rooms at
85 degrees and 70 humidity early in veg
and flower
and they're trying and trying and trying
to get there and they just can't get
there and they're chasing those numbers
you know i'd rather see somebody say hey
i can get to that same
sweet spot because if you look at the
vpd chart that's not the only number
that gets you there
you know so maybe i'm at 78 degrees and
i'm at 65
humidity what we're doing we're actually
doing the same exact thing
you know so when people i don't support
your temperature and humidity it's a
great question
because it's very important you know but
you might not be able to get your
champion committee where i can get my
attempted community at
and there's nothing wrong with that you
just need to look at the vpd chart and
you need to be right within that sweet
spot
yep cool um what week do you
i know ideally we don't like to spray
into flower
i mean with ibm but what week do you go
up to
well i mean what week if you're on a
we'll do it two different questions if
you're
on a maintenance program you don't have
any problems and you're using athena ipm
what yeah do you stop spraying athena
ipm
like week two week two yeah yeah
you know but hey listen if if you're
like hey i've seen
problems pop up in the in the past and
i've had issues
i mean you can spray that all the way
you know there's no issues with testing
or anything you know
it's just do you want to spray your
plants late flower nobody wants to do
that
yeah you know what i mean but are you
going to have residuals and are you
going to pass testing
yeah absolutely you're going to pass
testing you know i mean you're not going
to have any of you
you know but we always say you got to
find that sweet spot
of when you can spray to you know and
same thing just because we say hey we
stop as early as possible
if you're having issues i'm not going to
tell you to stop spraying
yeah yeah you know i'm not going to tell
you don't spray till week three
you know you need to spray when you have
a problem but ideally we too
stop ideally with anything you know what
i mean you want you want to cut it off
as early as possible
you know and that's the thing you know
plant count how many plants do you have
in your room what's your airflow what's
all that stuff i mean
there's guys i gotta pray until week six
or seven and flower
yeah you know and i'm not gonna tell
that guy like that does what he does
every single day to stop doing that you
know what i mean but
it's not ideal you shouldn't have to do
that if you're on your plans and you're
stripping them early enough
you shouldn't have to do that if you're
happy to do that you need to be focusing
on your environment and fixing the
problems there before
you know yeah airflow has a airflow is
is very very very important
um how do you are you guys using powersi
and how are you guys using it yeah so
uh we'll hit him with the foliar early
in flower
we don't hit him religiously because
there's not always times that we want to
necessarily slow down the stretch
yeah you know so if there's times where
hey we over veg a little bit the room
wasn't ready
this is the thing is we never chop our
rooms early
right we have rooms that go 70 plus days
you know we don't we don't grow we don't
flower based on hats right so we're not
we don't have any rooms that are
dedicated to hatch
right so if we flower a room and that
room is going to need to go 72
days the hashmakers can come in at 65
days
when they scope and they say this is
perfect they can come in at 65 days and
take the plants out
the rest of the plants are going to stay
inside the room we're not going to go
and stop some room at 50 days because it
makes the best blonde
prettiest hash and then the same flowers
end up on the shelf we don't do that
yeah yeah so i think that's also
important to know too
you know is we're taking these plants
you know
so if you have if you have plants that
hey maybe you took them over a week
because they just weren't done enough or
you have one tree in there that needs to
go a little bit longer
then we'll hit them with some power
outside and slow down the stretch
you know i mean everyone knows it's
amazing stuff you hit them you
hit them in flower i mean it makes
plants stack it's great stuff you know
it's a great folder to act
you know um but are we hitting every
single
are we hitting la cush cake with it that
that stacks hard isn't it
four pounds of light no are we hitting
mac with it no
you know what i mean are we getting some
ogs that got over
vegged a little bit and i'm looking at
like damn they should have went on day
seven and not day twelve
yeah we'll hit them for sure yeah as a
foiler
yeah okay um
have you seen me for me all that stuff
i've always been taught
that most of that stuff regalia
rsi it always works better as a foliar
spray you know
us as growers we're lazy of course you
want to just give it to them in the roof
and not have to deal with spraying
but i've always been taught and i've
always seen with my own eyes
that foliar spray for your spraying
these things
is you know it's like maintaining your
plants you know it worked
you know it gets them underway
so have you seen a uh a difference
in yield from pro to blended
or you know or growth from proto blended
at all
in flower no you know and it comes down
to the same thing you know
it's it's it comes down to the grower
you know there's no we don't run now i
can tell you this
i have seen a difference compared to
other lines you know when we did
side by sides with with uh blended and
proline you know
our a liquid line i mean it was
we've seen incredible differences
quality wise yield wise
but neck to neck head to head i mean
they're very similar they're both really
clean they both
they both go and clean come out clean
you know
white ash you know flush easily
you know uh but yeah it's it's
i can't say i see some huge difference
you know but there's also
you know if somebody overfed their
plants with the powder line and then
under fed their pla
or gave the right amount with the liquid
line of course you're going to have
better results
yeah so that's what i feel a lot of it
but when i see people test things right
and they use a new nutrient they're like
oh it didn't work that good i didn't
have that good results well if you did
the same exact thing you were doing with
your own nutrient line
you know of course you didn't have the
same results because
everything's a little bit different
there's different ratios and there's
different numbers and plants uptake
things differently
you know so it's like it's a good
baseline you know where to start you
know what your plants like
but there's always a little bit of
tweaking higher
you know let's talk co2 real quick is
there
i mean do you do you adjust the co2 in
your flower rooms at all
uh as far as uh levels of parts per
million
or do you equate co2 levels of parts per
line to your feed
ec at all
uh we usually just turn it down uh
to 500 parts per million like first day
of week seven
that's pretty like we usually keep it
right at like twelve to fifteen hundred
parts per million
and then fucking right at week seven cut
it down to 500
day one week eight it's off okay cool
so i love it simple yeah
one one other question i've seen in here
is somebody asking us if we could do a
fl
a clone feed chart yeah absolutely so we
we uh we
shared exactly what we do for clones but
uh athena would be more than happy for
our customers to make a clone feed chart
because we want you guys to have the
same success we're having
for sure yeah yeah we'll do that we'll
make it uh we'll have it up by next week
um so 12 to 1500 questions on the on the
ppms and then
week seven drop it to 500 parts per
million uh yeah i mean you can go
if you wanted to you can map your
feedings and and and do all that stuff
you know what i mean we've done it
before but
12 to 1500 seems to be the sweet spot
and and another big thing that people
always miss out on is co2 and bitch
co2 early in flower you know i mean one
of the most important things in the time
that you're going to see the best growth
with co2
is early in veg and early and flower you
know i mean
it's it's you want to talk about the
levels and veg that you guys like to
maintain
1500 you know i gotta remember we're
running our veggies really hot
hot and humid you know and that's when
co2 worked the best you know
so we'll get those i mean you i mean
that's that's how we got the name the
jungle boys you know you walk into one
of our rooms you're like holy shit it's
fucking jungle in here you know yeah so
so you walk into our bedrooms you're
sweating your glasses automatic i can't
even wear glasses inside the bedroom you
know because
they automatically you know um
and that's when that's when you see uh
that's when you see that that that
explosive growth is when you're hitting
them
early in veg and early in flower with
co2
nice um somebody asked
your time really quick i i just went
cure time and flush time so
we flush for uh about two weeks right
the last two weeks of growth is when
we're flushing our plants but we're also
monitoring the inside of our cubes and
we're dropping our feedings
so i mean we can we can flush a plant
and get it to a
zero ec in a day or two you know but we
also allow that plant to recover and
take all that up
you know and make sure that there's
nothing inside of it so
the easy answer is two weeks of flush
time okay
and then cure
but slowly dropping dc value slowly
dropping ec
values as we pull our drybacks as as
we're drying the plants out
more right so later in flower
you want to take that water out of the
plant you don't want a bunch of water in
the plant later in flower
yeah you want to do high hot longer dry
backs yes but you also got to be careful
with doing dry vacs later in flour
because if there's a bunch of nutrient
inside that cube
that's when you walk in the room like
why'd my plants fry why they look like
shit why do i have all this burnt leaf
on my plants
because inside of your cube had a high
ec and you were pulling it back
and the plant did water to uptake yep
um what sprayer are you
using for foiler feeds or foil sprays
uh i mean we don't really i mean if
anything you know
back in the day you guys made uh the
paint sprayer what's that company
graco a lot of money oh my god you guys
you guys i mean their revenue when you
guys uh
first dropped the pay sprayer back in
the day went crazy
i mean i know i switched from that you
know uh
that system that was a game changer for
sure
yeah but uh i think you guys are
were you the dram 50 right now yeah now
we just have drams in all of our
facilities you know they cost
as much as a fucking honda civic you
know they're expensive
you know every time i see one i'm like
damn i just bought a honda civic right
now
you know um but you know
the time that you save and the the
being able to have a hose that you can
go throughout the whole facility
like here we have it upstairs and the
downstairs so we have one upstairs we
only have three here right
i think we have three here we have one
in the we have one of the badges
one for all our fire rooms downstairs
and one for our flower rooms upstairs so
we don't have an elevator here
um so we can't be carrying those things
up and down the stairs
yeah um we had another question here
curing process
you know how long are you guys carrying
flour for temps
yeah so uh so same thing that we've
always said
60 60 is what we shoot for in the drying
room
you know 60 degrees 60 humidity you know
and depending on how the temperature and
weather is outside
and all that stuff 14 to 16 days the
plants will sit inside there and hang
you know
so at that time that that's the start of
the cure process
you know and then from there they get
bend up in big bends
you know where they'll sit for about 10
to 14 days
yeah yeah in bands you know and then
from there they'll go to the trimmers
you know so so total cure time is three
to four weeks
you know counting drying and when they
go into the bins
you know which is plenty of time you
know you got to remember
no one has done more testing than we
have and no one can tell you that those
terpenes start to degrade
and anybody that tells you that a long
cure is better
that's some bro science shit because i
spend
millions and millions of dollars on
testing and sending cannabis to labs and
telling me when is the peak time for
terpenes
and when once that cannabis is dry
the every single day those terpenes
degrade
so when people say well why don't you
why don't you guys cure your
your your flower well we don't want it
it's like saying why don't you open a
banana and sit on the table and eat it
three weeks later
yeah it's exactly it's the same exact
thing happened you know what i mean
and the testing tells us this all the
time because when we send a fresh flower
that's just been cured and just been
trimmed to the lab
and it's three percent terpenes right
and then three weeks later it's one
percent turbulence
you know it's degrading you know yeah so
i've always i've been saying this for
years you know cannabis is like fresh
fruit you know i like my fruit fresh
i don't like my fruit you know four
weeks later when it's been sitting in
the bowl and it's all rotted out and
it's the same exact thing
ideally what how many weeks do you like
to see it on your shelf
i mean so let's take we we hung it in
our room that took about 14 days
right and then let's say seven to ten
days by the time it gets
bent up and trimmed up and processed and
sent off to the lab you know
so from the time it's actually dried
completely dried
seven to fourteen days okay and that's
as fast as possible that i mean
you you you can't do any fashion it has
to be trimmed it has to be sent out for
testing you have to wait for the test
results
then once you get the test results you
package it you stick it you put it on
the shelf
that's as fast as possible sure we might
be able to save off a day or two but
with the legal market that's about as
fast you can get it out
yeah you've seen that delay with testing
probably about a week or so
five days yeah i mean you know if
if three days is like a really fast
turnaround for the lab
but five days is about where all the
labs are at right now
okay any other questions those are the
main big ones
i think those are the main big ones you
know yeah
that was about an hour yeah so real
quick i just got another one unknown
profit what up bro
ec and coco what's the maximum you
suggest
so if you caught the beginning of this
we talked about it and we're going to
replay it
it goes for this when we talk about coco
when we talk about rockwool
they're both hydroponic mediums they're
both very similar the only downfall
about cocoa is you can order the
substrate
there's not a lot of tools out there
like grow sense that'll let you monitor
the substrate
so with cocoa you're better off getting
a little bit of runoff with coco
and with that as long as you're getting
runoff you can
feed pretty high you know i'm talking
clones i'm not talking seed you know of
course seeds need
less cc and you can eat them a lot less
but i'm talking an old clone that's been
around forever
most all of them can take a really high
ec you know a 3.0 ec in cocoa
no issues whatsoever you know but if
you're
you're hitting a 3.0 in cocoa and you're
letting your plants dry back a whole lot
then you're going to have a bunch of
issues
it seems like cocoa holds on to a little
bit more than the rock will
sure yeah definitely that's why i'm
saying make sure you have runoff if
you're if you're playing with higher ec
and coco
i know it's a little early you know as
far as the leds go
um you know we've done a lot of testing
on him but
how are you feeling how you feeling
about leds versus
hps on that front you know i know it's
kind of off the topic but i get i'm
getting a lot of uh
yeah i mean i'm stoked about the leds
for the shorter plants
you know so that those short to medium
plants i'm super stoked about them i
think they
they they can they can hold their own
you know the far bigger plants that
stack all the way down and they grow
bigger and they're
i don't think the led is where it's out
for us
but if but we grow so many varieties
that we could literally have varieties
that we just grow under leds
you know yeah so a lot of our shorter
and medium-sized plants
all those plants are going into our led
rooms we just had we had a 77 light
uh de luxe room at
cudahy and we pulled those down we're
putting up leds
because we were stoked with the results
and we figured hey we can grow our
shorter
to medium plants here which we have a
ton of you know
and that's going to be the plan for our
leds right now is we're going to focus
on
our uh our short and our medium plants
will be growing under leds
nice no it's good to know and what do
you think
we do get a lot of inbound about double
stacking
on flour what is your opinion on the
efficiencies of double stacked flour
and would you guys ever think about
doing a double stack flower
and why oh we've thought about it for
sure
i mean there's been many times that i've
walked in the room like
we should double stack this room you
know
it just becomes it comes down to quality
right
when you start having things that aren't
in front of your face every single day
the things on the top kind of get
forgotten about yeah
you know it's not right in front of your
face every single day so when you're
doing it on such a large scale
you know if you know i had a garage and
i had you know eight lights and i was
double stacking i'm there every single
day i'm working
sure you know but when you're on a large
scale and things get put on top and
they're not in front of your face
a lot of times things get neglected you
know but
if you're if you're if you're going watt
for watt and you're growing
a large plant and you're double stacking
you're putting led and led but you could
do the same thing with an hbs plant and
grow a bigger plant and get
you know i have to see the numbers i
still haven't seen anything that fully
convinces me quality wise that double
stacking is where it's at
quality and quantity wise you know but
listen i'm i'm open to anything
you know like i'm not gonna say i would
never do a double stack because
next week i'm gonna do a double stack
you know i'm not saying that i am but i
probably will
you know but right now i haven't seen
anything that says we need to go double
stack
yeah you know you need to have the
facility for it too yeah you can't do a
double stack in a
12-foot ceiling room i mean it's just
going to make your life so hard
yeah yeah 100
that's pretty much it hey guys
i think that's how you guys doing good
good
appreciate everybody coming on here
we're gonna we're gonna post this right
so everyone could
no it's cool like this was uh invaluable
information i know it's big
to you know for for a cultivator you
know like you guys to be just giving
this information out
to the masses is is huge and i think a
lot of people that's why
you're the jungle boys a lot of people
respect that you know i know that
i have my life as far as my business is
my grows and everything have come a long
way since
since uh since i started following you
many years ago and
and just i know a lot of people
appreciate it and it means a lot so
thank you very much
appreciate it thank you guys thanks see
ya