Ryan Martinez it was the ED girl for
jungleboy and she was my best friend
since 16 I'd laugh because I hadn't
particularly gentlemen it was funny with
just the way the world works
my wife and I are up at a show in and
Northern California at the High Times
event we get up to drove the blades down
I don't give out aids very often when
we're judging weed so we walk in and I'm
standing there at the counter I'm like
honey check it out that is an a-plus and
so is that and so is that she like looks
at me in shock she's like what those
three right I get the height bed yeah
those three right there are a pluses
that stuff over there is kind of a beat
but these three right here those are a
pluses those are solid solid genetics
right there so like four months later
I'm in another conversation with a
friend and he's like oh yeah do you know
the head girl for jungleboy system I
know no idea it's like it's Ryan
Martinez I just started laughing I'm
like had to be one of five people I know
okay add to be that I grew up with he
was a big grower right here in Malibu
and he helped me develop my program back
when we were 18 years old we worked
together you know like you know screwing
up plants feeding him to death live and
learn right this iteration so it was so
funny when I just died of Tears when and
it just was like oh my god what a small
world call him up I'm like hey dude you
had lost touch with him I just yeah I
had been in Montana growing for seven
years and you know he came up actually
when I set up my program in Montana you
know cuz he was my best friend but we
just had gone gone our ways and doing
our thing and
you know he got married and had a kid
and he was down here busy as hell and I
was up there just busy as hell you know
just living your life right and just you
know a few highs but not any real
communication you know and I just died
of Tears what I'd like had to be one of
five people it was either Ryan Martinez
Marshall Davis Kelly bellissima you know
who grew that our jungle boys out of LA
they wanted me to come on board with
them but their their culture isn't
exactly my culture they have a certain
swagger you know where I'm more of a
low-key quiet farmer I don't play with
anything white I smoke weed