I find a lot of benefits to just the
oils and the creams for for pain joint
pain and stuff like that it's been huge
I actually retired in 2011 because of
back pain and one of the things that
really helped me was was smoking
cannabis there was so much pain that it
hurt if I sat down or her if I stood up
and heard if I moved it didn't matter
and it was extremely helpful and allowed
me to function on a daily basis and
little by little able to kind of work my
way back into training but yeah and I'm
the kind of person that if I'm not doing
martial arts I'm miserable I get
depressed so I need that as an outlet
for for me physically and creatively and
if cannabis is has allowed me to do that