[Music]
if I compare myself to other food
companies that make food without the
Cannabis component what's the difference
well I mean I I've been saying the only
thing that's illegitimate about my
business is the way that I'm treated
because you know as we were talking
about
um you know creating the highest quality
product I can one of our first goals was
to produce it in a commercial kitchen
cuz back in 2008 it was pretty much
being made at home by someone stuck in
their backpack delivered to the store
you know coming out of a backpack in a
home kitchen and you know we wanted to
kind of
elevate
um the expectations and the Norms of the
industry so a key way to do that was to
produce the products in a commercial
kitchen so you know we could we could uh
convey that they are made in the most
responsible Safe Way um issue with that
is LA County Health Department does not
allow cannabis to be infused into
products in a health inspected kitchen
um by
law
um by definition of putting infusing
cannabis oils into food products you're
adulterating food and that's illegal so
I'm basically you know at this stage of
the game I'm a professional food
adulterates that's going to change soon
and you
know technology and Society is always or
quite often you know a couple steps
ahead of of laws I mean if you look at
what Airbnb is doing or what Uber is
doing these are companies that are
breaking the law because they've created
a new technology or a new platform that
that just doesn't really uh isn't being
contemplated by local laws yet in San
Francisco county they also don't want
you using a health inspected kitchen a
commercial kitchen they don't want you
using a home kitchen either they have a
rule where they suggest you're using
[Music]
um uh some Kitchen in the Middle Ground
area like a a semi commmercial kitchen
at a retirement home or you know
something like that that's that's what
their I think that's what their uh local
Department of Health is suggesting but I
know companies up there are using
commercial kitchens as well got it but
but that they're always sort of they're
using commercial kitchens but they're
always sort of looking over their
shoulder yes who would be the ones to
affect the policy changes to catch up
with where the industry wants to be or
is well Howard Zin said that democracy
is not only a counting up of laws it's a
counting up of actions right so I mean
the way we affect change is by doing
what we do you know and and uh you know
popularizing or normalizing cannabis use
and that's what's happening so you know
we're we're furthering the discussion by
starting the discussion you know and
um you know the discussion is um
capturing the attention of a lot of
people right now so the laws are going
to change real short real quickly here
you know it's 2015 this is something
I've been dealing with since 2008 and
um you know there's assembly Bill 266
which is looking like it has a lot of
momentum and it's going to be passed um
by the legislature and signed by the
governor in September and this is July
August we're in August now so you know
that's next month and and tell me what
legislature legislation 266 is about it
basically says that um the Board of
Equalization will be in charge of
Licensing it says the department of
health will be in charge of testing and
food safety um you know manufactured
products infused product safety and it
says that the the Department of
Agriculture will be um in charge of uh
you know the the agriculture component
overseeing you know safety and in
cannabis cultivation and do you think
those three organizations are currently
educated and equipped to take on those
responsibilities um if they're not
educated they're not equipped and
they're not educated yet um but they'll
be mandated to get educated and so
hopefully it happens quickly in the
cultivation side of things really what
needs to just happen is people need to
you know stop viewing cannabis through a
stigmatized lens because agriculture is
agriculture you know there's a lot of
suggestions that you know can can abis
be you know subject to a whole
different
um you know set of rules than any other
plant or food product that's grown you
know um Tomatoes any food product you
can think of you're given a license
based on the square footage or the size
of your of your farm and in the Cannabis
world they're still in this prohibition
mindset of wanting to do it based on a
plant count that's actually been you
know
changed we're no longer assembly Bill
266 no longer contemplates the size of
your grow by plant count but for a while
there it was and that's just because you
know federal law over 99 plants certain
mandatory minimums kick in and for
enforcement plant count is a really
simple easy way to to judge the size of
a grow but um you know they don't do
that agricultural enforcement is not
based on you know more or less than 99
tomato plants so you know it's
just from the cultivation side of things
it just needs to be viewed as just
another plant right
um with the manufacturing side of things
there's going to be a lot more of a
learning curve for the you know the
regulatory um oversight body they're
going to have to learn a little bit
about THC and a little bit about
chemistry and how you know thca is
carboxilate into THC and potency and the
different cannabinoids that are in the
plant and what they do and which ones
are psychoactive and which ones aren't
um they're going to have to learn about
you know viable testing methods versus
ones that don't work so well um there's
going to be more of a learning curve for
that
[Music]