my name is Kenny Morris and i started
the Venice cookie company in 2008 I came
from I was operating a retail store a
couple different retail stores called
the pharmacy and these are retail stores
for cannabis there are dispensaries
they're collectives and just notice that
you know one of the main things that
attracted people when they came in the
store was first of all a wow I can buy
cannabis in a store now and be look at
all the other products it's in beside
just raw flour right people could always
go to their dealer and find cannabis
flowers but um the new novelty and the
thing that really captured people's
attention was all of the peripheral
products all the infused products that
were now available so it just became
real clear that that was going to be the
growth area we used the the pharmacy as
our incubator account to kind of do some
basic market testing see what works what
didn't work and we used a couple other
we used a couple other store fronts as
well we started out as the Venice Cookie
Company so we started out with three
products that were three cookies and we
haven't really looked back and made a
cookie ever since we've grown more into
a beverage and a chocolate company but
we yeah we started with a vegan cookie a
normal product called a cookie brownie
which was essentially a Toll House
cookie recipe with white chocolate chips
and butterscotch chips and then we made
a piece crispy treat which was just a
rice krispie treat and I guess the way
the products have evolved over time is
for one thing they've gotten a lot
smaller in 2008 it was still a real big
deal to go into a store and buy a
cannabis activated food product right so
they happen to be they tended to be
really large
sold in a clamshell container you know
huge full of calories look at me look at
what I have look what I found I got this
at the store so as the novelty's worn
off over the years and people rely on
these products to take them everyday for
some sort of medicinal or wellness
effect you know as the thrill wore off
as the novelty wore off they just want
the product to be smaller more compact
may be more discreet you know less
calories easier to consume less of a
chore to to you know take into your body
every day we source the raw material we
extract it we test the extract we test
the oil we put it into the food products
and we test the products so that's the
process we're originally doing an
ethanol extraction we're using alcohol
and a heating process to make what's
generally known as rick simpson oil
we're using that for our extraction the
problem with using alcohol as a solvent
is it pulls chlorophyll as well so we
were and we were getting an oil that was
black it's kind of like green food
coloring in a little tiny vial it looks
black but it's really green and the
bitterness that you get from chlorophyll
just in parts a little bit of an extra
taste we're trying to get rid of so we
moved on to co2 and other extractions we
sell and distribute the products all
over the state of California from the
you know right up against the Mexican
border all the way right up against the
Oregon border and you rely on
distributors or do you do you have
direct relationships with all the
dispensaries or we use our sales team
okay so you have an internal sales team
correct we've been taking on for at
least a couple years now practically a
new employee or two every month so the
growth of the company and the expansion
of the company's been pretty profound
pretty significant yeah and there's not
much of an end in sight