[Music]
if I'm watching you know a news channel
and there's a doctor who um wants to
kind of discredit cannabis as medicine
you know often you'll hear them use the
term well a lot of people just use it to
get high and the journalist or the host
of the show or whatever goes oh right
right right I I understand um but is the
doctor and that journalist even sharing
the same definition of what getting high
means or they have completely different
ideas of how to define getting high and
they just nod their head and agree on it
without really having any sort of
discourse to Define what getting high
means you know when when I hear people
use the term you know getting high I
always like to say what does that mean
you know and I think it would be
interesting to get a huge different
cross-section of people and ask him what
does that term mean
to some people getting high means up to
no good to other people getting high
means temporarily forgetting about your
problems to you know relieve stress to
other people um getting high means to
avoid your problems which is a Bad Thing
some people getting high means um you
know those people who dodge the draft
and aren't Patriots or there's just so
much tied up in what getting to some
people getting high means I'm a rebel
you know what I mean or getting High
means you know I I think for myself to
other people getting high means you know
I I I disagree with my parents so it's
like there's no real clear-cut
understood definition of what getting
high means so I think it's a really
dangerous
uh kind of irresponsible term to use um
especially if you're a medical
professional um so uh I I just think you
know our word choice it's like it's real
easy to come up with a term that can u
mean so many different things
and that's to me that's an interesting
conversation whenever someone uses the
term getting high and I say what's that
mean I always get a a completely
different answer from everybody one of
the big things we hear against um people
who are against the use of cannabis is
that well a lot of people just want to
use it to get high and I hear doctors
use this term a lot oh people use it to
get high but I think that's such a
non-medical term and if we're talking
about cannabis in terms of you know
wellness and medicinal use I would like
to know I would like to hear what a
thousand different people thought or
think the word getting high means
um because I think it means something
different to almost everyone and
uh you know I think a bunch of people
attribute whatever negative thing they
want to the term getting high and some
people think of getting high as a
positive thing but what does what does
it mean to get
high I think another thing that would be
interesting to to have journalists
explore is um due to the rise of these
CBD only laws in certain States
um uh where you know CBD because it's
been on CNN and Sanjay gup has heralded
it and it's non psychoactive it's
getting a of good press right now um and
the there's kind of this
misunderstanding that's being formed and
perpetuated in Congress and other places
where CBD is the medicinal component of
marijuana and THC is the recreational
component of marijuana and that's not
true they're both very therapeutic you
know
molecules and um the two of them
together when combined are more
effective than either one um used
alone and so I think one of the things
that one of the conversations that
cannabis also starts is the the rise of
uh whole plant medicine or um maybe the
um the notion that something Beyond a
single molecule medicine can be more
effective right like the whole reason
Whole Foods called their supermarket
Whole Foods is because you know why take
vitamins from a pill when you can get
your vitamins from Whole Foods right and
a carrot or a or a beet or you know
different foods they have a whole Litany
of of uh different nutrients in them
rather than just a single molecule you
know rather than a single nutrient so um
that's another aspect of um how cannabis
is pushing a conversation forward is you
know plant-based medicine
um the popularity of you know medicines
that aren't just single molecule
medicines that can have you
know a multitude of beneficial effects
and then of course we've all heard of
the term the Entourage effect so
[Music]