bye
cannabis is ultimately a freedom of
choice issue you know and that that's so
relevant to our lives in so many ways
you know I mean I'm happy to see that
the country is finally grown up and the
supreme court is ruled in a way that if
two people love each other regardless of
their sex they can get married you know
that's that's a freedom of choice issue
and it's a it's an issue of you know
largely of how tolerant we want to be as
a society towards people who are doing
things that don't harm other people so
you know cannabis fits into that
conversation you know gay marriage is
part of that discourse and then there's
other ways of looking at the issues and
how its kind of relevant to you know
society you know there was a case where
you know someone went through the
airport with ten thousand dollars on a
domestic flight and the TSA said that
that ten thousand dollars in cash
smelled like marijuana or the duffel bag
that it was in smelled like marijuana so
they seized that money from that guy and
civil asset forfeiture allows you to
take money from people without filing
any with without you know prosecuting
and even getting a conviction it's uh
it's a way for enforcement to fund
themselves you know it's policing for
profit and you know I think that's a
that's a big problem i think that trains
law enforcement to subconsciously
disrespect our citizenry by seeing them
as revenue streams and it actually sets
up the exact opposite scenario that
enforcement was intended to provide
right citizens aren't here to serve
enforcement enforcement's here to serve
the citizens but we set up this thing
where you know enforcement views the
average citizen is a revenue stream and
that's just fundamentally wrong
on so many levels you know and that
happens with you know seizures if
cannabis is involved that happens with
just getting pulled over and getting a
you know a seatbelt ticket or a tail
light being broken ticket is it creates
a fundamental problem about how
enforcement views the citizen and
consequently how the citizen views
enforcement and you know anyone with a
Facebook account at least on my facebook
feed it's just constantly filled with
you know disrespectful encounters
amongst police and and citizens of all
colors and you know I think I want to
use the cannabis issue as a way to kind
of continue the conversation about
things that aren't necessarily directly
related to the cannabis issue you know
and I think that's what people are
starting to realize is being involved in
the cannabis industry it's almost one of
the most profound forms of social
entrepreneurial ISM currently you know
because yeah we definitely do feel that
we're having a we're changing the world
you know we're having a direct effect on
how people perceive cannabis and
tolerance and freedom of choice and the
concept of medicine and what we should
and shouldn't be able to to do with our
with our lives so so yeah it's clearly
I've devoted my life to this it's got a
lot of meaning to me you know