[Music]
these people that I respect prior to the
change in regulation and my whole desire
for that interview series was to propel
people forward so that they could
survive and it's really nice to
interview the same people again that are
still alive and so their different
directions different skillsets different
desires but all of them you know to me
premium breeders people that I've used
to scare people into success with their
material and people that I've used to
steer my own self into success and so
we're gonna let them basically just chop
up a little only got the one I think
when I go one Mike what we'll do is
we'll just well let them introduce each
other one by one with what they're doing
and then we'll start getting into some
what are you doing right now
because all you involved in interesting
stuff and it's it's an excellent story
to listen to because these people are
just the same as you where they're
individuals that that are fighting their
way through the system and the only way
that it's going to really work is if
you're using the material putting it
into play and then they're able to then
keep creating stuff that you can put
into play so we really have a you know
true symbiotic relationship as cultivate
or breeder so with that all right thanks
Kevin everybody
so Gavin here has been a troubadour of
our culture and the region and has
probably had just about as far of a
reach as anybody and sort of like you
know singing the you know really just
like telling the story the way it needs
to get told especially with you know
sun-grown cannabis and organic
regenerative cannabis so thank you Kevin
so much and my name is NAT Pennington I
founded Humboldt seed company in early
2000s and I started breeding cannabis in
Humboldt County in 1999 when my daughter
was born who's here with me and I'm just
incredibly honored to be up here with
the illustrious freeborn selections and
Mean Gene and of course Jason from EQ
genetics thank you
[Applause]
all right so the the the vague
introduction here my name is Jackson I
go by me and Jean freeborn selections
and I've been breeding stuff since the
90s keeping stuff since the mid 90s
since I was pretty much a kid and just
looking through things and trying to
make better plants for you know
originally just me and my buddy so we
could have something a little better and
trying to improve and keep stuff around
and not not lose the stuff that's cool
that we want to be able to have and
that's about it and you know thanks to
keV and these guys for doing this kind
of shining a light on you know the
positive aspect of what can be done and
not just dumping a bunch of garbage into
the earth to try to make money and yeah
thanks everybody for coming out
[Applause]
so my name is Jason Mathis and I started
equilibrium genetics and I want to thank
I want to thank keV and you know I mean
gene and Matt you know for coming out
here and being on the panel with me
and so everybody hear me in the back
all right good it's really great to have
opportunities like this to bring the
community together what's going on right
now in California's breaking my heart
it's it's been a long road for me coming
from the East Coast I'm originally from
Northern Virginia and I've been really
involved in drug policy activism and I
worked a really long time for a number
of organizations to help pass laws
across the country and when I finally
get to legalization in California and
now I see what a monster it is and it's
it's it's just breaking my heart seeing
what's happening to our community so so
I just want to stress that everybody
just stay vigilant we're you know it's
not over and we're going to improve
these laws you know I've seen a lot you
know happen in the past year and it I
didn't know if anybody was gonna show up
today and just to see this many faces in
the room we were still doing this it's
just it's it's really good
yeah knowing when I was a good mic I'm
gonna pass this one to you guys and I'm
gonna take this one right here thank you
um when we at the first regen event in
Vancouver it it blew my mind and who was
there because I realized that that this
had grown in this organic way of people
who wanted to actually continue cannabis
culture and agricultural integrity and
when I saw the the people that were at
the event and I I knew the speakers were
all solid because I looked at the room
and I've met a bunch of them but I met
the people in the room and I couldn't
believe the level of commitment and I
said whoa we're definitely gonna be
alright we're gonna have to fight but
there is a lot of people that are about
it and then we have this one here and
like I said this isn't my event I'm just
a speaker I'm just putting on some of
this presentation today but I didn't
organize this event I didn't create the
idea I'm a helper so I'm just grateful
to be part of it but it blew my mind
when we had to go find another venue
because it was too big and and that's
not bad and so from Jason's point of
view someone who came from the south
where you extremely regulated he and he
comes out to California and gets
involved in the industry and then sees
the changes and for him to say whoa I
didn't expect to see anybody and lo and
behold you know you see a building it's
huge
so there's a we're gonna jump around
folks we have some time you know and I
want to get into some information about
you know um what do you use the base
material you do what are you doing but
the first thing I wanted hit that cuz I
haven't had a chance to chat with him is
enacted something interesting where he
did a giant mega phyno hunt and he he
tied a bunch of people into it so that
he could actually get the number of
participants required to look at
material in all these different
circumstances and situation and he's use
that orange photonics box so to be able
to do a lot of the metrics himself and
we never got a chance to chat about it
and I just think it was awesome and I
don't know if it got covered enough
really because I don't know if anybody
hunted a population that big
here so I mean you you might be an ofc
like uh I come from a family of whalers
historic whalers and so there's always a
joke that we're out wailing that's
wailing you know looking for that white
whale and I definitely went crazy so
maybe I should name a strain Moby Dick
yourself anyways thanks keV
so I guess sort of the impetus for that
was just this practice of being a type
hunting and it's something that I know
you know all of us have really probably
done in our lives whether it was like in
an organized an intentional way or
whether we you know read our own seeds
and I mean how many people in here are
our breeders like have how many people
have either even accidentally you know
right so you know I mean it's it's
something that that I think can can be
done collaboratively and can sort of
feed back into what we kind of need in
in our community where you know we don't
have access to quite as ample flat Ag
land and maybe we don't you know maybe
our County makes it harder than it
really needs to be to have permits and
get licenses and so I think one of the
strategies can just be to to use our
innovation and so doing that in a
collaborative way with a bunch of people
seemed like it might be you know a good
idea and so we started that last or 2017
in the fall we kind of came up with the
idea and
ended up I think around like 15
different farms or groups tied into it
and went around had a few big events and
the the process involved taking a lot of
cuttings before flower and keeping them
alive and of course a lot of labeling
from the field to the to the clone room
making sure that that didn't get messed
up and so that was quite an effort and
definitely some of the folks in this
room were we're on that team and they
know how hard it was like I think Daniel
took 3 or 400 of them himself
right so anyways just kind of coming
together like that in a group effort and
trying to really improve genetic lines I
mean I have a group of friends at Davis
that I ended up getting close with doing
like salmon genomics research and you
know they're really very brilliant
geneticists and kind of a question that
I had said was like well what are we
gonna do you can go out and find markers
and do all this fancy marker-assisted
breeding and all this stuff like that
and they kind of said you know what you
guys kind of already are doing what you
really should be doing which is just
like hunting through populations
I mean cannabis is like this exciting
really brand new thing and so even
though we're all facing down the barrel
of Corporate America coming with its
free markets and commodity pricing I
think you know there is still a lot of
exciting things to do and they said the
no matter what the
Syngenta's in the monsanto's no matter
how heavy they come in with biotech in
and the capabilities of you know mass
sequencing and all that stuff it really
takes a human who knows the plant really
well to be able to even you know inform
any of that stuff so they're still years
away and they still have to learn about
this plant that we all know so well
because we've worked with it for years
so you know when all hope is lost I
think sometimes it's you can just
remember that like we're a powerful you
know we're powerful contingent if we're
a collaborative contingent and you know
they can't what is on it but anyway I
don't know
so phenotype hunting I mean I think you
know gene you want to talk about
phenotype on thing well I was gonna ask
you you we can go into the piece but I
was some stuff that all three you're
doing that are interesting right and so
I wanted to give a chance for you to
talk about the mega Fino hunt and the
fact that I don't think anybody really
understood the scope of what you did it
was a big I'm somebody who likes to hunt
populations and I'm like oh you were
hunting a big population and you had a
lot of people helping you had a lot of
people involved that's a logistical
nightmare you got to use some modern
equipment that was portable to allow you
to be able to afford to do it because
holy Christ having a lab test that much
stuff would have bankrupted you and then
so then all of a sudden you become a
competent field lab operator because
you're having to make sure that the
tests are actually standardized so they
they make sense and I think that that
was just something I thought was awesome
and and I just didn't see enough
coverage of it magine and I fit for the
sake of transparency too I do business
with all these guys meaning that my
store carries their products right so
this isn't a sales pitch for him but you
got to say that otherwise
if everybody's trying to push something
in in this case I'm just trying to push
what they do but the point is the team
release is all mine three rolls and
that's the first time I see Mean Gene
come out as a pre-roll and it was always
typically all in genetics and the
question was you know are you having to
change your lines to work with your
you're a new direction in Flour and able
to use the existing tools what do you
notice in from a breeders point of view
and I and I know that all of you
excellent cultivated suits us most oh
you're so you know what do you having to
do to shift into that new realm of
product diversity that you're doing well
the the the trip about that was
basically that like I myself like I roll
a joint in my hand I hold the weed I
break it in my hand I roll it up and I
smoke it right away
like I don't know I don't like to roll
my joints and then smoke them later so
like myself I'm like not a pre-roll guy
but the weird thing is that uh
dispensaries people either want to buy a
little bud or they want to buy a joint
like that's mostly what it is so
basically my buddy was just like hey you
know we got your flavors we want to we
want to put him out and you know he's
like can we stick your name on it and
say oh this is your this is this is
these flavors so that there's you know
basic brand recognition cuz it's so
important right now for people to be
able to look at something and go okay
I've heard of that I'm gonna try it
people want things on their shelves that
have some recognition to them you know
and it's like the stuff that we all
regard as being like hype like it's like
okay there's there's different forms of
it and and a big a big part of it is
really just brand recognition and
anytime you're selling something you
want people to be able to look and go
okay I I would buy that so I don't know
the pre-roll thing is funny to me
because I was like yeah you can put it
on there don't don't call them pre-rolls
that you gotta call them joints there's
a the whole pre-roll thing is funny I've
had I've made jokes about that for years
like you can make it you know how to
make a
you know you know how to roll a joint
you know but um but the trip about it is
is that with the whole thing it's like
okay now you got the weed now it's got
to get tested now they want you to test
the pre-roll so it has to be rolled up
before the testing takes you forever to
get the testing back and everything and
it's so it's like in general for me I'm
like okay well there you're already
looking at it being to me it's degraded
but because people are gonna be buying
pre-rolls I'm like well the pre-roll is
a pre-roll if the weed was good that
went into it it's gonna be one of one of
the better pre-rolls you know but um but
it's just a trip because of the whole
the way the market is cuz I would like
to be able to say okay here this is weed
in a jar on the stick hardly trimmed you
can really look at it you can see where
those outer leaves super-healthy
was it you know how the weed like I like
to look at it like that people always
look at my weed I carry and they're like
you didn't trim it I'm like you yeah I
didn't trim it but look at it you know
you can see what it is you can see the
features you can see how far the resin
grows out on the leaves like if someone
gives me weed and it's and it's the big
Leafs are moved then I'm happy with that
when I pull off those leaves I'm seeing
it completely untouched but that's not
gonna work on the on the market
unfortunately because people look at
stuff in a jar they want it just like
what people call poodle cut they want to
cut down it's like Oh half the hairs are
cut off yeah but it's it's all bad you
know it's like well that's cool but it's
just weird because with the new thing
everything has to be changed and to
touch back on what he was talking about
with the value of people who are real
weed people in the new paradigm of how
everything is like I just I came to the
realization talking to a buddy of mine
you know if you really know something
and you really have experience and
you've really done stuff you have an
advantage over these people who just
have really deep pockets so I'm really
disappointed
I understand
I understand like the reality that
people see okay here's this opportunity
so I'm gonna bring this to the table and
basically they have deep pockets and I
have this knowledge but what people are
gonna start to understand and I mean
like all just tell all you right now so
you can maybe hear it before you have to
learn for yourself
those people basically you're disposable
so information only goes as far as
information goes and as soon as they
have your information or they have your
whatever they're getting from you
they're gonna throw you away so it
doesn't matter what kind of contract you
have or any of that if these people have
that deeper pockets they're there
eventually they're gonna shit on you you
know so that's just a point that I
wanted to bring up that if you have
something and there's the you got these
big investors or whoever they are these
big corporate dudes and they're like we
we got to have this and they want it all
we're gonna give you all this money and
do all this shit like don't give it to
them watch them fail and then help
people who you know are actually trying
to make it and then you'll have this
huge advantage but the problem is that
we're all down a little bit right now
everything's messed up so when you see
an opportunity you go well I better not
everything's going to shit so I better
jump on the opportunities but it's
almost like like an analogy would be
like alright well we've almost fished
out all the salmon so I should just go
fish a shitload before they're gone or
we've almost cut down all the old-growth
redwoods so I better cut down my
old-growth redwood before it's gone but
people are taking this really priceless
valuable stuff and they're giving it to
the man basically and then they're just
getting fucked and then these dudes are
coming up with these with this killer
you know
these killer ways of operating and in a
lot of case they can't really understand
it anyway they still need the people but
I've just been seen with a lot of people
they're like oh yeah well we we know we
need you for this we need you for that
people get these jobs they do it it gets
a little bit further in and they go
you know it's like the old the old Eddie
Murphy you know hey what do you say we
kick what do you kids say we kick
Clarence out of the band and steal all
this good ideas with the with the
Beatles you know the fifth Beatle is
like okay cool we'll just kick you out
and take all your shit you know and
that's kind of what's happening with um
with everything and that's what he was
talking about with like okay you have
these things of value so if you have
something of value and people are
basically trying to take it from me it's
like it's just it's a bummer because a
lot of people have really helped the
assholes to get further and then it's
not there they're not really gonna wind
up getting anything and so if if they
need to take I mean everybody here who's
been doing stuff for a long time
remembers when you first tried to grow
really good weed and you first tried to
dry it right and you first tried to have
everything come out and you saw your
buddies leading you went and his his
weeds always better than mine and that's
how these guys would have to deal for a
long time but then they're getting
people basically like us to come in and
tell them how to do everything right and
they're they're basically gonna they're
gonna get your ideas and they're gonna
throw you away so as much as you can
it's like you wanna these things are so
cool because right now I know anybody
who wants to come to something like this
isn't a bunch of assholes essentially
like all you guys are looking at a
different aspect of it and like to me
that's that's where it should be going
and that should almost be that should
almost be locked off from the from
everything else it's like you want
everyone to get the information but at
the same time it's like you got a you
got to keep it out of the wrong hands a
little bit too cuz it's getting it's
getting watered down and you see it fast
and I've just been hearing so many
horror stories from buddies who are like
yeah they put me on they're gonna do
this they're gonna use my genetics
they're gonna do all this and then
pretty soon they're like damn and then I
showed up at the meeting and they said
like I'm out but they got all my ideas I
did the whole thing but they're the ones
with the deep pockets and I don't you
don't have lawyers that can battle their
lawyer so now what am I gonna do you
know but that anyway I was something
that he said and that was you know it's
just the new the new thing is crazy so
try to you know what brought that to
was talking about like mmm you know
being able to market being able to
leverage things trying to basically find
the people to help out who you know are
like-minded and don't just look for the
the Golden Goose and try to jump on it
keep you can keep your thing small you
can do something you can still just grow
some weed you can still just sell a
little and not chase after this idea
it's like it's got to be two worlds
because there's the one world that's
going on that everybody's overly
ambitious going for that and then
there's the world that basically all you
guys are in and it just like really
don't even get caught up thinking that
any of that has any value
really for any of us you know but no no
it's it's real you you have to believe
that yeah you the problem is that people
think that if you don't get it solved
right now you're not gonna solve it and
you didn't get here in a year took your
whole life to get here yeah so so you
might just keep marching forward and be
intelligent and for me people try to
access stuff for me but it's I'm good at
picking up sneaky shit and so I like to
play with you but the new people are
coming to pick it up and they send
people to talk to you but the thing is
they have a very directed questioning
that's and you can pick it up because
it's it's not organically derived it's
scripted and then once you get that now
you can trounce those guys too and be
careful with who you endorse if you have
a good reputation for what you do be
careful because they could take it from
you and then it's no longer yours and
that's what you've worked for this whole
time really is a level of integrity and
Trust to where nobody's perfect but for
the most part you're pretty reliable
that's something that is is called
goodwill in business and goodwill is
very very valuable and the people that
are coming in need the goodwill so they
can then make their marketing occur and
get trust and buy-in and what you get
left is is basically nothing and it
doesn't mean you can't work with
individuals but like in my case if I do
anything contractual I have my own
lawyers right the contracts and I pay
for that so I have my own lawyers come
with me even though people don't know no
we
need a lawyer I said yeah I always need
a lawyer when I go to court I bring an
attorney because I know they're gonna
talk a language that I really don't
understand and I always equate it to
bring in Mike Tyson to a bar fight that
if you had to get into a bar fight and
you might with Mike Tyson you would say
I got this I'm really good at this let
me handle this part of it
and you now just keep an eye on my back
and that's kind of how I see the stuff
that we're working with but man you know
every time you have to put the money out
to cover the attorney to do the deal
it's your money and they're their cash
driving us and that's really why we
don't we always bring back to that
common that the people around you are
the ones that you got here with and
they're the ones that you're gonna have
to team up with and share resources with
and in some cases it's not a bad thing
to put the farm down for a season and
not farm it if you can't afford to make
that product sell it'd be better to let
it sit for season and go get a job
working with your other friends on their
farm and then pick up the operation
again because I let my own farm sit last
year the way the way it worked with
permitting was they wanted to put me off
until August on a plant and I said no
why would I want a plant in August so I
said it's better that I don't and I
won't pay the excise I won't have to pay
the taxes and I'll just have to make
sure I work harder on my other stuff
because I'm not gonna get there the
income that I had hoped to get from the
farm but I also realized that there was
no guarantee on the income either and so
if you start playing this game of
desperation you put yourself in a
situation you can't get out of and if
you take a look at your whole life every
major screw-up you made you made out of
desperation because it took away good
judgment and so this is some important
stuff to really understand Jason Jason's
been a busy boy man you're somebody that
like I follow the drops and I mean I
don't know if anybody drives more than
him like literally when I met him at his
his car looked like he had put it
together with duct tape and he's like
bro I'm doing a lot of driving and then
I see him in a new car and he's like bro
I'm doing a lot of driving and but he's
getting his product out into the market
in a really good way and it's
interesting product and so you know
what do you been doing thank you thank
you keV yeah I've been I've been busy
that's for sure and still investor free
still broke still just in the struggle
like all you it was really good listen
you guys talk because the the Sharks are
out there and it was everything you guys
are saying is everything that I've been
going through for the past couple years
and just feeling desperate feeling like
you want to go talk to these people that
say that they got solutions for you and
they really don't at the end they just
want to hear you talk they just want to
you know put the tape on record and let
you just go and so okay so we captured
that alright now let's go tempt the next
guy and try to get what he's got and
none of those none of those things ever
amounted to anything other than nice
building my wheels in front of a bunch
of people and Maduro just going and
getting a job working for somebody else
if that was what I was going to keep
doing it's exactly what you said you you
you maybe you get a contract even that
solid is can be and they can still
switch things up a month or two down the
road they've got your cuts they've got
your seeds or whatever they've got all
your plan and how you do it and then now
they got some other dude they hired for
$12 an hour to go and do everything that
you were doing and that's not going to
happen if you're self-employed doing it
for you with your friends with people
that you have real relationships with
and so
yeah and so I'm still I'm still
struggling I'm still at this I'm still
driving miles and you know and hopefully
for many more years I came here you know
to California almost you know penniless
the few hundred bucks in my pocket lived
in a bathroom for seven months and in
East Oakland and you know I I still go
back to there sometimes where it's like
I'm doing alright I was alright then and
I'm alright now
you know so it's it's all about feeling
inside you and and getting desperate is
like it's kind of like you have this
vision of like oh I could be with this
big group doing all these fancy things
but like you there's you're not going to
do that or it's very unlikely and then
you then you try to see what kind of
compromises you can make to achieve that
and I feel like a lot of that is just
it's smoke and mirrors like the folks
that are out there doing this you can
can probably they're gonna make it
really tough in the next few years I
hear people talking about that they're
gonna be selling below cost in the
future there's gonna be big groups you
guys already know all their names
they're out there and they're they're
out there to crush and we're gonna have
to have something unique and special and
highlight the people aspect of this more
than anything and the the the community
is why I'm part of this that's why I
wanted to make seeds because I want to
make the seeds for future generations
for for other people past when I'm dead
and gone are gonna be going and growing
these strains you know I don't feel like
if if I've released a seed and you guys
see on the Shelf you can do whatever you
want with it you can breed with it you
could share it with your friends I'm not
gonna take any offense to anybody
working with my work because that's what
I'm doing with other people's work I
didn't invent cannabis I didn't create
any of this stuff I'm just making my own
crosses trying to provide to the other
people in the world and so
you know so I just try to try to stay
humble and you know keep keep doing the
work that makes me feel good and and
it's served in the community and being a
part of the community and feeling like
I'm part of a family that that makes me
wanna get up in the morning go do things
so so you know that's that's that's why
you know that's why I came all the way
out here to see oh you guys and back to
what I was saying before about what's
going on with the canvas laws where
nobody that I knew in the game two years
ago was even allowed to participate
anymore like so I don't know the answer
to that but I know that that's not what
I was working for when I was working for
you know the the students for sensible
drug policy and drug policy Alliance and
and these other big groups that that
I've definitely you know put in a lot of
volunteer hours for and you know I feel
like there's there's still a lot to be
desired in in California cannabis you
know we're supposed to be ground zero
for the best cannabis in the world and I
see the community that carried the water
for so many years through the scary
times being shut out of this thing where
you know other folks are jumping in that
that didn't have anything never they
never had dirt under their fingernails
and like I said I don't know the answer
but but something tells me it comes
through community and us getting
together and and strength in numbers and
making sure that we get active at the
local level and at the state level
[Applause]
it's gonna be hard to follow you
the where's curious is uh you're all
working on interesting stuff and I know
some of the work you're doing all three
you but you're always constantly
refining in switching process with
something excited about this year you
know whether it whether it's for the
market or not but like what's something
you're into yourself that you're working
with you'd like to see people access in
any form gosh so many things but I want
to say on what Jason had brought up and
what me and gene brought up Beth did you
speak this weekend Beth Schecter hi okay
so the open cannabis project looks to
protect the cultivar the strains that
we're all you know we've known and loved
for a long time and and hopefully
combinations of all of them so that we
can all keep doing the work that we've
been doing breeding and cultivating and
it's a nonprofit organization and
there's definitely gonna be some big bad
Wolf's come in to get genetics and it's
really hard that what do you do you hide
them away like don't give them away
you know don't come to an event like
this and and say here have a few of this
and a few of that cuz you know maybe
there's somebody in the room or
something you it's almost impossible and
so we just gotta kind of support an
organization like that is really the
best way that we can keep cannabis open
source and keep like the genetics of
cannabis accessible to everybody because
the Syngenta's and the Monsanto's would
like to you know just tie up all these
strains and of course there's this
phenomena that's unusual where something
has been in under prohibition for you
know since in all of modern
times that has been basically illegal so
you know any innovation that has
happened has not been documented because
you know it's like at Humboldt C company
we keep freaking notes during the
breeding season and then burn them in
the fall because it was like you know
I'm not trying to keep notes around
about you know how many goddamn plants I
had and you know so charge enhancement
back in the day what's a charge
enhancement you know it's although you
were in the game I caught an extra
couple years on a case I had to fight
because I had spreadsheets comparing
operations and it gave me a criminal
mastermind charge and we all laughed and
I said if I was so smart at winning a
fucking court but no nonetheless the
enhancement was really punishing because
I was using tools to document work goes
in it was impossible to keep this much
data when you're running this many
operations and I had my hand and a lot
of cookie jaws way back in the day yeah
you know and so you know those those
folks that look to capitalize so much
could easily come in and and try to you
know to say that they've created
something that's new when really me and
Gene's been breeding it for 20 goddamn
years and you know so on and so forth so
that's a good organization to support I
really appreciate what Beth's done and
you know as far as some exciting stuff
that we're doing I think you know really
that big phenotype hunt effort was
exciting for me and what else are you
gonna release the product this year
we'll be dropping the sort of selected
cuts like Daniels farm we picked one
that we're calling magic melon and that
one just really smells like melons and
its kind of gassy fuel finish but yeah I
don't know I just I feel really just
happy to be able to
work on in cannabis and share share the
the genetics and and definitely like
what it did I got an email the other day
and I looked at the email and I thought
it was kind of weirded it said Burpee in
the email and so I replied to the email
and did some fishing and sure enough it
was Burpee and I don't really I don't
know like are they big bad wolf or not I
mean I don't I didn't follow the
corporate ladder all the way out but
that's the kind of stuff that's
happening so definitely be careful but
you just gotta we we got to keep
charging forward and so exciting things
just breeding more and more all the time
and and we're doing some genotyping and
putting it in the public space so that's
a way that you can once you do that if
you don't patent it in a year then it
becomes public public domain and so
that's what I would call defensive IP
versus offensive IP which is getting a
patent and you know sending out cease
and desist letters to everybody in the
room he doesn't pay you a fee for for
growing it or whatever and I think that
there's you know I'm not saying I'm
completely opposed to patents but I
think definitely that it's it's a
slippery slope and so you know there's a
lot of things out there that just are
that should just be public domain I mean
if I could just take a snapshot of the
whole cannabis space right now and make
sure that that could continue to be the
way it is and people could continue to
grow the plant I think
would be a good thing to do but it's
costs cost a lot of money to genotype so
you know that and and that's not the
only solution to there's other ways to
go about it but yeah so that's that's
exciting
I don't do min gloom you know no but the
thing is though it's hard they're all in
the real everyone in the room is in the
real yeah and and a lot of it is the
struggle because that's so much the
reality of what you're having to deal
with and what I wanted what I want to
make sure though is that the things that
you see and that interests you because
see you guys are you're the painters
that create the the ink that we use to
do our work and so you know you see you
broke out the melon and so the thing was
he said hey know what we found was
something that was unbelievably Melanie
with the beautiful fuel back and we
think it would be attractive and it
would be valuable for the market and and
that's that's what I'm seeking from it
and and the part about us all struggling
is as real as it can be and and I try to
make light of it because otherwise you
go i'ma cry and you know and tissue
paper is expensive so what about you big
gene which what you messing around what
directions do you go with your lines cuz
you you work some lines that you've had
for a long time but you switch the
direction on them and it's kind of neat
because it lets you swing a picture yeah
I mean what I'd really like to do is do
I'll do the I'll do those fresh hybrids
and then try to go through and seed a
lot of plants every time I do anything
so then I think you can go in all these
different directions so when you make
that that fresh hybrid you get you know
if stuff is if stuff is fairly
consistent you start with then you you
get a pretty you get a pretty it's
pretty predictable to know what you're
gonna get but then when you make that f2
you get all the weirdness and then when
you go when you get all the weirdness
then that's where you can really you
know make one thing into a million
things you know so with with some of
them
tried to take them different directions
and then some of them is just a real
clear direction but like um this year
I'm really trying to work on like the
root beer stuff that's really cool
because it's it's a trip like with doing
seeds there's a whole lot of seeds that
are really interesting and they're and
they're awesome and like they all are
you know really valid in the space as
far as going okay we need to have all
these things but it's really a trip
because when you go to actually sell a
lot of weed it kind of has to look a
certain way it has to have you know
there has to be something about it where
it's like okay that's shiny that has
people really like a little color to it
asked to at least have a silver look if
not dark or purple or blue or red or
whatever you know regular green but
better be really tasty and really stinky
to be able to compete you know so like
the root beer is a cool one because of
the the way it smokes the way it grows
all that stuff so this year I'm trying
to do like a back cross to that clone
twice and the original male I started
with was almost the same thing so it was
already pretty consistent right away and
then going back to it a couple times
made it made it really nice and then
what I'm gonna try to do with that is um
I'll probably go back one more time to
the root beer clone to make it so that
it's like really root beer seed cuz it
has got more and more frequent when you
back cross not everything does that if
it's too inconsistent throws too much
weird stuff you know but it comes
through so it dominates in the crosses
and and then but I think what I'm gonna
do while it's still just a little more
open at the at the at the two back
crosses I'm probably gonna do a bunch of
out crosses of it this year and then do
the same thing with the cherry limeade
and the reason being that when you get
like if you go to get clones from
somebody you know how it is it's like
you have to everything's cool to have
some like okay I'm gonna have some of
this I'm gonna have some of that but
when people like want units and weight
of something you have to be able to have
something that people look at and even
if they don't know the name its
recognizably what they is in there
paradigm of what's the dank some of the
best we've might look like shoelaces and
be all messed up and look like dr.
Grinspoon or something you know
but when you when you really want
something that you can have in your bag
- people go okay you you just want that
instant yep there it is and so those are
things that do that you open the bag you
I want that so like I'm trying to do
that because when you you know you want
to have plants that grow well for you as
a farmer and then you need a product
that's really gonna be that thing and
that's the whole thing I was talking
about with like with brand recognitions
like people go oh it's hype a type of
type it's like we'll hype hype doesn't
last so like I remember when cookies
came out it was like that's hype it's
not good it's like well maybe it's not
as good as it's not a strongest headband
or cam or whatever is your thing but
you're you know it's like if it was just
hype it wouldn't be here ten years after
I got it it's still here and all the
crosses are still that and when you
really get into it you go okay this is
cool stuff and but the reason why it's
valuable to grow it is because you know
when you finish it you can sell it like
if you're a tomato farmer you know most
people are gonna wind up like okay this
one has shelf life it's good boom we're
gonna grow these Roma's we want to grow
these really cool air loom rainbow
Tomatoes but when you go in the stores
only a little bit of those go over here
you got this whole tier of these Roma's
over here what our beefsteak so ever so
we're gonna grow those so you need
things to fit in people's paradigms so
I'm trying to put out some stuff that's
really like people go oh it's the hype
stuff oh it's just it's another gelato
cross it's this or it's that but it's a
trip because if you don't have something
that people on a knee-jerk reaction will
look at and go that's the stuff that's
what everybody wants then or do you
really want to have 350 pounds of it and
you you wanna you want to have a quarter
pound for your head or whatever to share
and you know maybe you got somebody who
wants this or that but you know I'm just
trying to really make sure that like the
stuff that I'm putting out is stuff that
when you're done with it it's what
people come back
like this last stuff I released was like
I had that Pina the Pina a lot of times
a CVD plant but it's super Hardy its
structures great it does will not get
p.m. it's like so easy in such a great
you know you could probably dry farm and
I haven't tried but I have seen my buddy
leave the Pina Cross cherries that I
made in some three gallon pots basically
in a in a in a in a greenhouse that
wasn't being grown in so it was like a
hundred and thirty degree desert in
there every day and the plants he
watered him when they were starts they
never grew but then they butted and they
finished and there was this killer weed
in there that we basically found going
to his house and I was like well that's
got value too you know but but it's weed
that when people you know it originally
I was like it's CBD people only want
Kush I'd have a little bit of it people
would show up and they'd be like no we
want more of those we want that one so
that's you know something try and trying
to put stuff out that's actually like
can really be practical for people that
are farming it's like the sky cuddler
Kush like that's in the conus favorite
weed you know it's like got the
knee-jerk okay this is cool I understand
that it smells gassy but as a grower to
its really performing you know so that's
just the focus of like the stuff that
I'm working on in general is to be like
that like I love the lime and the lime
is great but the lime is a little bit
more it's a little more leafy when you
grow it it's so I'm trying to work it
into a little bit more different stuff
so that's like cross it back with a og
keeps the nose gets a little meat on the
bones that's what the lime pop cush is
you get the huge plants if you're
growing big plants so I've been working
on that but then I made like I took like
the cherry limeade f5 and I put it on
gelato
herb you know things that you're like oh
that's a stupid but it's like yeah but
that's what people want in their bag to
buy so you you got to have that you know
what I mean so that's kind of the this
stuff I've been I've been trying to work
on more stuff that's like that and then
at the same time I'm always doing my
regular stuff that's for me that I you
know that I that I vibe with even more
but I you know you can't help but but
also vibe with something that you look
at and you go whoa
well that's incredible I mean I went to
the ego clash and hopping down there and
I saw all the stuff and everybody I
walked up and they go which one which
one you know would you say would be good
out of there and I missed the part where
you smoke and all that and I just looked
in the case and I was all that number 14
that looks like that's that's fire right
there I don't know what it is but it
looks good it's got that good old-school
canny
frost it up look and then they announce
the winner and they're like oh the
number 14 gelato 41 or something you
know and I was like oh all right well I
mean you can't really argue with you
can't just like just hype pocky
strain whatever it's you can't you can't
you know yeah I learned that from a guy
that was in fashion
and and I've not historically been known
as someone who's been fashionable so I
asked people who are fashionable about
you know fashion yeah and they said you
can't argue with trends that people do
because what you're saying is that
you're not intelligent enough to
recognize that they made the choice to
do it and so what happens is you cut
yourself right out of the trend and I
think that's the same with what you're
talking about the plants at the bottom
line is if if 41 cut wasn't hot then why
is it moving at a rate that's
supernatural and it doesn't mean you
need to jump on it but you need to
understand why the white what I learn
from someone is tooth these two things
in life those that know how and those
that know why and those that know how
work for those that know why and for us
it's the why that's what's important for
us otherwise we end up just being how
how do we make it and we understand why
are we making it and what what is that
direction and and I agree man I see all
these modern cultivars that are red hot
and I go I got you some of them are my
personal preference but I don't deny the
fact that it moves at an unbelievable
velocity and when you do objective
testing where I take I take things that
I think are hot and I give them to
people who are in markets that are
unbelievably picky and they have money
which means they have access and I let
them run them to find out compared to
each other which one has the velocity
and then it lets me really understand of
these elites which one really is the
attraction and why and
and also lost that lets me understand
which ones didn't I think had the
attraction and I go whoa the market
still likes that but so much of it is
that that that visual appearance and
you've been trained to choose those
things because that's what we've got the
last 30 years in cannabis and I always
tell people some of the strong spot I
have a smoke that it looked like it was
a piece of cabbage run over by a tractor
and it got me so high that I had to
drive around the island three times cuz
I couldn't figure out how to get off the
highway on the on-ramp and I was I was
out in Hawaii and I got so lit that I
couldn't really get off the freeway and
I was laughs and I just said screw it
I'll just drive it out and at some point
I'll come down and I'll be able to
figure out how do you get off the
freeway you know and what I wasn't
laughing at the moment I was like whoa I
am scorched but if I could get my hands
on that again I loved it but the thing
was you know I challenge you to sell it
because it looked like it was some
cabbage run over by a tractor yeah yeah
yeah so that's why that's why it's like
you know like oh yeah gelato just gelato
cross you know what I mean like yeah I
made a gelato cross I'm a - herb cross
like the mail I started with though is
f5 and those generations to get to add
to get to f3 took a while out of the
twos to get to the four took a while out
of the threes it's not like I just want
one two three four five boom man gelato
and even that is a lot of work but you
know going along the way to go okay cool
we got rid of this we got rid of that I
mean I think you probably grew some of
the early cherry generations that I had
that have all the weird
herckel recessives in it that palm out
with that still had little duck foot and
they're teeny and they won't grow and
the weed is amazing incredible I already
thinks I've got to get both and then so
now like I have cherry lime F sixes and
if you grow those they're all big fast
vegging plants they all have the same
bud structure they all have the super
high 5% terpenes at SC 18 22 percent THC
real consistent all the same doesn't
mold doesn't break doesn't care if it's
windy you know and then take that like
what I use to make that and then that
was out crossed
to these you know height whatever and so
then you know with that then you at
least know you've got some
predictability there and at the same
time you have marketability so that you
you you're bringing because you've got a
there's only so many enthusiasts and all
of us enthusiasts can go ahead and go
okay cool yeah this is this really rare
weed thing you know like this is this
trippy like it's it's out there like um
like Caleb right now is working with
that Australian bastard cannabis and
people are like why would you want this
and I'm like if you really like plants
you want that because it's not the other
one you have but you're not gonna go
okay I'm gonna switch over my hoops to
this people are gonna go once it's
trimmed in the bag it probably isn't
even different because the leaves are
cut off and the leaves are what's cool
and it has valuable things and you want
to have it in your arsenal I looked
right out it and went if I can get a
plant that's like a bomb-ass Afghani to
grow with this size leaves you're gonna
have yields that are gonna crush
everything because if you can get a fat
bud on something that veges faster than
that with a tiny little leaf it's just
gonna get Sun right to the bud the whole
way she can have these huge buds like
this but instead of being on the end
with these big fat leaves that block
everything out you're gonna have them
six feet long so that's where you get
like the cool stuff and though those
things are valuable for breeders but you
buy a pack of seeds you're like dude I
want to grow this and maybe I want to
find a clone or I just want to grow
these and just have good bud like I try
to make sure that my seed you plant a
row of it I have to be able to plant a
row of it and have 10 or 20 of them and
hundreds or three hundreds or whatever
and look at him and go okay cool I'm
glad I grew that in my garden so that's
what I try to do that's what I try to
put out you know but with the new the
new stuff too was it's I'm trying to
like make sure it's you know always
because the cutting edge turps and
something that that fits into the
picture pre marketed yeah yeah just do
it making smart business yeah and that's
why that's why I was saying about better
to loop back that's what was cool about
the root beer is it almost looks like a
cookies or it looks like it's something
like that but it's cuz it has black affi
in it way back in it
hindu and then it has the headband the
la cush like Mandal had back in the day
and so those it makes it like this ultra
potent thing like if you're used to
smoking cookies and you smoke this
you're like okay this is super
satisfying smoke you know it breaks up a
little better and it's got you know just
really killer so those are those are
ones that are that are going and that's
the that's the thing maintaining those
cool that cool all that neat stuff and
then being able to go okay here's what
we need to be competitive because we do
have to be super competitive and all you
really need is a plant that is that
special and people will go oh okay I got
it like it's good it's great for
everyone to share everything it's great
for everyone to share especially these
bulk these these bulk gene pools you
know what I mean but like if you have
your own clone and everyone's like oh
you can't get like maybe you don't want
to give that clone away cuz maybe you
want to have something that you're like
no I know how to do this you might talk
to someone's grandma she's like sorry
you can't have my cookie recipe no
because it's my wanna have this I want
to win the I want to win the contest at
the whatever you know what I mean or
whatever it's for like there's a there's
a there's something to that you know so
like definitely everyone's got to share
but it there's there's a huge edge to
being able to go okay I have this thing
and I'm the only one with it and it's
something for everyone to think about
that find that plant where you know you
you're you might not be able to sell sfv
you're like I I was getting you know
three grand for this sfv now people want
to give me 600 everything's crashed but
then you go to talk to somebody in
they're like dude I have this one and no
matter what everybody my buddies got
this Vermont Diesel it's like pre sour
diesel diesel look you know like I don't
know if it really is but that's how it
is it's like just straight like super
skunk it smells like skunk and then
underneath it's just like clove and it's
super super bomb and he just calls it
diesel and anybody who looks at that and
they tell you oh sorry this good indoor
but I'm only gonna give you a thousand
for it you're like cool
where's the next guy cuz one out of
three people who smell this shit are
gonna say dude what do you want like if
I have that I can sell that to people
for whatever I want to ask for it and
it's just because people don't all have
it if everyone has it people see a bad
version of it now all of a sudden it's
whatever it is it's cool its cush but
there's definitely like a value and that
of looking for your own thing having it
and you know being able to being able to
run with something that's you know got a
little edge on it but so that that's
what I'm always doing trying to make
stuff like that I took all right G
that's absolutely right and you know
like when I look around this room I
think what the reality is is that so
many of us like if you think of it's a
race or whatever a racetrack so many of
us are actually like lapping the whole
industry that it's easy to look like
you're behind but we're really all just
like so far ahead and say what gene was
saying is like sometimes you gotta you
know give them what they want and so you
know you do a few draught of crosses or
make sure everything is you know a
certain THC level for for the year but
never ever give up on those cultivars
that like that mean everything to you I
mean I can't like back god eight nine
years ago people would give me such a
hard time really why do you have seeds
that make purple cannabis everybody
hates purple they were like oh it's it's
because it's deficient your your weeds
purple because it's deficient in
whatever something they tell me and I'd
be like no it's it's not and this is
like so the trends and I guess the whole
lapping thing like we're always like a
one-lap ahead and sometimes it can look
like we're kind of behind the pack but
really we're just like ahead of it and
nobody knows it yet so I think does for
gene
so ya know same thing you got you got a
lot of killer stuff you you you work
some interesting directions since I've
met you and I like that you know you've
been you've been really putting together
some interesting combinations and the
number of people that bring me material
that you've done I got something my job
right now someone said man I doesn't
kill equilibrium working I said all nice
what is it and I laughed because each
one of those samples was radically
different than the other because the
lines were different and I I like that
when I see people have separation and
what they're doing and and your desires
to go these different trends and so
you've been you've up with some cool
stuff what we've been what are you doing
going on I'm I think this young and shy
dig deeper into I've got so many seeds
and so many things I've collected over
the years and I kind of want to I like
that branching out in a whole new
direction just like kind of outside way
somewhere where maybe it's something
that's been sitting on the Shelf that
I've been meaning to get to forever and
I haven't decided anything I'm gonna
work with yet this year but there's
there's a few contenders the Malawi
lines did really well you know over the
years there's been a lot of people
coming back saying the African Orange
was something that was really mold
resistant for them and and I've seen
some of the flowers of somebody you know
brought me some of the flowers today
from Humboldt that was that was just
probably one of the most citrusy
versions African Orange I've ever seen
and that's certainly a direction I want
to go in as things that do well on the
coast because I've been in you know I
was in Santa Cruz for so many years and
it's it's hard to grow almost anything
in a lot of the areas around that County
that's actually where I first saw some
mean genes work as I had a friend out
there that we kind of shared a little
patch one year and he I guess I guess he
he had gotten some seeds from you and he
grew the root beer and we grew the the
PK and there was some of your cherry
limes and it was like Oh lime I forget
some other and they were just beautiful
just the Oracle lime was insane
especially in light of what you were
talking about with the
bag appeal just like there were just
these bulbous buds that just just looked
amazing and probably the probably the
cherry lime at everything was was the
favorite at the end of the year just
just getting to smoke it and you know
the root beers were a little later but
they just when they when they filled in
they were like just so Turkey and and
and enjoyable and and last year your
Humboldt dream was my buddy's biggest
plants in the garden last year he's got
a picture of him just in the Anderson
Valley with this plant that's just like
gigantic you know so he's like oh I'm
doing this one every year now so you
guys kudos to you guys for you know
putting out the quality work and I think
yeah this year you know I'm gonna
probably pull out some of the other
Malawi hybrids maybe I've seen a lot a
lot of buzz around the chocolate Malawi
which is one that I haven't been working
with as much in the past and so maybe
pull that one out I think that's
probably one at the top of the list it's
the chocolate hash berry to the heirloom
malawi
and you know the the glue line is one
I've been working for a little while is
trying to find a reliable glue back
cross and find a male out of that that I
can hit two things and get that you know
chocolatey gassy roma and taste out of
the hybrids that come through and you
know maybe we're gonna pull off some
some crazy land races and should I work
with some you know some wild some wild
stuff and you know try to try to see
what you know what else we could put out
there that that is gonna be unique this
it's all about setting yourself apart in
this industry and yeah like you're
saying maybe you find a cut that you
don't want to share with people and I
would love to hear that somebody found
something out of my work that that
really worked well for them and they
wanted to keep around for years and
years and and and maybe it helped keep
them afloat in in tough times and so so
certainly we're gonna keep working for
mold resistance which is you know even
more of an issue nowadays with you know
the testing requirements and you know
some of the other projects you know
might might include you know maybe maybe
some of the other Malawi's or you know
I've kind of got a rough sketch but but
we haven't we haven't nailed anything
down yet you know I think get back with
the team and see what everybody else
wants to do too and you know maybe go
back and look at because I try to I try
catalog everything all the all the seeds
you know everybody that gave me C's
today we traded I'm gonna go and try to
catalog and keep keep a list of
everything and you know you do that long
enough and you're gonna have a nice nice
collection you know I hope I hope
everybody starts getting into more of
their own like Fino hunts and and
finding things that do well in your
local situation which you know whatever
property that you might have might be
even totally different from your
neighbors parcel because they're on the
other side of the ridge you know or or
maybe maybe the people down the road or
you know a little closer to a valley and
they get more wind or you know so so
it's a it's great to be here and see you
know all the different success stories
from different strains because that
definitely has a big effect on my
personal you know decisions of what I'm
gonna go and breed with is when I go and
talk to the community or I go to you
know the Emerald cup or you know you
know see somebody out you know you know
in town or something and they be so oh
well you know you're you're you know
sour orange or you know your your
Grandaddy orange or you know maybe one
of these you know dream queen blue or
this or that like did really well for me
and that's I love I love hearing
everybody's stories of what they've done
with my genetics and what they really
liked just like you know I've got folks
that rave about these two guys
genetics that that they've tried in
previous years so you know just yeah
keep the stories coming so awesome and
you know what I like is that uh it's
rare that most most people in nowadays
what I learned the internet is where you
talk shit so you can get recognition cuz
otherwise you don't exist
and unless you're flapping your mouth
throwing rocks at someone else you're
not even a real person and we're sitting
there hanging out and you're talking
about your experiences with genes work
back in the day and and that's work with
your boys stuff and you know it's just
it's just cool appreciate it thank you
[Applause]
all right I know you guys got questions
and so we've got some basic info that I
want to talk about out if they want to
cover some stuff themselves if they have
something they want to throw they
welcome but otherwise man let's get the
audience to ask some questions because
it's rare it's rare you get these guys
on the table at the same time so
did you hear he said he said what traits
do you look for us specifically in male
plants if you're seeking a good breeder
well I'm a big fan of the stem rub and I
really love terpenes and the all the
different possibilities that there are
in the cannabis species so that's
something that has done me served me
well for ever and I'll probably never
put down that tool you know no matter
what and then you know we did some some
testing of males this year that's kind
of a cool trick but yeah
and then I you know certainly structure
and if you're trying to breed for
homozygosity your uniformity then you
want to look for one that has a similar
structure to you know if you're trying
to make an inbred line for example or
something like that so gene you want to
do some of that yeah that's actually
just touching the plant and and and
seeing really what the smells you get
from the stem different ones are
different so like og and everybody's
nose works different but like me I can
pick an OG male hella easy cuz it smells
like dill pickles to me and if it smells
like dill pickles that one has it and it
doesn't mean that it'll necessarily
carry it depending on what you're
pulling it from so if you already have
seeds where you know that all the
females do smell like OG and then you've
get a male out of there that you know
like if I was gonna be breeding
something with OG for example I'd be
like okay what does it need improvement
on so you want a little bit of an
improved structure so it's a little more
sturdy you want improved resistance to
powdery mildew so if I was breeding oh
geez I'd probably
like stick them in a room and get them
really humid for a little while maybe
let them droop a couple times before
they're really flower and heavy so that
I can kind of trigger their stress
response so that they'll get attacked on
purpose so you can kind of go okay
there's the one that that that's
resistant because otherwise if you treat
to treat them you know if they have
perfect conditions and you're breeding
for something that's triggered by bad
conditions you're not gonna see it so it
doesn't you there's no way to select for
that so you have to kind of put
pressures on things to see different
things like if you want to know if a
brand if the branches are strong you're
gonna have to snap them you'd have to be
like alright weak weak branches you
break some you know and then like some
some plants grow with like actually
almost sometimes it'll almost look like
a bubble at the at the junction of the
branch and the main stalk so it'll
actually be like there's these ones
where they'll never break right at the
junction they'll actually Bend and kind
of break over right up from it a little
bit and those ones tend to be a lot more
sturdy and they I found those in in most
stuff so it's like you know little
things like that are cool to look for
but you know yeah the stem rub is
basically if you I really like to if I
can grow something if I have enough
seeds if I don't have enough I'll grow
them and I'll just use all the males and
all the females and do an open
pollination so I know I have a bunch
more and then out of my favorite females
then I'll try some of those and when I
do the FIR when I grow them out the
first time I'll try to figure out which
plants you have to observe a lot so you
look okay these plants I can notice
these things about them and then when
they finish as female plants then you
kind of see trends so you go okay well
the every female that looked like this
or that had this stem rub they wound up
being like this and then you can get a
correlation there and then you know okay
so like if you're if you're looking for
a good
Gmail and ego this one smells like OG
it's like it turns out no they're really
good og clones to me that I have they
smell like pickles so I want the mail
that smells like pickles if it smells
like og when it's done it might not
smell like og already smells like og on
the stem so that it's it's kind of like
learning the plants and I like to learn
them before I try to really do any
selective breeding and that makes it
easier and that's the thing about
looking for male traits is there's
overall ones you don't want one that's a
pest magnet you don't want one that's a
fungus magnet you don't want one that
has really weak snappy structure you
know if maybe if they're super hard to
clone or they have really weak roots
there's some basic things that you can
look for just overall and go it's not
the best plant for these reasons but a
lot of times with selecting males you
actually want to find the one that
carries what you like about the females
so that takes observation and figuring
out where it is and different different
genes basically travel in groups in
breeding to where you might try to get
rid of something and discover that every
time you get rid of that you get rid of
the other thing you wanted so maybe you
go oh I always want maybe somebody's
already May as I've already bred
something that you're starting with
where you go mmm the one that I like to
smoke I can grow as many as I want and
that one's I really like they always
have kind of flimsy branches so you
might be stuck with that unless you want
to make a new hybrid and then
incorporate strength and in your new
hybrid you can get new stuff happening
you know but it's really for for male
selecting to me is really looking
finding which male is the one that
really does what I want in that type and
then using those kind of males so it
really takes like studying the way that
is and then you can pick them and then
of course use your you know use your
general things where you go okay
anything crappy we don't want to use
that but have the ones that we like you
know you then you want to figure out
what's like the actual it's almost like
seeing a face and recognize in the face
or recognizing a voice you're
there's that plant I know that plant it
always does this you want to find those
correlations and those groups of traits
that all travel together like I someone
was asking me about the pias that I
sold this year their purple stem and
they're all purple stem and they all
have the same smell and the trip was
that the purple stem travels with this
particular group of terpenes so that
it's really easy to breed it to have the
smell if you just look for the ones with
a purple stems and then you smell the
stalk there might be a couple of them
that are a little off you go no but this
one has the most of that smell and it's
purple stem you put them together and
really fast I was able to go okay this
is that so if that wasn't that those
that male might have been the sturdiest
and the stinkiest and the fastest
growing but if you hate that smell don't
pick the purple stem one you got to get
a different one so you got to learn the
plants and then when you select your
males then you can you can have you know
success a lot easier you can also just
go I really like this plant and use that
male because you're likely to get plants
that look like it that might have been
what you like you're like wow this thing
has a luster and a vigor to it and it's
like well you're at least gonna get that
and then you can find out later if you
get those other traits that are
important to you too you can always try
it you always throw it and see if it
sticks but you wanna you wanna ideally
learn what you're working with first and
then like I was talking about the the
weird the weirdos in the cherry limeade
like if you didn't mind having really
little weird plants you might be able to
make really cool stuff with that cuz the
weeds always kill her the plants not
that good though so what I did is I
looked and looked
till I got males that had the same smell
and the same resinous leaves and
everything and then I went okay so this
is like that it's more rare in this form
but this has the traits I like in that
but this thing grows and it doesn't have
weird a weird look to it that freaks
people out so then you know you wind up
going with that but that's how I select
males personally is by learning what it
is like you're like okay what if you
were breeding dogs
no you'd be like okay you're not gonna
breed Rottweilers and go I liked this
one it didn't have Rottweiler markings
but it's good Rottweiler and then after
a while people be like this ain't a
Rottweiler dude you didn't pick the
right one that was a sport it was
different and it wasn't the right thing
to use so you want to learn you want to
know what a Rottweiler looks like you
want to know how tall is the shoulder
how tall is the hips
what's the sway in the back how long is
the tail on a puppy how do the ears lay
what are their where do their teeth sit
howard what what are the what's the line
in the front all that stuff to learn to
go okay now I'm breeding dogs so if you
really want to breed stuff you really
have to know the description of what
you're shooting for and that's how you
pick the males but that's not to say you
might you might have had a killer dog
that was like a Rottweiler that was all
black or all tan and you're like I like
that one nothing wrong with that you're
just gonna be going a new place and you
have to have focus for doing that so you
can just randomly select a male because
you like it but it's gonna be more
difficult to lock down the exact things
you want so you want to learn your
genetics to the typical Mew know
what can we as the community do on a
political level to protect the people
who do the breeding you know when Beth
was up yesterday it was one of the
better presentations I've seen in a
minute because it gave you a protection
tool box and I think that and I know
Jerry whiting and Jerry's a savvy smart
guy from the tech era and I think he has
the like the largest collection of Black
Panther memorabilia because that's what
his family was so he has this he has
this concepts of protecting things and
preserving culture in a different way
than most people do and because he was
successful in tech it also gave him a
different view of how these things
operate and I think that the stuff that
we took a look at yesterday was the
abilities to be able to get yourself
contractual protection and I think with
community protection and support is
really just try not to screw each other
you know fundamentally man choose not to
burn the guy you're doing business with
and that seemed to work for a long time
I mean to me it's pretty simple and I
think that that you know in my
perspective from someone who traffics
genetics what I want to be able to see
is and what I've always done is I've
always given credit to the people whose
cultivars I use or material I use or
information I use because what happens
then is you promote just like Jason was
promoting NAT and gene saying hey man I
ran his stuff that was killed and my
friends run his stuff that's a courtesy
he didn't have to say it but he wanted
to say hey you know you guys are some
some guys that I respect and I
appreciate and what it does is it adds a
level of legitimacy that you can't add
yourself I had this discussion with
someone today about the internet saying
the Internet guys tell you this is how
you promote yourself and I'm like no
really give a shit about them it's it's
just banter it's crap coming out them
off perpetually and you just turn it off
what you want is you want other people
to validate what you're doing in an
honest way because that resonates in a
way that you know is true because
they're not getting paid for it they're
not a shill and I think that that's part
of it is that you know you recognize
other people's farms and you commend the
product when it's legitimate and if you
don't have an ability to move your
product but you know someone who could
move product you push that product and
you make sure that person gets credit
and with the breeders you know don't
pirate their work of you know what would
you had so funny one cuz jeans a mean
King but he was talking about how they
would rename in these varietals so they
could just get rid of the breeder and
there was this whole meme about how the
breeder was diminished minimized and
wiped out so that we can name anything
we wanted but it's it's such a true
statement because you're so you're so
desirous of your own success that you
forgot how you got there and I think
when it comes to with the breeders that
if you can keep them alive in the
conversation all the time you know in a
courteous sense where this is the
material I got from Jason this is what I
used if you want to buy more you can go
to them if you've got questions you can
go to them you become in this incredible
referral network and I think that the
thing that protects you from shit in
life most is money your own money makes
you pretty safe because you can afford
infrastructure tools connections and
that's really what we've been deprived
of right now is liquidity and so we have
to kind of pull up our skills until we
can rebuild our liquidity but hopefully
this bout of poverty teaches us how to
behave a little more intelligently in a
communal form so that when we do rear
eyes up again as a craft culture you're
able to actually take the education that
we just got about how you better stick
together you're gonna die and then use
it to create the models of protection so
that you end up having individuals that
can do the work so that all you have to
do is do your work and a lot of people
would rather just grow and farm than
have to spend all their free time
breeding - so I mean that's my opinion
on it it's it's you you you you gotta
you got to be honest with whose work
you're pirating and make sure you kick
back credit yeah I'd agree with with
that Kevin I'm sure you guys have had it
happen I've had it happen where where
groups get ahold you work and they
rename it as their own and they don't
give credit and I I feel like the the
history and the story is a big part of
why things are appealing and so I I
always
try to be as forthcoming and factual
with with all the information that we
put out there about what we're working
with and you know there's there's
companies out there that are just
getting rid of the names altogether
where it's it's it's the all the all the
history of you know hundreds of years of
people carrying this plants just wiped
away and now it's it's this new just a
whole new way of categorizing things and
you know I don't know really how I feel
about that I like people being inventive
and being unique but I'm also you know
very connected to the history and you
know there's something that that might
not sit so well about about just totally
renaming people stuff you know maybe
maybe if you come up with a name for a
specific Fino like that that could be
okay but but still it's the the whatever
Fino of this strain from this person is
still be honest about where it came from
and you can still name your fee nose and
as far as protecting your genetics I
think the open cannabis project or you
know somehow doc documenting the genes
as open-source that's the only really
other alternative to trying to patent
your stuff and keep other people from
having it I want other people to grow it
but I don't want people to grow it and
then take it from me and say I can't
grow it that's crazy and that's
literally something that could be going
on right now we've got you know a number
of cannabis patents that have already
been issued that are gonna be
problematic in the future I'm sure
there's gonna be challenges to them but
I think one of them is any one to one
that doesn't have mercy and in it it's
technically under patent right now is
that correct there's there's something
there's some very broad cannabis patents
out there right now and I'm sure there's
going to be more down the road and you
know documenting your genetics through
groups like the open cannabis project or
or you know a way to to combat that you
the genetic data is fully important for
a lot of reasons but it's harder to
translate that information to it's so
more chemo type data and getting
donations for that will be really useful
to have prior argument so anybody that
didn't hear that he was saying chemo
type data is as or possibly more
important than the you know the genetic
testing so yeah and and that that can be
hopefully a discussion all on to its own
that's I would love to delve deeper into
that and how we can protect the
community's work as a whole one thing I
wanted to touch on is you know yeah when
when you talk about you know you're
saying you're gonna go try and sell your
product to people assume self-interest
and so they always take whatever you say
with a grain of salt but if they
overhear it from their friend that says
no no his stuffs dope I like that or I
like this type and and you're gonna take
that you're gonna take that in maybe a
little more deeper or what I'm trying to
say is is support your community and the
other people if you see something that
you like you know let people know and
hopefully others are gonna return the
favor to you and and that that's I feel
how we build the community together and
help help each other survive so so you
know definitely I think people take it
into account a little more when when
they hear it you know around you know
through somebody else or through the
grapevine or I heard that this that's
that's how hype builds is is you know
people over here from somewhere else
that oh that's the one and and yeah
there is something that's that's you
know genuine to that is there's there's
reasons behind why those things got
built up it can't all just be pure
advertising or
you know there's there's got to be some
you know human element to why something
you know become successful and so yeah
just support support your neighbor
support when they're doing good let
people know it you know and and I think
that that from all of us that came from
the era where you didn't rat on people
which seems to be a foreign thought
nowadays ratting out on people screwing
people over isn't ratting and so when
he's saying you know make sure you
support make sure you also call out
things that you see wrong because that
they're screwing him they're gonna screw
you
and by the time they get to you they
might not be anybody protect you and so
a lot of it is if you're seeing
unscrupulous stuff you don't have to get
out and broadcasted on the general world
but you can tell your friends man I get
asked all the time about would you do
business with this person and I try not
to screw anybody in the way that would
cause problems but ultimately if I know
that you have a history of pikin people
I always just say the same thing I would
be cautious and what that means is that
I can't give you a recommendation and
that you should do your homework so I
don't have to go too deep into it but it
just says that I can't vouch for you but
I'm not gonna throw a rock at you that's
throwing a rock at you and and that's
important because someone said would you
work with that distribute or I'd say I
would be cautious and then they realize
that there's some reason because I'm not
in a business against them so therefore
why am I having trepidation and it's
because I saw something or heard
something and I'm just like look you
don't need to get screwed either so you
don't have to go and you know
shish-kabob um but if people are doing
good work you know make sure you let
people know and if and if people are
doing stuff that are unethical in a way
that's gonna really cause problems
they're not gonna hold back against you
either most people hold back because
they're afraid of ramification they're
afraid back in the day was they're
afraid they're gonna lose all their
teeth well now that that's not one of
the tools and I don't really think it
should be a tool but it was a very
effective one you have to be able to use
financial and financial is to protect
each other and make sure that the people
that are doing the
work on getting beat to death and that
they're still around for you to utilize
as a resource and you you have to
preserve as many these resources as
possible because without it you end up
having a shrunken population of partners
to do stuff in the future and for me
like what I've done my whole career I've
needed the people around because I only
can do so much myself and my success was
really built off of all these
relationships I made with other people
and over the course of time we did
better than we did worse so don't
anybody screw you yes yes I believe so
that what you could do is if you did a
licensing agreement with the breeder you
could also bring material that you have
and do collaborative projects that
material would then be able to be
jointly promoted you'd be able to have
stock that was unique to you because all
the material from the cross would be
held the tool you could figure out what
was the cultivar you wanted to release
into the public as production material
not as a cultivar unless you're building
a nursery if you're building a nursery
then you said hey dad I want to work
with you on a project I would love to
take some of the stuff you're doing put
with something I'm doing let's find a
cut let's put it into the market let's
both be honest did the shit work yeah
there's a good one
and then I'll both you can do combined
breeding and you can do licensing that
allows you to be able to use your
respective IP and then you can then find
individuals that you can license the
clone to because one of the problems is
overproduction of varietals and so you
end up out competing the success because
you got too much of the same material
and you know that I think that's crucial
but I think a lot of us just need more
legal help with that where we need to
have more people like Beth come in and
attorneys that were like present was
great to have an attorney present
yesterday because he could kind of say
listen this is how we see this happen
and then you're able to get a better
idea because I don't think any of us so
at least 95% of us haven't have been
involved in patent protection of genomic
material you know I mean I'm someone
messing around all the time but it's
that's not what I do I still have
lawyers that I work with because I don't
have time to go to law school and I
don't want oh it's not my thing
but I need them
yeah I think licensing is cool because
really a license is just a contract
between you and your associate and you
know it certainly it's not you know as
binding as something like a patent it's
it's but it it's more voluntary and I
really I do encourage folks to do that
kind of thing I mean they look at you
know jeans pre-rolled line like you know
that's in a way like that's good for
everybody because you know that pre-roll
person might not have had quite such a
namesake or following and so you know
it's good for their pre-rolls and and
it's cool for Jean because he gets
credit all that stuff and just one more
thing like I I keep hearing you know
everybody we're all a little scared and
we all like know that the these big
powers that have deep deep pockets are
coming and you know you might sort of
react to it and do something that you
might not otherwise do you know get rid
of all your your purple strains or
something dumb like that but just
remember that like when booze became
legal there wasn't like a Jim Beam or
there wasn't Budweiser or Coors those
kind of evolved out of you know they're
being quick and and successes but then
you know or in the mid-90s all of a
sudden there was this thing that came
out it was like micro beer and I never
thought in a million years that there'd
still be breweries opening in Humboldt
County that are thriving and just the
same with wine like but it takes a while
for that to kind of
mature like you don't go into the gas
station down the you know over Piercy or
whatever and and stick your nose up at
the new microbrews but you do after good
you know maybe you do or maybe don't but
at the Korres I like PBR I don't know
but that stuff hasn't had a chance to
really like you know like the PBRs and
the course and the Budweiser's of
cannabis no one knows that that's who
they are yet and so it's gonna take at
least probably like another year maybe
two before that really develops and then
what I what I'm really confident about
is that the you know the regenerative
and the small and the real craft
actually then starts to have its you
know days in the Sun you know pun
intended and you know and I think that's
the same with strains - I mean God
remember how freaking long it was just
impossible to you know like its you just
had to grow OG and then you grew a bunch
of this really cool awesome stuff for
your head and but you just always you
know kind of had to grow a G and I think
that that's kind of changed too so you
know let's just remember that we are
pioneers and like I think you know what
me and gene said about like well I'm not
ignoring the fact that the markets
saying one thing but I'm also not giving
up on where my frickin roots are and
where my convictions lie and stuff like
that
[Music]
alright we got out Lissa but we're gonna
wrap this up because we got a little big
going on we're burning through some time
so I just want to say thank you so much
for taking the time to ask good
questions and I want to thank you guys
for taking the time out of your lives to
show up and answer the questions and
like I said Matt's been a pleasure to
work with you for as long as I've known
all three of you and my goal is to all
of you get grey like me and we still
didn't say business
[Music]