[Music]
the plants that you received were bred
by Josh and he'll tell you about what he
did to make them and they'll give you
the correct name on him but the main
point was that I was so impressed with
them in flower form that I knew that
that it was something that had an
ability to absolutely catch an attention
of a customer and it's something that
you can't deny it when you smoked it
when you smelled it when you felt the
effects and it was quality and I want
that material to be shared so that the
individuals can and that was his desire
to is to see the public get their hands
on it
so we're back to another breeding
discussion and I'm gonna do the same
thing I'm gonna let the guys introduce
themselves and then we can start getting
into some questions and once again thank
you for taking the time to audio your
lives to listen to these discussions hi
I'm Graham mr. Bob Hemphill
[Applause]
I've been breeding Kym cannabis since 95
and collecting clones since about the
same time and growing cannabis for
production so I've made my life and just
dedicated most of my time the
preservation work with just keeping
strains alive that weren't even market
valuable anymore and amazingly 20 years
later they've come back around where you
know like the clubs need to have
something besides the cookies on the
market you know and just trying to have
a diversity in the gene pool so we can
get those old school buses and just
thought kind of stuff so that's really
what I'm up to you guys kind of know me
I'm Joshua Rutherford I'm not really a
breeder I'm a pollen checker but
straight straight up like I you know I
feel like what I'm able to do is I have
a good nose and a good taste I got
blessed right away
the first two plants I ever grew was
Strawberry Cough in ATF and they were
legit cuts I've never seen maybe once or
twice as I've seen the ATF that even is
in the field and so I just got blessed
that way and so you know every time I
got something else it wasn't there was
like me being beep I just I throw throw
stuff away so fast I I'm heartless you
know I don't know if that's the best
thing there's probably other things you
can pull but it allowed me to do is to
make some money and to kind of be pretty
self funded I do have a small partner
but anyways so this one is um hi ho from
Kenner auto genetics I got and it was
feminized and so I wanted to sift
through and make sure I got the ones
that we're gonna have any Herms right so
I'm not really down with colloidal
silver or
whatever the other stuff is and so I
hadn't accidentally learned a technique
by throwing too much seabird guano
pellets down which is a super high in
nitrogen and so I I heard out the whole
bottom of my Obama Koosh one time and it
was just the bottoms and I was like okay
well that's something so I searched and
searched and searched and and somewhere
I found they Oh too much nitrogen will
force herm and so I was like okay so I
tried it another time I tried three or
four times and it's pretty predictable
you know I can buy the seabird guano
pellets throw them down pretty hard
water I mean really hard and it it works
so that's what I did with the PI hoe and
then I also had in the room this
Catholic schoolgirl that was pretty cool
and then this ruched seven from Kevin
and so I was actually scratching my head
on it cuz I'm just kind of reading into
breeding and so I was scratching my head
I hit up gene on Instagram and it's like
what should I do with this like is this
gonna just be a bunch of Hern bullshit
and he's like apple doesn't fall far
from the tree like okay that's not
enough information but it kind of is
that's how I felt so I went for it you
know whatever
so I ran 300 seeds of it and I spent you
know all night going through those cuts
and I pulled that about six of them and
and then smoked them and this is the one
I kept and uh I've run it twice and it
doesn't hurt I let it run extra long and
stuff so I've kind of checked it so it's
definitely stable and it's real big and
beefy I run it in the greenhouse it's
super floral I wouldn't put it in the
fruit category and there's not a lot
that I call floral that or that's come
across my palate that's really been
floral and it's it's a it's a different
customer like it my mom my parents
actually smoked it probably shouldn't
say that on the Internet yeah a couple
weeks ago for the first time in like 30
years you know and I just let him have a
little bit of it but it was perfect
because it's a real bright uplifting
happy high my mom was just like what
what is this flavor it it's kind of like
this muted lemon floor but you know
that's I know that's fruit but it's real
muted and florally rosey and yeah so I
was super happy with it now when I was
coming down I
to give something back to keV cuz he
gave me some stuff and so I was like oh
this is perfect they see it you know so
that's kind of yeah man thanks for for
being cool you know it's it's a it's a
nice one and and the thing was before
before I hardly get into it what's nice
about the panel is that I could
centigram like a preservationist cuz
he's he's someone who whole there is
many times I was talked to a man he
holds varietals for time and preserves
him because he believes in the priceless
innocent of it not just in business but
to himself and to the cannabis culture
and and Hardy
it was his scientific reader where he
has a very extensive background in many
different things and so it gives you a
different direction and then Josh says
I'm just a pollen chuckle but the truth
is I wanted to see people who would just
pollen chocolates cuz that's where
everybody started and what happens is
that you start to believe you don't have
a validity if you're not someone special
and the truth of it is is that you you
have to be able to start somewhere and
to get a plant that's that quality from
someone who's just the pollen chucker
lets you realize that you also can
succeed and it's important because it
lets you it lets you take and inspire
other people who are gonna follow you
every one of you will eventually have
someone who takes your place in the game
and it's important to be able to have
people that are gonna take your place
that have good ethics and a desire to
smoke kill weed otherwise you're gonna
be an old man filled in a land full of
boof and that's it's or women you know
it's and it's not what you want so um
it's beautiful to have the diversity and
I'll let Hardy go but that's the whole
point of it that that your your lack of
full time professional breeding doesn't
diminish your validity at all it's just
it to me you are the symbol of people
who love weed and let their taste guide
them in their process no that's that's
kion Hardy with have Cora genetics and
was as in care collective we're one of
the first well dispensary delivery out
of Mendocino 9.31 program and rode that
out till the end and then Mendocino
County as we know this
continue the 9.3 so at that time just
switched everything over to R&amp;D and
breeding and working with CBD cultivars
so that was that focus in 2009-10 where
you tell people show lab results and
they'd see CBD and it's like why are you
growing this you know they don't relate
to that and at a point earlier one thing
was even this was 2012 if you got caught
with lab results or seeds you're a
sophisticated operation and you could
you you were in more trouble
so if you had pictures and this is
something seeing this evolution and it's
like you're not a being a pollen chucker
it's like we were all chucking pollen in
the beginning back here when it was like
growing up around here when you had to
hide out in a fucking tree when you had
a helicopter coming over you sideways
and you just had a little bit of pollen
that you had to put on high and
pollinate on that plant at a certain
time but it was only one little plant so
this is how the especially this is
Ground Zero and it's amazing to see this
many people here like coming out like
this and I know things are changing but
we are like everybody in here is like
pioneer to the roots like this is coming
back home this last year and traveling
so much it's like you guys are this is
the shit right here like as far as when
you're gonna find good old genetics and
people that really have that hard a soul
and this last year having to travel
around and seeing the big corporations
that are coming in and just this general
disrespect or disregard for the history
of the plant that people here
responsible for keeping this plant alive
and being stewards of of these genetics
and now it's just kind of coming
together and part of this is like
collecting this data and part of that IP
because we all have something special to
offer and don't discount that because
everybody here has something their own
kung fu to bring to the table
what I was gonna say is what when you
first began and then in you know 95 zone
what were you what was the stuff that
you were working with when you first get
into cannabis because it must have had a
profound impact on the fact that it made
you love it so much that you never let
go of it because you're uh you're a
dedicated collector what was the stock
you were working with when you begin
unfortunately I don't have any of those
seats anymore but it new year's show and
between 94 to 95 like squirt some but
from humble and it was purple and grape
and just dink as fuck and that's what
encouraged me to like breed with the
males and females the next year is
because I wanted to have some more of
that because in years prior to that I
just grew Mexican back seat you know cuz
I there was no tank available and it's a
shame at the time I really didn't know
about breeding brothers the sisters that
just didn't seem right to me so I out
crossed that strain to Southern Virginia
lines and didn't keep it pure but if I
would have open pollinated that line and
kept it pure I would really have had
something special because it was amazing
I'll never forget I was at a Grateful
Dead show that next spring and I still
had summon there's these really pretty
girls from California on dead tour and I
showed him a bud and I didn't even say
that I grew and breaded I just said it
was from Virginia and they just laughed
at me and like started clowning me
thinking I was lying trying to pick him
up but I still think back and that was
some amazing when he dank just Afghan
purple shit that was probably Arkell
related
ya know I think that was like that that
was look at the little heyday of that
transition from the last of the outdoor
that still remained before the raids
here then the raids came in people's
populations compressed and then indoor
just blew up and that's when I started
seeing a lot of these old lines being
woven out because they just didn't work
on the indoor platform but yeah I don't
have a lot of this stuff from that
either that's what I'm trying to go back
and dig through time and find older
people that were able to hold on to
little pieces there's none of us really
know thing knew what we had we kind of
thought that it was gonna be here
forever like that because it had just
come into our hands you know you didn't
really have the same level of
appreciation for the scarcity now that
you did then you were like whoa I'll get
more good stuff so you went into the
early / the early person and are you
talking about this first stuff that you
really started messing around was that
the ATF caught yeah I actually still
hold it that's the only thing I've been
able to keep my whole damn grow career
I've lost a lot of stuff but we kept it
among three guys so it came into the
house we started you know busted and out
and four thousand a pack you know I
figured the game this out real quick in
a year and a half four thousand a pack
I've you know see you guys I'm moving
you know you guys are owned in that
basement and but it was um yeah it's the
the musky Asst earthy ax sting I think
I've ever smelled straight-up you know I
kind of sniff around to see if I can
find anything it's like forest floor I'd
love to talk to anybody that has any
experience with that with that cut Dino
Josh and Kelly have some connection to
the Matanuska I'm not sure the exact
difference some people say it's the same
but it's real fluffy and it's weak I
could see it across the room in that jar
we all would be like what's that one
it's white bring that one over here you
know and it's interesting cuz
marketability it's it it's fluffy you
know you when you grab it other charts
like oh I don't know pop that thing open
it fills the room and yeah so I'm
interested to like actually start
working and putting some stuff into it
so my goal the summer is to you know run
a bunch of stuff and find some mails
that I think will put some stuff on it
and just you know try to start learning
like
like which accent said was earlier I
know this ATF really well you know I can
walk into a garden and see crosses with
it actually I found that the other day
and a 502 garden they had a a Calley
crush crossed with it as like before she
could say ATF I was like ATF you know
just three leaves they always look the
same you know she's like how'd you know
I go I've been staring at that plant for
10 years you know so you're you're a old
school cat from the day here yeah and
that's one thing with this strings these
days and like looking somebody'd
mentioned earlier like looking at the
chemo type we've gotten so caught up in
this name game anymore it's like having
to backtrack from this and that was one
thing looking at CDD CBDs and other
cannabinoids it's like okay we're the
origins of this one recently is the
Varens and we're the Varens are the
origins of the Varens and we're finding
more from like that Africa from Africa
and like Lao areas so why are why is
this happening but it's like we're it's
having to backtrack right now so some of
these older sativas that weren't
marketable then it's that that's that's
still that smell and it's out there and
if that's the thing it's up its up in
these areas but Jerry for instance it's
like with that Panama red and going back
and like these poisons and like you go
back in history and on this lineage it's
identifying the baseline so that's
something the last couple years I've
been working on is Kuwait is breeding
bringing these older cultivars back and
getting that baseline back and then sort
of moving forward from there it's like
looking at it like that color palette of
like you have your CMYK you know you
have your basic colors so let's start
with this and from there we identify
these different traits and now that
we're able to look at the key mo type
and genotype of what these what are the
constituents of the cultivar that you're
looking for so it's like if you're
looking to make extract and that's all
you're looking for you want that Orange
to juice with those terpenes or if
you're going for just certain
cannabinoid
and and identifying those genetics so
it's like we've been monoculture so much
here especially in Northern California
being run by Sour Diesel and og because
this is the market this is what just put
in the paycheck in so that these
cultivars have been lost that were
actually have probably more of a value
because of what they have inside of them
instead of the marketability of what
that pretty flower looks like per unit
you know that's going to a market so
it's like looking at these cultivars at
what we're growing maybe not per gram
per square meter or per foot or light
but milligram it's like what is what's
inside of this and that's something
looking into especially the you know the
original cultivars these are where that
the treasures are and starting to
backtrack right now and actually collect
the data because that's where that IP
that all of us have worked our ass off
for is a value what are you we're gonna
get into some I'm gonna ask gram you
know what what what directions are you
moving into and you're here in Cali but
you're in Washington so the question is
gonna be you know what directions are
you seeing in your region and and then
your global you see a global picture
because you are connected to so many
different things and it was his way
we'll be able to see what's going on
here what's going on where you are
what's going on from your view we're on
a world wide picture so mostly I just
I'm working on some real strong Northern
Lights indicas and hash plants and
trying to get the old-school indicas in
a seed form so it's more axial
accessible to people I'm also working on
constantly doing open pollination zhan
different land races just to preserve
them and on top of that I'm also working
on several different lines and CBD
trying to isolate the CBD I'm working on
a Panama
that originally went from two - one two
three - once in the next generation and
then in this next generation after that
I've just found a 39 - one which is
pretty exciting so I'm really excited to
flower that out and check check the
percentages
what are some of the land races you
playing with well I just try to work
with and preserve any that I can get my
hands on and um you know a lot of people
in the seat buying market say they want
land race they really want good land
race that works well for them they don't
want every land race because there's a
lot of problems and you know when you're
doing a true open pollination you're not
even calling out there hermaphrodites
you know so it's just mostly for
preservation and look for good strains
that maybe I can pull the next seeds out
and make out crosses with them that's
something that would work for the for
the market but when I do find a good one
that I can release I will but it's lots
of times there's problems with the line
or this source doesn't want it release
pure unfortunately because I I've seen
some of the Northern Light the work
you're doing it's over the hash plant
and to me it's awesome because I mean
that was stuff that was red-hot and
ultra quality and it's time frame and it
I think kind of deluded as time went by
and I try to tell people the source
material was not weak there was some
stunning stock so it's killer that you
go and back that route and it seems like
it's pretty well-received - you know I
see some interaction around it you know
some just basically trying to duplicate
a lot of Neville's work and
unfortunately since he seedbank didn't
do a good job and keeping those genes
pulls so I had the old cuts and luckily
just the no:1 came to me from when I was
working with coastal seats and cake you
had gotten it from classic seeds
it was just things came together in a
really good situation with that wine and
Cantor Otto just gifted me some two by
fives that he made F Tucson and the
original F ones were made from Jim
Ortega and that's a eighty seed bank
stock and I'm real excited about that
because that's you know just the fact
that that can help share that into the
gene pool again is just a good place to
be you know it's awesome like I said I'm
older and and the the problem is that
you have all these fond memories of
stuff from a day when people try to tell
you that you know that shit's outdated
but I'm like I'm telling you no it's not
and it's gone and so you pine for the
memories in the past and when I see
people digging things out I get excited
because it lets me know that things are
still alive and lets you also know that
the your belief that trends continuously
move forward role and so it was cool to
see the Northern Lights work you've been
doing yeah yeah there was some of the
first kind but that I got a chance to
smoke when I was a kid and I just want
to say something that's not quite on
that topic but I wanted to get it out
here to the everyone so when I first
moved on the Emerald triangle in 97
there was an amazing amount of genetics
every farm had their own genetics
amazing strains first there was a purple
wave and then then there was the og
diesel wave and basically a lot of farms
stopped growing those original and
genetics just to sell their buddies here
so they got on the purple bandwagon then
they got on the gas bandwagon but you
know the people still have the genetics
here in the county it might be your
neighbor it might be your family
relatives whatever it is find those old
seeds and get out I'm out and if you're
not gonna work with them yourself give
them the someone that will and let's try
to preserve some of this amazing gene
pool that's still intact around this
county
but uh that's a good segue to what you
you asked about like some of the trends
were seen in Washington and we're closed
nothing comes in our little legal box
right now and it's super unfortunate you
know we can get stuff out for instance
like how did I get that out I I sold it
to myself as a medical patient from my
wreck farm to me and then it can go out
from there but I can't put anything back
in so the trend has been really
interesting right now I you know
everyone's really excited that weed on
the shelves is starting to look better
but it's we're just so steps so far
behind where we were before they killed
medical you know the good weed on the
shelves is just hydro weed and you could
you open it up some of it smells good
none of it tastes good you know I don't
want to say none of it there's some good
cultivators but you know kana as I
pervade the whole scene so um yeah I
don't know we're just seeing a lot of
the hot stuff that comes through that
people want to latch on to wedding cake
you know cookies crosses but I do want
to say it like I feel like you know
we're a couple years ahead of you guys
in this and it's that it's starting to
turn you know we just have had a couple
of bills that came up to allow they're
not voted in yet but to allow for small
farmers to sell direct and the the head
of the LCB the liquor liquor cannabis
board spoke twice publicly about being
behind and this like actually called
these guys I like I'm like you got you
know like this would save my family's
life like 10 days I turn around like you
know we'd pay our bills in 10 days if I
could sell this weed that I have here
that people will actually really want
but when I go into the stores they go is
it over 20% does it look like a cookie
no it's like I went I was I had to write
all this is gonna go off on this I had a
really you know I don't want to be too
negative but a hard experience this
summer heads I brought in some you know
I'm actually not in the retail market
I've just been kind of like creeping
along and so I brought some really
beautiful DEP in to retail and I'd you
know we do the whole thing so I packaged
it I did all of it right at trim did I
put it in these jars one ounce jars two
flavors
garlic-breath in the pie ho rough
trimmed right
$55 it's in glass it's organic it's some
grown like what else can you want I even
said hey man show me what you got in the
price range do you know 150 175 200
bucks on your shelf like what brown from
last year yellow from last year like
don't you think this looks better do you
think it would sell that's not organic
this is you know nothing because all
they want is that above 20% they want
that fucking tight thing and they go
with a go what else you got I go dude
I grew all this weed I'm two miles from
your store like I'm the guy that on the
TV that they want to talk about and he's
like what else you got you got some sex
lube you got some chapstick I'm like no
bro I'll go make some sweatshirts but
you know and but just kind of telling
all that that like I feel like that's
still coming big for you guys but you
know we've been talking over and over
again and we're just starting to see it
so I'm personally feeling encouraged
there's some some guys that just started
a you know bought a license and they
started with 16 lights and they got
certified Dominion seed skunk and he
came over and helped to make the
selections and they're selling out
they're crushing it everyone's talking
about this little sixteen light and
they're just you know they're doing the
thing we're talking about but just you
know nano almost microbe you know so
that's kind of what I see coming for
Washington is just kind of the slow slow
thing and in and to be honest I'm
waiting for another wave of it because
the the federal curtain hasn't dropped
and we haven't really talked about that
yet but like the people who we think are
big boys in California they might not be
the big boys when the federal curtain
drops you know Canada is I brought it up
last night it's scary dude it's scary so
it's just you know that's what how I see
it is like we got to keep doing this
coming together share with each other
find a way to survive and yeah I feel
you
yeah yeah this last year it's like
traveling more and working in
Switzerland and Africa as well and you
have now India and Colombia blowing up
these people talking thousands of
hectares this qualifies right now is him
and it's that point zero three percent
Switzerland it's one percent Macedonia
just opened up one and a half percent
they use point zero three percent as
this baseline so this last year was
breeding seeds especially for the
European market African market they want
feminized auto flowers and it's just
filled planet and they're going in and
harvesting with combines they're just
looking at it it's all going into
isolate so you have this this market
that is just CBD Hungary and what
qualifies that is this point zero three
percent these new cultivars though it's
wind to harvest them as well because we
have time it's like you go at eight
weeks and you're you're gonna be right
under that hot point and all of a sudden
you hit nine ten and some of these will
jump up and depending on the climate and
work you're taking tissue culture so you
can have vitro coming from the u.s.
going to Switzerland this the same
culture and it's the way it's performing
just like anything but its environment
and then you look at the the whole
profile of the plant and this is how
this is evolving so rapidly and right
now it's this hemp thing after this farm
bill passed especially here in the
states it's on the scalability so that's
the one thing with the CBD market right
now here in the states it's this there's
this huge demand last week the state in
California they said that and this is
something I don't know if it's been
talked about or whatnot but is that male
pollen is the state is looking
regulators looking at it as a weapon
this is something that the this is
somebody that doesn't know what they're
talking about but at that same time so
what's that gonna do for a breeder to
restrict you if you're gonna have a male
plant
you can't flower that male pollen out or
you're gonna you know these are things
that are in California we are so
regulated here like in you can go to
Vermont right now in $25.00 permit and
if you have 500 acres you can plan it so
what you know this of we're here dealing
with we're dealing with the most intense
adverse conditions pretty much on a
global scale right now and especially
here where we've spearheaded this
movement so as things change it's like
adapting here and that's the one thing
it's like these new strains everybody
has something unique here and it's that
something differentiating you do have to
feed into this you know the market what
it dick state right now and the
consumers is going to dictate what a
farmer grows as well that's that's part
of it so it's growing something that is
from your heart do you do you see in
your opinion you know as genetics move
globally product moves globally do you
see material moving from one place to
another specifically do you see
individuals that you believe will become
dominant in the production model is
there opportunities for the u.s. to move
product globally you know I mean what's
an opinion question but you know how do
you feel about it yeah and that's
something right now we're falling behind
very quickly especially with you know
CBD and isolate and what they're able to
produce in in Africa in these other
countries and have these establishing
these international markets with
importing and exporting through through
Canada through Australia through these
other companies and a lot of these other
businesses they don't want to touch the
US market there's enough profit they
don't need me to deal with the
regulations so we've been getting seeds
right now to try to get a true breeding
seed or regulated within the state of
California or within these other states
for export to go through and get your
international Narcotics Bureau license
for exporting we're behind and I don't
know you know moving forward on that it
takes the capital and that's the thing
we're talking a little behind it to move
this forward requires a help from
private sector but also the academia
sector and finding that here in
especially California with the new hemp
bill if you have an academic tie to a
university we're gonna be able to allow
to cultivate and breed hemp cannabis you
know it's like growing the dank like
that's where we were able to do right
now is crossbreed to something you get
that it's just fire dank that it tests
at that point zero three percent so it's
him to explain that right now to the
authorities and the powers would be they
still don't wrap their head around it so
let's breed the shit out of everything
we can to get the dank out there not the
qualifies as hemp that's what they're
gonna look at it they don't you know if
you have the Terps and you have a whole
cannabinoid profile as long as it
doesn't have THC in it it qualifies as
him I always think that you know once
the big guys get playing they're just
gonna pay somebody to change that limit
you know from point four three to thirty
you know I saw it where I asked the
question someone who was in importation
years ago for fabric and I was like why
do you get the product from hungry and
they said because they can use cultivars
that have higher THC levels and we're
allowed and the production quantity per
square foot is increased
they said that you can't get what we
need as a production plant to give us a
profitable product that has that lower
THC percentage they didn't want the
cannabinoids they wanted the biomass to
do fabric and it was he was explaining
to me how us was not a hemp leader in
that because we weren't allowed to use
the plants that had too high of a THC
level and he said for some reason the
plants that have the quality for fabric
are just over that amount and he said
and it just doesn't make sense to spend
so much time trying to hunt it back when
you could just go to Hungary and they
were pumping it out freely and I so it
for them it worked because they needed
it and I think that as time goes on you
know the US would do it too it's just
that in the way our model works it
always seems to favor the wealthy you
know and I think it hungry it was
because they want to have business in
general where they they needed
have this take place they needed it to
happen they said look if everybody's
making money it's okay because
somebody's better than no money on a
commercial industrial crop but to me the
u.s. is a different model and it's the
same situation is you know what when do
when do we start to kind of get this
together you for a few Graham what uh as
you're as you're looking forward what is
uh what's the what's uh what's a
direction you'd like to see yourself in
a couple years
they just let's just let's just all
pretend we're gonna make it cuz then
it's easy right otherwise it's like I
don't know if I'm gonna be here and I
always tell people that I said I'm gonna
be here or not it's brutal but the fact
is if I don't believe I'm gonna be here
then I can't do long-term planning which
you believed you're gonna be here
because you've been banking stock for a
long time what's uh what's something
you'd like to see in a couple years for
yourself well you know just personal
desire as a breeder as a collector as a
smoker cannabis culturalism so I'm
definitely gonna be in the game in a few
years I want to be still in Northern
California in Himmel triangle ideally if
I could stay here and make a living
providing seeds to the community that
would be my ideal so you know I know I
feel like I don't want to go either I
get asked to do a lot of international
work and if I was younger and I didn't
have family it wouldn't be bad but you
know tripping around the world to do
business as cool as it is it steals time
from your life and it's been it's been a
gift to be a you know live here and I
mean I get the same go to I just want to
be able to stay here and work on the
farm that I'm building and go into the
genetic material that I've sourced all
these years and be able to use that as
trade to other people who have other
things that are I'm interested in so I
can start to continuously mind so that
you know the majority my life was spent
doing the work that I love doing
you got you got you got a farm you build
in yeah I own my farm and it's been I
mean for ten years I've been going after
this dream I have a dream and cannabis
has been you know big part of it but I
was able to buy a farm when I bought my
license and we have a son and I'm
married and yeah I would like to just be
doing a small farmer thing to be honest
that's my dream I'd love to have people
come out to my farm maybe on Saturday
buy some weed and some vegetables once
or twice a month in the summer do a big
dinner and like feed some people and
like showcase like I like to get into
stuff I love beer I love making beer I
love roasting coffee I actually want to
set up a tropical greenhouse I grow a
lot of lemons and stuff and just want to
get into care and me didn't like I'm
just a dork and I want to do that and I
kind of you know nothing big just like
just have fun and showcase what I like
to do and make enough money that I can
you know live a good life I'd ideally
like to only work 30 hours a week to be
honest you know next couple years where
do you see yourself going well develop
the farm here in Mendocino County and
want to move forward with the nursery on
that and just mainly Rd but being able
to work with more the academic community
and like work like with Eleanor here
like the Canadore what they're doing
with this barium and starting to take
this initiative to actually like it's
almost like starting over again but
these are this is like that learning
process along the way and here in
California it's just
especially unlike these large Pinot
hunts and like with Matt it's like this
is something you know being able to work
on this on large scales and that's the
only thing that's limiting in California
right now and in the states is we need
the hundreds of acres with hundreds of
thousands of seeds and being able to do
these large selects or large populations
and at this time in California is rather
difficult so looking at other locations
to be able to do this and then bring the
seed back here so it's these new
discoveries they're out there you know
there's the white elephants and the
golden unicorn
and something there's a lot that we
still have to still out there and
especially these old strains are
starting to be reintroduced where people
are looking at it sort of like the
Grinspoon I don't know if you've ever
drone that one it's like just you're
looking at it's like why am i growing in
but it's such a special little plant and
what it has in it and it's like what
extracts and whatnot but it's something
that doesn't look the best why are you
growing this but it's like what's it got
inside you know that much that's if I
had like a multi-year dream it would be
that the population that buys cannabis
starts to really have a an understanding
of what they're buying so they can
actually start to have real product
differentiation and you can start to
have the subsets the sub markets create
to have you have individuals have
specialize in certain things so it lets
the farms work lines and develop the
ability to have true Appalachian like
standardization where in this region
these things have been sorted out to do
best and you can only get these things
in this region and it allows the regions
not to have to go head to head for who's
got the best gelato but each one of
these regions has something that's
uniquely distinct to that specific place
and what to me what it'll do is it allow
you to start to have you know true
long-term preservation because if we're
just the beginning of an industry and
when I look at liquor I'm like wow you
got 70 80 years you guys been sparking
up what are we gonna be doing in 80
years you know and if we can do the
building blocks of it now and start to
create some of that stuff you actually
have the tools to go forward because
even though science takes over many
things there's always a Renaissance and
there's always outlaw there's always the
renegade that wants to buck that and do
it their own way and they're the ones
that always brought the wild shit
forward and that's what I hope to see
too about um
advice to collectors and breeders from
someone who's done a lot of work and
held a lot of work what do you recommend
to people for just how do you do it you
know on keeping clones is just don't
give up you know it's difficult
during you know moves and should it's
just you just got to keep the focus and
don't give up and always make sure your
cuts are routed before you take your
next
and sicker in the flowering room or
killer or whatever you're gonna do and
then as far as breeding just don't breed
with cookies breed with something that's
true to your heart and try to bring
something different to the gene pool
question was you know um you know how do
you like for you you've maintained the
ATF for a long time and the the question
for people is like you know how did you
maintain it what's some advice you have
for people like when I'm someone who do
it was it does what I do which is hold
libraries of time and movement area for
time I always tell people redundant
copies and make sure you give it to
people that have an appreciation for
that thing they're not big collectors
they only want to hold one or two
varietals because they will not lose
them you give it to people who want a
mass library that stuff gets lost and so
I always tell people you gotta find
people who care about the variety so
much that all they want to do is hold
that one variety and I've lost varieties
for years and I've had people contact me
and let me know man I'm just so happy
with what I have and I go what do you
got and they go the stuff you gave me
all those years ago and I go you still
got the stuff hmm and I realize I can
remind that shaft and get those valuable
goodies back out cuz I've lost them
through for whatever you can only hold
so much stuff and it's the redundant
sharing and it's choosing who you have
hold the plants people that just want
everything don't have an appreciation
they just want bulk collection and if
you are a professional you bulk
collections in a different form because
usually have people to help you with it
or a more stabilized infrastructure so
you can keep it but for me if you want
to hold a specific varietal for time get
two or three people who just love that
varietal and it's all they want to grow
because that's what works for them and
then what you have is a redundant bank
in multiple locations of unconnected
people so that you don't get caught up
in a law enforcement Jam and you all
lose your gear or you don't get caught
up in
where it got lost because the person
just didn't need it anymore so they got
rid of it
they wouldn't get rid of it because
that's what they use you know and so
that's how I try to make sure I can keep
material alive is to share it with
individuals who have a commitment to the
cut and then hopefully we can do some
kind of out cross or sell fit to hold
material so at least we have some
genetic preservation of it but for you
you held an ATF cut for a long time you
know that was it I mean well you need
though you kept it cuz of money you know
it was like yeah we my buddy bought it
for four thousand you know just for the
cut back in the day and we were laughing
at him you know and then we started
making money on it you know is this
three of us doing this little you know
start out thing and we just kind of
looked each other in the eyes said it
you know it doesn't never go past the
three of us
and we kept it that way actually we
agreed to give it to one other guy and
he's the only one that held it after a
while because we all you know ran it for
years and years and it's kind of like
alright they're sick you know I've been
given this one dude ATF for five years
and he's kind of getting sick of it you
know but we always it worked so anyways
I had done some moving you know around
and and I was able to get it back and it
still does really well and so now I'm
mad now I need to start like saving it
cuz I've realized the value and it you
know it's kind of like one of those
right next to me doing near the
workhorse for me and I haven't really
given it as much appreciation you know
cuz I've I've been really excited about
new things and kind of like you know
going around but luckily I had some
buddies that were just doing work just
making money you know and so they didn't
care they just you know but but as I've
gotten into legalization and everything
stable it's like when you were saying
that man through the moves it was like
oh god I'm so glad I don't have to move
again I'm so glad I can have as many
damn plants as I want like it's a relief
because it's such a is very hard to move
it's very hard to ship a clone it's all
this stuff is like you know people don't
realize the you know it's hard
especially because you in order for it
to have any time in between tending you
have to have it in a pot size big enough
or a system that has enough capacity to
take care of it otherwise you're having
to make sure that you're constantly
doing it and if your life gets
bumpy you end up coming home and seeing
you know a racket that animal and you
just like how that didn't work well
that's honestly why I hit him up because
I heard you know him rapping on some
other stuff and I was just like man
that's impressive like you got to be a
solid grower some solid skills you gotta
be really disciplined to like stock all
that stuff and it's a service to the
community like it's some you know thank
you for like you know and unto others
that like do that work in librarian yeah
ya know the librarians get and things I
notice all the guys are the good
librarians they're wary because
everybody wants to borrow your books but
they don't give a shit about bringing
them back and they just want to take him
and copy him and pull the cover off and
put their own cover on it and then you
want to give any any credit to the
varietal itself so it's like a
disrespect to the plant that did it I
look at plants in some respects
different because I I call this old a
kay cut the cut that bought my house and
whenever I look at my home I will always
think of that plant because that was the
plant that I used to buy the home I live
in that plant was so valuable that I
could generate enough funds from it to
put a house that my kids live in and you
have like a different emotional
connection to it
and when you see people just kicking it
like it's you know a piece of trash you
want to kick them in the ass yourself
and that but that's what drives you to
hold and keep for you you know are you
are you doing a lot of bank and I know
you've evolved in a tremendous amount of
scientific work are you are you holding
stuff in in in vitro for I'm still you
still hold the stuff yeah that's vitro
right now it's the focus and that's
working on that here that's we're on
right now in Switzerland they're much
more ahead even in Africa with what
they're doing it's like they're even
taking males and putting them the
library so we're going through and
trying to keep our hands on everything
right now and alive and it allows that
to do that it's just being able to share
that and the to this point what you're
saying as well as this being responsible
of carrying on that torch but giving the
people that's worked with that to move
it forward to where you have it and
that's
back to even like on some of this or
these older strains it's like the
indigenous people that like from Panama
or you have the you know these different
African scenes that were have been kept
alive and then they're going in somebody
else's hands who would when it was
criminal it's like this sort of like
with Neville and you know we look at the
baseline of genetics and like Sam the
skunk man and you go back to the Hayes
brothers here and these genetics that
originated here that went back to
Amsterdam and then kind of have floated
around but this basic gene pool this is
what we're working with and to be able
to share that information and know stuff
like Neville like with what Jeannette
you like with what you're working with
these different old cultivars and being
able to share that as well because
there's and this is like vitro is really
good right now I know you've been
working with it as well but the other
thing with it as well as being able to
transport the germ plasm you know yeah
yeah much more stable format yeah and in
a much more efficient way to move it and
I'm not sure about you know regulatory
stuff but in terms of moving things in
general it's always better when it's
preserved protected and compact yeah and
that's so that's something as in-vitro
with experience right now they don't
really question it as even you know it's
so with shipping but with the right
permits right now and that's what
qualifying as hemp and doing your due
diligence to have lab results right now
then it's being able to share that and
put it at different locations like
throughout the world and let somebody
else propagate in different areas and
that's something like in this area
something from Mendocino that's
performing well out on the coast that's
really resilient but yet won't do well
in the in you know in inland areas so
it's like are you seeing are you seeing
pockets of material in Africa that still
goes back in time like that hasn't had
the Dutch infiltration that see like
when I when I was over in Hawaii in the
in the mid 80s it was the last of the
Southeast Asian varietals grown in the
cane fields and so I go there and I get
to experience some world-class cannabis
it was perfect because the soils the
climate all matched up with those type
of plants and so you had this incredible
combination and then I go back you know
years and years later and I got this uh
this white kid that's telling me about
you need to check out the aloha white
widow and I was like that's not what I'm
looking for I'm looking for the
cambodian that used to grow out here
that used to take top your head off make
you almost peed your pants he had a sit
on the toilet smoked it where's that and
they're like oh no no you want the white
widow and I'm like no I don't want the
white widow I know at the white widows
like what I want is the things that were
from here
did did Africa have the ability to hold
material in constant do you still have
to look as someone who's discover in
stock because to me I'm like Afghanistan
got hammered all over Asia got hammered
from war Africa had so much war and
famine and issues as your mining
material you stable to mind some of that
killeth stuff from the past or is it
it's getting polluted quickly it's it
really is it's hard to find like I was
in this last year went to through
Ethiopian than the Seychelles Islands
right there and it's even finding these
old land races where all of a sudden
it's like oh these guys were here from
Amsterdam a couple years ago and we have
a white widow mango that we open
pollinated with all our land race stuff
so all of a sudden is this with what's
happening is it's harder and harder to
find
from from Africa and that was years ago
Southeast Asia
you know I traveled through Vietnam
Cambodia Laos island area trying to and
then even that was mid 90s and you're
still running across places where people
had brought other genetics in so this is
one thing going back in this
diversification and being able to keep
things from there from the origin you
know in Southeast Asia India Africa and
keep these genetics separate and being
able to do to do testing and that's like
the kind of the back step of documenting
this but like yeah Africa it's it's
anywhere in the world right now it's
like Irian Jaya Papua New Guinea you're
going there in these air
people have been there with cannabis or
him it's amazing because you know for me
for my background from being in cannabis
when it was coming over from all these
places throughout the year in cycle it
just let me experience a range of
effects that I don't experience now I
called most of the stuff we play with
now homogenized cannabis and what I want
is I want to be able to have these
unique directions to fit what I want to
do and how I want to feel and I people
try to tell me that you know it's
imagination that you're you're dreaming
that things will better at that time and
I said oh no they they had unbelievable
effects and the directions were
phenomenal and they were very unique in
the way they sent on how you made you
feel and you just you don't see this
except in some very rare cultivar so we
see something it's highly marketable and
a quality but like you know you're
working with some of that stuff that
panama's I remember some killer panama's
that was just thumping and the the
flavor profiles were unique in the way
it made you feel was unique and the
problem is that as soon as we started to
hybridize it down so that it would work
in our climax as soon as we started to
try to bring it in door we basically
just started calling it out of existence
and we dumbed it down do we turn the
qualities down and if you know for me
when I try to get when I meet people
that like you like I've known you for a
long time but I know that you're you
know you scouring the earth and I'm
always like did you find some goodies
someplace you know the goodies still
remaining somewhere and and and
unfortunately the goodies are out there
but they're just not market you know for
the most part but the some of these
cultivars that take 14 weeks that the
flower still 14 weeks is like a football
and it hasn't filled in but but this is
something that it's good to have in the
toolbox you know let's not get let's not
get let this go and I think right now
that's these different unique cultivars
that we run into it's keep it alive or
share it with somebody else and you know
it's like that
it's that cannabinoids that feed your
endocannabinoids you know everybody's
different and that's that's the thing
something that
one strain it's like is that could be
that key that helps you like with
epilepsy it's three to five percent
right of people that are affected by say
Charlotte's Web but what are the
cannabinoids within that cultivar that
are accessing your endocannabinoid
profile and that's something collecting
big data right now going into this on
the pharmacogenetic level is identifying
these genetics plant genetics and then a
person's makeup and seeing that eighty
year old lady that's in Australia that
just got help from a certain profile and
helped her epilepsy epilepsy and then
you have a three year old child in
America or somewhere else that you'd
never know that this particular balance
of a one to one fight and that's
something working one and was finding
these old land races from from Africa as
well but developing a full cannabinoid
profile you know what I'm talking like
five percent THC five CBD 5 CB n CB g CB
DV HCV flatlined across the board or
these different profiles and then when
you identify a cultivar like that being
able to put it in vitro and you put that
on the show so we're we're good on time
we got a little bit time for some
questions
great great so you guys got some
questions shoot him while you're here
why did why did import weed stop coming
in the country import weed stopped
coming in the country primarily because
I was somebody that was involved in the
enforcement of this and so what it was
was it was a function of size and so
when the people were shipping drugs into
America and in Brown 1980 is when the
door really got shut the the the
difficulty to ship a product into the
u.s. became much more difficult and it
is a lot easier to ship a suitcase full
of cocaine than a truckload of cannabis
and a suitcase full of opium is a lot
easier to ship than a truckload of
cannabis and so it was a function of the
economy and the us instantly kicked up
its domestic production to make up for
it
it's just that what we did is we lost
you know the
cest a lot of these incredible type
effects and highs and the tones that
were there were also about the
experiences you got when you smoked it
and the people in the United States are
in their own paradigm America is its own
little planet and so it just skewed it
and then after a couple of years
basically nothing was coming in on any
quantity it got to the point where
America was really jamming the whole
Mexican drug trade because we were
producing so much herb up here in in
Northern California that it was really
cutting back on the amount of money made
in Mexico and if you talk to people in
Mexico you can talk to villages and
they're like oh man when they when you
guys started really lighting up heavy
you financially broke us because we
didn't realize that it wasn't just
cartels moving weed it was villages
moving weed and that the cartel may have
been the trafficker
but the villager was the producer and so
we started becoming competitors with the
Mexican farmer and we didn't really
understand that for them it was life and
death because they didn't have
alternative forms of money the cannabis
was their money you can't just come up
growing weed and you also can't collect
weed if you don't have a license you can
only have six plants and so I always
throw six plants out there for enjoyment
but oh my god how the hell do you bank
varietals for time and breed and
reproduce when you're only legally
allowed sex and so it forces everyone to
go right back into a criminal status and
someone's like yeah it's only a
misdemeanor but I'm like the point is
that it's still a criminal status and
you get would get your product seized
and so you don't have an ability to hold
a living collection unless you have a
permit and for most people man that's no
small trick answer question right he's
asking what's the major differences
between the Northern Lights cuts you
hold because they're all named numerix
what's the significance of that and what
does it mean to you and how you use them
so that's a very good question so we
would really need the guys here that
originally bred the Northern Lights
strains to answer all these questions
but from what I've
from read and understand and what I've
heard through the cannabis culture is
Northern Lights number one is the pure
form two three we're crossed indicas NL
five six seven eight nine were crossed
uh sativas to hybridize NL five has the
best bagged peel and the best marketable
bud NL two has the strongest most indica
a lot of Juniper just real cush smell
Northern Lights number one is the
backbone of all the other ones you can
smell it in there it was the building
block it's what Neville used if he had a
clone and he wanted to recreate that
clone he that was the male he used when
he wanted to make a pure hash plant off
the hash plant cutting he back crossed
off of the Northern Lights number one
when he wanted to bring Big Bud to the
market and he just had the Big Bud clone
he back crossed off of Northern Lights
number one sin it's a real building
block as far as it by itself it's great
smoke but it doesn't have the bag appeal
that's your question thanks man
any other questions yeah you saying how
do you go from bag appeal to smoke
appeal in actual reality and and and
where everyone screams education but if
you want to get an education in America
you're gonna go broke so the the issue
with education in our situation is to be
able to have some loosening of the
regulation that allows you to have
events where individuals can come and
meet cultivators and then cultivators
can then be able to sit down and
casually without trying to sell them
product expose them to what they have
and then they can also explain to them
why they like it whereas it shine most
people whose
smug you remember most people nowadays
can't roll the joint
I sell cone rollers and stuff and I
personally don't like a filter so I'm
somebody who likes to taste the weed in
his mouth so cardboard in the mouth just
doesn't do it it's for me the same way
but that's because that's what I know
but I realized that nobody can roll a
joint anymore
they they they use devices to smoke and
when you're using a bong or glass and
you're torching it with the lighter and
you're burning that shit
burn ability is an issue but when you're
smoking it in a tube it's definitely an
issue and that's where the pre-rolls
people don't have issues because by the
time you smoke it it's dry so the
combust ability is incredible but you're
lacking the quality of flavor and so
there's this this reality of why are you
putting the product on the market and
the people who buy the product have to
understand this is the truth that these
things are on the Martin same thing when
you explain to people why the tomato is
on the table because it fits in a lug
and why does the Cavendish banana sold
compared to other bananas because low
and behold it doesn't need refrigeration
when you ship it it tastes good enough
and it doesn't require refrigeration so
those financial concerns dictate the
consumption reality and when people say
education people like all people are
gonna be doing the education I'm like
yeah people who trying to bank money who
don't know what they're doing when I see
people in Napa running terpene seminars
and and all I'm looking at I'm like
Romeo joint and now that doesn't mean
you're legit but if you can't even break
up some weed the amount of weed you've
handled in your life is probably pretty
small so you're the last person I'm
gonna ask for for an in-person
demonstration I appreciate cannabis you
might be an incredible scientist and you
can explain to me why I get the response
and reaction I do from what I'm doing
but you're not the one I'm asking for
turn me on to grass and that's what we
need is we need people like yourselves
that are Korea smokers Korea growers who
can appreciate quality and you can sit
down
with customers in a cannabis manner
which is non-aggressive and let him try
it and then you can say let's see this
is nuggie and it works and we sell it
for this but personally we smoke this
loser looking hay like weed because for
me that you know the the quality the
high isn't is is perfect and they go how
do i buy stuff like that and then you go
right now we need to figure out how do
we get it to you and that's try to work
out the supply chain like we talked
about this morning but once you get
customers that want your product you're
no longer pushing drugs they are pulling
drugs and there's a radical difference
in business velocity when that happens
I'm asking Bob some good questions
I was calling bob says his nickname
everybody had a nickname I I always
fascinated with when I met him he was
somebody who was explaining to me the
varieties he held and he was going
through the chain of custody in a manner
that made me laugh and I said how the
fuck do you remember that many names who
held it because it was so conscientious
and that's why when I was saying to him
how do you hold material because it's
it's these little things I notice in
people that I don't think other people
understand about what drives you to do
it and what level of desire and fatah
you know humble guy fantastic and highly
knowledgeable gardener in a market
that's insane and I wanted him to be
able to explain you know how do you
integrate those worlds because he's a
superior farmer and for hearty it's the
questions that I wanted to get out of
him were you know using your knowledge
of the current scientific situation in
the global situation what's your
thoughts on it and from that point man
there's a trillion questions you could
ask and so shit I mean I think we
covered what I wanted to see the
question is there something that you
want to know you know is there something
you feel that you could ask any one of
these people to get a little bit of
direction and that's really the truth of
it
you've done a lot of research from all
around the world what have you found
most recent research different that's
the Varens through there was you know I
don't know if you're familiar with
Doug's baron and then finding the you
know this this lineage of where it came
from and then and bringing that bringing
that out that's a particular strain
though that is not appealing as well so
it's been one that has taken a lot of
time and money and patience to move it
forward and it has moved forward in like
when you see a two to three percent gain
in those cannabinoids it seems like it's
been significant with the with the
Varens more so than THC being able to
take something in a couple back crosses
we're getting it up to above 20% and
these desirable terpenes but yeah to
that point it's the the Barons that
we've been looking at to increase eight
right now so it's getting that over that
10% right there and it's it's yeah and
it's a lot of testing you know this is
something it's so you can have that same
phenotype and that same expression in
something you know back crossed up to
even we've seen you know as far as what
the variance is you know you're going to
six generations and while of a son out
of a hundred tests do you see these all
of a sudden you see an outlier spike
where it's going up above even 1% 2% and
then they're these outliers that will
shoot up to above over 5 and then it's
how many tests we have to run before we
get that 10 do you see when you're went
I've noticed sometimes it when we're
looking for specific cannabinoids and
we're trying to run them there seems to
be a blockage from other cannabinoids
it's almost like the plants competing
with what it's going to produce and so
when you're
you're working with th cv which is just
so trendy right now are you seeing into
relationships with other other
cannabinoids that our linkage like drag
or if you see another cannabinoid do you
notice that it stops the production of
THC v like we know there's limits of
what can be for me other than the within
the cookbook yeah you know and you have
to that to that point is that seeing
that the with the THC v is as well the
spikes in THC as well so it's
identifying and that those particular
high th C's and then all of a sudden
you'll see completely CBD completely
knocked out alt altogether and that's
right now it's being able to put that in
a controlled growing environment because
how much do you know this is something
as these environmental conditions at
what point is that is that as well being
attributed to to that makeup get one
question sit down well as far as CBD
goes I know if you can get a more fungal
dominated soil you're gonna get a higher
test result
does that help is that what you were
looking for
I I haven't done that but yeah well I
was just gonna like just kind of
reinforce as what you're saying that it
that that does exist you know like
people that taste my weed and and I'm
not saying this is necessarily a good
thing but I've been using a lot of the
same mixes for a long time and they
always say you're all your weeds tastes
real similar deal and um I think it's a
bit bit mix like what I'm putting in
there in put wise it's a bit environment
it's a bit like my biome that's I guess
the part that I wanted to put up you
know I'm touching the plants I'm
touching the soil the guy I learned to
grow from he taught me how to mix and
he's he goes you're sweating good and he
goes shake that shit off he made me
shake my drips off and I think about it
every time I mix in soil that the sweats
going in there and that's gonna taste
you know somebody it's kind of gross
when you think about it but somebody's
gonna taste that down the road and that
it's leaving an impression and you know
and my what's going on with me is is
what's going on with my microbes to my
emotions my life and I've you know it's
a little bit weird whatever I always try
to approach my gardens with the clear
head if I have to stop and smoke a joint
take a walk I don't always do it but
I've always tried to put little signs
and stuff to remind me like I never work
angry when I work on the plants I think
that really does I chill because you you
are rough it's like with your kids you
deal with your children you need to make
sure that you turn down your personal
shit with any decision you make with
them because otherwise your harsh and
that impact on them is tremendous
because they're sensitive and I look at
plants the same way and I just tell
people that's why that's why I love
cannabis because it slows me down I
can't be aggressive I can't be hurried
or rushed I have to move at the plants
pace
and I think that that changed the way I
perceive life they let me understand a
natural progression that things can only
move at the pace they do and when you
try to go past that you miss things and
you cause problems and so I agree man I
turned down my my drama when your when
your monkey brain or whatever they call
it like everything breaks around you you
you know you're just you know it's like
you just causing more problems by being
in that space you know so I don't know
do you have any testing minimum it's
it's um it's almost putting taking
inputs out is something like the last
couple is helpful with breeding how far
can you push a plant to stress for like
dry farming for instance have you seen a
lot with that all of a sudden you just
pull the water off pull the plant off
water and have it like it just all of a
sudden it does it doesn't fill up but
the the flower the way it changes in
that and the terpenes within it so it's
really taking as much as possible out of
the plant as far as input and seeing its
performance and and because some plants
will just they won't they can't handle
it they're gone so just move through on
to the next and some of these ones that
are really vigorous and then you can
we've taken these vigorous plants and
then put them in a greenhouse that's got
you know that's got mites but it's got
bugs so it's got p.m. throw it next to
these plants how does it perform is it
getting these diseases some of them that
don't pull them back outside and keep
working with that
how much duress and stress can be put on
the plant and see good performance and
that's like looking at it from an
athlete's point and then when you give
it a little input it's kind of bringing
it back down and taking everything out
of it and then when you give it a little
you know couples pellets of you know
seabird guano or whatever it may be that
fertilizer than you watch that change
Strawberry Cough yeah that's a deep
question for me it would be something
that no one in the cannabis community
knows it's just the rapture
it's an old NL g13 house playing across
from North Carolina the question was
what do you regret losing the most I
lost a plant that would have come out of
like the late 80s out of riceland and
when you lit it it looked like a burning
tire and I got so high when I smoked it
that I'd lay down on the couch and my
girl would come in and I'd wake up and
she'd be wiping my face with the rag
asking me if I was sick because I was
feverish and I would mumble and I'm just
really high and it had the most complete
effect I've ever experienced then it was
stunning cannabis in every aspect it had
a visual quality it had growth quality
it had a quality a high that was unreal
and it got killed by mistake and I said
I'll we'll go find more like that but I
realized quickly that that was a memory
and that was the one I wish I had back
more than anyone it was so green it was
almost like blue and ice the cold like
you know like a blue varietal but it
literally would make regular people ill
they would it would it would fold you
over and and kick you in the ass and
send you home and say come back when
you're grown up
the beauty of cannabis is that all of us
have that special thing and that's why
I've always been trying to explain to
people you don't have to be a big banker
but you got to bank a little bit you got
to make sure you keep some stock you got
to make sure you're involved in some
breeding don't let anybody talk shit to
you because your pollen chucker you're
somebody who has historically done what
we've done since the dawn of time you've
chosen things to put together for your
desire and when people ask me you know
what should I smoke I'm like I'm not
qualified to tell you because I'm not
you I can put you into things and I can
help you understand why you like it but
front of
I'm not you I'm not qualified to tell
you what you should like it's like
telling someone who they should love you
know qualified what you you what you I
know you lost something good man you've
had a lot of stuff in your hand boy oh
yeah and that's where you come in with
the sharing and it's like I being a
being breeding seeds and taking these
times it's like they're your children
and it's like that's like the one thing
it's like spreading that right now and
it was like back in the you know the
early 90s and and running into walls and
and getting losing these certain
genetics and that's like what was drove
me back to go to like Southeast Asia
it's like finding this you know that was
happy pizzas I don't know if you've been
to Cambodia but you eat this fucking
pizza and you're tripping you know
you're you're in Cambodia on the end
there's this different level to that and
this was something when you could grow
this and it was a nice producer it would
grow under the manzanita as well here
and you could put it in a mixed bag of
tricks and get fifty six hundred a pound
for it it had different colors it wasn't
that name but that's like these some old
South East Asian you know these these
long flowering times but just the
soaring psychedelic highs and that
different feeling and that's part of
that backtracking and finding what
exactly like one of them with CBD it was
reaching out to you know with Ringo and
like Jaime when this was when people
were first introducing that you know the
1e telegram osa and that you know that
canna tonic those old genetics and it's
like okay well this was Oaxaca this
region Colombia you know where were
these things coming from and then trying
to search those out and that's like when
you mention that with Africa what's is
getting is we're losing this you know
these unique ones that are out there and
it's being able to find these special
ones but at what point we we you want to
share these but you don't want them to
go under the wrong hands and that's
something we're gonna be facing right
now being breeders I think coming more
and more as we've got the bigger players
that are coming in and
just they don't realize the time and the
energy that's put into these certain
cultivars and how rare and special they
are and that that's something that we
have to protect drew drew Strawberry
Cough I lost that I had right away and I
thought about it a lot like my pops and
beans and I haven't found anything it
was it was that I'm pretty sure it was
the Strawberry Cough because I've seen
the COFF and it had that you know that's
very distinguished like real thick smoke
you know but it was the first plant that
we ever I remember going to did to
plants under two lights and we got six
pounds and we were like it was like
blown away the first time that ever
happened and it was very easy to trim
just these little golf ball nugs which
most the COFF is not in the Strawberry
Cough it's his bigger you know denser
fluffier but it was really anyways and
it was it was really because I was
medicine for me I came into cannabis
from a bicycle accident and so I was
fucked up I got hit by a car I was
fucked up really hard for a couple years
and just like learning to grow weed
walking around the house smoking as much
weed as I could and it was that
Strawberry Cough that like really was
able to help me manage so it was a damn
sharks breath that I lost it to I got
stuck with the shark wreck cutting and I
hated that thing and as I took a cut I
thought it was a strawberry and I messed
it up and it was a shark's breath and I
could never get rid of that fucking
plant all right Manny I just want to say
thanks for taking the time to spend the
day with us and it's a privilege to have
you all as an audience and I would love
to have you give a hand to the
individuals that put this together
and give a salute to yourself to man
because really you all we worked hard to
get here you worked hard
the fact that you're yours and you still
here doing your thing means that you
didn't give up during a lot of hard
times and you didn't give up under the
oppression that's occurring and that's a
testament to willpower and resiliency
and I salute you for that so thank you
very much for your time today and let's
go yes serious
[Music]
you