mm-hmm
[Music]
it's like I have people who send me
seeds to give out for free to other
people and I love when they give me
specific notes like one guy did a lot of
this breeding in like Maine yeah so he
was breeding for similar things to I
think like the Washington state area
uh uh and so when I know people are in
those climates I'll send them something
like that yeah no you're you're trying
you're trying to like if it works for
them too because that'd be cool
they're similar just the main main comes
in colder quicker so they're both wet
but Maine has a fucking a definitive
it's like a short Runway yeah
Washington Pacific Northwest is going to
be warm and temporary for a while it's
gonna be really mold you know 50.
yeah 50 degrees in and 80 humidity so
but it allows you to be able to steer
people in the right way and
that what we were all talking about you
know earlier how do you get people to
want to educate the only way you really
get education is through interest
and and what you have to do no better
way than hobby growing growing exactly
growing a plant I don't care coffee is
not addictive but growing it sure is
well and the Hobby and the hobby The
Hobby
relationship starts to make you more of
uh detail freak yeah and just understand
it like whoa it goes like that I'm
amazed and you start to figure out
really what you like and so what you
find isn't that just because it's grown
organically outdoor which is what I'm
into doesn't mean that you have to like
it most you might like Athena in
rockwool because that's your fucking
mouth and you're not wrong yes you're
not wrong
it's just that what you have to be able
to do is have people be able to
experience enough different
methodologies to understand where is
their preference so when they go to the
store they can ask better questions of
the tender and it's not so much for me I
make it I'm like I'm if I if I don't
think that there's a huge knowledge base
here I'm like okay you got anything
that's uh any any Farm that's running
outdoor do you have an outdoor section
you got a sun grown section and you know
that it's always going to be older pot
it'll always be older pot than any of
the newer pot in terms when you look at
the date so but what I know is that if I
can go through and I can then look at
the I could look at the cultivars I can
kind of figure out which one's held up
best to storage because I kind of know
from playing with them and I go oh this
one usually holds up really good and I
think the antioxidants
and this Farm's out of Sonoma and so you
break when you get it out of the car you
break it open you go there you go and
the smell is slight because it's faded
but as soon as you crush it it's bumping
and you know the mouth is going to be
there the store ability and huge and
that lets me but that lets me be a more
intelligent Shopper if I'm shopping at
dispensaries out of the area if I'm out
of the area and I want to go explore
dispensaries I go and have fun with the
blood tenders and I'm like what do you
got what's hot what are people enjoying
right now what do you like if I wasn't
busting what's the best thing that
you've seen come in this week and what's
something to caught your eye and what do
you what do you uh what do you notice
and it allows them to be able to be
creative in the thought process and then
it allows them to be able to steer
directions and then you're also able to
say okay what I like is I like these
things I I also like to explore what
other people are into it's like if
someone introduces you to their music
collection and you're just like play me
what you like and they're like in some
direction you're like it's not my thing
but within within that thing I like what
you like totally like totally well you
can also appreciate the the detail of
the individuality
it's nice not to all be the same it's
nice that it's nice to have enough
commonality that we can all get together
but enough differentiation so that we're
never bored looking at each other
because every time I see you doing
different shit that I don't do you makes
me interested you know um everybody's
got some weird shit they do that's cool
and I think that that's that's a it's
important but being a home grower lets
you touch the product in a way that
helps you really understand what you
like and what you don't and you're able
to become a far more educated individual
and the only other way that you can
understand products it's like building
your own sneaker almost you have
non-biased tasting panels and I mean
non-bias wear like and when I when I we
sometimes companies will ask me to help
them
release products to the public
and what I do is I bring people in to
communicate to the audience what these
products are
and what I make sure is that the people
that we bring in
are unbiased in what they're talking
about they're not telling you what the
fuck they like or what they don't like
that is not a relevant topic here what's
relevant is this is what this is these
are relatable flavors and scents
please try and now what it does is it
allows people to make unbiased decisions
as the consumer and they're not catching
your your your your direction of I only
like OG I only like hella jelly and I
only like it grown on the floodplains of
the Eel River in the in the in the crook
where the sawdust used to catch you know
what I mean because even there's those
little details right
you can't sing any of that shit we get
that cold air at night right in July
that cools it down right when that's
right
and people like what the fuck are you
talking about the ultimate tear water
yes but most people don't understand
what that means
and so it just becomes overwhelming and
what you want is you want relatable
scents and flavors and you're simplify
it and make it presentable it's so
approachable yes so say like you and I
we're gonna we're gonna bring this
forward right we're gonna we're gonna
take Josh's uh that that black white
gold we're gonna bring It Forward we'd
smell it me and you would sit down and
say okay what's all our relatable scents
and flavors
and we were doing that earlier we were
pulling up some strong citruses we
grabbed a heavy lime we picked up a
light Tangerine it had a fuel oil in
there it had a almost like a rose tone
and from that cherry pie
that what we would do is we would go and
gather those those salad and we would
bring it to the event
so now when someone says what is this
thing we're like hey this is what this
is this is how it was grown and here are
the relatable scents for you to smell so
that you can see if you can pick it up
and so when you're talking about pencil
eraser the best thing you could do for
good gas is is bring a can of tennis
balls
smell that that's Fuel
and what it does is it allows them to
understand what people are talking about
but it also lets them get caught up in
patterns
and and your your job though is to just
allow people to understand better what
this is how it was grown where it came
from but you never add your influence to
this process because what you're not
trying to do is educate someone to buy
what you want because that's really more
of an infomercial what you're trying to
say is these are all considered good
products you choose what you like among
them because the bottom line is indoor
herb that's grown onto chemical is as a
more subtle profile and when we start to
go into heavier profiles just because I
like it thick and full doesn't mean
everyone else does and that's the same
with wine so if if 85 there's no wrong
answer it's all you it's like who's the
consumer and the nose who's the consumer
generally pretty much and if the mouth
corresponds yeah yeah there is as long
as there's a just following your nose
through a big palate it'll it'll get you
through it'll get it it'll really hone
in on different like almost like
personalities and types of people and
like people that resonate together
you're like wow like you can be totally
different in all kinds of ways but
there's like similarities based on you
know who kind of likes what cannabis
yeah yeah there's only to me there's
only four real interactions like when
when I when I when I broke down cannabis
in the four divisions right Earth and
fuel fruit and fruit and flower fruit
and floral and and that was like that
was uh that was it was like a compass
but when I came up with that hypothesis
and said this is how cannabis really
breaks down to me from looking at it
from all these years when I add the the
team from UCLA challenged that and then
fucking prove it that really does break
up into these categories
it allows you to understand that 95 of
the population that came into the state
of California looking for a medical card
came in for one of these four reasons
that 95 of the Cannabis we see in the
world basically fits into these four
fucking directions
they're directions that fit and our job
in cannabis in the industry of cannabis
is to help people just understand where
you find your mesh but not for me to
tell you where to find it I can tell you
why I do what I do and why I like what I
like but I'm not telling you that my
shit is going to be better for you than
the shit you like so if you're someone
yeah no cause I'm be honest man that's
what I love about the scratch and sniffs
like putting scratch Snips in front of
like three or four different flavors and
watching people go through them it's
just like when they're like really
distinctly different varieties of like
real turping cannabis scratch and sniffs
like people light up on different ones
and you'll like see like you know
they'll smell like somebody like they'll
be eight people in a row that'll all
love you know the Calia team this like
new line that we just dropped but then
there'll be a bunch of people that'll
come in the they'll love the blueberry
pancakes which is like waves and there's
almost like natural waves too yeah yeah
there's groups of people yeah flavors
and all flavors have a cycle and some
and some flavors to me like in deep
oranges when they're hot they're
blistering and then when they fall off
it's a vertical and then it disappears
for a while and all of a sudden it comes
back comes up yeah because you can only
take so much of it that's why the
skittle's kind of interesting because
the flavor and the skittle didn't
diminish in desirability and when when
that lawsuit went down
Mars did the research on it and said
which was amazing but it was you know if
you have Skittle in the gene pool it
equal to 17 change in value of your
product in the California Market
which is which is Big so they got sued
Skittle got sued by for the name but
Mars candy sued them and so when Mars
candy sues you they're bringing a
research team and a legal team and the
data that they so I read the lawsuits I
was just fascinated by it but that was
the quantifier was they said oh yeah
we've been injured and money has been
made and we can say that money has been
made by the virtue of the fact that
they're they're diminishing our name and
they're making 17 more for a Skittle in
a product than a non-skittle product
which blew my mind because there's no
other there's no data that corresponds
to that but they they were able to mine
it because they're Mars and it's the
Cannabis industry yeah and they can
abuse it got no leg to stand on nope and
it's Mars they're they're you know it's
kind of like fucking with Coca-Cola or
you wanna you wanna have a you want to
screw up somebody's life uh add some
Disney to the video
[Laughter]
oh man but at the end of the day you
know you want you want people to be
happy with what they do and for me what
I like is being able to play with new
things and put them out and let people
check them out and
kind of just keep the Curiosity peaked
you know the stuff that I do
professionally
it's the same thing but it's very
targeted it's you're bringing it is
still down yeah I call it like a
contract killer you're bringing me in to
kill a problem and and that's it that's
why I'm there I'm there for a specific
thing I need a Target without the target
I can do nothing like yeah and without
the target I do my thing that's the
difference I don't do nothing I do I do
your thing but that's not necessarily
the thing exactly needs to be done in
that specifically exactly but those but
but I'm clear about the division and so
I clearly divide them it's very
dichotomous to me so what it does it
allows me to maintain my interest
and and what I'm into
so that I never lose like why I why I
really like doing what I'm doing and and
I love the scientific work I get to do
and I love working with some of these
giant fucking operators because you get
horsepower you just can't get in the
garage you just can't get it you just
don't know what it's like to look at 20
fucking thousands yeah do we want to
take 10 000 clones do we have the
capability of taking 10 000 clones we do
I want to see okay
I wanna what I and so that way I can see
the limit to the left and then I want to
see the two light person who only works
a specific thing for time and comes up
with an outlier because there's a purity
there that's to me just overwhelmingly
beautiful it's what I love about the
craft community
and and sometimes I'm in the craft
community and sometimes I'm not
dependent on
what I'm working on but I'm always a
smoker like that that's I was a smoker
before I was a grower and I was a smoker
and a grower before I was a dealer
and you know so for me I'm always still
a smoker and what I what I really want
to have happen is the desires I want for
myself
of availability access affordability
Community different genes that we can
work with Gene banks that we can borrow
and lend from they don't have to give me
the fucking plant but they can sell me a
vial of pollen you know what I'm saying
sure you should be able to sell me a
vial Apollo so I can go and pollinate
and work there should be abilities to
have
people work and develop in the Cannabis
craft without having to be under an MSO
label without having to be under a Big
Brand label well the msos are looking
for something different I think than the
craft like exactly there's not much
overlap at all like what they're looking
for in like the you know the Matrix
they're trying to hit is drastic but the
craft copies them though that's the
problem the craft copies the craft
doesn't there's a whole different Market
well the craft the craft people are used
to selling the Malibu Dawn they're not
selling the dispensaries needs to start
a distro yeah
because it is no fucking point so what
the small operator like for me what I do
is I take all the Clone lists that come
across my phone right in fucking rivers
of them
and I just screenshot them
and I just show somebody and I said hey
watch this I said see this right here I
said this same group just hit me up
twice which means they're hungry for
money so we're gonna watch the Clone
price then we're gonna see the Clone
price drop then you're gonna see Teen
then you're gonna see one gal and what
they're doing is they're just holding
this fucking plant moving it through
their world because they can't bear to
get rid of it so they're spending
fucking 40 bucks to sell you a 10 plan
because they don't catch that nobody
wants the fucking thing and you made too
many of them
and so and taking care of plants is
expensive oh it's tough and and when
you're looking at this these lists it
just lets you understand that when you
see huge quantities coming through just
realize that those things are going to
be mostly grown and so that's the pool
you don't belong in as a 400 500 pound
operator 400 500 pound operator they're
looking for your Niche which is maybe
some Heritage Market that you got into
or you're looking for the next new thing
what's that next thing on the horizon
and 10 there right so to me we got like
you know it's kind of the bell curve
right so I go 10 on the left they'll buy
whatever the fuck you sell 10 on the
right you have to basically pay them but
that 80 in the middle is swayable and if
I can move them over to here a little
bit I might even get one percent of the
10 on the right to move so I'll get a 91
which puts me into an A and so it's this
middle that I work with of what are they
seeking and what they're seeking is this
this Nexus of quality and value but in a
diversity that's relatively simple so
that you're not having to to try to
create too many different Lanes you're
saying okay the distro wants 3 things I
take a look at the three things that the
distro wants which is basically into
this box and then I increase
the the the category where the sales are
hottest so right now this year I would
make a prediction I would say if I was
to have Indica a sativa and a hybrid I
would go more sativa more hybrid less
Indica because what do we see the
steering of what and how what does
Indica mean narcotic
hybrid balanced sativa ethereal where
have we focused all the work narcotic
because all the gene pools we work with
for indoor are that short flowering
cyclical speed of use when we go to
hybrid we start to get into this middle
Zone but people didn't catch that just
because you breed something together
that doesn't make it fucking good and on
the cerebral end of it that shit is a
project to get necked down into a
desirable level and so everybody goes
you know oh blue dream all of a sudden
then everybody's the same thing you get
tired of it how many days in a row do I
have to smoke the exact same shit well
if we're going to see this whole
Resurgence at Hayes's training yeah yeah
I think next year we're going to see a
little bit of it come in and over the
next three years it's kind of really
thick but it won't it won't it will it
won't pick up
the problem with it is we're not to me
what we're doing wrong with this shit is
we're not accepting the fact that we're
not supposed to fucking grow it here
you're not supposed to grow it here I I
fuck around on the equator oh it's a
different looking plant there I'll tell
you that much
um we should be growing it there we
should grow things here that are hybrids
that that North Americans can grow in
our our situation that shine and if
you're if you're growing things indoor
for 125 days how much does that cost you
to buy it oh indoors isn't it you know
what I mean so that's why working with
the genetics and bringing in that
trigger time and like actually but
you're you're modernized you're
modernizing it and for me when I and I
and I play with groups that modernize
where like I get to see what it looks
like when you take equatorial Africans
and compress them into a fucking soda
can size plant where you've you've
brought them all the way down into this
before and all the new autoflowers and
Autoflower conversions yeah but and I
and I like those too because you can
take the auto the auto Gene and just
Revolution lets you understand how to
increase Vigor and and speed of a
regular without having to really utilize
AI some of those those what we used to
call ruderalis but really Northern
flowering varieties because to me they
haven't worked out enough it's been
worked out yeah you guys been working
with that shit for a long time I meant
Charlie is oh my God like Pepsi Coke
challenge you can't tell tell the
difference there's absolutely no
difference there it's actually
preferable we've been seeing like the
all gas the emerald fire and the mint
Jelly Bean you know top sellers for some
people against their full season because
and a lot of times it's because they're
in an area where it was way more
appropriate for them to grow in
autoflowers yeah because it's finished
because if you're in like New York
Massachusetts Maine you're full season
stuff sometimes it's going to get beat
up a little bit in those late storms so
having autoflowers that perform like
photoperiodic cousin they're Proto
cousins that's a game changer kind of
area
oh yeah no no question that there just
has to be the ability for people to to
do this in a in a way that lets them
enjoy it but the thing is it's it was a
question of like I had you know I was
pondering this what the fuck's up with
d8 and why are you having such an
availability of derivatives of uh
analogs and how the DEA and the FDA is
so cool with it I'm like man they're
crawling up our ass everything we do
forever but when it comes to these
things and you take a look and it's
really who owns the hemp Fields who
really controls the derivative Market of
these products and it's other larger
entities that are in Pharmaceutical
and so no that would never happen never
happened but when I when when you're
when you're looking at it from that
perspective which is honest you you
realize that you know for so much of the
stuff that we do with THC based cannabis
where you know it's we call it cannabis
it it's so highly regulated that it
makes it almost impossible for
mainstream to touch it in a way that's
convenient and for reason and we have a
lot of research to be done yeah but but
no convenience for the consumer like the
regular smoker someone who just wants to
be able like what I would call like the
the regular craft beer consumer they
probably drink maybe a six every week
once every two weeks they have a beer
every couple days when they they're just
like you know what I just want to have a
drink and chill and I'm good and then
you got guys who drink a six a day same
thing with weed you know you burn a
joint I burn I probably burn like I
guarantee I burn every night when I when
I when I sit down at the end of the day
and I almost know I always burn sometime
like around lunch
and if I'm doing some zooms I'm burning
one of them on the zooms because the
fucking zooms wear you out they're not
smoking then all of a sudden you can
smoke yeah but but mostly you know two
three times a day I consume and I used
to consume I figured on the average
about 18 times a day so like for most of
my you know Youth and career I had a
joint in my mouth
full time there was never not a joint
fucking I was you know almost like chain
smoking where I was constantly lit up
and I think the stress was so high that
I didn't really realize that I just
found that this much cannabis use would
allow me to maintain like normality when
you run away otherwise unhealthy
lifestyle yeah because you're running a
wild life you know and pushing it to the
max yeah and and when you realize what
you're doing sometimes it freaks you out
and then you have like wait a minute a
lot of people don't realize that I know
the industry is like back in the day
there was this underlying level this
like constant stress well you're looking
at the helicopters flying today is there
a roadblock on the road for the consumer
the consumer having to stash the lead in
their drawers state troopers
I'd be driving from Boston down to Rhode
Island with pounds in the back with like
a Mass state trooper pulling behind me
for like five miles I'm going like 40
miles an hour in the right hand lane
just like fuck and you know that and
that's just real but it did it created a
stress level but I think that what I did
is I used to stress level across the
industry I use cannabis as as a a
nullifier of it so that it allowed me to
function at
because I couldn't ever even like when
we first started like the nursery there
was no medical Protections in place and
I had like 30 40 000 plants in the
building at a time in fucking public
it all they had to do was get the FED to
come visit me and I was looking at four
life sentences right like they were
reading about that being like what is
that what are they doing man I got you
exactly what I was doing right I've
never read at the time being like that
is so bad what I was doing but I
I had to be able to have such faith in
myself
that everyone around you had faith and
the only way to really maintain that
constant was to stay that Lit because I
was waiting I was way before oh fucking
hey like there was this there's levels
to this shit and I'm like oh no I went
all the way right and
but the thing is the team around you the
reason why they follow you the reason
why that you you get buy-in is because
people trust you because historically
you've able to you've been able to
navigate them through the dope game and
the people around you all made money
they all stayed safe they all made
benefit and they trusted you to figure
out what to do
and so when you know you get into these
levels of really responsible situations
that's why I fucking frown on half these
but most of these the new you know
modern CEO of cannabis is that
oh Jesus Christ man that I'm glad you
raised a lot of money but you fucked all
your investors and you shit on everybody
in your company
so like I got a code problems yeah you
got a fucking drug problem you got you
got fucking you got issues
to me I'm not like that's not what I'm
looking for you know and so what I what
I knew was that if I was bold enough to
do what I was going to do I had to make
sure that the people around me never
lost belief that I fucking believed
that there was never a moment you fucked
with me that you didn't think that I
didn't believe that I could pull it off
because I know that that's and I learned
that in the military right that when you
want to get people to do really hard
things
you can either create shame
or passion
and shame I don't like but passion I'm
about and I know that the way you get
someone to come out of a helicopter is
you go first
and if you go first they go fucking me
I'll follow you're behind them
and so what I what I what I what I did
was the same thing and and I think that
that it
it changes how you see the you know the
world because of it but at the same time
it doesn't mean anything to the people
that are here today and they don't
really have to appreciate it because it
was choices me we made but what I want
to see is I want to see that that
struggle resulted in a benefit for
people so that they were able to be able
to use Herb in a way that was positive
for them and it allowed more
I know that I'm only so limited I'm I'm
just me but when it's us it's we and
that means that one of you in the room
is going to bring an idea forward that I
never could
and so the only way you can continuously
create is to have continuous new ideas
and the only way that can really take
place is through Community participation
and my my desire all this all this time
as I got older was like I just can't
wait to see what's going to happen and I
hope people Crack the Code yeah what's
going to happen next is like the coolest
thing don't be a fucking hater you're
looking into the canvas you know it's
like
nothing that's totally blown apart as
far as like quality for me now it's just
like what's next there's stuff in here
like there's molecules that we're like
it seems like we're manifesting them out
of there there's like making shit up
where was this coming out of here
so Potter Valley so we had some Potter
Valley some Michigan
um I'm not sure I I grew that one in
Humboldt I'm not sure what the other one
but the but the genetic work was all
done in Washington so like that's not a
bad Community you know you got all these
together and what we have is directions
and nothing's better than the other
they're all super unique shots as long
as they're a girl yeah well shit
that's a pretty good interview yeah
brother how you doing man
yeah
sounds perfect hey
thank you
[Music]