[Music]
the bottom line is you must create
markets in order for you to be in the
market if you have something that's so
specific that only three people want to
buy it when those three people don't
want to buy it you're sitting on that
shit and you can't you don't have an
ability to sit on flour
you can't offload it you can't take it
and say well now we're gonna blow it
because you've already processed it so
you've wasted money you've spent time
you have to be very clear and the way
this works is that you start to create
these sun-grown models that allow the
customer to say wow that was really good
I would like to buy more sun-grown
instead of trying to fight for your
brand value what you fight for is a
bigger picture of brand value that you
can then get under and then you start to
be able to get differentiation you start
to get noticed
once you're noticed you can now
introduce the customer to what you do
and then you can start to be able to
release the information of when your
products gonna come out if you follow
the way people buy things they don't
like variety everyone's a kind of
variety and I'm like really how many
different kind of shoes you got not that
many women women like variety and shoes
but really they don't buy how many
different foods do you buy how many
different things do you really buy when
you go you go to the supermarket do you
leave with a different item every time
no you have a range of things that you
use and that's basically how people
function is they work off a repetition
and pattern and so what you have to do
is realize that that when you go into a
store and there's 400 varieties
the customer goes to many and they ask
the person who's selling it what's
selling what's hot what do you like and
in a simple sentence you've destroyed
the business but for almost every one of
those farms because the relationship has
to be built with the people who are
interfacing with the public you have to
be able to let them understand why your
product is better you don't need to give
them a t-shirt you don't need to get my
hat they don't
shit they're gonna give it away what you
need to give them is product
Aloha I command you because every time I
see you you give the same thing pack a
matches have some pre-roll and two
business cards so you don't lose the
damn thing and what that does is it
develops a relationship so that people
start to see you as an individual not
just the company and they get to
experience your product and they say hey
the last couple times I smoked the fish
it was pretty good when I go to the
store and I need a pre-roll I'll look
for that blue and light box and they
start to pattern and I think that these
are the things that you really need to
discuss and talk about in in the in an
honest sense because what happens is
people become very very protective of
their genetics because it's your
material that represents you and so
you're emotionally connected to it and
you're like I am my jeans but you're not
you're not your jeans
there's something that you work with and
over the course of your career you have
definitely grown more than one line and
so because of that what you've done is
you've always moved into things that are
marketable and to me the the destruction
of our culture in terms of diversity of
genetics was really around 2002 and that
was when the perp came out and so when
the perp came out the perp comes into
this perfect storm of internet and it
comes into Oaksterdam where you start
Ochs today and I don't mean the
University I'm talking about when
Oakland became Oaksterdam and the blunt
and how people bought pot and so I'm
watching this this I had the perfect
couple years before I got hot and all of
a sudden it blew up and I couldn't
understand why it blew up so I said I'm
going down the bay to check this out so
and I was always tied into the the hood
in the bay so I said let's go into the
hood and let's figure out why people are
buying the perp and when they ran up to
my car and threw that bag in the window
I realize that under street lights that
purple color with those orange hairs was
instantly recognizable in a way that
nothing else resonated and what it did
is it let people get ahold of a variety
that was high in sesqui terpenes that
didn't taste like shit Anna Blount so
the blunt and street lights
an instant recognizability created this
desire and in a brief second if you
weren't in purple business you weren't
in business and at that moment every
single person I knew who had collections
of genetics they had incredible lines
from the past couldn't sell any pot and
so they started throwing away all this
material and going into the purp because
you can't hold libraries if you're poor
you can't hold collections if you poor
it's kind of hard to light up a mom room
if you're not selling the clones it's
kind of hard to hold a huge collection
if it's a risk and it's a felony if
you're not getting paid because if
you're not getting paid you can't afford
a lawyer and so if you're really in
business you kind of understand I need
to make enough money to afford lawyers
or I'm gonna go to straight to prison
because the public defenders only there
to negotiate a deal they're not there to
beat a case so if your career at what
you do there was these realities that
shaped your decisions and the perp was
the first variety that took over a
market on a wide level and basically
wiped out everything else and I looked
at that situation because I didn't jump
on it as quick as I should because I
couldn't understand why people was so
caught up with it when there was all
this killer cannabis we were still
consuming and growing and I was like oh
man people just not making the right
decision and I realized that what I was
doing was I was emotionally blinding
myself to the market reality and so when
I went down and said I got you they're
doing it because of this let me know
that we needed to focus on per
production we needed to focus on purpose
we needed to get better models to get
the perp higher level and more purp
because if there was anything under an
80/20 in terms of perp the green ratio
it didn't have the money so you started
seeing per quod as hundreds on 90 tens
or 80 20s or 70 30s meaning perp to
green ratios and it changed the business
we're in to the degree that we've never
come back to the diversity prior the
small dispensary operations allowed
people to be able to move micro loads
you know 10 15 pounds to dispensaries in
a diverse form for a long time so most
people who aren't old like me that had
actually hustle in the day they
used to 215 protection and storefronts
to move pot and so they said people love
my stuff they do because you have a
storefront to sell it and it's
convenient but as soon as they shut
those storefronts down you're screwed
and everyone said I'm gonna use
Instagram you screwed when they ban you
I'm gonna use Facebook sorry they banned
you I'm gonna use Craigslist they banned
you so all of a sudden all your
marketing tools are gone you have no
tools and all you now have is
desperation where you're begging to find
a distributor who will possibly take
your product and then find some place to
move it and what takes place is that you
are victimized in that process and when
I when I research this I discovered that
the poorest person in the economy is the
agricultural worker the agricultural
worker is the single lowest paid person
and in any industry and I was like we're
gonna get buried alive because there is
no appreciation for agriculture that's
not how America works we work off an
industrial model so what we need to work
off of is this luxury model and the
luxury model was highlighted in a quote
I saw from the guy that owned Rolex and
the the the world was turbulent and a
reporter yelled at the owner Rolex house
the watch business and he goes I don't
know I'm not in the watch business I'm
in the luxury business and I'm ballin
and I was like I got you he was able to
transcend an industry by perception and
it's perception that you're working with
and right now we're perceived as losers
because we somehow aren't able to be 60
million dollar companies and because of
that consumers don't have access to your
products and stores and so the black
market may be pumping because it's
cheaper but the people that are coming
into the new market don't buy in that
form because they don't know people that
are growing the people that you want to
start to sell to with this burgeoning
new groups they only go to storefronts
they only know that access and they're
the ones that are gonna allow you to be
able to get product that's in and move
because as they systematically shut down
the black market and they will over time
it'll always exist but I'm not buying
any any beer on the street corner I
don't know it's now there's very few
items that
that we buy that if they can get the tax
rates low enough and they can get the
supply convenient enough do you go to
all the trouble to get it in the black
you just buy it normally and so the
situation is that you have to be able to
figure out what are you doing in the
short term so that you can survive in
the long term and when I tell most
people is you need to go take a look at
your distributor first who you who you
working with and this guy no it stopped
us on genetics but it's the genetics
that you're using that allow this to
take place and and to me the discussion
of how do you get paid is more important
than anything else because you're not
gonna survive if you don't and if you're
not crystal clear about that shit and
grow six in your yard and enjoy being a
cannabis consumer and have the best time
you've ever had because they can't get
you in trouble for that and you can
enjoy the culture you can enjoy being a
cultivator you can share with your
friends you can do all this wonderful
stuff but if you're gonna be in business
boy you better be crystal clear who
you're playing with and when I go take a
look at operations that are about to
spit out 250,000 pounds a year with
brilliant individuals running them with
agricultural programs that are on point
how do you compete and the only way that
you're gonna do this is through being
crafty and crafty mean and you're good
at what you do but you're sly and so you
have to be able to start to figure out
the things that you produce what regions
in the state like those things I did
this United States wide for clone
operations because the reality of it is
all the cannabis that was grown here
majority of it 90% was moving out of the
area and so what I did is I did market
analysis of all the major regions in the
US so I could understand what they
wanted and when you came in and spoke to
me I would have a private consult with
you and I'd ask you where you're moving
it and if you were moving it to Florida
I knew what I knew what you should grow
and if you were moving it into certain
into certain places certain demographics
certain niches I could tell you what you
should grow so that you had an ability
to actually sell the product otherwise
you're just growing something hoping
that it's gonna sell and when the market
was under produced
everything sold if you lived in Humboldt
you know about Red Dog Red Dog was this
green thing covered in red hair that was
didn't get you hi was she laughing in
the back way you remember the days of
Red Dog when Red Dog I ran wild in the
hills of so hum that shit's biomass
fodder you wouldn't give it to a goat it
was 48 hundred bucks a pound people
started to believe that they were
actually successful because there was a
shortage of product and the fact that
you could get it into the system
majors major shot made you fly but as
soon as it changed you were out of
business and so what I recommend to
people is you really need to take a look
at your supply chain who is your
distributor and who do they sell to and
the key thing that I think that we need
to work on is the ability to hold your
genomic forms after you've produced them
in a manner that doesn't destroy the
quality of the product until it can move
into the supply chain because once you
let go of it everything I see in the
dispensary almost 90% of it is
diminished and I know most of the people
I deal with I've historically done local
sourcing and so I go and meet you I
check out your stuff and I'm like it's
primo by the time it gets to me in a jar
it's not primo anymore and I look at the
dates and I realized wow that was a
seven month time frame that took for you
to get it from here to get it to me and
how many people are really thrilled
right now with their business models
like man I'm so happy I'm just gonna
jump up and down and cheer and a lot of
it is because you can't get return on
your money at a rate of speed that lets
you cover your costs and so what you
have to do is you have to like I said
earlier is take a look at what you're
trying to sell and realize that the
things that you produce is incredible as
they maybe don't get rid of them but
sometimes you just have to hold them so
I hold banks of plants that I know will
come back into trend for me it's old
stuff it's stuff from the 70s 80s and
90s things that make me happy from my
youth I know who I want to go after I
want to go after 50 to 70 year old
people people that have disposable
income because thirty year olds that are
the the biggest population of the
spencer ii people are cheap because they
don't have disposable income so they're
not gonna buy a lot of your weed they're
gonna buy a little bit see a shit
they're gonna be hyper picky because
that's all they have to do is be picky
and you're in the wrong market and so
for me I know where I'm gonna go because
I define it and it allows me to say okay
my future is to go after things from the
past does that mean I can sell them
today no but I will in the future once
we could start to establish our market
share what am i doing this season on my
own farm biomass because I know that I
said if I can get 500 a pound vs. 700 a
pound and it leaves all in two days and
it comes back in two months why that's a
good business decision and yes I might
lose total profit potentially but more
than likely I'm gonna make way more than
I ever would have made if I try to play
the weed game I'm looking at so many
people jar and shit up and I'm like this
isn't unbelievable you're not gonna sell
this crap and by the time you do it's
gonna be diminished and it's gonna make
you look like you're inferior and so
when I go to I tour dispensaries
constantly and I look at product
non-stop and I go wow I saw the truth of
it people love indoor because the people
who do indoor production are typically
better financed because in order to put
together in 3000 light operation you
have a lot of money and when you have a
lot of money
you also have financial planners that
say hey we need to have supply chain
management so let's get a distribution
license let's get a partner that has
storefront ability
let's get packaging and manufacturing
and so all of a sudden they can get
their product to the store in two months
so indoor in two months is different
than outdoor in seven months and the
problem with it is is the customer is
unhappy and so I go in and and have
friends that buy product from an
incredible number of dispensaries
because they are they're older and they
have money they're affluent and they
love weed and so they sample pot
constantly and their never-ending ly
dismayed at the quality and they're
always horrified at home bolting Trinity
in Mendocino God the herb is fucked and
I said it's not let me bring you up to
Humboldt and let's go smoke fresh weed
and then
my god it's the best part of a smoked
but it's lost in translation and so what
I tell people that are caught in these
situations is that you need to have
flour that is rock hard because
processing manufacturing will not damage
it it needs to not be so mono terminan
because unless they keep that stuff at
below 68 you're gonna destroy it it
needs to be heavy sesqui dominant so
that when they smoke it and burn it they
get the experience and you need to make
sure that it yields enough in a
convenient enough way so that you're
actually making money on what you're
doing and people like yeah but that's
commercial I said no no it's targeted
commercial is massive production you're
doing targeted production and you're
putting yourself in a situation by using
genetic choices to find things that work
one of the things I think that's a
important point is that you find what
variety worked under what methodology
because you're gonna choose things that
your friend grew and the problem is that
your location doesn't produce the same
product so some things need to have a
cooler temperature and if it's warmer
you flare off these monos no matter what
you do and if it's not sunny and hot
enough you don't get density and
therefore that's an issue and so when
you're trying to match up what you put
on the market and you're choosing things
that people have what you're trying to
do is make sure all the factors match so
that you can actually take data it's
called extrapolating if I take data from
one set and apply it to another
it doesn't mean it's accurate it doesn't
you have to make sure that everything
holds true in both sets otherwise what
you're doing is you're you're doing a
guess and what we want to be able to do
is take the information that you all
have which is this unbelievable quani of
information of how do you create
incredible cannabis and then what
varieties shined in those production
methodologies and then instead of
looking at you enable like use your
frigging competitor he's not he's your
collaborator you're all basically in
collusion if you have to be careful cuz
I get yelled at when I say those words
because price-fixing and collusion scare
the regulator's but that is the drug
business
and it's also community business and as
long as you don't agree to set price you
can most definitely communicate about
how to do production and what I did for
this event was Josh brought me this
incredible plant that he bred so Josh a
humble guy
excellent cultivator and very good at
sifting good genetic material and he
says keV I sifted this out I want to
give you a copy here's some of the flour
here's the plant and I smelled it and I
said holy shit that's sellable and so I
did the snake JAMA test where I put it
in a jar and I hold it up to you and
when you smell it I move the jar around
and if I can get you to dance with the
jar back and forth and then you realize
I got you I got you so that lets me
clearly know that you were enthralled by
the flowers so much that you didn't give
a shit that I was making you move up and
down and jump all over the place then
you realize whoa I was so attracted to
the flower that you had hypnotized me
like it was a flute and it's
snake-charming and so then we go okay it
has the nose to grab someone's attention
and then you smoke it and you go yes it
matches profile the expectation of the
nose is delivered in the mouth so that
you don't let someone down how many
times have you smoked something that was
incredible in the nose and it was a in
the mouth and you're like hey garbage
and so the problem is you're
disappointed so you can't disappoint
them
so the profiles have to match I'd rather
have it low in the nose and awesome in
the mouth than vice versa
and so his variety matched identically
and so and I'm someone who studies
market and I'm good at picking things
that go into markets and I said whew
that has everything we want in taste and
in smell visually it works what's the
high like beautiful and I said oh this
is a tool and it's not a tool that you
need to switch your whole garden to but
it's something that you produce and what
you do is as a cultivator you're not
allowed to do a lot of the things you
were prior but just like today I'm
bringing six plants because I can bring
six plants anywhere I want I'm allowed
to have six plants in my possession any
time I choose so therefore I can bring
six plants into this build and I can
hand
to you with no illegalities you can go
to any one of these dispensaries across
the state with an ounce in your pocket
and you can go and meet the people who
are running these facilities and you can
say here here's some stuff that we mess
around with and what you do is you hit
him with shit that slaps him in the
mouth so hard it basically takes the
teeth out of the back of the jaw and
they go wow that's incredible because
it's something that most people don't
get their hands on and that's an
introduction so things like that allow
you to open doors and so what I did is I
brought these plants in and I said I'm
gonna auction them off mean and you're
gonna pull straws to see who gets them
but the real truth of it is is that I'm
gonna give them to you and you're gonna
figure out a bunch of you share the
goddamn thing you're gonna take the
plants and you're gonna say listen I'll
cultivate it I can share a clone because
you can share clones amongst each other
as cultivators every farm has an ability
to produce its own material I helped
write these laws on how nurseries farms
and stores into relate because I have
all of them and I said nursery should be
able to sell product but not retail farm
should be able to not be a slave to a
nursery they should be able to have
their own nursery option but they
shouldn't be able to sell the the
nursery products they grow because then
it then it competes with the nursery
stores should be able to sell the retail
so that each one of these operations has
an ability to make money because
otherwise what happens is you're
favoring one over another and they all
have to get paid a good business deal as
both of us walk away satisfied if we if
we walk away pissed off bad business so
in order to make it work you have to
create a fairness and in the situation
that we created so that we would be able
to have some kind of success in the
different forms was that individuals who
had their own farms could do their own
nurseries for themselves they could
breed they could produce seed they could
produce clone form you can share six
plants and so I brought these plants and
I propped up some plants and I brought
in six and I'm gonna give them out but
what you want to be able to do is don't
be a prick and hoard it take the plant
and share it with the people that you
know so that what you have is
something that was selected out of 400
plants in a greenhouse in Washington
that absolutely caught my eye so heavily
that I said whoa that's the introduction
you take something like that you use
that as an introduction to the to the
stores you introduce it to your
distributors because when they smell it
it's instant sell ability and what it
does it allows you to start to enter a
market and then now you start to get a
conversation but when you're having to
give things that are delicate nuanced
and fragile and and design for people
who are more caught up in the ethereal
qualities of cannabis that's a limited
number so in all our minds everyone
knows pot like this and then people get
pissed off at blood tenders they don't
know what they're doing I had to give
them an education I'm like to get paid
15 bucks an hour to expect you could
paid 4,000 a year to grow weed of course
you're intelligent at it because you get
paid for it and you get to spend all
your time doing it but someone who's
making almost minimum wage how smart do
you think they are about your product
and you're gonna give him this long
drawn-out bullshit story about how
special you are
no like look I'm here to get fuckin
paycheck I just want to do my job
but they don't want to do a bad job it's
just that how much education can they
possibly have little unless you paid ten
Jers thirty bucks an hour which is like
a living wage and they don't so what you
have to do is make it easy you have to
make things loud you have to make things
rich you have to make them to where
they're sellable and then what it does
is it allows a tender to recommend a
product that then makes them look good
so the person who comes back doesn't
tell them you're recommending some
bullshit I don't want to deal with you
anymore
because everyone who buys weed my whole
career I've seen it
they aren't not connoisseur in anything
but when they come in they break out a
loop I'm like holy Christ here it comes
because in cannabis you could be ultra
picky and have this ultra high level but
everything else in your life you cause
dirty your fucking sneakers are falling
apart your house is a shithole you got
friends that are there nuts but with
your herb you're the most discriminating
connoisseur in the planet and and since
that's a reality you have to work with
that reality and what you do is you make
it easy and so
I know some people to me like damn I was
gonna win me one of those plants but
really what I want to do is I want to
give them on you all figure out who gets
them I'm gonna put it on the table and
you don't figure out it gets him and get
some shit some phone numbers and say
look give me a cart of that thing when
you prop it because you can share a cup
with your friends and what you're doing
is you do in regenerative culture you
want to live you you better work
together you're gonna die and it is so
clear I get to I get to do consultation
for some of the largest companies in the
world and they fly and and I don't go to
visit them I make them come visit me
here because it brings them down to your
level so they have to fly into Humboldt
they gotta rent a car drive to my
greenhouse and I look like I'm homeless
half the time I shaved today I no
serious I shaved today otherwise I look
like the janitor and in half the time
when people meet me the first time they
think I am the janitor and they ask me
hey where's the guy that I'm supposed to
talk to and I was busting balls and say
all the smart guys are in that other
room and they all go there and then they
have to come back and they go and and
for me it's great because I like to play
games like that because I'm really
checking you out as a person and and
what we're doing is we're mentally
wrestling and once we even the playing
field now you're gonna have to play and
that's the point of this this lecture is
that man I've done these lectures for
ever on this stuff but this one's
specific because it's about everyone in
the room that eyes experience that
cannabis it's really good grass I would
say across the board 95% of the stuff
that I see the people in a space produce
and I smoke and I see
it's gorgeous pot the question is who
you selling it to and how do you get it
to him and how do you make sure you have
something that the market wants and how
do you make sure you're not just looking
on Instagram saying oh my god I need a
skittle gelato hybrid or I'm screwed
well the problem is everyone else has
the same idea if I don't have purple
punch I'm well you got purple punch you
got punched in the eye you got a black
eye because people only buy it once
now you can hybridize it and take those
those visual qualities forward but if
you're consuming it you're like yes all
I no nose no mouth no Pawa Instagram pop
and so the people that are in cannabis
unfortunately because we were so and I
was too I was someone who had multiple
identities I used to change
and outfits to go check all the
operations I ran I was somebody who was
constantly under surveillance I used to
have the cops going through my trash and
I should take all the dog shit in the
yard and put it in the garbage so that
when they went through the fucking bags
that's what they got was a bag of shit
and and so you know I had to pay the
price for this but the bottom line is
that I was somebody who was living in a
I was living a very secretive quiet life
and I'm not I'm someone who loves to
talk about what we're doing but I'm not
someone who's loud in public I'm kind of
quiet which people find hard to believe
but actually I am and and I was very
secretive with what I did criminally
because I came from a criminal
background from family members that were
an organized crime and so I learned last
shot your mouth and never rat on your
crew and you be intelligent every step
of the way because the punishments real
and when you go and visit your family in
prison year after year you go all the
punishments real and so I was very very
quiet and when I got into the position
to be in what we call legal cannabis
what I did was I realized that in order
for me to make the education work I had
to shut off all my black market
operations so I took this massive pay
cut to become normal and and everyone
who knew me was like that's what I
watched my mind they were like you lost
you frigging mind man you you basically
going to be poor and I said kinda what
I'm gonna do is be free so that no
matter what I do anywhere I go I'm not
afraid of you come into my house and
checking on my shit man fact every event
I put on I invited the sheriff's and all
the regulator's so much so that
eventually they just said fuck we don't
need to be around you anymore because
it's almost a waste of time but what it
did was it let me participate at a level
of involvement that was absolute so
where I wasn't half steppin I wasn't
toed if in I was fully submerged in the
real because I was so afraid that I was
gonna reach
older age and be working at Walmart I'd
spent my whole life in cannabis and it
was such an incredible life and it was
such an original app there was I didn't
copy anybody you know the vertical nerve
I was the first person through a
vertical nursery in the country and so
these models that I was coming up with
were based off the fact that I was
looking for a way through a problem and
because I didn't have any any fear of
you catching me and I knew that there
was no statute of limitations issue with
what I had done because I hadn't done
any capital crimes I could be
unbelievably open and because of it it
let me connect into the media and it let
me connect into universities and it let
me connect into academia and it let me
connect into massive businesses and it
allowed me to be able to get an
education to a degree that almost no one
I know has because I've spoken to every
monster in the game and what they wanted
was my knowledge of the thing and I made
them trade me knowledge I wouldn't let
you hire me as a consultant you got to
play a game with me because I already
had most of my stuff I owned my property
I own my home and I made enough money
doing legal cannabis on a salary that I
could afford to take care of my children
and pay my basic bills I just didn't
have disposable money anymore but the
fact that I had already achieved the
success and I was building businesses
that were generating millions of dollars
let me have an audience which then let
me have an ability to use that power to
blow a hole in the wall so that
everybody behind me that I knew could
run through it so when I'm able to take
a look at a market and say that's the
hot spot I go and tell my friends that's
the hot spot and that's something that I
found that I'm historically good at is
it's a game called where's the money
it's over there I can see the money it
moved it's over there now and I make
sure I pay attention to this and I make
sure I use the tools that I have to
share the information with the people
I'm around because unlike a lot of
people I saw drugs on a global level
when I got into when I get in trouble as
a kid
I went in the military when I when I got
out of training school I go back to high
school and graduate and I looked at all
my friends and I realized we were all
gonna go to prison for the rest of our
lives and a bunch of we're gonna die and
they did they're in the joint for the
rest of their life for crime or they got
killed in crime and I was like this
isn't what I want and I didn't have any
any alternative so I went in the
military and when I went the military I
became a salvage diver and because I was
young and I was bold I would dive on any
project and so the military used to loan
me out to the DOJ and the DEA and in the
mid-80s I used to get dropped out of
helicopters in the middle of the ocean
on a billions of dollars worth of drugs
so I got to see what hundreds of tons of
cannabis and cocaine look like coming
into the country and I realized holy
shit we're smoking a lot of weed and I
realized that nobody that you were in
around was a competitor because nobody
that you knew was producing 120 tons of
weed and it was in the it was in these
conversations with the drug traffickers
that I realized and they helped me
understand it that really I was actually
way more like them than I was the
military and that the future of the
world was gonna be cannabis and so I
just said well I might as well start to
restart it on a like a scientific level
and when I got out of the military in 89
I sparked up indoor we're using the
government vehicle to pick up all my
lights and so that background of seeing
cannabis in the billion dollar levels
and seeing you know half a billion
dollars of cocaine and you realize oh
there's a lot of drugs being consumed
and so it changed my perspective on the
people I'm around because you are not my
competitor you are not the the hole is
so huge that the perception that we're
in competition is what screwed us
because you had petty competition with
each other and you didn't share the info
you don't share the genomic forms you
don't share the contacts you don't share
the connects and I'm someone who
historically always have because of that
experience and it changed me because
when you realize that nobody that you're
around is the competitor they're your
collaborator what it does is it starts
to allow you to share information
and I was been able to use that ability
to gather knowledge so that I could
survive and I'm always really clear
about it my mission is to not be 65
years old work in a Walmart and I don't
fault you if you work there but I know
damn well you wish you weren't you
really wish you weren't having to work
at 65 years old make a minimum wage
having to figure out how to how to chop
up two and a can into six meals because
otherwise you gonna be broke and I've
seen enough people that were poor I was
around enough poverty enough struggle to
realize that when you're young you can
handle the beaten but when you're old on
you might not be able to and if God help
you you get sick and so my whole
direction was I believe that cannabis
will one day be normalized and I believe
one day we will have a craft industry
but how do we get from there to here and
so that's why I give up so much
information all the video stuff I shoot
is to share this information is really
because I was covered so heavily by all
the major media I've been in every
newspaper in the country at the same
time simultaneously multiple times so if
there's 1500 newspapers in America I was
in every one of them same day over and
over it was unreal
and it was something that I didn't
intend to have happen it just did but I
realized that if I use that as a tool
then I would be able to use it as a tool
to help out my crew and when I get in to
medical cannabis really heavily I
realized that my crew was everybody I
was involved with in any capacity and so
that's what the lecture today is really
about is what we did is we brought in
all these killer breeders because the
breeders of the individuals that give
you paint that you use to paint your
picture and the picture that people want
to buy changes over time and you can
only be so intelligent with your palette
and so what you need to do is you need
to have access to other people's palates
and the palates that they use you can
then use to freshen up your paint so
you're still in the sell in art business
otherwise you're in the hang in the art
business and people aren't buying it and
to me the breeder is completely
diminished because no one understands
really the work it takes to do what they
do and so I get connected to breeding
all the time but I'm not a breeder I'm
someone who's a seed reproducer where I
whole genomic forms in seed form because
I've been raided and armed robbed and
workers kill shit and you kill shit to
where I've lost so much material that I
like redundancy so if I can take
something I like and put it into seed
form I can I can seal it put it away and
hopefully I can keep that genomic form
through time so my breeding desires are
really to hold material and then to do
sifting but I don't breathe breed for
stabilize lines I don't breed for the
market so I don't consider myself a
breeder at all and I highlight the
people that I do consider breeders
because what it does it allows me to
utilize their artistic ability to stay
current and if I can be somehow involved
with them in a positive way where I can
promote them I can carry their work I
can introduce them to the public
I can then utilize them in collaboration
then what happens as we both survive I
stay current the breeder stays current
and so it was the basis of the whole
breeder series we did a couple years
back where I paid for all of that that
was that's free so my company paid for
all of that because I wanted the public
to understand that as much prop as you
give me I'm only someone who works with
material that I get from them and I
wanted people to understand who the them
was and I wanted people to understand
what made them and what drove them and
where do they see the directions coming
so that people could make an emotional
connection to them and then say you're
the person I want to work with because
my desire is pain relief in cannabis I
want to go that route and you're someone
who bred for that specifically in all
your lines your selection process was
for people who are in extreme pain
you're someone who breeds for visual
stunning you understand trendy market
you're someone who breeds for resistance
you're someone who breeds for biomass
you're someone who breeds for extraction
every one of these people have a
specific direction you can't be all of
them I don't care how bright you are I
meet some of the smartest people in the
world and I'm telling you some of them
can't tie the friggin shoe they have to
wear velcro but they can they can split
an atom and they can't tie their shoes
because you're not everybody in all
things and cannabis is so massive and so
diverse and so
complicated and so complex that the only
way you're gonna survive is if you paint
the picture so that everyone has some
kind of equal credit and in that
direction what you do is you end up
having the ability to access these
people so this situation today is to
bring in all these killer breeders that
are just fantastic at what they do and
what it does it lets you get to see them
in real life
and start to introduce yourself to them
so that you can access what they do as
time goes forward so that if the trends
change and the products that you grow
are no longer moving on the market you
know where to go and get materials so
that you can repaint your work and my
recommend is don't I ever get rid of
your core material hold it because all
things come back in time plaid is trendy
polka-dots are trendy and so at one
point red-hot then not now back and the
thing is that if all you and cannabis
and I'd say you know there's a few a
year my age but most of you probably 20
years younger than me you're gonna see
that these trends keep rotating through
and I don't think any of you want to get
out of cannabis so you wouldn't be a nor
generative conference because what
you're doing is timelessness you're
trying to build something that
transcends time my desire is to be able
to also participate in that I want to
take the property that I use to make
money and I wanted to turn it into a
farm so that my children could hold it
over time I wanted to turn it into
something that had an ability to be an
asset and not a liability so it was
never sold I wanted to be able to treat
it as a preserve so that all then the
animals that were there still remained I
wanted to bring in biodiversity I got
exposed to all these brilliant people
through what I do and I realized man I
want to do that too but I also realized
if I fuck this up I'm gonna have to sell
it and I don't have time to make that
mistake and so what I did is I looked at
every single aspect that needed to be
covered done and understood and I got my
hand and every single cookie jar I could
get it into and it aged me you know III
if I grow a beard I look like I'm 70
because it's so white but what it did
was it gave me an unbelievable amount of
understanding of where we're at what are
we doing and the fact that for most
people you're emotionally taking a
beating
than anything and that what you have to
be able to do is realize that your valid
the genetics that you hold are valid
your choice is a valid it's just that
you have to be timely
where are you valid in the time line and
so for us it's to say what are we doing
with our products who am i selling it to
who's the people that process it
manufacture it and distribute it what
stores do they sell to what's the
expectation of the people at those
stores so that you can make a market
penetration so that you get some form of
brand differentiation where people start
to realize that you are on a shelf that
you're still there next year and what
happens is you start to build a
recognition and for me the longevity
component is the biggest one most people
really don't understand that you need to
be constantly present all the time or
people forget who you are and so you
make a big splash and then you're out of
the market for nine months and then you
come back and you're gone but if you can
create a splash big enough to get an
emotional buy-in and you can get people
who want to give you emails and you have
an ability to be able to highlight what
you do through digital marketing which
is cheap and you send them flyers and
you send them pictures and you send them
information and you let them know that
your products are coming out and you let
them know that that it's limited batch
and you know there's only 200 pounds
total available period and you let them
know in advance people will come and buy
that product and hold it and you will be
able to have an ability to get people
who want to mess with you and in the
process of messing with you it's the
same thing I did with genetics where I
moved as many plants for other people as
I ever did for myself I moved so many
black market ops plants was no word for
it and I got no money off of it and
people say why do you help out so many
people move in genetics and I said
because ultimately everybody's coming to
me for the information and if I can put
you into the right direction
you're still gonna come to me and when
my day comes to sell you a product I'll
sell you my product but I don't have
that product today so instead of telling
you know I don't know where to go I
would refer you and what that is is
that's networking and what you're doing
is you becoming some
very powerful because you answer the
problem of how do I get it and you're
somebody that says you get it from him
and instead of me getting in the middle
of the deal to decrease the actual
profit that that person makes you become
a good middleman and step out of the
deal you become more of a connector and
then what happens now is you start to
get respect from the customer because
they realize that what you're trying to
do is satisfy a desire and that desire
is success for all people and when that
becomes synonymous with who you are
people will forgive you for your ups and
downs and what happens everyone thinks
you're gonna be perfect in business if
I'm like bro if you can hit a 92 man you
you're unreal that means out of a
thousand people you serve nine hundred
and twenty of them correctly cuz 80 of
them are gonna be pissed
forty am I gonna hate you because they
just hate in general and forty of them
because you made a mistake but the nine
hundred and twenty who you didn't have
issues with are the ones who sustain
your business and most people have never
been in public business and they sure as
hell haven't had to deal with public
business with the internet and what
takes place is you have to be able to
make a connection and a penetration so
that people just realize I do business
with this person because they give me
something that I need and when I wanted
to find things that were comparable
similar rare you become a network your
digital marketing is more important than
any of your other brand bullshit because
and I don't mean on Instagram because
people who are 50 to 70 don't look at it
people that have money don't look at it
they don't look at it to buy weed they
come into the store and they trust the
person at the counter your ability to go
and figure out my distributor sells to
these seven stores you go drive to those
seven stores yourself and you introduce
yourself to these people and say I'm the
farmer from this stuff here is something
that I cultivate you can give them a
joint you can you could hold up an ounce
in your pocket you make these
connections so that people start to see
you as a real person they go wow that's
really nice product I'll remember that
and then when someone comes in and they
refer it they're able to refer your
products and then you and I have an
identity
anybody who's successful right now in
the market
it's connected into a vertical chain and
I study this and I'm like it's scary it
is scary if you're the farmer you're the
most vulnerable and you're relying on
distributors to sell your pot and the
problem is that they're not qualified
because most of them are selling shoes
two years ago and so now they're selling
your stuff so what you have to be able
to do is be able to take the things that
you have that are highly attractive you
meet these individuals you showcase it
and then you take a look and you're
asking them what do your customers want
here and they're gonna tell you the
customers here typically needed to be
under this amount of money so you need
to go backwards and figure out what can
I grow that will let me make margin on
something that fits that and then you're
able to use your craft skills your
organic methodologies which are very
efficient to deliver products that fit
those ranges and that gets you
penetration and once you have
penetration you have recognition and
with recognition comes acceptance and
Trust and now you can take them anywhere
you want in your portfolio but when you
try to say this is what you should be
doing they step back and so this is this
question is the this this thing today I
thought about it I was like this has to
be a marketing lecture and it has it
really does because most people are
getting the shit kicked out of them
financially and I'm like wait a minute
you all have incredible genomic forms
you'll have collections you got buddies
that have stuff are you selling selling
good well cuz I'm not seeing a lot of
happy smiles when I ask that question in
general and it's really because of these
issues it's about trying to understand
what's the material I have to grow to
satisfy the sale and once I can do that
now I have an ability to start releasing
my material and start to build your
unique brand and and I hate to use the
word brand because there really is no
brands in cannabis nobody's big enough
to satisfy brand when you think a brand
you're thinking Nike you're thinking
Pepsi you're thinking Heineken you know
name anything that you know that's a
brand you're none of those and what we
need to do is create the brand of high
quality Sun grown biologically based
cultivation and under that
and we all fall underneath it and then
what that does it allows you now to
really cheapen up your marketing because
all you have to do is be able to
understand how do we work together to
create an umbrella we all get underneath
it we fill this pile with the stuff we
have when it's correct and we identify
the destination market once you identify
the destination that's what you produce
and even though you might love your
Bridal to death well you're allowed to
grow six plants legally so I tell people
all the time you want to get an
emotional ride girl six and those are
the ones you get to keep I grow six and
I turn four of them into IRS so that I
donate because unfortunately I know too
many people from the Med years that are
dying to cancer and they can't get
anything and so I only need two two
plants to satisfy years worth to smoke I
mean shit if it's a big enough plant I
can't smoke the whole thing in a year so
I choose things that I like and I choose
things that I want to donate which lets
me still participate in the culture that
we came from which was collaborative
community and it lets me still be able
to feel like I'm a human being and then
I put that emotional shit to bed and I
go after the business like I'm at dump
doing business and I'm crystal clear
about it and a lot of times it's
offensive to people because when we have
discussions I mean I'm brutal and I rip
your plant apart because I make you
substantiate your claim and it kills
people because I watch them have
emotional breakdowns in the conversation
because their connection to what they
produce is some form of their identity
and we talked about that a little
earlier it is not your identity
your your identity the product is
something that you produce that reflects
your desires that reflects our ethos
that reflects your skills but it changes
over the course of your career and so if
you remember to hold the material that
you've been holding for time do as much
seed preservation as possible
so this way you can keep these genetics
because there's a lack of them globally
you're not gonna mine this stuff I get
hit up from countries all over the world
that are asking me to provide them with
jeans and I'm like where's all your
jeans and I realize that they're going
because cocaine took out all the jeans
in South America and heroin opium
production took out all the jeans in age
and so lo and behold you have radically
shrunk gene populations to mine from you
go into any part Africa civil war strife
famine plague took out the cannabis and
so all of a sudden cannabis is just like
coral and so coral a friend of Mines a
world-class coral collector and he said
Kathy goes we hold more varietals in
house now than is available in the ocean
because the oceans are acidifying and
all the corals dying and so people like
him hold coral and then they sell it as
frags and they ship it globally so that
other coral collectors can access the
material and I realized that only within
the community of coral ists do you have
access to coral because you can no
longer mine it from the ocean because
it's no longer there so the material
you're all holding is actually priceless
because you really can't go find it
anymore but what you need to do is is is
is don't believe that it's been been
minimized because that's the lesson for
perp perp said hey your weed isn't worth
anything anymore you need him sell purp
and instead of people saying I got you
let's let's make seed pops they threw
everything away so they could go full
purp and the problem was it screwed them
down the road because they got rid of
half of their easel they no longer have
the paint needed to make new varieties
they don't have an ability to stay
current and when you start to use stuff
that's trendy you bottleneck your
genomic form and you make it susceptible
to things you're not aware of and so by
having a tissue culture facility and
having lab access we find that some of
these very popular varieties if I pull
them from the general population
sometimes up to 60% of the samples are
carrying Fusarium they're carrying a
fungal problem some of them have viral
issues so everyone using these
bottleneck genetic forms are susceptible
to major problems and so it takes places
you have to be able to say I got you I
can't go chase trends that are
bottleneck genes because if we have a
pathogenic issue I'm screwed and so you
have to have enough diversity and you
have to be able to take this diversity
and understand how do you diversify it
into the markets and that's why we
talked about the fuels the Earth's the
florals and the fruits because
fundamentally that's how cannabis breaks
up
scientifically it breaks up into these
divisions based off of these Terp
relationships and once you can start to
see this it starts to help you
understand how to market your product it
helps you understand who your target
audience is it starts to let you know
that when you look at the database you
can figure out what's working I love to
use the the the digital galaxy from
Philo's because it lets me take a look
at relationships between plants and lets
me understand am i working with
something that's unique or am i working
with something that's not unique and
what's the level of homozygosity
heterozygosity so if i breed it am i
going to get an incredible spread of
genes or am I gonna get a narrow spread
of genes so it's information that you
can use to help steer your directions
and as we go forward there'll be
individuals that do incredible work that
produce varietals that the market wants
and you're gonna and we learn yesterday
all the different licensing agreements
you'll be able to license material from
other people to produce product on your
farm using your methodologies so that
what you have is sell ability and then
at some point in time when you get
enough brand recognition you can release
new things you're allowed then to say
look I can do other stuff adidas always
had three stripes but lo and behold once
they got market penetration they could
change some of those things and they had
other things that they could sell and so
I always look at what people buy and
what they do and I try to overlay that
over the reality of what we do and
because my desire is to always be able
to preserve protect and move the genomic
form forward through time I know that
the hold is priceless and to share is
priceless and to be able to understand
how do you take this material that you
have identify where it's going identify
where the supply chain problems are how
do you get around those issues by
choosing genetically what you need and
so it's just really a series of checks
on a box that you just start checking
through and say the pot that I sell has
a lag time in processing don't make it
in any way high monoterpene if it's
extremely aromatic be very careful
because by the time the user gets it
it's done
when they burn it satisfactions gone if
it has rough handling we're the people
that do this
mechanized work if it is in any way open
it will shred in process and by the time
the person gets it it's in pieces so
what you sold them was a bag of crumble
and it wasn't crumble when you let it
leave your building but it's crumble
when I get it out of store and so you
you these decisions have to be made and
you have to it just basically disconnect
your emotional shit you have to be a
robot when it comes to making business
decisions and then you able the opposite
of a robot in order to hold the culture
and so it's very difficult because
there's almost no industry like cannabis
where all of us had to pay such a heavy
toll the whole time to participate so
your connection to what you do your
connection to your plants it's your
identity but the truth of it all is it's
not these are things that are part of
you but not all of you and so I'm not
gonna go on forever on this because the
the the the point is I want to get all
these breeders that come up here and
start to work and talk but I wanted to
cover some very specific things of
understand that cannabis breaks up in
two major categories that's
scientifically accurate that's important
because the public loves people with
titles behind their names telling you
them things so they don't listen to you
but if you put the word PhD in front of
your name they will and what you need to
do is have science quantify the things
that you do so that when you put it on
the table and it gets challenged there's
a proof and now it's not an opinion and
now what it does it allows you to be
able to not have to have such an
intimate argument with individuals
because if you argue with them you lose
the sale you want to be able to make
sure that you're measuring your supply
lines
who's moving your products where do they
sell it how do they process it most
people don't have a vertical chain it's
too expensive
it's very expensive to have all these
things in hand and if you're a
distributor and a farmer on a micro
license whose grill who's growing the
weed and doing the work when you're
selling it and so a lot of it is you
start having the ability to do it but
unfortunately you don't have the time or
the resources to do it correctly and
then what
doors are going to take you on when
you're not able to provide to them
product on a consistent level all the
time you're basically a flash so what
you're having to do is you're having to
find specific operations that specialize
in niche pot what's a good example
people's people's dispensary right a
beautiful beautiful facility but they
look for really high quality products
because the the buyer is discerning and
he understands that the customer wants a
better product and so he sources out
product from smaller entities over
larger entities because he understands
this how many people are at that
education level not that many and so you
have to go find dispensaries where the
people who are running them are
intelligent and they understand the
reality of customer satisfaction and
they understand that the only way to get
really high quality product is from
craft manufacturers because the details
are all checked and if they can figure
out that they want to deal with you and
they want your product they can find the
distributor who will make that happen
and so the farmer and the store need to
make the relationship everything else in
the middle can be worked out but if the
store doesn't want you people think that
you're pushing products what you want is
it to be pulled you want your product
pulled out of your hands so that all you
do is produce it and then people desire
it and that has to be through
relationships and it has to be through
given individuals varieties that are
easy to sell and it has to be able to
understand what the margin has to be and
if you can't produce that cultivar that
you have and get paid for it put it back
in the library and then sell the things
that have an ability to be sold and when
you eventually get the market
penetration you want which should happen
over the next couple years and that's
not really that long a time it's a
lifetime when you pour and it's just
like oxygen three minutes with no air is
a long time and so in in in life it's
whatever you have least supply of this
most important and when people challenge
me on that I tell them hold your breath
and they start choking and I'm like BAM
you at least supply of air
while you was struggling to breathe you
thought of nothing else so whatever's in
the least supply is most important and
for us the thing that's going to be at
least supply is liquidity and finances
and what we need to be able to do is
just survive these transitions until you
firmly establish this new industry they
will go after the store situation they
will open up these opportunities because
they're they're 700 million short in
California unexpected tax revenue in
order to get the tax revenue they can't
tax more they have to open up more sales
so the only way that's going to happen
is through the the relaxing of the laws
and the development of an industry that
means that in a couple years all of us
have an opportunity to really
participate in the craft industry but
right now it's about survival and so
like I tell people if someone said you
know what are you gonna do I was the
same thing I'm going crude this year I'm
gonna blow the farm crude so that I can
blow it and walk away with the paycheck
so that I can afford to pay to keep the
farm alive and what I do with my farm is
I can hold all my genomic forms at your
farm because you have an ability to hold
your material in-house you're not you're
not set up for six if you have a license
you can have as much as you want within
that specific square footage of what you
do and you hold the material and you
start to create the story around the
material and you do it digitally because
that's the cheapest way to market and
you start to be able to meet these
people at these dispensaries and while
they're there you pop it up on the phone
and you show them some cool stuff and
you start to link to other farms and you
start to link to other varietals and
pretty soon what you're doing is you're
creating an information network of
what's available or otherwise I get it
from a distributor and it's a SKU and we
go through it and say alright this stuff
is that's the right one that's at the
right price for my market because my
customers can only spend so much money
so I can't give you a $90 bag but if I'm
in Hollywood
I can and so if you can make a
penetration into one of those places
then you can move some of these
extremely less efficient cultivars that
don't give you the same amount of yield
but what they do is they give you
different
but if you try to put that into a market
where people want to pay 45 bucks you
screwed and you have to clearly see it
and so the the world were in now is
really to me a survival world and it's
about making sure that you keep your
neighbors alive it's making sure that
when you get varietals like Josh bread
that's nasty you realize that you and
your neighbor could both produce it
maybe your whole Hill could produce it
because what it'll do is it allow there
be enough of it to satisfy the customer
for a whole year and then the customer
comes back to go work with your group
because that's how it works with all
products that's how normal things are
marketed that's how normal things are
consumed and that's what has to take
place and that's why I said I brought
those plants in because I said oh my god
this stuff is Killa and I wanted to
horde it and so as soon as I want to
horde something I know that's what I
need to release because that has the
value and if you just instantly want to
release it
so so so that's really the lesson on it
it's it's it's just trying to be very
honest with what you're doing
determine the destination do your
numbers if you're not really good at the
business end of that have someone do an
assessment of your efficiency so you can
figure out does it make sense for me to
grow this and does it make sense for me
to work with it I and I tell people a
lot of it too is that if your desire is
to everyone's like I'm gonna take the
top 20 percent of my plants and I'm
gonna turn it into flour and the rest of
it's gonna be concentrate well if that
stuff isn't over 22 percent it's tough
to get it into an extractor because they
have to make money too so if they can't
get a return they don't touch it if the
Terps aren't high we're not stripping it
so I have a Terp stripping facility
where all it does is strip turps and
then dry the material convert it to blow
it into biomass so it's pre converted
before we have to turn it into
distillate because these high-end
cartridges are only from cannabis
derived terpenes what that means is that
if you have varieties that have an
incredible turn profile and a quantity
of it that makes sense you can grow that
just for that and you have an ability to
diversify what you're growing to fit
certain markets so there's things that I
started mining that release an
incredible terpene signature with a high
biomass load early so that you can get
your crop out by mid-august harvest the
numbers that you need which is the the
oil the scent and combine it but it has
to work if it's low numbers extractors
won't touch it so you're gonna give them
20% to the customers flower and the
other 80% is gonna sit still because
nobody wants to work with it and then
you get caught up in what people like
and you're like no solvent less is best
in in Vancouver Canada it is but try
selling that shit in California don't
want it they wanted it's such a small
rate of speed that the best hash makers
I know don't sell it quickly at all
people want convenience California
market is convenience its simplicity it
spends its the masses want this so you
have to say I got you the variety that
I'm gonna grow not only does it do what
I want
and its quality in the smoke but the
numbers are over twenty two and three
five on the Terps otherwise I can't blow
it and sell it now I have to sell the
whole plant is flower and so now what
you're doing is you're having to degrade
the quality of your flower to be in the
mid market but the problem is that still
your labels still your brand it's all
tied in you'd have to create two
companies one to sell your high-end
flower and then another name to sell
your lower-end flower because it's
visually lower in quality and that's
complicated and so I tell people I said
listen I said I'm telling you you have
to go after this reality and understand
it well the beaten you're gonna take is
going to be so aggressive you're gonna
have to capitulate and the question here
is on our regions and our values is that
someone told me there's no twenty-five
years ago I hung out with an economist
who was a from a long history of farming
so his family were very successful
farmers in the Central Valley but he
became an economist because he said I
hate farming but what he was was a
brilliant economist and he and I had
this as a man this would have been 95 so
in 95 I'm having discussions on the fall
of Humboldt County to Salinas and
Monterey and Santa Barbara because he
said the cut flower industry disappeared
due to NAFTA and so a free trade
agreement made it cheaper to ship
flowers from Colombia to East Coast than
from California to the East Coast and
overnight an entire cut flower industry
disappeared he said that's what's gonna
happen to you you guys are gonna get
wiped out and you're gonna get destroyed
and I said to him I said well as an
economist I said wouldn't my route
through that to be unique product
differentiation and then micro craft and
he said yeah that's the only way out he
said your regions have global
recognition but you have to be able to
do is survive the transition and the
region itself will have the brand value
and so everyone's arguing that I should
have went and picked up operations in
central California but I said I hate
central California look Northern
California so why would I want to be
down there I want to be where I want to
be and I believe that the value here
will hold and then I'm talking to
someone who does
the buys for a major Canadian LP and
they just picked up a million square
foot of humble canopy so that it allows
them to have a craft division in their
portfolio that's not bad because when
you have people that are developing
craft businesses in your region what do
they do they advertise the reason why
it's craft is because it's coming out of
your region and so you get to do
something called piggyback and you get
to go ride that forward and that's why I
think that if we can just survive this
next couple of years and we make clear
decisions on what we're doing and if you
want people to really love what you're
growing then you need to use your skills
as a farmer and produce a product that
they want and then over time you can
give them the product that you'd like to
give them which then lets you feel happy
about what you're doing because you may
not like smoking gorilla glue a blue
dream but the bottom line is the
extractor sure do they love those
products because they're hot numbers
high-yield easy to grow and it allows
you to catch holes in a market that are
here right now and that's really turning
your ego down and just saying look I'm
here to do business if I want to
experience my culture in the way I knew
it I grow six plants we smoke and share
and enjoy and I have shit that nobody
wants to buy but I'm enjoying it and
then the business of farming is farming
and if you really need to understand the
reality just go look at agricultural pay
scales and you're gonna find out that
farmers get screwed globally and when
you put that I never tell anybody I'm a
farmer I said because I would imply that
I'm broke and what that does is it
absolutely change even when I'm
struggling I don't tell you I'm
struggling because people love to see
people hurt because it allows them to
feel like they're in power so when I
play business games I always tell people
I don't know what I'm doing and I watch
your response and when I see your eyes
blinking I know that you're trying to
fuck me and so now I know I play the
game with you because I want to be able
to feel out the reality I want to be
able to understand the deal that I'm
doing
and it's that understanding of what's
taking place and so the perception that
we have to have is that where we're
being looked at like we're failures
there's somehow we screwed up so bad
that we're desperate and that we don't
produce good pot and that the big
companies do it correctly because that's
the imagery that's being painted and so
I always talk about yeah it's a struggle
but the bottom line is all businesses
struggle and what it does it allows
people to see a normality and then we
could also say but we were able to be
successful four decades prior so we have
a history of longevity and now we're
having to work with the transition so
that we can move forward and then the
customer doesn't see you as a victim as
soon as you start begging for anything
you screwed you screwed never beg when I
got in trouble in 2002 I had to write a
letter of contrition because I caught a
felony right and I had to write a letter
of contrition and so I wrote this letter
and my lawyer and my friend said are you
out of your mind and I said no no this
is one I'm giving to him and it said the
only thing I did wrong was I move too
fast for the rest of you Kevin Joe dream
and I got the max penalty because I knew
I was going to get it anyways so I knew
they were gonna screw me anyways and I
said you might as well take it on your
feet than on your knees because at least
at least you're holding yourself to a
standard and that's the truth here is
that every time you capitulate bend beg
pray the public sees you as a victim and
then they want to beat you down in price
when you go to the store and you play
this game they want to beat you down in
price because that's a business and what
you have to be able to do is give them
things that they want so that the
negotiations affair get you on a shelf
get you into the public eye get you an
opportunity to make connections you take
those connections and you network them
like you have your whole lives because
everybody here how to sell their own
weed so you all know how to do business
you all know how to produce a product
that the public wanted so what you want
to do now is just be able to kind of
readjust that shift and use the genetic
tools that are available to you because
there's a lot of material available to
be able to put yourself in situations
where you can succeed
I think that's enough for the
conversation so the main point is you
guys don't bow down don't get off get
off your knees only only time you should
be on your knees is what if you're
looking for your car keys because you
dropped them out of your pocket
and other than that and maybe and maybe
as we stand under the crosshair as it
falls and crucifies me from being shitty
is in is in humility but not in begging
for mercy from the market because no one
gives a shit about your struggle and the
people that you're selling cannabis to
are going through the same beating you
are but they've been going through it
for a long time because they've been
diminished in their wages and so most
people are taking a brutal beating and
you don't get sympathy from people who
are also in the same circumstance what
you want to be able to do is give them
some form of escapism some form of
satisfaction some form of genuine
quality and those are the things that
transcend and once you have that you're
gonna able to have a penetration that'll
happen that allow you to move your
products and then start to rebreathe in
your genetic libraries that you've held
and built and nurtured and now you start
to have an ability to where your father
only produces one thing the thing that
you know produces best on your farm and
there's there's there's 1,700 people who
buy the entire farms worth of product
and then you're done for the season but
when you re release you re release the
information and you can set up the
desire the stores that want to carry it
the prices will be there it's it's a
reality if you look at every other
market and so for me I'm somebody who
was career hustler who said wow I'm
gonna get buried alive let me study let
me learn let me share and together we're
gonna do it so it's gone
[Applause]
[Music]
you