[Music]
no longer to any the grower communities
have money go to any grower community in
the California ask them are you doing
well financially
tell me anyone raise their hand and say
yeah I'm doing great I'm making money
like my business is thriving
very very few cultivators some
distributors are doing well some
extractors are doing well couple stores
are probably doing well processors you
know that kind of stuff
secondary outside of cultivation the
cultivators show me anybody that's doing
well I I take a look at all these
Canadian companies coming in snatching
up territory
there's a lot of Canadian investment in
houma County people aren't aware of so
if it's heavy here it's heavy everywhere
and what they're doing is they're buying
up areas that have historical
cultivation sites they're buying up
places that have good brand value for
the future of cannabis because they can
make a long-term investment we don't
have that ability we have to survive
right now and for me it's easier to get
a job and stay poor and keep my farm
alive then try to risk running the farm
and lose money or run the farm and
divert it and have any issues and lose
the permit and navigate
permit again and I'm just like so what
are we doing so I I've made the decision
you know years ago that for me the farm
was gonna be forever and so whatever I
had to do to keep it alive didn't
forward is what I was going to do and if
I could just work on getting the
permaculture Gardens put in to where I'm
actually creating a very closed loop
system over time and it's happening and
then I work on a genomic project where I
can figure out how to get one line that
I can build that works at my property
that has a quality that I think is good
that I know would be good for time that
I have an ability now to be
differentiated in the market and if I
can just survive we'll be okay because
our regional have brand value with the
Appalachians
the ability to stamp humble products
here is huge
so when Maguire put that in it was
brilliant because what it needs to do is
give us differentiation so that you
can't just say well son grandson grown
because really it's not the Sun grown in
Texas and Sun grown in Florida and some
ground in New England even though I love
the New England grows and the grow is a
killer there's like the Michigan boys
the Michigan boys can grow some good
weed they do not have the same ability
to grow what we can grow here because
we're in California we have different
climactic situation so it gives us some
advantages in different ways and humble
has a historic reputation which is a
gift to be able to live here and be able
to be part of it but you know for the
average cultivator oh my god when they
stepped into a bear trap and and I'm the
average cultivator and and the irony is
that they're being held up by sequa
environmental review and meanwhile with
those resurgence of prices in the
traditional market it seems that there's
it could be encouraging I imagine people
both going indoors more which is
obviously for the environment and also
diesel grows more little Samoa is one of
the reasons
people if the Emerald triangle voted
against their financial interest and
voted for legalization was because one
of the major reasons was they really
wanted to stop the environmental harm
that they saw the you know the reckless
black market growers that didn't care
about the environment so many people
here want that to stop because we do
live in such a beautiful and important
ecosystem and so the regulation being
what it is it's the good actors are
trying to come forward and get permitted
and they're being held back and
meanwhile the it seems like the diesel
dope is returning to the hills Oh
guaranteed it's just I remember years
ago I was when I first got to work first
went to work in Arcata someone came in
to buy plums it was right after the
financial collapse the world was
crumbling for most people and I looked
at this person I said didn't I see you
on a jury selection for me on a week to
trial and they looked at Hara and I said
amazing how now that you have need it's
okay
well that's called reality and so diesel
dope is a reality where if they're gonna
satellite the space so heavy that you're
gonna pick everybody ever Ellen
for what he done Duggal homeless what
are you gonna do don't want like what do
you I mean what are you going to do
there is no alternative especially if
you have such an investment in what
you're doing
and so it's a nightmare because the
whole point about going into into
legalization with Humboldt was to be
able to create all these killer outdoor
grows and then in northern Humboldt they
could do the indoor operations because
you can't run out there on the coast and
and indoor is a necessary evil in the
world of cannabis because it fits in the
model right now and they're even
creating indoor Commission's to further
the indoor production of cannabis
because that's how we should produce
cannabis because everybody that's got
indoor spent huge money on the
infrastructure and that means typically
they're tied into bigger operations
which can lobby that way the outdoor was
all basically owner operators and to me
it was the it was the beauty of the
industry was all these small individuals
producing really gorgeous cannabis and I
knew that we would never have the
diversity we did prior because it just
doesn't work it doesn't it doesn't work
for the model where you only have a
three pounds to sell to the store they
need more or otherwise they they sell it
then there's you're not there they got a
cultivate a million different clients it
makes it hard for distribution because
they they source it then everybody likes
it and they can't get it again then they
get it doesn't work and so that's why
the region's had to build multiple
varieties that were licensed that were
patented that were protected and
everyone's like free the plant let it
run a while but I'm like it doesn't work
like that an Ag it only works like that
in black market AD because there's no
regulation but once you regulate it and
you make it so that bigger companies can
enter safely without losing
infrastructure in a raid well there
there's economy escape takes effect that
economists scale just means how big do
you have to be to play the game here in
and what we're finding here is that none
of us are big enough to financially
survive this
and when you are you're paying this much
money for the real estate to put a store
in you're paying this much for the
people you're paying this much for this
your margins are small the the farmer
they build this credible farm they
produce this gorgeous product that then
sits at the farm for seven months so for
seven months nobody got paid with money
come from from my investor let means
he's trying to get back when he gets
paid but you're just basically a worker
so you'd almost be better off not taking
the investor keeping the property you'll
get a job and hang out for a minute the
number of people I know that have jobs
and I was mind-bending where they went
and got a traditional job so that they
could just stay alive as this thing
sorts itself out because otherwise what
you do is you'll work for a full fiscal
year and not getting any money how do
you do that it can't be emotional this
is not an emotional thing you're in it's
just it's real and so your emotions you
know they they're important because it's
what drives you but if you live off of
them in a business you're going to die
and this this this is a one-percent
Walmart model and even a lot of the
stores you have to pay for shelf space
so the stores charge the farmer for
shelf space the farmers get charged for
every step of the process I looked at it
before they ever get paid that's why I
built all the other that's why that's
why I built the other operations was
because I knew that I wanted to be a
farmer more than anything because that's
where my my my heart lies if I could be
hit the hill every day I'd be the
happiest I could be but I got into all
the other things because I knew that the
farmer and life gets screwed and I knew
that if I didn't have multiple options
then I would basically end up losing the
farm into bankruptcy
and I didn't want to lose the farm
because I wanted to give it to my kids
so I'm in my 50s for crazy sex I'm not a
kid I've been I've been in the game
since I'm 12 so I got over 40 42 years
of hustling you know 40 41 years of
being involved in multiple felon
cases everything I name the damn thing
I've been in it so for me the goal is to
be able to take this beautiful piece of
property here and give it to my kids and
the only way I could afford to do that
was make it into a farm and the whole
time I was doing it I knew that it was a
risk but I knew that if I could just
look at it for a really long-term
purpose then it would make that risk
something I could understand and I
expected to be able to make enough money
off the first year of sales to just
balance it out but I didn't expect big
wealth I just expected balance and what
I see is complete in balance and it's
mind-bending that it got this bad and
the state is so traumatized that they're
talking about sending the National Guard
up to you know northern Mendo southern
Humboldt to get her and I don't see them
not doing that I can see the satellites
get them all the information they need
you know it's gonna be a very
interesting DEP season very interesting
because why would you wait for outdoor
why wouldn't you wait for the depth so
every because everybody's strategy is to
get quick depth in before that's the
game's over that's when I'd come in and
get you why not they're not stupid they
have all the tools and so all of a
sudden everybody is you know really
riding on this little moment and it's
pretty scary and so for me I let my
farmstead fallow last year I got hit up
with archaeological reports and by the
time I was going to be able to actually
plant it would have been a longest and I
just said why so I went to proof of life
pictures of me with newspapers and all
the growth sites on the farm and that
way I had documentation and then they
did satellite confirmation so every 50
days they had photos of my farm on
satellite and they said hey you never
grew and it completely took away that
$20,000 excise tax and because I didn't
cultivate I didn't have to file income
tax so I don't have to file but there's
no money so there's more money and not
growing for me personally there's more
money and not growing I'd rather lose 15
grand a year then lose a hundred grand
because I'm gonna have to grow it all
out then I'm gonna have to hold it and I
don't have on-site processing so I'm
gonna have to send it to a processor
then I'm not the JA
then I'm going to get label then I'm
gonna have to get it distributed then
I'm gonna have to wait for the money to
come back and then I'm gonna have to
keep bleeding it out and I'm gonna watch
it deteriorate over time because it's
going to change you can oxidize so we
don't have this multi-year shelf-life
we're not making concrete block so I
can't just put the Block in the yard and
wait until next year when the building
projects jump up if I don't move it it
dipped airier rates and if your label is
on it you look bad because it looks like
you can't grow a good pot and so when my
friends are doing all this am a little
bit work for me in LA I got these older
guys I hang out with in LA that are that
are wealthy older dudes and they have
time which which wealth gives you and
they love to smoke so they go and check
out samples of every dispensary there is
they go and look at everything and buy
weed constantly and smoking and all the
group of older smokers who are all
affluent a very rare group rare but
because of it it lets me say hey they're
unhappy with everything they touch and
so the thing is that that's not build a
brand value you know building brand
value you built a brand value when
you're in an indoor model in Los Angeles
and you have a supply line that lets you
function because you're in some very
trendy spots but how much did it cost to
build that facility how long's it going
to take you to recover that investment
value how much you actually making as
the operator with investors in the room
so yeah you have a piece of equity and a
paycheck but the perception that
everybody's wealthy here is not true and
the investors are waiting to get paid
and most of the operations that I see
that are major on their second or third
cultivate or second of third CEO and the
investors are like holy Christ I could
let out ten million already now I gotta
bleed more because they're in the same
situation that Ben's a great example
I couldn't have more capital even flow
can hundred twenty five million they
raise they're losing a million and a
half the month so they're losing a
million and a half the more they're not
making money
in there there their earnings were great
this month yeah a million and a half
still under what they should be so any
other business in home economy would
collapse but because they're so well
funded they play the game and ride it
out but the bottom line is is that the
modeling you're in and I'm not in that
model I was I wanted to be I wanted to
be in the 10,000 square foot model I had
I got 18,000 a little under half acre
for my cap but I want to shrink it down
to ten over the next couple years so
that I could just be in that Kraft
designation I could have something that
I produce that was of a really nice
quality that's shined on my property and
I'd be able to overtime push it into
this US market because our region would
allow it to take place and then it would
it would be a decent income for the farm
but it would just be an income it would
pay for the farm basically I never
intended to be able to just grow again
ever once I once I looked at the future
I said none of us I'll ever be able to
do what we did we'll never be able to
grow a couple hours a day five hours a
day and have great money and application
that's done you're far enough you pour
and you're going to struggle and you get
used to it and so you better build
multiple income streams or you're going
to go bankrupt and that's terrifying and
it's as real as it can be and so for me
and then I built as many things as I
could build and I'm trying to push as
far ahead as I can with every tool I can
the only thing I'm not doing is trying
to screw anybody but I'm trying to take
every advantage I can if it's science
I'm going to use it if it's common sense
I'm going to use it and when I lay down
the numbers on a piece of paper and I
take a look at it like I'm going to
continent it says there's no money here
it is wishful thinking and so I think
the farmers and cultivators you know if
you're in a situation where you
a good relationship with some stores and
you have convenient processing and
you're able to you know churn a decent
paycheck then you know you go go forward
just make sure your product is you
clearly understand look at what the
nurseries are selling go take a look at
everything nursery online take a look at
their catalogs try to get out of those
products because every major
manufacturer is using those nurseries
for their products so therefore you're
going to see a million pounds of purple
punch you know and it's some of the
vessel I just knocked it because it's
it's so beautiful
it couldn't be any prettier in your hand
but it doesn't have a secondary buy so
there's a lot of products like this and
I just use that one as an example
because it's gorgeous but people don't
want to buy it but because everybody
knows it's hot it got over produced and
then now it's in your it's in your
arsenal and it's on the shelf it doesn't
mean that people want to consume in it
just me that's what's there you need
things that when they consume it they
want to consume it again and you need to
be able to find who you're selling it to
whose the distributor what stores that
they sell to the farmer then has to go
to those stores and make the
relationships at the stores know who you
are so they know that your products good
you can bring it out with you and smoke
to join with them and say look that's
what I'm selling this is what's there
that's illegal
otherwise to rely on all these other
people to do the business for you and
you're putting yourself at this
incredible vulnerability hoping and
praying that all your pots going to go
and then you're going to end up having
to backdoor it and I don't fault you for
that either because that's where I came
from
so I would I would never afford anybody
for trying to survive it's just that god
help you you get caught and they take
your license because now your property
is no longer licensable like you have a
problem now you're gonna have to go
explain to the BC say hey I know you
caught me selling out the back door but
I want my property to get licensed and
I'll just say that we don't want
[Music]