so if I chemically treat I can I can
control most all pathogen problems but
cannabis is so regulated that it creates
the situation where you have to be hyper
clean to the degree that like when I
show up in jobs and I'm like like you're
gonna dress me and they go no no we know
who you are I'm like I'm a fucking
vector it doesn't matter who I am like
where's my contamination shit and I
think that people are not aware of the
fact that you know like the aphid right
now that's our special guest of the day
the multiplication rate of that thing is
unbelievable and in the aphid family
even though we're working with a
different type of rude aphids changed
French wine forever
it wiped out an industry they had to go
to Americans rootstock which they didn't
want to do because they had to admit
that it the the pathogen came from
America in like 1870 so it comes over
smashes the whole French industry they
have to go to American rootstock because
they had resistant varieties it changed
an entire industry because no one could
deal with the problem and it still is
that issue where you still can't use
specific grapes and specific regions
because it the moisture level in the
soil just allows them to flourish and
the plants and I'm resistant so we bring
in this aphid issue and it is deadly in
an operation if you're not having a
containment that's incredible and I
don't think anybody really designed the
operations to have that level of
sterility I think one of the the
cleanest socks I know is the is it's an
indoor but it's a wonder Brack stop down
in Long Beach where you have to go
through basically you know blow blow
tubes to go in so it's almost like
you're going into a like a virology lab
but that's the only way you're gonna be
able to run it and I think that that's
the the change is that on these massive
mega operations we have to have to
rethink the whole workflow containment
who goes where who's allowed to be where
and and how you absolutely keep yourself
protected because once you get an
infestation and canopy that dense this
then you can do you can't bring in any
kind of predation that's going to
out-compete the reproduction rate of any
of these predatory problems for us so
actually and I think they drinks the
world loud to use like I mean these
fucking aphids like some thrive on some
of the shit we used to try to get rid of
them I mean I don't know what it is but
I don't want to know any names so these
products but there's only a few of them
you can use in the late flower and I
mean it's at the point where I think
Dave if it's like I said just drink that
shit some of them die but they multiply
so fucking fast that it just it blows
the doors off mm-hm
anything yeah yeah exactly I was just
gonna say that yeah yeah do you want to
talk about just in case you want to talk
about some of the stuff you've seen in
operations you've consulted on and kind
of some standard operating procedures
and best practices for bringing things
and from the outside which typically is
clones and cuttings well yeah I mean you
know there has to be a quarantine a
portion of the facility when you're
bringing in stuff in for intake and then
you got to be able to look stuff over
pretty good and and whether you're using
you know I just posted a little story of
a little microscope thing that isn't a
fancy microscope like Scott use it but
it cooks up to your computer or you can
use like a jewelers type of microscope
handheld deal that you go around and a
lot of the PCAs and regular AG use these
things and you just look at the leaves
and so you know there's just a lot of
looking at these clones when you're
bringing them in because
you know every nursery has a little
something it's just at scale there's
just no getting around some of that
stuff and so no matter how hard they try
you have to try just as hard and not you
know kind of waver on thinking that
things are clean when they're not
because you can look at 30 different
leaves all around all these trays and it
takes you know one leaf to finally find
something and most people up on five and
so you know it's a tremendous amount of
looking at things paying attention to
that stuff and it's not necessarily my
you know my my original deal but I've
just been a lot of it lately and so
communicating with a lot of the farms
and people that I work with even up in
Humboldt it's not just in you know a
valley type of thing it happens to be
all over like I'm talking and if you
talk to people you know at least when I
talk to them one-on-one you know people
are say straight up yeah I'm fucking
having problems this this situation this
year some people blame it on the big
rains we had two years ago that all of a
sudden you know brought in all the
aphids after the drought you know
there's all these folklore going around
or whatever but nevertheless they're
here and they multiply fast and it
doesn't matter where you are in cannabis
this state that state up north down
south or whatever it's a problem for a
lot of people and it comes back also to
the viroid you know it's you know the
viroid for the plants whatever you want
to call it the dotting is a huge problem
too and I think that's a big vector for
bugs it's a generational thing it's been
transferred around a lot of the people
that found this viroid don't want to say
they're saved bugs don't transmit this
shit but there's a few people that I
really believe in online and stuff that
I follow and they're deep into bugs and
they say that it does and I kind of
agree with them because people have to
realize a quarantine too right is you're
not just quarantine against a sow that I
like I'll give a plug to the company I
like that I mean I wish they gave me the
microscope but I love my little Dynalite
because it plugs into my pad and it
gives me a big screen to look at and
it's really a fish
but that doesn't let me look at viral
issues and so the problem that people
would bring new plants and is it's not
just pathogens that are going to
multiply in that form but it's in viral
and once you bring that plant into the
facility anything you cut or touch and
transfer SAP you can transfer that and
now you start to move it into your
populations and by the time you realize
what you've done you reduce your overall
Terp levels potency levels resistance
anything that has to do with sugar
transport and so I think that what
people don't do is they get new plants
and they need to send out tissue sample
of those plants to a lab it's 550 bucks
and you can get a virus analysis and
then you do your diligence on searching
the plant for things that you can
visibly see and then you let the lab
search if the things that you can't see
and now you know you have a plant that's
pretty decent and if it's priceless then
you send it off to a lab and get it
meristem cultured let them scrub it let
them return it to you clean if it
doesn't have any virus issues it doesn't
need to be meristem scrub so you can
save yourself the five grand but you got
to make that decision I ask people all
the time when I go to these jobs I said
who picked the library but why you
growing these plants and they go because
this is what was here before and I said
what what's the basis of the choice and
no one can answer it the investors can't
answer it the growers can't answer it
and so you look at these things and you
just like wait a second there has to be
a really clear idea of what you're
trying to do with your production
destination where the products are going
to go what you're going to use and
instead of trying to make these
phenomenal collections of eight thousand
different types of varieties you get
core varieties you can work with that
you know that you can understand that
there are problems if they have
inherently with resistance and then you
can simplify it and then you can expand
what you work with but man people take
on so much complexity they don't look at
the problem clearly enough and then when
it moves out of that quarantined
to the nursery then it spreads into all
the bays so it's not even isolated in
one Bay it's in all the bays and now
there's nothing you can do it's just
non-stop trying to sterilize the space
bring new material in but I'm telling
you these things can hide in a fucking
molecule and when they pop out they pop
out with like 8,000 children Russert
mites were considered deadly but the
aphid makes all of these things look
really really simple it's true man and
and the virus the protocols now with
some of this stuff are insane and that's
something that people can also you know
a lot of times these nurseries are kind
of transparent on how they do things and
so you might be able to pick up nowadays
on how well they're dealing on
containing their virus because this this
shit is no joke you know and so there's
nurseries I know and things their
protocols are insane and I mean each mom
has its own set of scissors they don't
ask for scissors for it yeah it doesn't
move you don't take it with you anywhere
it stays in a cup of bleach right there
near you know that plant or that
specific area of the plant so each plant
has its own scissors the D leafing when
you're moving around and deleting cuz
you're making wounds there I mean it's
just kind of crazy I mean it's it's kind
of coincidental that we're dealing with
that you know that I know the Dutton's
been around for a while but now with
this corona virus and the HPL virus or
whatever everybody's getting real
fucking you know Sanitary talking about
drinking rocks and if you're if you're
running if you're running these nursery
operations and you get this infestation
and you release it into any of these
operations the lawsuits are going to
bury you alive and the the thing that I
noticed is that you know every
investment group has some attorneys fond
upon the team so lawsuits aren't hard to
file when you're business partners a
lawyer and it really starts to create
issues where the the nurseries and even
if it's in-house nurseries it's your
in-house nursery you have to treat
like you're gonna get sued because
you're going to end up killing your own
business but for it you know while
shooting ursery they provide to the
public the diligence they have to put
together to make sure they're protected
because there'll be no forgiveness for
the mistake because the margins are so
small that you can't make it up and
here's fast we could we could make
mistakes because we were all in the
learning curve and we all had a
different level of the ability to what
we could do because lack of legalization
changed our ability to actually put
together stable infrastructure but now
that all that's in play
man it puts you in a hell of honorable
situation and I think that's where the
rise of the labs are coming in where the
the technology to get around these
issues with orchid to get around it with
banana to get around it with strawberry
they had to go that route because they
couldn't control it any other way
they're going to transfer in our
direction and I just think that that's
important for nursery operators to
understand that the technology that's
coming out to deal with these issues is
expensive and it's not simple to do and
you have to make sure you're clear that
that's going to be the future that's
coming so if you make the decision to be
a nursery operator you develop
partnerships with these groups for you
become your own laboratory based system
but ok I think a lot of the conventional
agricultural practices we had and how we
function prior are going to change
dramatically just like socially with the
coronavirus mean this shit just change
the world in a day