what you have is you have information
that's used is basically marketing it's
kind of like reading old high times God
and read the shit in years it's like
reading high times and every article was
basically to sell the material on the
next page so they're not giving you any
information they're giving you a
marketing pitch wrapped around some
photos so the problem is you're not
really getting true info you're getting
marketing and what people need is true
info because that's what's gonna
resonate and I think in these could this
kind of community that's what you get
and when people come to hang out and
experience that type of situation their
educational level skyrockets and their
appreciation of cannabis culture
skyrockets and it means if they'll take
the time to ask the person at the
counter would you direct me into
something like this because the person
at the counter who's the lowest paid
person in the dispensary is the
gatekeeper to every one of your farm
successes