Kevin what what genetics are you seeing
trendy like let's get into kind of what
people are growing this year and what's
trendy enough what's trending down and
then prices and I thank Eric you know
you you've been in the price game for a
while and you know are we gonna see
stable prices and the you know light
Pepsi's and then the fall harvest or are
we gonna prices going up are they going
down what cultivars are people growing
what's what's the hot stuff what's the
trendy but trendy internet driven but it
has a commonality in the sense that it's
got something gas in it something that's
got a battery cake something that has
some type of citrus or flavor from like
cherry pie so you you have skittle which
drives orange that's in your runs you
have any of you gelatos and then any of
the cakes then they go ice cream cake
they throw the cherry pie back in it
anything that's oh gee driven it's just
that the people are seeking oh gee that
used to be more oh gee so they want to
go back to the foundations of OG where
they don't have such a changed profile
and I think that when people talk about
trends you got to understand that if
you're a green house operator and indoor
operator you can control your swing
between day and night you're diurnal
temperature change is much smaller than
an outdoor grower if you use great as an
example when you start to have a small
swing it produces a lighter more
delicate flavor the greater swing
produces a more robust flavor and so
when people take varieties that have a
robust full flavor that they're used to
and they transfer them into situations
where they get less of a day/night swing
they turn down the volume and conversely
if someone takes something that has the
delicate flavors and they put them in
the outdoor environment it hearkens it
and so you have to be a
just determine like what are you doing
as a producer and what works in your
environment that's going to give the
customer what they seek what's their
expectation and you're trying to give
someone something that is gonna catch
what's currently involved which is
something that has flavor and has power
where power addicted low numbers stuff
just doesn't move things that are trendy
most definitely move the education on
small batch craft cannabis is an
educational process because the average
consumer isn't aware of it so you have
to take a look at what's trending but
what is what is on the ass end of a
trend and if you go to a dispensary and
you see 17 gelatos you might not want to
grow gelato because you're gonna have to
compete with 17 other people on the
shelf and so what big companies don't do
is they don't run past day 65-63 there's
a little sweet spot so that takes them
right out of GMO type stuff GMO meaning
that that that beautiful chem cookie
cartwright it's just really rich but
it'll pull 34 I mean it's hot but it
needs to go a deep cycle stuff like that
is where the craft cultivators have to
work you you almost you have to go to
things that gives you a natural
advantage because the market won't be
big enough to overpopulate because
larger companies won't produce those
varieties so you have to go into
storefronts
you gotta identify because that's where
this is all moving and store fronts so
you gotta go take a look and say what's
on the shelves what seems to be not in
stock frequently and then what you do is
you don't have to look for that exact
product you have to understand what it
is that people are getting from that
product and once you have that now you
can create something that's a substitute
for that product and it allowed the
blood tenders the sales people to be
able to move it so as long as if it's a
distributor needs where it's above a
certain numeric I say and and and this
is Alyssa's doesn't have to be about
real and perceptions and on the other
shit it's not about 25 it should sit in
a
so it's gonna have numerix that are
adequate to move through distribution
and it has to be on a level that's not
so over produced that you'll be able to
have velocity of return on your products
but the bottom line is cannabis doesn't
break up into so many divisions it's
still breaking up into fuel earth fruit
and floral and the subsets that follow
within that are true and each one of
those divisions hit specific markets
differently and for the you as a as the
producer you have to be aware of what
distributor you using and what stores
they sell to so that you can understand
where your products going to end up so
that if you're dropping og into San
Francisco it's not going to move to the
tech crowd because that's not what they
desire as an effect maybe in Corona
buyers time because in the house but
prior they needed things that are more
cerebral uplifting more in the in the
fruits of laurels if you're moving it to
old school groups they're not looking
for fruit they need something that's got
a heavy or sit-down something reminds
them in the past those earth groups so
you know that the trending part about it
is that everyone looks like what's the
big picture but you as the grower have
to identify who moves your product does
your distributor where does you
distribute a move that product to and
all these questions can be answered no
one's trying to keep it secret from each
other because the distributor the
storefront the producer does not want to
lose money so you just have to be able
to be proactive on this and that's what
people they they just I got some clones
I grew it now I'm trying to get rid of
it cuz that's how we always agree pop
that is not the way you grow pot right
now you've you form your reliance on
your distributor because you need him
without him you can't move the grass he
needs you to have product that moves you
can sit down and say where are you short
where do you see supply issues where is
our overproduction and then you can
actually start to make the decisions the
tough part about trendy shit is trying
to go through the nurseries to get the
material because you have so many
nurseries popping up and none of this
shit's necessarily genomic remarks you
don't know goddamn idea what you're
picking up and you get things that are
this but they're not really
they're uh they're an S one of its
qualities not present so there's no list
of nurseries right now that have the
things that you need and that
information has to be present unless you
hold all your own stock and you produce
it yourself and you're developing a
stability which is fine it's just that
it doesn't let you get trendy markets
which is higher price points because
there's less of it and there's more
marketing that's built in through the
internet so I think you know for the for
the larger producers recognize that your
facilities produce a product that has a
lighter more delicate flavor period it
just holds true the stress from that
switch makes the plant produce
differently in terms of flavonoid and
terpene production so accentuate that
fact most people like by old wine not
robust one so the crowds that want the
robust let them get it from the craft
producers because their situation will
accentuate it larger producers go after
the varieties as they sift and smoke and
say oh this is delicate and light
doesn't make me choke does it make me
cough very very refined go that route
and identify which which is the hot
items in the market and then try to
figure out why people buying it
repetitively trendy shit only sells once
if it's really just trendy if it sells
over and over again it's satisfying
something and I try to identify what
that is I smoke and I go red what am I
getting out of this shit and sometimes I
go I'm not getting a damn thing out of
it I'm just getting the best marketing
ever seen where they're able to push
this product so fucking well that they
convinced you you need to buy it but if
it's genuine you'll buy it again and
that's what you're trying to seek what
are the things that are hot why are they
moving someone talks about you know we
don't like new strains and it's the it's
the Heritage strains I'm like well
fucking white runts one the amarak up
the judges of them Roe Cup aren't a
bunch of new people they're old smokers
that variety satisfy their needs to the
degree that they liked it and then you
look at Josh D he's not small
he took the original og cut or he had
moved it ended well I think he's an ice
cream cake that moved
so using his production methodologies
using varieties that have current
applicability he was able to also win an
emerald cup for his division and so it
shows that some of these things can
shine in the right environments and that
the people don't swing so radically in
what they want you don't have to chase
the new new perpetually because what
takes places you don't have an ability
to optimize your production so you never
get comfortable with the cultivar to
where you're able to understand what was
the optimization to make the Primo so
when when people chase trends I'm like
look twenty percent of you canopy let it
be the trend you know another sixty
percent of you can't be let it be the
stuff that's that's your your goodie and
then have another you know twenty
percent of the canopy has insurance
where the shit comes off no matter if
the fucking grasshoppers inhaled in it
because you need something to pay the
bill and I think that you know the way
you you you stratify your your crop
portfolio is about insurance stability
burgeoning trends is that a solid yeah
that was that was awesome
yeah cuz the daytime smokers are the
main consumers that are going to the
dispensaries throughout the day aren't
you know trying to get annihilated all
the time you know most of us the
seasoned veterans I guess you could say
we're you know going for that
Annihilator shit first you know fall day
the new recreational market is fine with
blue dream dream dream cannot be bad
that's the problem that if you dream
sold all the weight that it did does
that mean that everyone who smoked it
was stupid you mean they didn't they
didn't right liked the people that
smoked it aren't on Instagram that's all
turned into really bunk where people
started pulling it early and just
pushing the shit out of it but long
cycle blue dream is really a nice
variety and done right it's it's it's
good and so those things
certain markets that's if you look at
blue dream blue dream Seattle and San
Francisco - tech ops product in those
groups because they don't want to get
wiped out they need enough mental acuity
to continue stealing all America's money
[Laughter]
[Music]
what was in the mason jar that you were
smelling earlier Reserve f2 from the old
aficionado release and then we went into
it and I went looking for something that
had really no gas in it and we're in
lined with Jackson's black lime then the
black lime reserve because the reserve
was that heavy chem that Leo and Ellie
put into that mix and rest in peace
Ellie the it's just really clear and
light in terms of the smoke and just
gives me this uplifting buzz so it's
kind of fun to smoke sometimes when I
when I want to get high but I don't want
to have to wrestle with the high I'll
burn it but it's just really really
limey and clean and just it's really
good grass man that's a good selection I
didn't select it a friend of mine did
but it's got a really develop palette
and pulled out a large breeding project
he said hey I got the cut you're looking
for I'll hook you and then what when you
say you you smoke to knock you out
should starting when you wake up what
are you smoking well I mean I'm always
an OG leaning towards you know living in
Grass Valley for almost 20 years now
there's been a lot of OG we went from
Afghan aight around here and the OG just
I don't know just sits well with me but
I can't always find or get the
traditional OG that we started out with
so I'm kind of on to that variations of
things of different OG fee knows or cuts
or whatever renames they are
but you know I'm always happy when I can
get linked up with people that have some
you know Kim D or I'll I'm happy with
gelatos and some of the you know you
know like when I'm up north I try to
search out some of the stuff that won
the Emerald cup you know because you
can't find it further south a lot of the
local dispensaries up in Humble have the
if not the the variety of those farms
and so you know I personally am a big
fan of all the craft farms you know from
here to you know any of them anywhere
but from here north of where I'm at so I
give some love to some of those farms
Kath Kevin since you're based in humbled
you want to give some love to some farms
yeah there's a lot of good farms
Ridgeline I know
Delmon that one the amarak up I want to
say you know if you look at companies
like redwood roots they're distributors
almost all the groups that are running
under their banner are local good farms
that balloon gazer the Jacob and Carla
from the farm over in Trinity just
stunning farmers braceland you have a
lot of really nice farmers in the sense
that their their relationship with
cannabis is developed and so what
they're really trying to do is give you
the best possible product where they
take it to the moment of ripeness like
there's a level of care it's really
impressive and it's something that I
look up to as a farmer because these
people that's all they do is farm that
grass and and I have a variety of things
I'm involved in as a farmer but I most
definitely looked at these people for
inspiration on terms of the the finest
details of care and it just reflects but
it's it's all over the place it's not
just us here everywhere I travel to
craft farmers or craft farmers whether
they're from New England Michigan the
whole Pacific Northwest it's all the
same it's it's people and and it doesn't
have to be
old or young it's it's it's this desire
to do a better job and drive a higher
level product and it's it's a beautiful
thing to see and at the same time it's
kind of heavy because they're not
capitalized they can't gain funding it's
hard to tell an investor that you're
here to do the best job he's like I just
need a fucking paid and they're like
well I can only make this much money
they don't see the value so they can't
gather the funding they need to have
liquidity to stay alive during the
process and so you see them breaking
down you know it's it's it's brutal
that's wrong no no mistakes made and
they look old man yeah I thought I look
old I'm like holy shit they're catching
up and it's it's that struggle of trying
to hold your ethics on I want to produce
the best grass that I can grow and I
want to give it to the customer so the
customer gets that experience and and
it's it's it's incredible to be able to
source those farms and so that's why I
shot it out to the roots guys because
yes brands forward this there's Humboldt
brand humble brand Rubin and the boys
they're trying to get the humble
products out into the public and I'm
sure there's groups in in other counties
that I'm not familiar with they're also
the purveyors of farm products and
putting it out it's just the bottom line
is the farms don't get enough of
recognition what happens is you see a
video and it shows some farms but it
never lets the farmers sit down and kind
of talk to you a little bit and connect
to the public about what we're trying to
deliver what and then the farmer that
the farmer can then portray the picture
the consumer can say you know what I
like things like that I like stone fruit
herb meaning you know peach flavors
apricot flavors cherry flavors I like
those things these guys focus on that it
seems to do well that's where I'm gonna
go make my decision none of this
information is accessible by the public
and it's just miserable because the
public is getting fucked because they
don't get to get the good grass they
want for the exquisite experience
and as these farmers disappear so much
of that desire to produce anything over
60 days disappears yeah and that's the
thing a lot of the good there's a lot of
good people on the bench right now still
from the changeover of prop 64 whether
in a band county or you know just aren't
able to pull a license together yet and
some of the things like that so I mean
there's still a lot more to come as soon
as some of those things get worked out
you know a lot of missing people are
gonna come back and a lot of people that
maybe had to take a break whatever the
case is because yeah I mean I think
there's a lot of room for for craft for
a long time coming because like we said
earlier some of the bigger facilities
some of the consumers there's a lot of
Education that needs to go to the
consumer too because a lot of that craft
stuff stays in these crafty areas as
well the consumers that know craft don't
let that shit get out very far and like
you were saying I got a second that big
ups to the redwood roots family because
they really get it out there and work
with a lot of great farms then and I've
always kind of thought they were a cool
group of people so just quickly focusing
on the California market and kind of the
economy right now in front of iris and
all that Eric your your current I mean
if I understand correctly you're
consulting with a large Salinas project
right yeah so so which implies that
there's a large investment and they're
putting money in they're doubling down
in this market so what are you all
seeing like is this year are we gonna
see your over year growth and in you
know acres harvested and total weight
and the California like it is stuff
still growing our investments being made
are people pulling back what are your
predictions for 2020 given that it's a
complete knuckleball of the year well I
think people are going for it if they
can because the prices have gone up you
know I mean we saw a little bit of a
drought last year so the idea is to
capitalize on the chances that that
drought could exist again
now until you know maybe even July
depending on how the weather goes is
gonna dictate a lot of that stuff too
because with the colder Springs it's
harder to get planted and even though
people get planted a lot of people don't
have adequate heating systems to
primarily keep the soil and the water
warm so the irrigating with colder water
until the temperatures warm up and
things like that and so really last year
you know as much as prices were going up
it was hard to get everything to market
and have debt season be a true depth
season like it normally was in July
because a good amount of people didn't
get planted right away part of it was
the licensing - if your license was
coming out of that temporary zone or
whatever and so there was just a lot of
calamities going on at one time but
depending on the weather going forward
this year because even more
sophisticated greenhouses are bigger not
even that sophisticated don't have a
root zone heating they just have up
above heating and nine times out of ten
when I go to places they'll tell me the
angle of the Sun and when I ask him what
the temperature of the soil is they
don't know and if it's below 55 degrees
we're drawing popcorn and it isn't the
angle of the Sun so you know we we kind
of have to see it's hard to make those
projections but if everything goes right
weather-wise coming into spring right
now and people get planted and we get
the yields and July is what it's
supposed to be then you know I think you
know everybody's got a good chance but
if we start to see cold spring
continuing areas we're gonna see less
product coming out that's viable and not
everybody can bounce to biomass anymore
unless you're vertically integrated and
you're making your own oil and freezing
your own product right there though not
everybody's running around going where's
the biomass where's the biomass the
people that are hunting biomass are
really strict about what they want
anymore it's not just biomass it's got
to be high THC non-detect
an intense screening process goes on and
things like that and so you know it's
always changing in in the art of the
pivot is really the name of the game the
art of the pivot your book
yeah well the beard grows did of did it
Ben with the TG genetics on his
propagating purpose and
was the name of the the podcast but it
couldn't be more poignant because that's
you know I met with the beerd Bros the
other night and then and it's all
strategy and how are we gonna pivot
through this one whether it's an
upcoming job that we're trying to pitch
or you know work on or if it's just the
long-term game how what's next and how
do we see what's coming you know without
having to revert to news articles and
things like that it's really the boots
on the ground and talking to people and
you know luckily some of us like you
know Scott and Kevin and and some of
these other guys are able to get onto
farms or talk with farmers and kind of
get the real aspect but we're not out
here writing articles and letting
everybody know you know it's not a
billboard that you can drive by or a
ticker-tape or something like that it
really is you know like farming you're
talking to people and you're trying to
look at mother nature and you're looking
at the other aspects and trying to put
this puzzle together and see you know
where it's gonna go
I mean I'm I'm missing the golden tarp
days and wondering if we're ever gonna
have any events are we gonna be able to
get together and share enjoy yeah we're
not sharing joints we're not sharing and
you've got you know this isn't this
isn't done yet
this this stuff is just beginning this
type of viral contamination issues for
us socially and so it changes
dramatically about people's connection
to others and and how they use cannabis
and how they get information so
everyone's on the internet right now
that's why that's why the signals jam
because anybody's on the net your
problem is is so much bullshit info and
fucking blows my mind and people are so
quick to attack other people that
anybody that has a question gets beat
down by people that can type quickly hmm
so nobody nobody has any fucking clue
what's going on
and the problem is is that you have no
no no way to know and so I'm you know
I'm just grateful that I've been in the
game for a long enough time that it lets
me see what's taking place by just
virtue being here and I tried to share
the information I can that's not on a
disclosure agreement so a disclosure
agreement I can't tell you any of that
shit
but the stuff that I uncover myself I
can share because I know that the
information isn't going to make you take
me out you're gonna have to go execute
whether I want to see people do well
because I I've always had this dream of
a unified industry where we could all
grow cannabis all over the place and you
got to see the diversity you got to see
the complexity you got to see the unity
and in my mid-50s you know that's still
my goal so it's it's a it's a really
good thing that you know you put this
together P to get a bunch of us together
to talk to the public I'd love to pick
your brain i monetize that you know it's
it's it's 300 bucks for an hour on the
phone and I tell you so much shit that
you don't know what the fuck to do with
it up I'll give you every fucking option
let's rap on that and I we still have a
hundred
[Music]