[Music]
this is my pot Eric and and Eric was
someone that I had on an interview for
the first breda series because I respect
them as an individual and I respect his
work but what Eric did was Eric
transferred over to topicals
because his ability to get a license was
hampered because nursery licenses to
function as a breeder require a nursery
license to sell and that means you have
to have commercial real estate and so
commercial real estate is expensive and
so for the majority people that I know
they don't have the ability to really
have all the tools and so aren't shifts
over to topicals but lo and behold one
of his flagship creations wins the
Emerald cup and I said oh my gosh I said
you're still a breeder in who you are
and you're still alive in cannabis
because you just made an adjustment to
where you were gonna go forward with
what you did but I said but I would love
to have you come up and you know and be
introduced because you're somebody who
created a variety that won a major
competition and allowed the people who
grew it to have cell ability because
these these wins give you publicity and
then it creates a demand and I just said
man even though you're not breeding in
the normal sense anymore your creations
are resonating and he also had done work
prior that he didn't get credit for that
I had done huge movements of the
material and he gets a hold of me one
day and he said hey on the galaxy my
material in your material are the same
material and I don't understand how that
can be and I said oh it's easy
somebody fucked you and I got ahold of
it and you never got credit so what
we're gonna do is we're gonna give you
credit for the material you did because
otherwise what happens is you get
diminished so
[Applause]
so so definitely not a one-hit wonder
someone who's been in business a long
time who has done a lot of good breeding
work who's developed a lot of varieties
the the we called the green ribbon but
it was the hottest variety in the
Sacramento cannabis market so before
they wiped out the Sacramento cannabis
market it was booming the variety that
he created was one of the hottest
variety is one of the hardest clones to
get your hands on because it was hoarded
and when I realized that he had done
this I said my gosh I said you need to
be able to bring this out and so my
whole thing with a lot of the interviews
is I just give you a chance to talk and
then I'll ask some questions and we open
it up to the audience quick because
you're gonna want to ask people these
questions of like what direction are you
moving what what motivated you to do
this what was the source material you
used where do you see the industry
moving because these are the information
that you need because you're not gonna
get this from anybody nobody in the
mainship everybody makes you sign and
these you can talk to him now and so the
thing is all the information that's
being generated is being preserved and
held for a very specific group of people
just like economics economics was a
study paid for and funded by the wealthy
to understand how do they remain wealthy
and why do you not get economics
education in school because they don't
want you to be wealthy and so to me this
is the same information as you get an
opportunity to talk to some sharp people
and I'm gonna get off the mic and give
it there everybody hear me hello my name
is Eric miner I own HBK I'm second
generation a farmer yeah so yeah I'm
second generation my father grew when I
was really little and then I kind of
picked it up in high school I'm so Cal
so I don't really have a lot of ties to
hobble area except for the last few
years as I've been progressing to get up
into this area I had a lot of success
with my topicals I started making
topicals in the mid 90s my daughter was
born with a rare skin condition so
I was one of the few that were actually
making topicals for people before there
was excess material to just say hey what
the hell are we gonna do with all this
material that's dump it into a topical
brand and try to move it so there were a
need for what I was doing at that time
and when I first started breeding in the
early 90s there were no seed banks
available to Cuzco you know order seeds
if you needed seeds you had to source it
from somebody else and then create your
own seats you just didn't go by big lots
of seeds to then you know oh I want this
drain I'm gonna go source it out so for
me um breeding was a necessity in the
beginning and that kind of just led into
me getting the strains out there but
realistically like the reason I got kind
of screwed on some of my strains was
being an older breeder we didn't tell
people what we were doing we stayed very
quiet we only dealt with certain people
and only ones that were trusted so and
even into the mid 2000 range I was still
being very quiet about what I was doing
and a lot of strains got out because I
wanted those strains to get out to to
the farmers that needed them but as some
people do they didn't you know be
forthcoming with that and made an
advantage for themselves
which ultimately brought me here because
as we all know things come full circle
you know and so this year my chili
birdie hit baking at the Emerald cup
[Applause]
thank you and so yeah that was a strain
that actually came full circle when I
released that in 2014 at the emerald-cut
I kind of took a beating on that string
at the time those strains the lavender
was played out pretty heavily nobody was
really interested in working with it
then because they had driven it into the
ground and the key lime pie was taking
kind of not that great of reception
because it was the the cut of cookies
that nobody really wanted to mess with
and after I had done the work with it I
was like wow this is something that
really needs to get out to the public
and I tried to kick and stomp and tell
people when nobody really listened and
then when I met Kevin for the seat
series a few years back I brought it cut
up and I was like hey you know this this
is something you guys really need to
check out and it took another two years
and realistically as a breeder it's not
just you breeding something amazing and
saying hey this is what I've got it
takes a community of people to get that
out there to the public it wasn't it
took several people with big social
media accounts and and being able to get
that strain out to customers who then
told everybody hey you know this is this
is amazing and then it created a buzz
about that strain and that's something
you kind of want to work with when
you're working with your strains is make
sure you have something that you can get
out to the public and that public's then
gonna tell everybody hey you know this
was amazing we want to work with this
and that will then come back to you and
and hopefully make your product more
accessible and want people want that
want it the other thing is as a breeder
you have to find your niche what are you
doing are you creating a commercial
brand that other farmers will then make
a lot of money off of are you doing
extract work are you doing heirloom
preservation and a lot of that is
acclamation to what you're doing so some
people are don't have the ability to do
heirloom preservation because some of
those strains just don't work in your
area and then with that so you kind of
have to find your niche who are you
working with who are you selling to if
you're doing extraction work you know
your
you gotta find the ones that the
extractors are wanting and it's really
listicle ii a two-year process of being
able to get those strains out there
because the first year you're creating
those strains then you're doing R&amp;D
research with those strains to make sure
they're even going to be acceptable and
work with the people that are using them
so you have strains that you create you
think oh wow this is something that's
got to be out there to the market but
then you get it into commercial
production and it doesn't transfer over
well into the market because it's either
fluffy and the public is like God you
know that's not what I wanted or the
terpene profile isn't currently what's
up to par with what everybody's looking
for at that time so realistically two
years prior you need to be thinking
about well what what am I going to
create that people are going to want two
years from now because as a breeder
you're not just gonna make something
right off the bat dump it on the market
and everybody's going to get it not very
many people have that accessibility to
the general population to below their
strains up unless you have a
multi-million dollar account with
advertisers and social media so as a
small based farm you really have to talk
to your customers talk to the people
that you're working with say hey what
are you hearing from your people what do
they want is it fruits is it is it oh
geez is it gases as autos and then from
there start to create your plan of what
you want to create and get out to the
market what was this what you start with
in the 90s what was your what was your
beginning source material for your
topicals dah that was from Jamie I
started working with Jamie at resin
seats through advice through Ringo he we
talked about CBD production and um
figuring out whether those would be more
applicable to topical creams and once I
started experimenting with that a little
bit we started realizing that CBD was
really what was where the topical
applications were I've been making Tata
THC only trains for a while
but I wasn't really getting the results
that I really wanted and then once we
started doing work with Ringo strains
and then what Jamie from resin we really
started to see a big boost in that but
now the CBD market has really started to
change if you are thinking about getting
in the CBD game you have to really think
about the new ham production and how big
that is and what they will entail and if
you are a small farm you might want to
seriously think about one to ones that
are even based because that is so that
will get you a little bit farther in the
game because you're not competing
against multi-million dollar ham
productions well the the thing that with
with the with the new have laws FDA
takes on him and under the under the
farms and with hemp production you can
make it into a product called we call it
no backhoe so it's not tobacco but you
smoke it like it's tobacco and you can
use it as topicals but under the in
california the bcc regs is any cannabis
that you use as consumption so if
individuals that produce tincture based
medicine and has to come through bcc
regulations under that umbrella and
that's something that's massive because
most of the people who got into him
really sold most of their product as an
edible tincture if you went to any one
of these stores it was 90% of the
products sold were edible tinctures so
everyone said oh man I'm gonna get into
hemp I'm just gonna kill it and the FDA
said sorry we want to do multiple
licensing agreements so to speak where
you'll get regulated as a hemp Purdue so
you can produce this but on this level
you have to produce it under the BCC and
so for Eric as a topical maker he can
now source hemp material but if he was
someone who was a tincture maker he's
not allowed to use hemp as a derivative
to make into that so if you're into any
of these with holistic medicine you have
to understand like where to source it
and like he said with the 2014 when he
released the chili verde the gas was on
fire like it's still on fire in the in
the in the hot markets but everybody
wanted fuel yeah it's the market changes
so fast one day they want one thing one
day the next day they want something
else
so diversify on what your breeding try
to get a little bit of a rayon
where you're at the oh geez the cheese's
the gases the fruits they come and go
and if you hold on to those stocks if
you're ready and you're watching the
market you'll be able to drop those and
a lot of the altar stuff comes around
you know if you are primarily looking
for the hottest thing on the market and
you're like oh I gotta have the skittle
gelato right now you may be left behind
because next year that it's not gonna be
the hottest thing and realistically in
breeding programs get a good testing
laboratory figure out where your numbers
are every single breeding project that I
do gets tested all those all those
genetics I have to know whether I'm
getting good terpene profiles what the
terpene profiles are what the numbers on
the percentages are and then from there
that gives me a base on what I'm going
to do with those plans as far as are
they getting good nutrient uptake as the
root structure good or the branch is
good and then from there I can start to
go into how does it how does it harvest
out how does it transfer over into the
market and then from there how does the
extract company come back to me and
there's a lot of array of what you are
looking for when you start to breed it's
not just crossing the hottest thing with
the hottest thing and dropping those
seeds in the market those are the guys
that get in trouble because they're
creating something that is based off
something else and they're not doing the
research or the time to develop the
plant as a whole completely across the
board I've made genetics before that I
was like oh my god this is amazing I
can't wait to get this out to the market
but then when we would get it into
certain areas they would burn up because
the temperatures they couldn't handle
hot temperatures or they can't handle
cold temperatures or you harvest them
and all the way through the growth the
plant is just stinking amazingly you
harvest it you cure it you get it in a
bag in a jar and all of a sudden it's
like oh there's nothing there those
strings those are the ones you have to
eliminate as you're going through the
again such a bunch of friends from
Europe and their large industrial seed
makers in Europe and we were having a
conversation about the success
of the variety ak-47 and we were talking
about how when Simon did the breeding on
it because he did huge populations of
10,000 the pullers pull his parental
stock out of what it did and he had
sourced all the material that he put
together and he only did five strains
total out of his catalogue what it did
was it let him take ak-47 and go into
the genomic material and swing the
direction then so if the market wanted
it to be more this he could go into it
and pull it and compete as a we would
call sativa one year he can compete as
an indica another year he could compete
as a mixed the year after all using the
same genomic material because he had
enough paint in that container to paint
whatever picture he wanted from the
tools that he had but ultimately it let
him still keep pushing ak-47 every
single time and I think that's all I
ever saying is that you got to have a
bigger picture and every one of the
breeders you talk about they're gonna
say the same similarity you have to have
a bigger long-term picture of what it is
you're trying to do because when you
chase trends typically you catch the
tail end of it it's kind of like stock
when most people when they get into the
stock they get in when they see it hot
but by the time they get in it they're
at the crest and then they make a Buy
and from that moment forward it's
diminishing returns know what if you go
to stay dry and uncomfortable as
possible on the stage as the key so you
know Kevin Kevin is used to it he can
talk forever on a mic I this is like the
third time I've ever actually been on
the mic so it's kind of difficult for me
[Applause]
but but we we brought you in to the last
event and we bring into this event
because it's not on the mic that that um
that's where you do your work you know
like for you you're you're a humble
quiet guy and it was just the fact that
you know you have a true love of what
you do and some of the work you've done
has been incredible and the hpk topicals
have always been well-received
and your varieties are well received and
as you sitting here now you know what
what what direction are you looking to
go with what you do and I you are you
trying to find you know hem producers to
work with to get cannabis to source like
what do you do now as a topical
manufacturer yeah my team now as a
topical producer uh solely um I have
decided to kind of wait out to FDA
figure out what they want to do with it
we have some money set aside for FDA
approval and licensing and then once
they figure out what they want to do
with him
hopefully I'll know they get some
funding or financers to back me up on
either creating my own production or
finding somebody that we can partner up
with to then pull that material and
what's the change in the hemp laws in
California in July it kind of really set
a lot of people back and it really
hindered the consumer to find these
products and now everybody scrambling
running around trying to figure it out
and so a lot of us just have to be
patient and I'm just being patient and
waiting it out I've been developing my
brand line I've been developing our
testing to make sure that we're
producing clean meds we just went
through pesticide and microbial testing
as well as cloten see and so that's
always something I've been focused on is
making sure I produce good clean meds
but as far as the hemp market goes it's
getting ready to blow up and I'm I'm
glad I'm kind of in a position to be
able to take advantage of that but at
the same time I'm not sure where I'm
gonna be at at this moment it's kind of
scary and so I see a lot of people out
there struggling and worried and and I'm
with you I'm there yeah so but yeah I'm
really thankful that I did created
Oh company in 2010 that I can now rely
on and hopefully if we can be very
existing successful that will then
hopefully transfer over into me getting
another farm license in creating my my
genetic brand again right now that's
just kind of on the side burner and yeah
that's where it's at so it's so awesome
to see that you made the transition and
I was I couldn't be any happier when I
saw you I saw you fly with flash across
the screen and I was like vindication
yeah yeah
nobody had was that caught me off-guard
- yeah it's really nice to see that you
know I spent so many years as a guerilla
grower and in the black market in the
early days that it's still really hard
for some of us to come out and talk and
tell people when we are doing and how we
are doing it because it's still really
scary for us the first time I talked
with Kevin I broke down at the end you
know you know it's really emotionally
tough for me but as the industry is
changing there are a lot of people like
myself who are now finding out that even
though we spent 25 years doing this the
industry at some point they respect that
but if you don't have an education
behind you and a firm understanding of
what you're doing and how you're doing
it to to give that back to the public
you will be left behind fast I've been
told by several people lately that I am
overqualified and under-qualified at the
same time I dropped out of high school
to grow cannabis in the early 90s and I
spent 20 years in the bush is learning
how to grow cannabis very well but
recently I've had problems with the new
industry that came in they wanted they
want paperwork behind them they want to
know what kind of you know agricultural
degrees I have what kind of plant
science do you have what kind of college
background do you have and that has been
tough for me because I don't have that
but I know how to grow amazing cannabis
I know what the plant is like and
and so courses like this the more you
can get out there get that put onto your
resume learn things that will help you
down the road and I think the natural
Korean organic farming will start to
take over bigger in the commercial
industry because a lot of these people
are realizing that they don't want
pharmaceutical products and when you're
using nutrients salt based products
those transfer over into the product
that you're smoking and a lot of the
consumers are now figuring that out so
you see a decline in the hydro base
markets and we've been really starts to
learn how to get your natural Korean
IMO's down you get your organics down
you get your Google culture down doubt
is only going to help with your overall
brand questions let's create the market
know an answer no but that's because
what happened with cannabis was a
travesty occurred and the laboratory was
created and no one really understood how
to use the lab and so what they find is
a twenty must be better than a ten and
five Terp is better than three-term and
so all of a sudden this perception of
numerics became valued and the customers
started to believe that if I spend 40
bucks for a bag and it's a 28 it's gonna
give me more usage than a $40 bag that's
22 and so it's a perception of
efficiency and dosage usage so titration
how much I consume based off what the
numerix are and the problem is is that
nobody really was able to get the
education out quick enough because it
was a new industry and so this
incredible dumbing down occurred to
where people don't really understand
that what they want to do is consume a
product that gives them satisfaction and
efficacy and that's not necessarily
numerically connected and so over the
course of time you'll see those products
rise up and move forward but right now
you're having to fight an uphill battle
to advertise it and I think that what's
gonna save us is that the people that
are coming into cannabis who aren't
caught up in numbers and aren't caught
up in in the past of cannabis they're
gonna want good cannabis and so I use
people who are very light smokers that
are extremely heavily affected by THC
Dom stuff and I try to find interesting
ratios interesting Turk profiles and
that they're happy with because we can't
be used as the test case because we're
basically immune to normal smoke so
we're bad as a tester for that yeah
we're bad yardstick so you know I think
that that's the case and and but for
like what he does with it with the
topical blends and stuff that's a
different usage
just like with the extracts or the
textures because that is about ratios
cannabinoids tert profiles in in a form
where the people that are buying it
aren't looking at the numbers some of
the most successful stuff we sold almost
had zero numbers on right now there's a
big shift in which market that's about
to happen because you have the Central
Valley getting ready to come on with
major hemp production and when you are a
farmer if you cannot farm twenty acres
or more of him you will not stay in the
game when you are making concentrates or
isolates or distillates from those you
need to be big in the game at this point
now when it comes to the cannabis
industry you still have a lot of leeway
as a smaller farmer you can still work
with that but as the Central Valley
comes online do you better be ready to
compete with those guys because they're
gonna be dumping massive amounts
and the general consumer populations
south of Sacramento realistically they
don't really the bait cartridge market
is big with CBD but the general consumer
is not really looking for flour that
tests less than 20% because they're not
really smoking it everybody that's
looking for it is concentrating it down
and then selling it to the people that
are making products like myself and like
myself it's easier cheaper to buy
isolate than it is to try to buy a pound
of flour and then concentrate it down
and to make it into my products that way
so I told somebody recently that was
asking on The Hague what's up Carville
now page about growing hemp this year or
CBD and I said you know you might want
to seriously think about staying with
craft cannabis because once the Central
Valley and the hemp initiative comes
online you're gonna be going up against
multi-million dollar contracts and I
don't know if you're seeing that now but
down in the Central Valley where I'm at
they are hot about going big I mean I'm
I'm doing consultant work in the
relationship working in Colorado you're
talking thousand acres thousand thousand
acre farmers in norm and that's
frightening you know that's a tough
thing to compete against my my buddy
knows a guy that is the largest hops
producer in Washington his only client
is an either bush so he sells the one
person only and he has a robotic
automated hops farm and he has a 30
million dollar extraction unit that does
the extract and he can do twenty
thousand pounds an hour of extract and
he showed me a jar of hops diamonds and
and hops Turks and I said what the hell
was that he goes tops bro and I said
what are you guys doing it with that he
goes that's how we sell it to Budweiser
they don't they don't buy it they buy it
as an extract and they added to their
beer mix and it blew my mind to see a 30
million dollar extraction device
robotics orders robotics sifting the
hemp industry is gonna basically be corn
and the part of it that won't be will be
in the edible form because the FDA won't
let you consume that they let you put it
on your body and they'll let you smoke
it but they won't let you consume it
and so it's the for you as an individual
where if you wanted as we talk about
genetics early if you want to stratify
what you're doing then you produce
things that are gonna catch the ethereal
market mental market lifts and then you
catch the stuff of people who want to
have health and wellness and that means
that part of your product diversity
could be CBD material but CVD and ratios
that work with tert profiles that work
that lets you do some form of efficient
cold extraction so that you're able to
actually get product out that goes under
your label that lets people who use your
label now see that you're valid there
and move forward what I was involved in
all the initial release of CBD in the
United States so I'm one of the first
people to touch CBD and I definitely
released more CBD than anybody probably
other than Stanley Brothers and they're
working off the stuff they bootleg from
us so the the point of this is that I
saw the evolution of this and people
asked me why did you give up so much
material for free and I said because
when you have a necessity you have a
validity and if we can get people to use
CBD medicine and get it fairly priced in
my case free what happens is they see
all of us as cannabis producers
differently they realize that we're not
social pariah that we were painted to be
and if mainstream people can use a
product and use a topical from Eric and
say man that made a radical difference
in the quality of my health
he's valid when their son comes in and
said they sell weed to I don't know
let's look it up and all of a sudden
they become you a brand ambassador
because what you've done is you've taken
away somebody's arthritis my mother who
was a staunch antique anibus individual
where the shit was demonic um when she
got cancer I was able to help her with
CBD medicine and my mother is now this
cannabis advocate that's almost
hysterical because she's in every single
thing I'm doing everybody she's talking
to it they're like boy your mother's so
pro cannabis and I said because it did
something for her that changed her
opinion and because of that she realized
that she had chosen wrongly in a
judgement so she reversed her decision
and now she tries to utilize that
education and knowledge to help people
and that's really where you take a look
at some of the CBD pieces because
is the tremendous amount of people that
need that a far more than need to
consume it in smoke and when you touch
that population and you do it elegantly
and graciously it changes how not only
do they view you but they view all of us
that way and what I wanted to do is I
wanted to be able to continue in
cannabis my whole career and the only
way I was gonna be able to do that is if
I could get the mainstream not to see me
as somebody that they wanted to put in
prison perpetually and the only way that
can happen is if you have a value and so
you have these abilities but you have to
be very intelligent about how much of
your product are you selling in that
form so some small portion of CVD - the
ones one - ones high turf levels so that
there's aromatic because I'm cold
extractions it's this whole synthesis
that actually gives you the efficacy
that you're seeking and you make so that
it works to you you can put it under
your label it work that's what you do as
a flower producer so you get to do your
flower you get to catch a medical market
and you stay out of commercial hemp
unless you are a real farmer where
you're talking silos and you're talking
John Deere equipment because you're
gonna compete with some giants Czerny
anybody with questions that pertain to
breeding I know you take that you see
more of that than I do well totally I
see it but but see what what when when
you doing what he's doing what he says
what he says I see a quality and as
someone who's got career time when I
spent 21 five years doing it I know that
this is a quality product and I know
that if it was presented in the right
form it would sell and then what you
have to do then is be able to figure out
where it belongs and seasonal shifts are
based off of media hype based off of
good advertising based off of things
that are usually bigger than you and
what you want to do is you want to
create a portfolio of things that allow
you to fill those holes as they open and
when they close you just retract and put
something else in and so good readers
are going to work on
variety aligns but not so many that they
don't have control of what they're doing
and what it does it allows you to deal
with the realities of human nature where
they don't always want the same thing
every day but they don't want too many
different things and where you live is a
huge situation for that where if you're
in Southern California it's
exclusiveness so it's things that nobody
has so as soon as it gets out it's no
longer trendy and if I take a picture of
myself smoking it I'm not that sexy but
if no one else has it I'm incredible and
so the ability to understand the
mentality of how things move and work is
huge but that's why like whatever it
does is because the stuff that he worked
with that I used he had done years prior
and it hadn't lost its appeal and so the
quality of the work still resonated
because his desire to create a quality
product was there and his knowledge of
what the market wanted was there and now
the question is how do we move it into
the right locations and that's where you
have to have this this organic group so
that you as a cultivator can say hey
wait a second my shifts not trendy right
now and you find out somebody that I got
the trendy stuff I'll hook you up and
then you're able to catch the whole fill
the need get the check continue forward
and then next year your stuff is sexy
again right and that's kind of as a
breeder you have to make a decision on
what you're doing for me I have specific
lines that I work and I stay within I am
NOT a trend I'm not I'm not following
the hottest trend I have specific lines
that I work that I like that work for me
and that's where I stay at and I have a
lot of people that look at my menu and
they say hey there's no skittles on here
there's no gelato there's you know
there's all these strains and they sit
and quilt that's not what I work with I
work specifically in certain things and
you have to make a decision as a breeder
and what you're going to breed are you
going to be trying to just follow
everybody else or are you working your
specific lines and how those lines work
for you
so I've been working in genetics dad you
have to make a decision whether so what
he's asking is he's asking he's holding
some clonal stock that's local that he's
had forever but they're clonal stock and
now he wants to create seen from those
clonal stock so what you have to do is
you have to make a decision do you want
to you can make you can make feminized
seed from those by spraying them and
making seed stock from those or you can
cross pollinate those with a male that
you've brought in or you can do a sub
cross and try to be no hot back out
those lines and then use those genetics
to make your own stock with that's kind
of the only problem with that is that
the genetic package that you're holding
sometimes is unique so how many times do
your parents have to recreate a child to
get you a lot and so if it's cannabis
varieties that have specific properties
and we have a variety that seemed to
work for spasticity and so I tell people
that's the one thing I'm never going to
get rid of because it has a power that
I've haven't seen in any other varietal
because across the board it works for a
thing and I tried to substitute
everything to find out something that
was similar and it didn't matter and I
don't think we're intelligent enough at
this point to understand these little
intricate details because the synergy of
the turps cannabinoids oils relationship
between bacteria all those things create
too much information to be able to just
say it's that so what I know is you take
that in sell fit hold the material keep
the clone if it is priceless keep the
clone you can people have huge
collections but I'm like what are you
collecting for some things just are
generic but some things like if you have
something that you collected that you
said man this is my core thing I love it
I just wish I could hold it and not have
to play with it you might just find that
the real truth of it is is that hold it
in some seed form where you have some of
the genetic material
hold the clone don't get rid of the
Cologne because this clones that I've
had that I cannot replace I don't give a
shit how many seeds I go through I can't
find him
cuz guy in the back has been grabbing
long term his question was about
long-term seed storage that that's kind
of that's opening a can of worms for me
sort of because I'll take some abuse on
this but for me I don't like to freeze
long term freeze my seeds because I've
had bad problems with that later on down
the road because as a as a general
consumer I can only buy the freezer
that's on the market and if the power
goes out or if it breaks down I'm
struggling to try to get those seeds
refrozen again so for me what I like to
do is I'll I'll store them in in sealed
jars in dark area and just below room
temperature and I've never had problems
with my seat stock lasting you know
pretty I've had seed stock for 10-15
years that still pop within 24 hours
what happens is a lot of people will
miss store their seats by freezing them
and when you're opening and closing the
door constantly or pulling those to that
whole entire seat batch out you go
through all your seeds they defrost then
you put them back in the freezer
sometimes that has a longevity issue and
you will degrade your seeds but I have
other breeder friends that swear by only
keeping them fully frozen all the time
it's it's a personal issue with you but
heat will screw up your seeds you get up
above 80 90 degrees and it's prolonged
your seats are not gonna last long
that's just for personal experience
living in SoCal well the moisture
fluctuations screw you to where you you
you get the seed to get moisture in it
and it activates the enzymes and then
you reach chill it dry it and it
deactivates it except if you utilize
some of it and if you repeat that
process a couple times there's not much
left on the seed and so we can go into
the lab and we can go in vitro and get
into the seed but the
problem is that it's just like with
tissue culture there the number of
mediums that you have to use to find the
right base formulation usually is around
10 so if you're trying to do a TC op you
got at least 10 base formulations you
use you find the one that's closest from
there you start to refine and that's why
it takes so long to do tissue culture
with cannabis is because you don't have
a recipe book you can pop up like for
orchid so I can pop up a book and I can
pull out a recipe and say this has been
formulated by these scientists from Duke
and they say use this
well cannabis you don't have that and
anybody who does is holding that shit in
their pocket cuz it's a lot of work so
I'm trying to crack seeds from 70s that
I know haven't been held right but I
know that there's still enough material
to salvage and it's just a process for
the labs to be able to create the
auguste solution and the hormonal
concentrations to allow it to open up
and start to move so they can get
cellular activity so they can harvest
some form of cell that they can then
micro propagate that and go forward but
you know for the average person you know
to scrub a plant at lowest cost at 6
grand for a meristem scrub average is 10
so if every plant you touch is 10 grand
I mean let's see it's kind of costly and
so like for me holdin seeds it with the
difference I think too is that when
you're someone makes seeds you're taking
them to fruition and you are running the
mothers till the seeds aren't completely
fully stacked with carbohydrates so you
have a true time capsule then he takes
this seed that was fully developed and
then he holds it at a humidity level and
a temperature range that buffers it when
you go buy a pack of seeds if it's a
trendy seed half of a white because the
money's there so yeah they might crack
but they're not gonna hold because they
weren't developed enough so they don't
have a large enough sugar storage within
them to be able to give you what you
need and so for guys like Eric that a
seed makers they have a far better
ability to preserve see than the average
person because the average person
doesn't realize that that plant has to
basically look like shit
when you harvest those seeds the you are
taking it way past the visual Beauty
because you're harvesting seed
now once you do that I would recommend
you run a desiccant pack and you put
them in a seal-a-meal and that way you
can seal them up so that you're not
having any infiltration and it keeps
them nice and flat and what it doesn't
let you stack them up in a bin and if
you can put them in a cellar or a
basement or a cold storage it's how it's
done historically so I don't like these
I don't like the freezers either because
I've always had power problems and so
unless you have a full time power supply
there's an issue and people talk about
oh it's possible but I watched the
scientists running out of the seed bank
in Antarctica with paper boxes with the
most valuable genomic material on earth
running for their fucking lives and I
said well they spend a hundred million
dollars to build that and they're
putting things in paper bags running for
their lives the odds of me getting
around that probably pretty slim so I
kind of look at it the way he does where
I try to hold material but I hold it in
sealed sealed meals so that I can
flatten them out so that I can hold more
material other than big containers of
jars and if I could do it correctly when
I do the ceiling on it I seal up a
second pack that's small so if I want to
pull something out and play with it I
can I don't have to open up the whole
package otherwise what I'm doing is I'm
cracking the whole pack and now you have
to go through the process again and
every time we open it up we expose it to
oxygen we expose it to change in
humidity and if we humidify this we
activate the enzymes we start the
biological process and then we have to
shorten it it doesn't work well and one
of the things I like to do too is I'll
do an initial 24 hour freeze right after
harvest and we shuck and clean the seeds
they will get frozen for 24 hours and
for me it's kind of um it's kind of like
winter set in it's called that seed that
yeah they've analyzed that seed that
winners come it's ready and then as you
pull it out of that 24 hour freeze then
it goes into our humidity packs where
we're putting them away at just below
room temperature so that seed has been
gone through its full cycle so it's you
you've read it it's gone through the
full cycle you've harvested it winter
has been it's you know it's gone through
its winter cycle and now
ready to be propagated once you're ready
for that so initial 24-hour furries for
me has always kind of been initial but I
always like to make sure they're clean
before we freeze them because I don't
want to have plant material in there
because the plant material I'll notice
will point more stir and and I learned
you know years ago from people that were
running mountain varieties that they
vernal eyes before they cracked so they
would take the seed they would do cold
treatment and then soak it cold and then
it stimulated growth because that was
the natural genomic pattern of the
varietals but stuff that was equatorial
was opposite was higher higher warmth
levels so depending on you know where
your original stock comes from you have
different strategies but the main thing
is to make sure that you're doing enough
preservation and you have enough seed
that you're able to actually go back in
in mine and people that are doing really
work a good work on this what they're
doing is they're refreshing this
population every five years you just
can't put stuff away for the rest of
your life you have to basically go back
in and then do an open pollination with
your stock where you're taking a variety
of males and a variety of females so
that you're picking up as much genetic
material as possible and then when you
go back into it you can steer the
direction you want based off the needs
that you have then
um you know that's kind of personal
preference also um when selecting males
I I'm kind of looking for certain traits
that I want to add into my females so
either structure or I'm looking for
colors or I'm looking for terpene
profiles or I'm looking for diversity as
far as nutrient uptake or stability as
far as heat stress mold things like that
and that comes with a little bit of
trial and error so a lot of breeders
will do open pollination so they have a
little bit of diversity so that they're
not choosing just one male to make their
population with it
pre testing them that's why I have a lab
I'll go through and pre test my males
you'll actually have a THC content in
your males and you can kind of tell
through diversity of how far you think
that male will pull your teensy content
to a plant because I've tested males and
they show very little anywhere anywhere
after six to eight weeks but normally
I'll wait until they start to drop
pollen I'll cut some of those pollen
sacks with some of the leaf stem
material and then I'll send that in and
ask for a potency test and that kind of
gives me a low ratio what I'm doing and
I like to use my tests to figure out
where my ratio is on what I'm doing but
realistically you'll know when you find
your males and you're going through them
there will be certain males that are not
doing as well or they don't have as good
a structure or they just don't have that
smell that you're looking for and you
can kind of eliminate them out it when
you're getting into big Pinot hunts then
kind of some things change on that but
holding in males a small property with a
small section can be tough you almost
want our own separate greenhouse that
you can seal off or an indoor where you
can keep them separated or work with a
friend whose house of six plant license
and you can throw some males at their
place and it's not going to populate
anybody in their surrounding
area you know that's why breeding is so
tough because you have to almost
dedicate yourself to breeding or not
breeding people that try to side breed
end up with a lot of material that ends
up with seed later on and then your your
customers are like hey I got some got
some seeds what's up you know it as a
quick win like what I would people were
having problems because their their
varietals didn't have enough numerix and
so I said look let me sift you out some
males to make this happen because it's
easy because I'm gonna sit I'm gonna
sift for a specific trait and so I can
do a sack crack 200 seeds within a week
or two of growth and I have my first
true leaf after the coital Eden I can
take a stamp and sex them and call out
all my females right because I'm only
looking for males then I can let these
males grow up to they're about eight to
ten inches and I can take the top four
inches off and send it into a lab for
predicated analysis that predicate of
analysis is gonna tell me right at that
moment what are my THC CBD CBG levels
and in ratios I always look for high CBG
levels because that's the base
cannabinoid all cannabinoids are
converted from so if I'm looking at
numbers and I have a huge CVG reserve I
know there's a lot more left in the tank
and then I can look at these ratios and
I can say okay we're in a ratio that we
like and we have disproportionate totals
we start to use that population of males
to go into other plants that I want to
increase and then I measure the progeny
the children did I increase what I
wanted to increase and then we're able
to find out which male through the stamp
then I can take that population and do
it again and I can start narrowing down
the amount of plants it takes me to get
into a specific characteristic and I was
going after numbers heavily for people
that I they needed to sell pot and if
you're in the dispensary business and
you don't have numbers that are real you
screwed and so what I did is I use the
same tools we use to go from 5% CBD to
20% CBD in a year to basically do with
THC plants so it let me get a hold of
material that I knew could throw heavy
numbers on something and then I
gave those males the people who wanted
to get into breeding because they had an
incredible collection but they were
working with varietals that were 14 to
17 and I needed to get him up to 27 so
we found can we find males that
consistently added one thing which was
numerix and then from the numeric
population you pull out the quality so
ultimately it's always this sifting
process that you're going through but
lab analytics are helped incredibly and
now with marker assisted reading and the
ability to look at the plant to say you
know how homozygous or heterozygous is
it meaning how much of the trade is
going to be carried and moved it helps
you because if there's too much
diversity then you're having to do too
big a population hunt and for regular
people that's a lot of work it's
expensive to every time you guys all
know what testing costs so every time
you throw in a lab test you know 100 200
300 bucks and so as a breeder for me it
gets very expensive and at some point so
yeah so when somebody says hey I'm
asking this much for pakka seats it's
the on look I'm looking for if I'm if
I'm doing what I was doing at that time
all like just like with CVD all we cared
about was increasing CBD levels because
the numbers were too low so once I get a
population of plants that produce a
higher overall level of CBD now I can go
through those populations and do my
resistance testing I can do my
production testing but I can get every
other quality I want and if it's 3% CBD
I failed
and so with marketable cannabis in
today's industry I needed up in these
higher numbers 28 to 30 well I went into
some of these chem lines and I started
spending some time using predicates of
lab analysis which just lets me all it
ball it means is that I'm doing testing
in juvenile stages and with CBD plants
it's not as cement meaning that with THC
the numbers stay pretty consistent but
with CBD sometimes you end up having as
the plant matures ratios shift a little
bit not as not as accurate but with
predicated of THC analysis I see a
higher level of accuracy with CBD we saw
less but the bottom line is if I'm
looking for one trait that's not hard
look for 20 traits that's hard that's
real reading but so what I was doing was
increasing the cell ability of cultivars
that were sexy but not sexy enough now
and I just used lab analysis and because
I was fortunate that I was involved with
so many labs and I was able to drive
business to the labs once you make money
for people people give you a little
better break on the deal and so it
allowed me to have an incredible price
differential on what I was doing so I
could play Frankenstein all the time and
ask these questions but no one else I
knew had the funds and I had the funds
only because I was driving so much
business to the lab that they just said
we'll play with you but for most people
they don't that's why for these you know
younger breeders that were coming up I
would give them material that I said hey
look we know that this plant throws this
turf profile it throws this
morphological shape
and it throws this chemo type on the
majority of plants it touches and yes
there's outliers but overall you'll get
a population that's easier to sift
because you'll love more of what you
like and and the more of what you like
you'll find the one that's exactly what
you like
it's the sifting process that's that
it's the demon that's the one where you
have to hold all the plants in redundant
copy and then you have to be able to
actually sit down and standardize your
testing and be honest about it because
the one thing I've noticed about
breeding is that if the progeny isn't
better than the parental stock you
didn't do anything
but because you made it it's your baby
and the reality is is that you got a
three-headed kid and yeah and as a
breeder like he referred to you earlier
you have to be a you almost have to be a
robot at this time state because you're
creating things that you hold very dear
to you because you've worked on them and
now you're going to release them to
people who are then going to do bad
things to them and so that's tough you
know so that's something you have to get
overs you got to be able to release your
stuff and be able to stand behind it and
hope that they do well with it and
that's kind of these two guys been
fighting over two questions so what I'm
gonna do is take em first and then what
is the biggest reoccurring mistake that
your competitors make that their
performance I think that when it comes
to doing genomics work it's an
assumption that a and B combined will
give you this and the reality is that
often it doesn't it just doesn't match
up and it's it's what I did is I took a
look at all these other forms of
breeding so I look at people who breed
cattle people who breed dogs people who
read fish and I realize that there's an
intangible genomically that it just is
and what you have to work with this as
much skill as possible and then some
good fortune and good fortune is a big
one because people always underestimate
just the truth of
that and and and that's the that's what
makes human being so incredible because
you can crush down a population all you
want but out of the ghetto comes
somebody who can split an atom because
ultimately in that genetic code pops out
something unbelievable from parents who
were normal you can get exceptional
somewhere in the line prior they had to
be exceptional but it doesn't have to
come out I use myself as an example of
I'm a good reader male because I don't
really screw up the good woman that I
chose to have kids with so the kids that
come out are more like their mom than me
all they have for me is their more
stubborn so that's what we notice is
that my kids are stubborn and driven but
other than that they're more like their
mothers in appearance and in personality
and so I'm a good reader male because
when you put me on top of it
all I'm adding is some very specific
traits hey you know what I wanted to say
real fast to you before we what we get
the question but if you notice we've
been having a sign language presentation
you know what happened was a friend of
mine Candida mushroom and he's hiding
somewhere he hits me up and he says Kemp
I have some friends that are farmers in
Oregon that are hearing impaired and he
said you know this is something that
needs to be brought into a conversation
because did you know that this many
people in the country or globally are
hearing impaired and I didn't and I
realized how ignorant I was to that
situation and so he was like we need to
do some work so that we can get
cultivation information into the hands
of the people that are hearing impaired
because they have to build the
vocabulary to explain what you're doing
and I said hey we're doing this
incredible regen event filled with
really kill of people breaking out
incredible information maybe we can work
it out and Josh was gracious enough to
say hey I would love to have that and so
what we have is we have people that are
signing so that we can record it so that
we can share it because fundamentally
it's it's it's the world we're in really
a cannabis is inclusive
so I just wanted to say thank you so
much for taking the time to come
[Applause]
explain the language barrier no doubt I
just wanted to bring some attention
because it's like what's going on and
what it is is that you have this massive
global population you can call today
cannabis cannabis to me was always the
most inclusive world and to be able to
be tying more people into what we do is
beautiful and the individuals were
lovely individuals and their cannabis
farmers too so it allows them to be able
to have an ability to understand the
material and find a way to translate
words that aren't translated yet and so
that's what's going on you know I think
personally okay the question is is what
one of my competitors what's their
biggest mistake that they're making
right now and that's kind of a two part
that's two parts for me personally I've
made this mistake over the last two
years and I'm just now getting a hold of
it is not being aggressive in your
marketing and your social media and
getting your name out there I'm I'm old
school so it's been real tough for me to
get out there and want to feel
comfortable talking to people and I
wasn't aggressive enough to get a
website and get out there and really do
a lot of events like this that's a big
problem now because if you're not
getting out there and they're not seeing
you and they don't know who you are you
are not going to make it because this is
a new new age of society where they want
to be they want you to be there you know
it's Kardashian thing you know you got
to be able to to show your friends look
I got this and I got it from him and
then that brings it in the other part
is hyping up something too much and
releasing it too soon without knowing
what you've got and then it screws you
later on down the road because all of a
sudden you've got a hundred farmers that
are pissed off because they spent six
months of their time on all of a sudden
they can't do anything with it because
it didn't work out that and the same
thing with the social media you got to
be careful don't over hype something and
make sure that what you release is good
like I said it's a two-year program for
me because once I make something it's a
whole year of doing deps indoor-outdoor
full Sun you know shade how did it how
did it go across the board to consumer
like it did the did your vendors buy it
you know there's a lot to it and that's
where people make the mistake is
overhyping something that's not ready
for the market with with commoditized
crops crops that move globally so that's
corn wheat those does take ten years
it's three years of doing the breeding
and then and then seven years of sifting
the lines and so literally it's a
10-year process to release something
that's a commoditized component and with
cannabis ten years is a lifetime and so
you know the thing is you want to get it
to market right now but the people buy
seed stock from any other industry
they're buying a very different type of
seed and so they have expectations of
reliability repeatability and I think
like what he was saying but see he's
honest so he says listen if he sent
something out that was untested he just
say look I haven't tested it I put
together some interesting stuff if you
want to buy it this is the cost and then
you can run through and do your tests
but I wouldn't commit my whole crop to
it and then they can find out if it
works and you know it's important but
when we really take a look at what
scientific breeding is and how we got to
where we are with these major crops and
stability the amount of work required to
get there is so huge that it lets you
realize most of the stuff we're doing is
just basically throwing darts with our
eyes closed this gentleman right here
before we forget it no no sorry
I think the chapter first you have to
ask why is it high B so why so I take a
look at it and I look like I like touch
- shit all the time and I smoke and I go
quick quick turn it's gonna hot and it's
not gonna be hot but when I consume it
and I go whoa that is some good grass I
buy that see now I have something that
that's ii buy cannabis where if I bought
it once I'd buy it twice and I can start
to say whoa this has a quality that
resonates and if I was to smoke it in
ten years it'd still be good grass
that's what you want to work with in
your directions and sometimes I don't
think that the farmer is really
qualified and they hate they hate to say
this but you've got to have somebody who
can move pounds somebody knows how to
traffic and they're gonna be honestly
telling you this isn't the right choice
and what they tell you is the one you
have over here that you're not looking
at that's the right choice and so if
your abilities are broad where you have
many skills then you don't need to have
the help but if they're not then don't
be so arrogant that you don't ask for
some help and what it does that lets you
determine what is the trend and why it
was like when I did the perp when I went
down and sat in the car the bag got
thrown in the window and I took a look
at it under the streetlight and realized
that the color was clearly defined under
under HDI in a quick turn and that the
blunt didn't change flavor I knew now
why it had value and so I realized it
was gonna stay in vogue until that
social change
changed but then they took that and they
modified it and the perp is the cherry
pie the cherry pie is the cookie it
didn't go out of vogue you just move the
current to where it goes by adding
little things that keep you trendy but
if perp was a monk then it wouldn't
still be current and that's what you
have to take a look at and don't chase
trends unless you're involved in
Hollywood meaning that you have people
that are setting the trends and they're
able to let you see we got traction and
then you smoke it and you go that's real
now you can run it because you need at
least two years when I release varieties
in kelowna form I want to see at least a
two year little egg span where you can
run it this year and get paid next year
you get paid and on the third year you
can get paid but it's not red-hot
because everyone's gonna pour into the
market and fill it so two year three
three years a dream oh gee is like a
legend where if you had the same Cup for
the last 15 years you would've got paid
but now has to be spicy I agree it's
just that what's gonna happen is it's
gonna it's gonna change into which
gelato which which subtlety it's kind of
like looking at wedding cake and
birthday cake so wedding cake yields
better and it gives you better color but
if you consume it next to birthday cake
it's not as satisfactory and so the
thing is you have to be able to say okay
why do they like it I got the gelato 41
right so the 41 has this incredible
cherry pie on top of that that flavor
profile that lasts in the joint it's
gorgeous but the thing is if you go only
that route what we noticed is Fusarium
prone and so all of a sudden now your
whole library is prone to pathogenic
pressure so maybe 15% of your line
becomes gelato or gelato hybrids and
you've used them for years and had
success and people know when they come
to you that they can get those things
but you start weighing everything heavy
that one way
oh you got a problem that goes south
welcome that that depends on the project
that I'm working on
depends on whether we're doing open
pollination or where I'm doing something
specific that that's that's generalized
and if I'm doing open pollination I'm
usually losing at least three males
depending on how many pills I'm using
but yeah what'd he say an open
pollination meaning like when you land
pollen onto the plant are you allowing
the male and the female to naturally
pollinate themselves are you directing
the pollen okay for me I like to collect
a pond and then I use it as needed with
a brush or I'm taking it out there and
I'll have a paper bag put my butt in it
make sure you shake it yeah now I also
do direct open pollination in the
greenhouses where the males are in there
with the females
the fans are blowing and they'll be in
there for a couple days to make sure I'm
getting a full complete thing but if I'm
doing specific breeding in the in the
garden and I don't want to contaminate
everything yeah take it in a jar take a
brush brush go out there you can
actually now get sleeves that you can
put around your plant that's a mesh you
can inject your pollen right into a
little thing it drops it right in there
you seal it off and it's not going to
affect the rest of your plants so yeah
it depends on what the program you're
doing on I would be using the mid
branches normally the whole plant
because I'm I'm breeding for everything
two years ago when I was with the Mendo
hideout we were just doing branch
specifics on lower branches because we
were trying to maintain the rest of the
flower for production so how deep into
the cycle you go like you know this is
going to depend on your varietals
because all of them have a different
flowering period so if they produce an
abundance of pollen receptor sites early
that's when you need to hit them right
if you don't see that happen and so say
between 21 to 25 so I like a little
sweet spot but if you're going to go
into something that might finish it at 9
days then lo and behold there's no sites
at 28 days it's still in a transitional
vegetative stage so you have to
basically choose your pollination times
for the varietals that you're using and
that's trial and error and that's your
R&amp;D and then what you do is you record
it and so that you know hey when I
pollinate it at this time this way
I only received this much seed mass per
square foot and it gives you a really
clear idea of what's the efficiency of
your pollination and that matters and
people like I only want a couple but the
thing about is it if you copy how they
do it commercially then it'll lets you
use someone else's brain you know it's
it's better not to learn through a
mistake it's better to let someone else
fuckup in you learn through their
mistake it's painful and just admit it
though don't be afraid to admit it you
know don't steal the credit that's my
whole thing with readers is that they
always get screwed because most of them
are so passionate about the work that
they don't chase the protection the best
example I have a brand protection is
Michael buffer and Michael buffer come
up with one phrase let's get ready to
rumble
do you know how much that phrases worth
half a billion dollars and you know why
it's worth half a billion because he
sends a team of lawyers to beat you to
death if he finds out you're using it
and what it does it lets him proprietary
own that phrase breeders rely on people
like us farmers growers nursery
operators store operators to be
conscientious of the fact that they put
all the work in and so instead of me
taking his work and then re labeling it
myself I make sure I give credit to him
and and push it and then what it does it
lets him do the work he's supposed to so
I'm riding on his coattails but I'm not
stealing his coal thank you so I tried
man I tried you know
[Applause]
there's this one guys been trying to get
a question forever okay one more
question
oh crap you know pollinate crap yeah so
at a general level because I'm just a
regular farmer I like coconut water or
hydrogen peroxide and I'll soak them
Kevin has a whole way more intense
laboratory procedure he can explain to
you but for me I'll think they're soaked
them in coconut water and then they go
in the ground yeah I use regular real
coconut water because that coconut is
that life juice that's in that coconut
is see that's to get that seat going it
works amazing I'll soak them in coconut
water then they'll go into either paper
towels and wait so check my germination
rates or they'll go straight into the
soil blocks there's hydrogen peroxide
you can use the regular store-bought
hydrogen peroxide but it's not quite as
great as that they concentrated quick
little roll around in them and then back
in yeah and and then they'll go into
purified water packs with paper towels
or into our soil box but kevin has a
whole intense way of being able to do it
a lot of it is does the seed have the
ability to break through the husk and so
you can mechanically crack it and you
can also sometimes scarify it to make it
so that it can be the liquid can imbibe
easier because sometimes you get a skin
on the seed that's very resistant and so
what I do is I make these containers
where I glue sandpaper inside the
container and then I can just shake the
seed and scarify it and then once I've
scarified it now I have the ability to
get liquid to penetrate easier and then
I'd want to it depends on just how old
this is but if I can use an h2o to
solution what it does it allows me to be
able to get a form of oxygen driven into
it so that I start to have this this
metabolic process move forward and I can
also use stuff like grow Kashi in a
liquid form because what I'm doing is
I'm getting
but I call buyer protectants I use that
on TC plants to where if I can give the
plant a bio protective form it allows
this to imbibe and it allows it to
instantly have the buyer protectants
needed to survive as a child because a
lot of the stock that's tough to crack
is typically a little weaker in general
and so I want to give it everything
possible so I don't need to go through
300 seeds to get 50 out and what you're
gonna find is some plants just do that
those aren't the ones you you work with
in that form it's like the clone ability
when I'm looking for cultivars that I
want to work on a nursery level if it
doesn't clone I can't use it so I've had
plants that you couldn't strike roots
for 30 days that makes it impossible to
put into a clonal operation and that's
what maybe understand how many killer
varieties we've lost because they're so
hard to propagate it's just the reality
you know and so I think I think that was
the last question
right thank you
and thank you Eric from HP cave in
always a privilege thank you
[Applause]
[Music]