uh this is kevin mckernan and i'm um
i'm obsessed with genomics and lately
it's been cannabis genomics at least
since uh
probably nine years now since 2011.
hey everybody this is jason wilson with
the curious about cannabis podcast
thanks so much for tuning in once again
uh today
so today i'm really really stoked to
have on a guest i've
been sort of casually following for
years and i've been
wanting to connect with for a long time
i'm with kevin mckernan with medicinal
genomics thanks so much kevin for
being willing to come on the podcast
thanks for having me jason i've uh
really enjoyed all the guests you've had
so far so it's been a it's a great
podcast to get going oh thank you so
much i appreciate that and i look
forward to
having you right in there with everyone
else that i've been speaking with and
um today we're going to talk about um a
topic that i haven't touched in any
other interview
primarily because it gets into an area
where
there aren't a ton of people doing this
work but we're going to talk about
cannabis genetics and genomics and
microbiology primarily
um and so kevin for those listeners that
maybe are not familiar with you and your
work can you briefly describe some of
your
academic and professional background
leading up into
your founding of medicinal genomics and
the work that you're doing there
oh sure so i started off my genomics
career at
the whitehead institute back at mit so
this is a center in cambridge that was
sequencing the human genome
and was part of an international effort
to sequence
the human genome along with the saenger
center and a few folks
uh in in japan and europe uh that was uh
from 96 to 2000 and i was managing their
research and development team there
so we built a lot of the robotics that
um that
automated the dna purification and and
got the
sequencing running there and in 2000 uh
when that project was coming to a close
i decided to
spin out a few of the patents that we
had acquired at the time there
into a company called agincourt and this
was a dna sequencing a private entity
that was a dna sequencing provider for a
lot of people in the in the
pharmaceutical and healthcare space but
we also sold
dna purification tools that help people
extract dna out of cells
and fast forward to 2011
um seven years in that in that time
frame the company also built a
dna sequencer known as a solid sequencer
that eventually went to market under
um under applied biosystems they were
the
those in the sequencing field they
probably know of maybe two companies
that have had
fairly large market shares throughout
the history of dna sequencing and abi
was the first one they had all these
sanger sequencers and and uh
they have um they're still in the market
and they still do their thing under the
thermo name
but there's uh now illumina who's a very
large contender and are
arguably um a larger entity now and we
were competing with illumina
with a solid sequencer for a period of
about five years
um and then in around 2011 i decided to
just do something different and
get out of the industry and go and go
into the plant genetic space and we
began sequencing cannabis genomes back
in 2011.
flew over to amsterdam and extracted a
bunch of samples over there
met don and aaron from dna genetics and
dave watson and a bunch of other
robert clark a bunch of other folks
showed me around over there
and we really didn't know what to do
with it at the time we just knew that
genomics helped so many other markets it
was bound to help this one but we had no
idea what to do with the information and
how to turn it into a company
um so we kind of explored a little bit
um and uh i'd say it was a very slow
start with medicinal genomics because we
were a company that was embedded inside
of a clinical diagnostic company known
as cordogen
and most of the company's efforts were
sequencing kids with epilepsy and
mitochondrial disease and arguably
a lot of diseases that center around the
ecs uh
although the people in the clinical
sequencing space probably don't know
what the ecs is yet
um they're as you've probably heard from
many of the guests you've had before
it's not really taught in medical school
so that was an interesting business but
a very challenging one because as
insurance companies moved into the space
after the ama
they didn't like this idea of sequencing
for uh idiosyncratic diseases
um diseases we don't really understand
you don't want to reimburse for that
so they started raising people's
deductibles and making that type of
sequencing very difficult for people to
do
and that's when we decided to shift the
company fully into sequencing cannabis
genomes because we saw
ironically less headwinds regulatory
headwinds in the cannabis space than in
the clinical sequencing space
so if that gives you any sense of
background i've wandered from research
sequencing to clinical sequencing all
the way into what people might call
recreational sequencing
but always has dna in the thread and
what is it about
working with genetics and studying dna
that
that really draws you in that you that
you find really interesting
well personally i like the fact that it
reveals how different everybody really
is
i mean we have this societal tendency to
want to group people
into uh into either races or
or sexes or or these other large
categories and treat the entire
population as one
and what we're learning from the human
genome projects that is incredibly
stupid
everybody's very very different and
unique and personalized medicine is
clearly the way to go
uh and it's just taking time um to sort
of fight the system to make the system
aware of the fact that you're not going
to have an algorithm to apply to a
population you're going to need to have
physicians actually speak to patients
uh and ascertain that individual's needs
um
so that i don't know that that has
always been uh appealing to me as i i
generally don't like one-size-fits-all
principles
they're just grotesque and um uh and
there's a tremendous amount of potential
in sequencing people's genomes and
improving
improving healthcare uh now that that
same story really resonates in cannabis
because you get involved in
cannabis genomes and you realize they're
even more different than people are yeah
yeah and this concept of a sativa or a
hybrid or an indica
is is garbage yes i'm glad to hear you
say that
and so we have to change that if we
particularly if we want the medical
system to start to speak this language
um they're not going to prescribe green
crack to somebody
you know it's it's they're going to want
to know terpene profiles maybe even a
genotype because there's a lot of dark
pharmacology as you heard
um spoken about before uh the the
chemotypes are great
but they only measure maybe a dozen
compounds and we know there's thousands
uh and so the genomics is another cheap
way of getting at that information
and i think the other thing that's
really exciting about the genomics field
is there probably isn't a field out
there that's moving at a faster pace
um when when you start looking at the
cost declines in dna sequencing
we've never seen anything like this
before and any even in the even in the
chip market where you hear about
moore's law and and moore's law is slow
it's actually something that kind of
gets laughed at in the sequencing space
because we're always held back by the
fact that the chips aren't fast enough
yeah and the sequencers are moving at a
faster pace than uh
than the semiconductor improvements are
so it's a um
it's one of those fields that forces you
to learn about
um dna storage and you know data storage
information whether that be in dna or
not in dna storage
you have to learn about hard drives you
have to learn about internet bandwidth
you have to learn about
chemistry required to sequence these
things so it's very
um you can't get bored in this space
yeah yeah
man there's several things you've
touched on that like spark
passions inside of me as well i mean one
um like i mentioned before we started
the interview
part of my background is in i.t and
even in um you know chemistry labs that
i've worked in a lot of times i end up
becoming the technologist because i'm
very interested in the
equipment as well and and the idea of
information and so
one thing about genetics that interests
me but i'm so
deficient in my like formal training
with genetics but just the idea of how
information is
stored transmitted you know in these
ways that are not necessarily intuitive
but then also what you just touched on
is something that
several clinicians that i've interviewed
have talked about is this move towards
what's sometimes called in of one
medicine or
um yeah individualized medicine trying
to figure out how to use that genetic
data
to understand what a patient is sort of
bringing to the table
before going in to prescribe certain
treatments and everything so that you
can narrow down
um with much more confidence what might
be more likely to work
yeah and i think it's really important
we learned this in the epilepsy field
that um
sequencing and understanding the
patient's genome can can can save lives
i mean there are certain mutations
in um in epilepsy that just require
vitamin supplementation and the seizures
go away
and that can often get in the way um
you might put them in cbd and not notice
that for six months and
then they end up honeymooning out of it
and it really turns out they just
actually needed vitamin b6 or b12
or folic acid or they need to be in a
ketogenic diet because they have glucose
transported mutations there's a host of
there's at least like 24 different forms
of genetic epilepsy
that are actionable based on the genome
itself and they may not always lead you
into benzos or cannabinoids they might
leak the path that doesn't even involve
these
these compounds so um we think it's very
very valuable
the the challenge is um cannabinoids
right now sit in this really weird legal
conundrum where
it's difficult for doctors to prescribe
them it's even more difficult for you to
have a genetic test that actually tries
to look at the variants
and make informed decisions on which
cannabinoids to potentially use or if to
use them at all
because there's a lot of there's a lot
of fda scrutiny on direct to consumer
genetics right
there shouldn't be but there is um they
don't like
having patients enabled to make
intelligent decisions they want that all
to be channeled through
the fda appointed medical school doctors
and that doesn't scale um it's important
that physicians obviously
are very well trained and know what
they're doing but um the the better
thing is to make sure all the patients
uh begin to pay very close attention to
their health because there's no one who
is more vested in the outcome of their
health and the individual
and arming them with information in my
mind is always a good thing but
um they don't see it that way yet and uh
so they have been
cracking down a lot of companies that do
direct to consumer genetics if they ever
imply that they're going to be used for
medical decisions and 23andme was one
case of this where they just got
um they got hammered by the fda and they
kind of sent a signal through through
the uh
through the field that if you do any of
this without going to the fta we're
gonna come down on you so
um we we for a while we're but we're
looking at panels that would genotype
patients and try to discern you know
whether they had like an mthr
mutation and they should go one
direction or whether they had variants
that might predispose them to opiate
addiction because there are some known
that increase your likelihood of opioid
addiction and that might be
that might coach you in the direction of
cannabinoids but um
i think the sequencing needs to get a
lot cheaper for that to happen because
right now it's probably
a couple hundred dollars is prob might
be better spent going to through
dispensary and just experimenting with
different
cbd and thc ratios until you find
something that actually works because
the
science we have around the genotypes is
still um is i would say it's fuzzy but
still it's early
it's very early correlating these
genotypes to
to outcomes well that's that's exactly
what i um
where my mind was going next i know that
one of the
limitations currently with some of the
genomic research on humans is just
trying to understand
how to interpret the data that's there
and how to correlate it
to um you know very specific things and
something that i think we'll get into in
a little bit when we talk about cannabis
is that genetics can be very tricky in
that you can think you have the full
picture
of what genes
and you know what correlating enzymes
and things are responsible for
trickling out into certain effects and
then you realize the picture is more
complicated
than you initially thought and there's
more involved more genes or
um or even novel mechanisms that you
weren't even aware of
it's very true it's an onion and you
keep as you dig into the genetics you
realize there's just there's
many more layers to the data from the
transcriptomics the proteomics
all the methylation that's going on so
it is uh it can in fact be
a rabbit hole in that regard but um
on the bright side this is a plant
that's largely not been studied yet
and when you look back over the last 20
years where they have applied genetics
to plants
the productivity gains are just massive
um
they've just the agricultural revolution
that's happened is
as clear as day now that like since they
sequence the rice genome and the wheat
genome you can see the number of traits
that they're starting to discover and
how they can use that to breed for more
efficiency
um it's it's something when you when you
see those papers
you start to recognize that like the
carrying capacity of the planet isn't as
limited as we might think
yes that we are going to get more and
more effective
at uh at biology and and
how we as humans fit into that biology
in a way that isn't as wasteful as it is
today
yeah exactly i mean something that comes
to mind is like um
you know in the classic story and movie
jurassic park where
the idea that life finds a way you know
studying studying these things helps you
understand how
life is so adaptive and able to
um you know reveal different traits that
you never would have imagined might have
been
you know possible um in order to you
know continue persisting throughout time
and
it's interesting to see humans role in
that i think um
something that i think about a lot um
you know sometimes people have a
tendency to talk about humans as if
they're outside of nature
right yeah and and you know in the sense
of this work it's
you know i don't think of it that way at
all like we are we are part of nature we
are part of how
life is unfolding and and interacting
with itself and
so in this in this funny way you know
people
studying genomics doing this work
unlocking these tools and
understanding how to be more conscious
and how we
influence life and that sort of thing
it's interesting it's like mother nature
doing these things you know through
itself but using humans
as a tool um to this it is it
does bring up a lot of um controversy
right in terms of gmo
and should we should we be are we part
of nature when we start modifying nature
and um
is this analogous to beavers building
dams and bees building beehives and all
the other toolbookers out there
uh are we meant to utilize or intellect
to do this to nature and that's uh
um that's a deep topic that can go on
for days but um
my general sense on it is there's
there's multiple different ways one can
be
uh performing gmo i mean arguably mendel
was doing emo
it was genetic genetically directing a
breeding program
uh and we can do that today too but even
at a faster pace because we have
basically better measurements we're not
just looking at maybe the color of the
peas we're actually looking at the
cannabinoids which you can't see with
your eyes or you're looking at the genes
that encode them
so that you can track these things at a
much faster pace but i think we're also
going to be confronted in the next few
years with
how does the community feel about
removing genes from the genome
not actually adding any foreign content
but maybe
it's important that we delete a couple
um
rare cannabinoids so we can comply with
the usda's hemp blocks
right there are some leaky cannabinoid
synthase genes in the genome and some of
them you can get rid of some of them you
can't
depending on what your goals are and
i've seen rumors and maybe even a couple
patent applications implying some people
have gone about deleting uh
these thc phase um i don't think you
need gmo to do that because you can find
plenty of plants that don't have it and
just breedful
let's say it was some other gene you
wanted to get rid of
i think that's going to kind of come our
way i think the other thing we're going
to see
are people who are trying to be very
cognizant of the fact that
gmo has a marketing problem right now
that they're going to try to do
manipulations with the plant's own genes
they're going to maybe take
the chlorop take the chloroplast genome
and add stuff to it because the
chloroplast genome sits at
extraordinarily high copy number
and you might get more expression
putting certain genes there
there's other people who have thought
about putting other markers on the y
chromosome
as well and find males from a drone
flight
and oh interesting yeah
that's probably going to require a
foreign gene i don't know of a gene and
cannabis off hand that might in fact
do produce that marker but someone the
obvious one is
green fluorescent protein which was
pulled out of a jellyfish
that's used to mark all types of other
transgenic plants and
you could pop that into the y chromosome
and have your plants
glow in a certain wavelength such that a
drone flame can identify males or rip
them out
and those males presumably won't
propagate if you're good at removing
them
but there's always a risk that they'll
make pollen that could spread and then
there's a
property rights issue as to who you know
did you did you get your pollen into my
field and who's responsible for that and
um with all of these modifications uh
that also tends to bring the elephant
into the room which is patent rights
um it's easier to get patent rights on
things that are clearly man-madified
than things that have been naturally
bred
there are breeders rights there are
plant patents and there are utility
patents which we're seeing roll out
right now and they can cover naturally
occurring plants
but it's far easier to get something
through the patent office
if you've clearly changed it from nature
i don't necessarily agree with that
moral philosophy but that's
the facts of the matter that's what we
have
so i think we're going to be faced with
a lot of these things sooner than we
realized if you actually go through the
patent office today
you will find patents in there that have
cannabis in there where they have
put glyphosate resistance into them they
have put
human p450s into them to modify
cannabinoids so that
they are more water soluble upon
extraction
there have been ones that i suspect
they're going to be ones
working on c3 to c4 photosynthesis
conversions and
there's a host of these mods that are
already in the patent office this
doesn't mean the technology works yet
right patents have no obligation to work
there's anti-gravity devices out there
right they're just ideas
but um usually people don't file those
unless there's some preliminary data
because the expense of filing isn't
something you just do on a
on a brain fart yeah you actually want
to make sure it's worth calling the
lawyers for so
um i know i see a wave of all of this
innovation coming
uh into a community that has very
diverse opinions on it
and i'm kind of kind of curious where
that's all going to go
yeah i agree it'll be uh over the next
um
10 to 20 years it's going to be very
interesting to see how
everything evolves and how the industry
accepts certain technologies
and and rejects others very very
interested especially when you have
like like you were talking about just a
second ago with thca you have these
market dynamics influencing
some of that you know where you've got
um
people that are more so maybe now than
ever feeling that pressure
of needing to find um
genetics that are going to ensure that
their you know livelihood stays intact
now that the farm bill has passed and
you know we'll see how it changes over
the years
but i know that's why there's you know a
big push now for
cbg dominant cbga dominant cultivars and
everything
but they're still getting thc um in some
of those
um so it's interesting and this this
starts to segue into
some of the research i wanted to talk
about but before we get into all of that
to set up a good foundation can you
describe a little bit of
um some of the tools and techniques that
are used to study dna
and kind of uh keep in mind that some of
our listeners don't have any background
with any of this so
sure yeah yeah absolutely so um there's
there's generally two different types of
um dna sequencers that are out there
there are
there are sequences that are used to
re-sequence a genome
generally at much lower cost uh if the
genome
if a reference genome is already known
okay so let's say like
we did the human genome back in 2000 um
it wasn't really finished and still
isn't finished today there's still some
centromeres that haven't been fully
sequenced yet but you know 99 of the
genomes known
there's a large effort trying to make
sure we have maps across all the
telomeres and centromeres right now and
they've managed to diverse a couple
chromosomes from from telomere to
telomere
but once you have that reference genome
since the human human population is
fairly inbred
we differ maybe by one in a thousand
letters in the genome
what that means is you can use a much
cheaper sequencer to resequence
other people's genomes and then just
compare it to the reference
and these are this is usually where
alumina comes into play they can only
sequence about 100
bases of dna maybe out to 300
some extreme cases they can do paired
ends or 600 base pair reads where they
do
two 300 base pair reads aimed at each
other uh and that gives you
um it does really well in the human
genome you can remap
and and and sequence people's genomes
for probably under 500
now um that doesn't include all the
analysis but just the raw cost of the
sequence is getting close to
close to that point um now with that
said when you're re-sequencing
and you're mapping to a reference that
is fairly representative of the entire
human population
uh you can figure out where all the
single letter changes are
really easily it's a bit more
challenging to figure out where
entire chapters of the genome are
missing with those technologies because
when the read gets shorter than the size
of the variance
it's very difficult for those reads to
actually detect the variant
so so as you approach like 25 to 50 base
pair
changes in the genome the short reads
systems start to stumble and miss
important genetic variation so there's
been an effort to increase those read
lengths and most of the zephyrs have
gone in the direction of sequencing
single molecules of dna
so that they they get a cleaner signal
it's very
the illumina systems right now in order
to read the dna
they first amplify the dna to a couple
thousand copies
and then when you're sequencing that
particular colony
you're actually sequencing a thousand
molecules that are all marching in step
down the dna strand and what invariably
happens as you go out and read length
each one of those
reactions is probably 99.9 efficient but
over time
they start to get out of phase the the
molecules get out of sync and it gets
very difficult to start reading the
sequence
so to get around that that synchrony
problem uh
what the the direction the technology
moved was to sequence single molecules
which is much harder to do
because you need to be a thousand times
more sensitive but once you're reading
single molecules
you never have to worry about the rate
at which the polymerase decides to read
the molecule you just let the thing run
and you get to read the dna as the thing
is copying it in real time
so uh the two sequencers that are
probably most known for this
are pacific biosciences sequencers and
then
an upstart sequencer that's i probably
have one floating around here somewhere
it's called oxford nanopore um and uh
they they they're much smaller
footprints but they're much noisier
these things
will thread dna through a biological
protein pore and when the dna gets
threaded through
that pore uh the current starts to
change on you
based on the sequence context that's in
the pore so the thing might zip through
at 500 bases a second
and as it's doing so it's leaving a
current profile
that tells you some information about
the sequence um they're about 90
accurate they're getting better they're
it's a very quickly improving platform
but the interesting thing about that
platform is it's so it's so small
it's portable you can bring it to
coronavirus outbreaks you can bring it
to africa
i see all right and then you usually
need a hell of a lot more bioinformatics
in the back end to clean up the signal
those are um the read length and those
are unlimited right now
um they have had reads go out to two
million bases on those things so it's a
massive breakthrough on reed length
um somewhere that's a little bit more of
a compromise between the two
is a system that also sequences single
molecules but the way it reads it
is using a zero mode wave guide
which is basically an array of very very
small holes
and there is a phenomenon when you're
trying to image molecules
single molecules in particular which are
very small is the the problem you have
with anything that uses
light or fluorescence is that
fluorescence is actually a fairly
large wavelength um if you look at the
wavelength of blue light for instance
it's 500 nanometers and you're trying to
measure things that are angstrom so it's
kind of like shining a floodlight
on top of a speck of sand trying to
watch the speck of sand
and if you have more than one speck of
sand in the flood light you really don't
know what you're watching
and so what they had to do is build
these tools
that focus light into a smaller diameter
than the actual wavelength of light and
that's done with the
technology you can see in the front of
everybody's microwave oven the microwave
actually has this remote waveguide there
that prevents those much larger
wavelengths from from
um from getting through but what happens
at the
at the surface of that never put your
hand directly on the surface of that
thing
it won't let you because there's a
screen there but if you were to get
close enough to that
there would be a zeptoliter volume of
radiation coming through there
and that zeptoliter is enough to
illuminate a single polymerase
molecule copying a dna strand so pacbio
does this really elegant
device where they read eight million of
these holes at a single time
and they've managed to be able to put
circular molecules
into this thing so when the polymerase
grabs onto it and rolls
and starts to copy it it runs it around
like a gerbil wheel
over and over and over again so you end
up reading the forward strand
then the reverse strand then the forward
strand as you do this 30 or 40 times
you eliminate all the noise and they now
have
20 000 base pair reads that are 99.9
accurate which is like an absolute
remarkable breakthrough
and we've only had that in the last like
four months wow
um so much of the work that you see in
the paper we put out
actually used a technology of theirs
that was a little bit older that was
probably 50 fold less accurate but it
had
200 000 base pair reads we use that to
assemble a few of these cannabis genomes
and very recently we've gone
back and resequenced them with this
newer hifi chemistry that they have
um to even to you know improve the
references even further but
it's those two main tools that i think
are first are being used the most in
cannabis right now is that we we don't
have good references
and the human genome is easy in
comparison to the cannabis genome to
sequence
a couple of the things that make genomes
easier to sequence is that
if the mother and the father genomes are
fairly similar
it gets they're easier to sequence and
that's the case with humans in case of
cannabis
there's probably a variant every 50
letters instead of a variant every
thousand wow
that's much more difficult to sequence
because um the mother and the father
genomes are like sequencing two
different genomes that are blended
together
and that can confuse a lot of the
algorithms trying to put the sequence
back together
so the the long reads on these platforms
and
particularly the long ones that have
accuracy are what are really
shining through they're the ones that
are putting the genomes together in in
in perfect order near perfect order
right now um
and uh that's enabling us to start to
ask can we build a single reference for
cannabis where we can resort to these
cheaper tools for mapping
and i think they've already still out on
that we we do do a lot of illumina
sequencing the pre-print that we have up
there has 40 genomes that were done with
aluminum mapped back to the reads that
were
the references that were built with pac
bio but one thing that we discovered
doing this is that while there's a
single letter change every 50 bases
uh we're finding there's an equally high
rate
of like entire chapters being deleted
this is what people
call like structural variation uh
and so that pro that um preprint listed
about 58 million
single base pair changes in the 40
genomes that we looked at
but in one of the the trios that we
sequenced which is a mother and
a father in its offspring you did that
all with pac bio so we had the
visibility to see these large chapters
being
deleted and added and we're seeing
upwards is about an eighth of the genome
that's in structural variation between
just an inbred cross
that's an enormous amount of genetic
material that is different
uh just by crossing siblings right so
let alone
if you step out of the cross like a type
one with a type three
you're gonna it's probably gonna be even
more diverse than that
and it's beginning to beg the question
whether
we should we should go with the old root
like we did with human where we make a
reference genome and map everything to
it it might just be
the time and where the technology is
mature enough where you just forget the
short reads altogether and just always
use something like that bio
uh that's a cost question right now bio
is probably 10 fold more expensive than
illumina so a lot of people want to
want to try and leverage the aluminum
platforms as best they can
but if you really want to know what's
going on
a single sql chip from uh pack bio which
are usually a couple grand
you can probably get a trio sequence on
one of those now
so we we tend to recommend people in
breeding programs
if you don't know where your parents
came from and you're not confident in
them at least
sequence the parents with pac bio and
then you can do all your f1s and f2s
with the cheaper tools but if you're
starting with
a ref a distant reference like the ones
in ncbi where you don't even have access
to the germplasm and they may not even
be the same type of plant
most of the references up there are type
3 plants
you're you're going to have a bad time
um there's so much difference between
those references that uh
they're a great starting point let's say
but um i think the direction
the field is going to go is in these
tour depan genome
where you if you're going to build a
reference it needs to include type ones
type twos type threes type four plants
so that we have all the industrial um
uses of cannabis in there
as a reference so we're not missing
genes right not just focusing on the
drug type cultivars and
right right or the hemp one right right
yeah exactly yeah and can you describe
um really quickly for our listeners what
are type one two three and four
uh oh cannabis varieties uh so this goes
back to etienne de meyer's work and
probably dave watson's and few others
they um they classified cannabis into
five categories um these need to be
refined but this is just a historical
classification where type 1 plants are
thc dominant and tend to have a
23 to 1 ratio of thc cbd
type 3 plants are cbd dominant plants
and have the inverse
relationship type 2s have both genes
and they make both thc and cbd
uh and as you get into type 4s they
don't have either gene they don't have
thc synthase or cbd synthase and they
they just make the precursor cannabinol
and uh type fives are broken even
further upstream and don't even make
cannabidiol
yeah and so they're cannabinoid free
plants now what we've come to learn
after doing all the sequencing is that
was
a remarkable classification system they
figured out not having ever seen the
genome
so they figured all this out kind of the
old school way with mendel so they don't
really know or haven't really never
published where
those markers are in the genome uh the
pre-print we put out
at least attempted to do the most
popular ones that we find
and the most common variations we see in
these cannabis genomes that map to this
nomenclature system are
the the type 1 plants have a broken cbd
gene so they really only have thc
synthase there
and whatever cbd is coming through is
probably
uh promiscuous synthesis from the thc
synthase gene
these these genes are not 100 pure they
don't make
uh only one compound they tend to
predominantly make one compound but leak
a little bit of the others
likewise if you look at the cbd plants
they usually
have the thc gene completely deleted
and the reason why we think the
nomenclature system probably needs some
more refinement is that there are some
rare cases where you can have a thc gene
be present in a type 3 plan but it has a
point mutation in the gene
that's deactivating it but the genes
still
and so that can throw off some testing
tools we've had testing tools in the
marketplace now for three or four years
that try to just look for the popular
ones the the full gene deletions but
they're
they get tripped up when there's a
actually a thc gene there
and there's a point mutation that's
killing it because the assay is not
sensitive to pick up that single base
change
um likewise if both of these genes are
missing from the genome
there it's usually a good sign that it's
a type 4 plant and
so a lot of people have been using the
sequence information to breed
for cbg plants right now because when
you have both thc
and cbd synthase is deleted uh
you have less synthase genes that could
be leaking thc expression
yeah uh and the the the other genes that
we're paying close attention to in that
in that pre-print
are the cannabi chromium genes because
those are the next classes
related genes to each different base and
the plant for some reasons made like
eight of them
uh it has got more of those than the thc
and cbd's genes
they're not heavily expressed in a lot
of the tissues we've looked at but again
we haven't looked very
deep at um i think to really find can
have a chromium expression you might
need to be looking at
different time points in flowering and
maybe in veg states
to really see it turn on we we happen to
see the most kind of a chromium
expression in male plants and i don't
know why
oh interesting yeah that was the only
place we actually got our
expression that study were in male
flowers and uh
and the jamaican lion plants that we
sequenced have a
a can have a chromie cassette a lot of
plants don't even have that cassette so
um but but that's another gene that that
people like to keep their eye on
if they're trying to breathe a wider
spread between
um a cannabinoid and thc that's
compliant with the usda regs
is um they pay very close attention to
the copy number of thc synthetic cbd
synthase and cdc's and this and that
usually gives you
some guidelines as to how much you might
leak yeah yeah
have you um going specifically to cbc
just for a second
um in any of the work that you've done
have you seen any
correlations with um uh differences
in environmental qualities that that
might influence um cbc in any sort of
way and the reason i ask is there's some
old literature
i mean possibly i can't remember when it
came out is possibly late 90s early
2000s so it could be totally irrelevant
now
but it was based on looking at some of
the data that was coming out of the
university of mississippi
and um and some of the
some of the accessions that they had
they were seeing higher levels of cbc
and there was speculation that it
might have something to do with humidity
or something like that given that the
plants were grown in mississippi
versus you know more arid environments
where they normally would be grown
so that's it's a really good point and
one thing that that surprised us in this
whole study
is after we sequenced um these 40
genomes and there's a figure
in the paper i should point people to in
this that may give them a perspective on
it let's see which one it is
i think it's figure seven eight or nine
uh
what we looked at was the presence of
these um copy number variations
your audience probably can't see this
but but what shocked us
uh we'll maybe post in show notes or
something is that um
blue means they're deleted and red means
that you have the genes the jamaican
line strains are here
purple they have they're heterozygous
for it but what was shocking to us
is that there are all of these different
strains out there that don't have
this kind prominent cluster this isn't
one gene this is two billion bases of
sequence that's deleted
and what's on that contig that's been
deleted
or the portion of the kind of gets
deleted happens to be three or four
other genes
that are involved in pathogen response
there's an aquaporin gene in there
there's um there's a few of them listed
in the paper but
uh so if there's any cannabinoid that
would be
most directly linked to environmental
conditions and perhaps pathogen response
or humidity
i i would pin it on that one because you
can see that there's a
there's a common deletion in the
population that
when it's gone you lose some of these
other genes with those cannabinoid
synthase genes
and so those plants arguably are either
going to be more prone to pathogens or
have a different response to stress
um then i mean one of them is actually a
gibberellin transporter
all right that gibberellin's a really
important plant hormone and i don't know
how
how many more the genome has i've got to
go and look at that but just seeing
one of those things get get deleted um
means the the plant's probably gonna
have a really odd response to stress
and it's in very close proximity to the
can have a chromium genes that
you know that that might be uh you know
reason to believe that uh yeah the
kind of chromium expression might be a
little bit more linked to um
to these these types of changes wow
really fascinating this is already like
making the the uh gerbil wheels in my
in my head spin because that's something
i've always wondered about and
and hearing about this this genetic work
is nice because you know with my
background
looking at the the chemistry of the
plant and doing um testing that sort of
thing
cbc is one of these problematic
cannabinoids where um
if your method is not really dialed in
to really
measure cbc accurately you can get a lot
of other compounds that can co-elude
around the same time as cbc there are
isomers of
other cannabinoids that show up around
the same time so you know something i
say to a lot of cultivators and
extractors that are trying to get
information on cbc
is you know some of the data that's
floating around on your test results
about cbc
you can kind of take with a grain of
salt that might be cbc might be
something else
um it's one of the it's just coming out
of the labs i just know it's
one of those problematic cannabinoids
that a lot of times is not super
accurate compared to you know cbd
thc or cbg even um
yeah well that's a that's an
industry-wide problem in that um
we have a hard time as it is correlating
some of these genetics to the particular
chemotypes
because we're usually relying on
genetics and
genetics from all over the world and but
then you know chemotype testing that's
done in 50 different laboratories that
all run different methods and it's very
hard to
standardize uh and and get get results
that you believe in unless you take
control over all that and run it locally
that means you're usually studying
plants that are only within your state
um because you can't get the flower
material across state lines legally
unless you're dealing with type 3 plants
so it's there's a lot of limitations i
think to the research because that and
and as your other cast have mentioned we
do need to be looking at
the flavonoids yeah can flavon a e and a
variety of these other
um cannabinoids that people are starting
to find like the italians the thcp
is probably at very low levels and some
cultivars that we just don't know about
because no one's been looking for it in
our standards
yet exactly yeah yeah i mean the um
you know cannabis as a biochemical
factory is um
geez the potential there is is really
incredible it's
you know um something i i also say to
people a lot is you know if you're a
researcher wanting to get into cannabis
research it's an exciting time because
there's
uh depending on you know if you can
think outside of the box of just thc and
cbd
um there's so much low-hanging fruit to
pursue
regarding research projects and stuff
there's so much work that needs to be
done
um and that's why it's exciting you know
i have mixed feelings about the way the
hemp industry is going but one thing
that's exciting with
labs needing to get dea licenses to
handle him um this changes the game
as far as labs being able to work with
um like universities or even you know
other labs that have been you know kind
of slowly trying to do cannabis
research on a federally legal level and
have you know kind of struggled and
there hasn't been a strong
network of researchers there to kind of
support each other
um that's going to change a bit like
already i've done a little bit of work
with some universities to help them get
um sort of caught up on some of the
scientific literature and get
some analytical methods um in sort of
uh development and moving towards
validation and stuff and i'm really
excited to see
what momentum we're going to see when
these labs are able to actually
move material to one another um and
and universities are feeling comfortable
not risking
you know their funding and that sort of
thing to actually touch cannabis
um yeah that is starting to happen we're
seeing um
cornell get funding now we're seeing
harvard get now
but you're right about the da issue that
that's almost going to guarantee
that labs that know the least about the
plant are the ones
that are put in charge of it yeah it's a
good point yeah
and you know and the testament to this
is just look at what happened to full
spectrum labs right they
they were an operating cannabis lab who
tried to play by the book
applied for a dea license and since they
were at the time
presently handling cannabis they got
raided and shut down
right so anyone who's currently right
now handling cannabis
uh they're gonna be really reserved to
go and apply for a da license knowing
what's happened in the past that's
almost gonna invite
a dea raid unless you set up a
completely new business that's
financially untethered
and and then somehow get your
intelligence in there
and then apply it's just uh um it's
certainly going to favor
pre-existing dea laboratories and from
the ones that i know they're great at
picking up cannabinoids and urine but
they're awful exactly
yeah they've been focused on toxicology
and that's that's really the only
the only thing they've they've been
really working on um
yeah it's going to be interesting um
there's going to be a
learning curve for sure that um we're
gonna
have to wade through over the next
several years while
um labs get caught up but yeah thinking
about the long term
i think it's all um i mean of course i'd
rather just see cannabis descheduled and
then
you don't have that right and then this
is
right yeah to study a plan is kind of
crazy
it is it absolutely is and that's
something i always try to preface
as much as i talk about you know part of
my
job on the side is helping people
navigate these regulatory waters and
and so i talk about it a lot kind of
casually but you know i do like to point
out it's like i don't want it to be this
way
i definitely don't yeah but it is and
you know and it's what we have to work
with until it changes
um well um so segwaying into the the
research that
you know we've um been sort of dancing
around let's let's talk about
um the study that just recently put out
so
right now it's in a pre-print form
but so there's a ton of data there in
this research you looked at
um a jamaican lion cultivar
and yes and that wasn't
go ahead oh as you say you were you were
mapping the
uh parents the siblings and you were
looking at
um genes related to cannabinoid
expression
uh sex expression and pathogen
resistance is that right
yes yeah and so just uh you know caution
all of it it is a pre-print it's not
been through peer review but all the
data is public so anyone can grab the
data and
uh download it and play with it while
it's going through peer review um
koji is a great place to go if you want
to look at the data it's a genome
browser
comparative if you just google c-o-g-e
or comparative evolution
or comparative genomics genome browser
you'll you'll see a
search in there for jamaican lion or for
cannabis and you'll see a certified
reference up there that has a lot of
this data
linked in it's got great graphical tools
so you can you can kind of play around
with this data yourself but
yeah so the the the purpose of that
project was to first build some good
cannabis references
um back in 2011 we sequenced the chem
dog strain with
these short read aluminum tools and
those have
we probably did a billion reads and when
you try to assemble those reads the
genome's so complex that you only get
like
uh puzzle pieces out that are about 3000
liters long this is what we call a
contig size in in genomics and you want
those content sizes to ultimately be
the full length of a chromosome it's
rare they ever end up that way they
usually are broken up into a couple
pieces because the centromeres are hard
to get through and some of the telomeres
are hard to get through but um the human
genome has one or two chromosomes after
15 years of being declared finished
done finally hip to tip so yeah we're
going to do much better than that in
cannabis it's going to happen faster
because we get to stand on their
shoulders but
um so that there's this there's this
term in the in the genomics field that
measures the contiguity of genomes and
it's known as the n50 number
this is the average size of the length
of the pieces of your puzzle
and cannabis chromosomes are usually 60
to 100 megabases
in size and you'd love for your contents
to be perfect stretches of
60 million bases long i think the
largest one we have in one of ours is 40
megabases so it's
it's close we're almost we're almost to
perfection but the references we had
when we started this project
the n50 size i think the largest one at
that time in genbank was about 150 kb
so 150 000. so a big improvement from
and then john page's group put a few out
a few days after we released the
jamaican line one they put one out from
purple cushion vanilla
and those inched up toward 400 i think
sunrise put one out that's in the 750
range
uh 750 000 bases but the the real
assembly gurus don't get excited until
you're over a megabase
um that's kind of like a a mental
threshold that they want to see
before they start considering a
reference grade genome um and we still
weren't quite there yet
so we decided to keep sequencing and we
just all that we did different than the
people behind us
uh was that we just jumped on board of
the newer sequencers
uh the latest and greatest chemistry
just pushed the jamaican line reference
above the megabase mark so it's
currently at around 3.2 megabases on the
preprint that we put forward so the
average stretch of sequence in there is
is a stretch of three and a half
megabases long
um now the other thing that's important
is looking at
the quality of the sequence to make sure
there aren't a lot of errors because
when you have
58 million variants you don't want to be
spending your time on 5 million ones
that are wrong
it's a lot of error to sift through so
the the the more later sequencers tend
to have
a lot more um a lot better error rates
and more accurate data
now the other thing that you tend to do
to really build a strong reference
genome is you like to sequence a trio
which is uh a cross basically a
a mother father an offspring and the
reason you do that
is you can then triage your errors that
that don't make any mendelian sense from
the ones that should we call these
mental errors and there's less than like
a point two percent
mental error rate in the in the jamaican
lion trio that we have
um so what that means is you look for
variants in your offspring
and you say do i see evidence of this in
either of the parent if it's not either
parent it's probably a sequencing error
and you use that information to
basically categorize what variants are
real or wrong
the other thing that usually has to go
on when you're dealing with a new
species and we're doing some work with
this on google and a few other parties
in the space
is you usually have to retrain your
algorithms that look for the variants
when you're dealing with a genome that
as polymorphic as cannabis
all these tools were trained on humans
so they're only expecting a variant
every thousand letters when they start
seeing whatever
faces yeah they start throwing
everything out saying this is a
different organism get hell out of here
so you have to go back and retrain all
the base callers and all the variant
callers to start calling the variants
more appropriately and they usually take
the tools that are used for mosquitoes
mosquitoes
have a variant like every 20 bases
they're probably one of the most
polymorphic species out there
and so the tools that they did on gambi
they can anophelese gambi they can then
kind of tune to be somewhere between
you know humans and and anopheles and
and uh
and settle in on cannabis so we went
through the effort of doing that type of
training
with the tools that we're using so we
get the base calls really accurate
and the assembly is very accurate and
then once you have that sort of trio
that reference set
you can then confidently take illumina
data
and map it across all of those
references and start asking questions
like
are there entire segments of the genome
missing um what's the polymorphism rate
in all the genes that are out there
how many highly damaging variants do we
have in a given cultivar
um in other words gene like mutations
that actually destroy genes
how many of them there's like 2 000 of
those in a given
genome there's that many genes that get
obliterated through
polymorphisms once you also have these
references
the next thing you want to do to curate
them is you go and sequence the rna
off of as many tissues as you can and
what that does is it tells you
what genes are being turned on and where
they are in the genome
today we don't have great tools that can
just scan a reference genome and say oh
i can see where all the genes are just
algorithmically
they really want to see biological
evidence of how those rnas are getting
written off the genome so if the
listeners aren't familiar with dna and
rna the analogy you often hear
is that dna is like information on hard
drive
and the rna is what's in your task
manager which programs are actually
getting executed off that hard drive
not every cell in your in in the genome
or in the
the plant is going to be expressing all
genes all the time
right you know a trichome is going to be
expressing a lot of thc synthase
but it may not be expressing any of the
root proteins that are right
that are needed to interact with the
mycorrhizals so
you you do this to try and get as many
pictures of what genes are on and which
tissues
this helps you annotate the genome so
you know where all the genes are and i
don't think we're done with that process
yet we did this across five tissues
uh we found about 27 000 genes in the
female genome and about 32 000 genes in
the male genome
and those numbers are likely to increase
over time as people survey more tissues
and and do more sequencing
one thing that is really um a bit of a
breakthrough that's happened this year
in the sequencing platforms is those
same single molecule sequencers can now
be deployed on rna molecules
and in the past we didn't really have
that we had these short read sequencers
trying to ascertain where the rna is
mapping to the genome and that's really
hard to do because rna is kind of like a
fragmented hard drive
it never reads a gene from uh
like a capital letter to a period as a
perfect sentence
now what tends to happen in the genome
is your gene gets scattered across
uh the genome in like ten different
pieces
uh almost like fragmented data on a hard
drive and there are tools in the cell
that when you make that rna transcript
they go and splice out the regions that
are the exons
and make what's known as a transcript
and it the process of excising those
exons it can do in a combinatorial way
so you can have uh any given gene
through a process known as alternative
splicing of that rna
can make you know three to ten different
proteins
so the protein complexity is not a
one-to-one correlation with the genes
that are in the genome
but having these sequencing reads that
can read across the entire gene
genes rna in one shot means you can
accurately place all of those exons back
into the genome
wow we haven't had that in cannabis
until until this year actually i think
we were the first people to probably put
out any
pac-bio rna isoseq data that gave us
really clean information
on intron and exon boundaries um that's
uh that's something that's really hard
to do
with short reads particularly in very
polymorphic species
um it's it's a bit of a challenge so we
now have that
that backbone inside that koji browser
we can see where all the transcripts are
in five different tissues uh and then we
also started to play around
with methylomes this is the epigenetic
code and it's never been done in
cannabis before
it's very hard to do in cannabis because
cannabis the genome is 63 percent at
so there's there's four bases in can in
in most genomes
a t c and g and the human genome has
roughly an equal amount of all four
letters making it a fairly
easier genome to work with but as the
genomes skew their themselves
more in the direction of one nucleotide
pair or the other
it's kind of like putting a jigsaw
puzzle together where all the pieces are
the same color
and having less entropy and signature in
each of the pieces and so you find
yourself confused more often
well when you want to do methylation
analysis
you have two choices you can use some of
these single molecule sequencers but
they're not good at doing it in plants
because plants
methylation patterns are far more
complicated than microbial ones so
you can hit microbial or maybe human
methylation patterns with the single
the single molecule sequencers today but
they don't handle plants very well yet
so we had to resort to a tool
that's known as bisulfite sequencing
this is something that will convert the
dna
if it's not methylated into it all the
cytosines in the in the genome
if they're not deflated they get
converted into into a t
into a different base and so by
sequencing this
before and after a conversion like this
you can figure out all the all the same
protected deflation mark however
the genome goes into something like 88
uh at it becomes so at rich
that you can really you lost trying to
put the reeds back into the genome you
only like map half of the genome back
with this tool
but it's the only thing we've got today
uh to handle methylation and so we we
ran that on four different tissues to
get an understanding of
where all the promoters are in the
genome the promoters are the regions in
front of the genes
that are usually responsible for turning
the gene on or off right and when
they're methylated they're silencing the
gene
and when they're unmethylated or
hypomethylated
they're turning the gene on and so we've
got beautiful pictures now of thc
synthase and
the adestine gene which is involved in
some seed development
those methylation patterns getting
turned on and off dna
um one reason why we're excited about
this is it does give you
it gives you better paleogenomic tools
if you ever want to look at ancient
cannabis samples
you can't do it with rna rna is one of
these molecules that breaks down really
readily and very quickly
it's it's that way on purpose because
it needs to make those rnas to send a
signal and it needs to kill those
programs afterwards and so
there's all this feedback mechanisms and
cells to destroy rna after it's been
expressed
methylation however sticks around for a
really long time you can actually pick
up methylation signals on
ancient dna samples and
so it can give you some understanding of
what genes are turned on and off
uh across long time horizons uh and so
there's um
there's an interesting aspect to
methylation data in that regard
but um but that information is now
together in public and people can kind
of comb through it
um that was leading to your i think your
final question
which is what do we see in this data
regarding
pathogen response right and
the pathogen response front uh we
we took a little bit of a myopic
approach in that we we looked at all the
genes that have been published in hops
that play a role in pathogen response
particularly powdery mildew resistance
because
powdery mildew is a type of pathogen
that's very cheap to detect
um there's not only pcr assays for it
you can visually see it so
you can tell if a powdery mildew
resistant or not uh if it's surrounded
by other plants that are loaded with it
and it seems to not have it
um that's not the case with a lot of
other pathogens you can't see them so
it's hard to to phenotype them
but we so we looked at kitinases
kitinases are enzymes that are
throughout the kingdom the plant kingdom
you see them in all plants um and you
also even see them in fungi
yeah yeah so it's an interesting game
they some fungi express these to kill
other fungi
a one that makes kitinases to kill
aspergillus so
um it's uh it's a weapon that's used to
fight off
fungi because the cell coats and fungi
are
made of chitin and another molecule
known as a beta-glucan
and beta-glucan is something plants have
evolved to fight as well
with proteins known as thomatin-like
proteins these things chew the other
thing that's inside of a fungal cell
membrane
so we looked at those two gene classes
and then another one known as
mlo which is a mildew locus that was
discovered or mildew resistance locus
that was uh
discovered in um in hops and in other
other plants as well but there's some
work done in hops trying to map this
out so all in all that was about 82
genes that we just went through and said
are there any
large like copy number changes in these
genes that might correlate
with pathogen response and we're
starting to find some of those patterns
in jamaica line
there's a handful of thalmatine like
proteins that have copy number
amplifications
that seem to correlate with path with
powdery mildew resistance
uh and there's some kitinases as well
that are sticking out so
those have been uh interesting to look
at but um i i wouldn't say it's the
final chapter on that story because i
think we have found the genes
responsible for powdery mildew
resistance in jamaican lion
but i don't think you can necessarily
apply those to all the other plants out
there because i think there's five to
ten different modes of resistance out
there and we just happen to be looking
through the lens of one of them
right right no that's a that's a really
important point when
when people read this data that it's
it's
very fascinating and it gives you
insight into this one
mode of action um but like we were
referring to earlier there could be
the picture is almost certainly more
complex could be other things going on
um that's that's super
super fascinating i um there's a couple
things
that i wanted to ask you to define in
case anybody's listening and has gotten
a little confused
um one is can you briefly describe
simply what methylation is to listeners
which
normally my exposure to it is around
like heavy metal resistance and plants
and that sort of thing
um but yeah just briefly describe um
what that is put that in context for
listening yeah so
the atcs and g's in the genome
faithfully replicate themselves in cell
division
but there are other marks almost
environmental memories that get written
onto the dna
and they get written under the dna in
the form of methylation they tend to
methylate cytosines seeds in particular
there is some methyl a that you see in
bacteria but
the most common methylation pattern you
see
is uh is a methylation signal that gets
put in cytosine now there's a couple
other
forms of methylation on cytosine that i
won't get into but in
in neurons and humans there's
5-hydroxymethylation and there's a
variety of other forms of methylation
but it's still all working on
the cytosine base just different methyl
groups hanging off of it
but this is usually something that's
done uh to make the dna coil
and to contract it's uh when you add a
methyl group it makes it
a more hydrophobic um
molecule it's like adding more carbon to
it makes it greasier and so
the dna changes properties and the
methylation tends to also attract other
histones and other proteins to it to
wrap the dna and coil it
and a lot of gene expression is based on
just uncoiling the dna
getting these histones to move out of
the way getting the dna to relax so that
an rna polymerase can come in and start
to express a gene
so you tend to find the regions of the
genome that are getting silenced
get get heavily methylated the cytosines
get methylated
uh and then when they're getting
expressed they tend to erase that
methylation pattern
now sometimes in rare cases this
methylation
is is accidentally heritable it gets it
gets moved through
sperm and meiosis and into they've shown
in rats and mice that they
there can be methylation signals and
small rna molecules
that transfer environmental information
into the offspring
it's a very very subtle effect it's you
need very large n numbers to really
prove this and it's probably a minority
of the heritability that's going on in
genetics
but it's fascinating yeah it's it's it's
one of these it's one of these things
that's brought back
the debate between uh you know darwin
and lamar
you know darwinian genetics versus
nurture
exactly it's it's it's back and it's
it's good that it is back it's been a
long time lamarck has silenced for
many years but the reality is a little
bit of lamarck was right
uh and that there are aspects of your
environment
that will get written onto your dna and
a small portion of that may in fact find
its way into the offspring such that the
environment can actually change the
genetic outcome in
future generations but um again that's
it's a very subtle effect
and and not nearly as powerful as the
mutations you might see that are
actually written faithfully
into dna yeah the thing that pops up in
my mind to conceptualize this
in a totally different way my wife is a
mental health therapist it reminds me of
the concept of
intergenerational trauma it's like you
know
right these subtle things that can
you know get passed on um that relate to
to how you know somebody uh grew up and
and their environment and everything
but it's interesting and i know we're
deviating but i think
this is something in general i wanted to
ask you about misconceptions around
genetics and and genomics and stuff so
the concept of epigenetics is talked
about a lot it's a very um
it's a big sort of buzzword in
pop popular science pop culture science
and stuff like that and so i
one of the questions i was going to ask
i may just ask you now what are
some of the misconceptions that you hear
kind of popularly shared about
genetics genomics and and particularly
epigenetics whether it be
related to plants or humans um that
you'd kind of like to set straight
so the scientific field is really
excited about methylation for the
complete opposite reasons that pop
culture likes to magnify its effect
um the the pop culture likes to uh
almost guilt people into their actions
today are gonna hurt some child three
generations from now and that is
remote garbage it's it's it's hard to
hang out on but
um the uh but we're excited about it
because it teaches us about the
machinery of
of expression and and the cell when we
see
the cell methylating certain things it
tells us
it gives us another vantage point on
what's going on um it's one thing just
to measure the rna that's coming off of
these
off the genome it's entirely another
thing to have and to know
which parts of the genome is methylating
as a result of this because that implies
there's a feedback mechanism that there
is
something else in the cell that is
responding to a signal
to make something transcribe and maybe
even a feedback mechanism turn it off
uh and so we like having those circuits
all spelled out so we're really excited
about epigenetics for that reason
but a lot of that often gets um uh
pushed into pop culture as being
uh you know this your actions from three
generations ago
are now impacting uh the direction of
the human population
and uh that that's the there's very
very very thin evidence for those things
i don't doubt that that some of those
studies are in fact real but the ireland
famine is one that comes to mind but
it's such a weak p-value and such a weak
effect
that um you'd be better off worrying
about whether you're
you're staring at your phone too long
walking into a street i mean
yeah yeah really yeah well there's
there's stronger selective pressures out
there that are likely to
affect your genetics than than some of
those um those epigenetic effects so
uh it's unfortunate but it happens you
know that the science often
gets interpreted politically and i think
uh epigenetics is one that
that has uh a sort of guilt associated
with it that's being
leveraged politically well yeah and for
people that are not scientists
or have a very vague understanding of
the research that's gone into this it
can really freak people out
unnecessarily it can cause a lot of
stress like you like you mentioned
um that that really isn't warranted and
another example that comes to mind
is you know concern over um you know
different types of waves that are
passing through your body
you know um and the effects of
gravitational waves and this sort of
stuff that
some people um when they start hearing
about
um oh gosh like quantum quantum gravity
and
uh quantum mechanics is a big one where
people start to hear these concepts and
then they get really strung out worrying
about
um these effects of things that you know
the effects may be real but they're so
small in comparison to other things that
have much
bigger pressures on you like you're
saying that it's like it's not really
worth exerting the mental energy to
worry about that when
you're already here you have much more
real um
issues to deal with that you probably
don't have to worry about
um you know wave just
gravitational wave distortions being
caused by you know comets and things
moving through
you know the galaxy uh strong that is a
great way to describe
string theory yeah
so so go and going back to the the
research study now
so well i guess one thing i want to
summarize for listeners too
just to kind of talk about some of the
techniques and the things you've
described so we
we talked about basic um dna sequencing
and that is looking at the possibilities
essentially
of the organism what's what's there the
foundation to work from
measuring the rna allows you to
understand
what's actually at play um within that
dna sequence and then the methylation
piece being able to look at that
helps you understand how the environment
is influencing
these things that are at play is that a
a good super simplified version of
explaining that
you know methylation in many ways is i
actually like the rna data better
because there's
so much more information content there
and it's it's more accurately mapped
but the methylation is kind of another
confirmation yeah when you see
uh promoters uh have methylation
patterns that promote the expression of
the genes you
um you have more confidence in actually
what's going on so it's just another
it's another view under the genome
um but yeah that's that's effectively
the central dogma right as we have this
genome it is
the hand that you're dealt and if you
don't have certain aces in that deck
you're never going to get them no matter
how much light or water you
plant so if you don't have a thc
synthase gene you're not going to coach
that plant into making thc
some other way yeah um however if you do
have a thc synthase gene if the gene
doesn't necessarily predict that you're
going to make
seven percent versus 14 percent thc
right
at least that gene doesn't we're hunting
down a couple other genes
that are related to the precursors in
the pathway that might in fact have a
bigger impact
on the magnitude of expression but right
now the genetics between thc and cbd
they really just give you the ratio yeah
to expect
but they're not going to give you uh if
you push the magnitude of expression
of a given ratio too far it will break
the the usda
regulations and genetics today aren't
going to predict that
um i think in a couple years we'll know
that we'll know that there's a couple
genes
stream that everyone's looking at um
that are involved an aa3 and aa1 and
um there's a libertolic acid cyclase and
transfer
all of those things are great candidates
for mutations that may in fact
be driving the magnitude of expression
between a seven percent and a fourteen
percenter but
you know if you have a fourteen percent
cbd line uh
you're going to be risking that popping
hot um it's gonna it's gonna probably
approach that point three percent
under the given regs that are there and
so a lot of people are unfortunately
trying to find seven percent lines grow
twice as much material
only so the material 99 percent of it
ends up going into an extractor
ratio no longer it's absolute entity by
regulation but
it's what's there but to the point of
your analogy on cards um you know if
you're missing both aces cbd and thc
you're going to be you're going to be
making the precursors the kings if you
will
and uh and that's uh so the genetics can
be very very predictive and they can be
predictive at a very early age
and they can also scale that's one thing
that i don't think everyone yet
appreciates while
they probably are never going to give
you and never going to be a replacement
for an hplc value
you're probably never going to have a
field portable hplc that can run
thousands of samples a second
yeah yeah that will be doable with
genetics it's just a matter of time
um but it it it's much harder to imagine
getting that to work with an hplc system
that's field portable
so so they're complementary and we
always encourage people not to view them
as one versus the other because
there are many more things that you can
measure with genomics and its price
points are changing so radically you
should pay attention to it but they're
always
going to be complemented by people who
have good analytical testing equipment
yeah and i think that's a an excellent
way to summarize that it is all
complementary and even within analytical
chemistry there's
sometimes a a strange um
competition between analysts that prefer
um kind of traditional chromatography
and those that like to rely on mass
spectrometry and
you've got some people that are very
resistant to
you know they kind of want to stick to
chromatography and you know and that's
what they do and others like really
trust
um spectrometry and and then i mean
obviously
i mean they blend together you use mass
spectrometry
as yeah exactly um but there is a funny
there's
you know within the science world there
are these weird little camps and tribes
just like anywhere else
where yeah yeah and they exist in
convincing too we all bicker over what's
the better platform to use
right yeah yeah um are there
any other lessons that um
that you gleaned from this recent
research project that you want to talk
about i mean one thing we
mentioned but i don't know if we really
got into it was the relationship between
these um cannabinoid acid synthase genes
and the pathogen resistance we touched
on it early on but i don't know if we
really got into it
yeah so um the ongoing debate in the
field is
what is responsible for residual thc
expression in plants that don't have a
thc synthase gene
yeah why are why are hemp plants popping
hot
and the number one culprit for that is
cbd synthase um whenever people clone
that into yeast and and
run it they tend to get like 20 to 1 23
to one ratios of of cbd hd so the gene
in yeast will make promiscuous thc
um you can alter the ph of those of
those conditions and
even get those genes to make all the
other command points
yeah um in fact there's a there's a
really good presentation i'd recommend
people look at
um it's a can med presentation from this
october from andrew horowitz from
dimitrix demetrix is a synthetic biology
company out of jay keisling's laboratory
and uh jay keising is well known for
cloning a lot of the plant genes
into bacteria and and into yeast this
freaks a lot of people out but there's
actually really good science that you
learn
when you isolate a gene into a model
organism like that
because you can perturb it in isolation
of all the other cannabinoid genes that
are in the cannabis genome you take
one of them out and put it into yeast
and then you can play with the ph and
and
you can play with temperature and all
these other conditions feed it different
precursors and see what happens
and what they did is they fed those
yeast hexanoic acid and they got thcp
so they actually found thcp before
we found it in the plants yeah the
italians discovered it
very recently but if you actually go
through the literature realize no they
were making this in yeast
and they learned that the synthase genes
in cannabis
that we currently have if you feed it
octanoic acid will make thcp
so we don't need to go be looking for a
different thc gene it's
the same gene will fold thcv and thcp
we need to be looking upstream maybe in
the pathway that's that's governing
what makes hexanoic acid and what makes
oxynoid gas
so we're beginning to be able to use
synthetic biology to teach us about the
plant
we did a very similar thing in in this
study in that we took a couple of the
genes
that we saw were related to pathogen
response and we cloned them
into e coli we took a thalma team like
protein
that was amplified in the jamaican lion
genome and also amplified in a couple
samples that we got from colorado seeds
and from minibus
mark jordan's group and those ones
we put into into e coli and once we had
excuse me that cannabis gene getting
synthesized in a coli
we can make gobs of it and then apply it
back
to microbes that we know infect cannabis
like fusarium and aspergillus
and see if that peptide actually kills
those microbes at least in a petri dish
and we demonstrate some of this in the
paper it's not killing uh we don't have
evidence that that the tlps the
thumbnail like proteins are
are killing aspergillus but we do see
that it's retarding the growth of
penicillium species and of pusarium
oxysporum
the next experiment we have running is
grabbing the other gene we found
that was correlated with this resistance
which is a kitenase
uh we have that getting cloned and
expressed nikoi as well and
most of the plant literature shows that
if you combine these two you get a
better a one plus one equals three
effect
and uh you really can knock down um the
microbes once you have both of them
present so we're in the process now of
taking those cannabis genes and just
making gobs of that protein
so we can test out the theory is are
these the proteins that are responsible
for keeping cannabis powdery
are they some of the proteins i should
say not the only ones that are making
cannabis pottery milk resistant
and can we consider those as like a
foliar spray um
there's it's it's one thing to have the
genetics and know how to breed for
resistance with this particular form of
resistance that's very helpful but it
might take time
but there are some jurisdictions
particularly here in massachusetts where
changing your genetics isn't easy
you have to kind of run with the
genetics you put into the seed to cell
tracking system and if you want to add
you've got to go through a lot of
paperwork with the ccc and it's a big
hassle
so some people are kind of locked and
loaded with the mothers they have and
they're looking for
ways to fight off these pathogens with
native peptides from the cannabis plant
not with some foreign molecule that's
going to end up in a vape
yeah and so we're really excited about
that side of the market because we like
the idea of enzymatic
pesticides because enzymes degrade yeah
exactly
and you can you can destroy them and you
can get rid of them so you can use them
in a really ephemeral nature
and they're not going to end up like
microbutanol concentrating into your
vape cartridge
um and we'd rather do this with peptides
that we know are from the cannabis plant
because the consumers are already
consuming those
exactly you don't want to grab something
foreign that might trigger an allergic
reaction we want to grab something that
has been
time tested with human biology for
thousands of years and
if it's come out of cannabis it's
probably been through that ringer before
yeah that's that's super exciting using
using these technologies to think about
different types of pest management and
something that came into my mind
then too is you know we've we've been
talking about pathogens
but what about
genes related in some form or another
to beneficial relationships that the
plant would have
with microorganisms so the thing that
that kind of shocked us that came out of
the paper was if you look at the rna
expression
in the plant the most heavily expressed
genes in the genome are these kite bases
however and they're also the most
differentially expressed genes meaning
that the
the different rna the rna expression is
quite divergent between
tissues but it's completely absent in
the roots
and i think the same was similar with
the tlp so
um why is it not expressing
pathogen response to the roots well we
think that's due to
a lot of the work people have just
demonstrated before us but these
mycorrhizal interactions you might have
in the root systems if you want to
foster mycorrhizal interactions
you you don't start off that handshake
with a toxic kite
right yeah come on in and let me kill
you while you're at it
yeah so that's kind of fascinating
because the roots are not making this
stuff uh and that's probably to have
some type of commensal react you know
relationship with the with um the fungi
they're in the soil
the other thing that was kind of
interesting along those lines is that
that deletion that um
we see so commonly in the type one
plants which is a canava chroming
deletion
uh it's quite present in a lot of the
hemp lines and
many of the the hemp growers are looking
they're working in breeding programs to
cross
and and capture that cannabi chromium
deletion into their hemp line so they
can just
we think that's what's responsible for
the thc levels that you see in type 4
plants
you'll see some type 4 plants out there
that are like a hundred to one
and uh they don't have thc or cbd
synthase so the only the most likely
place that that residual thc is coming
from is probably they can have a
chromium cluster and so people are
looking to just try and get rid of that
yeah particularly if it's already known
to exist in the population we can just
do a couple crosses and get there
but in the process of doing that we have
to pay close attention to those other
four genes that are on that that
deletion that are involved
in pathogen response because that may
alter
you may breed yourself of a really
compliant hemp line that is loaded with
patriarchs and powdery mildew
um and and that's a little bit more
frightening to us actually because the
usda has nothing in the regs for
microbial detection
no no you can have it loaded with
aspergillus
and uh and as long as it's below 0.3
it's cool
uh and that's a bit of a bummer for
those who are used looking at cbd flower
for like a smoking
program i mean there's a lot of success
in people swapping out cbd for tobacco
uh or swapping tobacco for cbd i think
switzerland's been doing a lot of that
work and
yeah uh that's a much safer alternative
as donald tashkin's shown but
um i don't know that i can say that if
it's gonna be
hemp that can be loaded so we need to do
more work there that's still just a
a theory that these genes are missing
when you when you select for cannabi
chromium
deletions um there's a lot more work
that needs to go into proving that those
are in fact more pathogen susceptible we
haven't done that work which
just kind of pointed out the fact that
it's a common deletion people are
probably going to breed for it and it's
going to come with these genes getting
knocked out
but one of those four genes is a gene
that's involved in viral
response and viruses we know are we're
now
starting to be able to detect those uh
with the rna sequencing data that's
not a lot of the laboratories and and
the discovery phase
of cannabis viruses is really just
beginning um there's there's only a few
that have been that have been really
quantitatively nailed
but i think we're going to see 10 more
in the next two years
uh and and that's going to change um you
know how we manage those as well
yeah i feel like i keep seeing um like
every year
since i don't know one or two years ago
i'm starting to see
uh or people are messaging me saying
have you heard of this virus that's been
identified
and sometimes these viruses have very um
cryptic names because they don't have a
name it's um like
i can't remember the name of one
yeah it is yeah exactly yeah those are
in ncbi and i can't
i don't know we made assets for those
we've never found them in cannabis
uh and it's probably just it's very rare
the challenge with our with the viruses
is that uh
they're usually rna-based sometimes they
they're vibroids and they don't even
have a protein shell on them so they're
very susceptible to breakdown
which means it's unlikely they're going
to make it to your laboratory intact
um yeah across state lines and very few
people want to hang out for that
experiment that you know you
they think they have a virus they torch
it they don't yeah and let's put it over
here so you can play with it
it's it's uh it's it's a bit to ask
saying hey can you save that one for me
and ship it across state lines um so
what usually means is you've got to
teach people how to do rna extractions
in the field
so that you can get something that's
converted into dna or is in on
ice and can survive the shipment to a
laboratory and we're just not there yet
as a community we're still getting some
of those tools
out to the masses so that people can do
on-site rna preps but
um the ones that are tightly linked to a
you know
close um university can probably get
those those studies done and we're
starting to see that
i think darkheart nursery did some work
uh looking up the uh
that was a viroid that was a hopslayton
viroid but there was also some excellent
work out of israel looking at a lettuce
chlorosis virus
excuse me that um that was they actually
demonstrated white fly transmission in
that paper
so um the pest management is actually
playing a role because some of these
uh pets are they're actually the vectors
for the disease
um but we we've built uh quantitative
pcr assays for
all three of those for for cannabis
cryptic virus
hops um latent viroid orbits obsolete
and thyroid and then lettuce sclerosis
virus
and we're just in the early stages of
working with people to get them to test
these out so if you know people out
there that are interested in
quantitative pcr tests to monitor that
um we have the tools we just don't have
the grows or the gardens of the places
to deploy them we need to partner with
people to see
exactly how to put those things to use
yeah i think i think it was the hopslate
and viroid that someone asked me about
very recently um and i hadn't
heard about that in the context of
cannabis at all
until they they mentioned it um one
thing
that i was wondering is is there any way
to test a plant sort of generically
to understand if it
um is likely to have a virus regardless
of identifying what that virus is
because i know a lot of cultivators
battle this you know sometimes viruses
appear as like nutrient deficiencies of
very similar symptoms and i
have cultivators that ask me a lot how
do i quickly know whether this is a
nutrient problem
or a viral problem so this is actually
an industry-wide problem that's not
unique um to cannabis viruses
um they don't have necessarily conserved
sequences that we can rely on to
universally capture them and sequence
them so
yeah um if you look at fungi and
bacteria there's tricks that you can
play they yeah
they all have to have ribosomal dna
operons right so you can design primers
that will amplify
all yeast and mold you can design
primers i shouldn't say almost
because there is there is even some
divergence amongst
um primer sites you might pick to try
and amplify all of these things
but um likewise with bacteria usually go
after the 16s region and
and that a single set of primers can
probably get you everything in the
bacterial side of things we don't have
the the analogous um
primer sequences you might target for
viruses that
would be conserved across all of them
they're having this problem with
coronaviruses right now but they have to
engineer new assays for these viruses so
they can spread them around the world
and um the virus mutates a little bit so
they have to have multiple different
primer sites that target
the coronavirus um so what people do in
the case where
they can't use something as fast as qpcr
is they resort to rna sequencing which
just captures
all of the rna that's present uh
sequences that
sometimes they'll try and deplete the
really common
ribosomal sequences that are in the rna
so they get more efficient sequencing
but it's another it's
expensive step um and then they blast
that all through through dna dna
sequencer
and then filter that information for
sequences that look like they're from
the virus
so there's some several viral databases
out there that you can leverage that
will scan your rna sequencing data for
um for virus content but you know that's
that's expensive that's
you know you're talking about hundreds
to thousands of dollars to do studies
like that so it's not something that you
just do on a whim
um and so you find yourself in is the
scenario
of doing lots of tests for individual
viruses of suspect
now um i've not seen tobacco mosaic
virus
ever show up genetically i've seen
people
say they have it due to some pictures
but i've not seen it
actually show up in a test that proves
it was that it's probably something very
related but not exactly tobacco mosaic
virus it's probably
a hops mosaic virus or something yeah um
there's a few of those
that have been listed so uh it does make
for um
a bit more cumbersome of a test how they
handle this in human clinical studies is
they tend to have
uh multiplex tests that look for a panel
of rhinoviruses
uh so they and they maybe they first
scan uh you know 20 or 30 of them with
qpcr
and then depending on what hits they get
they might
they might do uh narrow it down to some
other some other ones so
that's at least what they're doing with
the coronavirus they have a test that
looks at um a handful of cold common
cold viruses
rhinoviruses and norton and neurotype
viruses
and then if they see it's negative for
all of those
they've graduated to maybe a sars or a
coronavirus test so i
will probably see something similar like
that in cannabis as there'll be a
two-step screen
and if you really need to know because
you're it's plaguing your entire grow
you might graduate to doing uh dna
sequencing and rna sequencing to
really figure out this is something
novel that's not never been seen before
and now and you want to crush it that's
that's usually what you do yeah
yeah fascinating i know that's probably
um
yeah i know growers want that
easy sort of detection fix i'm sure it's
disappointing to hear that it's just not
there
um but i i know many growers that have
tried to battle with
what they thought were nutrient
deficiencies for far too long
um trying to battle what would actually
ended up being a virus and
you know just wasted a lot of time and
everything and my response is usually
like if you're really worried about it
just
can you just torch that plant and move
on um
you know rather than wasting so much
energy and time
um and some growers are now getting that
point because their fields are so big
now they're not worried about saving a
single plant or a handful of plants so
they're able to
just cull the ones that seem to be
causing problems and move on
which would be more typical in bigger
forms of agriculture
moving changing gears quite a bit
what are your thoughts on how genomics
research is going to influence cannabis
taxonomy in the future because that's
that's a really muddy area
in general cannabis taxonomy is one of
these things that
nobody i mean even you know botanists
and
um chemists and geneticists it's hard to
get on the same
page on how to classify plants or even
how to define what a species is um but
where do you see that
moving towards in the future so we're in
this weird time
frame where the entire phylogenetic tree
of
life is getting redefined yeah yeah and
so i'm kind of waiting for that dust to
settle before i weigh in because
yeah i mean there's no way to do it
genetically which is if you're 95
identical to this other microbe you're
the same you know genre or the same
species they're trying to make
make metrics like that to begin
calling these and is needed because we
have a lot of redundant nomenclature
even in the microbial
side of things if you try and get
aspergillus species out of atcc or other
cell banks
you'll find that a lot of them haven't
been sequenced before and then you apply
primers to them from the literature
that are supposed to hit them and they
don't and then you sequence this genome
and realize it's not what they told you
yes um so a lot of the stuff has all
been been done with eyeballs
people looking at the morphology and
looking at these things on plates
and of course organisms can express
really bizarre phenotypes i mean
the classic cases is like a caterpillar
and a butterfly right
same genome complete you wouldn't if you
looked at those things you wouldn't call
them the same species
if you look at aspergillus species they
can be just as genetically diverse
uh yet they look identical uh so you
know
the look of the of the species is no
longer trustworthy for classifying them
now
speciation in general usually involves
um whether they can continue to cross
right we have cannabis plants that all
cross with one another so they're
arguably the same species now if you
want to subdivide them into
subspecies indica sativa and all that
that's um
that's great but we we probably need
some paleogenomics to really nail that
um if that's in fact the story that the
indicas came out of one geographic
region and at one point in time um and
the sativas were more equatorial then
maybe
that will bear itself out but right now
they've been so mixed
uh in and inappropriately named during
that mixing process that that
the sativa indica thing doesn't measure
doesn't match up to any of the genetics
right now yeah
um so i i um i usually don't get
involved in a lot of debates and whether
we're going to call these things chemo
bars cultivars or strains i tend to mock
them actually because i
i i i don't find a very productive
conversation when the whole tree is
getting rewritten we can argue over
the taxonomy stuff later i tend to just
read the dna because
that's the answer you're really looking
for what you're looking for
in this categorization is how do these
things differ biochemically
and so chemovar is a great name but it
doesn't right now the king of ours we're
measuring aren't really measuring the
flavonoids so
i i don't view that as a legitimate way
to necessarily
draw the taxonomy um uh but ultimately
it's the heritable units uh that are
that govern the taxonomy that's taxonomy
is dna
and anyone who tries to tell you other
words is going to be proven
horribly wrong in time yeah and now i
think that's
really important to point out i remember
when
in some of my early graduate work
studying mycology how frustrating this
issue was
of learning um
the taxonomy of you know different fungi
and then tomorrow it changes because
just like you said
there'd be some genetic work that's done
and they realize oh these things that
look
identical even under microscopy and
everything they seem
the same spores look the same have same
ornamentation
but they're different genetically and
now we've got to call them something
else so
students everything you learned wipe
your brains like you know
now we're changing uh changing the whole
system and
and even botany too um you know i was i
was a botanist with the uh
the blm for wild bureau of land
management um scouting native
native plants around oregon and
everything and i realized um it had been
a while since i've
gone back and looked at um
you know the scientific names of a lot
of the plants that i worked with and
um so just just a few months ago i went
and looked and saw that
about half of them that i was studying
that had already gone through um
like general changes and that's where
things have already gone through changes
again
and been reclassified um and split and
everything and so it's just a headache
of trying to keep up with all this stuff
um
to give you a sense of the the the wave
of headache that's coming even further
uh there the last study i heard i think
was in the uk they're going to sequence
a million species
right yeah so once that happens
everything that you learn you gotta
rewrite so
yeah yeah and uh it's we see the
aspergillus species are getting renamed
all the time brazilians
got got caught out of uh out of niger so
um
i have no doubt it's gonna happen in
this field but i i've i guess i've been
advising people in cannabis just stay
tuned and be patient because
this is the wrong time i think to fight
over those those terms
because we're just in the earliest
stages of sequencing everything and once
we have a map of like 100
000 different cannabis genomes i think
we'll have a picture and we probably
aren't gonna
try to force that picture into sativa uh
you know indica
antiquity uh we're probably gonna say
okay the autoflowers are over here and
the
right the genotypes that have these
types of clusters are over here and
it'll be named in a coordinate system
that's probably more related to
large segmental uh duplications or
deletions that are related to its
diaspora around the planet
yeah i agree and i think the main thing
you know any listeners that are
banging their heads against the wall
about what how to talk about cannabis
varieties
um you know the main thing is to think
about like
what are you trying to communicate in
the first place and and what do you care
about and that can
sort of drive your vocabulary a little
bit you know if you're
if you're looking at cannabis varieties
and you're trying to understand chemical
differences then talking about
chemotypes and stuff
could be valuable as long as you
understand that that's a
you know a a tool for us to communicate
things not necessarily some hard-coded
taxonomic structure yeah exactly
yeah yeah i think that's important in
general because it's very rare
that science drives to a consensus we
want it to yes yeah
but yeah i mean i think they changed the
definition of the kilogram last year
right they did yeah they did yeah you
know so you're like oh shit
that can change right so that was like
tied to some astronomical unit of
wavelength of light or something i
didn't realize it was ever going to
change but they do and can sense hey
there was a consensus against marijuana
for 80 years it was pretty successful
right yeah and clearly that's in the the
latest stages of changing today so
um yeah i think you're right it's it's
about communication and sometimes the
communication that's most popular is
probably technically wrong
but if your goal is to communicate think
the most amount of people that will
understand what you're saying sometimes
you just use the language that's that
that conveys that most simply i think
that's probably the case with what's
happening with strain no one likes that
name because it's a microbial term
but if you exactly you know if you do a
google trends on strain versus cultivar
or chemovar
there's no one talking about cultivar
chemo bar uh everyone's talking to
continuing to talk about strain so if
you want to effectively communicate to
large audiences sometimes you have to
use those terms um the reason people put
things in latin is because it's a dead
language and the language doesn't change
yeah and so we we don't yet have chemo
bar or cultivar necessarily in
latin i think cultigen might be
technically a combination of
an acronym of latin terms but um it's uh
i think it's all about making sure we
have you know we have communication and
not necessarily hard fixed religion
because
there's one thing we're going to learn
in the next few years is that whatever
we're seeing in this podcast today
will probably be partially mocked as
being wrong yeah in a few years
yeah i mean um two things that come to
mind there i mean one is
uh i've always been a fan of richard
feynman in his work
particularly like as a science educator
yeah i love that guy
yeah he he did a lot of great work for
science education in general much less
you know the physics side of stuff he
worked on but something he
talked about in one of his late books
called the meaning of it all
and he talks about the the problem with
science education
in our culture is that most lay people
expect that's what science does is it
produces facts
and it produces you know in those facts
everyone can
form a consensus around them because
they're facts they are known they're
hard you know
objective truths um but the reality for
people that are
you know actively doing research and
um you know diving into all this stuff
is you realize
there there aren't a lot of hard facts
if any
and consensus is harder than you would
expect depending on what you're trying
to get consensus over
and what richard feynman said is that
ultimately what science does is it
gets at answers to questions it may not
necessarily provide you the hard answer
but it you know gravitates towards the
answer and it's always
moving towards that answer even if it
doesn't quite
get to that very specific hard truth but
when you talk to people uh like for
instance on a political stage and you're
talking about let's say climate change
people want to know people want to know
the facts they don't want to know that
you've got some general idea of where
the science is moving towards and
you know they don't want to hear about
probabilities and confidence intervals
they
you know they just want to know what's
the state of things and what do we need
to do
um so when a politician is willing to
just
assert solid bold you know flat claims
um people resonate with that because
it's a lot easier to digest
than the actual muddiness of science
yeah i know it's very true it's very
true
it gets weaponized often times
i mean my my view on this is they
they only separated the church in the
state so that they could replace the
church with people
in white robes versus black robes yeah
and now the scientists are propped up as
some kind of priest that can read the
code of life
yeah um and everything that comes out of
their mouth is is ironclad truth and
we're going to drive politics off of
that and that's that's nothing could be
further from the truth
really is happening sciences we're
generating questions not answers most of
the time
yeah yeah exactly no that's a that's a
great point it's it is generally about
trying to figure out what are the better
questions to ask
and then that drives what research
you're going to do and and how you're
going to approach a question and
um isaac asimov another um
writer science educator you know even
though he he
wrote a lot of um fiction he had a
a paper that he wrote in response to
someone criticizing a statement he made
about
um you know basically kind of like what
you said just earlier that you know in
10 years everything we're saying now
a large part of it is going to be you
know mocked out and thought of as wrong
he made a statement like that and
someone said well you know if that's the
case then
you know does that mean that um
essentially um a lot of things are
wasted
and that anything could be overturned at
any time and he was like well no no like
what that means is just that our
understanding gets sharper over time and
it feeds off of what came before
it's not that what's going to come after
is going to be totally
you know irrelevant and in total
opposition to the science that's
happening now
it's just going to keep pressing forward
and i think the example he used was like
the um the
spherical nature of the earth and how
you know eventually we learned that it's
not a perfect sphere and that it's
you know sort of like a lemon in a way
you know it has
you know this sort of oblong nature to
it and it even kind of like wiggles and
moves and
um and you know before that it was
assumed that you know the earth was
was flat you're right yeah you know all
these things and so
just pointing that you know these these
aren't total overhauls of what came
before
but their refinements and you know it's
like getting the
uh clarity tuned up even more as
as things go on i think that's important
for people to understand that you know
what we're saying is
not that all this is just getting thrown
out and that you know a lot of
scientists are essentially wasting their
time
but that you know we're all standing on
the shoulders of everyone that's come
before
and people 10 years from now are just
going to have a very different
set of eyes than we have now yeah i mean
that's
to me that's probably the most
compelling um argument i've heard
in this climate debate is that um
the number of ideas that are human
generated tend to be cumulative
like they're they're idea bridging and
so the fact that we had twice the amount
of population back when einstein was
around or or edison
or you know you know pasteur right pick
you know
if you did population control because
you were concerned that we
weren't going to be smart enough to
figure out how to use things more
resourcefully
you would have picked off you know
einstein or
maybe maybe pasture and then where would
the world be if we only had electricity
and not the germ theory of disease right
the fact that we have uh that we had the
population we had back then
uh we are so much more richer and more
um resourceful today
than than we would have been if we
actually choked the population back then
so
yeah i i think it's a really important
it goes back to the concept of humans
not necessarily being a cancer cell on
the planet we're actually part of this
thing we have to learn as much as we can
about it so that we don't
uh we don't unwisely use the resources
that we have but
um ingenuity is um is very important and
i think the evidence is pretty clear if
you look at people's standard of living
and if you look at people's income
they tend to become more environmental
as that goes up over time
a lot of the environmental damage is
done due to poverty and more people are
moving out of poverty than ever before
and so we actually have a really bright
future that you won't hear about in the
political sphere because that's about
selling fear
yeah that we're all going to die
tomorrow from coronavirus and uh
tsunami or something but uh i think uh
i'm very optimistic about the fact that
um the population is going to be fine
that i think we're
science is going to be it's
exponentially building upon itself
and we often underestimate that that
fact i mean
just now we're in the first generation
of people who have access
to all information knowable yeah on
their phone
yeah right school is now irrelevant no
one wants to say that but it is right if
you're
you if you like to read and you're
curious you don't need school you need
your phone
um yeah and no parent wants to say that
to their kid but
uh we didn't have that when we went to
school we had to go to centralized
campuses where all the information was
literally stacked on paper into
in the libraries that in microfiche so
we could comb through this stuff
and be near the people who were smart
who already read it but now we can be
near those people on conversations like
this
and uh and have all the information
that's going to radically change
uh idea generation yeah and and it's
going to radically change
um people's access to capital and the
ability for people to grow and to invent
and to become more resourceful with
uh with the limited amount of resources
we have
um and i think it's really exciting that
cannabis is like emerging from
prohibition during all of this
because yeah we now have probably one of
the most resourceful plants on the
planet
where people have been restricted from
being able to really adequately study it
and now
the gates are open and we can study one
of the best photosynthetic organisms we
have
uh that can literally you know feed the
world with this thing yeah uh
so there's a tremendous amount of
potential i think for solving a lot of
these climate
concerns people have i think just by you
know doing what we do so well with hemp
uh learn this thing figure out its code
figure out how to tweak it figure out
how it interacts best with the
environment and that's going to be a
combination of not its genome but also
the microbes that
are in the soil and the more we can
learn about that we're probably not
going to come to consensus about what it
all means
but as feinbeen is saying we're going to
be pushing ourselves in the arc of being
more and more efficient with what
limited stuff we have here
yeah yeah man yeah that's such a
great summary to bring this whole
conversation back around
um i really appreciate how much time
you've been
willing to spend with me we've been
going for almost an hour and 45 minutes
i have a
a couple a couple of uh closing
questions
for you to to cap us off one is um
what other research interests do you
have beyond
cannabis um i usually like to ask every
every scientist i interview that
question so i'm really interested
in um other pathways that
are in its neighboring plants lately so
i've been looking a lot at
the um and also this concept of xeno
xeno hormesis that
um your your previous guest kevin
spellman will probably have a lot to say
about it but
um so uh hops has a similar pathway that
makes terpenes and
it makes a different set of compounds
that might i would probably call the
analogous medicinal compounds and hops
or the uh
xantho humor okay yeah yeah right and
and those compounds are starting to show
anti-cancer properties much like the
cannabinoids
um we don't know really what receptors
they had and why
but everything that's needed to make
those compounds
uh has some homology to the cannabis
genome
it's possible the cannabis gene could be
making some of those compounds as well
um i don't know if it's going to need to
be crossed into it or how that would how
we
genetically engineer it but it's
something that it makes you turn back
and look at all these other plants that
we've taken for granted
and start to ask but what are the
secondary metabolites in those plants
because yes
the only reason we've paid so much
attention to cannabis is that
one of them has a really easy bio assay
to tell you when you're getting
something right chc
yeah we don't have that in in in hops we
might have beta-carotene which is a cb2
agonist but you
you probably can't really feel that
unless you're in pain and you take a lot
of it
um so all these other compounds that we
can't really perceptually feel
uh we need to go back and look at
because they've been
the the fda system is selecting against
these things yeah
uh in many ways the the regulatory
environment we have here in the united
states
favors um large largely capitalized
companies that can then pay politicians
to limit the regulatory space of the
operators and so the genetics tend to go
through bottlenecks in those
environments
and we end up having massive genetic
shifts because of regulations
um yeah and so i'm i'm somewhat
fascinated about the impact of
regulation on genetic drift because i
think
there's genocides going on all over the
place uh as a result of this this point
three percent thing is going to create a
massive just like
prohibition yeah creating rich type one
genetics
and probably a depletion of a lot of
type threes this point three things
gonna have the opposite effect it's
going to end up meaning
we're going to have to select a very
narrow set of cultivars to move forward
that are compliant with the usda and
it's going to wipe out all types of
diversity we don't know yet
because the those selections arguably
are going to wipe out these other
secondary metabolites no one's measuring
right no one's going to be measuring the
can flavon pathways in the process of
doing these
i mean we are we have sequencing that
looks at that pathway but very few
people
are necessarily going to jump on that
train right away um so the process of
even putting in microbial regulations in
place
this means plants that like and enjoy a
particular microbial background
are going to get eliminated from the
population yeah right let's say you have
the plant that needs trichoderma
tracheoderma is not harmful
yet some of the regulations in some
states don't have
cfu language right colony forming units
they're
in they don't know what the hell they're
counting they're just saying exactly
right it's it's really really um uh
ignorant uh for to think of micro
microbiomes that way
so when you put that in place all of the
plants that can get through regulation
then go through a genetic shift right
you get the selection for plants
that tolerate low microbe environments
well those may not necessarily be the
most productive
plants from a secondary metabolite
standpoint no one's looking at that
they're just looking at maybe thc and
cbd
but all these other flavonoids might be
abolished in the practice of
doing that so i'm kind of curious at
seeing where that's where that's going
but
um the xantho-humel thing in the
xenohermesis is just
this concept that these plants um
are making these secondary metabolites
uh
to communicate to the things that
propagate their genetics
right so uh if you were to actually
look at the number of cannabis cells
and the number of genomes that are
dividing throughout space and time
there's probably a good argument
that it's winning that race compared to
humans that we are propagating more
cannabis dna
right now than human dna yeah because of
the nature of
how big some of these plants can get how
big their genome is the fact that they
replicate every every like you know 12
weeks and humans
don't replicate that quickly um means
that some numbers i've
drawn out suggest that yeah the cannabis
genome has
actually done a remarkable job finding
an ideal pollinator
um that likes to propagate it all over
the world and how to do that it did that
by
being able to make secondary metabolites
that tap into our biochemistry
uh to tell us that changes in the
environment are coming or
or what have you um so this work is all
done by david sinclair he's a guy who
does a lot of work on the fountain of
youth
uh and resveratrol and many of these
compounds that are involved in that
pathway but
he's got a great paper out there um
called xenohermesis
and it talks about how these plants when
the environment changes
they shift the secondary metabolites
they make so that the things that eat
them
their their mtor pathway gets triggered
so that they start going into caloric
restriction because the plants
biochemistry has changed to know that
the environment is going to change and
it's going to have an impact on the
amount of
of material that it can feed the um the
thing that's supposed to procrastinate
so that whole interaction space
i think is the key to cancer and if we
can
understand how those plants are
signaling the metabolism of the things
that propagate their seeds we will
understand cancer in a much better way
and a much more thorough understanding
of cancer because usually cancer
is a scenario of your own genome
having a metabolic defect going on in
the sub population of the cells and that
that metabolism is getting triggered and
it's usually because of an acidic or
you know a different environment a
mutation that's happened uh and the
things that seem to be
having the most potent effect on our um
on our cellular metabolism
are the vegetables and plants the foods
that we eat right
and that's what we need to better
understand to really understand cancer
so
um i kind of like that intersection of
plant metabolites and
cancer uh it kind of touches home for us
and uh
it's uh it's a field that um i think our
myopic focus at the fda
is constantly deteriorating because they
have this
reductionist approach of looking at
single compounds as opposed to
symphonies of them
and we're at a stage now where we we
have the tools to look at symphonies
they just don't fit into their trials
very well
exactly and uh and we need to rethink
whether their trials
are the right way to do medicine i i
happen to think they're not
that you can get a hell of a lot more
power out of a study with a hundred
thousand to a million people connected
via observational trials on digital
equipment like we do with peer-to-peer
networks
and five thousand or ten thousand people
in a trial that is
a sub-sampling of statistics to the
point where you
end up with vioxx like compounds that
escape that process
yeah i mean and not to mention the way
that the clinical trial
system is set up right now it it
creates such a high barrier to entry to
even
try to get to get through that process
you know
yeah it literally kills people and
there's no one willing to look at
the you know the scene in the unseen
here it's like okay the fact that a drug
takes 500 million dollars and you know
10 years to get through
has anyone done a survey and the number
of people that died waiting for that
drop right knowing that it's available
in europe and it's available
other countries have deemed it safe but
not here and those people don't have the
money to travel there
to do it so they sit here they wait and
they die yeah and there's people who
study this and it's a large number of
people every year the independent
institute does a lot of work on this
called um
under fdareview.org it's worth reading
because they go through all the
scenarios where
drugs that were approved in others in
other countries
so they pass you know other countries
criteria and eventually passed here but
three or four years later and they count
the number of deaths that occur because
of this
um and no one's responsible for this no
uh
and the you can't vote them in or out
and i think they regulate now like 25
cents of every dollar
so this is something that is um i'm
totally terrified
that it's going to come into the
cannabis space and somehow um
make the same mess of this space as it
did the opiates that being said there's
a lot of good scientists that work there
that yeah have all the right intentions
and
they are trying to put genetics into all
the programs they're trying to
build blockchains to track all the food
so they they've got all the right
vision i just think they don't recognize
that um
it's too big of a problem for one
centralized organization to solve
uh and it's too prone to regulatory
capture and corruption that
um they shouldn't set up that honeypot
they should somehow
decentralize it and have competing
agencies that can perhaps
invent different ways of regulating
because right it's certainly an
important feature of a marketplace down
regulation but not necessarily in the
way that it's getting done today
yeah and i mean i also find it kind of
funny that
um you know a lot of times uh drug
approvals approvals
get so hung up on needing to prove
a certain level of safety sometimes to
kind of an
absurd extent i mean right now we're
seeing this with cbd right now that
you know what the liver talk stuff yeah
yeah exactly and you know and not
acknowledging the nuance around
you know some of that research and
everything but what's interesting is
that the actual efficacy
of a lot of pharmaceuticals that
actually make it through
the process are not that effective
you know maybe for 20 30 of the target
population they may be effective
um right and and they have terrible
safety profiles
um and so it's i don't know it's a
it's a weird dynamic that the the safety
profile
of a lot of these natural products that
people
want to research and try to understand
how they can be elevated out of the
realm of sort of
you know this alternative medicine
sphere and try to understand like what
they're actually doing and how to
actually you know
legitimize them as medicines it's very
challenging
um even though the safety profiles of a
lot of these things are
pretty well understood by this point
yeah and
the i think the other big hang up
they've got is uh there is this
gold standard um almost religious
consensus as you mentioned before
on double-blind placebo-controlled
trials being the only path to ensuring
safety of medicine and i think that's
being fundamentally challenged by
if you look at the the work on what
governs the placebo effect it starts
pointing back to the endocannabinoid
system
yeah uh and so there's actually papers
out there on on the endo
endocannabinoids is being involved in
the placebo effect and analgesia right
so
how do you put cannabinoid through
double-blind placebo-controlled
trials yeah placebo effect we think is
is
is people's reactions they're they're
ecs their production and anxiety is
caused probably by anandamide or
something that when they take something
they're taking control of their problem
they're they're taking action and that
action gives them confidence and that
boosts their inanimate levels maybe
right
and so the very pathway that you're
trying to
interact with is what's involved in the
placebo process so
i think that's just all going to create
noise and we should be looking at very
large observational studies that
that we can enable now with these
digital tools that we have
uh and that's probably going to give us
a far faster and more i mean
back up and just look at the vape crisis
right right yeah so
this is a cox 2 inhibitor um you know
cbd a lot of people are vaping cbd
sometimes thc
and they both have analgesic effects and
so i throw them into that category
of advil and ibuprofen replacements
maybe even tylenol tylenol is in fact
an endocannabinoid member it makes am404
with a shitty liver metabolism but
so people are vaping these things
probably because they like getting a
little relief from some pain and some
fun
um that took the field probably 10
months to resolve
right because everyone was sharing
information rumor came out of this this
company's making crap this one's got bad
vitamin
acetate ideas are flying and with all of
the networking we have
there's a crisis that was affecting
maybe a thousand to two thousand people
right there was nine million vape pens
sold a month right 90 million
maybe 100 million over the course of the
year and
we only had an incident rate of one and
forty five thousand right effectively
um now there's that that's one piece of
uh arithmetic that's important for how
quick how frequently we sample for these
contaminants in canvas we're not
sampling nearly deep enough to find
a frequency below so even if we were
testing for vitamin e acetate i'd argue
we still would have missed it
because the frequency of of this
creating a problem is so low
that you need to up the sampling rate
you do in the industry to find it but
that being said can roll it back to
vioxx right
vioxx went through probably killed 50
000 people and it took the fda five
years to finally admit they were wrong
right and why is that well because uh
admitting they're wrong after they were
paid a lot of money by the
pharmaceutical energy to
put that drug through is harder to
reverse right it's just it's more
it's more crow to eat than you want and
many people don't realize the fda right
now is governed by the pedufa act in
1992 which
means about half to two-thirds of the
revenue going into the fda comes
directly from the companies
that they regulate right this is
it's a euphemism for bribery um right
yeah
effectively how can that agency with a
straight face
claim that they are out for the consumer
when they're on the payroll of the
people they're regulating
this is going to lead to really bad
decision making even if it has the right
intentions
um and the incentives aren't there when
they make a mistake
they're going to get a bigger budget
yeah you know so
this is this to me is like we don't need
this near cannabis the cannabis
hasn't killed anybody so what does the
the fda
what they've already done to cannabis if
you just look at epidiolex has made it
30 times more expensive yeah
made it an isolate put into strawberry
flavoring
that is registered as a pesticide by the
epa and then added in like super lows
which
like gives people sneakers yeah right
into a worse drug by and and and gw has
to kind of
unfortunately put up with this right and
uw is filled with people who know
yeah yeah know the the extracts are
are more effective but they can't get
something that complicated
through i mean they got sativex through
but they haven't gotten it through not
in the us system
yeah yeah and then it's dvd
right yeah i mean um ethan russo and i
talked about this in our interview and a
little bit off
interview too but you know the fact that
uh they're struggling so much with
sativex and that if sativex does make it
through the us system it's
it might end up being a very different
uh
pharmaceutical altogether than what you
would find in the uk
or um or in spain or um things in canada
too
um and it it it is really interesting
and i i agree i mean i've been following
gw for
pretty much since i knew about you know
knew about them in
i don't know long long time ago in the
early 2000s or something
and um you know i've followed the work
of several of the
different scientists that have come and
gone that have that have
worked with gw and it i agree i mean it
seems like
as far as i can tell they understand the
the best way to actually apply these
medicines
some of the research they've done is
actually highlighted you know that yeah
yeah yeah but they're having to play the
same regulatory games as anyone else and
um you know it's it's so common
especially in the canvas industry for
people to bash
anybody that is perceived as you know a
a dastardly pharmaceutical company
and hey they write the rules they they
got to play by them you're right they
don't blame
sometimes they write rules when they're
really big i don't think gw's at that
scale
no no they're not and that's something i
try to remind people of
you know is one they were doing this
work in other countries initially where
they were able to do things that they
can't
really do here and some of the
products i mean sativex in particular is
actually a very impressive
product when you think about it it's not
i think there's a misconception that
it's isolated thc and cbd but it's not
it's
it's a standardized yeah it's a
standardized extract
yeah and um yeah ethan and i were
talking about
they do actually a really good job
measuring they're measuring things that
the labs are measuring
right i think they're measuring sterols
a host of these other compounds
that we're not seeing in the
dispensaries so they have with hands
down the best manufacturing process for
this
that there is i don't i don't doubt that
one bit yeah but they're getting asked
to make they're
getting asked to point that amazing
scientific engine they have
in the wrong direction right but tell us
what's the active
yes yeah that's all they're all active
right
yeah yeah yeah so it'll be interesting i
mean you know i would love to see in the
united states some
process for getting um herbal medicines
approved as
you know legitimate standardized
medicines and
you know now we have like um
what are they called like medical foods
that you can get prescriptions for that
often are usually just imported from
other countries
but uh the example i always use is like
standardized ginkgo biloba extract that
you can get a prescription for
and it has standardized amounts of you
know certain chemical constituents
um but it didn't go through the you know
it wasn't produced in the u.s
and it it you know it's an interesting
process to even get it to be
um allowed to be used the way it is in
the united states and it's just one of
those things that i think a lot of
people don't realize
that there are alternative ways of
determining what is a medicine and
how to give people um access and that a
lot of countries have do have some
pretty
decent ways of handling herbal medicines
and this isn't a complicated problem to
figure out it's just a bureaucratic and
political problem uh to figure out in
this country
is and unfortunately i think it's that
same process of
um you know politics and bureaucracy
that are forcing these
really odd distinctions between medicine
and food yeah yeah
yeah and uh like recreational versus
medicinal is to me it's like
mind-boggling that that people don't
recognize that
if you do the recreation you won't need
the medicine it's it's
right they're one in the same it's just
when you get into a chronic state of
disequilibrium
you might call it medicine right but
yeah
but that distinction is purely political
uh and it comes i don't know where it
comes from it comes from some hatred of
people getting high
and yeah yet they happily to have you
know bud light commercials all over the
super bowl so
right yeah yeah i don't know it's a yeah
it's a
strange strange uh uh
state of affairs interesting interesting
um
time and and place in history that we
find ourselves um
hopefully it evolves in a uh
in a more favorable direction in the
future um
i i don't i now we've already gone over
two hours
so i'm beyond ecstatic that you've been
willing to talk to me for this long
um i want to give you a final platform
here
um let people know how to learn more
about medicinal genomics also
one thing we didn't even talk about but
is canopedia
so where people can actually explore
some of the
genetic data and even some chemotype
data that medicinal genomics and
and other groups have been bringing
together so i'll just kind of give you a
platform here to let any
any of our listeners know anything that
we haven't covered and where they can
find out more about your work and
everything else
yeah so um medicinal genomics we we make
uh in addition to doing sequencing for
for folks in the industry we make a lot
of tests to look for
different genetics in the plant so thc
and cbd and
xy testing we make assays for um testing
those markers
uh we have markers that look for
fusarium and powdery mildew well
basically all the microbes that might
harm the plant
and also all the regulated microbes so
we sell a lot of
quantitative pcr kits into the into many
of the labs that measure
aspergillus and seminole and e coli and
those things um
so that you can find in medicinal
genomics the sequencing work
uh there's a lot of it put public on a
site called canopedia a lot of people
don't know that we run that site because
of the way it looks
but that's that's a medicinal genomic
site for hosting a lot of this
sequencing data it's serving some
purposes for
for research and also for ip there is a
blockchain component of that
that will etch the time stamps that your
data is generated into a ledger that we
can't control so if we ever
become evil on you you still have your
data recorded somewhere else
um and that's all managed at the
canopedia site and then thirdly we do
run a scientific conference every year
called canmed
so um if you're interested in more of
these topics uh there will be many
people presenting there
um last year we had rafael matulum and
uh he's come most years i think this
year might be a little tight for him
because he's uh
he's getting the age where it's hard to
make that travel from israel but um
uh but other folks of his caliber we try
and bring in and have um
scientific discussion around uh crop
yield um how do you breed for better
crop yield how are we gonna handle
um appellations is one thing that's
coming up that we think is really
important for the cannabis field so we
don't turn into a monocrop in the u.s
yeah
and uh and then we're also hitting
analytical chemistry labs and
and uh and genomics topics so um submit
your abstracts take a look at it it's
usually
this year it's going to be in pasadena
down at um
uh at the pacific convention center i
think it's at the end of september
nice but uh it's usually around uh eight
hundred thousand people
oh nice that's awesome i have to keep my
eye on that see if i can
make my way down there i've i've never
been but i'm also not
i'm not a huge i don't know i i tell
people i'm kind of a
hermit um doing this podcast and
starting to like finally get out in the
world has been a big challenge for me
i've got to like get out of my cave more
but uh trying to make it to more
conferences regularly and canmed's one
that i've
had my eye on a lot just because of the
caliber of people that usually show up
there and and the
the um you know sort of higher level of
discussions it's it's one of
i've wanted to to make it too soft to
try to try to get down there
um well um thank you so much
kevin for for coming on and chatting
about so many topics
i've really really enjoyed it um keep me
updated on any
um big uh moves that you guys make or
any new
um you know publications like this
pre-print that um
you shared with me anything like that
and if anything big comes up and you
want to come back on the podcast
to talk about anything specific just let
me know i'll be happy to have you again
absolutely jason thank you for the time
and keep up the great work i love
hearing these uh podcasts i was i was
running out of things to listen to now
yours is on
oh i view that as a great compliment
thank you so much
yeah all right everybody thanks so much
for tuning in
and and listening once again if you want
to learn more about curious about
cannabis
you can go to cacpodcast.com
or you can find us on social media we're
on instagram facebook and twitter
and we also have a youtube channel now
and when we're able to get videos
of interviews we get those on there and
i've also started doing some
like site reviews and book reviews and
that sort of thing or at least
editing some of the video that'll come
up pretty soon so
check all of that out and as always
please tune in next time
i really appreciate it thanks so much
stay curious and take it easy
[Music]
you