[Music]
well I'm ripe Richard a lot of people
know me from the TV show Bon Appetit and
we're you know I'm a real live resin
enthusiast and we're trying to you know
bring the product that we really believe
in that we think expresses cannabis to
the highest level to as many people as
we possibly can
so they can have that awesome experience
and I'm kind bill and I'm known for
bringing live resin to the market being
the innovator behind the product and
yeah we this group of guys behind
libraries and project had had been with
this this particular product since the
impetus and we've finally been able to
band together under a unified brand and
bring the product to the to the market
so so we're we just launched in
California so we're available in in in
stores right now are our distributions
increasing over time
we're you know in terms of scale where
we're trying to focus on delivering the
absolute highest quality so while we
think we can scale up quality to a large
degree we're always going to be mindful
of that and trying to you know keep it
as as boutique is possible and working
with cultivators that really do
high-level work so that we can respect
that work and deliver a great final
product exactly like the reason that we
chose California as the place to launch
this is the availability of quality
quality start material right and so we
thought we could come out here and
really highlight the work that these
legacy farmers have been putting out and
and also you know what's important to me
and always has been is like access both
patient access and for me farmer access
to to regulation right
so can you talk a little bit about your
manufacturing process and how you're
utilizing the pulse evaders yes yeah go
ahead go ahead
uh-huh so I mean we we try to work
really closely with cultivators because
one of the things that we've noticed in
our time since you know starting this
process and doing this for you know of
quite a long time since 2013 the you
know the the handling process of the
material is super super important and so
one of the things we're trying to work
on is to develop relationships with
cultivators so that we can really help
them the entire way through I mean
honestly from the growing and everything
else even before that but from the point
of harvest there's so many things that
can go wrong with live resin just like
with live with dried product and so
that's been our focus largely it's
finding a really good partners to work
with and then be those that can be
coached into delivering exactly what
we're looking for using your traditional
process can you talk about those yeah so
one thing that we won't do is waver from
how we we do this until we find a better
way right so we're oh we're always
measuring measuring measuring and
looking to improve but we don't go okay
now the scale is this we can take this
step out and that's just not and that's
why we won't really talk about scale
because work will back into demand
correct as we're able to fulfill it
uncompromised but we're still very hyper
focused on a fast harvest meticulously
handling material getting it cold very
quickly and and having we have a process
where we bring the temperature down over
time rather than get immediately frozen
unless a facility is equipped with the
technology and they're there now that
there are now facilities that have
cryogenic tunnels that can freeze this
stuff instantly and make it easy
so is that an expensive process that's
expensive so it's so like larger forms
been afford to do that yeah we're seeing
these in the large light debt greenhouse
operations yeah a lot of the Central
Valley places that have you know
hundreds of thousands of square feet of
greenhouse there they're devoting you
know quarters or half of that
specifically to live resin production so
they have to have cryo tunnels yeah yeah
there's a lot of partners that we're
working with I mean we you know some are
smaller indoor cultivators and some are
you know larger scale mix mix like
greenhouse or pure outdoor so you're
pitting at diversity of genetics as well
right yeah so not you know what gets me
excited right we we want to the goal
here is to have a few things that you
can count on from us all the time we're
gonna always bring an OG we're gonna
always bring something in the orange
spectrum you know we're gonna have a
jack thing but we're also very excited
to see things that you might only see
once or that maybe this guy's we find
somebody that's been growing a plant for
twenty years and that's all they do and
that's really and that's a special
California thing too a lot of the time
yeah we can find somebody has dedicated
their career to one cultivar and then we
put it in this format and open it up to
a new you know user experience yeah I
mean I think part of you know to speak
to Bill's point earlier about just why
California I mean the the diversity of
what's out here and the legacy and the
history and the terroir and everything
that you can speak about is at such a
high level here that you know that
that's really what the live resin
process is for is capturing this
uniqueness and expressing it and
preserving it over time I mean being
able to like a vintner or you know have
something that was really special that
will never be seen again in the history
of the world and to be able to kind of
save it over time and savor it and I
mean it's a really special thing so I
think that's that's what we're trying to
create is something that has that level
of
was like oh like an exceptional year so
we've been talking about this for years
and and yeah we're gonna see that we're
we're gonna see that you know the Sour
Diesel deep chunk off of that hill in in
you know 2019 was the best year that
that we had the right rain and we had
the right everything for that and you
know the califor
sunshine does some special things of
these plants when given the chance so
and we're excited it sounds like this is
a for people with a tightly special
appreciation page but are you going for
the masses like what like this forever
offenses yeah yes so what we found the
coolest thing about live resin right is
a it's like the champagne of the
cannabis world in one way and that it's
like it takes this to its ultimate form
I'm into Japanese materialism right so
everything has its ultimate expression
and perfect form and for me my present
is that for the cannabis plant and
what's different about it then champagne
or a Bordeaux is it super accessible
this stuff tastes so good you don't have
to be a connoisseur to be like wow that
made my mouth feel insane and now
there's like skittle little things
floating around in there and I don't you
know it doesn't take a weed snob to know
that this is a good thing and our
favorite thing is the first time user
that has no cannabis context to see
their face when they tried live resin
it's you know a totally opens them up
and and it's a great way to drop some of
the statements that come around our
products and plant it's just a lot more
interesting and diverse than then ah
then people are given on the surface for
hash going oh yeah yeah and I think like
the the focus on flavor and and that and
aroma and that part of live resin is so
important and I think it's you know two
bills credit it's very forward-thinking
and and it's something that you know
doing doing the show a bong Appetit and
things like that
that was something that I really tried
to emphasize because
the ability you know or the moment when
a chef like smells these things for the
first time it's it's really mind-blowing
for them and I and it's the same with
beverage the same it's perfume same with
any of these other industries and so
it's really you know the diversity of
the cannabis plant cannot be overstated
and it's gonna blow people's minds
throughout all these different
industries to see how this thing can do
and and as an industry we've taken such
care for this plant because of the high
value because of the illegality because
of all these things that we simply do it
at a higher level than beverage people
then a lot of these other people cuz
they they haven't been taking the risk
that somebody like Bill has for you know
being a cultivator since 1987 uh-huh
you know that that's not some real stuff
you know super interesting there really
is a lot of innovation right I mean and
there's a lot of young people too that
are working this
aren't there who are like creating these
sauces and new things I mean it's an
exciting innovative space it really is I
think and I'm into saving this now for
like five or six years maybe even eight
I feel like still cannabis industry it's
akin to like Silicon Valley like 1979
early early and just like there's some
people really on fire and there's a lot
going on but we don't even know how big
it's gonna be
no one knows no one knows how much this
is really gonna affect society at large
you five years ago already am a thick of
things in Colorado if you asked me that
I would be in the situation that I'm in
and have the you know answer to the
board of directors that I answer to and
things like that I would say you're
dreaming and in the most fantastic way
but dreaming and and here we are so it's
a it's an incredible voyage but now this
conversation is leading us in naturally
to the method of consumption of these
products which is also an innovative
area
devices so you know because
traditionally it was kind of difficult
you know it was an expert and a little
skill and not only did you consume it
properly but that's not a mass appeal
you know activities so what are we
seeing in that area it's gonna really
open that's so exciting but the device
manufacturers are really coming quickly
with better and better things and then
some of the larger producers are leaning
on them for device like it's significant
a little back story so I've been making
hash since the late 80s at a high
quality level but I didn't decide that
and I loved hash in all its forms but I
didn't go oh this is the format that I'm
going forward with until the nail came
because there was now a good way to
smoke it that changed my life first a
bond a nail I was like okay now there's
a good way to do this I'm gonna focus in
and then the next thing that happened
was the whipped texture came and now the
stuff wasn't so messy because
traditional hash oil and a little 15
years ago was uh was a hot mess and you
know when I was 18 I had my best
friend's mom hand me a jar of hash and
she was like I know you gave this to him
and he's destroying my house with it
take it back
so device has always been the thing that
opened the next segment up and it
happened with the nail and it happened
with the pan it happened with the cart
and now we're going back to some cooler
more partible portable water filter
devices and I think that that's
important from a health standpoint
what is the what is the best experiment
so I get the best experience on a piece
of glass filtered through water and and
and simply because I have control of
that whole experience I have controlled
the amount of water I have controlled
the temperature of both water and the
glass and the it's easy to clean and
that's for me I'm very comfortable with
all of those things but I come from like
a glassblowing background and so a torch
isn't a foreign thing to me the torch is
prohibited though obviously for no
people for new people right so some
people may get their best experience
hitting a pen because they don't have
any baggage to go through yeah
so I mean we have all the textures like
you know butter shattered crystally and
all the things that people make but are
my favorites butter but we also have yes
yeah we're we're leading with butter and
cuz and we're gonna make more butter
than any of those other things because
that's what we really like and we think
that it's the best user experience and
again for more of an intro consumer
they're able to utilize that product
easier there's less mess it doesn't
slide off your dabber you get it all
there's there's a lot of reason you get
a consistent experience every time
you're not getting a big rock or just
terpene sauce or whatever so I think you
know we're leading with that but our
live resin pan is really special we
think because we you know we do a
process that does zero separation zero
distillate
it's a categorically different thing
than most of what's on the market and
you know my favorite thing in the
morning is to have a coffee and to sip
on my Skywalker og pen because it's such
a wonderful pairing and it hits that
note because I'm high all day right like
I smoked all day and so all I'm looking
for is flavor flavor flavor flavor so
having you know if I had five different
flavors as bill mentioned if I can like
Oh
I want some haze with this I want to
moji with this like that's powerful to
me I mean we're gonna have some some you
know recurring kind of hitters that we
want to keep in the stable like the
Skywalker og I think we're gonna have
that pretty regular yeah so we are
thinking about those things but I'm
hyper focused on fresh shuttin available
right so what's good right now what can
we get that's the best thing right now
and there's a value piece to like what
are we going to be able to give at the
best value for for the quality so we're
we're hypersensitive about right yeah
yeah right so because we found great
partners that have large quantities of
some of some things that are exceptional
that we can get at a value price we can
afford to buy some crazy expensive
things that are rare and one price at
all which is cool you know and we would
like people to only pay one thing but
give them a very degree of rarity and
and complexity yeah and I think you know
in general the raw concentrates will be
more leaning into the variability and
the small-batch aspect of things whereas
like you know the the pen where we're
looking to hit you know maybe slightly
larger distribution numbers with that
product and and you know as you
mentioned like it's less form factor
inhibitive so more people will access
that product than whatever body rock
concentrates so you know we're trying to
give people an authentic rock
concentrate experience in an easy format
and and I think I think that it'll it'll
do pretty well you know
but you're also man
I mean I feel like the markets got a lot
of room in it yeah honestly there's no
pie for everybody out here people who
love weed in California right so we love
California weed everywhere once that
happens all right so I try not to get
hemmed up on that stuff I always go back
to like what's the best thing okay we're
gonna make the best thing we're gonna
tell people that we have it and my
career's history shows that that's the
end of it you make the best thing that
you can you put out a product that you
can truly be passionate and believe in
like you see I'm excited about this
stuff I believe in it I've never sold
anything that I wouldn't buy and that
carries true right into the market and
that all takes care of itself then if
you stay true to what brought you here
and and we we've gone on a long road
right yeah we just keep giving the best
thing that we're able and make it
accessible yeah you you you you respect
the plan you respect the work of the
people that grow the plant you you honor
those relationships you honor what this
plant does for the world and how it can
change things and you just think about
that at every step so that sounds great
no you guys need and it's true but
you're also in a reality out there so
there's all of these people in between
you and and your PC you know who were
handling the product marketing selling
you know
that they're in control you know as much
as they are really important to because
people are you know touching your brain
so you know yeah obviously we're looking
for the right partners on the retail
side 100% and and we're looking for
people that can get excited you know one
of Rhys very strong suits is actually
like budtender education and
point-of-sale interaction and we provide
all of that type of support and so when
we get into a store we're not gonna just
drop product to the store we're gonna
interact with their bud tenders on a
high level and get them excited about it
that's who sells this product marketing
doesn't like gets it out there but who
sells weed our bad bud tenders and if
they like your product and you are easy
to deal with that part is it is you know
and we hyper focus on that on the people
that have the customer facing 100%
taking care of them and making sure they
are educated and well supportive and and
people I think I think customers and
people working within the industry
largely because a lot of them are new to
the industry are starving for education
it's it's it's something that the
importance cannot be overstated of of
like getting people grounded in what
cannabis is how it works why things are
good why things are different and and
it's it's a really it's a you know
seeing this happen all across the
country and all across the world now and
seeing and seeing the exponential growth
of it it also needs exponential growth
of Education and support and and real
support and not wool pulling because
there's a lot of that too
you know you both in your own way or
educate you know and have experience
doing that what were you gonna be doing
I talked a little bit about what your
roles are and what where you where you
see your energies going so I mean I I
think that I'm you know I've been doing
a lot of like product work recently and
you know trying to like get these things
out to market but I think I'm gonna be
transitioning more into like content
creation because again I I think the
importance of education is is real and
making education palatable so that
people don't even necessarily have to
seek it out where they get educated via
entertainment via things like bong
Appetit
I think I think there's an importance
there and so what I want to do is is
focus on that bring bring high
functioning people in from other
industries to increase their
understanding of cannabis and to you
know get to the point where we can truly
truly collaborate because what's
happening now is people are coming from
those industries into the cannabis
industry but then there's still kind of
a fence in between for no good reason
actually been out for quite a while so
you talked about like product
development so easier so is live resin
like the foundation of frog this is like
our you know Jack Daniels you know it's
never been exchanged but we're but
there's the next generations of fraud
onset that were coming up with is that
what we're talking about here so within
this brand of live resin project I'd
like to think of this as like the
beginning of the champagne industry or
cognac cognac like we've found a very
specific way to honor all of the special
traits of this plant and I'd like to
really build on that tradition and turn
it into something that's an honored
process that can carry on and I'm not
closed at all to new different ways of
experiencing this plant
in this format we're gonna hone how we
harvest and we're gonna always be open
to new technologies but there are some
core things about it that I'm unwilling
to change and I would like that to be
kind of the center of this brand is is
that we're putting a stake in the ground
and saying that you know this is the
beginning of something that people are
gonna enjoy for hopefully generations
and eons and we want it to be honored in
the way that that craft things are you
know and and and like I said before I
think that this is the pinnacle of
expression for our plan yeah yeah yeah
so I mean I I think one of the things
that we're trying to be conscious of and
one of the the reasons that it's called
libraries and project actually is
because it's it's it's an ongoing
process of figuring out you know how to
do the thing that we know how to do
incremental II better every day and then
also how to think about you know new
ways of modifying things to improve
environmental conditions you know things
like oxidation there's a lot of small
tweaks you can make and the storage of
the product the you know air exposures
throughout the entire process there's
there's a whole lot of headway that can
be made there that you know we're just
getting to the point now where we can
really start playing with that stuff
because we have a really sound base
after you know doing this since 2013
this particular process so they need
before that making hash and growing
cannabis and everything else I think we
you know we're now getting to the point
where you know technology coming from
other industries like micro
encapsulation and particle shearing and
all this stuff is going to have
applications with this but you know to
Bill's point like the purity of what the
library experience offers I don't think
will change all that much it will it
will it will improve and we'll figure
out better ways to deliver it to store
it to harvest all those things but the
core of it is so powerful because what
we're doing is very very high level
essential oil extraction higher level
than the perfume industry is doing and
that and that's categorical we've heard
that from the highest levels in the
perfume industry
so we're based in Oakland
and you have a lab up in operating 5:7
type 7 getting a degree stuff that had a
shift so and and as you know you know we
have all the pertinent toys and proper
freezer storage and really good
relationships with manufacturers and as
to your earlier question there's an
education piece for me obviously and I
educate well market face but I actually
spend more of my education internally
investors all the people that just need
to understand this on a higher level
architects engineers whoever it is that
inspectors state regulators global fire
chief yeah whoever it is that we're
talking to him to make the thing happen
but then the one of the reasons that I
chose to go this route was was I really
want to put a lien on on on the
equipment side there isn't a machine for
making this library so it's an adapted
process on somebody's equipment and
there's where there's some leaps to be
made all the way small in a bunch of
little places to build the device that's
designed to make this happen
yeah yeah no it was a super manual
process and then he made it less manual
into Tony freezer AdBlue River is
they're doing the exact same thing and
and so there's there's a lot of I think
I think that's where you'll see the
innovation I completely agree with Bill
there is that you know the actual
process and the actual equipment at both
for consumption and for production I
think is where we're gonna see a lot of
the the biggest shifts forward there's
gonna be more times fat in me or in
being equipment both running other
people's equipment and we're gonna build
a machine
honestly that like with my fabrication
background and all of this it only makes
sense that we make the machine that'll
do this correctly you will definitely
see me out promoting my resin project
yeah and you know I'll get you're gonna
see us on the East Coast soon enough
we're here in California but we're gonna
will pop up in Massachusetts hopefully
q1 yeah I mean you know there's there's
you know there's some states where
there's no solvent extraction and so
like we're just not really gonna play
there there's other states where there's
you know legacy markets where people
love hash where they're very familiar
with live president and they have
$10,000 rigs and everything else just
like California so we're we're super
excited about those markets and we think
that you know places like like Illinois
and you know Florida once they change
some of the regulations I mean it's
crazy yeah 100 percent 100 percent take
it home yeah
just thank you Tom it's always a
pleasure yeah