she's been working with Korean natural
farming and we're dealing more and more
with pathogens and pests on our cannabis
and on our vegetation with environmental
stresses that we're all feeling from the
external world so I'd love for you Wendy
to talk about some KNF practices that
can help us specifically to pass some
pathogens on our cannabis plants so
really the basis of a good pest
management plan actually starts with
scouting which as I've integrated more
and more with a lot of cultivators
across the United States I've realized
that most people don't actually really
know how to Scout properly one thing
that we discovered was that even though
we were scouting our cannabis plants
pretty well for the most part we weren't
scouting our companion plants so the
clover that you mentioned while it is
amazing and awesome is also a wonderful
banker for thrips
and those thrips will move from your
clover up into the canopy of your
cannabis so all of a sudden knows like
we have thrips in our cannabis where did
these come from and I look down at the
clover and it was like covered so
learning how to scout properly which
means that you're going to different
parts of your garden each time ideally
daily if you're gonna really you know do
it but at least every week and check
different plants you want to check your
top your middle inside and look at
different areas you want to get a really
good scope that you can actually see
things like russet mites because what
happens with our pests is that in
general we have outbreaks and at that
point it becomes very very hard to
manage them so you know preventative is
always best but you know how do you make
sure you manage an infestation before it
really gets bad because preventing is
not possible like we're talking about
nature right nature finds a way so what
we discovered this year is that it's
actually I mean I again I think pretty
much all of us could talk for like an
hour on each of these but so figure out
how to scout scout well start their
Korean natural farming really builds
theirs I've been talking a lot this
weekend about an 8020 principle so if
you do one thing and you do it well it's
take care of 80% of your problems and
with Korean natural farming what we've
found is that the pest pressure is
incredibly mitigated just on the basis
of having a very fungal e dominant soil
so using indigenous microorganisms get
your fungal dominance way up there
ten to one thirty to one super high
levels if you can and keep building it
throughout the years then your press
your pest pressure will be reduced more
and more and more that being said we
still do have bugs it's gonna happen you
know you're gonna get a bad cut from
somebody somebody's gonna come over to
visit your farm from their farm and you
know they're gonna look at a plant and
bam you've got something so what we did
was we reached out to a wide variety of
people we had some hemp farmers in
Colorado I had some farmers up in
Washington and Oregon and myself and we
all started trialing out jedem solutions
which is basically the son of KNF and
found extremely high success rates
somewhat I was talking to yesterday uses
the same regiment that we did and also
said it was highly successful in like
pretty much eradicating Russert mites if
it's on our farm the only place that we
had them really bad was the one little
area that we weren't doing anything on
which is a new field so already our you
know bacterial the dominance is too high
we had huge pest pressures over there
but we used genomicists Ellucian which
you can make yourself cost pennies per
gallon it's extremely cheap it's very
effective because the way that it
creates a wettable sulfur is not using a
liming process which is what these with
the industrial industrial wettable
powders which make your pest can can can
get resistant to the sulfur itself so it
ceases to be effective in long-term
solutions
you use it you can use it any time we
use it preventatively once a month we
did have an outbreak of what did we have
this year yeah we had some aphids but
those don't they're not they're really
not that difficult to deal with if
you're in a greenhouse it's different
but if you're in a greenhouse you can
cover it and heat it up really well for
us we had a we have a lot of natural
beneficial predators that come in and
kind of take care of the aphids for the
most part with the exception of the one
new garden which those plants were just
weak pests go to weak plants they
actually sense it they'll send out
signals the more bugs will come in so
the Janome sulfur is great to use
preventatively and it's great to use you
can use it every single day in the
evening an hour before sunset
you can if anybody's interested there's
the book it's a genomic it's the orange
one and he takes you through the only
thing I will say with this is that he
doesn't tell you anything about
protective gear so make sure you have a
mask respirator glasses the whole nine
yards
Saddam wetting agent is another one it's
a soap I use it for dish soap we use it
for hand soap we use it as our wedding
agent for our plants so you if you do
the dom sulfur the Jas you do the Janome
wetting agent and then if you
incorporate JHS Joe Dom herbal solution
which you can make out of a variety of
things the Jerusalem artichoke was
highly effective the ginkgo is highly
effective
apparently oleander is highly effective
I'm not gonna go there because oleander
is really poisonous and I don't really
want that on my medicine so and we don't
I don't know there's just something
about I don't want to do but you can try
it and then we also kind of went outside
the box and we did a california bay
laurel JHS which was really effective as
well and so basically the whole group of
us what we all came back with was that
JWA and Jas alone worked really well to
mitigate pest pressures adding JHS to
that regimen as well got almost complete
eradication and that was against Russert
mites a fits
spider mites oh that's what we had with
spider mites
my violas of all things and thrips
somebody had in Washington I'm missing
something there's another pest that we
all get that's tiny broad mites thank
you yes and broad mites and across the
board this trio of solutions was
extremely effective and it's extremely
cheap you can make it all yourself it's
super easy and it's awesome