[Music]
rinsing with spring water allows for
cultivation of a diversity of local
indigenous airborne bacteria to settle
attracted to the starch or sugar in the
rice rinse this rice rinse will set out
of direct sunlight covered in a
permeable lid for approximately three to
five days depending on conditions
a tuning one's nose to the sweetness and
slight sour of lab or lacto acid
bacteria by smelling this rice wash
daily will allow you to hone your skills
at harvesting at just the right time
because conditions such as humidity and
temperature and locality to find the
condition of culture within this method
becoming a practice lab maker is
essential
[Music]
it truly is a good time to be allowed
this is a time for its friendliness to
be discovered and down the rabbit hole
we go lab is an arrow tolerant anaerobic
bacteria it's found in milk and
decomposing plants is used funded li
implementations it's a major player in
our own biome and as is our plant
cousins helps us the tablet and
nutrients and maintain a healthy immune
system so let's make some lab what
you'll need milk jar and your inoculated
rice water now it's important your
choices in milk you can use organic you
can use any kind of bill if you want
more of the lab solution choose a milk
that's low in fat if you want to use the
fat and what's left over from making the
lab into cheeses then use as high a
quality of milk as you choose
[Music]
pour your inoculated rice water into
your larger jar first supporting the
milk has the action of stirring for at 1
to 10 ratio using your hand and
measuring helps you to develop the
hand-eye coordination to achieve
consistency in future intuitive
measuring
[Music]
using a 1/3 airspace is a principle
applied to light ferments and
inoculations within KNF or Korean
natural farming you are in essence
creating a microclimate of proportional
humidity and temperature conducive to
the reproduction of your inoculations
than the extraction capacity of your
light permits a clear separation between
curd and whey indicates a good
collection test with your nose that the
aroma is still evocative of living
organisms in this case tart or a
slightly acidic with floral overtones
each collection will vary slightly
according to place time and conditions
an inherent diversity within your
environment
[Music]
scrape any discolored surface off the
top of the curd and gently break it up
with either a spatula or a slotted spoon
for lifting out of the jar
[Music]
that is effective in making big size
fruits and leaves if you use too much
sweetness will drop so in the case of
fruit use less love in the later stages
and add WCA at one to a thousand and SW
at one to thirty WCA is water soluble
calcium and SW s sea water both are KNF
applications and if you'd like to know
more visit our website see me on
instagram at la-la grows and subscribe
to my youtube channel so here at Lala we
use about 1/4 teaspoon minimum twice a
day but remember it's also in our foods
we use about a cup in our baths we use
it to clean clothes clean floors so
really you know play just play
[Music]
join us in April for the next video
release we're gonna be talking about
Lala's balls Bokashi balls or coin in a
lab fattier lab fabulous visit our
website let us know what you're up to
maybe we can help you amplify see you
here