Kurian natural farming a regenerative
practice I'm Christina Trout of Lala
Gardens
first there was thistle to understand
thistle I need to tell you about a
reoccurring dream I had as a child
involving a centipede weirdly the scene
of the crime was in a white bathroom in
a white bathtub in my attempts to kill
the centipede it break into half and
grow and those halves would break into
halves and grow until the bathroom was
literally full of centipedes terrifying
this is how I've used this'll this'll
arrived after I done everything on my
property I thought a good permaculture
should do
I'd already tilled too late for
preserving the existing fungal
communities in this soil but I knew
enough by the end of my training that if
I could keep the soil covered that
diversity would return so I got to work
building layers of cardboard woodchips
leaves not to mention the literal dump
truck loads of composted manure why did
I feel like I needed to do all of this I
have rock-hard clay soils the most used
tool in my bucket of garden tools is an
ice pick more than a decade later
I have soils that are still prone to
compaction but there are clumps now
aggregates with clay and organic matter
riddled with worm tunnels and I can grow
a lot of things I couldn't then so
success and then that this'll fast in
succession after the bindweed
I created a haven for these unruly
misfits who moved in quickly and with
great determination we're well versed in
the problems of these invasive cousins
what happens when we try to chop or
poison thistle it splits into two three
four and each surviving piece starts to
grow more vigorously than had you left
it alone chemical solutions seem the
only option for meeting the challenges
of these successional plants whose sole
duty is to populate and return to the
earth in mass in an attempt to heal the
original damage done from disruption
including tilling I also knew enough to
recognize that with so much effort
applied in creating an environment of
would love they simply were not showing
up even over a period of time bringing
spore back from my mushroom hunts and
dispersing it into the microclimates I'd
created specifically for them I'd get an
occasional burst of chip loving species
a few puff balls but what thrived in my
soils were mustards and lettuces
radicchio and brassicas what do these
species have in common their bacterial
loving species I had created bacterial
dominant nitrogen rich soils and was
helping succession happen in a big way
because successional plans like ragweed
and thistle love bacterial dominant
soils succession happens rather than
seeing this is a natural law to be
respected and encouraged agricultural
science backed products and practices
have us attempting to halt a reverse
succession of the fixity attitude soils
are to be amended and weeds controlled
succession happens from bacterial to
fungal dominance it's Naturals way of
self-correcting building soils to
support even more evolving complex
ecosystems fungal dominant soils perform
in amazing ways including water
retention disruption of pathogens
absorption of toxins pH balancing
providing plants with a network of
nutrients eking populations whose sole
function is to provide plants with
everything that plant asks for fungal
dominant soils are literally the
probiotic for the soil and direct
relationship with the probiotics within
our own bodies the very ones which
secure our longevity youthfulness and
vitality without probiotics we can't
derive the nutrients we need we are
plants and plants are us without legs
without mobility plants have evolved
within their micro regions to work with
the microorganisms in the soil to
provide all it needs the micro organisms
in turn derive their nutrients from clay
and rock the dance of soil building
between plant and microbe problem is
we've been taught as cultivators to
treat the plant rather than the
conditions under which it is grown
to stave off problems we front-load our
soils with everything we think a plant
needs over its lifecycle rather than
equip it with avenues to find what it
needs through relationships with the
indigenous life in the soil even
disrupting the soils in order to give
the plant a head start and it's supposed
battle with nature we anticipate what
needs to be fixed in an unbalanced
system I had no idea how to fix my
thistle problem I decided to do nothing
literally I quit spraying I encouraged
the plants which decided to stay
clipped seed heads of those I didn't
want and said in a course of
naturalizing without understanding what
or could happen I first learned about
Korean natural farming or KNF as it
became first practiced in small circles
of cannabis growers in California in the
Pacific Northwest who raved about KNF
living soils and amazing results and
down the rabbit hole I went I didn't
follow directions I came at it with a
fixed attitude endless ideas for how to
improve the system having experimented
with fermentation and derivations I
thought I understood what I was
gathering from the misinformation
prevalent online I made huge mistakes
and yet the cannabis I grew was of such
an extraordinary quality that I knew I
had to learn the system I couldn't
believe the qualitative difference and
not only flavor terpene expression but
in medicinal quality It was as if the
plant was expressing a part of herself
that hadn't been possible before
introducing even a fraction of diversity
that would later prove to me the power
of indigenous microorganisms true to
place in time I first learned the
fundamentals of Korean natural farming
from Chris Trump whose family owns an
800-acre macadamia farm in Hawaii where
his practice of natural farming
literally saved their farm Chris learned
directly from master Chao making the
trek to Korea 11 times in 2011 Chris and
his family applied KNF to a few trees
moving to a 50 acre trial of trees where
finally his family farm is now a hundred
percent K&amp;F and thriving chris teaches
all over the world and there's no end to
the benefit of learning this teaching
hands-on
Master Choa who began practicing natural
farming in the 60s devoted his life to
teaching even though he faced
persecution from chemical company
lobbyists and government officials for
his teaching in practice Master Choa in
turn recognizes three teachers from his
early visits to Japan one taught him
respect for all life from another he
learned about enzymes and indigenous
microorganisms or IMO his third teacher
may who made the first kyoho cultivars
in Japan which are grapes the size of a
baby's fist teaching show the nutritive
cycle of plants and the importance of
observing natural law what is some a
revolutionary about master chose life
work in Korean natural farming is that
it works it works in any environment at
any time using the plants found thriving
in your area it teaches one to speak the
language of plants through simple
observation of the plants nutritive
cycle much like a human cycle doctor
chose simple technology is a sane
response to conventional agriculture
which is ecologically not sustainable
economically also not viable and
environmentally ruinous plant sciences
practice now is more concerned with
unlocking the secrets of how things work
in an effort to fix a broken system then
on observation of how life actually
works to not only self correct but
thrive industrial agriculture backed by
plant science views natural systems
through the same inherited fix-it lens
and it teaches us to do the same
a fixit's inori applied to my problem
clay soils required all my fix-it
approaches ultimately defeating me I was
left hacking thistle in soil with an ice
pick with no perceivable end in fact
that thistle was filling the spaces I
was spraying with roundup even though I
was fully aware of the implications
helpless a crisis of imagination with
nature's imbalances too big a problem to
fix it took me a year after Chris's
class to begin practice in my outdoor
gardens
I made the applications and continued to
apply them in my indoor smaller garden
gaining confidence in my skills of
making and applying applications I was
still entertaining the fix-it
tality subtly thinking of ways to
improve the system coming to terms with
my rebellious nature the paradigm shift
occurred with my first successful
harvest of indigenous micro organisms
building a box making the rice choosing
a spot 500 feet in elevation above but
within my microclimate that's fungal and
lush planting the rice field box in
place for seven days or so returning and
unwrapping the gift of that place and
such a fuzzy display of diversity
filling my nose with the aroma of a
primordial forest floor intoxicating
what natural farming requires is a
willingness to practice in order to see
in order to come into a greater
understanding of how nature works and to
trust the process
natural farming requires us to view
nature as perfect not as a static thing
but is a perfect working system of
balancing it requires us to become
citizen scientist basing our findings on
side-by-side trials in order to observe
the outcomes of our practices learn
exactly how our inputs of supporting the
natural system and a plant's drive to
express its genetic potential we learn
to talk to plants our education
concerning the growth of plants must
include the awareness that a plant has
everything it needs to thrive in concert
with indigenous micro organisms plants
have the capacity to build soil from
rock in healthy fungal balanced soil
plants an expression of true health and
vitality signaled to us an ecosystem in
a state of regenerative abundance
regenerative is not isolating plant
compounds as weapons against insects
viruses or pathogens regenerative is not
bugs in a jug microbes isolated and
grown at a lab nor microbes brought from
far-off places it is not plastic mulch
it is not tilling regenerative systems
are discovered through simple
observational skills regenerative
systems restore our Kapow
city for wonder for imagination for
discovery so what is the practice of
natural farming at the heart of natural
farming lies a process of cultivating
indigenous micro organisms through a
simple but precise method of harvesting
without disruption of any ecosystem
introducing this diversity into our
disrupted soils where it comes into
balance with what's there building and
restoring a robust biodiversity at the
same time that these IMO populations are
being introduced other applications are
applied to our cultivated plants through
foliar or soil drenches which directly
support a plant's communication with
this environment there are various
applications derived from plant
materials which will populate your
shelves a library of applications needed
over the course of a growing season
according to the nutritive cycle of the
plant natural farming in essence is the
application of the right material the
right amount at the right time it is
simple but specific these applications
are applied at ratios one to a thousand
or one to five hundred or one to three
hundred Zara homeopathic in nature so
while the gathering of materials
requires attention throughout the season
a small amount of the applications
you've gathered go a long way in a
relatively free and cost natural farming
is effective in any place any climate
any condition and by its simplicity of
application entirely scalable and highly
economical cultivation becomes
stewardship with such restorative
practices and as one becomes proficient
in gathering and applying these
plant-based applications
side-by-side trials are incorporated as
a means to observe directly how varying
applications work to increase vitality
and to enhance whole system functioning
if science is more inclusive of an
observational approach within whole
system's intent on compiling shareable
data through these simple side-by-side
trials then we could chart through
observation in what ways nature is a
perfect system and much more efficient
it's solving the same problems we were
trying to solve through derivative based
fix-it solutions namely food security
and a thriving ecosystem
rather than unlocking secrets if our
attention as a scientific and academic
community were on understanding the
relationship between things plant to
soil animal to human human to the
ecological hole we would naturally come
into harmony as stewards equipped with
wisdom born of practice long live the
natural farmer about thistle one of the
KF applications requires the cultivation
of the top four inches of plant material
at dawn science supports this magicians
approach growth tips of plants are
populated with undifferentiated cells
these cells are potent with possibility
in response to a host of environmental
conditions these cells can literally
literally do and become anything all the
materials required to present including
hormones and enzymes necessary for
growth it's these compounds were drawing
out with the sugar which has a drawing
effect much like salt this will is one
of the plants I now harvest for this
application its growth pattern is
unmatched the mineral content impressive
- its medicine for parasites and humans
and anti pathogenic in nature by
increasing the vigor and growth of my
hemp this year in part through the
application of thistle I was able to use
my hemp crop to control the understory
of this will from emerging it's still
present but I'm no longer cutting it in
an attempt to kill it it's become an
indicator of soil health and a marker of
the successional state of my garden I
know to mulch and inoculate to harvest
and respect through deep appreciation
what nature is trying to show me
you