[Music]
city of Los Angeles can't even get their
original pre-ics license properly we're
all struggling to meet a deadline in
August to have our annual licenses and
you that's just waiting for the you know
the Department of cannabis regulations
in Los Angeles once it goes from Los
Angeles kicks it up I think the state's
a little bit more ready to accept it but
because everything's based on a
municipality and where that's going
that's where there's just a big tangle I
know there's been a lot of
investigations for politicians taking
money under the table trying to direct
licenses into different people's hands
you know there's a lot of dirty money I
think we're seeing that all over the
country where politicians are not doing
the right thing and everyone wanted to
say oh here's this social equity program
and everyone's got a chance and I'm so
sorry about your injustice that happened
to you and same thing happened to me I
was arrested in 2012 why am i any
different in the amount that I went
through and what I lost
why is my social injustice any different
than someone else's I mean that's not
fair well your your pre-ics so it's not
even relevant to you yeah because I
could go back and get more licenses and
I can put put them under my name and I
would be my social equity partner yeah I
would love to be partners with me I've
been partners with me in cannabis for
over 12 years so I make an excellent
cannabis partner but okay so specific so
you're you're still operating with a
temporary license right now we still
operate with a temporary license we
actually submitted to put in our annual
license with the DCR believe last April
this past April a few weeks ago it's
still in a process I wouldn't see them
doing anything with that application
before July 1st maybe they said 60 days
and then they wanted another 30 days and
then that license gets kicked up to the
state our state license was extended out
to August right now
so as we get to that August deadline in
2019 the steadily they'll have to issue
another temp or the city will actually
do stuff in will actually start to get
go through the licensing process and are
all the pre IC o---- people in LA kind
of in the same boat as you every once in
the same way there's no permanent
license of admission to anyone in city
of Los Angeles and so when you all sit
down and talk shop on this topic what's
kind of the it's laughable it's really
laughable it's embarrassing it's
laughable you would think that with the
amount of knowledge that sits in a room
because Herb Wesson is also president of
City Council her Westman him his office
and his staff have been so with the
doors opened for everyone and us to come
in and talk about problems and how the
ordinance needs to be crafted and
changed and things of that for it's open
doors is that they've been like that you
do run in still to the council people
that put a roadblock up and instead of
seeing where the positivity and how
things could grow and the tax revenues
that everyone is so busy trying to go
after being able to collect those tax
revenues for the benefit of the
communities I mean everyone's already
trying to reallocate where the tax
revenues go that are better derived from
cannabis I mean Gavin Newsom was on the
news last week saying he'd like to take
the legal cannabis revenues and pay for
diapers I mean and you know how many
places do you want to take you know you
squeeze a turnip you can't get only get
so much blood out of something but
specific to LA so first of all how many
pre ICO shops are there who are waiting
to get everyone no one's got a permanent
I believe it's about note JP about 135 I
believe there's not a live process no
and think about everyone said the reason
that they license to the pre-ics was
because we had the experience we had the
paperwork in order we had everything
together so those applications were
probably the easiest to source some of
them may be missing certain documents
that you had to go back just because of
an attrition overtime or moving
raids and everything that we were thrown
at us for all these years
documents got lost but they've made
exceptions for them what's holding up
this the Department of what cannabis
regulations in Los Angeles I really have
no clue though two times I've visited
down there to pick something up or or
get a pass or give us admit some
paperwork no one was there I literally
sat in a lobby it was like an empty
office it's it's it's I guess if the
sometimes you need to get a business
person in a room when you're trying to
organize like an industry because it is
a business so that you have some kind of
leadership direction on that it's not
always just a policy driven thing and
still got to have the nuts and bolts in
the engine to make the car drive right
so what's the worst case scenario that
they don't get their act together and
the worst case scenario if they don't
extend the temporary licensing so I the
city the city and the state if they
don't extend that out if they can't
process their paperwork on time they're
gonna have to make another band-aid and
California seems just like that's their
favorite thing to do let's have another
band-aid well it's not work worried
about traffic and infrastructure and
things like that let's just knock it out
and take care of 18 months three years
we'll figure it out in five years what
we messed up then and that's such a
crazy way I mean they're a businessman
builds business from the foundation and
you have grassroots and you really build
a foundation that's part of why the pre
I cos I've been in the position they are
I've had Koreatown collective since 2008
you don't think I have a big foundation
and people really respect and come back
to us because we explain the medicines
we explain to them what's going to
happen where we try to help them with
their experience we really question to
ask what is it that you're looking to
treat everyone was talking about adult
use in recreational most of those adult
use recreational patients really needed
cannabis and they're really giving up
some of their other pharmaceutical drugs
the whole part of where we were supposed
to be going with prop 64 was education
and knowledge and
powering the people to be able to make
better decisions so that they would have
easy exposure and easy access to
cannabis so that they're like to improve
their lives and all they're doing is
making it harder and harder with the
taxes that are come on it's basically a
sin tax a person that needed cannabis to
survive every day so they weren't on
painkillers or opiates or taking other
kinds of drugs they can't afford their
cannabis anymore by the time you tax it
they can go find a guy in the street and
go get it from their guy and not pay the
taxes but we don't see the support from
the policymakers and the government to
try to get rid of that and to get rid of
the a little shops and uh and illegal
guys so taking into account the
traditional heat like real patients like
the little old lady arthritis people
with cancer
what are those cuz you know them
personally what are those people telling
you specifically they come to our store
they come to us right in there they've
got tears in our eyes because we can't
even give them free stuff anymore
we can't even pass along the samples yes
I'm fortunate because some of the
companies I do will leave me samples
behind in there they'll do them at a
discounted price whatever and then we
discount them to our patients so whether
they come in and they get something in a
regular size I can give them another
size for a dollar we've tried to come
around those things my partner and I we
kind of circumvented the whole THC
process drew a line in the sand and
opened a tee a CBD store two doors down
called the antidote because so many
people that have a stigma about THC or
cannabis and didn't know what it was
well now they can come get some pain
relief and get different types of things
and have no worries about having a
psychoactive effect of what's going on
but actually get that cannabinoid into
their system tell balance and regulate
their system so it seems like from a
retail operational standpoint that CBD
business has a lot is a lot more
unencumbered to just be a retail their
CBD the CBD store it's like back to my
hope again where I used to spend my time
in k-town and we were vertically
integrated and we
we literally took our clone to cut our
clones and we grew them all the way out
we grew them all the way out so that
whether it turned you you left with
flower in a jar or you had an edible or
you had a concentrate and we were
vertically integrated that's what I
recreated going back into CBD world do I
know I got to move fast
yes we created a skincare company
there's no one else in the space like
what we have right now do I know to run
fast and go fast and get it out there
and market it and brand it yes I do do I
think the regulations will be there in
three to five years a hundred percent
but the good news is is that I'm coming
from THC world so I know I already know
the rules and regulations so all the
testing and all those little things
you're supposed to be doing along the
way we're already doing in CBD world is
it more fun in CBD world yes I can't
think I'm not dealing with the bullshit
I have three to five years to not deal
with the bullshit I'm sure I'm sure the
government wants us to figure out how to
get their piece of that market as well
I'm not sure how they're gonna do it I'm
not sure how they're gonna track and
trace the THC because we've been in
place to track and trace every single
thing and they still don't have their
metric system ready to go and I'm not
going to be their first guinea pig
there's obviously a lot of talk about
the unlicensed retail shops really I
don't really see them as much but you
know I'm on my same path every day I
know that the LAPD is hard at work and
kudos to them because they actually
understand the cannabis industry in Los
Angeles better than anyone else they've
gone from our worst nightmare and our
enemies to our biggest supporters I mean
I can tell you the one to my district
have been amazing and supportive of me I
think that they have every right to go
in and shut them down they've now they
can work with the power company so they
go in they just cut the power first and
then they're like they take everything
but the unlicensed
are not your personal biggest pain point
as a business operator I don't I don't
feel the pain from those those shops I
think it's unfair because they're not
paying the taxes that's very unfair but
there's so much unfair in this world
like I can't tackle that that's really
LAPD and the city has to do that and
they're not going to get anything
straightened
that's this whole thing when everyone
wanted to just legalize cannabis they
didn't like think about maybe we should
fix the system we had first so we'd have
some infrastructure to build on and then
go forward but everyone was such a know
her E and government wanted the tax
revenues and they ended up shooting
themselves in the foot are you going to
be doing delivery yes we are we're
setting it up we're first launching our
delivery we're going to partner with
someone and it'll be like top tier stuff
so they can get a lot larger amounts and
then we'll roll out right behind that
we'll roll that where you can get
deliveries from k-town Direct and that's
where your brands that's where your
loyalty that's where all 12 years of
everything I've done in my community
will make me different than everyone
else because people will trust what I
put in them back also on-site
consumption when they finally approve it
for us we would go next door we're next
door to hookah bar so we've already
spoken to because you know it's like
five places on one lot so we've already
spoken and because I ended up being the
mayor of my community block I just like
said you have this in that you know they
don't run the hookah lounge really in
the daytime I said you got this part I
got my part and shook hands and just
wait for the licenses to come out for
the city of Los Angeles which I don't
think will be anytime soon 2020 No
I don't know even though I'll have an
annual license by 20 times that day
something I'm sorry but Los Angeles is
your biggest market it's got the most
people it's really embarrassing it's I I
think that we need to fix the things
we're doing before we start creating
more stuff yes I'm on the board of
glocca and SEC the Southern California
that's Adam Spikers group he's great
he's I will tell you and this is you can
quote me on the this if you're that's
still running
Adam Spiker really has done more to
bring cannabis in the cannabis industry
not just the dispensary owners which are
still like there and that's why I'm on
the board but the manufacturers the
cultivators and the politicians together
better than anyone else and I've been
part of the Calaca since 2008 I'm on
their board now and although we were
ordinance and things like that you
always had so much internal fighting
within the industry and this industry is
not gonna survive if it doesn't come
together and act as a community it's its
own village and Los Angeles really needs
to get their act together because so
much is being lost from California Los
Angeles because of the revenues I mean
how do you not have these businesses up
and running in downtown LA already I
mean all that income would be coming in
there all those employees would be
spending money in those local stores
they would still be to the gas stations
there to the little grocery stores to
all the food shops to all the food
trucks I mean it's crazy like and I will
tell you that Ron galperin who's the
City Comptroller he gets it and he's
probably done more behind the scenes to
get the engine going than anyone else
there I mean her blessings been there
but he has his own motives as well but I
think pure motives Ron galperin is like
a great he's been a great advocate for
the cannabis movement could you talk to
a minute about Blanca
and because you you you've been involved
with him for a long time right
so um and I've been really interested
for a long time and so I've been writing
about in covering the different groups
since 20 just 2015 but even since then a
lot has happened what's keeping blocker
together and what is it doing now I mean
I'll be honest it's really a framework
the people that the board members or the
winterly holding it together there was a
division that happened and when we
finished after they did prop D and
everyone had come together there were
some compromises made that shouldn't
have been made back in 2013 I believe it
was it was when we voted prop D and
there was a split there was there were
some splits that were made and there was
another group that ucba and they split
over here and then you had your old
traditional Galactica members over here
glocca came about and started to embrace
more of the industry in the village and
taking a look at things item by item
you couldn't just throw everything into
a basket you can't just arbitrarily say
no one else can have a delivery license
that's not the way we live in the United
States of America no matter what so you
still have certain principles that you
have to uphold
but the glocca became more to try to
involve themselves we became part of the
SCC which was at of Spikers group ucba
still operates over here by themselves I
don't have any issues whatever because I
always lived in Milan hula-hoop so I can
go to them and talk to them I understand
what they're trying to do but also there
are a lot of them are micro licenses so
they have their own brands that they're
trying to do they're cutting their nose
off to spite their face because who's
going to take their brand outside their
own little hula-hoop and what's the
purpose it's it's not going to work so
Adam has been like a real big spearhead
of trying to work together but there's
so much backstabbing and people don't
realize that you can't a lot more flies
with honey than you do vinegar that it's
it's the right thing so Glock is like
kind of holds on a lot of us did going
to the SCC
so we're there and very supportive I
came onto the board at SCC because I was
supposed to represent the dispensary
owners and try to get everyone to
understand like if she there's a reason
why she's doing this and giving my time
and I kind of like fallen off sometimes
had some personal stuff going on in my
own life and then I'm like no Adamson so
much if I can help him