so the county has had a ban on
commercial cannabis businesses for about
ten years that prohibition was recently
extended to give us time to develop
regulation so the board has directed us
to go out and develop regulations but
the board also wanted us to maintain a
status quo so that you know we don't
have any changes in what's going on
until they see the package and a prison
okay so there's a wrinkle in federal law
cannabis is an illegal controlled
substance under federal law so it's
still criminalized to sell to sell
cannabis even if you're in compliance
with your state and local regulatory
system so there are some things in place
at the federal level that have have the
DOJ hands-off at the moment we don't
know what the new administration will do
in terms of changing those those
guidance documents so this creates a lot
of uncertainty for the cannabis industry
and we may have cannabis industry
participants here tonight or aware of
this the primary one of the primary
issues besides being afraid to get
arrested is that they don't you know
businesses don't have access to standard
financial services that other businesses
could use like they can't take debit
cards they can't take credit cards
it's expensive to get a bank account a
lot of businesses can't afford a bank
account so there's a lot of cash in
these transactions that creates
opportunities for crime and from our
perspective as regulators they creates
opportunities for people to not report
how much money they're earning more
background so I mentioned this the board
of supervisors did direct the
preparation of cannabis regulations for
unincorporated County lats and uary
they gave us some of they gave us some
objectives to reach
so that's maximizing the transition from
unlicensed business activity to a
regulated marketplace essentially to you
know go from a largely unregulated space
to a regulated space it sounds easier
than it is
avoid blight and prevent over
concentration there is a worry that with
the location of businesses you could
actually end up with too many in one
place that could cause
either blight or overexposure or some
unintended consequences the board wants
us to address principles of equitable
development that includes equity and
licensing and also includes other
equitable development principles like
making sure certain communities don't
quote bear the burden of legalization
which could happen they are focused on
environmental sustainability measures so
we're taking a look at for example
cultivators who use a lot of electricity
we're taking a look at those rules to
see where can we conserve on electricity
and make sure we're conscientious and
how we're using resources and address
the issue of youth access and exposure
to Canada so it's one of the board's
goals to ensure that youth usage does
not increase that is a primary goal of
almost every regulatory system for
cannabis in the country and we are going
to talk about that today at one of the
tables
okay so community voices matters now let
me just explain what we're doing
usually the county will draft
regulations and then publish them for 60
days and people will come down to the
Board of Supervisors and they'll yell
they'll scream they will not have been
notified and the county gets defensive
we react we make some changes we're
trying to avoid that process for this
because this is so new and so different
and so dynamic and changing all the time
the board has asked us to go to the
public first get the feedback and then
develop regulations that are responsive
to the feedback so that's why this isn't
your traditional Town Hall because we
don't have answers for you yet we want
to hear what you say before we put pen
to paper on any of the regulation so
what you say tonight will be documented
will become part of a report we have 18
of these listening sessions everything
will become part of a report that will
be public that the board can consider
when looking at what to adopt or
unincorporated area so as Joe mentioned
18 different sessions you all are
kicking off the very first one and we're
going to be having these through August
12th so they'll be taking place in
evenings and also on Saturday mornings
all around all of the five supervisorial
districts and there are six particular
traffic areas around which we're going
to have the same kinds of facilitated
small group discussions and recorded
answers so that we can feed all of this
back into a report that's going to be
used to help to make recommendations
that will ultimately lead to regulation
so these are the six topic areas and our
six table are broken out along these
deep topic areas so who have you access
to exposure to cannabis that's one table
and the discussion for that table is
going to be guided by everybody have a
copy of your information packet you all
got the same information so everybody
here should have a packet that has six
different cheeps in it the quadfather
the six different areas except you we
give you something else we'll get you
others whether there's more fudge there
are a couple of discussion topics for
each of the different areas as well as
some background information and you'll
get a little bit of time when we move to
your tables that you want to start with
to sort of go over what the background
information is and then on the back you
will see that there are questions that
your facilitator will ask you to give
answers to those are what I'm going to
know part of the recommendations that go
forward to the supervisors there's one
of these for each of the areas so we're
shift Annabeth's business was located
with the location tables great that's
yellow cultivation who's our cultivation
tables green excellent right up here
taxation and revenue the money people
money and spending all right pink and
then equity and economic development is
in the back the blue table and finally
other concerns we recognized
that there may be some topics that you
want to express questions comments
concerns about that don't follow easily
increase other five areas there is going
to be a facilitated discussion and also
reported answers at that table so do
know that there is a place to go if
these are not the topics you want to
talk about so how this is going to work
we are going to in just a moment have
you break and first so through whatever
table you feel like you want to talk at
first there's going to be four different
periods of time 25 minute allocation for
used to talk so that means you won't be
able to necessarily go to all of those
discussion topics for 25 minutes you'll
have to sort of govern your own time and
maybe leave one conversation and go to
another but we have designed that so
that you will be able to have
facilitated discussions for four of
these topic areas at 25 minutes each
we're going to let you know when it's
time to move to the next topic area
first we're going to have a big song and
then we thought that might be able to
disrupt itself there'll be something a
little less intrusive like from somebody
going through to the table letting your
facilitators know that it's time to I do
want to ask everyone to honor the ground
rules for participating in table tops
there on the back of your agenda which
is the very first page of your packet
with a nice icon here basically we're
just asking people to keep your comments
brief respect one another not everybody
here will agree but respects one another
screen silence your cellphone's stay
focused and try not to talk over one
another because we definitely want to
capture what it is that you're saying so
we need to have talking one at a time
we're asking you to follow these and
when it's time to move to a new
discussion we don't need to go over
deeper games but just bear in mind these
are the rules that we're asking people
to abide by so the whole
I recognize that your facilitator is
there to help encourage conversation to
get your feedback into an improv new
regulations and they're not subject
matter experts if you have a question
about something that is technical along
the lines with what Joe raised earlier
there are question cogs here in the
middle of every table you can write it
down and raise it up there will be
people from the office of cannabis
management and perhaps others county
staff too who will be wandering through
and can answer those questions along the
way
yes comments will be reported for public
reports but no comments will be
attributed which is what we said before
so in general do you all feel like you
understand how this is going to flow yes
okay this is an experiment
y'all have a very close group we're
trying and risk so we'll see how well it
works and then we'll adapt it for future
sessions believe me so what I'm going to
ask you to do right now is to if you
don't want to stay at the table where
you are understanding that in 25 minutes
you'll be able to rotate to another one
now the time in a minute