hi everybody my name is Ruben honig I'm
the executive director of the LA
cannabis task force thank you all for
coming out tonight and thank you Jackie
for putting this on I'm going to give
you a very quick and passion speech with
less Smiles today because we are in a
dire situation right now in the city of
Los
Angeles the city proposed regulations
about two weeks ago and their
fundamental the fundamental structure of
those regulations are based upon a
certificate of compliance for businesses
with limited immunity and without
getting into deep detail into that that
is not a business permit it's not a
license and it's really vilifying the
industry and treating us like criminals
still so I ask that everybody on
Thursday comes out to probably the most
important hearing I know there have been
so many hearings in the city of La but
on Thursday there's a planning meeting
hearing it's at 10 to 12:00 a.m. in room
10:10 at City Hall the task force is
going to be there we're mobilizing all
organizations are going to be there
we're mobilizing everybody to come out
to that meeting and we have to pack that
room and tell the city council that we
must be licensed and permitted
we will not settle for anything less and
they have to move on this I don't care
if they hide behind the City attorney I
don't care who drafted what it's now
time that we're treated like legitimate
business people and that's all I really
want to talk about tonight