[Music]
Los Angeles County is by far the most
populous county in the entire nation and
that's being a factor in now cannabis
regulations and estates we're a third of
the population is just in this one
County it's something that is concerning
in general to make sure that we have
proper regulations going forward so that
it's something that can sync up with how
Northern California has been doing since
they've done well on putting their
regulations forward that Southern
California specifically Los Angeles does
it properly and in a way that would not
destabilize a regulated market within
Los Angeles what you have is you have a
population of about 10 million people
but it comes in through 89 different
jurisdictions and because state laws are
set up in a way that you have to have a
dual license to be a legal cannabis
operator obviously need to have one on
state but also your legal city so within
the County of Los Angeles the challenges
come in in that you could literally have
89 different sets of regulations for
people to operate legally my
organization and those have been
supporting this stuff to trying to get
the regulations done within the county
have been working on this for the past
two years now and a lot of progress has
really been made over the past year it's
an interesting contrast to look and see
because now we've hit this one-year
threshold or the second year in general
and you can look back and you can see
such a drastic contrast of how the
progress has been on the way so for
instance last year of February 2017 the
Board of Supervisors issued their first
motion towards exploring a regulated
cannabis market and it was a motion that
was very basic threw out a little bit of
Zoning what to kind of SPECT they staked
the flag in the ground at that time to
not allow for agricultural land to be
used which is a little silly considering
what the product is that we're dealing
with here it also becomes more
concerning because the vast majority of
the unincorporated areas within the
county are agricultural land some quick
statistics on that again
the unincorporated areas of the county
make up 65% of the entire landmass area
of LA County and within that about 40%
of that is agricultural land but they
put their first recommendations out
there to start exploring this but within
the same breath they also had one of the
supervisors had introduced a thought to
spend 25 million dollars to eradicate
all existing operators so it was a it
was a to face kind of thing it's like
let's look into this thing but let's
also get rid of the people which doesn't
really seem to jive with what the spirit
of props 64 is you know the intent is to
give these people a way of transition
exactly and that was in it's interesting
mention that because that was really the
ultimate goal the supervisors had stated
they said that there's a goal behind
this is to maximize a transition of an
illicit Reggae of an illicit market into
a regulated market so when they're
stating that the policies don't seem to
really support what their goal is on
that what you're looking at now and so a
year ago they wanted to spend that money
fast-forwarding a little bit we
certainly did a good job to fight back
against them spending that twenty five
million dollars so they did not have the
funds to come after the operators
because you know we just showed that it
did not seem to make sense for them to
do such a strict enforcement on them
prior to having real regulations in
there now you see
last week February now 2018 a year later
that the discussion is evolved with them
over time we've been able to host
expungement clinics and so on and so
forth that now the counties actually put
in a motion saying that they are
directing several different various
departments from the DEA to sheriff's
you name it to start coming together to
actually have a unified system that
could potentially just automatically
send out people who have previous
cannabis convictions and expungements
they would just get a letter in the mail
saying your record no longer exists and
that's incredible in contrast to think
that you know literally almost a year
ago to date they went from let's spend
25 million dollars to go after them to
now it's hey let's actually help them
out and get rid of this stuff on here so
LA County you know the the overall
discussion has evolved and they
understand the importance behind that
better than they certainly did a year
ago
doesn't though necessarily mean that
they understand everything that they are
is in there and so there's still plenty
of room to figure out what there is on
that one of the things that was achieved
last year is that the Board of
Supervisors through the Office of
cannabis management had set up a what
they call an advisory working group and
the Advisory working group was made up
of seventeen individuals with various
backgrounds from doctors on the academic
- you know literal medical doctors those
were pro cannabis and those were against
cannabis and the intent of it was to
have this group come together and write
a set of recommendations that the board
of supervisors would be basing their
recommended regulations for cannabis in
the county it was a very interesting
process it took several months with us
meeting weekly on that different topics
every time that we met you know to
mention on that you know I was part of
that process there if for a
recommendation to be made it had to have
reached consensus amongst all the
members within a committee so that meant
that those that were either for or
against it had to find language that
would be comfortable for both sides that
would ultimately promote a responsible
policy within the realm of regulations
here and it was interesting to see this
whole process coming forward on that
essentially what was two sides they've
come together to come up and make these
lists of regulations and coincidentally
we had 64 of them and I say
coincidentally because you know all this
passed with prop 64 and it certainly
wasn't you know our intent to do that
way but this list you know turned out to
be a 300 page reports that was meant to
guide the supervisors on saying okay
these are the next steps we take now
that we've done this this is how we want
to roll out regulations since that time
the Board of Supervisors have now had
you know that report was published in
October of 2017 and they've had now
several months to look at it study it
and consider it and they just recently
have now proposed their first draft
regulations and it's concerning to us in
general because they're their set of
regulations have come out and they
literally have 12 regulate 12
recommendations is what they're looking
at right now
is a 64 that we made and the discussions
that we have in there we're discovering
more and more while the topic is
certainly very multi-layered and complex
we're learning that they have not taken
perhaps the sincerest efforts needed to
study everything that we put out there
as well as other materials on them so
for instance there is a report that
comes in from the office of canvas
management that states that the current
market right now of the existing
operators is at a level of about 77 or
so so within the unincorporated areas
you have about 77 of these existing
retail operators they don't specify what
they're for delivery and they say that
it is in general they can't really
determine how many they have for all the
other types of from cultivation
manufacturing and so on but they have
this number out there and it contrasts
directly and they do point this out in
the report it contrasts directly the
recommendation that they've put out
there saying that they only want to
allow 20 retail licenses for the entire
county and that to us is an immediate
red flag because it sets up potentially
one of the largest illicit markets in
the largest county in the nation in
general and it's it's setting up people
to essentially be recriminate
on something that we're trying to give
them a pathway out of you know what was
in the past thing my father and and it's
it's an odd contrast again because here
we are last week the board passing the
expungement directive to get that
automated and and it seems to fit in
line with the spirit of prop 64 was and
yet at the same time the policies are
now just showing it's like okay we want
to get this taken care of at the same
time the possible just would lead them
right back to being recriminate again so
just sticking on in this is retail
you're saying from their deduction they
believe they're about seventy-seven
operators but they want to have 20 which
implies that they want to shut down 57
of them well yeah and and you know it's
it's an interesting thing it's a
discussion we have so one of the
recommendations we made is that they
need to provide for a pathway for the
existing operators so the intent is to
try to get rid of the illicit market and
encourage responsible operators to come
a regulated market but at the same time
there is a the supervisors level there
is a two paths of this discussion one is
what do we do about existing operators
and the other one is how large should
the market be and they're not
necessarily the same thing so we're
trying to showcase them saying that your
own report states that the market is at
least 77 operators big and that's
strictly on the medical side you know so
we don't know what the adult use side
could certainly grow that on there and
and and where that's illicit market
certainly comes in from that stuff is
because like you mentioned on that
that's if you're gonna just look at
those and they could transition let's
say no one else applies on that that's
immediately 50 some odd operators that
you know become illicit or have to stay
illicit it's not like something magical
that they're just gonna say we're gonna
figure out another way to feed our
families say as long as each of these
operators meets whatever the criteria is
for receiving a permit or retail that if
they go through that process each of
them could make the transition that's in
it is partly on that end what it comes
down to is now timing issue so the board
had originally intended to address this
on December 19th of 2017 and here we are
now pushing almost into March and it
will likely be March before they see
this issue for the first time it could
be longer than that so what was
originally intended that they would
start accepting license applications in
June of 2018
it seems like it will probably towards
the later end of 2018 maybe even early
2019 the applications start so what do
we do in the meantime of nearly a year
where you still have an illicit market
with operators are there that are
waiting to transition they would do it
yesterday gladly if the system was set
up they have they have I mean it's very
hard for them to understand what is the
best way to go forward on this by the
letterer law they it's been confusing so
prior to 2018 you could have operators
were technically States compliant under
prop 215 laws but locally they were not
compliant because the county had just
bandits now after the passing of 2018 in
our legal cannabis Mart
it it becomes more murky as to what that
gray area is yes we still have this
collective model that is recognized by
safe for the year but it really still
defaults by local law as to that's
something they can operate on my mom
so with these operators here they're
their intent and their desires obviously
come into this regulated market but with
no pathway they're existing for them the
only opportunity they have or thought
that they have is either to shut down
which is not an easy thing to do when
you have families to feed and not just
theirs but employees and so on or or to
continue operating with the threat of
potentially getting enforced against
we've seen that their intent is to
regulate and they want to have a
regulated market where we have concerns
as how quickly they do so the advantage
of them taking a little slower approach
on this is that they get to learn from
the mistakes of other jurisdictions so
city or light for instance has certain
things that they had perhaps
opportunities to do better on this is
where the county will hopefully not
repeat those same mistakes that doesn't
mean that they won't invent and create
their own mistakes as well - in the
process so the timing is what the issue
is coming down to on that and when we
have our discussions with the board on
that we know with their staff it's
concerning to us - where we bring up
saying hey here's this limit of 20
that's being recommended and we're
talking about the 77 to 77 that's in
their own report that came from the
county doing this and their response
list is saying where'd you get this
number 77 so you know when they're not
having the time needed I guess or
whatever they're not dedicating that to
to actually read their own reports and
study them to contrast and see what is
the right policy that's very much a
concern however you know we we
appreciate that they want to do the slow
rollout because they want to be
responsible and thoughtful on how they
do it the slow roll off cannot be done
in such a way that it just hurts people
in the process as well - so I know that
they want to do it slower so they can
kind of protect and have public you know
safety and health and me know involved
in all this but if it just hurts other
people that have been doing something
for I ever feeding their families and
they have no other way to go that's not
gonna work by there but you know like
you know the thing the other aspect of
all this stuff that's concerning is
let's say that they were just gonna
start with the 20 we would be okay with
that because they want to do a rollout
on that we'd be ok with that if there
was a reasonable time rate for the
rollouts their recommended time rate
right now is three years so essentially
they're saying we would give only 20
licenses for a population that is
equal to the fourth-largest city in the
state and that those 30 20 licenses
would only be there for the next three
years and at that point we'll reevaluate
and see where it goes it would issue the
20 licenses quickly but then they put a
moratorium on additional licenses for at
least three years
correct correct and and it's
disingenuous because these zoning that
they're currently proposing on that many
of the larger swaths of land that they
want to absolutely have no
infrastructure in them and all so
there's no sewage no power no anything
to go with that by time you get
permitting anything on that it could
likely take up to three years for an
operate to actually be up and running so
all the money all the funds that goes in
there that does nothing to go back to
their primary goal of transitioning this
market there's nothing gonna be there
these guys are gonna have to eat list it
running and illicit our market for that
to survive in one chain
[Music]