[Music]
the current recommendation on
cultivation is to restrict it to
artificial light growth only so they are
not allowing outdoor cultivation they
are not allowing mixed use within
greenhouses in any way shape or form and
for whatever reason they're not allowing
any type of licensed cannabis activity
on agricultural land so everything has
to be indoor it's a little silly because
within the committee we had we had an
operator come out good operator come out
and kind of tell us you know we got to
see how they run their indoor operation
and the indoor operation what we learned
are some facts on that the indoor
operation was about an 11,000
square-foot grow and we got some
statistics and data behind where it was
for their power usage on that because we
have concerns around this is gonna be an
eco-friendly thing so on to say nothing
about just taxing the grid in general
here what they ended up sharing with us
is that they did the math behind it and
said that for their 11,000 square foot
row if they were to transition to a
solar panel setup so they could be just
off the grid that way it would take them
the equivalent of 5 acres of solar
panels to power that on there and that
just makes absolutely no sense in any
way shape or form because part of what
the county is recommending is to use
renewable and renewable energy for that
but if you're gonna have to do it in a
warehouse location which is probably in
some populated city area on that where
you possibly gonna be able to get that
kind of square footage to say nothing of
the fact where does actually cost to set
that up so they want to force everything
to read industrial areas and it's a
little silly of a thought on that
because they want to see that as a way
of controlling the market and yet
historically the market went into the
industrial into the warehouse is a way
of hiding from all this stuff in there
and you know we had the chief of the
fire department who said that from a
safety point of view he preferred that
cultivation actually be done outside and
so we have all these other departments
are seeing the stuff in there and you
the directive has still remained to not
allow for any outdoor agricultural use
the Kappas they currently have right now
is it's 20 for retail 20 for delivery
and it's 10 for everything else so 10
cultivation 10 manufacturing and tab and
10 lab testing and 10 distribution and
again it's ridiculous for the population
size on that that doesn't add up
indoor capita 10 and then today do they
have a square footage cap like those 10
can in aggregate no no the the it's it's
just 10 licenses so with it's a 10
license and it's it's ridiculous all
around so let's say on that cap and that
cap would include whether their license
at a full acre well let's say it's in
door so you can only 220 220 2500 right
that's max license that you can get on
that correct okay so you have that max
so it could be a max of those or it
could be a max at only the 5,000
square-foot level you know and so that's
all in there and furthermore to go into
stuff there is intent and the county
wants to form a 15 person panel for
equity to discuss a discuss as equity
here their intent is not to they want to
set aside a percentage of licenses that
will go towards equity yeah certainly
certainly well I mean equity means a
variety of things what has been
historically so far in the topic let's
say city of Los Angeles seems to define
it as giving an opportunity for
ownership for a license to some of those
been previously affected by the war on
drugs mean they have a criminal record
or anything on that so should someone
been affected by having a cannabis
conviction and could not have
participated in the market or now they
actually get a leg up to participate in
a market by getting a license they'll be
reserved for them
in the county I'm I'm happy to see the
counties looking at a little bit more
we're at they want a wider lens on what
equity means it doesn't specifically
only mean you know ownership it could be
health stuff it could be other things
going forward there one of them we want
to see the county do is actually effect
a policy that would say that any county
employee could not get fired if they
tested positive for cannabis use so
that's kind of stuff that we want to see
a wider lens on equity for there but
within the specific model of you know
licences that would be given towards an
equity app you know applicants on there
they want to set aside a percentage so
if the percentage is let's say 20
percent they're matching that with a
panel that putting together of 15 people
so this whole panel they want to put
together 15 people to give let's say 20
percent of 10 licenses so that doesn't
seem to make any sense as to the
resource they would put behind something
and have such a low cap on their going
forward it seemed very disingenuous for
that is but the the issue again on the
cap being on there it's just from the
committee's point of view we address
that one of the recommendations we made
which the county has not seemed to have
taken into consideration yet is that we
said don't we wanted them to consider
alternatives to a cap and the
alternatives that we recommended is
because the county has so many different
communities some that may not want this
at all and others may want it a lot we
had recommended hosting a discretionary
hearing process so that way if an
operator comes into place and they want
to look at their the community still has
an opportunity to come out and say
whether they want them there or not and
that we thought was a better way to
adjust one of the proper levels as
opposed to putting an artificial cap
which at this moment really is that it
seems arbitrary there's really no reason
as to why they'd thrown out this 20 or
10 number on there and it's a little
silly on there too one of the other
recommendations we did which they kind
of seemed to implement but did not do it
for the reasons we did it for we were
concerned that there would not be enough
testing licenses or test laboratories in
place to be able to get product you know
healthy in and up in the market so we
what we recommend that they have a
reasonable number of testing licenses
versus the cultivation as it remains
right now they have a one-for-one so
they have 10 cultivation and 10
laboratory license essentially every
cultivator would get their own
laboratory that's that's awesome to some
degree which is ridiculous kids you
don't need that that's not what the
intent was behind what we did on that so
those are things when they're looking at
these caps it seems to be at this moment
I would like to think that it's more of
a test in the you know putting your toe
in the water right now for them to see
what is the right market you know right
size for the market because I understand
they may not know what is good for
cultivators and this and that but
makes absolutely no sense right and I
assume it it follows the same logic as
the retail there are currently more than
10 warehouse cultivators in the County
of Los Angeles you know when it comes to
the discussion of how large your market
isn't addressing with the proper amount
of licenses we speak with the
supervisors in there and some of them I
would say the majority of them are
surprised and happy to see that there
seems to be some data to say how big the
market should be certainly easier on the
retail side than anything else but at
least they have something to point to
and their intent is like one of the
things that they want to do differently
than the city of Los Angeles did is city
of Los Angeles did a roll out based on
license type so they did retail first
but there was no supply chain to support
it so where are you gonna get your
distribution where you gonna get your
product all that stuff in there
there was nothing legally within the
save in the county of LA mostly to get
that stuff the county is intent on
giving a full supply chain so they'll
give you your retail your cultivation
all that stuff going in there but it's
so limited that it doesn't make sense as
well - so that's why I kind of going
back on it's like the county doesn't
want to repeat others mistakes but they
seem to be thinking about new ones for
themselves crack supervisors
is just everyone dead set against
outdoor cultivation actually we've
learned differently initially when we
had the discussions last year the
keeping in mind that the outdoor
opportunities are primarily within
district 5 so supervisor barber she has
by far the largest district in the
county and that did you know initially
the discussions going from that office
was that they were concerned for you
know things such as water or this that
in the other and we've now learned from
the state Cir report and otherwise that
cannabis certainly doesn't consume more
water than any other crop that is
already in those markets and so that
discussion has not changed you know
we've had the recent discussions on that
and it seems to be more aligned with
it's a political decision so within the
county itself you have 21 Town Council's
and they don't really get much legal say
over or you know how things are run but
they do have certain certain parameters
they can run around and make certain
laws for their own town
if you will these Town Council's have
influence over the supervisors but the
surprise still get the last say on that
and what seems to have been happening so
far right now that these Town Council's
have been saying they've been against
this and the discussions in the county
as they go out to discuss with them as
we've gone out there to discuss with
them what we've seemed to have all
learned is that they are right to be
against cannabis operators as they know
it what the issue seems to be is that
they are against an illicit unregulated
market so we're crazy things happen
where there is no way for people to
enforce properly so and so forth and on
that line I think everyone sees on the
the same page for that one because it's
like no one wants that unregulated
markets when we have the discussion
about what a regular market can do how
it can benefit from taxes - Safety's who
so on and so forth job opportunities it
seems to start opening up a discussion
but the county has not been promoting
those other aspects on them you know
they have not been or should say been
promoting because I know it's not their
job necessary on that but it's they have
not been educating on the totality of
what cannabis and you know regulations
could be one or another for that but
supervisors bargain like I said when it
comes to the candidate to the
cultivation side now they're not against
it because they're getting prospectors
are getting people saying hey this is a
great area we want to be able to do our
stuff here of course the laws don't
support it just yet but they're hearing
consolation what can be saying this is a
you know you guys have the resources for
this we want to do this here and the
contrast is is like they want to hear
more from these Town Council's
themselves on what their thoughts are we
like that so long as the Town Council's
have an opportunity to be fully educated
on what the impact is on that and that's
where we are now trying to reach out
their Town Council's and see if we can
have that discussion or reach out to the
residents of those Town Council's and
see if they can start that discussion
themselves and see if they can start
understanding a little bit better what
you know the benefits one right now that
could be for them so just keeping on the
same point of outdoor cultivation you're
saying the Board of Supervisors while
initially say
nor in door is open to the idea of
greenhouse or outdoor but wants to hear
from the town councils that they wanted
in their local towns or agricultural
areas absolutely absolutely and so I
mean ultimately these are our elected
officials they should be doing what we
are asking them to do
if the Town Council's are telling you
and no we don't want this then they'll
likely listen but if they're saying hey
there's something here and we should be
exploring this that'll be a different
story for them to start seeing that the
the initial thoughts because it was you
know a year ago when they first passed
the motion to start looking to stuff the
initial thought was like let's just
limit this we won't have a very broad
discussion either I just take some baby
steps so the easiest baby step was to
say let's take the agricultural land out
of the equation because that is just
such a massive part of what LA County
has but now as we've learned we've seen
more data and more people's opinions on
the matter the interest is seriously
there now how do we bridge that gap and
how do we give ourselves the opportunity
and how does the county also see
revenues coming from that that could
easily go to other counties surrounding
counties instead that makes no sense for
that opportunity to go elsewhere on that
one thing I did like that there was a
recommendation that one of the
supervisors gave us and we put it
ultimately within the committee is that
we asked the the supervisors to do a
study I would say essentially how much
money are they're going to spend on
trying to enforce against all the
agricultural land although the operators
that are on there versus how much money
could they bring in in revenue if they
actually regulated allowed it to happen
so I'm hopeful that that study that they
will do at some point and they can
really contrast those numbers and see
where more benefits can come from that
are there tabs that are starting to
speak up to say hey we do kind of want
to explore outdoor cultivation in our
town or the environs of our
well yeah absolutely you know we had we
had a couple and come to mind right now
one of them was we reached out to
recently to have the discussion of the
Town Council we were prepared to go in
there with as much facts that we would
think supports why it would be good to
have a regulate market versus not and it
was a town council for Little Rock and
pear blossom so they're out in the
Antelope Valley area and typically that
area out there is very conservative we
thought that they would not be very
receptive to it turns out the entire
council was very receptive and they were
concerned that look what the currents
caps were on there and how that could
affect their town they were great to
point out that the area's the land had
no the infrastructure on there so they
were a lot more knowledgeable than we
were even prepared to see him there the
voting data seemed to support it on that
as well too so we knew that ahead of
time so they did vote about 54% in favor
of prop 64 so we knew we had that in
there other communities so that's this
or five other do communities such as out
in the Santa Monica Malibu mountains
area out there you have Topanga Canyon
and Topanga Canyon is an unincorporated
area very well known I think within the
cannabis space itself as well to
everyone kind of hasn't understood that
there are growers there people grow for
their own personal use or otherwise it's
been historically done there that's a
great location for all that what's been
surprising to us in a very positive way
is that that community when you look at
that voting data the community was
actually at 76% in favor of prop 64
passing so by far they were one of the
larger you know highest-rated you know
commutes that in favor of legal cannabis
there however the way the current zoning
is set up their supervisor who
represents them supervisor Sheila Kuehl
who is very favorable to topics she has
always been favorable she she wants to
see a regulated market however she has
not had a very loud voice in this
discussion because the zoning has made
so her district essentially would only
have the ability to have only one
dispensary in the entire district for
her
and no cultivation and no cultivation
would be hard to find anything else on
there so the entire Topanga Canyon area
all that stuff in there there is no
zoning that is allowed for any
commercial cannabis use indoor outdoor
you name it so this is an example where
the Town Council's started getting in
the year of the County Board of
Supervisors saying hey we would like
either indoor outdoor cultivation in the
Topanga area that maybe the Board of
Supervisors would start to listen to
them and change light like that it seems
like the current policy is all cannabis
cultivation in this little tiny needle
pin sized area of the entire county
that's where it's all going to happen
and what we need is people in different
areas saying hey we'd like it in our
area too and by the way we also like to
do greenhouse or outdoor yeah and I mean
it's really important because they've
that if that town council could vote the
voice that opinion more strongly to
supervisor Kuehl she would be even more
encouraged to supports you know
expanding and actually having a viable
cannabis market I think right now what
they have proposed is not a viable
market it'll be a market where you'll
have people that'll spend their money
and pay their taxes and also been there
but they have to be competing against
the illicit operators and the illicit
guys want to be responsible they'll be
just possibly going to jail for
something that is innate if you're
leaving but there's also the contrast to
where you have certain Town Council's
that have people that sit on them that
are conservative have based their
opinion and they voice that opinion but
it doesn't reflect what the actual
voting data is for the area so if the
panga canyons Town Council has decided
that they've had this discussion
previously last year when we went out to
do a opportunity to speak with them they
spoke about it for you know about an
hour on the thing and since that time
they backed away and said great there's
not gonna be anything happening here I
don't see that that is reflecting the
will of what the resident
are there and the residents are the ones
that need to show them but it's just
something they want they need to go to
their town council and they need to talk
to them and say we voted for this thing
if we don't do this there are parents
that could be separate from their
children there could be so many other
consequences on this stuff if they are
continuing to do their grows because the
law is no longer support them to do that
[Music]