they won't eat me that's right the
ladybugs
won't eat me that's right they won't eat
can i touch
uh yeah you can touch i don't want to
they're joking
they're getting my finger they are not
to eat your finger do you know what they
like to eat they like to eat
aphids they like to eat bugs
okay little buddy come a little closer
no
come closer come closer right there
perfect okay
what do you have what do you have in
your hands
ladybug yeah and what do ladybugs eat
they eat bugs right
they don't eat your fingers right
okay so we're going to let the ladybugs
out today
yeah we're going to open the ladybugs
okay ready
should we do this should we do it
together
okay ready to let the ladybugs out okay
here they all come oh my gosh oh
okay we'll put some right here okay
oh my gosh look at all the ladybugs on
my fingers so the ladybugs
eat aphids on your pants
yeah the one went on my pants oh my gosh
okay let me put them down here
oh yeah yeah hold on okay so the
ladybugs are going to eat about
50 aphids a day and when they're
uh and we also have me
i know we also have lace wings and the
lace wings
eat even more late or eat even more bugs
and normally you'd want to let the
ladybugs aina don't be scared look
they're all over my fingers and they're
not eating my fingers oh my gosh so many
ladybugs
okay so we have a lot of ladybugs here
right
okay let me oh yeah let me get them off
me
sorry guys okay so normally we should
have let the ladybugs out at night
right before it gets dark out don't
touch them
because uh that's when the bugs that
they eat
are most active that's when the bugs
they eat are
are eating the plants and we want the
ladybugs to eat the bugs that eat the
plants
by and so we also have lace wings
in the other container and
we're also gonna get some predatory
mites that are gonna eat the
no no no okay let them crawl on your
finger we're gonna get some predatory
mites
that are gonna eat uh spider mites and
broad mites
that's what they like to eat but the
ladybugs don't really eat the spider
mites that much
so anyway this is how we control the
bugs in here
because we don't want to spray bad
things on our plants
bing bai
so what do you think okay do you want to
open the other one
yeah okay here let her go let her don't
touch her
here you're gonna stand over here okay
there's a lot of ladybugs on me
i know they're on me too okay so let's
walk over here good girl
okay ready okay come on little buddy
let's go over here can you come over
here
oh my gosh okay
so come here hold my hand okay let the
ladybugs go
come hold my hand
okay come here he's shy he's shy that's
right
okay come here look you're gonna open
this one too okay okay
yep they're all are they coming
here they come
okay you hold you hold the container can
you hold the container
okay so what do you have in your hands
what do you have in your hands
containers
well you have ladybugs right and what do
the ladybugs eat
baby girl what do the ladybugs eat
leaves well now they eat other bugs
right if they eat the leaves we
definitely would not be letting them go
in here
okay i'll hold that so the ladybugs
eat aphids and other bugs oh no
don't pull the leaf
he off it okay so we're gonna put this
get hold him so he can feed him
okay hold on we're gonna put these guys
right in here okay
right there and then we'll come back
tomorrow
oh my gosh look at all those ladybugs
look at all the ladybugs on my fingers
okay ready where are they
now they're all over the plants so what
we didn't bring today
are the they're called predatory mites
and they're
not their name is neocillus
californicus can you say neocilis
californicus
californian chaoses say neocellus
names can you say this neocillus
californicus yeah yeah
so we're gonna let those go in here too
he's not shy anymore no they're
definitely not shy
right
the ladybugs are not shy
that's right and i have some in my shirt
so i'm gonna take my shirt off
okay
oh my gosh let's see where they are look
there's one on the back
okay can you grab the one is there one
on my back baby girl is there a ladybug
on my back
yeah i would take your office thank you
hey they're all over me you got them
okay
you got all the ladybugs off bubba's
back wait i feel another one do you see
any more on my back
no are you sure i it feels like they're
on my back
okay let me see if they're any in my
shirt
all right
you pull my pants up thank you whoa
oh my gosh we let all the ladybugs go
good job
can you say good job