you see in pockets and material in
Africa that still goes back in time like
that hasn't had the Dutch infiltration
that see like when I when I was over in
Hawaii in the in the mid 80s it was the
last of the Southeast Asian varietals
grown in the cane fields and so I go
there and I get to experience some
world-class cannabis and it was perfect
because the soils the climate all
matched up with those type of plants and
so you had this incredible combination
and then I go back you know years and
years later and I got this uh this white
kid that's telling me about you need to
check out the aloha white widow and I
was like that's not what I'm looking for
I'm looking for the cambodian that used
to grow out here that used to take top
your head off make you almost peed your
pants you had to sit on the toilet
smoking um where's that and they're like
oh no no you want the white widow and
I'm like no I don't want the white widow
I know the white widow is like what I
want is the things that were from here
did did Africa have the ability to hold
material in constant do you still have
to because someone whose discover in
stock because to me I'm like Afghanistan
got hammered all over Asia got hammered
from war Africa had so much war and
famine and issues as you're mining
material you stable to mine some of that
killer stuff from the past or is it it's
getting polluted quickly it's it really
is it's hard to find like I was in this
last year went to through Ethiopian than
this Seychelles Islands right there and
it's even finding these old land races
where all of a sudden it's like oh these
guys were here from Amsterdam a couple
years ago and we have a white widow
mango that we open pollinated with all
our land rate stuff so all of a sudden
is this with what's happening is it's
harder and harder to find
from from Africa and that was years ago
Southeast Asia
you know I traveled through Vietnam
Cambodia lout Thailand
area trying to and then even that was
mid 90s and you're still running across
places where people had brought other
genetics in so this is one thing going
back in this diversification and being
able to keep things from their from the
origin you know in Southeast Asia India
African
keep these genetics separate and being
able to do to do testing and that's like
the kind of the back step of documenting
this but like yeah Africa it's it's
anywhere in the world right now it's
like Irian Jaya Papua New Guinea you're
going there in these areas people have
been there with cannabis or him it's
amazing because you know for me for my
background from being in cannabis when
it was coming over from all these places
throughout the year in cycle it just let
me experience a range of effects that I
don't experience now I called most of
the stuff we play with now homogenized
cannabis and what I want is I want to be
able to have these unique directions to
fit what I want to do and how I want to
feel and I people try to tell me that
you know it's your imagination
that you're you're dreaming that things
will better at that time and I said oh
no they they had unbelievable effects
and the directions were phenomenal and
they were very unique in the way they
sent on how you made you feel and you
just you don't see this except in some
very rare cultivars so we see stuff
that's highly marketable and a quality
but like you know you working with some
of that stuff that panama's I remember
some killer panama's that was just
thumping and the the flavor profiles
were unique in the way it made you feel
was unique and the problem is that as
soon as we started to hybridize it down
so that it would work in our climates as
soon as we started to try to bring it
indoor we basically just started calling
and out of existence and we dumbed it
down do we turn the qualities down and
if you know for me when I try to get
when I meet people that like you like
I've known you for a long time but I
know that you're you know you scour in
the earth and I'm always like did you
find some goodies someplace you know is
the goodies still remaining somewhere
and and and unfortunately the goodies
are out there but they're just not
markers you know for though for the most
part but the some of these cultivars
that take 14 weeks that the flowers
still have 14 weeks is like a football
and it hasn't filled in but but this is
something that it's good to have in the
toolbox you know let's not get let's 9
you get let this go and I think right
now that's
these different unique cultivars that we
run into it's keep it alive or share it
with somebody else and you know it's
like that it's like cannabinoids that
feed your endocannabinoids you know
everybody's different and that's that's
the thing something that one strain it's
like is that could be that key that
helps you like with epilepsy it's 3 to 5
percent right of people that are
affected by say Charlotte's Web but what
are they cannabinoids within that
cultivar that are accessing your endo
cannabinoid profile and that's something
collecting big data right now going into
this on the pharmacogenetic level is
identifying these genetics plant
genetics and then a person's makeup and
seeing that 80 year old lady that's in
Australia that just got help from a
certain profile and helped her epilepsy
epilepsy and then you have a 3 year old
child in America or somewhere else that
you'd never know that this particular
balance of a one to one fight and that's
something working one and was finding
these old land races from from Africa as
well but developing a full cannabinoid
profile you know what I'm talking like 5
percent THC 5 CBD 5 CB n CB g CB DV HCV
flatline across the board or these
different profiles and then when you
identify a cultivar like that being able
to put it in vitro and you put that on
the show