[Music]
my question goes back to the theme of
today's talk which is the preservation
of land rinses there seems to be out of
prohibition into this becoming more of a
medically accepted therapeutic agent to
almost like a green rush towards
crossing land rinses with other strains
to then achieve a certain outcome with
certain pathology or with that said just
to use your example sir a little bit
earlier with green house medical you see
these companies these genetic banks
going to places like Congo and Brazil in
Colombia in taking these land dresses
and then patent that knowledge later so
that the indigenous people that have
been growing this for me for thousands
of years are now having to buy this back
from the rich world so with all the
amazing benefits that preserving these
land rinses bring to us how can we also
ensure that when you think of the war on
drugs and the people disproportionately
affected by this this prohibition don't
suffer because we are so busy preserving
them that we're actually extinguishing
them by crossing them III do tissue
cultures of all of my genetics I have
two refrigerators that are completely
filled and I will keep them preserved
for as long as possible and I have a
hundred and thirty two of the listed
four hundred and ninety eight you know
strains that are available and we we do
do breeding and we do that intentionally
to zero in on effectiveness okay a prime
example for you is I brought back a pure
Afghani when I came home from the Marine
Corps we won't have too much of a
conversation about that but it was the
the best pain reliever down to earth
pain reliever that I ever ever grew and
the one problem that I was having was
okay it's let's simplify it a person
who's in pain 24 hours a day is
predisposed to be an
they're always in pain okay so what if
you could take away their pain and
change their attitude because if you can
change the attitude then you bring the
socialization back which communication
and community help to rebuild and
regenerate and rehabilitate the
individual not that you have to hold
that person up or hold their hand okay
it's just through common communication
so we took a pre 79 euphoria which was
known for taking a woman who can go from
zero to in three seconds and
turning that switch off so that she
becomes mom again you know or that that
person who is suffering from you know
PTSD type issues that snap to judgment
or snap to reaction to what you see you
know happening around you so the idea of
it was was take away the pain and
changed the attitude
well we achieved that goal in creating
the you Gani and that was crossing those
two strains both of which are land race
trains and then leaving it alone we left
it alone after that but what we found
was that it actually worked for a sight
sound odor / alertness / awareness and
paranoia in a veteran giving the
individual back but getting rid of the
symptoms of all of the PTSD so it's
there's a certain point where you should
cross you know and try and find an
effective change but there's also a
certain point that you should allow it
to go it's a thing should not after
think something's been crossed
you know you cross it back to and ensure
that you have a stabilized Fino out of
it and then at that point there do
testing you know so when you find
something that works test it on other
people that have the same type of issues
and see what the reactions are as
growers what you should be doing when
you take a strain into a dispensary take
a little make little cards okay so that
when a patient goes in and get your
product and takes it home that there's
ten questions on there and you tell them
listen if you
are all these honestly and you bring
this back in or mail this out to us okay
the next time you go in you're gonna get
10% off or 20% off of your product but
over a 30-day period of them testing
your medicine you can actually pinpoint
what works and what doesn't work but
what you're gonna find is that by going
back to the original land raced range
you can actually target better so the
other part of that to answer your
question the land races have a whole lot
of history and have been used by Wiseman
and medicine man from my part of the
country of the world to China so to go
back to that gives you a reference and
sort of like the Sun on demand takes you
back to the Sun which is your reference
and if you can get the terroir there's
your reference and if you come with a
genetics
there's your reference you're somewhere
there the hybrids that have come about
is because it's called resistance
farming right because you're resisting
nature as you go when you go indoors
you're resisting nature so you have to
do something else so now you've got to
take an Afghan and you've got a 28-day
cycle I need to make money so you know
what limit how do you think og cush came
along right because somebody wanted to
make money they wanted a short cycle and
they wanted to get a high so it's not
all about THC it's not about THC it's
about full plant extract it's about the
ensemble effect gives you know what that
plant has figured it out already you
trying to screw up in there you trying
to go in there and try to do extractive
and all that trying to be a farmer
pharmaceutical company again is totally
excuse my French but it totally
because you're poisoning the
people you're cutting your own business
and you're shortchanging you you're sure
damn we can't look in the mirror now so
let's go back to that so what hopefully
we're trying to do here is to talk about
how do you create your own medicine for
your page
how do you differentiate yourself in the
marketplace as a small farmer empower
yourself instead of trying to be like
everybody else in the grow find medicine
that you want to grow that you have in
your heart that you would like to solve
a lot of the growers that we talked to
had personal experience Harry Rose would
treat well although things went awry for
him in his business model he's back
again as rosette down in California he
was saved by his own balanced tincture
and that's why he's here so every I'm
sure most of you have stories of people
you've helped or you helped yourself get
that medicine the one that you feel the
most passionate about and make it as
best as you can you're gonna blow away
everybody people can find their way to
you if you do that in a very natural way
even if it's indoors sorry yeah I just
wanted to answer your your question and
it's true of intellectual property from
indigenous people around the world is
yeah it's being taken and being used
commercially and so it's that this has
been happening across the amazon basin
where pharmaceuticals coming in and
finding these plant medicines and it's
we're not just facing it's not just
about preserving small farms here in
Oregon or in California but it's across
the world women have been cultivating
this medicine they have been getting its
it's been allowing their children to to
go to school and that still we need to
keep those small farmers around the
world alive and and preserve that and
with that I don't really know exactly
what the answer is around around
genetics and around I mean it's I don't
want to see a surf system where it's
like okay we come and take your genetics
then we sell it back to you and then you
grow for us oh now you can make a living
because you grow for us and that model
cannot it may not be the right one part
of these genetics they're entering
commercialism for the first time these
land
races these were grow and not intended
for money not whatsoever it was used for
spiritual healing it was used for
healing people in this clash with
commercialism is it's it's it's very
real and it's something that we should
all be thinking about well I mean it's
pretty obvious that that I that we all
agree we want to have great genetics we
want to have great light you know we
want to have natural soils I mean it
just makes sense to do it that way and
and I I just I'm always so impressed
when I come to a talk like this and I
listen to people and you know I have my
stupid ideas and then I hear somebody
you know we find it make it even better
and and you know this is this is what's
so cool about this industry that I don't
think we'll ever see the big guys doing
we get together we share information you
know I was like that I always like to
say we're a bunch of we're just one big
cell you know and we're all enzymes in
here and we're all helping build a cell
better and that's what we do and and and
it doesn't matter whether you make money
or not what matters is that you grow the
best plant possible because that's what
it's all about
we're supposed to be growing the best
plants possible so let's go forth and do
it I just
I just wanted to add to this conflict
between between commercialism Indian
farmers and that is is that this this
culture of gifting and sharing is with
the home grower and we should be
encouraging and be helping everyone home
grow okay so I'm gonna answer that so I
have a new book coming out on
autoflowering cannabis because I think
that now that we've got the stigma going
away and it's becoming legal in all the
states and in Canada and Bolivia and
everyplace else it's the next tomato
this is the plant that my mother will
grow when snap peas came out what I say
is is once or twice in a lifetime a new
plant is developed for the home gardener
snap peas oh my god now there's 15
different kinds of snap and I might add
I think it started right here in Oregon
autoflowering cannabis gives you the
ability to grow from from seed to to
flower harvested seven to nine weeks
that's tough and you if you fertilize it
too much you screw up the soil food web
too much they don't grow well holy crow
it's a plant that needs to be ignored
and assent to give it natural conditions
it does phenomenal they've improved the
genetics now that we've got lights and
things that we can even leave and make
them even better this is the plant that
my mother my sisters I don't have a
sisters will grow at home because it's
just like a tomato plant so it's coming
folks and the home gardener we need to
support so
[Music]