[Music]
so I'm here today because what keeps me
in this industry is that no parent
should have to worry about administering
medicine to their SI child or get in a
car and have a fear of going from their
legal grow to the legal dispensary but
getting arrested along the way the laws
here have to change um California I
worked here for 10 years I got out of
about 4 years ago and became a
consultant kind of Nationwide and in
Canada um I really fell in love with
building facilities so I've kind of done
it all ran
dispensaries uh cultivated for 10 years
uh but I really love the way of building
is put together and what that means so
that's what I'm here to talk to you guys
about tonight so it all starts from the
same place and that's the plan that's
the grow that's how it's grown and we
have an obligation as caregivers as
brand ambassadors what have you to
deliver medical grade cannabis to the
community at large I believe that's a
moral obligation it's an ethical
obligation and pretty soon it's going to
be a legal obligation so we all have to
get on page with that and the idea that
you know a lot of Growers are one
Harvest away from losing everything so
this means that they have to push bad
product onto the market a lot of the
times it's a big problem in this state
it's a problem in other states so I'm
here today to talk about cleaning up
your Grove um let's
next and so when a flower doesn't Bloom
you fix the environment in which it
grows not the flower so that's
what I focus
on this is benefits of indoor a working
with cannabis so when I started scaling
up into facilities that were 5,000
50,000 100,000 sare ft or more I found
large scale Egg and I thought where have
you been where is a large scale egg so
the hydro industry did something pretty
tricky where they renamed all these
things that already existed benches
became tables stands trays they changed
the vernacular so you wouldn't know what
to look for on the internet you were
paying three times the price but if for
an inferior product so once you scale up
to a larger facility you should never
shop at a Hydra store again I hope
there's no Hydra store owners here are
there just kidding um
so it works for
garages um so yeah much a large scale
EGS industrial equipment is beneficial
to streamlining the production
procedures of cannabis uh the
consistency quality assurance methods
used in large scale egg it's very
similar I hire plant scientists all the
time and I teach them cannabis it works
really really well the idea that you
have to be a 10year veteran grower to
get this is just not true it helps but
it's the same methodologies it's the
same nutrient base it is a plant it's a
plant that functions a million different
ways and we have thousands of different
strains but that's where
so why automation is important to indoor
cannabis uh we don't install Automation
in our facilities so that your grower
can become lazier and you know just kick
back and watch the plants grow it's so
he can do his job and actually look for
problems before they become problems so
if you're spending your time hand
watering or checking timers or doing any
of these things that can be done through
streamlined automation that have existed
in large scale a for 50 years you need
to check your program automation is
scary at first I was terrified by it but
it's really served me in a lot of ways
so from everything from SE to sale
software to become compliant to machines
that fill pots once you scale past a
certain size you have to automate it's
not an
option so the importance of R&amp;D and you
can't really see this um Tracy who was
just up here a few minutes ago I work
with her a little bit and mainly she's
one of my really good friends and
favorite people on the planet uh her
daughter suffers from an optic pathway
GL a tumor she's supposed to be blind uh
cannabis pretty much saved her vision it
saved her health overall this kid you
would not know is sick when you meet her
she's the happiest most joyful
three-year-old you've ever met in your
life first time I met her she jumped in
my H lap and said I love
you and uh it's a big part of it has to
do with cannabis it's undeniable at this
point so when I think of you know an
8-month-old or a 90-year-old or someone
with a severely compromised immune
system we have that moral obligation
again to give them the best quality
medicine so the studies that they're
doing in Israel is basically they're
studying they're stripping apart the
plant and studying the individual canavs
the ones that they find most useful so I
think they have 11 of them mapped out at
this point
um and they're inputting them into rats
and what they're showing is that the way
the strain profiles are manipulated
through this testing it can alleviate
breast cancer by 100% but one won't
touch pancreatic cancer so I believe
within the next 5 years or so we will
have kind of a map of what strains work
best for what illnesses and they're
currently working on that now looking to
publish research that I don't even know
if I'm allowed to talk about um so they
do these 96 wellplay accounts where they
take 96 little trays and they'll put the
same tumor with the same genetic
mutations in each tray and they'll try
different strains of cannabis uh
different profiles of the cannabinoids
against these different genetic
mutations and some will touch it by 100%
some's 30% some's 60 so we want to know
what that 100% is and how we can
replicate it every time without
fail so with regulation comes
responsibility comes responsibility to
legality to our patients most of all I
think it's Patients First that is my
number one mission is to make sure
patients get the best medicine
possible so we designed clean rooms uh I
took some server process processor HVAC
guys from Silicon Valley and I employed
them and said what can we do with
cannabis and so we realize that there is
a big disconnect between cultivators
construction companies Engineers we came
out on the market in Colorado legalized
and said okay you can go to 100,000
square ft so what did they do they
grabbed the guy from his garage that
grew the best stuff that they knew and
they grabbed the construction company in
town and they tried to put the two
together it doesn't scale that way it's
like trying to turn a liquor store into
a Costco it's like trying to buy a hydro
store instead of large scale app so the
reasons we do clean room designs is to
mitigate pests and pathogens from even
entering the facility so they don't
become a problem later uh to cultivate
medical grade cannabis of course to
comply with State imposed legislation
and guidelines um accurate scientific
studies in R&amp;D based on the best
material possible I don't know if you s
sanj gupta's weed 3 or what they're
studying out there in the University of
Mississippi but uh it's absolute trash
if you study trash you're going to get
trash results what if we study the best
stuff what if we study the most
consistent stuff what do we get then
that's what I'm
interested negative pressure this is a
big one so like 90% of the facilities
that I walk into have sewer gas because
we have these carbon filters that we're
designed for garages so that your
neighbor wouldn't smell your stash
growing in your garage so you have them
sucking constantly at like 1,400
cfms um so when you first put together a
building you can do some Diagnostics on
this and this is how we put together our
buildings is we do lower door test this
would be on a retrofit not a ground up
um so it measures the overall building's
air leakage quantifies Heating cooling
costs and it tests how sealed the
building's envelope is it exposes all
major points of air leakage there's a
lot of reasons for
this so let's talk about the hazards of
reverse negative
pressure it invites Pest and pathogens
into the cultivation facility so if you
have air sucking in you have that
reverse negative pressure going on
there's a lot of problems that come with
that so air will always travel the path
of lease resistance so it's going to
pull from all the most undesirable
places your basement your attic every
crack every crevice and it's always the
most undesirable places um it's not the
most efficient or costeffective way to
control an
environment especially when you're
trying to save money in price per pound
is so
important um and the last is it can pull
SE gases into the room through dried out
P traps so those air filters will always
dry out the P traps so unless you have a
trap primer or you've thought about that
before 90% % of the facilities I walk
into I walk up to the floor drain and I
can always feel that air hit my hand and
I know those people have breathing sewer
gas very bad
problem this is another one um so this
came from you know cultivating in your
garage and you just throw every hose
into whatever drain you have well unless
there's an air gap in that hose it's
going to grow bacteria and this comes
from condensate lines of air
conditioners sorry to get so technical
um so the condensate lines from air
conditioners if there's no air gap it'll
actually grow molden bacteria straight
into your head unit and distribute it
throughout your room facility what have
you uh biological contaminants so this
caused from Dirty HB
systems uh microbes Legionella this is a
big one so Legionnaire's Disease was
caused uh came from Legionella uh it's a
water board bacterium it's detected in
cooling tower water but it can also grow
through that condensate line as
well cladosporium is a common of
Outdoors this is also when you get that
mold smell in your air conditioner
that's
cladosporium this is another one I'll
just F through uh endotoxin a cell wall
component of gr negative bacteria this
is a really bad one uh known for
respiratory problems and all kinds of
things
so controlling HVAC
biocontamination uh upgraded fil
filtration efficiency of overall system
maintain proper filter changes proper
maintenance and cleaning of cooling
coils drainage pan should be added to
all of your
Sops uh design the system with the
Airstream so it doesn't come in contact
with that internal porous uh system in
the aack in your uh your head units
because that actually breeds some people
don't know this but your best form of
integrated Pest Management is a good
environmental system people will treat
oh I'm putting florite mid and all this
stuff and they keep coming back they're
breeding in your agac system nine times
out of
10 uh so reduced surface area and all
particulate matter so particulate matter
the best way to describe it is anytime
there's a lot of particulate matter Pest
and pathogen have something to Clan to
this is an example of that so all this
crazy duct work up here that's totally
excessive and unnecessary should be
recessed and these registers should
Point down and be blocked out with
drywall if you have a bunch of this duct
work running through your system you're
going to have to get up there and clean
it every few months all of it and it
just creates more surface area more
problem remove all exposed wood from the
cultivation facility wood is not your
friend
um you want to replace everything with
metal or Unistrut you should never use
wood in a cultivation facility it breeds
mold breeds bacteria bre
pathogens you can use antimicrobial
paint too if you already have it in
there there's also wine barrel paint
that works really well
um uh so this is a system that my
company kind of invented to streamline
processes because back when we were
using the HPS lights they have to be a
foot and a half to 3 ft away from the
top of the canopy at all time um well we
thought it takes way too long to move
these lights so we invented this system
where with the touch of a button you can
move the lights um and we have these
rows up to like 60 80 ft or 60 lights or
80 lights in length we can make them as
long as possible and you can move the
whole row streamline very simple you
don't have employees standing on ladders
trying to move things um just works
really well so that's part of
automation uh irrigation is a big one
this is a facility in Richmond I think
Oakland um so this is a top feed
fertigation or top feed uh doser system
and
uh it was basically all locked in place
so we had to add these OCTA bubblers on
each line so that it blew oxygen through
the line so it's less likely to
clog you have a lot of options when it
comes to irrigation basically depends
what size your facility is uh cone
bottom reservoirs Pros or you know you
can be Zone to multiple different
areas uh controls the ability to
irrigate mix and drain
um I can't read the next one but the
cons are it's difficult to clean you're
focusing on human error and uh I'm not a
fan of leaving it up to here in error
I'd much rather blame the
machine but we build
these um okay so these are dener systems
this is kind of when you step up and you
don't want big bulky reservoirs in the
room you want line fed irrigation
they've been used a large scale egg
forever um we've kind of integrated them
into cannabis and they have some cool
fail safes and user alerts that tell you
anytime your set points are
off uh fertigation this would be like
your priva or Argus Big Boy system when
you you know have to feed 64 different
this goes up to yeah it feeds up to 64
different nutrient regimens so if you
have a Perpetual Harvest or you're on an
assembly line type circuit you would
have to have one of these systems uh the
cons are The Upfront cost that's about
it uh but they are scalable they do come
in smaller models and you can scale up
but I'm a big fan of
those oh this is uh the biggest facility
that we've designed to date this is in
Nova Scotia and they're held up in
licensing process so they're like 80%
built out right now um but yeah it
basically functions like a clean room
facility usually it's a clearer picture
but you enter on the side all these are
different hallways so cultivation team
has their own hallway processing team
has their own hallway uh ancillary
management has their own hallway so
there's no cross contamination everybody
has to shower before they go into the
facility put on a pocketless gown and
walk into the facility because Canada uh
when we first designed this they
proposed no pesticides organic or
non-organic so we had to design it in
this fashion so that we would never have
a problem because we couldn't use
pesticides they also have third party
Auditors propos that would come to your
facility pick the sample they want if
that doesn't pass testing there's an
on-site incinerator where everything
goes
yeah
so so those are the standards we build
to I don't like using pesticides so I
design so I don't have to use them I had
one facility that functioned for seven
years without a single introduction of
the pestop pathogen so I know it can be
done it's just a lot more
work
[Applause]
[Music]
question so as a consum as a
consumer how do you know that what
you're buying doesn't have pathogens and
Myro in California you don't and in
Colorado you still don't any state that
can pick their own sample out of a batch
and go okay this looks good and send
that in for testing you're really not
going to know um unfortunately so that's
kind of my fight and that's why I get up
and speak because I do push for the
third party Auditors I I'm a big fan of
reg ulation I'm a big fan of compliance
and I want to know that anything that is
grown and giving to Tracy's daughter or
my grandmother who stage four is going
to be helping them and not hurting them
so hopefully they'll be some kind
of eventually I hope so I mean when I
started 14 years ago none of this was
happening and in the last four years or
so I feel like we're moving at lightning
speed so my hope is that sooner than
later it will be implemented and if any
I have anything to do about it on my
soap box then
hopefully here we go
yes you work with a lot of businesses
that are scaling up what you find is the
biggest challenge for the company owner
the business
own um there's multiple challenges and
with everybody every individual client
it's different it could be scalability
it could be budget it could be the team
already in place it could be a failing
facility so I I don't think there's one
universal answer for that question there
there are
multiple um you know
challenges I think the biggest one we
face is budget so when we come from this
kind of garage mentality and you try to
convince somebody to scale up and that
they need to basically create a food
processing center it doesn't register
they like oh but I built this for 20
grand like no
what is that Nova scoti facility cost
generally $34 million to date and
probably going to be more than that but
they've been and what's the um what's
the payback what's the investment how
many years it's going to take
to I can tell you that it pays back
faster than any other business I've seen
But in Canada's case can't give you a
number but in Canada's case they've been
held up so so these guys took a risk a
big risk and they put a lot of money
they sent everybody buil out build out
letters said go ahead build out your
facility it's okay and then you know a
year into the building process they said
stop everything we're not legalizing and
everybody's been sitting in line ever
since so we had to drop hammers you know
two a year and a half ago
now do you need Pharma to fund this or
do you need Farmers to fund
this do you need Pharma to come in and
start funding these B facilities no no
no that's legislation it's not about
funding they're well funded but they
don't they are not P they said go ahead
start the process then they pulled
everything back and now they're not it's
just held up it will get pasted it's
kind of a too big to fail scenario but
yeah hi hello
um I have more of a technical question
um in your clean rooms have you ever
brought a technology called Aros
sign into the into the clean rooms it
was a technology developed by Nas
supposedly for do you work for Aros I do
not I do the same thing you do actually
and I I was curious about the technology
I've heard things good things about it
supposed develop like space station are
those the they're like little glass
tubes that it passes through in the
byproducts radium or something like that
it's similar to
Fed to destroy
EOL longer but supposedly it's good for
killing pathogens and fungus yeah
there's a lot of new products out there
I'm not familiar with that company
there's a lot of so the NASA born
technology is typically five cell and
all it all comes from the same house
that's negatively charged ions that bond
to positively charged ions that are 100
times heavier than gravity so it'll kind
of grab anything in the air that's an
Airborne particulate like a a powdery
mildew and it'll drag it to the ground
so it doesn't eliminate it but it's like
a magnet that goes around and Care uh
magnetizes the Airborne particulates and
drags them to the ground I think that's
the same
technology yeah we do we do use it and
it's phenomenal okay good yeah m
okay thank you yes you're welcome good
job all right hard to see over
here I was wondering about your um you
said a lot of the cleaning with the air
conditioning um during the season how do
you fluctuate the air when it gets
hotter what is what is the best method
you have uh and when do you run your
life like if you're running your life
obviously at night when it's cooler the
air you're pulling in um how much air
conditioning you would need is it an
outdoor system that you so yeah unfor
how do you the temp with with bugs and
mold it also has a lot of temperature
right so it all depends if we're
designing a facility in Nova Scotia or
our new one in Hawaii like it all
depends on that environment so it's not
going to be the same environment so when
we do our uh en enironmental
calculations we take everything into
account we take in your longitude your
latitude your record highs your record
lows the insulative value of your
windows the depth of your slab without
getting too Technical and boring
everyone in the room there's too many
parameters for one single answer it's
just that every building is different so
to keep the the best way to keep fuel
efficiency so you're not having to run
your air all the time and keep your
temperature tostain like at the right
temperature each
you're yeah so there's a program called
right soft it's kind of like CAD for
hbac and you can plug in all those
values into it and it'll spit out those
uh those numbers your R values and
everything involved if you normally run
your like at night or do you day it
depends on the facility sometimes you
have to be on a flip because you're on
you know some kind of power grid
situation where you don't have enough
power so you have to run one 12 and 12
and another 12 and
12 there's no real way to know how to
keep your temperature the same in the
season well Seasons I mean indoors you
create your own Seasons so that's what
but you're pulling air from outside your
air changes per hour yes are pulled from
outside so that would hot outside you're
pulling hot right so you would have to
engineer your entire building and that's
why I hire clean room experts from
Silicon Valley to engineer each building
individually and put the parameters and
set points based on their environment
based on their
structure I was also wondering if there
any interning possibilities with these
facilities what's that interning
possibilities for these facilities we
are looking into that yeah um I'm
currently leaving the Hawaii for 3
months so after that time
possibly okay we got time for one more
which is going to be right here all
right so um my name is hello um I want
to know
how I want to know how uh your industry
could help the edible
industry it all starts with the plant I
know ites how how could your industry
help
the CH personal how could you help
me by producing clean consistent
products year round I understand that
how would I get what you do to me um so
I am just starting to work in California
again after the 4year stint when they
passed the new legislation I actually
came back from an 8-month stint in
Chicago we're working on some
manufacturing facilities here out in the
desert and some other places that but
it's probably theoretically California
for me for our company is like a year
out and the other question is so what
you're saying is the paraphrase what you
were referring to are you saying that
there's no such thing I stretching I
understand are you saying there's no
such thing as organic there's no such
thing as um a lack a total lack of
pesticides that is every road or some
until something like this is the
norm yes and no there there are some
responsible cultivators out there that I
have to give credit to that do
everything the right way my brother is
an organic farmer in mesino county and
he will cut down and throw away
everything before he puts a pesticide on
it there are those people have to
[Applause]
commend okay we're done
question thank you
guys