[Music]
since we're talking about legalization
and before I introduce the panel members
I do want to say that I think we want to
have a working definition of
legalization and when I talk about
legalization and I'll ask the panelists
to stick with me on this I'm talking
about the ability of a human being in
the state of California to use cannabis
without any fear of arrest or
prosecution by the government okay
that's what I'm talking about about
legalization now the second part of
legalization which is a lot of what
everyone's talking about it is here
today is how does that look like in
terms of creating the product and
distributing the product okay but when
we talk about legalization we're
fundamentally talking about no one
should be arrested and prosecuted for
using this substance someone like Bruce
margan has been dedicated 40 some OD
years to defending people and and and
the attorneys like myself and Bruce are
adamant that this has to end so that's
what legalization is and that's what we
mean okay now uh to my left Dale
garinger has been fighting that fight
for 40 years Fiona Ma's joined this
fight in the last uh year or so and has
become an uh Is On The Board of
Equalization Dale's at Cal normal Fiona
is On The Board of Equalization she's
elected by 9 a half million people in
District 2 which goes from Santa Barbara
cuts the state in the middle and goes
all the way up to the Oregon border and
she has been an outspoken advocate for
the state to get their shit together and
make this work okay I'm on film I think
um Jeff raber uh uh is uh PhD uh put
together um an incredible business
called a workshop and law enforcement
was very excited about his business to
and arrested and raided it a few months
ago uh I don't think it was arrested but
you might have been arrested
yeah so we're still here you know it's
like the end you know uh uh someone uh I
think it was Ken Coy was talking about
the end of World War II the end of of
Wars are nasty times you know end World
War II Japanese kamakazi Pilots the
Germans at the Battle of the Bulge you
know they go in and they they they wreak
havoc because they're losing and they're
vindictive and that's what we're dealing
with we're going to see more arrests
more prosecution by state authorities
over the next two years until this thing
three years until this gets sorted out
so be careful out there and
unfortunately Jeff really learned that
hard way Amanda Ryman is now the
marijuana policy Project Director no the
what's your title
now no no no no she is she is running
the
marijuana marijuana La policy the
marijuana lawn policy project for the
drug policy Alliance and Amanda has been
an incredible Ally on the reform side
you know we have industry folks here we
have politicians we have reform folks
and and the reform in of this whole um
cannabis problem it can't happen without
activists okay and that's how how we
present ourselves when we're doing that
and finally Willen waldrup another
member of the industry who's been has a
company that's become very prominent and
all these panelists uh deserve a round
of applause as all the audience does for
being there and stepping up and fighting
this
[Applause]
fight I want to turn uh first and to
Fiona and ask you Fiona how do you think
you can influence how the banking and
tax issues that Tony was talking about
and that everyone in this room is
struggling with how can you help
influence and make this thing work for
the state of
California thank you Matt thank you
thank you Matt um Matt and I met many
years ago when I was on the San
Francisco Board of Supervisors as well
as Terren Allen and we were really
talking about the night
Coalition how to make San Francisco a
little bit more hip and not have you
know the bars closed at 1:00 and
everybody out on the street you know um
creating uh that situation and then you
know 10 plus years later now we're
working again on this issue so I want to
thank you for your advocacy um and
sitting on the San Francisco Board of
Supervisors from 2002 to 2006 um in San
Francisco like we didn't really talk
about uh cannabis I mean it was more
about how can patients access it better
how do we you know ensure that um you
know that everybody whoever needs it um
can access it so then when I got elected
to the board of uh Equalization in
November all of a sudden I represent the
Emerald Triangle along with assembly
member Jim Wood and Luke Bruner uh found
me at Senator Maguire's town hall and
said hey miss Ma you know you represent
us we'd like to come in and talk to you
about cannabis and I said okay fine and
they came in Matt and Terrence and and
Luke and talk to me about many of the
issues that are facing this industry and
I was honestly quite shocked um I did
not know um all of these kind of issues
you know the raids and the banking and
the transportation and um just you know
tracking and and all of that and so we
started my office and I started on kind
of an 8mon uh cannabis 101 learning
listening tour just for ourselves and I
just want introduce my staff who's been
here we go on every tour we just got
back from 12 meetings in 48 hours in
Colorado yesterday um and so I want to
introduce Seth doton he handles my
Agriculture and as Tony said this is
agriculture so Seth is the expert I have
Tim Morin he handles my legislation in
Sacramento and then Genevie japa is
based out of my San Francisco go off as
my district director and handles all my
Outreach and so again the one thing that
I think uh that impacts everyone in this
industry is the lack of access to Banks
or credit unions and I can't even
imagine like every day every week having
to go around and get Cashers checks uh
to pay for employee taxes to have to go
pay all of your bills uh one by one you
know in cash your utilities your rents
your um I mean it is just maddening to
me and that you know cannot use an
electronic transfer you cannot use a
check yet the IRS and the Franchise Tax
Board they say no cash allowed right so
how are you supposed to pay your taxes
and then we also found out at the Board
of Equalization that we used to have a
no cash policy as well until we you know
are authorized to collect sales tax how
do you collect sales tax from an
industry who cannot have a bank account
and so this really started me on my kind
of passion to figure out how we can um
Bank um this industry because it is just
maddening that there is so much cash out
there and the fact that you all can't um
access banking just like normal
Americans is really kind of unamerican
to me um so we've been working on this
uh obviously we've been pushing the
federal government um you know there is
a bill right now HR
2076 um many of the legislators have
signed on but it's kind of stuck as we
all know the federal government I don't
think is going to be um dealing with
this issue this year or next year is
kind of the consensus um in the meantime
you know the co memo and the uh finson
guidelines came out and um it's
difficult for banks to bank this
industry but it's not impossible and we
just got back from Colorado and there
are six banks that are out so to speak
um that said hey we do want to bank this
industry they're working with software
uh providers to provide better due
diligence and hopes that The Regulators
are going to um allow them to continue
to bank and I think California banks and
Credit Unions the Community Banks and
Credit Union should be uh looking into
these technology platforms to do more
Banking and to take on you know this um
this industry um we also have an
opportunity you know passing the three
bills that we passed um at the
legislature you know to see what we can
do also uh to try to you know allow
Banking and sem member wood um also has
a bill AB
15409 15
1589 15 1549 um that he uh just put over
the desk the last night of session um
which is going to uh look to create a
state chartered Credit Union within the
State Board of Equalization
and so we figure the State Board of
legalization has been collecting taxes
sales taxes legally uh for the last 20
years and you know states are um exempt
I guess from the money laundering laws
and so we've been doing this why can't
we you know increase our capabilities at
the state level at least provide the
basic Merchant banking right paying your
taxes electronic transfers you know that
kind of stuff um so I member wood and I
are going to be working very very hard
over the next four months um and then we
are going to go into official committee
hearings when the legislature comes back
uh in um in January so those are things
that we are doing um anything we can do
to help uh to you know any ideas that
you all have please let us know we are
open as you know it's a big Market it's
going to be a big Market if we legalize
there's enough room for everyone in this
market we need more ideas um not less so
thank you
Fiona you know and I I have never and
and I don't I've never haven't spent
time with with assemblyman wood but I've
never met a politician that I like so
much as
Fiona I mean she has got balls I mean
it's unbelievable geneveve has been
fantastic Seth Tim please she's not
kidding when she says come to talk to
them they're they've been really great
does anyone on the panel have any any
kind of followup or comments about Bank
or taxes that they want to make the
driving point because I I'll keep moving
this along um
Dale we've got AB 266 243 643 what is
going to happen in November of
2016 the language will drop in the next
two weeks we're told sooner sooner one
from uh reform California another one
from another group uh maybe maybe one
what's going to happen happen does this
bill that we saw is that going to become
relevant in the future or is is the
legalization initiative going to wipe
out all the medical cannabis regulations
what's what's your view of how this is
going to play out well uh that's a good
question um I think we should look at AB
266 as a starting point uh for the next
year to uh get the the Machinery going
and to get people in the industry
involved with the various State agencies
that they need to get involved with and
the various State agencies in in
position where they can actually deal
with the businesses um after that uh of
course any initiative is going to take
effect on uh November 9th uh
2016 and uh I think what you'll see is a
another sort of broader kind of
framework for General cannabis
legalization proposed that will sort of
fit like a large glove over AB 266 and
allow AB 266 to evolve into something
else uh there's going to be a lot more
legislation and a lot of Regulation
legalization is a longterm project um
it's it's going to be going I mean look
at prop 215 that's been 20 years and
we're still working on it uh it's going
to be 20 years and more that we're
working on uh these regulations for
cannabis is anybody else on the panel
want to just sort of follow up on Dale's
uh comments or any thoughts you've had
about how this is going to play out I I
keep telling everyone that I think that
once the initiative passes that this set
of bills uh regardless of all the work
and time and energy that went into it is
going to become largely irrelevant and
that the key language that I plan to
advise my clients on is the initiative
language and that that I'm going to be
transitioning them getting ready for
that as opposed to as opposed to this
Cal normal however would advise
everybody in the industry to look
seriously now at complying with AB 266
if you want to have a be a step ahead of
everybody else because people who are
compliant with AB 266 are definitely
going to be at the head of the line as
we move Beyond to 2016 and I we've
certainly been telling everybody every
grower and everybody uh you know with a
bakery or uh uh other product Services
been underground to at Le get a Boe uh
resale uh permit even though you don't
you aren't liable for taxes get the
permit so that you get into the system
uh it's going to be very important you
and we also have an expert Michelle peel
sticker from the Boe uh who can also
help with the sales tax issues or
register anyone here but like in
Colorado the medicinal the medicinal
dispensary owners um and the people who
were in The Market already actually got
first dibs into legalization so that's
correct and and we also saw that the tax
for medical can patient in Colorado 7%
versus the adult use or I use the word
adult use uh rather than recreational is
31% I believe so that's and you're
seeing a huge and gets back to Tony's
point about Market distortions you're
seeing a huge number of people still
getting doctor's recommendations going
into the the retail brick and mortar
places where you can both go as a
patient or as just a consumer but you'll
pay more taxes uh and and that does
create some distortions um Jeff rber um
you you're you a brave man you've uh
you're encountering the the the the the
Last gasps of a Dying regime uh and and
we should all applaud you for for
standing up in front and and taking it
and moving forward so I really really
want to acknowledge that uh for you and
for everyone else who's encountered law
enforcement and and and I and I have to
really watch my language in public about
this but it's it's really a tragedy what
what we're still seeing out there and
it's not ending it's not ending and as a
lawyer I can promise you and Bruce and
the other lawyers in the room will tell
you it's not ending uh not it's not
going to end until we we finally you
know Drive the last nail on the coffin
but you know we have a a a statute in
California called the health and safety
code section 11379.6 which says that you
cannot through any method chemically
extract from Cannabis and my chemists
who I cont contact with tell me that
everything you do that to cannabis is
chemical extraction whether it's smoking
it putting it in water extracting it
using CO2 extraction using butane
extraction and that fundamentally what
the legislature was trying to do with
that extraction statute was to prohibit
dangerous activities the bill that was
just passed has a license six and a
license seven for manufacturing which is
really extraction license six is for a
nonvolatile solvent I I don't understand
are solvent can a solvent be
nonvolatile yeah okay and then you have
depends on your definition okay so that
and that is the whole problem that we
have with all of it let me let me get
right there with you and then a type
seven which is the only license type
that was specifically uh shows in the
statute as being they're going to have
limitations to it I didn't quite
understand why they did that may maybe
the assembly men's uh the assembly men
uh who are here can explain that to us
but the type seven will be for volatile
solvents which are like butane and those
will be allowed but
limited what's going to happen to the
extraction industry as we move towards
legalization where do you see this all
going it will get much more
sophisticated but it will like where it
will actually go and what we're allowed
to do depends on the definitions so for
20 years we've had no definition of what
you're allowed to do in California and
that's created all the problems that you
see and certainly why we're kind of
caught up in that machine um and the
next step will be what is that important
definition of volatile so as you ask
many different chemists you know
different terms May mean different
things to different perspectives when
you have lawmakers who are not educated
in chemistry trying to set definitions I
often see cannabinoid defined improperly
even cannabis may be defined improperly
um that is the key fundamental piece of
any legislation or any law which is
those definitions so definition such as
independent or what a distributor could
or couldn't do what volatile means or
doesn't mean or what really are going to
be important pieces of the regulations
and that will Define who's doing which
part or not so you know water is that
going to be volatile or not volatile
alcohol how what you know alcohol is
definitely volatile so which types is it
set by boiling point is it a long
definition of every type of chemical we
don't know what those things are yet
today but that will definitely Define
who's allowed to do what and I think you
will see see great deal of scrutiny in
terms of your methodologies how your
cleaning procedures are done your
standard operating procedures your
building codes your equipment being
certified by engineering stamps and
everything that a processor is going to
do is be highly highly scrutinized in
terms of safety cleanliness and
operating procedures so it will move
much towards GMP production good
manufacturing practice and most
definitely will not be allowed to be
done in your backyard anymore my my
clients my clients in Colorado
um have learned over the years that they
have to spend a lot of money on
lobbyists and people who can work with
the legislature and Regulators uh have
you met with any uh of the legislators
or do you have a plan going forward to
get involved in the regulatory
rulemaking process that if the governor
signs this bill will then ensue
hopefully when he signs it yes we will
be involved um I've done that in five
different states so far to help State
Regulators really understand their
definitions understand you know what
testing means what manufacturing means
how this plant could be handled and I'm
certainly very anxious to get involved
in California to the greatest possible
extent that I can you know um William
wre you go by William or Bill or will um
has a um also has a company that uh does
a lot of work in the Cannabis sector can
you talk a little bit about where you
see issues such as product testing
consumer confidence and even product
liability for for product failure going
forward in a legalization regime
absolutely absolutely I mean uh doing
some research a number came out in
research 11.4 billion and that number is
not the state or the size of the
California medical marijuana Market even
though no one knows that number is it
was actually the five largest uh
pharmaceutical lawsuits for product
liability now just that's just a
staggering number anything you think
about God that could devastate an
industry and starting to read through uh
the proposed language for for ab 66 and
looking at how um testing is now become
an independent body uh there's been a
lot of companies in the state of
California today that do internal
testing they have full labs they do a
great job on putting out great product
but from a consumer's perspective they
want that independent they want that
third party to come in and confirm that
that product is you know is is
satisfactory you know it's safe they
they know what the potencies are they
know that if it's an edible or a extract
there's no residual solvents or they
know what the limits are and it's below
uh acceptable standards um so as the
industry continues to mature and kind of
give you a little bit of background with
my company is we assist companies in
multiple States through the legalization
process as Matt said it's how do I as a
business owner stay legal how do I not
get arrested how do I manage my cash how
do I you know handle the complete
vertical um so you know we clients in
Maryland Oregon uh pic have now client
in Hawaii which is going to be a great
place to go visit TR I like that client
I need need to go visit them a lot um ex
they're not going to let the lawyers
assist them according to the state 18
person State Bar committee that just
issued an opinion the other day you just
can't form their company but um as it
relates to uh testing going forward I
mean there's some conflicting language
in a266 whether or not it's to be you
know can the cultivators or the
manufacturers go direct or does it have
to be managed by the distributor I think
as the uh assembly men have said you
know some of that cleanup language is
going to come through you know where is
that process going to be um but we have
to look at it from an industry side we
have to look at it from a consumer
safety side specifically with
recreational hopefully right on the
corner you know the recreational
Market's going to be looking at is this
product safe you know we don't want a
repeat of what happened in colado end of
last year uh you know prob heard of the
livewell scenario where you know some
supposedly non-infused um uh product was
given away at a at a at a trade or at a
a local event you know and I think a
number of people got SI
cuz they thought they were eating you
know non-infused candies um so from a
liability side you know we're just
starting to see some precedents and as a
business owner the the biggest concern
is you know we've acknowledged or the
federal government acknowledged in in in
the bankruptcy courts you can't declare
bankruptcy so what happens if you get
sued well number one you need to have
great insurance number two you need to
ensure that you're doing everything you
can do to communicate to your customer
of you know product issues product
liability issues um
and I'm not an attorney so but basically
we have enough in the room but the
aspect would be is you know making sure
that you're communicating the everything
you need to do from a labeling side from
a product side uh to your consumers so
that you're protected um just a
correction I I've actually put clients
in bankruptcy in the sector so at least
out in the ninth circuit we've done that
that may be different in Colorado I saw
opinion that there anyone have any
comment on on on on Will's uh uh
statements anyone
yeah good I would just like to say
whenever there is a bad actor or a bad
situation and there's media that's when
legislators get all worked up cuz then
we feel like we have to go fix it so I
agree with you like to the extent that
you know you're you know labeling you're
warning you're you're you know policing
you know yourself to make sure that
consumers aren't taking you know too
much product you know I like the rookie
cookie in Colorado where they're you
know actually you know educating folks
firsthand like if you don't know you're
not ready don't do it but um those are
kind of the things that will keep you
know the legislators and government out
of this
industry and I would Echo the same thing
I mean all of regulations are really
about building a good label for consumer
protection and information so all the
testing that's required is to protect
the consumers as well as understand your
operational effectiveness and
efficiencies so it's not something that
I should have to do it's something I
want to do for my brand for my business
for all of those people that are going
to be impacted by the products and it's
really a great sign of responsibility
and something that everyone should
embrace and want to do and as a testing
lab for five years no one wanted to do
it because they thought they were going
to be charging themselves you know an
extra cost but it really is a good
investment in your business and it's a
responsibility position that says I care
about those who are going to be impacted
by the products they're consuming well
it's pretty clear based on everything
we've heard today so far that there will
be people who will be able to make the
transition and people who won't you know
one of the statistics I like to use is
in 1902 there were 207 car companies in
the United States 8 years later in two
1910 there were three and I I think
everyone is going to have to learn a
whole other level of professionalism and
approaching this if they're going to
survive uh Amanda last but not least and
for sure not last but not least because
Amanda Ryman and the drug policy
Alliance have were you know I always say
that the drug Reform Group like Dale and
Amanda and drug policy Alliance and
other groups brought the ball down to
the 10 yard line and that it's in
probably that the business sector is
going to bring it over the goal line
because of the money resources they're
bringing the Republicans into the
discussion I mean they've just done a
lot but Amanda's drug policy Alliance
and her energy in doing reform work and
in Pro you know Prop 47 that the drug
policy Alliance did I mean I can't glow
enough about the drug policy Alliance
and about what the work you guys have
done I mean really on the ground really
really important work so here we are
Amanda we're probably about to legalize
marijuana the very thing that that you
have been working for uh and and you
know and and and and there's going to be
a lot of work to be done in the next
year and we all know it's it's going to
get nasty and dirty out there there's no
question about it and we're all I'm
rolling up my sleeves and you know we
know we've talked about the plans that
were things we're doing what's going to
happen to your work after legalization
where where will you be your focus what
will the reformers and the folks
concerned with social justice issues
what what will you be
doing retiring in Hawaii
yeah um no I think that's a really good
question you know I was at the Cannabis
business World cannabis World Congress
uh last week also down here in Los
Angeles and really remarking about how
things have changed in just a very very
short amount of time in terms of who
attends these things the type of booths
see I mean there was a time when you
would come to these events and the
booths were all either how to grow pot
without anyone knowing how to pass a
drug test or hemp clothing and pipes I
mean that was the booths at these events
and now it's really changed um but I
want to take a step back for a minute
because you know a lot of what we've
talked about on this panel has to do
with that second part of that two-part
definition of legalization and we focus
on that a lot I mean because as you said
you know maybe that's what's going to
bring us over the goal line right is
this idea of the actual industry that
this will create and the money that
comes along with it however there was a
lot of marijuana selling and purchasing
and consuming going on in this state
long before we ever even had the idea
that it could become a lit industry and
so as we move now to this idea of
legalization we have to think about how
our history of drug prohibition and the
War on Drugs is going to negatively
impact this industry for certain
individual uals and that it's not okay
for that not to be part of the
discussion that always has to be part of
the discussion so what I wanted to do
here with my brief time is share some
information with you um to kind of let
you know why it's really important to
advocate for things like not barring
people with criminal histories from
getting into the industry by advocating
for policies that are expunge records
let people out of jail make sure that
they're not barred from getting jobs
that they're not barred from getting
housing that their children aren't being
taken away I mean these are very serious
issues and let's face it they don't
affect everybody equally and looking
around the room they don't affect too
many of us so I wanted to make this
point uh DPA and the ACLU we did a study
looking at who's getting in trouble for
infractions uh marijuana infractions in
California as we know in 2011 January
1st possession of less than an ounce
became an infraction in California
punishable by up to a $100 fine similar
to a parking ticket before this happened
though we still saw racial disparities
and who was getting trouble for
marijuana so when possession was a
misdemeanor we saw you know 6.6% of the
population in California's
African-American they make up 177% of
the folks getting misdemeanors so that's
before we even went to an infraction
then we go to an infraction and we're
like oh well now it's just a parking
ticket now it's no big deal well let's
see if what Los Angeles did with their
infractions the first year that they had
infractions on the record um so in Los
Angeles African-Americans make up about
10% of the population and they receive
25% of the marijuana citations now when
we go to a town like mine of Oakland
which believe me I'm an evangelist I
love Oakland to death I will say nothing
but good things about them except that
in Oakland sorry African-Americans make
up 25% of our population and 76% of
people that are getting citations for
marijuana possession so even when you
look at a place that you feel is
extremely cannabis friendly we've got
Oaker Dam down the street we're still
seeing this kind of discrimination so
what does this mean for the
industry how many of you think back to
when you were 18 19 years old how many
of you were in the job that you were
going to do for the rest of your life
when you were 18 or 19 years old and you
were like this is my career forever and
I'm
settled right not a lot of us right so
the point is that when you're that age
you're still trying to figure out who
you are and what you want to be and you
don't even really know what you want to
be so here's the kicker when we look at
the average age that people are getting
in trouble for marijuana in California
it is not the same across racial
categories for whites infractions tend
to be given to people 34 year old 34
years old or older for people of color
blacks and Latinos it's 19 years old so
here we are creating this awesome
industry with all of this opportunity
and we're going to be cutting out people
that before they're even old enough to
bu a drink have been labeled person non
grada in the new legalization industry
of marijuana and that is not okay so
while we can get really
[Applause]
excited about the industry and while we
can utilize the fact that it is bringing
tax revenue which can go to schools and
can go to after school programs and can
go to the kind of services we need to
bolster communities that have been
targeted by the War on Drugs we have to
make a special attempt to ask ourselves
how is this going to impact the people
who have been most impacted and that's
where we should start from because
honestly at the end of the day it's that
first definition we have to take care of
before we can ride off into the sunset
and pay attention to the second one
right comment anyone uh want to comment
on on these issues yeah Dale uh yeah let
me follow up uh on plans after
2016 personally I'm going to retire I'm
going to be s next year my goal was to
legalize marijuana in California I will
have accomplished that hopefully by
November 9th 2016 and uh can uh uh uh
relax but normal is going to stay around
because Normal is the National
Organization for the reform of marijuana
laws and most of the United States will
not have legal marijuana after 2016
there's a lot of work to do and as long
as it's illegal elsewhere in the United
States there's going to be this great
big black market demand that's going to
continue to drive the the pirate Growers
here in California who have been such a
a problem for our environment and
otherwise D you know that that's a
really great point you raise is and what
happens when we vote for legalization in
2016 to the rest of the country what you
know California they say leads the
nation right we we talk about you know
so many things the environmental issues
here start here does does it is it going
to is it going to matter that we
legalize in terms of the rest of the
country well I think it will yes it will
matter to the politics of the rest of
the country and I was in Mexico and in
fact they were saying down there if
California legalizes Mexico's got to
legalize because help they're bordering
on us what do you think Amanda oh yeah I
think that the implications for
California legalizing are way more
International than National I mean
everyone in the country thinks we crazy
so when we pass legalization I don't see
like other states being like well
California does that we want to be like
them I mean I think it does create
momentum but I think it's more about you
know having an economy as large as ours
having legalization when other countries
smaller than ours want to legalize but
aren't able because of the single treaty
on narcotic drugs which is going to be
discussed next year and so I think for
the very first time the discussion is
going to be do we just take marijuana
out of the list of drugs that countries
aren't allowed to legalize and if that
happens which I think California
legalizing will be a big impetus for
that you're going to see Mexico I mean
lots of countries that have wanted to do
this but haven't just because we've said
no and we're the seventh or eighth
largest economy and that that's what
you're saying matters Fiona so I just
wanted to add my my office passed me a
little note asking to explain the
difference between the initiative
process versus the legislative process
and we're talking about legislative
process and I just want to give a shout
out to Hezekiah Allen uh and and um um
uh M Jamie Kerr who have been you know
roaming the halls in Sacramento
educating uh the elected officials and
they've been doing a great job as well
as Matt and can uh California Cannabis
voice but when we pass legislation at
the state
level legislators can change the
legislation at the state level so if you
know 266 you know we passed it they
don't think it's working they can go
back and they can change it internally
within the body when we go to an
initiative process once we pass it by
initiative the only way we can change it
is to go back to the
voters so that's a big difference
between what happens in Sacramento and
what happens Statewide and that's why I
think Matt's saying you know depending
on what's in the initiative the
initiative trumps what happens at the
state level so the legislature could
actually pass legalization we wouldn't
have to go to a voter initiative right
isn't that how that works assembly men
would you ready to take that what why
don't you just right right let's just do
that right so it isn't it is important
that everybody ways in with your
legislators you know with the initiative
writers you know op EDS whatever it can
be because I'm just telling you you know
coming from San Francisco I did not
realize all the issues and if I don't
realize the issues forget about like
everybody else that's you know um you
know in in public service so I just want
to encourage everyone to do as much as
you can to go and be friend offer your
card go in meets you know offer you know
ask him to come on a tour because it has
made a huge huge difference to like me
and my team and how we view this whole
industry and what we need to do as
public servants let me let me turn now
it's now September 26
2025 10 years from now we've legalized
marijuana in
California what what do what does that
look like out here anyone anyone can
give me a little you know I've been
through this before 20 years ago when we
did prop 215 and I remember when it was
coming down and I knew it was going to
win but I knew that I had no idea at all
what it was going to be like the next
day and I and and I really did not I
mean the dust is still settling from
that meteor uh so uh you know I think it
would there's no way to to speculate at
this point what it's going to be like
but let's do concentrate on November
2016 and take it one step at a time
anyone uh thanks for the advice is
anyone I I like
speculating forecasting is has been
essential for my practice of law for the
last 15 years my clients want to say
what's going to happen next what is it
going to look like anyone anyone have a
well I mean I hope we have a much bigger
broader solid base of knowledge about
cannabis how it can impact different
people how you can guide them to the
right products because we know more
about the plant what it offers people's
physiology and interaction with the
plant and how we can create
professionalized standardized
reproducible products for those specific
Al in that fashion and that they might
even teach yes no thank you they might
even teach what the endocannabinoid
system is in medical schools which they
don't do yeah Amanda um well I would
like to see cannabis regulated like
alcohol and what I mean when I say that
is that I would like it to be just as
easy for me to go out with my friends
and consume cannabis out in the world as
it is for me to consume alcohol out in
the world yeah that may take 10 years
yeah good well well yeah I I do agree
with her Amanda I mean if we look at 10
years now we want to see the Tipping
Point you know I know you talk about
International but we still got to think
National and down and focus on what does
normal need to do nationally to get all
of these states one of the things we've
seen from our perspective is as new
codes are coming out you know Colorado
Washington laid down the foundation now
with Oregon and Maryland and other
states you know there there's a lot of
best practicing and Fiona just went to
Colorado and looked at banking what's
going on there so what I think we're
going to see is once California's regs
are done whether it's ab66 is the final
one or the recreational RS that come
following and the procedures that behind
that is other states now have a
blueprint in which they can just pass
and roll in you know they can keep their
government costs at a lower point and
they can immediately roll out and start
recognizing that tax revenue um and you
know from a 20125 I mean we really want
to see interstate commerce I mean if we
really look at I mean I'm right now
originally from Southern California
living in Las Vegas I look at indoor
grows in Las Vegas they're they're
tremendously costly operations and
they're inefficient we need to be
relying on that California Cannabis that
could be shipped Interstate you know
from Sami and Menina homeo County the
Emerald Triangle you know we got to get
to the point where we see interstate
commerce where we can keep efficiencies
abroad and keep this business going
strong yeah if you want to you had
something or you want to well I mean
it's taken 20 years for us to regulate
215 and even then I don't
know what's what's really going to
happen right um because it's you know
just a framework but there's no de uh
details the devils are in the details
and I would just encourage you know um
all of you who have been operating in
this Sphere for the last 20 years and
doing what you think has been the right
thing kudos for the industry but we have
not been Reinventing the wheel you've
been using like standards that have been
used by the federal government the state
the international um community so I
would hope that our legislature does not
go back and try to reinvent all the
standards for for all of the different
you know industries that are in here
because you guys have been using
established standards and it's been
working and and everyone just needs to
step forward and not be afraid to come
and talk to the legislators who are very
interested in hearing more about this um
I think maybe we have time for one or
two questions anyone have anything uh
yes uh Mickey actually could could you
stand
up uh Mickey Norris has been an advocate
for cannabis legalization for I think 40
years now since 89 89 88 and as a dear
friend with her husband Chris Conrad and
Chris has been testifying around the
state trying to keep a lot of our our
friends and colleagues out of jail and
so a real Round of Applause actually to
you and your husband uh you know I mean
this is this is we we're this is a
celebration beginning despite the war
that's still out there and the
skirmishing and the islands that are
they described earlier that uh uh you
know there's so much that people like
you did did and Dale and and Bruce I
mean this is a real celebration we're
we're getting we're we're winning we're
winning it's just taking time to finish
it off good your question okay to me
legalization isn't complete until
cannabis
consumers enjoy all the our equal rights
the same as everybody else in society
including our you know rights to have
our family a right to work um all to
receive the benefits of society that
everybody else does and I'd like to see
some Protections in initiatives or
legislation do you see that coming down
I mean with the with legalization will
hopefully come the end of stigmatization
that that has perpetuated prohibition
and and all the harms that are
associated with it but to me it's a it's
still a matter of civil rights and and
we're not done until we have our civil
rights um one big thing that happens
when you legalize is that the odor of
cannabis is no longer probable cause to
suspect a crime which is a huge change
from where we are now uh so
that's a big uh change for civil
liberties and I I suspect that there's
going to be some advances for civil
liberties at least for medical patients
uh forthcoming um uh in 2016 too yeah so
um I also spent six years in the legisl
before I termed out and the difference
between again the legislative process
and the initiative process in the
legislative process you have 120 members
uh who are trying to work together to
try to come to some common usually a
majority vote when you go to the
initiative process you can write
anything you want in the initiative
initiative writers can put anything they
want it does not it is not subject to
attorney general uh attorney general um
review it is not subject to the
legislative process review so that's
kind of the good and the bad right the
bad is that you want to change it you
have to go back to the ballot the good
is anyone can put anything they want
like every day will be Fiona Ma's
birthday and I have to get gifts and if
the voters pass it then that would be
the law of the land right that is the
truth of the matter so we really need to
work all of you need to work with the
initiative writers to put in all the
things that you think the state should
be doing and just a note you can
actually put an initiative that certain
sections of it can be modified by the
legislature right so you actually do
have a little bit of a middle ground
there uh which which we hope to see um
any other uh questions before we uh
thank the panelists uh for being with us
today one more question no yes yeah go
ahead loud please just speak up I want
to know when it gets
[Music]
how what you're talking about the 2016
and initiative once it gets passed and
we're probably not going to be using
word dispensaries anymore that's sort of
a medical term say brick and mortar when
when will the first brick and mortar
state license uh get re uh receive a
license because we already have the
other dispensaries it'll it'll be about
the middle of 2018 earliest depends
what's in the initi it depends what's in
the initiative as well you're going to
see normally in initiatives like this
and and with even with 26 6 there's a
regulatory rul making process that takes
can take a year year and a half
depending on how well things how fast
the government can move and then once
that is finished they'll issue the
applications they'll start reviewing
them and then they'll be issuing them
and I think Dale's right sometime if you
pass it November 2016 you're probably
looking at 2018 before the first license
would issue yeah so Colorado when they
legalized it took them over a year
because the legislation said that you
had to get a local permit before you
could get a state license and then
everyone kind of sat around going well
who's going to go first and so finally
right the state had to push and say okay
fine we're going to give you a license
assuming you're going to get a local
license and then that process took a
year even for that um for
them yeah it could it it could depend
plan on two years I want to thank the
panelists if everyone give a round of
applause for them for thank you very
much
n