that's why we've seen the true medical
market in cannabis be decimated I worked
with parents that were already spending
$1,200 a month for their child who has
epilepsy and now it's over 3,000 or
$3,600 a month when they can find it and
it's not the same as it was before
and so we've we have lost the medical
market and that's why I got into
cannabis like cannabis saved my life I
had epilepsy for years and I haven't had
a seizure in four years now because of
cannabis and and and I forget that at
times like this is why you got into this
industry is to help patients and to work
with doctors and bringing down stigma
and that is a huge part of what we're
still fighting here stigmas going down
but at what cost