so Eric let's put you on the the
cannabis business psychiatrist chair so
to tell us I I want to dig into kind of
your path in your journey so so you're
do you know anyone else who is as small
as you are from a cultivation
square-footage standpoint which is 2,500
square feet no no a lot a lot of my
friends that work with you know they
have been much larger facilities 10,000
square feet you know I'm a bit of a liar
Lauren do you know any cultivators that
are only at 2500 square feet
[Music]
Oh better hey I might know one or two
but not that I can think of it doesn't
jump out at you all right is it by
choice is it by necessity as a tactical
you're you're you're playing chess when
everyone else is playing checkers yeah
you know that's an interesting question
how much how many businesses are like oh
yeah I like being really really small
you know going bigger if it's kind of
you know I've been in this since early
2005 so I've kind of seen the evolution
of this industry and I would say
probably around 2009 or 10 you started
noticing more outside money coming in
you know back in the Bush years
everybody was scared to get into
cannabis unless you were okay with the
idea of going to jail for selling
cannabis you know a lot of a lot of
people that's not okay with them you
know it's kind of a few of us kind of
nuts that hit that were okay with at a
time but it's what we had to do so you
know when the when the Obama
administration came in people started to
get less fearful going to prison for
cannabis he started seeing more people
entering the space that were hesitant to
do it before and by about 2010 or 11 we
I just started noticing more and more
money come in and where I saw that money
backing up were operating
is that you know to me I had known and
they had been around and I wasn't very
confident in their abilities to scale up
and so fast-forward further to 2014 you
know I got my small warehouse here and
by 2014 a 5,000 square-foot warehouse
was not on the low end of things you
know it was it was medium to small you
know but you know people were just
starting to look at 20,000 square-foot
warehouse and really going bigger so as
this is going even more money is coming
in and these operations are kind of
getting very inefficient and then as we
were looking to expand about 2016 and we
started having to compete with the
really cheap money out there and we
looked at a bunch of spaces we spent
about a year and we we landlord started
charging exorbitant fees for space you
know we look at places with rent like a
$3 a square foot and it was completely
unsustainable so for us we're a
bootstrap operation we can't you know we
don't have a huge fund to operate at a
loss and as we try to gain market share
so basically just put my head down and
we were just gonna work with what we had
and just try to weather the storm I knew
at some point the bubble would pop and
if you have a large operation that is it
isn't making money it's just a lot more
to cover and so with us we've kept a
small lean operation so going through
this you know we we've really had a easy
time managing the storm and at some
point when this pops my idea was some of
these companies are not gonna make it
because then they're just structurally
incapable of surviving and so when that
happens permits are gonna be coming up
the price should drop from 3 bucks a
square foot down to something reasonable
even a dollar 50 which is still a little
overpriced but still can work so that's
the plan is just keeping solid with our
small operation how running tight books
and you know we'll grab the opportunity
when it makes sense and you know over
the last three four years looking at it
it hasn't made sense and we looked at
expansion would mean something
sustainable and I would mean bringing on
more investors and you know I'm in this
for the long run I want to have a
company ten years from now 20 years from
now and we're not you know when we
weren't trying to build something up and
just flip it and get on it you know I
got I'm a lifer Eric this is super
interesting one of the themes that's
raised it's interesting that in the
current uncertain times smaller
operations may have an advantage over
the larger ones and that smaller
operations kind of defines you what do
you feel about that and also do you
think that you might see real estate
prices start to come down and maybe more
opportunities some spaces that were
previously unavailable become available
I think it has to happen i I can't
envision a scenario you know we we all
know there are some larger companies out
there that are running pretty serious
operating deficits and I think if the
laws of percentages you know it's a
larger company if everybody's operating
at the same loss percentage the larger
company it's really going to be a bigger
number than a smaller company so I mean
that's one thing where I think the
smaller company does have an advantage
obviously you have to do things well
having a small company that's failing
versus large company failing it's all
failing you know it's just what's the
level of failure I mean I've always
likened this kind of to the late 90s
dot-com boom where you know you can't
have 10 companies selling pet food
online but at the same time it's gonna
come down to just a couple of them some
of them are gonna be inefficient but
weathering the storm especially if all
10 of those companies are operating at
deficits operating at the smallest
deficit is gonna be the advantage you
know at some point turning that into
round you're going to be the quickest to
actually start operating on profits and
at that point I think the world's going
to be your oyster and with most cannabis
called to be
I know I I don't I can't really think of
any of them that are really running on
profits right now everybody is some are
very close to breaking even and some are
far away from breaking even but I don't
really know that any cultivators that
are just you know absolutely destroying
it on their books it's you know it's me
I'm sure there might be one or two that
are kind of barely there but it's just
what the tax is where they are it's near
impossible so let's dig into this a
little bit and we've talked before we're
friends I've interviewed you and we've
talked about your business and you have
tight margins right like you run a
really tight lean operation and I think
the last time we talked you said like as
long as people are willing to spend you
know 50 bucks for an a you're gonna do
okay so our people still willing to see
that and what about the dynamics that
are outside of your control price points
at the dispensary and and all of that
all of that stuff that that you know
could potentially affect you really
seriously have you had are you changing
a lot of shops is your product like what
do you you know how have you had to let
some people go
how have you survived you maintained
with those thin margins we we actually
we we brought one more person on so on
ours we haven't let anybody go we've
hired one more person we have is the
team right now we have seven seven
employees up from six to seven and then
there's three managers which I consider
myself a manager as well yeah in that
and that's part of it I do a lot of the
companies will have four people doing
what I do you know I head of sales I
also handle the compliance the metric
the accounting quality control and I and
I still do deliveries as well it which
is not as far as I know about the only
owner of a company that shows up at
dispensaries with the deliveries and
just like hey I'm own or two so but it's
great because you know
again I'm also I also do the marketing
and with no marketing budget you just
have to be creative you know and you
have to you know my a lot of my
competitors have a large well they used
to have a large marketing budgets and I
never had a marketing budget so it's
kind of my my strategy is always
asymmetrical warfare if if you're you
know if your opponents are doing one
thing and you can't do it you have to
figure out something that they can't do
and so with me it was just engagement on
the ground level of people at shops they
can spend fifty thousand dollars a month
on marketing I can do that but I can go
into the shops and personally make
connections and bond with the staff
there and get them to become believers
in my product you know and that that's
something you can't do with the
marketing budget you know unless you
just can't because your team isn't going
to go to the same levels that an owner
of company is gonna go to so so just
quickly you're the one managing like the
Instagram and all that stuff yeah yeah
yeah as you can see by my whopping 1,500
followers so I'm a better farmer than a
social media guy yes I back to price
points you're a quality grower you're
like where now do you lay in the in the
in the scale of price points in the
shops and how sensitive are they to to
that right now
so which which shelf are you on we're
definitely a top shelf product and our
direct competitors are the premium
brands out there so and who would be
some of the other top shelf brands
things like maven kingsguard
there was one other one I gotta throw
THC designs out there you know because I
love those guys Pro Farm is another
great brand but you know so some of
those I'm very good friend Pro Pharma th
you designs are very good friends with
them we go way back you know they're
they're like friend competitors you know
I'm I'm happy to see those customers I'm
happy to see every business in our space
do well because at the end of the day
I'm a cannabis community guy and we're
all cannabis community and you know III
want every business in our space to do
well because we're weed people you know
it it's better to get along as we people
without but but those are our direct
competitors or those companies they're
also doing a very great job they're
producing great flower and they're at
price point similar to us what I have
noticed in the last two months is there
has been some volatility in the
wholesale market price and I have
noticed some downward pressure just
generally you know I think premium price
used to be you know about twenty one
dollars to twenty five or twenty six ol
sale and I see it starting to kind of
fall to around eighteen to twenty and I
think it's starting to get hard no
matter how good the product is to go
much over twenty some of them do so
we're starting to really look at
wholesale pricing and how it's gonna
affect our margin as well
and you know and as far as that just
getting efficiencies and yield increases
to offset any sort of a wholesale price
if we have to look that way but you know
analyzing wholesale prices is definitely
just just from talking to buyers we've
been looking new shops
I just brought on a sales person as well
to start going to the San Diego area
we're gonna start being carrying down
there you know this is always saying
we've actually in the last two months
been looking more at expanding than
contracting so you know it's a it's a
good thing is kind of the moment we've
been waiting for and I've been waiting
for the kind of crash to happen and this
is for us and a small company I feel
like this is going to be our time here
to breakout so that's kind of what we're
we're pushing for us or we're definitely
be more aggressive right now than we
have been well as a tiny company you
don't need to be in a lot of shop so how
many shops are you in now we as of last
week we were in 16 we are now in 18
shops and you know we're optimistic
we're gonna have three or four more by
next week and we're gonna be any close
to our cap I think we can probably
sustain right now with our increase
about 24 shops total so we're we're
bumping up to that next level and at
that point we're gonna have to stop or
else we're not going to be able to
supply our existing shops and
and then at that point is when we start
looking to expand and are you following
kind of the craft beer model which is
you you can centrically start with your
home turf like you're not trying to sell
up into Humboldt and the Bay Area and
Sacramento as a tiny la brand or are you
spreading out yeah a little bit also
about the legacy nature of your of yours
of your strains I mean legacy is an
important part of your brand right yeah
yeah it is it is which is which is funny
when I thought up the name legacy it
wasn't a term for the old heirloom
strains that it is now but it just kind
of worked out but you know a big history
nerd I've been in shop since early 2005
and I started noticing a lot of the
strains from that day were just
disappearing and so pretty much what we
run is almost a history library we we
run the heirloom streams most of our
stuff is 10 to 30 years old our genetics
you know we have the master Kush which
nobody really has we have trainwreck
which is another one that's pretty much
disappeared
we run Sour Diesel but the real the the
Massachusetts cunt chem dog from the 90s
that's we run we have a Malibu 9u1 OTV
from Rick Shima we got you know we got
that from you know all the legendary 90s
grower that passed away about nine years
ago but anybody around LA in the early
two-thousands knew who rich shiva was of
the early shops but yeah we really
specialize on the old classic Afghan
value always another one we have and you
know for me I'm 42 and I know a lot of
people who are late 30s and 40s remember
these old strains and you know at some
point I lava cakes are good and the
various gelatos and sherbert sand it's
great but sometimes you just want those
classic strains that you can find in the
big book of buds or you read about you
know in High Times and Rosenthal was
going back in the day you know I think
there's a lot of appetite for the
nostalgia and I just would hate to see
it disappear and since cannabis and
genetics is such an oral history you
know it really just relies on kind of
storytellers to keep it alive you know
and we're kind of a storyteller
what we grow I think so sorry with 2500
square feet you have how many different
cultivars we have 12 which is not the
most efficient thing and we don't run
all 12 at once you know some of them we
run more seasonally we probably have
four main strains that we do the most of
but will rotate in other ones here and
there again just because I just don't
want to lose them and some point we a
larger facility you know we can focus
more on it but does the seasonality work
from a marketing standpoint where it's
kind of like hey this this this strain
dropped in this shot or in all the shops
and get it now because it won't be
around for long and people come running
in because they know that they won't be
able to get it in a month it's really
more you know and when you flash my
social media with my small number on it
the one thing with that is that
everybody on that are very dedicated
legacy fans and you know I can be very
accessible with 1600 people when they
message me I talked to him back we
totally will geek out on genetics all
the time on there but it's more like it
it's really more the rare ones like the
look like the legacy glue which is you
know gorilla glue for which can't call
it that people will hit me up saying
when is this coming out and miss this
strain
but gorilla glue is still prevalent
enough that you can't you can't run it
that much he just has trouble moving
because it's so flooded so it's more
people will hit me up say when is this
coming out when is this coming out or
you know and it's more kind of the
demand picks up like that and of course
the second the second I stopped running
something for a bit then everybody
everybody hits me up for is the nature
of the beast that's a good problem to
have
alright so on an annual basis kind of
what's your capacity for like how many
pounds of flour are you producing per
year how many turns are you doing per
year
this year we're on track to do right
around 300 pounds okay and and then are
you sending kind of biomass
for extraction like are you is the whole
animal being eat killed and eaten and
used and or using it all yourself we use
it all ourselves views all of the animal
and funny you said that these are our
pre roles that we are working on they go
and they go into these nice little
pre-roll boxes these are our small nugs
and our sugar leaf part of the
advantages of having a small crew is
that my processing team does everything
from harvest all the way to pre rolls
they do you know they do the packaging
they do the trimming so our process you
know as it comes down you have your big
families that don't have THC on it those
all get trimmed off for the drying
process when the trimming happens the
sugar leaf that comes and gets combined
with the small bugs our sugar leaf when
we used to get us out to processing
tested already around 18% so it's very
good viable material along with our
small buds with your tests around 22% so
we blend those together our pre rolls
tend to average about 20% THD and we use
everything so we're not sending any
biomass out because the prices on
biomass are pretty tough you know and we
kind of came to this about four years
ago when the prices on biomass was at
probably the lowest has been which was
150 a pound and I'm looking at my really
nice indoor grown with lots of terpenes
and a great aroma to it and 150 a pound
and I just felt insulted by it and so I
was thinking what do I do with it you
know so we started working to create pre
rolls and that's another thing is to say
no so aside from our 300 pounds we
generate about 120 pounds of material
that goes into pre rolls as well are you
doing any kind of ice water hash or
anything like that or I don't we don't
you know we are strictly a cultivator so
we are allowed to do pre rolls and flour
we're not allowed to do any extractions
with our permit so I would have to
contract that out and then I'm competing
with the biomass market and they look at
a pound of my stuff like I looked at
account of outdoor stuff if there
weren't that regulatory issue
would you have a washing machine on site
like if you could do it tomorrow if the
regular just wave the magic wand what
would you start doing that maybe do like
hash and fuse pre-rolls or something
like that I I used to do this back in
like 2008 or 9 which you know I I used
to get into extractions and I used to
take my trim and make hash out of it and
I kind of realized quickly on that what
I love to do is grow cannabis and I knew
other people out there that love to do
extractions and so my passion with
extractions doesn't come anywhere near
matching theirs and so I felt like they
are gonna do so much better of a job
than I can I don't want to compete with
somebody is Patti in any area they're
passionate about because what I'm
passionate about is growing flower you
know so I thought it's just really good
to stick to what I love to do and you
know not do something that I'm not as
into and then the pre-rolls moving for
two pre-rolls instead just made sense
and I really I think it was a great
decision that we did our pre-rolls are
they're excellent pre-rolls if you know
and and how many are gonna be in a pack
like what's the and then the wholesale
on that yes yes yes in a pack we do a
half gram we do seven of them again I'm
old school or so I like everything in
eighth so our pure old packs are 1/8
joints 7 1/2 gram joints and they tend
to retail around forty to forty five
dollars you know it's after-tax some
places are as low as $35 plus tax retail
typically $40 and they're all single
strain you know we have black hay is
pretty rolls we have sour DT rolls every
stream we grow we also do a pre-roll
version of it bread and then just
quickly getting back to the question I
asked a while ago which was you know
your your your strategy for dealing you
know if you could pick 20 retailers my
assumption is you kind of want to pick
them where they're close you can go
visit that I mean obviously not during
lockdown but you know you can do
FaceTime and you're not out and you know
on what what's the town on the corner of
the Arizona Nevada border needles yeah
you're not like like needles isn't your
starting point with winning shops over
right no no although I am in some shops
in the Monterey Bay Area a good buddy of
mine I go back with oliver summers who
has try cannabis he has a shop in San
Jose in Castroville so you know two
weeks ago I got in my district van I
left a 4:30 a.m. and I made a delivery
to Santa Cruz
I'm Angela Brady Castroville drop
samples off at a shop in Seaside and so
I'm hoping to do a little circuit up
there as well but as far as shop
strategy you know and this is another
one where I have the advantage of being
a small company you know other companies
like THC designed with you know they
produce a lot of flour they they they
have to try to be in almost every shop
so for us since we only have for example
right now we have a capacity for 24
shops I don't I don't really want to
pick shops next to each other I would
like to pick shops like with a bit of
radius one I'm a personal relationship
and a customer service guy at heart
so it allows me to have this like a
loyalty relationship with somebody else
they know that the next shop down the
street isn't going to carry legacy
strains if my people want legacy strains
they have to go to that shop the other
thing it does for me is it'll help me
avoid slotting fees if I have an
instance where which which happened to
me where a shop I had been into a long
time hired some new buyers that came in
they tried to beat me down on my price
they said you're gonna drop your price
or we're not gonna carry you so I ended
up going a block and a half down the
street to the nearest shop that carried
them where a friend of mine became the
senior buyer and I took my whole catalog
over there they didn't want to basically
beat me on price or charge me a slotting
fee and and that's what it is and I
probably had a good 30 or 40 loyal
customers that went to that shop that
just moved a block in half down the
street and went to the new shop so to me
having that sort of like an exclusive
is what I came up with the only leverage
I'm gonna have against slotting fees you
know not I'm not gonna go to the shop as
slotting fees because it just won't work
so Lauren you you know Eric is a small
company and I assume you're working with
lots of kind of mom-and-pop operations
as well or are you seeing kind of like
what what are you seeing with your
client base in terms of the the business
and regulatory issues they're dealing
with as small companies so I do deal
with a lot of small companies and I
think you know some of the points that
Eric made are certainly true for my
clients in law as well in terms of being
able to feel a little more nimble as a
small company versus a larger company
that may have a lot more employees to
have to worry about or something like
that but I also find that the small
farmers are struggling a lot there are
just a lot of burdens and requirements
both from the state and from the local
governments the taxes are really a
problem that is brought up often and you
know that the lack of ability to get
some of this relief right now from the
federal government that's something that
has you know folks are hurting more so
than other businesses despite you know
uh efforts to try to make this business
treat it just like every other business
that's not really happening right now
so you know just the just the onerous
rules in the regulations the fear of
really not knowing what's going to
happen next you know in terms of is this
going to be consolidated is it not going
to be consolidated other changes that
keep happening and and there's the cost
the cost is getting to be it's it's a
lot for these farmers and so whatever
you know whatever can be done to provide
some both financial relief and and just
other regulatory relief would be in
these these businesses interests that is
you know the issue of dealing with
having to deal with the distributor
for example to do the COA testing I know
a lot of small farmers that just aren't
able to get attribution license due to
you know the specifics of their property
or financial constraints or anything and
it does put them in a situation where a
lot of times they have the at least it
seemed it feels like they have less
power in the situation than this big
distribution company they're working
with you know and something that our
office what we do is we try to you know
we do a lot of education to the
community and to our clients and you
know we've encountered lots of
circumstances where small farmers were
being taken advantage of by other you
know folks in the supply chain
distributors or retailers or
what-have-you and it's you know it's the
situation where we have folks in this
industry that are coming out of really
the shadows where people have been you
know growing secretively for many years
because of the law folks were told for
many years not to write things down you
know don't put it in a contract now
things have changed you know weigh it
down keep accurate records do it out in
the open it's not hiding anymore and
it's it is quite a shift in terms of how
you're operating how your mindset is you
know a lot of times there are folks that
you know just weren't necessarily from a
traditional business world and maybe
they can't afford to hire folks that
specialize in each of these areas so
they are having to take a lot of that
responsibility on for themselves so
there is just the learning curve can be
greater for certain businesses than
others smaller businesses but they're
super resilient too and I'm really
hoping that the small operators are able
to survive and they have to do things
like you know creating a great brand
that folks really appreciate and having
an that following it is it is hard to
compete with these massive operations
but it's not impossible I think I think
branding is is critical having a great
product is critical educating the
community about your product about your
practices I'm excited about the ocal
regulations that you know comfortable
to organic certification I have lots of
friends and clients who'd be interested
in getting that on their product once
it's available because at least let
people know we're doing this as
organically as possible even though we
can't actually use that word on it are
the rules and so you know a lot of these
same challenges have been shared and my
law office is a small office too we're a
small business there's you know three
attorneys and some support staff and so
I feel that we've been pretty good at
being nimble and adjusting to the
working from home environment and things
like that you know maybe more so than
some of the bigger firms are that are
doing lots of layoffs and whatnot right
now so that is you know just some kind
of observations you know for all these
businesses right now they're gonna have
to make some adjustments going forward
and that's just whether it's cannabis or
not and so it's important that we work
together as a community to provide
assistance to each other and I think
it's in in terms of other small
operators it's it's in other small
operators interest if there's if it
doesn't just become a situation that's
dominated by the big players right and I
think something that really makes
California's cannabis culture unique is
how many different farmers there are and
producers and the history just like Eric
and his legacy strains there's so many I
love the name of your company there's so
many legacy operators out there that
have that have made you know the
cannabis culture what it is today so I'm
hoping they're able to survive this I
think there's both pluses and minuses
you know I guess plus I'd be more nimble
than a bigger company but the the
negative side is a lot of times these
smaller mom-and-pop don't have access to
the same funding that the bigger
companies do and so that can make it a
little more challenging to pivot in
times like this but we'll see I've got
my fingers crossed
okay so my takeaway from what you just
said is that I should go into a
dispensary and buy weed from an out of
state MSO multi-state operator I should
go to support them
so just quickly two questions for both
of you well accounts payables has come
up kind of operator chatter and are both
have you seen obviously cash on demand
or on delivery would be nice but that's
not always the case or you Lauren across
your client base or you see more kind of
delinquent
you know accounts payables and and
either farmers or distributors or brands
or retailers being like where's well
maybe not the retailer's but where's my
money when am I gonna get paid because
obviously that puts a crunch on a
business when when you know someone owes
you money and you're relying on that
cash so that's for both of you and then
Eric just quickly I did if you're doing
three hundred pounds a year that's about
averaging 25 pounds per your twelve
strains right I mean obviously some of
you grow more some of you grow less but
the the minimum size for testing is
fifties you're just kind of sucking up
the cost of testing small batches right
so let's let's start with the accounts
payable but and then we can get on to
the batch size Lauren what are you
seeing with your clients or is anybody
frustrated that people aren't paying
them yes lots of people are frustrated
there is a lot of this happening just
like you said lots of bills going unpaid
and folks getting not what they thought
that they had agreed to and it's
definitely it is really a problem and it
doesn't just extend to the businesses it
extends to
ancillary businesses and whatnot the
whole system is kind of waiting to get
paid because they're waiting for someone
else to pay them and it's I think it's
pretty unsustainable I think that
there's some structural changes
obviously they need to happen for that
to get fixed and I also think that at
least you know for for our clients you
know it's important that when you are
entering into these agreements with
yours
pliers or your producers that you have
some terms in the contract that give
some parameters as to when payment has
to be made right and there can be a
range but it is important that you have
a system down for when you need to get
paid and what happens if you don't get
paid and there's a lot of folks that are
involved in handshake deals and that
gets pretty fuzzy in those circumstances
can you give some examples of good good
clauses you would have in that one to
expect payment section of the agreement
well it's going to depend right on on
what type of contract it is whether it's
between a cultivator and the
manufacturer if it's between a
distributor and a retailer and it based
on the parties obviously they can change
that however if the payment isn't made a
you know immediately right at the time
of delivery then I would say there needs
to be some kind of metric measured in
either days or weeks when payment has to
be made by and if it's not paid by that
date then there's gonna be some
penalties that kick in or maybe the the
contract is gonna get rescind that's
it's hard to say there's no
one-size-fits-all approach but really
the key is you have to have something in
concrete terms of a date whether it's a
specific date or a range and if payment
is not made then there has to be some
consequence that happens otherwise
people are just not going to get pay and
they're gonna think they're gonna a
beluga towei with that in the the
specific license license categories of
operators where are you seeing the most
uptick in delinquent payments is it
distributors to farmers is it
distributors to brands is it retailers
to distributors is it kind of work where
are you noticing the uptick the most i
probably cultivator is not getting paid
by distributors is what I'm seeing the
most but I've seen it in a difference
you know in different circumstances got
it and Eric what's uh does anyone know
you money right
now yeah i I'm nothing nothing that's so
outside of the dorm that I'm concerned
about getting paid but you know this is
another instance where I have have the
benefit where being a smaller company is
good and you know funny enough Lauren is
an attorney will hate this because I am
totally a handshake guy because I've
been in this forever and most most of
the shops I'm with a lot of my known the
owners for ten plus years because back
in the mid-2000s I've protested in front
of half of their shops when they're
getting da-rae so I just have great
personal relationships and you know as
it's just quickly can you give a shadow
to some of your favorite shops you want
to give some any shop some love yeah
yeah my alma mater where I worked for
nine years LA PCG and you know going
away from the handshake Showgirl Long
Beach
love that shop they have a great staff
the sweet flower shops where one of my
best friends became a senior buyer there
and I love the vibe of their shops yeah
let's let's go with the old Malibu Ning
and high tides a great shop as well they
go way back you know and try cannabis
see yeah every one of herb delivery as
well
goddess delivers I'd do a lot of
political work without ya shout outs to
shout outs to every shop to crazed
legacy pretty much with terms it's
everything everything these days is net
30 you know and part of that is the
shops still have quite a bit of leverage
because every day a shop is going to
have a ten different sales people trying
to generate new accounts of the shop and
so from purchasing managers standpoint
it's just you know it's just a cattle
call every single day and so being a
salesperson doing cold calls and
cannabis shops is just it's just a
really brutal occupation it's just you
gotta be able to deal with rejection
after rejection after rejection and
so part of part of what makes it tough
is if your net 30 start to come late you
know you you have to be very careful how
much of a fuss you put out up about it
because if you start putting up too much
of a fuss about it a lot of shops are
just gonna you know they're just gonna
decide to stop carrying your product and
go with somebody else I mean it's not so
much an issue with me but I do know it's
the issue with with a lot of other
brands that just really need to be in
every shop and so when that happens as
well you know with a lot of these big
defaults you know that I have friends
with companies that have kind of six
six-figure bills that Road by shops that
you know I you know they're trying to
figure out if they're ever didn't get it
back and you know throwing in laughing
is that is that one shop that owes them
six figures or in aggregate they're owed
six figures by a bunch of shops I hate
calling anybody out so I will merely say
that it was a large chain that offered
them stock for their consignment debt
Wow can I say a company name and you can
blink if I guess correctly med men the
actual mechanics of getting paid do you
get paid directly from the retailer or
coast through the distributor so how
exactly does that work good it goes to
the distributors so I don't actually get
paid if I did get paid I would be on the
hook for paying tax on the excise tax
which is on hold another thing
distributors have to go through but no
it goes to my distributor dn8 event do
you have a single distributor or a
couple distributors I have a single
distributor I'm distributed through the
same company that distributes tht design
okay and what company is that they are
13:46 la LLC
but yeah that's that's a company that
distributes THC design you know uh I go
way back the owners of THC designs are
really good friends of mine we've been
doing political work together for six
years you know and that's the benefit is
you know and another thing like Lauren
was saying with small businesses one of
the things we have with small businesses
I know TC designs is seems like a big
business but I mean it's they're they're
a mom-and-pop - they started they
started from absolutely nothing and they
grew themselves self-funded to what they
are today you know so they're not like
outside money they're not a Canadian
fund company or anything like that
they're a independent company and so one
of the advantages I think that a lot of
independent companies have more so is
that we're really plugged into the
cannabis community and I think the
cannabis community does treat their own
much differently because we've always
kind of been on a bit of a you know
countercultural group and so I think we
kind of stick together because we all
have this counterculture nature to it
and so I think when people who don't
necessarily share those same
counterculture ideas come into it you
know we kind of can spot them and I
think a lot of the small the small
operators here because we love cannabis
and we love the scene and we love the
industry and people who are into it and
so I think we kind of just naturally
bond together as kindred spirits and
this so I think the way we relate to
each other is much different than
relating to people coming in from Wall
Street or anywhere else you know anybody
wants into a great I don't mean to be
disparaging people coming in from Wall
Street or a comedian fun but you know
some of the some of them remind me of
people who used to make fun of me and my
friends for smoking weed at high school
you know and it's and now the here they
are you know like you know these that
cause losers and now they're running
companies in our space and someone's
like okay so what what are you doing
with the rest and up-and-coming retail
brands like High Times which obviously
is an old school like
legacy brand but is now also big
corporate player are you gonna have a
fuzzy relationship with those retailers
no I mean you know again I'm a customer
service person and one thing you do in
customer service is you never talk
poorly about your customer and these
shops are my customers if it's run by
high times if you know if let's I don't
know but let's say Dick Cheney decides
to buy some cannabis shops or no let's
say John Bainer because he invested in
the space already if they're a customer
they're gonna be a paying customer it
really does you no good to disparage
them or talk poorly about them you know
even the larger companies who you know
we may or may not have alluded to before
you know that a lot of them have been
customers of mine in the past and they
have great people working there and you
know when you're looking at the ground
floor no matter who owns a company when
you go into a shop you deal with the
blood tenders those are the same
cannabis people that we've always had
you know so as far as as far as for
myself like I would love every single
cannabis shop no matter who owns it to
take a look at my brand and consider
carrying it like I would hate for
somebody to not like my brand because of
some egotistical reason or political
reason or anything like that you know
it's it's just good to value you have to
value your customers no matter who they
are or else you're not going to have a
business you mentioned kind of getting
investment so you haven't taken on any
outside funding beyond either yourself
or maybe even just some family or
friends correct yeah I have a partner
who I started with back in 2014 that you
know we working our first space but yeah
I mean short of that and that's just an
independent one and a lot of it was my
savings that I built up I started
growing in 2006 I grew in a spare
bedroom while I worked in the dispensary
and then I had a buddy who moved to
Colorado from a loft downtown I took
over that and then I took over a garage
and Sherman oh so at one point I had
three residential cultivations going on
in at about 2013 I was ready to jump up
to industrial space and so I did not
want
no spots and yeah but otherwise so far
we've taken on no no investing we've
just bootstrapped it got it so getting
back to the question I had thrown out
there before about you know 300 pounds a
year 12 cultivars which breaks down to
about 25 pounds per cultivar which means
that you're you're not because I know a
lot of people who you know you'd love to
grow something random in a small batch
and get it out there but then you're
hammered with testing fees and so unless
you're growing at least 50 pounds in
that it doesn't make sense but you're
you're sending 25 pound or even maybe 15
pound batches out to get tested and and
what what are you paying for a test what
lab do you use well my so um my
distributor handle handles all the
testing and since they're such a
high-volume distributor we do get we do
get pretty pretty good prices on it but
um our average batch size tent we tend
to do split room so yeah we we do
batches of like 12 pounds at a time
which is definitely brutal it really it
really cuts into our cuts into our
margins in case some of our strains will
do full rooms up and then we'll end up
with about 20 pounds of it which is much
nicer but yeah lab lab testing eats up a
big chunk of money from us you know just
again because we do a smaller thing and
part of the reason for that as well as
because I do the sales so if I'm growing
in my whole facility to two types that
means that I'm going to have to have 40
accounts you know if I grow five types
then I can drop that down down
considerably because instead of taking a
half pound of time at my one variety
they'll take a half pound of four
different varieties and so it's just
less it's less sales work for me to do I
think if I really only grew one type and
I grew larger batches I would probably
have to spend that money on one or two
our outside salespeople to reach the
extra shops that I could get got it deal
any of your of your product no no we
don't hole so everything is everything
is packaged in Branham you don't do any
wholesaling or white labeling because we
had just heard recently from actually it
was Greg who said that he was actually
making more money wholesaling than
putting his product on his own shells
that that was the strength of the bulk
market for him it was the lunacy of the
of the tax and all this to create his
own put it in his own Brandon yeah yeah
the the the bulk the bulk market is
really has really strong prices right
now I'm not really sure why or what it
is about this but over the last few
months definitely the bulk prices have
really have really been strong and this
this would be a whole other issue for
somebody else other than me to tell you
why but but it's definitely is
definitely happening but does that play
a role in in your future plans at all
like if you were to expand I mean how do
you see that part of my if it continues
to be a strong market he's he's Greg
Prince's is selling to a very well known
brand which I'm not going to say really
well-known and for a consumer that's
just you know for someone like me
walking in that shop it's kind of
telling me I don't know necessarily what
I'm getting but but that aside there's
no reason to necessarily believe that
the strength of that bulk market is
going to necessarily go away because
demand seems to be there yeah I'm pretty
torn on this I do think that the most
successful operating model would involve
you selling 100% of what you produce
under your own brand
because otherwise if I'm if I'm selling
bulk to somebody they're paying bulk for
that and then they're doing additional
things on top of that which is going to
increase their cost you know and and
also as more operators and more
facilities come online I think
especially larger ones you're gonna find
that the bulk market is one that's going
to be much more subject to general
commodity prices you know like with it
with everything looking at this you have
you know your your crude oil price and
even you hear of your gasoline price
which is your finished refined product
and both of these markets are impacted
by each other but they're also both a
little bit separate you know your
refining capacity is gonna dictate your
gas price just like the bulk price of
crude oil is you know they're not
necessarily in a vacuum and so having
everything going out and branded you can
control what you're getting but if if
50% of your inventory you have to bulk
price if there's a glut in the market
and the bulk price drops 1,100 a pound
all of a sudden all of a sudden half of
what you're selling you're you're
probably losing money at or you're not
making anything if the prices say strong
with 18 to 2,000 which is where they are
now then then you're doing fine but you
know with anything else if if there's if
there's a space for somebody to come in
and occupy because you know if it's
costing everybody a thousand bucks to
grow a pound but everybody is getting
1,800 on it without markup more people
are gonna fill that space and produce
those pounds until all of a sudden you
have over capacity and then the prices
are going to crash and then when they
hit 11 the inefficient people are gonna
pack up shop and it's gonna be cyclical
but if you're selling your product to
consumers
you're kind of immune from all that
because you're just getting your
wholesale price per package date so
that's the place to be I think relying
on bulk whole sales as a business model
is playing with fire or a hot potato
it's gonna work out sometimes but
there's gonna be times it doesn't work
and you're gonna have to figure out how
to adjust to that but I think most
people relying on bulk are trying to
figure out how to get a larger
percentage into retail
as fast as they can which may be that's
part of why we're seeing some downward
pressure on wholesale prices in packaged
goods versus bullet yeah I was just
gonna ask you what your projections are
for kind of let's say end of 2020 spot
market pricing for you know per pound on
both the regulated market and then what
are your friends in the traditional
market telling you our is life is it la
dolce vita is life good right now or I
mean I've been in this room I don't have
a lot of friends and uh outside in the
traditional market anymore you know your
friends are all masochists they all like
the pain of getting into the regulated
market you know I guess the people the
traditional market are too busy going on
exotic vacations around the world
whereas I'm just eating ramen and
bitching about it with my regulated
market friends I don't know if they're
doing that now
so do you think in the regulated market
the per pound prices you know obviously
you have like top shelf mids whatever
but do you think on average prices are
gonna go up at the end of the year do
you see more farms coming online and
prices going down by the end of the year
the prices are so strong right now on
wholesale I I don't see how it could
last till the end of the year I mean if
it does I'll be mildly surprised I guess
I won't be totally shocked by it but I
mean the prices are really really strong
right now but might like it give me
ballpark pricing that you're seeing four
pounds of you know different caliber
flower of a top shelf and I know might
my knowledge is endure the greenhouse
stuff you know I so so let's do end or
top shelf indoor what's the per prompt
rice I hope I have multiple friends with
brands yeah about $2,000 cod4 bulk
pounds right now of good quality stuff
you know good testing you know we're
talking like 25% plus TAC like your top
Balt is going for mm sometimes 2,100
pounds co d I have even heard of
distributors prepaying for future
harvests that haven't even come down yet
that's how hot the market is right now
and I've never heard that and what was
it a year ago that same $2,000 pound was
a 14 okay
14 and growers calling me asking if I
knew buyers now it's it's a broker's
calling me asking me if I can track down
any any pounds out there you know and
send and yeah and in deaths this
happened about three weeks ago a month
ago I had I had somebody call me who I
used to know somebody who I never
thought I would hear from again
calling me asking if I can if I can find
them any farms that had any top shelf it
in Flour and that's that's when I was
like what is going on here you know and
I still really don't know but I just
know the markets really hot right now
I'm not on the bulk wholesale and I just
don't know I don't know how it can keep
up like this but right so for both of
you and let's start with you Lauren I I
thought it'd be interesting as we bring
people on if people can give an example
of a situation where you had to educate
either a local or state regulator
politician on some topic or you you had
a friend or someone who's you know
Lauren you're a lawyer so you you heard
of it you talked to another lawyer who
had to educate someone on something what
give me an example of something where
you had to educate or you know someone
who had to educate either a local or
state politician regulator on some topic
related to cannabis so that they could
be sensible with their policies and
regulations yeah I've got a recent
example of that talking about the
shelter-in-place orders that went down
for coronavirus in Sonoma County where
I'm where I live and where my office is
located
the county's original shelter-in-place
order when it was defining what's an
essential business and what's not an
essential business the first version of
it said that medical cannabis operators
were essential but it implied that
anyone that didn't have a medical
license wasn't included and it also said
that effectively like testing labs were
not essential unless they were testing
cannabis that was destined for a medical
facility and so I read that and I was
like there's no way that's not how this
works there's you know you're when
you're in the lab is testing products
they don't always know what facility is
going to be selling it the labs
themselves aren't designated as medical
or adult use they're also not they're
not really growing the plant producing
the plant anything they're doing
something that's a purely you know
testing health and safety you know
function and I had no idea why the
county had written their health order
that way and so I reached out to the
health department and I mean it turned
out that the county just had no idea how
cannabis testing labs worked and you
know I think they thought that maybe
they were affiliated with a dispensary
or something like that or that all the
you know products came in with a big
label that said this is gonna be for a
medical user this is not gonna be for a
medical user and was I explained you
know that's just not how it works I
would you know I was able to get the
county to revise their shelter-in-place
order to make it clear that all cannabis
testing labs in the county are essential
businesses and can stay open no matter
what they're testing and that all
cannabis businesses no matter whether
they're medical or adult use are
essential and can stay open because not
every person that uses cannabis a lot of
people use cannabis and what we really
is a medical way but don't consider
themselves the patient or don't have a
medical card and so they shouldn't be
excluded from you know the ability to
use the services and those businesses
that employ local people shouldn't have
to shut down just because the county is
you know misconception and so anyway I
talked with them about all that and I
was able to get them to amend the
shelter-in-place order so
but it needed education it was people
who are making these rules don't really
understand how the industry works don't
understand the supply chain and all the
intricacies of it I think the whole
medical versus adult use designation
really has its hasn't it creates some
problems like this where we're creating
you know two separate categories of
buyers and don't get me wrong there are
some people that absolutely are medical
patients and they deserve to be you know
I think prioritized above people that
are just trying to get high but even the
people that are just trying to get high
if they're doing it because it's calming
them down because like for me I have
that anxiety it helps my anxiety that's
a medical use I mean I might take xanax
for that instead and I'm not and so I
think we need to rethink you know what
we think of as medical use and just and
educate lawmakers about exactly that and
Eric do you have an example down in
SoCal of having to sit someone down and
teach them something
you know a lot of that was more you know
my 9 years behind the counter as a
budtender there was plenty of education
on that and misconception to kind of
speak into what Lauren was talking about
as well like I wonder percent agree that
people use cannabis you know it if not
medicinally is to improve a quality of
life which I would consider therapeutic
at the very least and you know there's I
think times where you know it's
important for people not to judge other
people and like with cannabis at the
shop sometimes people would come in and
some people were more obviously
disability than others and this is you
know going back in the mid-2000s when it
was much more strict on the medical and
I remember there was a older lady in
line and you know she had like a walker
and she had a younger kid in front of
her you know very urban looking with
that you know flat rim baseball cap all
that and telling there was a big line
telling him that he should let her go in
front of her because she was sicker than
he was obviously and I remember this kid
lifted up his shirt and he was just
multiple surgeries and just zippers up
and down from everything he had and it's
just kind of like you can't really judge
somebody by looking at them as well you
know and this is something we would deal
with law enforcement backbends who would
basically say medical cannabis is a scam
these people are just scamming it
they're not really sick you know and
they would say things like we parked
outside of a shop and watch people walk
in and now none of them looked very sick
and this is in West Hollywood you know
and my question is like how do you know
from looking at somebody if they're an
AIDS patient or a cancer patient I mean
short of having just done chemo you know
so so I really think with that a lot of
it is you know what one of the reasons
people really use cannabis and I think
it comes down to it at the end it's
really therapeutic and it improves the
quality of life and to me having
something chemically that can help
improve your quality of life as a
medicinal use you know and I do think a
lot of that does get shortchanged and
you know I even my
all you know I talk I talk about to be
about stoner culture and things like
that because that's there as well but
but I think deep down we're all using it
to improve our quality of life and so I
guess that's that's how I'd answer it
okay so Lauren can you talk about
something you guys are working on behind
the scenes that maybe is related to or
requires a legislative change and then
oh and or something that is is more
regulatory like the BCC CDFA or CD pH
can change without requiring legislative
change yeah I mean at the at the state
level you know we have reached out
individually to our state lawmakers and
asked them to support tax relief bills
because that's something you know that's
gonna require legislative fix and so I
do encourage everyone to keep putting
pressure on your local state senators
and representatives to support cannabis
tax relief measures just quickly on that
front I mean what's the reception like I
feel like it's about as obvious as as
you know the the Sun rising and the East
that taxes are way too high does the
state know that like when you talk like
who are you talking to and are they like
yeah we know taxes are way too high and
it's crippling yeah I mean so my
interactions for the most part have been
kind of with the folks that represent my
area who are people like Jim wood and
Mike McGuire folks that are super on our
side and so they're very much aware of
it I know they are doing what they can
to lead this effort and I think you go
over all folks in Sacramento do realize
that taxes are too high I think we can't
look at cannabis in a in a vac you know
we have to realize that the state is
doing a lot of other things too that
require money and you know for which
these taxes are needed these and other
taxes and so lowering taxes is always a
tricky conversation because that money
needs to that money's being used for
stuff and it's gonna have to come from
someplace
else potentially if they're not getting
it from this industry anymore
and I also think that given the current
state of the health emergency right now
things like requests for cannabis tax
relief are you know coming after things
like you know getting an emergency
health care and and and financial relief
to to businesses that got shut down but
I think the will is there I think that
maybe next session I think once I'm not
sure too sure how likely it is that
taxes are going to get state taxes are
going to get reduced during the pandemic
I can't predict the future maybe that
would be wonderful I I am I'm thinking
it might happen kind of once the
emergency has passed us a little bit
however like I said anything's possible
there's a at the local level taxes are
also big problem we haven't really
talked about that yet but a lot of
different cities and counties are also
adding their own taxes on top of the
state taxes which is where why the tax
they issue in general is so burdensome
and so that's certain local governments
may be more willing to alter that it is
Sonoma and I don't know if it's just
count like what's your is are you just
Sonoma County or their local
jurisdictions as well like Santa Rosa
that it's own yes and Rosa has its own
Canada's policy and their own set of
taxes that are lower than sonoma county
unincorporated cannabis taxes and both
of those relative to other
municipalities are they reasonable or
yeah I would say that Santa Rosa
reasonable in Sonoma County is
unreasonable relative I would say Santa
Rosa is more reasonable than Sonoma
County Sonoma County their their
cultivation tax structure in particular
is is complicated and it can get very
expensive you know it's based on the
size of the
as well as whether it's indoor/outdoor
mix light and it can get to be just if
you you know depending on what you're
doing you can get very burdensome and I
think it is higher than others I've seen
lower than some others I've seen but in
terms of just the industry in Sonoma
County right now is really struggling
it's something that would really help is
is reforming the local taxes as well as
the local permit process here in Sonoma
County that is very onerous people have
put in applications two three years ago
that haven't gotten to a hearing yet and
have been charged more and more money
for the county to keep reviewing things
and it's been bounced around to multiple
reviewers and so the county has just
some problems with how the program is
working and my understanding is there
are some changes that are going to be
made hopefully in the future that would
may move things around a bit the goal is
is to try to get all of cultivation
permitted through egg weights and
measures rather than the permit resource
management department that handles other
types of permits and so there is an
effort internally and from groups like
Sonoma County Growers Alliance and and
it's know a kind of a Business Alliance
of the county and some other groups to
change how all of that is done and
within the city of Santa Rosa I'm not
too sure if there's been any talk about
you know changing their process they're
pretty efficient within Santa Rosa and
they've approved a lot more cannabis
businesses and their taxes seem more
reasonable but the backlog of businesses
waiting for permeate away in your County
I don't know an exact number but there's
a whole lot I can get I can get that
information and you know distribute to
everyone is interested but there are a
lot of folks that submitted applications
and are waiting to hear back at least
probably at least 50 if not more than
that potentially even like a hundred
applications that have been filed and
haven't really got anywhere if not more
and so the county is only permitted a
handful of
you know can issue to handle handful of
conditional use permits for larger sized
outdoor grows in the two or three years
since the program has been active
there's a few more smaller permits that
have been issued and some permits for
things like manufacturing and
distribution but what's the what's the
square footage of the when you say
larger size what how big are we talking
so the way it is right now if you have
if you're ten thousand square feet or
less and you're in an agriculturally
zoned parcel you can get permitted
through the AG department but everything
else which is ten thousand and one
square feet up to an acre which is the
current cap they have has to go through
PR and be the permanent resource
management department and they have just
tons of bureaucracy and they're taking
forever and they their fees are higher
their application process is more
onerous than the folks that have about
ten thousand square foot or less and are
in an Ag zone and can just do it through
the AG department and so the idea is to
just bring all cultivators over to that
Naga Department process if possible and
so you know the former AG commissioner
and the current ad commissioner are very
much on the industry side here locally
and so they have been pushing internally
for that to happen and so we'll see
we're kind of waiting right now as the
county deals with you know you know
coronavirus but I've been talking to the
AG commissioner and he tells me that
sometime this fall that is going to be
discussed that type of a moving of
cultivation over to the AG department
and we'll see if the Board of
Supervisors is with it yeah I think that
really anything that they can do to help
people stay in business to get more tax
revenue again if they were to slightly
reduce local taxes and make it less
onerous to get a permit they would have
an increase in tax revenue because
there'd be more businesses that could
actually you know get permitted and
survive and operate and that's basic
economics exactly and is that something
that literally the Board of Supervisors
just has to get together and say all in
favor of reducing taxes by 50% say aye
or is it more complicated than that
well I'd have to you know I have to go
see at the county's current tax
ordinance to what extent they can lower
you know taxes you know what their
ability to do that is my my guess is
that you know they'd have to agree on
that and there has been some hesitation
but the last time reducing the county
taxes was really brought up to the
supervisors was before coronavirus it's
been a little while since that efficient
issue actually got all the way up to
them I think when it comes back to them
again which should hopefully be soon
it's something that the Sonoma County
Growers Alliance is taking on as a main
policy objective you know for the rest
of the year reducing the taxes when I
get back to them again they might be
singing different tune just realizing
how any relief they can provide is going
to help these businesses and the county
so yeah and that politically speaking
there has been you know the current
Board of Supervisors is pretty
supportive there's a one member of the
board who was very anti cannabis for the
longest time but seems to be coming
around
we had a new hemp ordinance that went
into place last month so people can now
grow hemp here in Sonoma County as well
as cannabis so that's something
interesting that the county's done not a
lot of counties have allowed both and so
it's yet to be seen how that's gonna
work out if that's fiction the Board of
Supervisors and so I'd say our strong
the industry's strongest ally I'm sorry
no words yes some weight which of these
this very diverse group of people is is
the most supported than the least
supportive this industry yeah the most
supportive and the the woman in red hair
she was just voted out so she's gonna
finish a term and there's gonna be
another white man replacing the lady
with with red hair but the most
outspoken advocate has been the lady in
the tan jacket that's Linda Hopkins and
the most outspoken opponent has been the
guy on the far right the suddenly larger
gentleman that's
David Rabbitt yeah he looks like a
closeted stoner can I fold in a subject
that you might be dealing with up there
I'm looking at an article lawsuit seeks
to shut down busy bees organics in wine
country this is in Santa Barbara County
but it's a X and so the lawsuit also
includes the the board is the
supervisors I think is they're accusing
them of a breaking certain laws in
approving certain permits but it's it's
ratcheting up and aren't you in wine
country also are you seeing any of these
dynamics and play yeah I'm up in the
wine country for wine could do more this
Sonoma and Napa area but something that
we have seen up here is concerned by the
wine growers that it's gonna cannabis is
going to impact there a taste of their
grapes the taste of the Y and they're
worried about that kind of a taint going
on they're concerned about the cannabis
industry using up all the water that
they need even though you know wineries
use far more water than most Canada
those farms do there has been there was
a RICO lawsuit that was filed against a
cannabis operator a year or two ago and
the idea was that it was hurting and it
wasn't it wasn't filed by a winery it
was just these people in a big house but
they were claiming that their property
value is going down because of the
cannabis farm next door I don't know
what the current status of that lawsuit
is I know the judge originally
throughout the RICO claims and was
letting other parts of it go forward but
then I didn't follow it I didn't really
know anyone directly who is involved in
that lawsuit but it is certainly a
concern that's being that is being
raised up here now another concern is
fire safety and making sure that all
these roads are fire safe by are
accessible we do have a lot of one-way
kind of dirt roads going up mountains in
the county and it's also fire territory
and if so it can be dangerous to have a
cannabis farm at the end of a one-way
road if you need emergency vehicles got
to come in and out this other people on
this
so that's been an issue that opponents
have started to use to oppose Canada's
projects it's looking at the roads to
get in and out making sure they're all
up to fire codes and and trying to
install projects based on something like
that and I think there is there's some
merit to that obviously the roads need
to be safe if you literally get vehicles
in and out safely and not get to a
problem where the fire truck can't get
there because the roads not wide enough
however I think that's also now being
used to stop like legitimate projects
that you know do have everything in
place but there's they're just trying to
stall them so how about raids you know
up and Humbolt Mendocino out in San in
the mountains of San Bernardino friends
have been talking about the raids are
coming back again and a full force are
you seeing that in Sonoma or what are
you seeing I don't think there's been
any raise in Sonoma County not that I
can think of I have heard about the ones
that you mentioned up in the angle and
down in Central Coast area thankfully
that hasn't really happened happened
here and I hope it doesn't I mean it's
absolutely you know terrifying when when
we have that kind of a harsh law
enforcement approach to people selling
these plants and you know I certainly
think there are folks who are bad actors
and the industry people that are growing
in you know state and national parks
people who are using dangerous chemicals
people who are just you know not
following the rules but that's not the
folks who are in the regulated industry
for the most part and so I'm hopeful
that they don't you know continue
resorting to those scary tactics that
really you know can leave people with
PTSD for a long time to come afterwards
yeah I mean and Eric how about in in LA
the raids they have don't come close to
making a dent in anything you know and a
lot of it as well is that especially
with kovat 19 going on there there has
been a lot of a lot of violent offenders
released from jail who are back
the into the city here and so property
crimes have gone way up
break-ins have gone way up and that's
something I've over the last two months
with indoor growers here break-ins have
probably went up a thousand percent you
know I know I know of uh
some companies that have had attempted
break-ins every week you know and
typically maybe you'll get an attempted
break-in once every three or four months
you know cuz it just happens you know
there's there you know a lot of these
are done by criminal gangs and it's very
organized but yeah the amount of
break-ins over the last month and a half
is just levels that I've never heard of
before so that's definitely something
going on but yes and then police are
just very occupied here with everything
else for them I think cannabis is a very
low priority which is frustrating and I
know Tom you hear this from Greg all the
time is that the illegal shops are there
sometimes a block and a half from a
regulated shop the inspect the permit
people come show up the inspected shop
and they'll say hey a block and a half
away is an illegal shop wanted to go
check them out and the inspectors are
scared to go there you know and so they
don't really do anything and you know I
think really with with enforcement if
there's one thing the last where we have
ninety years of drug war has showed us
and that enforcement really really is
not the answer and the answer is to
incentivize legal businesses to be
competitive with the illegal businesses
imagine if everything was flipped in 80%
of the market was legal and only 20% was
illegal we'd be very close to stomping
it out maybe we can start rebranding
that herd immunity yeah I mean that that
gets back to the sensible taxes I mean
that that's pretty much the main all
they need to do is be sensible and you
know you don't really have a moonshine
market you don't really have a you know
and illicit you know cereal or CPG
market I mean maybe you have knockoffs
on the on the you know streets of
Chinatown in New York but uh it's tough
to be you know I remember when they did
the first bug
when Jerry Brown was governor and this
is part of it you know we talk about
what we understand is economics because
we've all owned businesses and it's you
know if you lower if you lower the taxes
you generate more economic activity
which often will actually increase the
revenue you know I remember when the
first tax report came in and it was one
third of projections you know when Jerry
Brown was governor deep you know they
talked about the first tax cut they
projected 120 million coming in or
something like that and it ended up
being like 30 million that came in and
the first hit from his quote basically
was like you know well if we hit
one-third of our tax revenue we're not
going to cut taxes because then we're
gonna get even less money and they you
know a lot of people they just don't
even look at that other side that you
know if you tax it less you're gonna
have more businesses coming in which
will raise it and that they're oblivious
to that side of the argument and I don't
know how to how to broach that gap so
that do you understand that you know
that that's actually a real thing you
know that gets back to me kind of it
seems so obvious you know I I bring up
Walmart Costco and Amazon they do high
volume low margin and they they have
their very profitable right vs.
Lamborghini which sells you know a
limited number of cars per year at a
very high margin but not a lot of them
and that's our that's our that's our
California tax structure where the
Lamborghini tax structure but nobody's
making lots of money because you also
don't get to deduct anything and but so
just quickly when when you get paid but
so your distributor collects money from
the retail shops and then do they litter
like is everything in cash or talk about
like are they walking in with a big
duffel bag of cash or do you get checks
for anything or no but but it is it is
all cash like there's no checks or
anything
yeah yeah it's it's it's cash I mean I I
could get checks if I wanted to but then
you run into the whole banking thing and
you know but that cash is just the
easiest way to avoid D do you do you
currently have a bank without naming
names right but how many how many banks
have you gone through um well let's see
I you know the thing with banks isn't if
banks know you're operating a cannabis
business they won't allow you to use
their bank and as far as I know I'm not
sure if you're allowed to tell a bank
your banking account is for something
other than a cannabis business so I you
know I'm not sure about the legalities
of any of that and it's not to say I do
or don't do any of right but but that
but but then the persistence of the
Facebook machine well I'm just gonna
write that you know I've been to this
industry I've been in this industry a
long time and so self-incriminate and
coughing criminais ssin is not the best
thing which I'm sure Lauren will agree
with me that self-incrimination it is
never a good
don't don't incriminate yourself it
whatever I think we can so any any I
think we can probably wrap and I just
wanted to see if Lauren or or Eric if
you guys have any last words
faint things that are top of mind for
you in the the joyful California
cannabis industry so as far as from
myself you know I would just like to
point out we didn't really get into it
but there was that really bad fire that
happened on Saturday in downtown LA on
headshop Row where they were where
most likely tens of thousands of cans of
butane that ultimately were most likely
intended for people to illegally make
hash oil and I think one most of the
initial reports blamed it on making hash
oil which turned out to not be the case
and you know our industry gets blamed
for that and secondly it's another
example of why we need to continue to
work harder to to make our industry a
hundred percent legal aboveboard and
away from the illicit industry so things
like this don't happen some of the first
responders and LAFD firefighters were
hurt very very badly in that fire one of
the injuries I believe is is going to be
one that you know will be life-changing
for one of these firefighters and you
know this this happened because of the
illegal industry you know and it is just
you know it's and and at the same time
we kind of get blamed for it so it's
just shows that there's more work for us
to be done and we have to continue to
work to make it a hundred percent legal
industry in a zero percent illegal
industry so we don't have these things
happen and god bless our firefighters
for going into these situations and it
really just illustrates the bravery of
them all of our first responders you
know let's throw LAPD in there for you
know that they do a lot of a lot of
tough work as well and all of our first
responders all over the state and so
really just want to give a shout out to
them and yeah that I guess that's where
all ended on something kind of
completely different and I'm sure more
will come out to this and it'll become a
topic for another time
Loren top of my mind right now is
getting cannabis businesses the the
relief and the assistance they need so
you know that could look like extending
the deferral relief that the licensing
agencies just offered you know if we can
get that extended past 60 days that
would be great if we can get at the
federal level there's efforts now to get
first of all to treat cannabis like
other businesses so they're eligible for
all the SBA loans and other federal
relief but also now the cannabis effects
for cannabis banking has been added to
the latest coronavirus relief bill and
it's called the heroes Act and as as
written that would you know open up
banking access relief for cannabis
company is and that would that would
help a lot I think I have a lot of
clients that are struggling because they
don't have a good access to banking or
their accounts to keep getting shut down
or and it limits your ability to get to
get funding really as well so that is
we'll see if it passes I'm not super
optimistic about it but I think what it
shows is that at the federal level level
I actually think that coronavirus has
increased the chances of cannabis
getting federally legal sooner just
because so many different states have
deem these businesses to be essential
and so many different now federal law
makers are signing on to things that
would add you know provide cannabis
relief I think that there is a tide
that's you know turning their federally
I'm optimistic about that I think folks
should get involved and advocate to all
your representatives local state and
federal because you know legalization
would certainly help a lot of things
then we can do cross-border transactions
we could you know participate in a
global cannabis market that is out there
and so that's really the thing and also
just you know making sure that everyone
stays safe right now it's a scary and
confusing time stay safe stay sane and
helping each other out and well we can
get through this but no one can do it
alone we got to be there for each other
alright and on that we will end the
conversation let me just conclude with
the slide and so thank you everyone I
appreciate your time and with that we
are stopping the livestream
you