[Music]
I'm very pleased to be moderating this
panel today really looking in depth at
some of the lessons from early regulated
markets across the country including
California Oregon and Colorado again
that Lindsey Robinson California
cannabis Industry Association so I'm
gonna pass this over to Caitlin first
off hi I'm Caitlin or so I work for the
Colorado Department of Public Health and
Environment
I have been with CDP for 10 years in
January yeah it's been a while I have a
mechanical engineering degree I have
played several roles at CDP from writing
actual regulations writing drinking
water regulations was one of my first
roles to doing community outreach
projects the role that I'm in now is
very dynamic and interesting I'm
basically a free environmental
consultant for all small businesses in
Colorado I personally happen to
specialize in craft brewing in cannabis
a lot of people laugh and say like is
that your real job it is those those are
two small business sectors in Colorado
that are large growth industries that
both use a lot of environmental
resources just inherent in their process
and so that's kind of the the Nexus of
my role and really I'm here to just help
make the cannabis industry more
environmentally friendly and I have to
follow that so my name is Jesse Peters I
was a co-founder of eco firma farms
which was a cultivation operation up in
Oregon we sold that business in June of
2018 and time that we sold it we were
cultivating indoor cannabis for $199 a
pound we were doing it on a hundred
percent renewable energy and we were
almost carbon neutral I since then have
founded mantas growth investments we are
an MSO consolidating companies primarily
across the west coast and I was a
founding member of the organ cannabis
Association and still a board member
there
I'm Gary court lat I'm an engineer with
Southern California Edison I work in our
energy analysis and customer outreach
organization work with our business
customers with energy efficiency and
I've been doing that for about 10 years
through that time I've been working with
our agricultural customers and for the
last four years I've been dedicated to
indoor horticulture okay
so let's dig in as many of you know if
you operate in California we have local
and state level laws that govern what
you can do in various jurisdictions
across the state and it is a very
complicated patchwork we have some
communities that are quite friendly to
cannabis and are regulating you know
manufacturing distribution retail
cultivation and some were it's a
complete ban de facto prohibition so I'd
love to talk first off with Gary just a
little bit about what you see in the
challenges particularly in Coachella
Valley and what some of your the main
factors that you focus on currently so
the the the main issues that we have in
the Coachella Valley originally were
that our infrastructure wasn't capable
of providing the power that's required
for these facilities the initial
investments there were made in Desert
Hot Springs and the city in their wisdom
when they were doing this decided that
they wanted to make a cannabis business
park and they did that in an area of
desert that was was zoned for five acre
single-family homes and suddenly we have
actually about twelve different
facilities there and about thirty acres
so and each of them takes about you know
one one to five megawatts so that's the
same as having a megawatt that serves
about 750 homes in California so it's
the same as having between
you know 750 and 3,000 homes on a five
acre lot we you know we kind of jump on
this from a lot of topics I think this
is a really kind of important one to
look at where as California and Oregon
kind of did the same thing right we have
this free market for licensing which I
am a huge fan of because whereas some
people say it's a race to the bottom I
would say it's a race to be more
efficient and if you are looking at
building a cultivation facility in
Desert Hot Springs and your exit
strategy hopefully that you have one is
to be acquired by someone else in the
future I can tell you personally as a
West Coast MSO operator I am NOT looking
at your company we're looking at
potential for interstate commerce when
we move forward in the world California
and Oregon are known for growing a large
quantity of the whole country's cannabis
in the north where you can get power for
better prices where there's renewable
resources and so as much as I appreciate
all of it I think it's you know when you
hear these numbers not only coming from
a power perspective or coming from an
environmental standpoint but you have to
think of it economically as well what is
your exit strategy what is your plan I
mean everybody who goes to work every
day has an exit strategy it's to retire
so you've got an exit strategy if you
haven't thought about it yet and that's
the either that you're going to retire
from this company and give it to someone
else which means it needs to
substantially survive through what is
going to be a very difficult and Tremmel
Jewess market over the next two decades
or you need to think of where it's at
and be really efficient with it and so I
think that this any of these things and
heeding warnings to thinking of what
you're doing moving forward is crucially
important at conferences like this I
think they covered it pretty well but I
think the only thing that I have to add
is you know coming from Colorado's
perspective and being one of the most
mature markets in the country we you
know we learned a lot of hard lessons
really early on and we also there was a
lot of fear around being the first to
legalize in the way that we did and so
all of our regulatory structure was
centered around safety security and no
diversion to the black market
environmental and if
see standards were not considered that's
that's why we have the situation in
Colorado where most of our cannabis has
grown indoors under lock and key
and it creates a lot of environmental
detriment so yeah and I think you know
we as going through the process with
with California over the last several
years we have tried to look at Colorado
as as a roadmap on what worked and what
what didn't and I have to say a lot of
California regulators um did not really
heat a lot of the warnings that we saw
from Colorado and have implemented
regulations in California that are that
are caught that are proving to be
problematic and I think one of the
things that we talked a bit about
earlier and we really also wanted this
to just be a conversation amongst us and
then obviously open it up to all of you
and be able to learn from each other is
the stress on the on the grid and I
think that you're seeing a really
dramatic case of that down in them in
the desert areas so can you expand a
little bit about that and if you've gone
through if there's been any significant
complications that have in some ways
affected people's businesses or their
ability to maintain yes so Desert Hot
Springs is actually one of the better
examples of what we've been able to do
to accommodate they're real close we
have wind power that's out in that area
it's designated for other parts of the
the grid but it means that we have a
distribution level or I'm sorry a
transmission level substation in in that
area so we were able to expand an
existing distribution substation to
provide a little bit of power and we
were able to bring power in from other
areas to support the facilities there
the the other extreme to that is
California City where that's a community
that's basically it was a retirement
community there's no no industry to
speak of there
was a large housing tract that was
planned and power was put in for it but
it never developed so that allowed us to
pull some power but the major issue is
that they again put all of their
cannabis facilities in the cannabis
Business Park that Business Park was
located a half mile or so from the
nearest distribution line and not only
for electricity but also for gas and
water and so the the basically nobody
out there has power or any other
utilities there because of that so
that's the other extreme yeah so for
those who aren't familiar with it and
we're kind of newer into the California
market so I apologize that I'm not
completely up to speed on on all
California regulations so no one's
allowed to hold me to any of this
disclaimer but no there's a green zone
up around Arcada that where California
established some regulations that remove
the taxation and basically said for lack
of a lot more red tape apply for a
license pay the fee and it's yours we're
not going to play the game of continuing
to look at regulation upon regulation
upon regulation and and so of course for
me looking at MSOs this this is a giant
flag waving around the sky that says
come by my company because if you think
about the way the California market
works and some of the things that in my
opinion we're starting to see as an
issue in California is you're looking at
the the every as everybody makes
regulation and we spoke about this
earlier Santa Barbara just came out and
said that you can cultivate cannabis and
we are doing that there oh by the way
wait you can't dry it it's a big fire
hazard what was your plan with all of it
when we got done growing it so you look
at this regulation and now we've got to
figure out what we're gonna do with it
okay we're gonna turn it to fresh frozen
or are we going to ship it to a drying
facility you know when I send it to the
manual to vation tax and then when the
processor sends it to the manufacturer
to package it they need to
pay a manufacturing tax and then when
you send it to the distributor you pay a
distribution tax and then they give it
to the delivery or the retail where you
pay attacks and now I'm spending $62 for
a gram of cannabis that's been handled
47 times in a bag that I can't see or
potentially even recycle when my friend
Rick has been selling me bags for 40
bucks that now grows like 18 different
strains I love all of them and it's
still 40 bucks why don't we have a giant
market in California I feel like we're
figuring that out and so when you look
at the green zone you look at this space
where I don't have to pay any of that
tax in the middle so if we get really
efficient with those locations and I
don't pay all that tax in the middle and
we vertically integrate ourselves
throughout there maybe we can start
getting a product to consumers at a
competitive price and start getting the
unregulated market do you want to come
into the regulated market that's the
goal right yeah so I mean I again I
think that there are a lot of lessons
that we're learning in California real
time we obviously have we you know the
the local access and local control has
been a huge component of how California
has regulated cannabis which has turned
some communities into much friendlier
zones than others and then even within
those communities they have green zones
or areas that are much more friendly but
oftentimes we've heard from our members
that those areas are not necessarily
conducive for running businesses and so
I think you know we touched a little bit
about on that with access and and just
over taxing of the grid especially and
then really just making sure that these
businesses are kind of you know grouped
into a certain area I think is
beneficial in certain ways but also
problematic in others and so we're like
I said trying to figure all of this out
in real time in California and it's
basically like running a small country
or even a medium-sized country really
and we love over-regulation so one of
the things that I I thought was really
interesting about what Caitlin said
earlier is and I'd love for you to
elaborate on your 30 different
conversations that you
yes so when you know one of the things
that the roles that I play is I am
researching the air quality impacts of
the cannabis industry something that not
a lot of people are talking about
besides you know the secondary impacts
of power generation but inherent within
the cultivation and processing is is air
emissions terpenes are volatile organic
compounds they're not just an odor
nuisance volatile organic compounds I
have a slide on this but I'll show it to
you guys in a little bit volatile
organic compounds are ozone precursors
ozone is toxic for us to breathe it's an
it's an issue that that's pretty big in
Colorado and with the way that we
legalized marijuana in Colorado not only
did we force it all indoors but we zoned
it industrial and we put all these other
regulatory restrictions on setbacks from
schools and other cannabis businesses I
mean there's a lot of regulation now
surrounding where you can grow marijuana
in Colorado and what it did is it forced
about 60 to 70 percent of the
cultivation into our metropolitan area
the reason why that's important is not
only we stressing our grid but we're
stressing our municipal drinking water
supply our wastewater effluent our air
quality because ozone is VOCs and
combustion emissions combined so when
you put it in the city that's where all
of our power plants are that's where all
of our traffic is that's where all of
our combustion activities are and so
it's just compounding issues with the
way that we legalized and forcing you
know what should be an agricultural
commodity into a literally manufacturing
environment yeah and I think one of the
the items that we had touched on earlier
as well is that you know in in you
having conversations on the regulatory
level in terms of air quality compared
comparing Colorado to California I'd
love for you to highlight an example of
how difficult it is to regulate here
yeah so in Colorado we have one Colorado
Department of Public Health and
Environment California has many many
many just from an air pollution
standpoint
we have over 26 air pollution districts
that all make up you know one big carb
California Air resource board and so you
know when I am working with other states
and other entities to try to educate
them on these issues and inform them
about how to make smart policy it's
really difficult when you go into a
state like California to advise them and
you've got this whole patchwork of of
not only different regulations per area
you have different regulatory bodies you
have different perspectives you have
it's a lot so it you know what takes one
phone call to educate another state like
maybe you know Michigan or Oregon takes
about 30 phone calls to educate
California and it's all piecemeal yes
they don't all talk to each other
surprising well maybe this would be a
good time for us to segue into your
PowerPoint because I think that that
will generate more conversation amongst
the panelists but then also is just a
ton of information that we hope you all
can will comment on as well and you need
this our first two slides we're going to
share as a group and we're really going
to focus on the environmental impacts of
the cannabis industry and not just the
energy impacts I know that this
conference is really focused on the
energy impacts if you want to click it
for me I can just cue you but I want to
point out the other environmental
impacts and so just inherent in the
cultivation and processing and camp of
cannabis there's many environmental
impacts so we've talked about energy but
what about water and in whether you're
growing indoor or outdoor there's water
impacts in an indoor environment you're
taking the drinking water water supply
that's treated to drinking water
standards and put it in that towards an
agricultural commodity that has a lot of
energy impacts it takes a lot of energy
to treat that water all right we got it
and so there's there's also in an
outdoor environment or use all you also
have a lot of irrigation systems and you
need to be efficient with those and so
that kind of gets that water efficiency
in an outdoor environment you got runoff
and erosion issues and then also indoor
you've got wastewater effluent so you're
putting all the
pesticides nutrients you know you got to
be aware of what you're putting down the
drain because those wastewater
municipalities that weren't
traditionally set up to support a large
influx of indoor agriculture are now
taking on that burden there's there's a
lot of waste from the industry plant
waste Universal wastes like your
lighting your ballasts your electronic
waste and then there's also hazardous
waste your leftover solvents cleaning
supplies chemicals those types of things
as I mentioned air emissions terpenes
are volatile organic compounds I got a
really great slide to explain why that's
important and then also just you know be
aware of the chemical use associated
with cultivation you've got pests if I
pesticides fertilizers solvents and
outdoor agro environment you also got a
lot of rodenticides so just kind of
being aware of this inherent in the
process whether you're indoor or outdoor
there is a environmental burden that
you're putting on the community and we
all need to be smarter about how we run
our businesses to reduce that burden so
I'm going to turn it over to these two
guys to comment on environmental impacts
of cannabis cultivation yeah you know I
look at a lot of these and obviously we
look at environmental efficiencies right
but I also look at economic efficiencies
and you start looking at these things
and you look at for example water
treatment irrigation runoff erosion
waste water effluent and you start
thinking about if I'm in a facility
where I pay a water bill and I pay a
sewage bill and eventually I'm told I
need to start separating out my
fertilizer which should be something I'm
doing on my own you start looking at a
cost associated to that and that cost
Association breaks down to price per
gram that is going to be a cost under
how much it costs me to cultivate hands
down and then I look at my competitor
who say is in agricultural land they're
on a well they have literally dug a hole
and got native plants that all of their
runoff goes into and cooks off all of
that which is a fancy BIOS well but in
the end it's cooking off all your
nutrient that is if you're using too
much nutrient I I have just erased that
cost from
bottom line so now we're competing and
this goes down plant waste
am I in a gland where I can put a fence
around it put a camera on it and I can
let it compost and then I can reuse that
compost and then save myself on
fertilizer or am I using a dumpster am I
having to pay to have it removed through
waste are you having to mix it with 50%
non marijuana waste before you put it in
the dumpster right and as we go through
this chemical use pesticides automation
to understand that we're using the exact
amount of fertilizer that we need to use
at the exact times under the exact
conditions per strain the research that
we talked about yesterday when you're a
cultivator and
you know we're all kind of used to it
you've got these cultivators all of us
I've been guilty of it a thousand times
well we can figure that out later
because the margins are there three
years ago I had a two years ago had a
conversation with cultivator from here
in California said we get $2,800 a pound
that's not going to change for at least
three years I don't care what my price
per pound is I haven't called him lately
but I got a feeling that that is not his
statement today
so you look at all of those pieces and
and you think to yourself while I have
time I have time to get to it or I need
to be able to produce a facility to be
able to do that and these are decisions
that need to be made now while you have
the time while those margins are there
no matter what your equipment says it
can tell you it's 99% efficient at the
end of the day you have humans running
these machines it's not going to be 99%
efficient
think about you know even when you take
the plant material out of the system
after it's gone through its you know
it's regenerative evaporative process
that those inherent within that plant
material still going to be solvent so
that solvents going to continue to off
gas that those solvents butane propane
ethanol those are all volatile organic
compounds and again I'll talk about the
importance of VOCs in a second
also co2 releases you know you can use
pressurized co2 for extraction as well
there's co2 releases from that and also
you know worth noting in the indoor
cultivation environment there's a lot of
CO supplemental co2 that's used within
that environment as well then once that
solvent is spent
doesn't last forever right it goes bad
we have to dispose of it as hazardous
waste and so those are the other
environmental impacts and then being
aware of plant waste - you know there's
all these regulations out there
especially in Colorado we have a 50/50
waste mixing rule where you have to mix
it with 50% non marijuana waste before
it can leave the facility that doubles
our landfill footprint on it and
honestly we don't have a lot of issues
of people stealing trash marijuana trash
so that's something I'd like to see a
change to that and we have seen a
positive regulatory change as of January
1st in Colorado we now have a rule where
the composting truck if it rolls up
under surveillance and the dumpsters
under lock and key of the plant waste by
a way of tit the truck taking that
dumpster and putting it in the back of
the truck that's your 50/50 waste
compliance point and that's acceptable
that's really important because that
also makes composting more accessible
for cultivators because you pay per
pound to compost so if you're doubling
the amount that you have to compost
you're doubling the amount you have to
pay to compost so just things to be
aware of that it doesn't just stop at
the cultivation environment that it's
also processing and then you know
distribution as well with all of the
packaging and distribution so yeah I
think that California's had a hard time
learning these lessons from Colorado
especially around the environmental
waste piece so I think having a few
years advance on California has really
shaped and informed the regulations that
you're now dealing with and again we're
a larger state but I would love to hear
maybe a little bit on Oregon on how how
things are going up there with you know
waste management in Oregon has been it's
been I would like to say easy in the
sense of it hasn't been over regulated
but that being said when we look at
processors and you know honestly there's
a lot of stuff that Oregon is starting
to look to Colorado for a lot of the
studies that are being put out now what
we're talking about right now this is
going to be sensible for us to turn to
when it comes to waste management and as
far as farm waste management
we're we're looking more towards
regulators an organ are concerned that
that there's diversion potentially
happening through waste
so when organ looks at waste it looks
more on the regulatory side of diversion
that is rapidly going to change probably
across the industry but especially an
organ and looking to Colorado on the
processor side because just the volatile
chemicals the VOCs the look towards what
is happening is we can refine that down
with processors
I believe that Oregon's gonna turn to a
higher regulatory stature there um and
that that's obviously going to affect
pricing so it's another one of those
things talking about where if you're
trying to be economically viable
building a c1 d1 facility even though
you're not required to and always trying
to be have ingenuity in trying to decide
how you're going to handle waste with a
moral structure that not only goes
behind environmentally friendly but also
considering what could happen regulatory
wise in the future and being prepared
for that we're juggling all this all
right
so I'm gonna go into a little bit more
Colorado specific issues and and some of
the work that I'm doing just very
briefly and I say that because this
could literally be a three-hour
conversation and I'm gonna do my best to
keep it very short so why are VOCs
important we mentioned that VOCs are
coming off of the plants as they grow
and in the form of terpenes right we've
got mersin pining lemony meter pennilyn
those are all being released into the
atmosphere and those are volatile
organic compounds it happens to be that
the terpene emission profile associated
with cannabis is highly reactive for
ozone formation
so when VOCs go up into the atmosphere
they react with other types of pollution
those other types of pollution are
specifically nitrogen oxide we get
nitrogen oxide from combustion sources
cars power plants oil and gas activity
anytime you're burning something it
could be agricultural burns um it could
be wood burning activities if there's
combustion there's going to be nitrogen
oxide again
really important for Colorado we we are
not meeting EPA health standards for
ambient ozone concentrations are ready
and then we regulated cannabis in a way
that we forced everybody into our
metropolitan area co-located next to all
of our sources of nitrogen oxide what we
don't know right now is how many pounds
of VOCs are emitted per pound of
cannabis grown that's a question that
I'm trying to answer with my research
currently I've got a research grant
through Colorado Department of Public
Health and Environment where I'm
actually collecting air quality samples
at commercial cultivation environments
to answer this question of how many
pounds of VOCs are emitted per pound of
marijuana grown once we're able to
answer that question we have really good
plant count tracking or you know
production tracking in Colorado through
our marijuana Enforcement Division so
then we can couple it that data with
okay how many pounds of marijuana are
grown in the state and where what are
all the other sources of nitrogen oxide
and VOCs and really at the end of the
day come to how much of our total ozone
problem in Colorado is attributed to the
cannabis industry some people they hear
my research and they think that maybe
I'm picking on cannabis or something
like that
definitely not we do this for all
regulated industries in Colorado we want
to know what everyone's air quality
impact is in Colorado and typically when
you get new industries that come online
EPA the federal Environmental Protection
Agency would be the one to do this type
of research to universally establish
what we call emission factors pounds of
VOCs produced per pound of marijuana
grown EPA is not gonna do that for you
guys so Colorado is stepping in and
trying to fill that gap in knowledge for
other states I'm not the first one to
research this issue there there is other
studies that are out there
however when Colorado looked at those
studies we didn't feel they were robust
enough to base you know any regulatory
or policy decisions on it's also worth
noting that cannabis is a agricultural
process especially the cultivation not
the manufacturing but the cultivation is
an agricultural process and agricultural
processes are exempt from air quality
regulations so at the end of the day
this is
fact-finding we want to know what the
impact is other states and and Canada do
you plan to make regulatory policy
decisions based on this research so
something to know about when mine was
only going back to the last point like
we talked about earlier this opens up a
space eventually to start looking at
incentives to get away from industrial
zones that could create this ozone from
VOCs right because originally like
Oregon we talked about when they were
looking at scent mitigation they were
looking at it because politicians were
considering what voters were telling
them and so somehow I got invited to be
on the three-person Commission to decide
how we were gonna regulate the scent
which is essentially the VOCs and what I
loved about it was the other two people
was the owner of fresh filters who make
carbon filters and the owner of can fans
who make vans that hook to those filters
just going out on a limb here I feel as
though maybe there's an agenda so so of
course we created indoor agricultural
rules around evacuating all of the air
through a carbon filter that need to be
changed on a regular basis and there's
there's better ways to do this and
obviously I believe that this study I
will work with the OCA and we will
attempt to push down this path for
something a little more logical and of
course try to incentivize those that are
in the right zones and also to I mean
this research is a benefit for industry
too because right now no one's really
quantifying the emissions at the moment
and carbon filters are not one size fits
all if you know these specific molecules
that you're trying to capture within
that carbon filter you can actually
manipulate the pores within the carbon
filter to be just the right size to
capture those specific emissions and so
you can be a lot more efficient if you
know exactly what you're trying to
control so that's the other piece of
this too is you know by capturing these
VOCs within the carbon you're
controlling odor but you're also
controlling the vo C so it's not emitted
in the atmosphere and then you're not
getting that those ozone impacts as well
so this really puts a new lens on on
odor mitigation in that it's not just a
nuisance there is public health impacts
and
and there's probably gonna be some
regulatory impact on the road based on
this so we'll move to fun stuff so
here's a project that I hold near and
dear to my heart and it was in the news
a lot lately so if you guys have heard
about it I'm excited so you know I
mentioned before that I specialized in
in helping both craft brewing and
cannabis become more environmentally
friendly in Colorado and I saw this
project as an opportunity to bring those
two two industries together in a way
that's economically and environmentally
viable and so what's happening here is
the first picture is at a brewery a
local brewery in Colorado Denver beer
company and those shiny tanks behind us
are the fermentation tanks the last step
in the brewing process is where the
yeast eat the sugars they produce
alcohol and co2 we keep the alcohol in
the beer co2 just gets vented this is a
every craft brewery out there co2 is
vented in large large amounts so it's a
very it's a big source of co2 now at
larger scale breweries like
anheuser-busch and Coors they capture
the co2 and compress it off the
fermentation and reuse it back in the
brewing process because we carbonate our
beer with co2 we pressurize our lines we
use it as a void space within the
fermentation tanks because oxygens bad
for beer we use a lot of co2 but all
that co2 at craft breweries that's used
within the process is purchased from an
outside supplier so they purchase co2
and they generate co2 right there's an
opportunity here then when you look at
the cannabis cultivation side
photosynthesis right you - it takes
light and it takes co2 you in that
process the plant is taking in that co2
stripping the carbon using it as energy
for plant growth right so it's a carbon
sink it takes in this carbon and it
breeze out the oxygen so with this
project we are capturing co2 off the
breweries fermentation tanks then we're
putting it through you know some really
great technology that's provided by
earthly labs that basically scrubs that
co2 and compresses
and then we release it within the
cultivation environment so projects
gained a lot of press support from the
governor it's just been it's been really
great all around to work with these
folks
governor Poulos actually came and toured
both the cultivation facility and the
brewery and did a press release on this
because it's a really great illustration
of small businesses coming together to
combat climate change essentially in a
way that's economically feasible for
both of them
these projects are both the brewery and
the cultivation have a 22-month ROI
that's less than two years
it saves during the pilot phase when
we're only feeding one bedroom in one
flower room at the cultivation it stays
a thousand dollars a month right off the
bat once we get it up to scale at the
facility it'll save the cultivation
facility six thousand dollars a month
that's huge savings and that's co2 that
would just otherwise be vented from the
brewery and it becomes a revenue stream
for the brewery yeah right isn't that
exciting it can be done Russian River
you know there's a lot of different
options for California to take on that
model for sure yeah and since we proved
that it's both economically and
environmentally feasible there's no
reason that this can't be reject can't
be repeated you don't need someone like
me and the government pushing and
rallying behind this project to get it
done you guys can just do it yourselves
but it helps to have somebody like me
rallying to be like do this and we hope
to see it be a repeatable project and I
think we're running a little short on
time but I wanted to just briefly cover
some regulatory lessons from Colorado
and so we've taken a little bit
different approach than some of the
other states when it comes to
environmental efficiencies for the
cannabis industry and that we don't
mandate them we just open up our
regulatory structure to allow them to
make those more environmentally-friendly
decisions because if we force them there
they may not be economically viable and
so that's that's kind of a different
philosophy that we have in Colorado but
we allow fiber recovery for an exemption
from the 50/50 waste rule if it's going
to fiber recovery
as I mentioned in the previous session
if you guys were here we allow take back
programs at retail facilities for
packaging and vape waste we also allow
you waste recyclers to process marijuana
vape cartridges without a special
marijuana license because the intent is
recycling and we allow for irrigation of
hemp with reclaimed water that's mostly
because hemp has grown outdoors in an
indoor environment we don't allow that
in marijuana because that reclaimed
water could aerosolize bacteria and
viruses so can't do it inside and better
access to composting like I mentioned
allowing that the composting truck to
pick up your plant waste put it in the
back and that'd be the point of
compliance for the 50:50 waste rule
Thanks great thank you so much so
obviously amazing lessons to be learned
from from Colorado California is a
little slow on the uptake on a lot of
those and you know I think that there's
certainly ways that we can build on the
knowledge of other states we'd love to
hear from folks if you have any specific
questions are you measuring this is for
Caitlyn are you measuring VOCs at the
like at the unit level that grow rooms
or is it estimated based on production
and known releases that is a great
question so we actually took samples at
the exhaust points to measure what is
the output for ozone but then we also
took samples within the cultivation
facility in the bedrooms and the flower
rooms harvesting processing so that we
can get unique emission factors that
kind of add up to that ratio of exhaust
so that because every facility is going
to be different and we can't just say
the exhaust from one facility is going
to be the same as another and so we want
to get that relationship established
between activities that are happening
within the cultivation facility compared
to what's at the exhaust point all of
our samples to were taken pre carbon
filtration because again carbon
filtration is highly dependent on on the
size of the pores and the filter weather
what is your HVAC exchange flow rate
if you have it too high what's the
temperature what's the humidity is so
variable on what is going to be that
carbon if filter efficiency so we only
did pre carbon filtration basically
without any controls what is the
contribution to ozone depends on where
is its parts per billion in harvesting
for sure it's more parts per million
when you're in flowered veg I thought
this was gonna be about growing mediums
so I do y'all can you all express your
opinions or just thoughts on
sustainability issues related to peat
moss first coco and where that's going I
mean yeah so we all know that
sustainability wise coco is better than
peat moss right like that that's kind of
been the standard statement for a while
even though we've have some new peat
moss beds coming out of Canada we're
saying no it's actually just as
sustainable I think that's a debate that
can be had over and over I I think for
mediums and we worked a lot at this at
eco before we sold that company and it's
something that I definitely look forward
to working with with some of our new
companies is the thought process of
being able to recycle your soil whether
you're using peat moss whether you're
buying and mixing your own whether
you're bringing it in through bags you
know a lot of farms it's really
commonplace that you use this soil you
put it a lot of times in a in a cloth
bag that are as thrown away at the end
and not cleaned or if it is going into a
pot that's being recycled they're still
taking the dirt and they're dumping it
they're bringing into landfills or
composting it they're 50/50 mixing it
but in reality with some soil science
and some work if you were on the right
property you could you could regenerate
that soil and continue to reuse it with
a good IPM program and I think that that
is something that we really need to look
at is cultivators in all of our
cultivation methodology for
sustainability to say that my cocoa is
more sustainable or less sustainable
than my peat moss is a moot point if I'm
recycling whichever one I have yeah and
I also think to the illicit industry
plays a really strong role in a lot of
the environmental issues that we're
seeing in California
because it is unregulated and we're
seeing massive pesticide use and trash
and debris and and discard and you know
that those that soil is often being put
into large contractor bags and being
brought to the dump and I totally can
understand the dank dirt confusion on
that I just I just put that together but
yeah I think that you right the more
regulated the industry hopefully the
less environmental issues you're gonna
have but then again when we look at
California we're not able to regulate
any or recycle any packaging yet and we
are going for the most environmentally
unfriendly packaging protocols possible
and part of it is because the industry
is the right on the regulated side is is
really struggling in California and so a
lot of it is just trying to put out
fires to stay alive with the hopes of
tackling some of these environmental
issues and in the next few years to come
so yes okay I have a question for Gary
so it sounds like you were fairly
successful in accommodating the growers
in Desert Hot Springs but if let's say
jesse is correct and maybe they aren't
the most sustainable business model and
longer term do you have a back-up plan
because I know working with SMUD they
accommodated all these growers in a very
specific region and upgraded their
distribution facilities and then those
growers have a lot of them already taken
off to go grow in like the Central Coast
so are you planning for that do you have
any idea yeah we are we are looking at
that I can't tell you exactly what that
plan is cuz I'm not involved with it but
our main concern from from the very
beginning has been stranded assets out
in these remote locations the you know
we're kind of in a bind because we're
we're obligated to provide power to
anybody that asks and so we try to do
that one of the ways that we offset that
is because it's a high risk industry
we're allowed to charge them a little
bit of the cost upfront so that they
they have to share in that
but it still leaves us with the
potential of stranded assets the the
desert Hot Springs area Atlanta area
those areas are are pretty well built
out with other industries that can pick
up that that load so we're not too
worried about it there are other areas
like California City where there are no
other industries and so that's a concern
out there to provide we kind of seen a
rise in non-volatile extraction methods
and production especially among smaller
to mid-sized producers I wonder if
you've taken a look at that at all to
assess if they're more environmentally
friendly and you know why couldn't they
get be a Green Zone unto themselves and
get some tax breaks to - you know
emphasize non-volatile yeah I think
that's a that's a really great idea and
you know our regulatory structure is
constantly evolving and you know I would
like to see more of an incentive
structure for instance in the in the co2
project there's actually no tax breaks
involved in that at all and there should
be we should you know just like we get
tax breaks for solar we should have you
know carbon capture tax breaks that are
there to incentivize we should have
incentives for these take back programs
that we've now allowed but what's in it
for the dispensary you know we're trying
to pitch it as you know you'll get
loyalty points for maybe bringing it
back and good customer retention and you
know better relationships but honestly I
think there should be some tax breaks
for that as well and I think that with
cannabis being so new in Colorado kind
of leading the way we're still kind of
fumbling around in the dark and trying
to figure out what are those policies
and so you know organizations like this
in Derrick's resource innovation
Institute and and all an NCI a all of
those those bodies out there that are
built on bringing us together and
bringing government and cultivators into
the same room to have these
conversations is really really essential
so that folks like myself can go back to
the government and say hey this is what
industries
asking for that last slide I landed on
all of the environmental efficiency
regulations those were all new of a
January 1st this year and that was all
because our regulated cannabis industry
worked with our marijuana Enforcement
Division and made them make those
changes so be a voice that's heard I'd
love to add kind of a side note on that
as well and one of the challenges that
we've had in California is is creating a
sustainable and workable social equity
program so for lessons to be learned
from other states I would say don't
follow California's lack of leadership
on that because we don't have a
statewide program that can help folks
enter into the industry there's really
high barriers there's obviously a it's
hard to access capital there's no
traditional banking system so if you're
trying to transition you know into a
legal market and you know you're coming
from a community that's been severely
disadvantaged and targeted by the war on
drugs it's it's almost insurmountable
and so we have a patchwork of regulation
on the local level and anything that we
do in terms of trying to lower barriers
to entry often has to go through the
legislature and if you guys have ever
dealt with the California Legislature
its pain in the ass and it takes a
really long time and so I would say be
very thoughtful about those are things
that states can be very proactive on and
can learn from the mistakes that we've
are making and probably will continue to
make in California yeah Colorado does
not have a social equity program either
and I also want to point out to you from
an environmental justice standpoint with
the way that we zoned cannabis and we
forced them all into our industrial
zoned areas those are also our poorest
communities those are also our sickest
communities those are also our most
diverse communities you know those are
health equity environmental justice
priority areas in our state and we force
the cannabis industry to operate solely
in those areas and so I think that's
something interesting to point out when
we're talking about social equity
question in the back yeah
hey there um I wanted to say the brewery
co2 to cannabis projects just about the
coolest thing I've ever heard of so so
two questions on that one is is there is
there any report or data or something
publicly available those of us who are
interested in it can learn more from and
then the second is is there an estimate
of what percentage of the co2 that's
absorbed by the photosynthetic process
ends up being re-released via being lit
on fire yes so we are definitely in the
data collection phase of this project
right now we are one month in to capture
mr. jared Polis was so excited about our
project our Colorado Governor that we
did a press release after only capturing
and successfully doing the project for
one week and we have a three month pilot
timeframe where we are collecting data
points to beer quality on plant quality
on logistics of the capture on the
carbon footprint of the trucks going
back and forth compared to you know
vehicle miles traveled from a
traditional distribution system of
having a bunch of co2 loaded on a truck
it's usually truck from much farther
away because it comes from a power plant
it's a byproduct of combustion so that's
an environmentally friendly practice in
itself to capture that co2 off of off of
the power plants but then we truck at a
very long way to get it to both the
cultivation and the brewery and so we
want to look at that and then to get at
your question of you know what is the
co2 sequestration rate of marijuana in
an indoor grow environment that's
something that I would love to study and
I want to study but I cannot get the
funding to study it because the ultimate
pathway for cannabis is combustion and
so that's something to be aware of at
least from you know Public Health and
Environment is you know if we're looking
at life cycle analysis knowing the co2
sequestration rate of the plants is kind
of a moot point if the ultimate pathway
is combustion and so when we look at the
via you know the environmental benefit
of this project we're mostly focusing on
the vehicle miles traveled
reducing that that burden there we know
that there is some environmental benefit
of taking you know what would be just
vented from the brewery and feeding it
to the plants because it doesn't all end
up in combustion but you know it could
ultimately end up in the landfill as
well and or you know when we compost
plants I want everyone to be aware of
yes composting is one step above
landfill but when plants biologically
break down they release methane and co2
and we should be aware of that those can
be used as commodities if we change the
way we manage our waste stream if we
didn't have this 50/50 waste rule we
could have on-site anaerobic digestion
of cannabis plant material where we are
doing this and basically a black box
breaking down that plant material then
we can capture the methane as a
commodity we methane is natural gas we
burn it and also co2 I mean that's a
commodity as well that we use within our
grow rooms and our extraction processes
so that's another opportunity there with
the plant waste I think I got a little
off track on your questions but I hope I
answer them thanks this questions for
Kaitlyn as well so the with the brewery
to cannabis project I was curious you'd
mentioned that some of the larger
breweries capture on-site and reuse and
I was curious it was there a particular
driver for these smaller breweries to
capture and then sell off-site rather
than to reuse on-site yes so Bree
depending on the size of the brewery
they are gonna generate way more co2
than what they need in their process and
actually when I ran into earthly labs at
the the Colorado craft brewers
conference and they showed me their
technology in their plan to implement it
their plan was to just implement this
technology at breweries to only capture
maybe 15 to 20 percent of their co2
emissions because that's all they need
as input to the rest of their process
and then they just vent the rest because
it there's no economic driver there and
when I saw that I jaw hit the floor I
was like from an environmental sample as
much as you can from an economic
standpoint capture as much as you can
and sell it and so this is really the
first time that that's been that this
has been done but I'm
you know I'm really excited about this
project because I think it's such an
inspiration point just start looking at
waste as a commodity to start looking at
partnering with different industries to
create independent localized economies
among small businesses you know we just
cut out a large co2 company by doing
this that wasn't very happy about it but
you know it's new ways of thinking and I
think that one thing that I always like
to drive home to people is this is true
today and every day moving forward we
have the most amount of people on this
planet and the least amount of resources
we've ever had we've got to change the
way we do things great well I want to
thank the experts on this panel for all
of your wisdom thank you so much for for
sharing it with everyone today and we
hope you all enjoyed it thank you
[Applause]
[Music]