what's interesting and concerning to me
at the same time is on each question I'm
finding that throughout the supply chain
you are interpreting the regs
differently and so if you're gonna
reflect back what are what could we do
to make sure and I know you're going to
tell me I know we got to get information
out but with all of our other
responsibilities do you have any good
ideas for us where we could do a better
job of explaining the regs I mean maybe
it starts with the regs themselves but
you know I think there's better ways to
get the information out and and one
thing that I worry about as we come to
the final leg of our rulemaking how do
we make sure we're continuing to
communicate and collaborate we've done
it a lot getting these regs out but how
do we going forward make sure we keep
that momentum so I'd love your thoughts
on that you know I think there's an
agency to agency component right so a
lot of the operators are are kind of
wrangling multiple sets of regulations
that they have to comply with
cultivators have California Department
of Food and Agriculture open air
cultivators have the water board the
water resource control board they have
Department of Fish and Wildlife and then
depending on how they choose to
transport their product if they have say
a self distribution transportation
license now they have BCC right and and
so how how like as a cultivator we
digest that body of material is really
challenging and then I find that there's
not always the same I don't know if
definition is the right word but maybe
interpretation of specific definitions
from statute so like we're really
suffering with the continuous premise
component especially as existing
cultivators that already built out right
how do we fit into that box but BCC
seems to have a little different way of
dealing with contiguous premise and say
CD FA or CD pH so those pieces make it
really kind of a quicksand feeling
because
you're not sure who to look to for
answers in some of those cases so I
think kind of more interagency
communication and sort of joint
educational opportunities would be
really fabulous you know what I was
yearning for in this in this last round
of these of the draft regulations and
also actually with July 1 in lab there's
not a lot of us who are currently
offering I think there's maybe 30 or
maybe more licensees now as they keep
adding on but in terms of operators it's
it's I think it's less than 15 probably
right now and what we're doing is fairly
complicated there's a lot of details and
if we get it wrong we can have a serious
economic impact on a party completely
unintentionally by making by
misinterpreting something to miss
applying it on a CoA that then can't be
amended and so when those transitions
happen I said you know why it would have
been really great from a collaboration
perspective if we could have gotten the
lab operators on the phone with the
regulator's to really walk through what
what the ask from us was in terms of
changes to help us understand the label
claim thing has been a little over the
top to understand what it means what has
to be what doesn't have to be where's
the where's the area of permissions
where's the area of no permissions and
so I think like a literally a simple
conference call with the lab operators
because we're a small number would have
been amazing and it would have cleared
up a lot of kind of disparate things
between us which affected the
manufacturers and it affected
distributors because our interpretations
affect everybody in a big way now I
don't I don't think that's totally
doable for everybody because there's a
lot more manufacturers and a lot more
distributors than there are labs so that
may not be applicable for each group but
that approach which may mean maybe there
needs to be more funding for outreach
personnel that are specifically just
about outreach and about giving voice to
that interpretation because there's
there's a difference in having a
discussion like with Elena who's Ben
who's an amazing resource on your team
to help understand the regulations but I
think there's people who don't feel like
they have that personal connection to
the BCC team or a go-to person and
somehow we need to create that sense of
everybody knows who to go to and that
person has the bandwidth to answer them
because there there's a lot of us yeah
yeah um you know California is the only
state that has multiple agencies
regulating one supply chain in cannabis
so that's very unique and you know
obviously causes lots of problems with
interpretation and who has authority
over what and I would say you know
something the CDT FA does that they
started a couple of months ago and
they've only had a couple but they've
invited a couple of operators from
distributors and retailers to discuss
the just the excise tax and and how the
tax structure is paid and what's going
on and and we ask them questions and
they ask us questions and we kind of
just have this sort of informal
back-and-forth conversation so that's
been pretty helpful because that's been
unbelievably confusing on its own and so
that might be an idea I know there's the
Advisory Committee which is very formal
and and sort of there by law but some
sort of more informal stakeholder
licensee conversation and right now
since there aren't a ton of licensees if
it probably would be easier to do at
this point then you know six months or a
year later when if there's more coming
out as more places and people get online
and I think the other thing is you know
going back to this packaging and
labeling which has just been a you know
interesting transition and our different
interpretations of you know what is
required I think having a a general
understanding because we were in the
position I you know the retailer BPG was
saying that we are we're licensed and
inspected by the bureau so we're gonna
go with what the bureau says and what
statute says and then there's CD pH that
has what they have and then that's what
them I think this also comes down to why
there may have been some difference in
interpretation we're friends now though
and yeah so I you know one of the sort
of more specific nuanced things would
come down to sort of the you know
statute says everything has to be in a
resealable child-resistant
tamper-evident it's in one sentence and
it says cannabis and cannabis products
and so that means everything from seeds
to clones and and the seeds and clones I
would say was a very interesting
question because that's what statute
says CD pH doesn't address it you
California DFA doesn't address it and so
you know we are erring on the side of
caution because we're like well I the
Bureau is the one inspecting us not DPH
so we're just going to go as far
conservative as we possibly can and then
and that's what I I mean the staff kind
of they're frustrated with me too
because that's sort of how I go I'm like
we're gonna ease up as we realize that
we can but we're just gonna start with
the strictest interpretation but yeah so
sort of the the crossover areas and
addressing those and and who has you
know what are you guys looking for when
you're coming in to inspect the
dispensary when it comes to packaging
and labeling stuff like that I I would
as a lawyer kind of shift towards you
know when statutes are interpreted
greatly for the business community by
case law and in case law and forms and
different fact in our scenarios how one
would behave the IRS uses decisional
memos I think that it might not be a bad
idea to do something like decisional
memos that have an expiry date on them
so that the statute says they change
those decisions kind of become but it
would really help us out a lot while
we're really the front line I mean if we
fail state fails right so it helps us
out in defining how we should go and and
I would absolutely agree one body to
making those decisions and in itself
working with CD pH or working with the
other departments to come up with a
decisional memo that is consonant across
the board so that we can make a decision
for example if I have a cultivation
license can I can I package for somebody
kayak egde somebody else's flour just
off of my farm like it's really not
clear
so and it doesn't have to be clear and
we don't have to wait for regulators to
make that decision but I think in the
interim if the bureau could just make a
decision for right now for the rest of
this year our interpretation is that
would be acceptable that allows us to
mount this effort without the constant
fear that we're going to get you know
Thor's hammer on our back and so there's
a lot of that fear of how to move and if
we could have some clearance on that
it's kind of like an FAQ but it's a
little bit more formal right so just an
idea to throw out there I think it's
been great the way that the agencies are
willing to travel around the state to
listen to all of us during the public
comments and I think it would be you
know there's a there's a huge
cross-section of companies some which
have staffed up to have policy
professionals focusing on the regs on a
daily basis and then there's companies
that don't have that resource and they
utilize their industry associations or
word of mouth or you know call the
bureau up but it would I think it'd be
great if there could be ongoing
opportunities for the agencies to in
different parts of the state have
workshops that are designed to focus on
their regs and clarify and educate and I
think that probably you would get a lot
of participation there's a lot of hungry
minds
I know it's it might open a new can of
worms if one answer at one venue is
different than another answer at another
venue so obviously not a perfect
solution but I think there's a lot of
people that be interested to come in
here and learn this is what we mean when
we say this so I completely agree with
you it can be frustrating for us just
asked our communication guys on when
people don't when they call and say what
agency do we go to or for us it does get
frustrating because it doesn't even even
internally it's difficult to work with
two other agencies and come to decisions
and and being consistent also it's you
know like you noted we do want to do
or outreach but we're also dealing with
new staff coming on every day and it's
hard to keep them apprised of okay these
are the these are the regulations that
are in place right now and and so we
struggle with making sure that we're
giving consistent answers and you're not
getting different answers and I think
you'll see once we get our final
regulations it's going to make a lot
easier we don't have the emergency
regulations the proposed and all that so
this is all really very helpful you know
I I could I could keep interrogating
these guys more but I think you guys
want to answer some question questions
of them but I do want to point out that
we did get approval our budget got
approved to have a public awareness
campaign we are going out to bid so we
are gonna get out there and start having
a campaign to inform consumers of who's
licensed the importance of going to a
licensed retailer and also trying to
bring more people from the unlicensed
market into the regulated market so
that'll be something exciting you're
going to see from our communications
team so we're looking forward to that
but this has been extremely helpful to
me and I really appreciate you guys
being so candid with your answers
[Music]