so when we talk about environmental
control and how it controls or impacts
the growth or the quality of the plant
we're talking about managing and
controlling the environmental parameters
that are important to how a plant grows
so with regard to light plants respond
to light in two ways one is through
growth which is biomass accumulation and
weight and yield and the others through
morphology photo morphological affects
meaning that the spectrum of light or
the type of light you're providing to
the plants influences the size and the
shape of the plant and so those two
things can be complementary to each
other with regard to yield overall as
well as quality but sometimes they're
not complimentary and the way I like to
analyze that or make that make an
analogy about that is to think about
economy
whenever I have conversations with
growers I always tend to lean toward a
conversation about economics and when
you think about what a plant is a plant
is a really a factory it's receiving
energy in the form of light it's
converting that light energy into
chemical energy through the process of
photosynthesis and then through a lot of
other downstream at a lot metabolic
processes it is creating the the
molecules that make up the plant some of
those are the structural molecules the
stems and the leaves others are the
chemical the other chemical molecules
that we grow cannabis plants for so when
you're talking about it from an economic
perspective as the plant is using carbon
that it's absorbing out of the air
through these processes of these
different metabolic processes of fixing
that carbon that carbon can either be
turned into a stem a root a leaf cell or
it can be turned into a cannabinoid
molecule or could be turned into a
terpene so those two things could be
competing with each other in terms of
the economics of carbon in the plant
tell me about the cannabis plant and its
relationship with light at different
stages of growth there are a number of
people who advocate manipulating the
spectral environment over their cannabis
crops to try to elicit various responses
and it's very challenging to measure and
quantify that because of the variability
of not only the genetics of the plant
but the environment that they're growing
in as well as the analytics it takes to
measure those types of responses so it
makes it very difficult to to verify and
validate that those types of
environmental influences on the plant
are causing the results that they are
intended to result in so one some of
those types of spectral manipulations
are to modify the spectral environment
for different phases of growth and it's
I believe part of it is as a legacy
issue where people have grown different
phases of the plant growth under
different types of lights which have
different types of spectrum so they
would advocate for a blue rich
environment in the veg phase which would
make um from a fluorescent light or a
metal halide light versus the less blue
rich spectrum for flowering such as
you'd get in a high-pressure sodium
light one thing that a lot of people
don't realize is that all of the
electric lighting technologies including
LED technology were never developed for
growing plants they were only developed
for human lighting applications it just
so happens that humans and plants see
the same wavelengths of light when I say
see I mean they both are sensitive to
the same wavelength range of life but
they see that light very differently so
humans use that wavelength range of
light for visual you know to see for
visual purposes plants use it for energy
that's their energy source for growing
and so plants absorb all wavelengths of
light in the range in that same range so
all wavelengths of light are useful to
the plant and drive in photosynthesis
okay I always hear like 400 to 700 so
yeah can you talk about is there any
research into the light outside that
respect like zero to 400 and 700 plus so
plants use the wavelength ranges between
400 nanometers and 700 nanometers and
that's essentially what humans can see -
but plants also absorb light outside of
those ranges and typically that like
those those wavelengths of light
are used for signaling in the plants so
on the lower end of the the
photosynthetically active radiation
range below 400 nanometers which is in
the near UV to UV range that can have
certain responses on plants typically
it's an environmental stress response
plants can respond to that in a way that
would protect themselves from that type
of so you should the plant saying this
is not normal something wrong is going
on I need to protect myself maybe like
have a thicker layer on the leaves yes
it's not necessarily that they would
perceive it as not normal but what they
would perceive it as is it's an
environmental influence that the plant
has a response to and so if they're
exposed to that environmental influence
meaning a UV photon then it has a
response to that you feed UV photon
plants are amazing living things because
they are they can't move so they have to
endure a very wide range of
environmental conditions and and as such
they've evolved many different ways to
deal with those different types of
environmental influences so if a plant
were growing at very high elevation and
exposed to a lot of UV they would
produce chemicals that would protect
them from UV damage to them just like we
put on sunscreen when you go to the
beach plants create their own sunscreen
when they're exposed to UV radiation and
sometimes that's in the form of
molecules that can be similar to if not
the same as the types of compounds were
growing cannabis plants for to improve
the quality weight so sometimes the end
result could be a good desired result
yes but when you think about the carbon
economy of the plant if the plant has to
put on a thicker layer of wax on the
leaves to protect itself from UV
radiation that's carbon that goes into
that protective layer that's not being
used to make cannabinoids or terpenes
for example okay how about the other end
so above
sure so so above 700 nanometers is
far-red radiation and that does also
have an influence on plants it tends to
be given a lot more importance in the
cannabis culture in cannabis cultivation
than it really deserves because far red
light is associated with phytochrome
responses in plants and that's
associated with flowering and so people
would like to correlate far red light
with flowering and cannabis plants when
the reality is it's the photo period of
light that's triggering that that
reproductive they're triggering that
reproductive response in the plant
through the photo period and not
necessarily spectrum it in the real
world meaning in an outdoor environment
is there more red light in the fall than
let's say like is there more blue light
in the spring and red light is because I
I know I understand that people have
these perceptions is it kind of coming
from what they're seeing visually yeah
it's it there is seasonal differences in
the spectrum but it really is very minor
typically where you see the changes in
the spectrum and the sunlight is that
sunrise and sunset or dusk and dawn
because of the angle of the Sun and its
penetration of light through the
atmosphere changes the spectrum but the
majority of photons the plants receive
or during the day and that spectrum
doesn't change much at all if you look
at the past 10 years of light science
research as it relates to plants what
were some of the sort of the most grant
like in your mind most groundbreaking
discoveries in terms of like aha this
has we've discovered what this does to
plants here's one that's pretty relevant
to this industry is years ago people
were using LEDs to grow plants and
people have been growing plants for at
least 25 years using LEDs that's when I
first started with my research at NASA
and we focused on using wavelengths of
light that matched the absorption
profile of chlorophyll a and B which
means you used it was blue and red so
mixing blue and red LEDs together was
producing a spectrum that was absorbed
by
chlorophyll molecules now the problem
with that is that those measurements or
at least that chemical or that
absorption profile for chlorophyll was
from isolated chlorophyll out of leaves
and measured in a test tube in a
spectrophotometer and that produced a
graph that showed that chlorophyll a and
B absorb light and the blue and red
range now that led people to think that
plants only need red and blue light and
that's we note that today that's not
true but it's led to a lot of technology
development for LEDs specifically with
red and blue LEDs and it's a the
combination of the two is a purple
spectrum which is not superior to a
broad spectrum in any way but it still
works it will grow plants as long as the
light levels are maintained at the same
as the broad spectrum you would expect
the same types of yield and same types
of responses from the plant
however there's a human factor issue
associated with a purple spectrum it's
very difficult to detect problems with
your plants if your responsibility is to
make sure your your production facility
is running well and you need to look for
powdery mildew or insects or nutrient
deficiencies it's very difficult to see
those under a purple spectrum so the
broad spectrum you literally when you
open those doors and walk in yeah so the
broad spectrum provides a superior
spectrum not only for the plants but
also for the people that are working in
that environment you have like the spot
level of light right and then you have
like the accumulation over a period of a
day yeah so can you talk about what each
of those are called and then like how
much how much sort of at one point in
time during the plant's various growth
stages you want and then what the
overall for like a day sure is that
you'd want yeah
so when we when we talk about light
measurement or light levels on on the
canopy we're talking about an
instantaneous measurement of light and
that's used with a quantum sensor and it
measures light between 400 and 700
nanometers it doesn't distinguish
between any of the different wavelengths
of light
tells you how much light that plants
absorb are hitting your canopy it's an
instantaneous measurement
there's also another very important
measurement for light and that's the
accumulated light dose that the plants
received and that's term called daily
light integral or DLI and that is
basically the instantaneous measurement
of light times time and so it gives you
a daily amount or a daily dose of light
that the plants receive and that's very
important because when you're talking
about a photo periodic plant like
cannabis that flowers under short days
and states vegetative under long days
it's very important to manage those
types of instantaneous light levels and
the duration of time that they're
receiving in order to maintain a healthy
plant under those different reproductive
stages of growth and development so
given that what are some of the things
you've seen when you walk into a grow
operation where they're either giving
way too much or too little and what the
effect is on the plant's growth and
health well what I will address though
is how you can use DLI to solve or
mitigate some of the problems people
have going from vegetation to flowering
phase so if you if you're focusing on
DLI as a measurement or as a parameter
of your grow facility you can have a
similar DLI in veg that you do in
flowering and what that does has a very
practical implication because it allows
you to mitigate the light stress that a
lot of growers observe when they go from
veg to flowering if they veg under very
low lights light levels then they are
they have a lower DLI when they when
they move those plants into the
flowering phase and they have a much
higher instantaneous light level under a
shorter photo period the overall doses
of light that the plants receive is much
higher therefore the plants have to
acclimate to that higher amount of light
they're receiving and the the immediate
response that the plants have is they
observe a stress response to light it
hurt that's too much light the plants
cannot handle that much light and the
new growth has to be when the new growth
is produced it is then acclimated to
those higher levels of
growers often have to dim the lights or
turn some of some of their lights off or
raise the lights to mitigate that light
stress during that transition period but
if you manage the alive it's feasible to
mitigate that light stress period by
having similar DL is between your veg
phase and your flowering phase
[Music]