[Music]
we spend a lot of time talking today so
I feel like I learned a lot about
solitude well a lot basically that it's
just a very very reflective duct work
and you can get a lot of sunlight into
your building excellent I've learned a
lot about just the the whole chemistry
between behind photosynthesis and plant
growth I really enjoyed your talk this
morning pretty fascinating yeah yeah I
appreciate that
so from the perspective of solar tube
know is there anything that you can
utilize in that like the sort of
horticultural space is relatively new
market for you it is and I'm anything
we're always learning about certainly
par how can we better calculate for par
what you know how do we aid in the
horticultural space in properly
designing a system how do we account for
daylight how we use the the current
design tools and tweak them to you
support for that solitude they develop
the really good it's it's a daylight
calculator and I think I meant I heard
you mentioned it's not really convey
label commercially but you guys have a
DLI calculator sure yeah
dearly late integral tool right that we
can use and there are DLI Maps or D like
daily light integral maps available it
takes a bit of digging but you can find
these for all kinds of different parts
of the world
yeah and for different crops less so
with cannabis at this point but for all
these different crops there are
recommended DL eyes even down to just
like different developmental stages
right so one strategy is just trying to
hit that target D Li and for something
like whether its greenhouse or whether
it's a solution like like like so - one
challenge that you guys are gonna have
is just by virtue of the fact that you
are still reliant on sunlight they're
going to be parts of the days and
certainly times of the year when you're
really not getting enough sunlight
absolutely so we we have to work
cooperatively so I really see the the
synergy between our products and the
work that
and that the job done and how do we
merge everything together right to make
the most efficient system possible there
may address the needs of horticulture
and plant growth and I think that's
that's something that you really taught
me is I really didn't realize that the
plant required different spectra at
different points in its life never
really occurred to me it makes total
sense now
but I you know what what we'd like to do
what we were designing with the system
is the dynamic interplay between the
amount of sunlight that's available and
then your LEDs that are inside of the
room and it's it's interesting how often
people will get caught up on oh well
there's not enough sunlight the counter
to that is really any second you can
turn off the LEDs or turn them down
you're saving money your and so to a
certain extent you know if you're up in
Alaska and you know maybe if if you know
it's not completely dark for 24 hours
but if you're in Maine or you're way up
there you're gonna have less light you
rely on the LEDs more but it's less than
what you would be doing if it was a
hundred percent artificial light
absolutely right off that way yeah and I
think your idea to I think you had
explored augmenting the daylight spectra
you know and with your tunable LEDs and
really helping address yeah different
stages of growth yeah I mean there's a
tons more research to be done on the
specific spectral composition as it
relates to secondary metabolites in
cannabis you know I think that we have
indications now that blue blue light
during veg and red light towards the
flowering phase sort of you know being
back in California reminds me of the
sunset over the California coast and the
fall where it gets your very deep red
but there really just isn't empirical
research and the cannabis space that I'm
aware of at this point that is truly
looking at how do the different light
spectral compositions affect those
metabolites yeah well and to that end
that's actually something that my
research program at fluence is pretty
focused on mm-hmm and you're absolutely
right I mean there isn't a lot of
research out there right now and what's
more is that on both the recreational
side and on the medicinal side there
isn't a clear desire metabolic profile
right people know a lot about THC right
and a little bit less know about CBD but
they know it's there
right and then further still they know
that there's this class of compounds
called cannabinoids right and this class
of compounds called terpenes and we know
that we like some kind of cocktail of
these things yeah why does cbn matter
you know we don't know exactly yeah and
you can you can look to a few different
parts of the world that are kind of
driving that more clinical research and
trying to understand how these different
cocktails of chemicals affect the human
body well mister otherwise right israel
is kind of the world leader in this for
what it's worth but yeah like we are
explicitly trying to understand how
different light qualities and letting
intensities and even like scheduling how
these affect these profiles right it's
something that I have some published
work on for my PhD and it's also
something that we've one study that's
publicly available we talk about it a
lot we did with proof calls of our last
year there grow our up in Portland OR
Ligurian that one was Jeremy plum that's
right yeah
with that study they were looking at
well they fluence we were looking at the
red fire red ratio and we basically took
one of our standard products that has
you know a lot of white diodes with some
red diodes and we took it at the red
diodes and added four red diodes and we
were comparing these two things so one
of these things had a red far-red ratio
of about 17.5 so in other words a lot of
red very much far red and then they'll
when the red fluoride ratio was about
six point one so it's still high red but
a lot more far red and what we found
there was that it did really interesting
things to the terpene profiles right so
what we found there was that it didn't
just in blanket terms it didn't just
boost monoterpenes or or you know
decrease Esper terpenes or anything like
that it selectively manipulated certain
terpenes interesting so what this says
to me and also kind of why i want to
explore this further is because what it
says is that with specific light
qualities you can manipulate and craft
really specific chemical cocktails right
and so as soon as the market knows what
it needs either recreationally or
medicinally will know how to provide
yeah and get them tuned the light recipe
essentially to the desired outcome of
the metabolism so what can we do to
support this process well I you know I
think that you know the the goal of the
IAE s conference is about sustainability
and I so in some ways we've sort of
jumped over sustainability but in my
mind reducing the costs of goods sold on
your cannabis flower is an absolute
necessity for long-term business
survivability so you know a good place
to start is with LEDs or a hybrid system
where we're looking at bringing in
sunlight with those LEDs just to simply
get your cost of goods down you know
soon enough we'll have interstate
commerce and I'm looking at the guys
that have built a 30 million dollar
facility in Columbus Ohio is there a
market which they can remain you know if
they're not focused on reducing those
costs and increasing their operational
efficiencies at this point I don't know
they're cool yeah they're gonna have to
moving forward right right yeah I mean I
think in terms of that particular
initiative to try and understand the
biochemistry a little bit better and the
mission to sort of drive certain
chemical profiles I think Solar tube is
a little bit removed from that story and
I don't mean we don't have that control
yeah so we don't we don't have the
control over the experiment that you
have but I could learn from you know
working on projects together and really
learning how we could use your tuned
ability to augment or work with daylight
and when is the right time to have
daylight because again the fun thing is
I mean ultimately with our product if we
need to turn it off at a certain phase
in the the developmental cycle right and
that's not an issue
I like to say that we in the research
that we heard up at Sonoma we fueled
with the solar tubes so we like fueled
photosynthesis with the Sun but then we
drove photosynthesis with the LEDs you
could sort of steer things in a way that
you'd like it to go and really just
pushing that further we were we were
just doing proof of concept you know the
first question was can plants grow under
these things you know that was that was
first then it was how how can we
increase our
efficient our productivity so exceeding
28 grams of square foot or 30 grams
square foot I think we peaked at around
33 grams per square foot and doing that
with the absolute minimal amount of
electric split experimenting with
different strains to see what strain or
maybe the bet was it
Sonoma Sonoma County Ohio okay alright
you're trying to throw me off because
I'm Canadian he won't know I think we
ended up hitting though in terms of
grams per watt was greater than two
grams per watch yeah I think so and I
haven't seen I haven't seen numbers
higher than that and you know
essentially we were looking at real-time
readouts of our electrical usage and
using it as like a speedometer and to
the point where we could just let's get
it down to 40 watts you know growing a
hundred square feet of cannabis on 40
watts that's you know a mainstream li
energy efficient yeah and then I think
the question the next question is what
do we do to work with the utilities to
get programs to support this process
because I think that's going to be key
moving forward is what can the utilities
do to incentivize you know really
functional well-designed hybrid system
yeah well and to that end I mean kind of
like I said in our panel over there I'm
not the best authority in the company on
this but we have a couple of people that
I focused very much on utility rebates a
lot of utility providers fluence has
been very successful probably one of the
most successful LED providers in the
cannabis space at getting those utility
rebates and so they essentially will
award you back the incremental cost so
how much more does it cost to do LEDs
versus the HBS they're gonna see an
energy savings we know that and then get
that incremental cost covered you know
really in terms of hybrid light systems
as well it's a matter of getting the
notion that there are other ways to
approach a hybrid light facility design
than just a standard greenhouse and when
we think about the the Sun grown indoor
the solar tubes with the fluence inside
of an insulated room really what you're
getting there is an environment that's
much more resilient to the outside
condition so if it's in Canada and it's
snowing in the winter you're able to
maintain your internal temperature with
a lot less in
energy input and so continuing to get
the word out there and demonstrating
that the technology works in multiple
areas and multiple climates and then you
know sharing that with with the industry
but also utility companies yeah so it
really becomes collecting more data than
in a lot of ways more data yeah you know
creating synergy between solo tube and
other other companies like fluence to be
able to put this data together to
demonstrate how it works
so you're accessible demonstrations are
gonna be keen absolutely and you were
mentioning you have like several like
over 20 just in North America right
studies cup lined up for 2020 yeah so
Wow that's impressive
yeah it's it's impressive and it's
terrifying and exciting and in a million
other things so I mean fluence has had a
tremendous amount of success in the
cannabis space in North America and
worldwide and that's great for us
because we can leverage that success to
really have a pretty aggressive research
program right and so a big part of the
strategy is how do we continue to
innovate in cannabis and how do we try
to address some of these bigger
questions our research of course is not
limited to just cannabis but since
that's what we're talking about right
now we have in North America probably
seven or eight really good studies
ongoing right now that will round out
within 2020 I'm pretty excited about
those
I can't be overly specific but I'll
share what I can yeah so I guess you
could say our research questions fall
into a few big bins right there's four
most there's just maximizing yield right
and people always want to know what is
the right spectrum for their top plate
and at that point usually when someone's
asking that we've already overcome the
debate of LED or HBS so are you also
studying temperature effects and ppfd
and what the optimal ratios are or
exactly the questions of the rest of the
environment parameters whether it's
temperature and day and night
temperature differentials and if it's
irrigation and nutrition and things like
that those are research questions that
we ask for my team they're sort of
second priority my team is focused
foremost on light light intensity like
quality light sort of scheduling things
like that but yeah so we're looking at
things like different top light spectra
and whenever we do a study we're looking
at things like yield not just total
shoot biomass but also harvest index so
how much of you yo this bud would you
actually care about how much is leaf how
much is stem so looking at these carbon
allocation ratios we're looking at
dynamic lighting so you know should you
be doing something different at the end
of your crop to drive secondary
metabolism a certain way just a 24-hour
cycles like sunrise sunset sure have you
done that yeah no we haven't done that
okay right so I think was really
interesting with your foundational
research was how you were able to show
that the plants do like to have a
dynamic source to a certain degree it
seems like as they how they woke up in
the morning change depending on the
light source yeah when it was exposed to
these subtly shifting patterns right
yeah watching them follow that you know
was interesting when we were when we
were looking at the time lapses back the
LEDs would come out let's say 7:00 a.m.
but the amount of sunlight that would
come into this space really wasn't you
know a peaceful look them yeah
significant until like say 9:30 10:00
but as soon as that Sun like did get in
the space the plants were just
you know they were essentially brushing
for that you know to happen so it's it's
interesting to think about that but at
that point you're still achieving you
were you know at the start of the day
you were achieving the the ppfd that was
desired right so it's truly the change
and special content yeah that all son
changed how the plants reacted which is
kind of interesting the special content
yeah okay would you attribute this do
you think too far red because that I
just think that so where we started
essentially was that okay they they come
up they wake up when they see the
sunlight and then there's this hot spot
that moves and they started following it
and it was just sort of an observation
right we didn't really empirically have
an a/b control but it seemed to me that
the plants were sort of appreciative of
the fact that they weren't just sort of
blasted with the maximum amount of light
for all 12 hours they were just sort of
this sort of you know dynamic see
something a little bit more natural you
know you could test it further you could
push it further but it just seemed to be
that there were some element where it's
more of a natural cycle for them and
that they seem to prefer the sunlight as
it moved through yeah you know I know
that you have some some education in
circadian rhythms specifically if we
were to try and pursue a study like this
we the sort of collective body of class
scientists not fluence and that solitude
in that you know
like whoever if we were to try and
explore this in the cannabis space how
would you recommend going about it well
I mean I think first of all I think we'd
have to figure out a way of being able
to sample well
studying the the various organic
compounds that you know change
throughout the change within the plant
over the course of the day and actually
do some controlled studies looking at
specific specific action spectra how
does it change the the organic compounds
present what's happening within the
plant I think it becomes a common I mean
it's an interesting question is probably
best answered with something that has a
very stable special content that we can
control but replicate the
the daylight process and then figure out
then how does daylight how we use that
dynamic nature of daylight and the
Chronos spectral dosage associated with
daylight to now really drive the the
plant the plant over the course the time
exactly I mean I think what we you know
all of us are scientists we appreciate
data in like collecting data up until
this point cannabis cultivation and the
industry practices have been basically
community consensus that was developed
in the black market right it's a totally
different set of market pressures that
businesses are operating under and so
anything really that furthers you know I
used to joke two years ago when it was
you know i can grow three pounds a light
and i saw well do you have any data that
shows that no all right well then get in
line you know so my grandma can grow
three pounds of light but now we're
getting somewhere we're moving beyond
that community census and challenging
assumptions yeah and it's it's all
towards the drive of increasing plant
quality but also operational
efficiencies i mean really we are
getting the point where we have
evidence-based design right process
development i think that i think we're
right on the cusp of being able to
really change kind of the old not
stigmas but the the way things have
always been done or how people have
certain preconceptions of how it should
be done and i think i'm really excited
with the the research that you're doing
and i think that that really drives the
industry and certainly jonathan
everything that you've done is it's it's
been fun to watch from a distance and
now it's it's interesting I've really
enjoyed being able to read your papers
and research over the last few weeks and
become more understanding of everything
that you've been giving all of our
respective backgrounds and I think we're
all it's mainly trying to contribute the
same same things for the world that
sounds like there's an awful lot of room
for
vibration may be fun love it yeah
excited about the opportunity
yeah me too definitely too great well I
guess I was kind of thinking about
moving forward and how this all really
comes together and I think it's
obviously more data more experimentation
collecting that data and going back to
yield above beyond biomass I think yeah
it's really about yield of the secondary
metabolites and terpene content and sort
of trying to determine how we are
activating these genetics on different
levels with this system and the synergy
of the system any thoughts on that maybe
I'll start yeah please
absolutely yeah so whether it's cannabis
or any other crop something that we look
at is really the interaction between the
genetics and the environment or if you
apply this to sort of human development
the sort of nature versus nurture and
yeah I would say that understanding the
environment is crucial because
inevitably for better or worse there are
going to be companies that are doing
things with breeding programs and maybe
you know genetic modification is going
to get involved and all of these
different things kind of on this sort of
more biological side more genetic side
if we start playing around with that
before we understand how the environment
impacts any of that it's just going to
become a very convoluted math changing
to many variables and exactly yeah yeah
so I think keeping control and testing
one thing at a time is going to be key
to success
data is no longer evidence collected
[Laughter]
just kind of like going down the line
what's each of your understanding of how
kind of plants what kind of light a
cannabis plant needs at different stages
of its life cycle well I'm certainly the
novice here so I actually look to these
two gentlemen because I just know they
like light and I've certainly learned I
mean the the the special content over
the life cycle is definitely new to me
that that's something I wasn't aware of
actually before this before today to be
honest so so I think Jonathan you and
David certainly are the two who has to
answer this question I think that the
best light for plants is the plant that
they evolved to utilize for
photosynthesis so that would be that of
the Sun but there are spectral banks
within par that we know drive certain
segments of growth based on the
absorption profiles and correct me if
I'm wrong of chlorophylls
and carotenoids yeah so I think it's
pretty clear that we can use blues and
Red's in early flowering or veg and then
late flowering one that often comes up
as well as is UV and the application use
of UV and what that means for secondary
metabolites but I personally haven't
seen empirical research that shows one
way or the other exactly what the UV
does and I just think you know we're all
sort of looking out into the horizon
that there is more to untangle with the
spectral composition but what we truly
know has yet to be known which is as a
science is something you find exciting
you know we don't know so let's figure
it out what does the UV trigger that
plants protective mechanisms
and that's worth irrevelant man yeah
yeah I mean that's one theory I'll pass
the David to be a little bit more
specific I'm sure so maybe I'll start by
answering the UV question specifically
the short answer is yeah well actually
that's that is sort of a good way to
think of UV as a plant stress and to
some degree you can think of it as just
sort of a more extreme blue now just
like Jonathan said the empirical
evidence in cannabis is definitely
lacking as a whole sort of the photo
biology of cannabis is a pretty sparsely
populated world right now but UV in
particular there's really only a handful
of papers that have directly explored UV
and cannabis chemical profile basically
the one that people tend to reference is
by a guy named John Lydon and his
research group from 1987 and they were
doing low doses of UVB I think that
Deepika mission of 310 nanometers a to
85% like that but basically what they
found was that with these low doses the
THC concentrations went up
proportionally and this was a long time
ago it was pretty well done study but
nobody has done anything on it since so
you know this is a question that that
worked
cautiously looking at it's tough to do
really good UVB research because it's
also a little bit dangerous
you know UVB for one you can't see it so
when it's went on you don't know and
secondly I mean it's the shorter the
wavelength that you have the less time
it takes for it to damage to you because
it's really just about the total match
of energy that's being applied to your
eyes and your skin and it's literally
just it has enough energy to break
molecular bonds including DNA bonds and
your DNA is always repairing itself but
sometimes it makes mistakes and if you
say you know what DNA I'm just gonna
keep hammering you with this UV
eventually your DNA's gonna go alright
well I've had enough kazar time so
anyway all that to say if we if we take
a less traumatic kind of explanation
about it and we just talked about kind
of mild doses of UV it's similar to like
when we go outside and we have exposure
to UV light we get a
and that's our skin protecting ourselves
from these UV light plants do the same
thing to some extent right and that's if
you look at grapes or if you look at red
leaf lettuce or if you look at
blueberries all of that pigmentation
that anthocyanin is protecting against
high-energy photons now with cannabis
the question that we're asking in one of
our studies right now is so you need to
do this with UVB or do you do it with
UVA or can you just do it with blue
which is a for us way cheaper to
manufacture the diodes have a way longer
lifespan and it's a way safer for
everybody so you know the jury's out the
photoreceptors are also a little bit
different between blue and UVB yeah just
cuz you read it on a we growers forum
doesn't necessarily mean that empirical
science was done to truly understand
that you know it's not a Thorat ativ
source well I think was what was pretty
interesting today which I never I'd
never drawn the correlation before but
was very interesting during our session
this morning was when we were talking
about the fact that obviously we have
photopic vision we have the photopic
special response curve for daytime
vision of the human eye but then what
was very interesting is that when I
realized that the circadian response
curve through the human eye PRG sees the
retinal ganglion cells actually directly
follows the same action spectra as the
blue end of required for photosynthesis
and the Cree curb it's like that was
pretty fascinating so I wonder if there
are any similarities who can start to
draw because my experience and expertise
is in vertebrate chrono biological and
photo biological response and what's
kind of interesting because we know that
the human eye and the the vertebrates
have obviously some danger zones and
once we get outside the visible spectrum
into the UV side of things it'd be
interesting to know whether maybe plants
have the same problematic yeah yeah yeah
sort of a danger wavelength
I mean isn't it just tough to supplement
UV back into an indoor space
predictively I wouldn't I would say
that's tough
I mean before LED there are a number of
other technologies like those
fluorescent tubes and there's there's a
few other things to start being a
tanning bed sure yeah that's a great
example um there are other sources of UV
as far as I know none of them none of
them have great lifespans and they're
not particularly bright not that you
want a hole so I don't think it's
particularly challenging and I've even
seen some really interesting deployments
of UV so the good side of cannabis right
UVB and UVC can actually be deployed to
deal with with superficial patch like
powdery mildew and botrytis and things
like that I've seen solutions where if
people have for instance a long kind of
four foot wide table and they have an
irrigation boom that moves the length of
it they've mounted a UV bar just to this
and it just kind of passes over and it's
sterilizer yeah yeah and I mean there
are other things too like certain sort
of strategic applications of UV B or C
you can induce systemic required
response in plants in other words boost
their immune system so you're doing more
than just that surface sterilization
you're also taking to the plant you know
be Hardy ER and defend yourself so it's
it's doable
that was my note from your presentation
yeah the photo reactivity and boosting
the immune system and perhaps pest
resistance with the UV yeah very
interesting
what so forget cannabis specifically
just like for each of you as people who
study plants and light what's kind of
like some seminal research that like if
you look at the body of light plant
science research kind of like what was
groundbreaking in each of your opinions
like and the understanding of how plants
react to light yeah that's a hard
question I mean yeah I - and I'm gonna
say this first one where I'm not at all
trying to just sort of toot my own horn
but a question that I've been kind of
asking for a little while is about plant
acclamation and just you know if you
grow plants in one light environment for
a little while what does that mean for
what we understand about light that you
use later on
there are a bunch of applications for
this I mean I know you said not specific
to cannabis but they're cannabis is a
good example you know if the light that
used during veg has any influence on how
the plants respond to the light used
during flower that's a pretty big
question that affects affects a lot of
people but on sort of mortar like
commercial agriculture side you can look
at it from the perspective of maybe
strawberries in strawberries excuse me
strawberries are propagated basically
clonally you can think of idiots it's on
like these runners kind of in a field
and they're in a certain light
environment usually it's sunlight but
maybe you've propagated them a different
way in a controlled environment you know
does that light environment where you
got all of your strawberry stock for
your production change how those plants
will respond to the light that you're
giving them when they're when they're
fruiting later on so I'm really
interested in that and then I guess the
other big thing to me is is this
question of far-red it's I have a
love-hate relationship with the sort of
far-red discussion just because it's
been going on for quite a while and it's
challenging because there's a lot of
really conflicting evidence about what
far-red does specifically for
photosynthesis and does it drive
photosynthesis and I'm not going to take
a stance here because again there's just
there's conflicting evidence that I'm
still weeding through trying to
understand it a little bit better so
when I think about far red and if
customer calls and they insist that they
want to speak to the research group of
all red that comes to me any I usually
just say well look it it has pretty well
understood sort of morphological impacts
and you can count on its most the time
to kind of stretch out your plants so if
you have a really compelling reason to
do that and there are some but if you
have a compelling reason to do that then
yeah it's a good choice but if you're
just trying to add it to get more yields
there are probably better tools we can
recommend for it but again it's
something I want understand a little bit
better
something that both of you have said
that kind of has piqued my interest was
the fact that you know based on the
different types of plants that they're
where they come from the finds what it
is that they want or what they need so
I'm kind of curious as we start to look
at increasing the yield of certain
plants if studying kind of where they're
that what their home environment is how
you know if there's a specific growth
season
how does special content change say from
spring the summer to fall is that
something that needs to be replicated
that we can replicate then in the lab in
the the indoor environment to further
reinforce right kind of the biological
need or
yeah I wonder and what you were
mentioning to with like CRISPR and
bringing in DNA technology have you seen
any studies where people are trying to
add another chlorophyll or like you know
mutant chlorophyll that yeah yeah I have
heard of people talking about this
there's more conversation about this and
kind of like the microbial space and
laying around with algae I mean there's
there's there's a bunch of wild stuff
going on there's there's something
called chlorophyll F which I did a
YouTube video on a little while ago and
which is great because that'll be a
version of me explaining and remembering
how that works yeah this version of me
doesn't remember but it's supposed to
say chlorophyll F it is sensitive to
different peak wavelengths
then chlorophyll a and B that's typical
implants and you know in theory if you
were to take something like a core for
life that has a different absorption
spectra and a few other chlorophylls and
somehow mesh them all into one where you
just super effectively absorb all the
light right that'd be cool but they also
the reality of that it's just like
there's this whole light harvesting
complex for all of these pigments and
proteins interact in a pretty specific
match yeah downstream signaling pathways
get chaotic a complex yeah I just add a
gene yeah yeah that protein nicely
integrate there's a lot more going on
but one day one day one day yeah I don't
I don't know very many centum seminal
papers and plant sciences you know I I I
think that the big realization for me
was once I understood what the Makri
curve was and then I saw what an HPS
light output I was like just how did
this even happen how did we even get
here you know it says if you were to
make data-driven decisions this wouldn't
even have been an option that you would
pick and so that you know really it was
more about me wading into plan photo
biology from a neuroscience background
you know not from not from a plant
sciences background at all so I'm not
you know immensely familiar with those
things we had talked about the legendary
Bruce Bugbee before again we had talked
about Bruce and his most recent research
can you just give the the since you only
read the synopsis can you give the very
poor synopsis it wouldn't be fair for me
to comment beyond that because I'm happy
everybody else's
yeah I know I mean I read the abstract
in the punchline as I understood it was
that he was saying that far red light
should be included in the definition of
part IRA for synthetic reactive
radiation because presumably in this
paper and it feels awful to be
commenting on this because again I
haven't read it yet but presumably in
there he has evidence that says or
clearly demonstrates that far-red drives
photosynthesis so I'm really looking
forward to reading it I just need to
find a time on a flight
we're yeah