[Music]
so the science started in conventional
agriculture with Elaine dr. Laningham
and conventional agriculture is a is a
thing and it's not interested in those
technologies techniques and there's a
massive effort to keep them out of that
area so kind of the cool thing is where
they're being really embraced and picked
up is within the cannabis industry and
these are the people that are living
inside a forest so I feel like what we
do is a form of ecological restoration
if I can if I can fix your farm the
forest will fix itself from inside
you're fine
and so the intense production model of
the states of like Nevada they went big
with warehouses in this heavy production
model and so their analysis of that
process was a very quick learning curve
and each week you're bringing new
batches of plants and on you know a
200,000 square foot building there's a
lot of learning to have right there and
the same things happening in light depth
I can go and help a corn farmer and turn
around one season and learn a specific
set of information from that interaction
and then I can go to a light depth
greenhouse and I can have five full
harvests in a calendar year so for every
year I get 5 full opportunities to learn
and that is propelling the cannabis
light depth and high production indoor
people I mean decades and decades and
decades ahead of the commercial
agriculture and so I think the long-term
implications that are really hopeful
because we're going to hit a point where
the average age of the farmer that's
growing our food is 62 retires their
kids are now lawyers because farming is
not a Prospera business and the mega
scale and we're gonna have a tremendous
amount of really educated talented
farmers that know more responsible ways
to produce food and they've been working
with altering environments I think
that's gonna be needed for human
survivability so that's kind of what I'm
all about I'm trying to help those
people and try to help that movement
people take what I say really personally
but I'm I'm here for human survivability
and the way I'm doing that is by
communicating what's happening in the
soil to cannabis farmers and that's a
really enjoyable thing to do with my
life I believe the question is about
integrating food production and cannabis
production into the regulated market the
reason why that question is asked is
there seems to be the farther you get
away from suburban America or integrated
heavily densely populated growing areas
you start to end up with organic living
soil sustainable practice farmers that
are growing their food along with their
cannabis and I think it came out of a
need because these are the same people
that don't want to live off food from
the center store and so they're trying
to grow their own food so naturally just
they threw it in with the beds of
cannabis and that turned into making
really good food and also turns out
farther you get off the road and the
more vegetables are grown with the
cannabis the bigger the plants get the
reason why that happens is in a living
soil system the nutrients are produced
by organism to organism interactions
those organisms are fed through plant
root relationships so the more roots you
can get into that living soil the more
surface area you have for the potential
producing nutrients and that's exactly
what happens and that was a really fun
transition for me like started out going
to you know the chemical farmers in the
mountains and the better I got at the
microscope the farther I got off the
road and the more food was being grown
with plants you have there is so many
there's so many specifics about no wood
there's you know certain growing
materials you can use there's certain
things inside and it's outside of the
building
so we don't I don't think an approach to
surviving the regulated era would we
grow food in with the plant just because
the complications but we can take that
learning lesson into the regulated area
and we can replace the food with cover
crops that host micro as a fungi we can
we can grow plants that host these banks
of populations of organisms that produce
nutrients in the soil so we still carry
that mentality in that method for
success but the regulate s it's a sticky
thing and but we've we've had a wide
array of root vegetables that grow the
brassicas are helpful in starting the
system because they're early
successional plants they become
antagonistic earlier on but they are
good for starting a system and so we've
had cover crop blends that have root
vegetables in it and all kinds of wild
things so you still you still can carry
the method for success but it might be
really complicated there are a lot of
people that are entering the regulated
market with brands and they also grow
food so whether those happen at the same
exact location I don't know that would
be risky I think just because now you're
combining two regulatory bodies so I
probably keep them separate if we can
move out of fear of problem mindset and
we can move away from being afraid of
things we can quantify them
mathematically and address them with a
cost-effective approach and that just
takes a mentality shift of the facility
but people are absolutely succeeding in
the regulated market they're absolutely
thriving in the regulated market doing
living soils the beneficial insects and
no chemicals in the building
and that would be my suggestion for a
reasonable pathway through the regulated
market remove all the things that can
cause a fail and create plant health
environments that lower pest pressure
and disease susceptibility and then they
can get you in trouble for any things
what the industry really needs right now
is help with best practices there's a
couple groups that are trying to do it
the TCC the ICF a not up on all of them
but the farmers are communicating to me
that that what's really needed from them
is a way to actually differentiate
themselves from the other growers I mean
we're in an era where organic facilities
in regulated States or using banned
pesticides really on and skate and under
it's absurd
disrespect yeah man that's an absurd
disrespect for human life
[Music]
that's absurd to me because we can
quantify mitigate and adjust for these
pests we don't need to poison humans in
the process and it's you know the
process is raising an intelligence I
think our farmers need to raise an
intelligence and that's kind of been
what I've been after mostly inspired by
like the Dragonfly Medicine people and
they said something to the effect of we
don't need any more rich people we need
educated farmers that can farm
sustainably so humans can survive
that's really I think the beauty of the
regulated era as we bring things to the
forefront and as we examine that examine
them closely it shows how much we're
relying on a by all means approach with
disregard to human health you know and I
think it's really irresponsible to our
fellow people and if you're a farmer
growing something that's consuming you
have the highest obligation to other
humans to act right
[Music]