we see the same thing with hashes too
like Nepalese ball hash if you do a nice
Nepalese hash a temple ball you know
that you're gonna get different
cannabinoids in there I know Frenchy
cannolis talk about you're seeing you're
seeing terpenoids coming out of Nepalese
hash balls that you're not going to see
in fresh flour and you're gonna get a
you know a little bit of CBN degradation
in there but if you do a nice long slow
Cure you know it's just you get that
much rounder whole plant feel you know I
used to live in the Caribbean for a long
time and we'd notice that almost all the
bud that would come out of the Virgin
Islands it would be a golden brown color
and a lot of that's because they don't
have indoor spaces to cure so they're
curing in the Sun because if you're
curing in the shade or in the jungle or
the bush where you're growing it you're
gonna get a lot of rot and mold and
things like that the whole cure concept
is amazing and the way the degradation
and the color changes and you see this
in dispensaries all the time now that
the stuff that's a little golden there
are little amber is just sitting on the
Shelf all this bright green neon stuff
is flying out the door and people aren't
realizing think about cigars think about
the high-end whiskeys think about how
you're developing phenols in curing and
in transferring tannins and that's
really the crux of the issue you start
changing these chlorophylls all over the
tannins it's amazing you see all this
weed coming out of South Florida that
was cured in the traditional tobacco
ways with the Spanish cedar and you see
the phenols completely change the
terpene profile when it goes in after
curing in 28 to 30 days in the Spanish
cedar it just completely changes
everything especially of the Haze's and
the you know more rootsy spicy strains
really just develop in that environment
oh yeah when with the tobacco model
there's a cigar now that's I think it's
like $10,000 for these the box of these
cigars but it's a 15 year old tobacco
that they've been aging in these special
humidors
and with tobacco it requires a much
higher humidity content they're gonna
they want to be in a room with like a 70
percent relative humidity to keep it
right and with cannabis especially in
curing we want to keep it down around in
the 50 range you know you don't want to
have too much moisture in there because
you know you can get pathogens and in
the curing process you have to worry
about
Aspergillus and other things like that
so you really need to keep your room
stable and you know keep the humidity
just perfect and the temperature in a
certain range and you want to keep lots
of air flow going through and just take
your time with it you know it's it's
amazing people are just in such a rush
to get things out the door and you find
that you know some of our favorite
things we have I'm trying to remember
the name is what was it at and push or
something that's was it the tanjur we
had one that's a three at we've been
curing which one yeah the tan is cush
we've cured it for three years and it
has drastically change in nose in flavor
in every single way and it's just such a
happy flower to smoke it's just like you
know velvet going in yeah it's so funny
to me how many of the same concepts that
we all have been focusing on and
developing for 20 or 30 years for
cannabis are so the same processes and
concepts executed in different ways for
soil building like you know you talk
about these temperature ranges and time
we have to think about those same exact
things for composting and for aging our
forest products we use redwood and in
our soil because we're up in Humboldt
it's a byproduct of existing industry
that was being wasted and so we use it
in a very specific way compost it in a
way to build all of the microbiology
correctly it requires intense
temperature monitoring where we have to
let it hit a certain temperature and
roll it and then let it build back up to
these temperatures and you got to be
meticulous you got to pay attention
you've got a test you've got to look at
the whole picture and if you're not
paying attention it's going to get away
from you and that's where the experience
comes in for curing is so many people
who are new to the industry don't even
see the concept as existing and that's
why they can't execute it well and
there's the the the depth of each of
those things with the cannabis you have
all the different cannabinoids you have
the terpenoid so you have every little
bit of it that you need all those parts
THC is THC is THC it's a single note
it's gonna you know affect your cb1
receptors it's going to trigger that hi
and you know you can get the most
refined oil that is 90% THC and that's
fine but in that flower you're gonna
bring into
maturation all of the other parts of the
plant all the oils and the the aromatics
and and really bringing it the same
thing with the soil you need the micro
arising you need the beneficials you
need the bacteria you need the fun you
need every single bit it's not dirt dirt
is dead soil is alive