[Music]
it's an honor to be in the position I am
right now and so I'll tell you a little
bit about what we've been doing the last
year and what's been happening over the
last couple weeks as all of you know
last year I was appointed but my
responsibility was to put together the
first state regulatory system for
medical cannabis and then something
happened in November and it changed just
a little bit and our role is expanded to
adult youth also so the Bureau serves as
the lead agency on this effort but we're
not doing it alone we also work together
with the Department of Food and
Agriculture and Department of Public
Health Food NAG is is they're the ones
who are licensing our cultivators Public
Health and manufacturers and then the
bureau is handling the rest with the
testing laboratories the distributor's
transporters dispensaries and micro
businesses so so we've been working
pretty hard doing a lot of public
outreach happy to be in Orange County
again because a lot of us all of us from
the three agencies one we all started
with practically no staff and as we got
them on board we need to learn we need
to learn about cannabis I'll tell you I
came from alcohol and I thought okay
I'll come do cannabis oh they're so
different I always say alcohol is easy
cannabis is more complicated a lot more
complicated there's a lot of learning a
lot of talking to the public and the
industry and seeing what you've been
doing and I think our job you know we've
tried to take an approach that we want
to hear from you and one of the first
things out the gate that really
surprised me I think was how open
everybody was to telling us about
cannabis about their business about
their struggles over the last couple
decades and I think I didn't expect that
and that has been a tremendous asset to
the three licensing authorities because
unless we
know what you're doing it's really hard
to regulate and regulate in a thoughtful
manner and so that's what we've been
working on our medical regulations and
along with other things too isn't just
that we're all three standing up an IT
system and and we have you know food nag
has to do an environmental study the
Bureau is also doing an environmental
initial study so a lot of things going
on simultaneously and I do I have to ask
what what is our aggressive timeline
we're going to be issuing licenses when
yeah you guys are supposed to be more
excited about that right and I know it
sounds really aggressive and what do I
keep saying we can do this we've got to
do it it's the law right and so a big
part of this list was getting our
medical regulations so as most of you
how many is already taking a look at our
regulations so far good that's pretty
good so for all three of us we came out
with our regulations last Friday and
then we had one straggler that was a
testing laboratory that came out today
by the way so that is out on our website
right now and we separated the packages
let me tell you having testing labs was
that was the biggest probably challenge
is putting together those regulations
but what now we're looking at is one
thing we need from you and we don't I
don't take this lightly Cal California
has a very robust rulemaking process and
I know we talk about we always say
regulations or what are regulations well
they're basically the requirements that
we're putting into place for our
everybody that's going to get a license
with us so we have the statutes we have
proposition 64 we have the medical
cannabis and regulation and Safety Act
so now it's it's further defining those
requirements so some of the things that
you're going to see in our regulations
first of all we're going to define a
whole bunch of things that you see in
the statutes we define them we also have
detailed what the application require
so exactly what you're going to see on
day one when you fill out an application
and then we go into further things like
what who's an owner is a spouse and
owner and all of those things what's
priority licensing and and some of the
things then when we went into specific
license types and we laid out things for
example the dispensaries there's their
requirements for storage and packaging
and hours of operation delivery
requirements so all those things are in
there but the California rulemaking
process you know I have this question
all the time people ask what's taking so
long what you know what's going on you
know and any why don't you just take
Colorado or Washington regulations and
just copy them and I say well well we
probably don't want to do that not that
they're not good regulations but they're
not those were those were those statutes
weren't weren't for California that was
for Colorado and they're very different
and the other thing is is when we do the
California rulemaking process is a I'll
tell you it for the regulator is
probably difficult but for the public
it's a great thing because of all the
feedback that you all the commenting
that you can have on our regulation so
you basically can shape those
regulations so what you see right now
are proposed regulations and I I may say
that a couple times tonight they're
draft or proposed they're by no means
final it is our first step of saying
okay we've gone about we've we've talked
to other states we've talked to the
industry we've talked to local
jurisdictions we've talked to the public
this is what we came up with in addition
to that text we also have to put
together what's called an initial
statement of reason for every regulation
that we have text for we have to justify
why we put it in there you don't see
that a lot across the other state so for
California if you want to say well why
in the heck does the bureau say this you
can go back to that initial statement of
reason and say oh that's why they said
it now that doesn't mean you're going to
agree with us and that's okay
we're okay with you not agreeing with us
but what we would like to hear is hey
did we get some stuff right hopefully we
got a few things right did we get some
where did we get some stuff and we're
not quite there yet well we want to hear
that tell us what did we get wrong and
and and then tell us how we can make it
better and that's what this is all about
this whole public process so right now
we're in the 45 day a period for us so
from last Friday from all of the regs
there's a 45-day comment period again
the testing lab straggled they came out
today so it started out a 45-day comment
period that's a chance for you to weigh
in and help develop these regs so what
happens next
well we look at those comments and we
have to respond to those comments
anyway what so so we will have to
respond to your comment and it's
important to note that these are for
medical regulations but a lot of the
work and what we put into them it's a
lot of it's going to apply on adult use
side also a lot of things are not going
to change so then what are we going to
do what are we doing right now well
we're already well we wait for comments
we're already developing the adult youth
regulations because we have to because
our regulations have to be finalized by
the end of this year otherwise we can't
issue licenses so we will be issuing our
adult regulations probably in the early
fall and we are going to do that through
what we have in a statute which is an
emergency rulemaking Authority meaning
when we notice them they pretty much go
into effect immediately and then all the
public comment is on the back end and we
have a certain time period we have to
get that done so a lot of why we want to
release the medical right now is because
we want to hear from you we want to take
you know you could give us comments that
I think will help us with the adult use
also another reason we'll probably wait
to the fall is why yeah he said harvest
not not really I was I guess I was we
were looking at that but
so but I think that's brilliant by the
way I'm going to start using that one so
we have two statutes right and so if you
want to be we want to have a medical
dispensary or you want to be a retailer
adult youth you have so far now we have
two statutes and the governor's budget
has said they want to try to align the
two statutes and why do you think we
want to do that true all sorts yeah all
those things but probably also but it's
a lot more efficient and productive for
and cheaper for all of us if we align
them together how confusing would it be
for you guys if I said well if you get a
medical dispensary you're under this set
of rules but if you get an adult use
you're going to be under this rule it
would be confusing for the state of he's
confusing for you
so what we're what we're seeing right
now is what's called the governor's
budget trailer bill how many have looked
at that yeah that's caught a lot of
attention so right now with the
governor's trailer bill they're trying
to align the two models and so likely
that won't that is currently a bill it
has to be passed by two-thirds of the
legislature and we likely won't know
what the results are of that until late
June and then we will know what it will
look like so right now we're preparing
we're always like we're always preparing
for whatever we think might come down
the road and then we also have some
legislative bills out there how many do
we have out there right now for cannabis
so it's so Kenya it's like a moving
target around you know it's very it
makes my job pretty interesting and
exciting because every day something
changes so we're waiting to see what
happens on some of those 60 I didn't
think it was that many but anyway those
60 bills to see how it may further
change what our roles and
responsibilities are but what we're
trying to do with these regulations and
I think it's important for you to know I
mean we we do as California we want the
best model we want people to look at our
model and say gosh California got it
right and that's important to me and I
think it's important to all of you but
then we also want to make sure we're
protecting our the patience and the
consumer and the public and the
environment I mean but at the same time
we don't want our regulations that are
so onerous on a business that it's very
difficult to comply so it's trying to
strike that balance and I'll tell you
it's not easy to do that and and and so
you're going to hear me saying this we
truly want you to read these and comment
on them because I think it's important
you have to you need to weigh in and I
think that's where we get to I don't
think the Bureau food mag and public
health can alone come up with the best
model for California I think it takes
everybody in this room to help us with
that
so please
[Applause]
so everybody so that so now is everybody
going to go home and download the text
of our regs right so to help you with
that we have a new portal how many know
we have now a portal that's cannabis CA
govt pretty good huh we were we thought
about making sure we held on to that
when you call it that or whatever it's
called a thank you oh yes we grab that
one and so it is a portal that you can
go to and you can get to all three
licensing authorities public health food
and AG and the bureau you can get all of
our regulations all of the initial
statement of reasons by the way we all
because these are considered major
regulations we all had to do an economic
impact report all of that is out there
and it's going to show you what our
economist came up with on the impact the
cannabis industry is going to have it's
all out there for you and it's one
portal and I really hope you you go out
there we also all three departments have
a listserv so if you're not on our
listserv we blast this all out on email
how many have been to just the bureau's
website yeah I see I would come back and
everybody raises their hand
see we want me and we've gotten you know
pretties we have some social media out
there I thank goodness I have a
communications guy that does that so we
have Facebook and Twitter and we're
pretty good about putting where we're
going to be at and what we're doing and
so what will be coming up in the month
of June are four regulation actually
five regulations hearings so we are
going to go out and to different
locations across the state and have our
regulation hearings and how many came to
our pre regulation hearings here a lot
of you so those were like it for those
of you went to that there was a lot of
small group discussions a lot of
back-and-forth on regulation hearings
are there they're a different format we
we actually will just do an introduction
and it's just a chance for you to go up
to the mic and give us your comments we
have a court reporter there and they're
going to take they're going to take that
all down
and it'll be sort of it'll be different
for you guys because we're not supposed
to say anything back we're just going to
listen to you so I'm sure for some of me
some of us who like to talk that's going
to be very difficult not to say anything
back but it's just the format of how
they do regularly how we do regulations
hearing for this so we're going to be in
LA we're going to be in San Jose
Sacramento and Eureka and then Public
Health and Department of Food and
Agriculture mendes challenge and I know
folks have said you know I just was out
of budget hearing and I know people
worried how are you going to make this
deadline how are you going to do it and
I think we've you know from day one that
was my calf they said this is this is
our deadline January 1st of 2018 the
only thing that proposition 64 did was
it just made it even more clear that we
had to issue licenses and so we have
learned to adapt and respond when things
change and I I really believe more time
isn't going to make that much of a
difference we need to start regulating
this process at this product at the
state level and and so is there going to
be some bumps along the road do you turn
on a switch on January 1st and license
everybody no you don't and so when
you're going to see in our regulations
and I would really like to hear what
people think of these especially those
of you who are in the industry and you
have your local permit we've looked at
having temporary permits for folks that
are in compliance to continue on we've
also looked continue operations and
giving you some grace period to get your
application in so we're not going to say
everybody has to be in day one we get we
gave like a six month period and we also
looked at testing because all canvas is
going to have to be tested but we knew
like if we start licensing people in the
first couple months likely the product
that you have in your dispensaries or
weirdest trip distributors or wherever
is not going to have tested so we put
some grace period to be able to test and
also get your packaging up and running
so I think those are things you need to
look at and really respond because I
think what's going to what I envision
January 1 is we're going to try to have
these transition and we're going to try
to transition as best we can to bring
folks into the regulated market because
I think it it's one of those things that
we need to work to everything's not
going to be perfect at once but one of
the things I say is maybe something
doesn't work us as the state has to be
ready to respond when things don't work
and we have to respond quickly because
this is an industry that evolves very
quick thing I'll tell you it is evolved
very quickly and so my commitment is is
when we do get you up and running we
have those regulations in place if
things aren't working then we have to be
able to respond and change those things
anyway it's an absolute pleasure to be
here I won't take any more time and
anxious to listen to your questions and
answer them thank you very much
what areas of the regulations are you
struggling with well I'll tell you uh I
think I said earlier the lab regulations
were that was a big heavy lift because I
know that as you see in both a um a and
medical campus regulation and Safety Act
that is a can you hear me okay that was
a big thing about the cannabis test and
making sure we're testing for pesticides
and having those levels of pesticide so
that was probably the biggest challenge
for us the other one was just I think
some of these things for me some of it I
was used to doing regulations at my
previous agency but actually coming up
with what we were going to require on an
application sometimes can be challenging
and what we are going to require who's
going to be an ownership who qualifies
as owners if you look at that was a big
question at a pre regulation is who
who's going to have to be background and
fingerprint and when you see our
regulations you'll see we have really
taken the approach of going aligning it
with Proposition 64 so we're looking at
a 20% aggregate ownership and what not
and not having spouses having to be
background but having to be disclosed so
that was a lot of back-and-forth because
we had different sides more people
wanted you know more you know more
background checks employee background
checks and then we looked at you know
there was two different sides so yeah
there's no employee background checks
either so we really try to strike that
balance thank you Laurie
last question before I introduce the
next speaker people in the business I
hear a lot of questions about Bank how
do we how do we Bank how these credit
cards is there it's probably a tad out
of your purview but I'm curious because
everything marijuana right now is sort
of under your purview comments on
banking yeah thank you that's a really
tough issue if any of you watched our
budget hearing
today that was a big question how are
all these state agencies going to accept
cash especially if we can't bank
cannabis and so a lot of time was spent
on talking about that you know Board of
Equalization the bureau everybody that
you're going to have to be bringing cash
and and I think you know we're preparing
for that our facilities are preparing
that to make sure we have a facility
that can take cash but is that really
the answer probably not the best answer
right now we're working with John Chung
our state treasurer has a banking
cannabis working group that I serve as a
member on that committee and he we are
trying to look for solutions if there is
there a solution for California and
looking to having a coordinated approach
with all the different agencies and the
local agencies and we also have the can
of it you know the Association the
cannabis associations on this board
likely we are not going to find a
solution by January 1st of 2018 I think
there still needs to be some federal
there's there has to be something having
at the federal level I think to make it
easier for people to bank cannabis in
the meantime we are going to all of us
are going to have an online system that
can take credit cards that can take
debit cards we're going to just take all
forms of whatever you're going to come
to us that we haven't figured out
Bitcoin yet but everything else what
we'll pay basically somebody asked me to
do that so I I think that's ongoing and
that's not the bureau that's that's
everybody that's that's the industry
that the state agencies the federal
government and I think you know at some
point we all need to find this solution
together and I think California coming
on board with the legalized market I'm
hoping there will be some movement on
that and that's someday you know because
I'll tell you from from my point of view
I know you guys are dealing with cash is
the safety issue the public safety
issues but even
when you look at here we're going to
regulate this highly regulated product
that we're going to regulate you and yes
a lot of regulations and then you're
going to still be using cash as a
regulator you following the cash and
figuring out that that you it's very
difficult as a regulator to do that and
so it you know I think for all of us we
all want to find a solution to this
thank you I will tell you there's some
people in this room from the grow
facility invests in supposed to gross
when it's all really going thirty
million a year and state tax are
thirteen percent you can imagine it's
like Scarface or something with big
barrels of cash so it's a pretty scary
proposition
hi my name is Jackie McGowan and I have
a question for Lori Ajax not also like
to say thank you all for all the hard
work that you're doing in many different
aspects of this industry I tracks local
regulations specifically the medical but
my question is regarding the
recreational adult youth and I've only
seen two cities talk about allowing
adult use dispensaries and if they were
to open their doors on January 1st of
2018 nobody's talking about the fact
that there is not one single
municipality in the entire state that is
even thinking about allowing adult
youths cultivation manufacturing
distribution testing so on January 1st
if you're ready to accept applications
for adult use dispensaries like the
voters have voted for where's the supply
chain that have come from so I think a
lot of you know a lot of these
jurisdictions I think what was said
earlier I think they are waiting to see
what the state is doing with their
regulations on both medical and adult
use a lot of them just don't have the
resources and so you know it's it's
usually the state rolling out the
regulations and the city and counties
following in this case they've been
doing it a lot longer than the state so
we have we do a lot of outreach with the
local municipalities it's not our job to
convince them one way or the other but
it's important to explain to them where
we're at on our regulation product in
our process you know when they're coming
out and we're we're thinking there'll be
a lot more movement but you're
absolutely right even in adult use we
can't issue a license if it violates
local ordinance or regulation so it is
local control which puts is challenging
for us at the state because we do have
to make sure that we're not violating
anything by issuing that license but one
of the things we're looking at too and
just to give you an idea on it's not
just the supply chain its the supply
chain across the whole state we worry
about whether there's enough testing
labs to test the product right and so we
are trying to get to a point where RIT
some would be able to start taking
applications sooner than January 1st
2018 and so we are on we are trying to
fast-track that and I you know I'm not
going to sit here and say we're going to
it's going to be ready because a lot
determines with RIT right now what we're
working on we are working we I have
staff that that's what they spend all
day long as configuring our system but
if we could take applications ahead of
time it gives us an idea of where people
are applying what how many license types
are out there and would really give us a
lot of runway for January 1st to give us
it would give everybody a lot more
information my name is Tamara Krusty
onion I'm a small edible manufacturer
and my question is to lori Ajax but
first I'd like to thank everyone in the
panel for coming tonight and for Susan
for helping put this event together as
someone that was in the pre regulatory
meetings that the bureau held I'm not
very optimistic about the viewer being
open to feedback from the public to
these regulations because most of the
comments that were brought up in our pre
regulatory discussions were I think the
exact opposite of it is in distress I'll
take for one example the milligram limit
100 milligram per package I know that
there are a lot of patients that you
know some of them are vets that have
PTSD and require higher dosages for
example 2 or 300 milligrams now if you
break it down and you think that a 10
milligram dose is maybe the equivalent
of 75 calories that means that in 100
milligram pack there's 750 calories and
in their dose there would be 20 250
calories that's above the allocated
calorie consumption per day how are they
supposed to take their medicine if
they're forced to eat so much calories
the bureau didn't develop the
manufacturing regulations that's from
the Department of Public Health but they
were with us that our pre regulation
hearings so I can't comment on on
on how they you know because they have a
lot of folks there research scientists
that came up with those regulations but
I will tell you for all three of us we
have continued to say these are proposed
regulations they're draft regulations
exactly what you're saying right now is
what I would hope that you would
communicate that to my colleagues at the
Department of Public Health because I'm
going to tell you they are very open to
comment but you have to also understand
there also when you went there when we
look at lessons learned from other
states or looking at some of what has
happened with the edibles in Colorado
and whatnot so I think you know maybe in
the beginning they came out a little
conservative but I think they're open to
just two other things especially if you
can justify the reason why it should be
higher my name is Pamela Epstein and I
am an attorney and a consultant in the
space I've had the pleasure of working
with operators and both with cities
drafting mtrs a compliant ordinances and
regulations and so as I'm reading
through the regulations
I have operator to our delivery service
providers who are able to go and get
medication to the patients that need it
that can't come into a dispensary I have
cities that look at dispenser or
delivery as an option that's easier for
them more palatable than a storefront
unfortunately in the trailer bill and in
the regs there is no outlet for them so
they need to comment and whereas I
appreciate the Department of Public
Health giving and in a pee license so
that we can have a more robust situation
in that realm we don't have that same
thing for the delivery so Lori my
question is for you but thank you
everybody for the work you do in the
space I think there's some bills that
are dressing the non front dispensaries
but even so even in a um a there's
nothing in there that says you have to
advertise that your storefront
dispensary I think when you look at our
regs as we go forward with adult use
it's for delivery it has to be delivery
it has to be dispensary employees so it
can't be a third party delivery but
there
or you just need to have a location and
comply with our definition of premises
which is separate and distinct whether
or not you advertise I think there's
going to be different cities and
counties that may not want you to
advertise so I think when we go forward
with our adult use regulations I I think
some of that may be resolved
[Music]