[Music]
breaking news and the LA cannabis scene
today tell us about it okay well the
city of LA has had a long and sordid
past trying to regulate cannabis measure
M passed in March of 2017 and there have
been a lot of businesses that have been
trying to figure out how they're going
to get their business licenses we've got
a set of the prop D businesses that are
still working their way through the
application process they haven't even
submitted their annual license
application so there's a bit of a
backlog we've got the phase two
operators who are the growers and
manufacturers and distributors so the
supply side of the cannabis market in LA
that have applied and are still waiting
to be processed and then everybody's
sort of on pins and needles about when
the new retailers can apply so this
morning the special rules committee
heard a number of recommendations that
were put forward by the department of
cannabis regulations and the breaking
news really deals with new cannabis
operators retailers delivery services as
well as some very interesting details
that will impact Phase two so the supply
side well okay so in LA we don't have
any sort of like hard caps it's not a
hundred dispensaries or a hundred
growers they're only a hundred a hundred
thousand square feet of canopy what we
have in LA is something that's called
undue concentration which requires
what's called a public convenience and
necessity process so what all that
basically means is in LA we have City
Council members that want to be able to
have some kind of say in who gets
licenses especially on the supply side
but also for retailers and so as part of
sort of the mess or goop that goes into
passing a local ordinance or any sort of
law different regulators
city council members and their staff
give direction on what they want those
rules to look like and they make the
sausage in certain ways and one of the
big ways that the sausage was made was
there was in particular one City Council
member a woman named councilmember Nury
Martinez who has a lot of growers and
other supply side operators in her
district and by the way there are 15
city council districts in LA and so she
said to her Wesson the council president
yep
I'm down with passing this cannabis
ordinance but I want to make sure that
we have some control right on the number
of operators that get licensed in my
district particularly again supply side
growers and retailers of course and so
what was put in was there are different
community plan areas in the city of La
so the city of La is like absolutely
enormous I mean it's like it's crazy how
big la is its sprawling sprawling
sprawling and so you know you've got
these 15 city council districts all
these different community plan areas
within each council district and based
on the population numbers they the city
will issue or go up to kind of a soft
cap on how many licenses per population
so all that's to say that for growers
who are in this phase to supply-side
grandfather the folks who supplied these
prop D dispensaries what what they're up
against or what they might be up against
in me alone no longer be up against are
these soft caps so people applied under
this phase to process hey we we grew for
these prop D shops and they submitted to
the city they got their temporary some
of them are operational or not
operational but what they've been up
against is this fear that man I'll go
through this this process I'll get an
inspection by building and safety I'll
put all this money into my tenant
improvements I'm committed to going
through the process in the City of LA
but I'm then gonna get to this public
convenience necessity undue
concentration potentially like basically
a wall that's what they're afraid of I'm
gonna put all this money into my place
and you know kind of really invest in
the process in the city of El
but then they're gonna be too many
basically too much canopy square footage
in my particular community plan area and
it looks like they may not be subject to
these PC end caps anymore and for we
like myself and a lot of other folks who
have been working very hard in LA
especially for the supply side folks
who've been operating in LA for years
and years not not in the dispensaries
not kind of out there to you know kind
of public facing this is a really big
deal so I you know we're crossing our
fingers we've kind of done a lot of
advocacy to get up to this point and we
have a lot of support within the city
within the department of cannabis
regulation I think you know for for it's
really great to see that the Department
of cannabis regulation is supportive of
the industry and of these phase two
operators and understands that you know
they're trying people have really
invested in this process and want to get
license so I'm really thrilled about
this it's great
almost news hopefully we'll see what
happens on Friday specifically talking
cultivation is that the part of the
regulation or the the license category
that you're focused on right now and
you're saying that they're currently
only four so you've got different phases
of Licensing right you've got phase one
prop D shops they could apply as a micro
business so fully vertically integrated
or four licenses distribution
manufacturing cultivation and retail
right so they could do one two three or
four of those counts or a micro business
yeah and those are the properties and
they're about a hundred and ninety of
those businesses that are in the
licensing process because just think
about this like you know the City of LA
enormous City trying to regulate
cannabis for the first time ever also
trying to implement a social equity
program also the Department of cannabis
regulation by the way is its own
Department it's the smallest department
in the city of LA what's kind of crazy
is when the city came up with the
cannabis policy instead of putting the
Department of cannabis regulation within
another larger department that are
human resources and other kind of staff
and support they created a whole new
department so this is a department
that's like a baby department that's
trying to regulate cannabis deal with
the social equity program and then have
all the other bells and whistles of any
other department in the city they have a
huge task really ahead of them we've got
a lot more work to do right so you've
got phase one properties that are in
that system they're in the queue they're
working their way through the queue then
second the city said we want to license
the people who made the products that
were put on the shelves of these prop D
shops right so the folks who are
eligible for this phase two were people
who were growers manufacturers or
distributors that have been operating in
the city of La since before like
basically since before January first the
phase two operators are growers indoor
growers type six manufacturers they
could also apply as a type seven
manufacturers people who are making
different sorts of edible products
people who are distributors yeah well
like black star so Bryant Mitchell he's
someone who's very well known and speaks
kind of at a lot of different events
he's someone like he's a Phase two
operator and and so they're they're half
so Phase two we think you know I don't
remember how many people applied under
Phase two it could have been as many as
six hundred but I'm not sure I'm not
sure how many people applied under Phase
two and and that could be actually less
than that because I think some of them
applied for three different licenses and
are you focused on I couldn't tell if
for cultivation you would rather have
the more the merrier or you'd like to
restrict the canopy space within the
city of La here's the way I view it so
I've been working with cannabis
businesses in the city of La basically
since like 2009-2010 I had a lot of
clients who were indoor growers for
example in LA who are manufacturers who
are distributors they looked at this
whole licensing process and the history
of the way that the city of La treated
them
other you know any cannabis company
looked at the enormity of regulation of
taxes and I would say eighty percent of
the folks I used to work with said see
you later I'm not I'm not engaging in
this this is crazy even though I qualify
some of them would also have been social
equity qualified for the social equity
program they just didn't have a lot of
trust in the system to be perfectly
honest so are they staying in the
traditional market are they I just seen
operation or we're not asking yeah I
don't know I mean I don't work with
those folks anymore because I'm a
business corporate regulatory attorney
so I work with people who are who are
going through a licensing process and
kind of taking that leap of faith on so
the point is a lot of your former
clients have stopped staying in touch
with you the logical conclusion is that
they're not going through this process
yeah probably not and maybe and some of
them I've heard from have gone through
that process in another jurisdiction but
there's just been a lot of the city of
LA has been very challenging on a number
of levels it's it's night and day
working with the city now as a cannabis
attorney and advocate is very different
today than it was for many years today
the city in large part at the Department
of cannabis regulation is wonderful to
work with I mean you've got you know a
really great Department that you know
has a lot more work to do but they are
very responsive to the community today's
hearing was a good example of that how
they're gonna process the new retail
applicants and social equity applicants
is a good example of how they're really
trying to be responsive to people I've
been incredibly grateful at how open
they've been and transparent with you
know proposed rules kind of running
things by the community different parts
of the community it's been it's been
incredible compared to how it was in the
past so the reason that this is a big
deal for people who are indoor growers
in the City of LA or let's say applied
as a non retail supply side micro
business is
they could have been in a situation or
and may still be we'll see what happens
and whether this passes but where they
invest in a process and that sort of
like as I mentioned before sort of like
jumping into gosh I hope this works out
it's been challenging with the City of
LA for a long time a lot of years and
we're not prop D's where this just the
the suppliers of prop D shops which by
the way this phase 2 thing was never
supposed to happen I mean I remember
when you know we went through different
sets of ordinances and there was nothing
for these folks and this was one of
those situations of waking up at 4 in
the morning and putting together a
policy letter and lobbying the different
City Council members and it was a
miracle that we got that in in the final
ordinance was an opportunity for these
phase 2 people but what they were coming
up against was ok you might be able to
apply but you might hit the PCN numbers
and it's certainly city council members
where you have very conservative City
Council folks they may say too bad sorry
I know you invested all this money
you've invest in this process you may
even have a state license like a
temporary license and local
authorization from the city and spent
five hundred grand on tenant
improvements whatever you needed to do
gotten the inspection from the DCR and
then hit this wall of this cap and and
it's too bad so sad you can't get your
license what this small sentence in
these recommendations that were adopted
today says is that those folks that that
cap will not apply to them so it's a
it's an amazingly big deal yeah and I
know and it takes so much kind of like
detailed to explain why that's a big
deal so just to recap for somebody
trying to catch up originally the City
of LA was basically saying we're gonna
allow prop D shops to make the
transition and maybe social equity
applicants but nobody else and then they
relaxed those restrictions to insert
phase 2 which is kind of like taking the
entire traditional market that operated
in LA
giving them some pathway to legalization
up until today there was a big fear from
that group of operators that I could
invest a ton of money to try to be
compliant and get my annual and get
dinged for I guess concentration issues
but then something happened today which
was that one clause that gave them hope
yes okay and we'll see what happens on
Friday but it's very promising okay so
they put the clot that they put the
clause up for vote today and then Friday
is when they decide is that kind of okay
okay so the gist of it is a lot of phase
two operators who were very concerned
and fearful now have hope hope yeah okay
yeah well that's exciting do you think
that's exciting
the City Council of LA huh yeah yeah and
what would we like to say to the Herb
Wesson's and other City Council members
what would you like them to keep in mind
as they vote that we really should
support la businesses and these
traditional cottage industry folks who
really have invested in the process in
the City of LA that this will mean jobs
in LA that this will mean you know
continued investment in this city and
that this is you know this is a
wonderful great gift that we hoped for
when we passed the medical marijuana
regulation and Safety Act when we passed
prop 64 and we said we cared about small
businesses that this really will
effectuate that and it's really
important and these businesses are
trying to fight their way onto the
regulated market and it's still not
going to be easy once they're licensed
it's just the beginning of a continued
fight but you know at least there is
that pathway at least people aren't sort
of just you know kind of throwing money
and and and a hope in a prayer at least
they're you know it's
it will be hopefully a more seamless
transition so that woman in that one
zone who is the one who added that
clause or proposed the addition of that
clause yeah so so different City Council
members obviously have different kind of
views on cannabis there's a council
member Nury Martinez who's not I mean
everyone knows she's not terribly
favorable toward cannabis in her in her
area in the city of La there have been a
lot of grows there's also been a lot of
illegal shops and so you know on on you
know kind of viewing things from her
perspective she wanted to and she wanted
other council members to have control a
little more control over who would be
licensed and how many licenses were
issued without putting a hard cap this
is what's called a soft cap so once they
reach the cap and this is for retail
manufacturing type 7 and cultivation
then you have to go through this
additional process that's very rigorous
like one would if you were going to get
some sort of like a special special
liquor license
it's a PCN process and that can be take
a really long time no guarantee goes to
the full City Council for a vote if your
city council member supports your
project then you may have a chance but
the amount of time and kind of lobbying
and unknown involved in that is huge
whereas without that PCN for those folks
that are already in the queue and kind
of working their way through the process
if they meet the certain benchmarks then
they will probably get licensed whereas
without this provision passing you're
looking ahead to this huge unknown
factor well what's gonna happen will I
be able to even get through the PCN
where the numbers in my community plan
area because none of that's even public
yet is so we have the elected officials
within the local cannabis community my
assumption would be that Prop D
licensees would say we already have our
cake we don't need to split it well
actually there are a number of property
licensees who have off-site non retail
locations so they also would benefit
from
the passage of this provision as a
generality our property licensee is
supportive of this clause are they
pushing to get like do they have their
lobbying machine showing up at the
meeting and railing against it are they
are they indifferent to it I think
probably if anything for it or
indifferent okay mm-hmm so there are no
constituents
no the only thing that we need to walk
very carefully around are really just
the council members themselves and
hoping that you know this really does
kind of move through that process it
likely will but what there's no no
opposition within the cannabis community
I think there's more of a well if
anyone's even paying attention to that
level of detail
not so many people are unless you're
really kind of steeped in the weeds but
mostly support I would say I mean I
think people realize that you know kind
of fairness sits on the side of people
who are you know supply-side folks in LA
these are LA business owners with la
jobs trying to bring out like revenue in
LA I mean you even have like the fire
department chief who is thrilled about
the opportunity to walk through these
buildings and make sure that they are
safe for for that and they've never been
in these buildings forever
totally not totally not you know so that
again this is another way that you see
certain offices certain departments in
LA seeing the benefit of being able to
work with the cannabis community and
it's only by regulating these businesses
that we have that opportunity and
meanwhile today you know there's also
there were also emotions about shutting
down illegal shops and turning off the
power and kind of how to deal with
enforcement and the other big things
that happened today were the cities go
out how the city is going to process the
new retail applications and the social
equity program
so probably April May there will be the
first window for applications for retail
licenses only Tier one tier two social
equity applicants need apply there will
be about a hundred that will be
processed
it'll be first-come first-served basis
there'll be a pre verification window
that your individual that you're working
with actually is a social equity
qualified applicant then some 30 60 days
later you'll submit about ten items that
include a lease and radius map and
security plan and you know you have to
kind of meet these marks you have to
submit it first-come first-serve better
be perfect and then you know your
application will be processed then maybe
nine months later there'll be another
wave of applications that will be
accepted for storefront retail that are
more that the reason for the kind of the
time lag is because the social equity
program promises to give business
licensing and compliance assistance to
people who maybe don't have access to
that right so the city is trying to
balance two interests number one folks
who've been paying rent on property for
a couple years
they are social equity eligible they
probably have investors behind them and
they're like my god I mean we have
clients that have been paying rent owned
places for two to three years they're
just waiting for this process they want
to get it under way and then there's
another group of people that are saying
yeah but we don't have where's that
business licensing and compliance
assistance that you know that we need in
order to jump into this you know into
this very competitive and rigorous sort
of game and so that's why waiting for
nine months for those folks so all of
that came out today to within retail in
the City of LA
is there any thought to following the
West Hollywood lead or consumption
retail would also
you know weekly just for sale buying
these yeah right now it's just for sale
but that's definitely been top of mind
for council president Herb Wesson and
other folks on the council yeah probably
yeah I mean you know ever since ever
since he started doing that he remember
this was like three or four years ago
was it two years ago where he started
doing these community gatherings at
night all over LA and one of the biggest
things that he loved to talk about is
like where are all these people going to
use their cannabis we need to make sure
they have a place to use their
candidates what's the deal with his
on-site consumption like and he always
got really excited about that and you
know I think we're definitely going to
have that in LA but again it's a lot for
the Department of cannabis regulation to
process I mean when I learned that this
department like what it means to not be
under another department that you
actually have to like like they have to
like hire HR people who's processing
payroll I mean that that they were not
even put within a larger department but
they had to kind of like cobble it all
together I mean that's crazy in a city
this big when you're processing that
many licenses how many licenses did West
Hollywood process exactly we're talking
about 190 only retail many of those have
three to four uses so that's 190 you
know times four or whatever then you've
got and I think they said there were
like 600 or 800 prop D licenses if you
count like kind of all of the different
components separately then you've got
the phase two that you know some several
hundred folks applied I mean this is an
enormous number of licenses so given the
cards they were dealt which is
essentially creating an entire
organizational structure from scratch
you would give them a good grade based
on what they have to deal with in
building an entire infrastructure 100%
okay 100 in the news you always see
these stories of kind of pointing
fingers and frustration within
la specifically well you know I I think
there is just generally in the world in
which we live especially in this country
and in this culture this idea that we
want to have it all right now and a lack
of appreciation for kind of the
contoured nature of the political
process and how things take time and are
complicated and we instead we want it
right here right now my way or the
highway kind of a vibe and that's just I
mean that's kind of it's a low vibration
and it doesn't really appreciate how
complicated all of this is when you're
talking about regulating an entire
cannabis industry trying to benefit
people who have already been operating
trying to create a whole new program to
benefit people who are harmed by the war
on drugs I mean this is a huge amount of
very groundbreaking really incredible
public policy and ideas that you're
bringing up sort of from the heavens
into reality into all these rules and
regulations and you need to hire people
then you need to implement I mean it is
it's amazing how much is involved and if
you're outside of the process and you
don't kind of see you know and and
really take the time to understand how
incredibly how much detail can go into
just one paragraph one one one issue
it's easy to point and say well why
isn't this happening quicker why can't
you guys get your stuff together that
that's always easy to do from the
outside when you see it from the inside
and the top that has to go into all of
this and not to mention a public process
and various studies and you know
implementation and what kind of
technology platform and this is this is
massive what's happening peanut gallery
any question comments museums
does these new findings out today does
it give more hope for more of the
process you think to people that want to
come in or is this is this really about
a celebration for those that
I've been building and have been here
yeah that's a good question um it's
definitely a celebration for those who
have been here for new totally new
growers totally new manufacturers so
basically the phase three I want to come
into LA and open up my grow but this is
not a win for them it's gonna take the
long long time the city has basically
said we're not we're just dealing with
new retail licenses who even knows when
the supply side in the city of La is
going to open up to new applicants which
makes the prop DS and the phase two
licenses even more valuable which is
great yeah I mean what's been really
incredible is how issues around
marijuana justice and reform have really
kind of swept the country and really you
know this morning there were a lot of
folks who gave public comment during
this hearing a lot of people talking
about the social equity program the
opportunity that you know individuals
who spoke opportunities this gives me
this gives my community and that really
is having reverberations across the
country and I think that would be one of
those sort of like those maybe it's it's
like a domino or some card that you take
and then it will all fall I mean it's
definitely one of the you know kind of
these fundamental issues that we're all
in this country and that certainly years
ago I started looking around like what
is up with this complete ridiculous
contradiction where you've got we're
legalizing cannabis in certain states
certain people are making tons of money
from it and benefiting from it in other
states and certain people who have been
most harmed not just still going to
prison for it I mean this contradiction
doesn't make any sense so you know I
know you kind of asked about like
businesses in LA but I would say the
social equity program that is of top
priority and you know thank goodness and
thank goodness it will also continue to
create that change nationwide which I
think will help with federal
legalization and hopefully be scheduling
stem well Arielle
thank you for taking a seat between
Hello Kitty and Star Trek Barbie
yeah welcome it's my pleasure
[Music]