Strawberry Cough yeah
that's a deep question for me it would
be something that no one in the cannabis
community knows it's just the rapture
it's an old NL g13 house playing across
from North Carolina the question was
what do you regret losing the most I
lost a plant that would have come out of
like the late 80s out of riceland and
when you lit it it looked like a burning
tire and I got so high when I smoked it
that I'd lay down on the couch and my
girl would come in and I'd wake up and
she'd be wiping my face with the rag
asking me if I was sick because I was
feverish and I would mumble and I'm
doing really high and it had the most
complete effect I've ever experienced
and it was stunning cannabis in every
aspect it had a visual quality it had a
growth quality it had a quality a high
that was unreal and it got killed by
mistake and I said I will go find more
like that but I realized quickly that
that was a memory and that was the one I
wish I had back more than anyone it was
so green it was almost like blue and icy
cold like that you know like a blue
varietal but it literally would make
regular people ill they would it would
it would fold you over and and kick you
in the ass and send you home and say
come back when you grown up the beauty
of cannabis is that all of us have that
special thing and that's why I've always
been trying to explain to people you
don't have to be a big banker but you
get a bank a little bit you got to make
sure you keep some stock you got to make
sure you're involved in some breeding
don't let anybody talk to you
because your pollen chucker you're
somebody who has historically done what
we've done since the dawn of time you've
chosen things to put together for your
desire and when people ask me you know
what should I smoke I'm like I'm not
qualified to tell you cuz I'm not you I
can put you into things
and I can help you understand why you
like it but fundamentally I'm not you
I'm not qualified to tell you what you
should like it's like telling someone
who they should love you're not
qualified but you are you you what you I
know you lost something good man you've
had a lot of stuff in your hand boy oh
yeah and that's where you come into it
with the sharing and it's like I being a
being breeding seeds and taking these
times it's like they're they're your
children and it's like that's like the
one thing it's like spreading that right
now and it was like back in the you know
the early 90s and and running into walls
and and getting losing these certain
genetics and that's like what was drove
me back to go to like Southeast Asia
it's like finding this you know that was
happy pizzas I don't know if you've been
to Cambodia but you eat this
pizza and you're tripping you know
you're you're in Cambodia on that and
there's this different level to that and
this was something when you could grow
this and it was a nice producer it would
grow under the man's and eat as well
here and you could put it in a mixed bag
of tricks and get fifty six hundred a
pound for it it had different colors it
wasn't that name but that's like he's
some old Southeast Asian you know these
these long flowering times but just the
soaring psychedelic highs and that
different feeling and that's part of
that bap tracking and finding what
exactly like one of them with CBD it was
reaching out to you know with Ringo and
like Jaime when this was when people
were first introducing that you know the
wanita lugworm osa and that you know
that canna tonic those old genetics and
it's like okay well this was Oaxaca this
region Colombia you know where were
these things coming from and then trying
to search those out and that's like when
you mention that with Africa what's is
getting is we're losing this you know
these unique ones that are out there and
it's being able to find these special
ones but at what point we we you want to
share these but you don't want them to
go under the wrong hands
and that's something we're gonna be
facing right now being breeders I think
coming more and more as we've got bigger
players that are coming in and are just
they don't realize the time and the
energy that's put into these certain
cultivars and how rare and special they
are and that that's something that we
have to protect drew drew Strawberry
Cough I lost that I had right away and I
thought about it a lot like my pops and
beans that I haven't found anything it
was it was that I'm pretty sure it was
the Strawberry Cough because I've seen
the COFF
and it had that you know that's very
distinguished like real thick smoke you
know but it was the first plant that we
ever I'm ever going to did to plants
under two lights and we got six pounds
we were like it was like blown away the
first time that ever happened and it was
very easy to trim just these little golf
ball knows which most the cough is not
in the Strawberry Cough it's his bigger
you know denser fluffier but it was
really anyways and it was it was really
because I was medicine for me I came
into cannabis from a bicycle accident
and so I was up mega hit by a car
I was up really hard for a couple
years and just like learning to grow
weed walking around the house smoking as
much weed as I could and there was that
Strawberry Cough that like really was
able to help me manage so it was a damn
sharks breath that I lost it to I got
stuck with the shark wreck cutting that
I hated that thing and as I took a cut
and I thought it was a strawberry and I
messed it up and it was a shark's breath
and I could never get rid of that
plant