[Music]
myling
what I'm going to do is hopefully
inspire you to start experimenting with
the minor
canabo um because we don't know what we
don't know and there's so much to learn
and there's so much um combinations we
talk about the Entourage effect right
and we always think about the Entourage
effect as THC in the Turpin or CBD in
the tpin OR THC and CBD and the
tpin but that's just a tiny tiny little
bit there's over 100 probably a lot more
than that right now but I'll stick with
a 100 uh canabo that have been
identified so far in the canvas plant
the one thing I like to um because I'm a
herbalist at heart and all plants I
don't like to play favorites but
currently at this part of my career I'm
playing a favorite but uh I like to
think of cannabis as the Gateway herb
because it's the plant that has been
studied the most for its medicinal
properties honestly no other plant has
been studied as much as cannabis has now
a lot of that studying the clinical
studies that happened through uh the 80s
and the 90s and the early
2000s the only way in North America that
you could legally study cannabis was to
prove how dangerous it was so all of
these clinical studies happened to try
and prove how dangerous canvas was and
it wasn't and so all of that studies are
sitting on a shelf
somewhere um which is kind of fun to
think about but during all those studies
people were going like wait a minute
this isn't dangerous at all look at this
guy's he doesn't have so much pain this
this person isn't has doesn't have so
much nausea this guy's not so anxious
anymore right so we're starting to get
these little hints at like wait a minute
somebody's trying to pull the wool over
our eyes here so
um we all know know that canabo just a
little review canabo in the plant itself
are in an acidic form so thca Tetra
hydroc canabidol sorry
tetrahydrocannabinolic
acid canabidol
cannabidiolic acid I make my students
learn how to S
these um but even before we get to the
THC in the CBD we have canaberal
CBG actually we have canab geric acid
cbga that's the mam canapino
or in not so folksy terms a little more
scientific terms you could call it the
stem cell or the the original
cannabinoid as the plant starts to grow
and just as those flowers are starting
to take form we have canaberal very
briefly shows up so canaberal alic acid
very very briefly shows up and then the
CBG cbga technically will morph if you
will through the work of enzymes into
whatever the genetics of the plant are
so if it's a high THC plant that THC
starts out as cbga right if it's a high
cbda plant that CBD first at one point
was CBG
so we could Harvest those flowers early
really early but if you're a grower
you're going like don't Harvest it at
the wrong time um but but we could also
create genetics that manipulates the
enzymes so that those enzymes stop the
CBG from morphing into something else so
then we can have high CBG plants right
and with that CBG wow is that ever a
great uh canono so we have our our raw
cannabinoids uh the acidic form and then
we have what's been called up until
recently the activated form so THC CBD
and you get your activated form by
heating up the Cannabis and that knocks
off chemically knocks off the acidic
molecule so then we're left with what
has up until now be called activated but
we're starting to understand that
cbda is pretty darn special thca is
pretty darn special we don't have to
heat our plants up
but what we can do is we can start to
have combinations of acidic and heated
acidic and activated together and we'll
start to see I'm going to give you a few
stats here of how um some of the things
that we're starting to learn about the
acidic form of plants plus some of those
minor canabo and if you're a breeder a
cultivator and you like to play around
with genetics see if you can start
playing around like read up on I don't
know how to I don't know how to tell you
how to do that I'm not a grower but uh
see if you can start playing around with
some of those minor canabo and move them
up so that we can get um other strains I
know there is a uh there's a little bit
of CBG starting to show up in the retail
market and there's a little bit of CBC
canaby chroming starting to show up but
I'll talk about that one in a
minute so phyto canabo we have four
types of cannaboids I don't know if you
guys knew that we have phyto canabo from
the plant we have endoc canabo those are
the canabo that our body makes we have
um synthetic canono that was the only
thing that you could legally study in
the United States for decades synthetic
canabo they're made in the lab they
mimic the ones that we find in the plant
however they're super po potent and so
some of the studies that we have about
THC
especially from the ' 80s and 90s that
research was done with synthetic
cannabinoids which is can be dangerous
because it is so concentrated and so if
you see a study that says THC is
dangerous it caused psychotic breaks it
might have even caused death it could
have caused high anxiety not that the
plant THC doesn't do some of those
things doesn't cause death but it can do
induce anxiety and those kinds of things
but look at the study go dig into the
study and if it if the material that
they were using was
hu212 that's synthetic THC right so you
have to look into the study and see what
kind of THC were they using was it from
a plant or was it from a laboratory now
we have a new kind of canabo that's
going to be coming out on the market if
it's not out already probably start out
in California it's where they're doing
some research and it's called
biosynthetic cannaboids biosyn syntic
cannaboids are grown in the same way
that probiotics are grown you know the
probiotics that you buy at your health
food store they're grown usually on
yeast and then uh once they're grown the
the yeast is extracted so you're just
left with the probiotics so there are
companies that are starting to grow
biosynthetic
canono don't feel threatened if you're a
grower it's okay there's room for it all
but one of the things about the
biosynthetic is it's not in a laboratory
so it's a little bit more natural but
we're going to be able to Target those
really teeny tiny canono well not that
the canabo are teeny tiny but they're in
teeny tiny amounts that would be really
hard to change your genetics of your
plants it would take a long time to
change your genetics of your plants to
kind of bump up some of those really
minor canabo so let's watch for those
coming in uh through the B synthetic um
Growers it's it's very industrial but I
think it will have a place but we can
also start looking for those and maybe
combine them with our plant cannaboids
right so that so all of a sudden the
possibilities of combination of products
out there just becomes infinite
right uh what else did I want to see
I've got my notes here just so I don't
forget um one of thing I want to go back
to phyto canabo so the cannaboids phyto
means just of a plant so our phyto
canabo we have never looked at our other
plant medicine to see if our plant
medicine contains
cannaboids we know about four or five of
them so easia a great uh immunity herb
does have canabo like activity uh
spilanthes which is great for mouth
Health um helis scarum liver wart and
there's a few more out there but
remember what I said a few minutes ago
about cannabis is kind of the Gateway
herb it's because all of a sudden it's
like hey if this plant this cannabis
plant has all of these cannabinoids what
about all of the other medicinal plants
that we've been using for centuries for
Millennia what how how do they actually
work do they work with this endoc canabo
system that we have in our body probably
but we've never looked for it before so
that's pretty exciting I think it's
going to spur on a lot of really good
research um okay chemical definition of
cannabis is it belongs to the turpenoid
family so all cannaboids are tpes but
not all Turpin are canabo okay so it's
just a the canabo are a subclass of the
turpenoid family um and so that's why
they're pretty close together how do we
tell if something's a turpine or canabo
still a little bit Up For Debate but it
seems to be how it interacts with our
endoc canabo system just how it
interacts with our body and things
change even in the five years that I've
been studying things have changed uh
caropine or caropine however you want to
say that there's still a debate is that
a turpine or is that a canabo because it
does kind of interact with the canab
with the endoc canabo system doesn't so
we may see kilene may get reclassified
as a cannaboid just like Pluto is it a
planet not a planet right we're all
we're just still trying to figure all
that stuff
out okay so
um if a cannaboid is a a part of the
tpine family uh that's kind of the
chemical makeup uh but what about what's
a u medicinal definition of a canabo
what makes a canono
medicinal um that means it right now it
interacts with the CB1 and CB2 receptors
and or CB2 receptors within the body so
it interacts with our endoc canabo
system so in early days we've only known
about the endoc canabo system in our
body since the '90s late ' 80s the '90s
not very long
um but we're learning that there's the
endoc canabo system isn't just this
individual system within the body that
has cannaboid receptor one and cannaboid
receptor 2 so uh aply names that these
canabo interact with all of the
different receptors within our body and
within our brain so there's so much we
need to learn and how we I guarantee
that the definition of the endoc canabo
system 10 years from now will be quite
different than what it is today because
we're just learning things so one thing
we got to do as cannabis people is we
have to be willing to to allow our minds
to be changed because the definitions
are going to change we're just like
think about um you know when they first
started realizing that the Earth didn't
rotate around the sun right those kinds
of things or that you know some the
early knowledge that we now know as fact
that's where we are right now so 100
years from now they're going to look
back on this time era and go like whoa
that's what they thought about cannabis
like oh they didn't know anything did
they right but we're here we're now and
we're laying the groundwork for future
Generations okay so when
endocannabinoids or when cannaboids of
any kind whether it's supplemental
cannaboids or ones that are body Mak
ourselves um interacts with the
different receptors we get a
physiological response in the body so
you can think of um you know sometimes
THC might make you really sleepy so it's
sedative and in some cases depending on
what Doctor you talk to and what
response you're looking for that
sedation could be a side effect or it
could be the desired effect that's why
you're taking it so gain if somebody
says you know this is a side effect of
using cannabis it says well sedation is
only a side effect if you don't want to
be asleep at that time but sedation is a
desired effect if that's why you're
using the Cannabis medically is to help
you sleep right so we always have to put
everything in
context okay where am I at for time
here uh let's start go back to
cannabigerolic acid or cannabigerol CBG
I said a few minutes ago that's the
first cannaboid very briefly in the
growing cannabis plant just as the
flowers are just starting to form so
long before they mature um you're going
to get cannabigerolic acid is going to
come in the M
canono uh c a n n a b i g e r o
l and then if you want to go with the
acid one it's uh put in uh I I see on
the end and then acid
yeah so we know that um in clinical
studies
CBG helps increase the
appetite which is great unless you're
sitting there eating a bag of Doritos
and you can't stop till you get to the
bottom but when we look at medically
there's a lot of health issues out there
where people are so nauseous or they're
so weak that they can't get nourishing
food into their body and so what these
Studies have shown in people with uh HIV
AIDS or um um cancer situations or other
issues where the body becomes really
depleted uh and it becomes this vicious
cycle because they don't have the
strength to eat but without eating they
can't gain strength and heal so if we
have some agents that can help people to
eat then they can help have at least a
chance of their body healing right so
cannabigerolic acid and canaberal so
both the activated and the raw form we
got to find a better word than activated
because they're both active in the body
but for now we'll use that um there's a
lot of clinical studies that show
cannabigerolic acid and canaberal CBG
help increase appetite now if you look
at studies down in the states where they
don't have socialized Health Care people
pay for being in the hospital those
studies actually show less Hospital
costs like that's an outcome of the
study we think of like who cares about
the hospital cost like we we help each
other here in Canada right with with our
taxes you know maybe I don't need to go
to the hospital but maybe somebody else
does and I'm happy that it's there for
them right so um down in the states
you'll see some of these some of these
clinical studies come in with like much
reduced Hospital costs which is really
great for them but also we can increase
food intake and therefore increase
weight um I have a um a just a little
case study of a client that I had a few
years ago a young fellow he was uh he
probably mid teens at the time and for a
whole school year he hadn't been eating
cuz he was so nauseous and a few years
earlier his older brother had had a lot
of health issues so this young fellow
didn't want to bother his parents with
his nausey and vomiting um and not and
not being able to eat so he uh he
basically was trying to ride it out for
himself for a whole school year he kept
losing weight and losing weight and
losing weight to the point where he had
to tell his parents so he went to his
parents of course first thing parents
did take him to emergency um and and get
them checked out um and then the second
thing that they did was call up me and
say he had found Street pot to help him
with his appetite and it was hit and
miss cuz you know when we used to buy it
in the parking lot at 7-Eleven you never
really knew what you were getting so
sometimes his little baggy worked
sometimes it didn't um to help him
stimulate his appetite so he um what I
did and this is this is you guys use
this if somebody says you know I have a
friend of a friend needs to stimulate
appetite take three or four uh flour uh
different flowers and bring it to the
person and let them smell it see which
one do you think is going to stimulate
your appetite I can tell you what
stimulates my appetite but what
stimulates your appetite might be
completely different so let them choose
so we did that we got them set up with a
dry her vaporizer and uh became part of
the the family dinner is that he would
sit down and use his dry hair vaporizer
have a few hits on that get his appe and
the family would have their meal
together as it turned out he had a tumor
on his adrenal on one of his adrenals
and um it was cancerous and it was it
was causing um you know whatever the it
was killing the appetite basically
causing nausea so he wasn't he wasn't uh
didn't get hungry at all but he had lost
so much weight he had left it too long
that the doctor said this is major
surgery you need to put on 40 lbs it was
a tall kid he was skinny you need to put
on 40 lbs before you can withstand the
surgery and so through the help of our
plant friend he was able to do that they
gave him three months you know three
months you need to put on 40 lbs can you
imagine trying to put on 40 lbs in three
months crazy right but he did it um
through the help of of cannabis uh and
just finding the the right strain for
himself so uh he had the surg
happy to say he's mid-20s at this point
out working having a great time loving
life so y cannabis saved another
one okay I got sidetracked uh back to
CBG um CBG also enhances the actions of
the other cannaboids so if we're taking
it with um you know THC or CBD some of
the major canabo or two major canabo if
you will if we add a little CBG in there
you may get a better effect uh from your
THC and CBD so that's another reason to
kind of experiment with adding your uh
kolic acid or keral in there um here's a
super interesting one um they've done
some experiment with uh children with
autistic Spectrum especially
non-verbal and I've got some I am going
to give you a few stats here they used a
one: one so half cbga acidic form half
CBG uh activate
form the range is pretty pretty big
range so from 2 to 20 Mig a day which in
the grand scheme of things isn't that
much I'm not sure what form it was I
think probably a liquid form um and some
of the
nonverbal actually were able to start to
make some noise and maybe not fully
speak but we're able to you know there
was some hope there with that CBG right
and on a one to one so half AIC half the
activated or heated
form um when we add CBG to CBD so CBD of
course is great for seizure disorders
and it's becoming very well accepted
especially for children and Pediatrics
with seizure disorders we need high
amounts of that CBD though um so for
seizure disorders we're looking at
somewhere between 3 to 600 milligrams
per dose to help manage seizures doesn't
always work but you could pulse it with
the seizure medication the
pharmaceutical seizure medication so we
can pulse it so when the pharmaceutical
stops working we can do the
CBD high high doses though when the CBD
stops working we go back to the
pharmaceutical right so we can pulse
them like that um but add some CBG in
some early studies are showing that hey
this actually makes CBD a little more
effective um and we may find that even
adding CBG in with your pharmaceutical
anti-seizure meds maybe that's more
effective we don't know yet we haven't
it's not that it it doesn't it's just
that we haven't figured it out yet we
haven't looked so many things we haven't
looked at um anxiety ADHD
OCD um 40 milligrams this was one study
they use 40 milligrams in so 40
milligrams a day so in two doses so 20
in the morning 20 in the afternoon uh
and this is just CBG not
cbga helped for people with anx I or add
or OCD which I I can I know add um it
can ruin your day right you you this is
what I'm going to get done today and
then add kicks in and squirrel squirrel
squirrel the end of the day it's like ah
I only got one thing done um so seem to
help that 40 milligrams a day but it do
did in the participants in that study
did have sleep disturbances they didn't
have a great sleep so again you know we
have to choose our battles here
um it could be similar for brain
inflammation which we know this horrible
Co that we've just come through three
years with it causes a lot of brain
inflammation so does a lot of other
parasitic activity other viral activity
people who have um Lyme disease uh the
co-infections from that cause a lot of
brain fog and stuff so this uh CBG could
help with that um and here's a really
interesting one if uh they've done a
clinical study with CBG with linol the A
tpine lolu and
lemine and they're finding that it may
help with staff infection so some of
those uh we're starting to get to what
they're calling post antibiotic age
where they think that possibly our
antibiotics well they are some of our
antibiotics already starting to become
less effective than they used to be um
but we could come to a place where our
antibiotics pharmaceutical anti bict are
working so there is a lot of really
active activity at looking at our plant
medicine to see what's going to replace
our antibiotics um you know if we get to
that place and CBG plus lenol plus
lemine may be pretty good go make a self
a first a self add in your CVG some of
your uh lemony uh some uh linol so so
some lavender and some Citrus and some
CBG High CBG plant could make a pretty
fantastic first aid uh first aid self
for ointment or
something okay better speed up a little
bit here um canab chroman or canab
chromic acid this is the second
cannaboid that forms in the the flower
before it reaches its whatever its
genetics are this is
even more brief less brief no more brief
happens for a smaller amount of time
than the CBG does so CBG forms first and
then enzymes kick in and it quickly
morphs into CBD canab chroman and then
sorry CBC canaby chromene and then
canaby chromin then morphs into whatever
the genetics of the plant are so there
are some people again some breeders
cultivators out there that are pushing
up the CBC so getting some usable
amounts from it so you don't have to
harvest your plants so early but again
figure out that timing
this is I have a uh somebody in the
Legacy Market who has a fantastic CBD
product out there both a a tincture and
a um a
cream I can't I've never seen anything
that does such a good job as the CBC
stuff like this is my favorite
cannabinoid at this point if if I can
have
favorites the skin healing properties of
this CBC is phenomenal so uh persistent
chronic um what they call refractive so
it means that it's resistant to any kind
of treatment uh eczema and
psoriasis takes care of
it um
diabetic uh like um diabetic uh sores
that you can get on the periphery
especially like on on feet and stuff
like that um he's had uh this friend of
mine uh is um has had people who have
been on antibiotics and and um you know
oral antibiotics topical antibiotics uh
all kinds of things nothing was touching
these diabetic
sores 3 weeks on this cream healed up
and so now this person uh this PA this
patient of his whenever they see
something o something's coming up just
takes care of it so it doesn't get out
of control right um this same stuff uh
somebody had a got a motorcycle burn on
their leg um and again same thing
doctors were flipping through all the
antibiotics all of the creams herbal
creams everything finally got to uh my
friend Bill and tried this CBC stuff
cleared up in less than a week less than
a week it cleared this stuff up so um
CBC play around with CBC it's
fantastic um
uh also is not too bad for pain um I
also know someone who had some eye
surgery done and the the stuff that the
doctors had given them was it was okay
but they started using the CBC cream on
just on their eyes now it is a very
clean product it's got some olive oil
and some like extra virgin organic olive
oil and some a little bit of beeswax in
there and then the
CBC so it was very safe to put on on the
eye so they were putting on the eye at
night and um so the eye surgery was
healing up but their eyesight started to
improve like what the hell nobody can
prove did that do that or was that from
the eye surgery but it wasn't expected
from the eye surgery the eye surgery was
for something completely different so I
was like hm wait a minute so you know if
he got some of that cream and your eyes
are you know need a little bit of help
then give it a try put it on at night
it's a little goopy um but put it on at
night so we don't know
maybe um okay cbda so good old CBD
canabidol um and can cannabidiolic acid
uh if we use the raw stuff the the
unheated the acidic
form um we can get better management of
neuropathic pain than the heated form so
make your tinctures with the raw stuff
you don't have to decarb it um or maybe
you decarb half and you don't decarb the
other half um gout 200 milligrams which
is a fairly high dose twice daily for
four days eliminated gout in this one
fellow that's pretty cool because gouts
pretty painful and it reoccurs if you
know I had a client once um a little
aside and he would get go every couple
months it' be so painful and uh you know
one of my first questions questions is
well what's your diet like he ah pizza
and beer well how often do you have
pizza and beer maybe three or four times
a week and then then I try and have
salads the other day Okay so if you want
to get rid of your goat you got to get
rid of your pizza and beer he like nah
I'm not getting rid of my pizza and beer
it's like okay well I'm going to be
treating you for goat so you're a good
money
maker um asthma CBD plus cbda so add
your activated form and your acidic form
you're going to get better asthmatic um
anti-inflammatory effects cbda is 5 to
seven times more available in the body
that means it gets into the bloodstream
five to seven times more effectively
than CBD does it's pretty good
um if we add
cbda with THC and
CBG we get much better anti-inflammatory
action in the gut right if we want to
improve our digestion and improve our
health we want to get the inflammation
out of our gut cbda THC is going to help
with the pain lower dose of THC and some
CBG in there might have some pretty good
you know clean up some gut
health uh seizure man management so we
were talking earlier about CBD is kind
of becoming a standard for uh seizure
especially pediatric seizure it's the
only cannaboid right now that is
accepted for for
Pediatrics uh for Pediatric use so um
they have found that one tenth of the
dose of cbda is needed for the
equivalent anti-seizure activity of CBD
by itself holy crap that's pretty
amazing gets better pain management cbda
versus CBD you need one 100th of a dose
of cbda versus
CBD there's one that's even better
anti-emetic so that means uh stopping
vomiting
anti-emetic um
10,000th of a dose so meaning only you
only need minute doses just micro dosing
of
cbda versus how much you might need of
CBD now having said that we know that
THC is a much better antiemetic than CBD
is but there's a lot of people that
can't tolerate the psychoactivity or the
the impairment from THC than CBD so we
do need a lot more CBD for anti anti-
tic than um if anyone came to me and
said you know how do I stop vomiting i'
I'd go with CBD uh an inhaled CBD not
not eating it inhaled it's going to
quickly quelch that um but for someone
who can't tolerate THC uh cbda might
might
work yeah anytime I'm working with
anti-emetic or nausea I want to I want
to quick action so so I'm going to
inhale I'm going to suggest they inhale
it yeah appetite stimulate what's
up yeah yeah any kind of inhalation
method is going to good and even you
know the vape pens we got some really
clean vape pen vape cartridges out on
the market now so yeah even that but my
my favorite is the dry her vaporizer
because it's the cleanest but it's kind
of a pain in the butt right it's not
quick a vape pen is super
quick okay moving on because I'm going
to run out of time here uh tetra Tetra
hydroc canabidol acid uh thca so that's
the unheated um and people like ah you
got a decarb you know for some things
you want to decar but maybe you don't
experiment get out there experiment try
it especially if you're a grower and you
have lots you have lots to play around
with try not decarbing and see what
happens um of course you can't smoke it
and not decarb right cuz smoking decarb
instantly right so um but that's when
you're making your tinctures and your um
um you're you know cooking it or putting
it into food that's not going to get
heated very
high um we get better nausey and
vomiting um the only problem with that
as we were just talking about is when
you're nauseous you don't want to eat
anything right so it gets a little hard
taking an oral product to quelch nausey
and vomiting unless it's something
chronic that you have throughout the day
right um effective at red producing
symptoms of irritable bowel and other
gastrointestinal issues and there is
some early clinical studies that show
that if we add uh a thca with a THC so
an acidic with a decarb form a heated
form together in a onetoone formula
we're going to get way better pain
management than just THC by itself and
also if for those people as I was
talking about earlier who either can't
tolerate THC the impairment from THC or
they don't like it um and I've had a lot
of patients that uh until I've figured
some of this stuff out that say like
well your medicine really worked your
cannabis medicine really worked but I
don't like being stoned it just it's too
disorienting for me so um so then they
push it away they don't want to try it
right and then that's really sad to me
because then they try and go to
Pharmaceuticals and might not be as
effective and you get other side effects
and stuff like that so if we have equal
amounts of thca and THC maybe we can
reduce the likelihood of impairment and
help people be people be more
comfortable and still have their
effective pain
medication okay then I'm going to talk
about the Varin canabo so uh um cannabic
acid Tetra
Hydro Tetra Hydro
Canin in Tetra hydropenic acid um that's
my tongue twister for the day so we've
seen the thcv thcv cbdv cbdv so of
course the acidic is the raw one that's
what we find in the plant itself they're
just a slightly different form they have
a different chemically a different tail
on the end of them the varen ones versus
the nonv ones if you will and so that
will have a slightly different reaction
within the body so this is where we can
start to really fine-tune like even a
year ago or two years ago when I would
give this lecture it's like okay tpin
are how we fine tune our cannabis plant
sure they work great but let's start
fine-tuning with our canabo and we can
really get down to some nitty-gritty so
I was just having a conversation this
morning about um you know people always
ask well what's the best strain for this
and what's the best cultivar for that
like I don't know what's the best diet
right because I'm a nutritionist as well
so people ask me what's the best diet
well there's 800 or sorry there's 8
billion people on this planet I think
there's 8 billion perfect
diets there's 8 billion people on this
planet there's 8 billion perfect pay
medications and we now have the ability
to fine-tune it so if something doesn't
work let's tweak it a little bit and we
can tweak dosage we can tweak uh ratios
we can tweak cannabinoids um we can add
and then we have all the Tarpin so can
you see the it's an infinite possibility
right there's an infinite number of
remedies that we can get from this plant
and then we start adding in all of our
forest friends all of our other plants
in there it's like we we we have
lifetimes of research that we can do on
this
stuff um
okay so we don't have a lot of research
on the varen yet um but there is I work
with a canabo researcher out of the UK
you can look up her um her Google
scholar page she has tons of papers and
studies that she's uh contributed to and
uh her her name is um sersa O Sullivan
Sira s a i o r s e I believe and O
solivan oast and then Sullivan uh she's
out of the UK and if you look up her her
Google Scholar or her LinkedIn uh you'll
have access she's really generous with
uh some of the stuff that she's put out
there um
um so Varin like some of these other
minor cannaboids are found in very
minute amounts but again if you're culer
and you know how to work with genetics
it's all that part's all magic to me but
you know see if you can bump some of
that stuff up the
VIN uh not a lot of research yet but any
research that has been done in the Varn
has just been done in the last 10 years
so when you think of the grand scheme of
things that's like a day we've had a day
worth of research if that maybe an hours
worth of research in the Vance there's
so much we don't know we don't know what
we don't know uh and there's so much to
learn about
that and then we have CBN so CBN is um
canaby it doesn't you get a small amount
of it in the growing plant um but
basically it's the degradation of THC
and we know that CBN is uh probably the
most sedative of all the canono it's
wonderful for sleep helps you fall
asleep helps you stay asleep um so I
threw that one in there uh I know people
who don't like being stoned but they
love getting a good night's sleep so
they purposely take their cannabis their
flower grind it up and put it in the sun
which you go ah it's like no I want the
CBN they want to change it into CBN um
so it's famous for Sedation but there's
some people that find it works really
well with uh for pain meds and so can we
take a little add a little bit of CBN
maybe for your pain medication at the
end of the day where you want to get a
little bit sleepy so maybe you have pain
meds first thing in the morning you have
a certain blend for first thing in the
morning you have a certain blend for
middle of the afternoon and you have a
certain blend for the nighttime right so
we can start to play with some of these
combinations CBN also uh is it it can be
an appetite stimulant so increase food
intake as well and so that's why I have
lots of people that say I smoke my big
fat doie eat my bag of Doritos and then
I'm ready for bed well that's the CBN
kicking in making you hungry and then
making you go to sleep which isn't a bad
thing I would just replace the Doritos
for something a little bit better
but okay there is also a whole study of
canabo in combination
with Pharmaceuticals out there so let's
not throw away our
Pharmaceuticals because we don't want to
go back to only living till we're 40
years old let's also not rely completely
on our F Pharmaceuticals because they
have a lot of uh collateral damage in
the body usually it's the liver that
takes the the biggest hit from
Pharmaceuticals but how can we pair
these up and so there's a lot of
research out there that is showing
especially in cancer treatment that if
we add cannab in to certain types of
chemotherapy that we can actually lower
the amount of chemotherapy that's
required to be effective how great is
that because chemotherapy has some major
major side effects right uh it mostly
Works kills cancer yeah but it also
kills a whole lot of other things in the
body so we have to kind of maybe we can
find a balance there um so some of the
studies are showing when we combine
Pharmaceuticals with cannabis we we get
uh fewer side effects we get less
frequent flare ups for people who have
chronic disease where they can you know
get a flare up of that chronic disease
we can uh increase quality of life so
fewer side effects that cause you know
difficult issues um and then reduced
healthare costs
right okay I'm going to I always this
idea about oncology in cannabis how many
have heard that cannabis cures all
cancer we've all heard that right we've
all heard it the memes are going around
Facebook all the time sure it's true do
you know where that came from a
laboratory what's that in vitro inv
vitro inv vitro means in glass in a
laboratory so yes cannabis has cured all
cancer lines in a Petri dish with large
amounts of avonoids directly touching
the cancer cells over long periods of
time that's where that Facebook mean
came from so yeah it's technically true
does that translate into the human body
not at all not at all maybe not even a
rat body right but it does give us hope
that maybe at some point we can figure
these things out and so there are some
uh you know some clinical research going
on where they're they're they're
injecting canabo directly into a tur
tumor when they can get to it I mean you
know if it's in the middle of the brain
that's a little hard to get to right um
but but they're working on it right so
um where can cannabis can help in
oncology is it can help less inside
effects it can make the traditional
traditional the the current cancer
treatment more
tolerable um it can uh help with pain
maybe better than the opiates um or
maybe in combination here there's
another thing I didn't even include in
here when you take THC with opiods like
with um you can with Codine or with
um morphine you can actually reduce the
amount of opius that you use by up to
10% which is hugee because opiates are
so addictive but they're very effective
at pain meds but if we can reduce the
amount of opiods that we use so we use
opiods and THC in conjunction with each
other at the same time we can actually
take fewer
opiates um okay so back to using
cannabis with uh our current day
oncology treatment um irritable bowel
symptoms we can help people sleep better
they can have a better appetite so that
they have the strength to fight to to
heal and fight that off um but then
things like anxiet
we can help them with anxiety thank God
I've never had a cancer diagnosis I can
only imagine how anxiety inducing that
is right it's not only stressful for the
patient but it's stressful for the
people around them so we can use
cannabis CBD is my favorite for anti-
anxiety can help bring down anxiety um
can also help with
acceptance this is where I am in life
you know you you can try and run but
your Shadows coming with you so can help
with acceptance and so that you can move
forward you can't usually move forward
with your life until you accept where
you are and and it can help with courage
as well can give us some
courage so here's here's my challenge to
you guys go out and
experiment when you're experimenting
keep good notes because you think you're
going to remember but you don't remember
that's my biggest problem I say oh I'll
always remember this and then you get on
to the two or three things L is like
what was that what combination what was
that ratio how much did I take um so
keep good notes
share experiment try different
combinations there's no rules anymore
cannabis does not have to be decarbed
high THC for it to be medicinally
effective maybe that's super fun and
there's a time and a place for that
absolutely but if we're trying to treat
disease with cannabis there's no rules
we can use the acidic form we can use
the the the decar form the heated form
we can combine we can add other plant
medicine we can add Tarpin we can do
combinations of all these things
um just mix it up yeah experiment keep
notes send me send me your results good
or bad right share them with your
friends um uh grow grow like every
season grow an extra plant and harvest
it early see if you can catch some of
that CBG or that CB CBC out of it and
then combine that with your fully mature
you know harvested at just the right
time uh
plant
also you know just because I'm a I'm a
mom and a grandma start lowo slow you
know thcv is more impairing than THV but
it doesn't last as long so just keep
that in mind but all the other minor
cannaboids you're not going to get that
psychoactivity from them so we can be
fairly careful but High
CBD as you know we think it's pretty
Innocent but it will kill your appetite
and if you're taking high amounts of CBD
which for some people say oh good I'm
going to lose weight yeah but if that
goes on for too long you're going to
lose too much weight and then you're
going to be malnourished right so uh CBD
can also bring your blood pressure down
too low um it can interfere with sleep
for some people for some people can make
them sleep all the time right so we
always have to treat the plant with
respect the same way that we treat our
bodies with respect right so go out
there experiment ment let me know how
you're doing uh get some little at home
test kits so for your your home grows
you don't have to go spend $1,000 to
find out what cannaboids are in there
there's some really great test kits out
there now so you know what you're
working with
um and I think that's oh
yeah I got a few minutes for
questions yeah any
questions yeah
endoc
canabo we produce them throughout our
nervous system
yeah Absolut well I don't know about
relaxed at all times because then you
might check out and not be
very productive with your life not that
we all have to be super productive but
you want to be able to get on with your
life but you know how there is some
experiments on how we can take care of
our endoc canabo system um this is one
way um being in community sharing with
other people um playing together is
actually what the clinical study was
when people play together whether that's
sports or dancing or um chatting and
sharing common goals your endoc canabo
system gets bumped up
singing singing increases your endoc
avonoid production so that you can
measure it in your blood amazing right
Body Work massage um acupuncture um ACU
like osteopathic sex right that all
bumps up your endoc canabo system if
it's good right it's got to be
caring
um uh running running will bump up your
endoc canabo
system um eating well alcohol kills your
endoc canabo system
and it kills your immune well how it
kills your immune system if you've ever
been on a a weekend Bender with alcohol
and then on Monday morning maybe it's
Tuesday you start to get sick it's
because the alcohol killed your immune
system and so now it's going to take a
few weeks to build that back up so
minimize the
alcohol um that will keep your endoc
canabo system in better
shape um there's one other one uh there
have there have been some clinical
studies on people who had difficult
childhoods uh whether that was through
abuse or neglect those kinds of things
uh they do find that the endoc canabo
system isn't as strong as someone who
had a very nurturing childhood so that's
for those people we need to really take
care of our endocannabinoid system
because it's already at at a you know
maybe not working as it's already has
some a bit of damage now that doesn't
mean that that can't damage can't be
repaired because we've seen people who
have had very difficult childhoods
become really you know very productive
and happy adults so um but just keep
that in mind might just be a little bit
more work um
yeah yeah you can you can get a THC
hangover for sure that can it it's just
it's lingering in the body it's it's
your liver is still trying to clear it
out that's why you kind of get that
haziness it's all about fun have some
fun sleep
in dance sing go
swimming play with your buddies yeah
it's yeah we're doing research here yeah
that's right any other questions
all right I have oh
yeah yeah so some of that stuff we got
to go look for it because there's
there's a lot happening out there right
now that's taking up all the chatter
right um
so the question was uh where's the
research we haven't now that it's legal
where's the research it can take from
concept of you know we should research
this to it making to to your doctor's
office 20 years so we're just getting
ramped up when you do clinical research
there's What's called the what's what's
the primary endpoint which means what is
the purpose of doing the research what
are we trying to prove here and that
statement has to be exactly what you're
trying to prove and so Professor ulvan
who I mentioned earlier she she says
that sometimes it can take two years for
them to decide on what is our primary
Endo how are we wording this because if
you don't word word the primary endpoint
properly for uh for your clinical study
and you don't hit that endpoint that
means the clinical study has failed even
though you might have learned a whole
bunch stuff right so the research is out
there go look up Professor ulvan there's
there's um can't think of the name of it
right now but there's a whole worldwide
endocannabinoid research Association out
there there's a lot of work going on out
there we just don't hear about it so you
got to go look for it um an interesting
one down in Brazil uh in 20 late
2020 um if you guys remember what
happened in 2020 2020 was our first year
of covid and Brazil did not do a great
job of Public Health measures so they
were they were one of the countries that
had the most people dying in it they
were one of the top 10 um somebody in a
teaching Hospital down in um in Brazil I
can't remember what city it was in
decided we should this is a great time
to do some clinical studies and they
took Frontline healthcare workers and uh
they had some of them just you know
because they were frantic our healthcare
workers took the brunt of that in 2020
it was brutal and uh so they had them
you know they divided them out however
many were in this clinical study they
divided them out half of them just did
their own thing and they were they got
counseling when they needed counseling
and and uh you know time off when they
needed time off and then the other group
um they gave CBD too and I can't quite
remember the amounts of CBD I'm looking
at one of my students over there if you
remember um it doesn't matter but they
gave them CBD on a daily basis and they
wanted to see if that helped with the
anxiety of being a Frontline worker in a
hospital where they're used to have you
know one person die a month and now
they're having 15 people die a day on
them and um and yeah their anxiety was
way down like and so those little
experiments unless you went looking for
it you would never find it right uh
because it doesn't make Frontline news
um you know one little Hospital in one
little city in one little country um
during all of that other clutter that
was going on out there so it's out there
the studies are out there you just got
to go looking for them and also studies
researchers will only put money into
something if there's anecdotal and case
study evidence so that's why I say with
you guys keep your notes because those
are your case studies and we don't have
to be medical professionals to have case
studies we just have to have good notes
and we can compile those notes and then
other people can read them and if
there's enough people saying hey I took
CBG and CBC I'm just making this up I
don't
know when I last time you know when I
felt like I got covid because I know I
was exposed exposed and you know I
didn't get very sick so hey you try this
when you feel like you got exposed to
covid and then you try it and you try it
and you try it and then we'll compare
notes and maybe only one out of 10 of us
kind of got sick where the last time
that happened nine out of 10 of us got
really sick right so those that's once
we get those kind of anecdotal things
coming out then the researchers go hm
maybe we should look into this a little
bit more maybe we should add some money
to this so there's no end of studies out
there um and it is ramping up believe it
or not that was that was a long answer
um where are we at for time I'm over
time so I will be I have a little booth
over there and uh if anybody want has
more questions come see me over there
I'll be over there for the weekend and
I'm also doing a plant walk on Sunday
Sunday morning same time okay thanks so
much
guys what's your name again
that I to
it so we're just going to break
[Music]
beaches
in in the I
[Music]
have where that
girl I
hand as
I that to my side and I
go Mountain