[Music]
okay that's a point eight eight twenty
eight is what actually the poem is gonna
leave
[Music]
I get to these point 9 yeah that's
chatter like he says I experience that
every time it's to melt even do anything
yep okay we got three point nine yeah do
you want to get a full with point one
are just a full one to do the like will
so that's actually also a thing if you
want to put it all together or you know
and then just press okay everybody go
out that's your caller yeah I think does
that makes the most sense you know if
that if that's the easiest certainly
whatever you think
[Music]
next time you got to try to get it
funnel Minh like one yaar hmm all of it
yeah I know all these guys do the same
thing
[Music]
[Applause]
get off here oh yeah so we know it's
completely melted
what don't gonna be yeah
this one's spinning yeah no Terry but
the other ones were like scraping pretty
well this one's spinning every time I
try to move it I'm just pulling them out
oh yeah
[Music]
muscle
Hey
[Music]
2.65 okay two points and this is aren't
this turn off oh I don't like that I'm
gonna plug it on my dad
oh okay yeah I was to say it's not it's
not hot enough yeah could I hit this
ball bang shit my left to 27 in I
shouldn't have to switch gloves here cuz
these was so messy already and this
silkscreen is really difficult with the
disclose
[Music]
oh shit
he's in a 25 night crowd screaming
as awesome
when you that for the
so that she - yeah
well you make it cuffing individual yeah
because it's such a small in my office
it's not gonna really benefit us to use
a whole yeah absolutely
honestly I find it to be maybe even race
well with the bag I'm such small out
because so much gets trapped in their
horror scenes and shit there's got in
there mmm
both often hey thanks for joining us is
a live Robin to us today with star
shining a total ban against which I
agree yeah a presence in high grade this
is brought a resin ranch GMO
so right now he's preparing the bag
yeah
[Music]
ten
little rap on it screw this heavy really
productive
oh this is abstaining thinking to the
truth
[Music]
just test the speed nicely the press is
still have enough in the speed of the
plate clothing there we go this is dupe
I'm just gonna blow out if I'm not
careful he's gonna put on a wrap and a
small small amount when you get in there
and see this
[Music]
back it off a little bit there's friends
gonna blow very clear
[Music]
oh wow
yes I see I haven't went over 20
because say good job so the guys that
resin ran holy God
looks like water
[Music]
look like
the light is colored
like some added some lemon
[Music]
Wow it's done here
alright gotta pull it to dance while
going up so much slower right now
[Music]
literally smells like our friend Dimitri
wait oh yeah oh whoa that's a crazy
thing to transform the center that's it
oh it's some lamb lamb
wiggity wow you guys really you can't
really even see it on the paper there
are spots in the tape
help me see the light are you falling on
Tosh late look go eliminate some time
for Hannah
oh well yeah yeah totally now you can
see those little squares here I figured
it was worth its buy the expensive what
can i yeah
bamm-bamm spaghetti land no it's all
right cooled off a bit now collect it up
no but you just do right off the bat
just take that one gram you're talking
about mm-hmm put it right over yeah off
these rips that's a purest of the pure
100 scale you do what I say
I have to do a second pressing
not focusing on very well
it tried to focus on it for a second
yeah it goes in and out I got to figure
out what it's focused thing is the
giving it doesn't have it one that you
can choose but I found it and that's
perfect
well it's so good that you're and yeah
it's just serious oh yeah that's a good
view of it you sure
you just saying have smellivision order
oh man oh wow the odor of this Rand Paul
mouth dude whoo oh no oh my baby sure of
it just like that that stage
Nicholas
pull that off a bit a little bit
simply a 50% yield I'm sorry to say oh
oh there's still more yeah
boom there you go that's like a dream
well I'm curious because if but like it
should be one third of the ratio just
cuz this is gonna end up being like
super small amount of diamonds who want
to get a fatty amount or like an even
ratio or some Island right now
what bank with some some good amount so
it's like a pretty deep sea some
diamonds and then like even it might be
less than I have a grandma last time
today know why empresa nice oh there you
go oh well then gold out then some ranch
farmers and definitely farming that
resident whether that's fire
two grams that's pretty good there was
what was it on the way through 70 yeah
that's two point seven half that's like
stir-crazy out Jesus
77% whopping their services in Wildman
oh so yeah I don't know what the ratio I
guess would be one still do this one
again of a higher temp oh yeah turn it
up right now
yeah
so yeah we got Graham to make the goods
out of those may not be the better yet
okay yeah guys so you're getting exactly
you know one young put these into this
much it's really easy Matt yeah it'll be
all right
calculated okay so I'm really anxious to
fight at this stuff yeah
[Music]
oh gosh
here's a little trick associated to one
if you lock your fingers you just take
the glove off your finger
[Music]
yeah
pretty honking
way back
[Music]
hit honestly though we don't look that
much better than his hash
I mean I said there's more definition
Oh Barry speaking
yeah
now watch week watching the watch
walking with the retard oh okay there
was very much done with him
really fucking activated now the bird
about ten minutes
oh really right there I thought yeah
yeah
that's literally the most gorgeous
fucking time
the second squish real quick here 180
degrees now Wolverton 160 oh nice all
that in just one blow real oh I figured
this would have to go hi
yeah but maybe we should have no such is
who fear why rural
Oh so he said why do you whip it for
consistency people are commenting hell
yeah well size micron byesies
I believe we're using 25 right well I'm
not sure what size micron bags of the
hash to use there but 25 microns 92 149
there you go I know that and then yeah
my silkscreen here's 25 micron which is
a little lower than you really need to
go for doing hash rosin 37 is my usual
but this stuff is really I just makes it
really clean and then it's also double
usable uh EE used as the thing that we
wrap the rosin back into to make the HCA
extract out of it the fuck daddy so
thanks and then yeah Emily and a weapon
it does it just kind of kicks in the
nucleation process which helps to cause
it to butter or change consistencies
which you need it to be in that kind of
tacky ER consistency or less less messy
before you can actually make it into the
THC a effectively otherwise most of it
was booze out of the bag this one was on
with right this is what the first grand
that we didn't live yet this is the
second ground that you whipped on camera
and writing it so you can see the
difference between the two clearly this
one was just whipped for it you know a
little while that one it was not whipped
at all looks beautiful says hell yeah
focus three people in the house now yeah
those look fucking beautiful thank you
sir sup neighbors so these guys
following Instagram
resin ranch extraction yeah they know
what they're doing
yeah this is hella dense split in the
house starting yeah gotta know they're
easier than love
well my limiting factors are out of my
hands you know if people are knowing the
product and they're isolating it clean
methods then most pretty much just skate
by on this end serious you know thank
you John 4411 thank you very much
this is donated lemon start out Thank
You Man that's fuckin awesome
when life gives you lemons you squish
them muhfuckas into some dank but yet so
one form this is kind of a nice little
squarish shape book yeah and get it
butter in the form that we want to wrap
it in the final bag well that's the wait
until the father to do that but you can
get that shape
oh dude Thank You lab max flashier than
that fuck yeah bro just enabling this
little infants of it yeah well we gonna
have some lemonade oh that is that fresh
hmm gonna get myself a second time
remember it's still beautiful color oh
wow yeah it's still clear yeah how are
you playing oh my god yeah I get the
time yeah yeah whoo garlic comes out in
2021 I guess forget that
so what'd you guys think can unicorn
swim - or just fly the thoughts was a
rosin master as the rosin teenage ones
are the thoughts that keep you up at
night
yeah I mean obviously they can breathe
in outer space but so that yeah of
course they can swim in cool BAM there's
the second press meat usually makes it a
darker color but it's still yeah it's
totally fun that's the same way oh my
god we ready to go try to have with that
yeah as I was thinking yeah fuck yeah I
know if we can just shut this down now
it's like make that into some tea later
or something no she should be there
awesome dude yo thank you a third squish
light but I mean that's fearful if you
want to or anything but yo thank you for
this fucking thing we'll do whatever so
parts you come on soon
cool fine y'all have a good night bhai
de Cerio thank you guys for tuning it
well yeah
[Music]