and inside the bag for the extended
period of time there don't want any of
it to come out for the first cycle 10
minutes and 100 degrees second cycles on
110 degrees for 10 minutes and you just
bump it up by 10 degrees every time
basically so we're just now about to
bump it up to 130 and at this point once
it's at that temperature I'll put a
little bit more pressure on it there's a
little most likely hold in place now so
you'll start to see the bag wet up
sometime around the 20 minute mark or so
if you got no pressure on it if you see
the bag wet up before that you got too
much pressure on and basically gonna
waste some rosin so now that's my timer
reset the timer
so this is actually the 31 minute mark
basically we got it at 130 degrees
gently apply some extra pressure I
really like this particular press the
long speak because you can really dial
that pressure in your just 1 psi at a
time lock it in place
right there right around 5 psi now you
get in real little tight here for our
extreme close-up we got done you can see
that the bag is just now starting to Wed
up little color a little little wetness
to it
sit there we go extreme close-up extreme
closeup yeah I know that it's good
actually zoom in on the part where I'm
trying to get it to the right well you
get the idea it's very much there at
this point when is dripping I'll do it
you actually want to do and I'm not sure
how
damn okay yeah
Wayne's World Wayne's World
okay yeah but it's uh you get it
actually see a little bit of moisture on
the bag now at this point on the archery
six psi yeah it's still pretty fucking
slow and steady at this point there's
gonna be a lot of a lot of waiting a lot
of thumb twiddling maybe some song and
comedy well I honestly I wanted to start
up because I think that it is very
interesting and the steps are important
and what you were explaining to me with
all really intense so I was like damn I
should play you know I think we pretty
much kind of caught up the most part
it's like the main thing is is just
going slow and steady at the beginning
because I have went too fast at it
before and the laws and all goopes out
and you know there's still THC a in that
rosin that oozed out initially so you
basically didn't harvest the THC a from
that and your first terrine layer will
end up being not just terpenes at that
point it's well that's a point voice
as close up as you can get it apologize
for the loud air compressor yeah
whatever
those mic here here that we're going to
end up with the best deal that
[Music]
the overall purity of this resin ranch
there's just not much in the way
[Applause]
so I'm imagining that the THC percentage
of this stuff I don't really know
there's no on that sticker there wasn't
no yes there's no way to know but
imagining that the rosin is somewhere
over 80 85 % THC and with this method
being as effective as it is you're out
really you know losing I have gotten
fairly low THC a yields in the past
while using a lower quality rosin
starting product I'm imagining this time
we're gonna have somewhere over 50%
that's the hopes so any other weed nerds
in there yeah when you actually do start
to put the pressure on you'll get a very
clear looking drip coming out of it
that's the terpene fraction there the
terpenes are more viscous than the rosin
itself so yeah the first thing that
you'll actually see is out might end up
being an actual liquid and drop I'm not
sure hmm
it's just like I said it's my first time
doing it with this high of a purity so
yeah yeah sure what's respect with it
but I've seen some shit come out before
that literally just looks like you know
nectar okay but yeah the first couple
that come out be like a higher yield of
terpenes that come out and then the ones
that come after that will be cleaner but
lower yield and those ones tend to be a
little more shatter II well find out
what we're gonna get today pretty much
every product
and end up with a different consistency
mmm pan upon you know how it was stored
what it was sprayed on it what it
experience in his life cycle which and
resident rancher seemed to really
optimize his growing environment
probably pretty fucking clean oh yeah a
lot of times cleaner stuff will be a
little more shattering or stable on this
side most okay I'm just bumping up the
temperature a little bit higher again
140 now you can see that there is a good
corner of moisture formed but nothing's
actually squeezed out of the bag yet
we're just at 7 psi now slowly creeping
up oh yeah
not really smelling it yet yes yes sir
yeah so this is technically mechanical
separation process this is what they
call it okay mechanical terpene
fractioning or mechanical separation of
th da hmm we're gonna we'll do a little
experimentation with mixing them back
together in a form of solvent free
diamonds and sauce
pressure a bit more around ten
well I can see the other side it's got
white
so witnesses leaving yeah at this point
it's slowly starting to separate the
more viscous terpene layer will kind of
get pushed away TJ there so that's
essentially that's the only thing that's
actually coming out of the bag his wax
is a little bit spencer pains they're
like to at some point it'd be really
cool to check it out and see like you
know what percentage of THC is left in
the terpene fraction and you know
obviously have to find out what the
rosin was going in what the turkey
fraction was and then what the THC a
just to get an idea of how pure of a
separation we're actually getting here
mmm oh yeah okay now you can really see
it started
so yeah there's some different ways we
can handle this at the end is uh most of
the stuff I see in the stores mm-hmm has
a pretty pretty dark tinge of yellow to
it that means that there's still a
little bit of the terpene fraction left
in the thca and the more times you
repress it after we get the separation
done we can just keep repressing it full
pressure and full heat hundred eighty
degrees and it'll just get cleaner and
cleaner well I had one that I did there
just was like perfectly clear crystal
another one I tried I didn't go as hard
high and it was still very amber colored
mm so it's up to you how you want to
play that I mean obviously you know
weights too much time in this situation
since you already off work well we'll
just we'll do it at the what I would
consider to be like 75% only done okay
if we keep going at it and keep going at
I mean you could add a whole extra half
an hour yeah 40 minutes on total faith
and and it doesn't really change the
purity of that publish oh yeah you
totally honest that's perfect
see the diamonds and kind of mixing it
back into its own rather than any way I
want to see I think it would be crazy
cool the way down each time to
separating out there's less in the
terpene or less in the THC a fraction so
right here do you think doesn't work on
a larger scale or would you have to like
yeah most definitely would you're
wondering to a certain point though I
don't think you could do like a full
plate full of it
hmm maybe you can just I feel like you
could end up being a lot more of a mess
because with the viscosity of rosin you
press out a whole plateful it doesn't
like this spillover the edges whereas
this stuff if it's really viscous it
could just like drip down into the
mm-hmm the inner workings of the press
there mmm
that's why some people do the extra
parchment folds and get that I mean the
directing flow and whatnot right but
I've actually had a lot of bad luck with
those causing the bag to slip around you
can't see the bag properly to like tell
when it's ready for pressure it makes it
way harder for me to not blow out or
shit like that yeah that's all I've kind
of stepped away from the directed flow
parchment typed okay particularly when
it comes to making actual rosin almost
impossible the low-pressure involved
with this will be more forgiving those
I'm going to be possible to do it
without blowing out yeah but it's really
I mean sometimes it's hard to see what
you're doing
when you need those directed flow
pouches okay one thing I've had problems
with in the past is I get the flow
proper but then too much of it still
goes out in the back
it causes a pressure buildup back there
and that can actually cause the
parchment paper to explode mmm in the on
the backside two more minutes will bump
up to 150 degrees and start putting real
pressure on this thing okay that's the
first big cyclic fold real cycle yeah
that's when it'll start to you might
have a few drips pulling out of here and
I'm not guaranteeing this stuff is gonna
be super clear mmm we've had some of the
past that came out they were like that's
a terpene separation right there oh geez
oh you twist the later ones they started
being smaller that's trippy and more
stable mm-hmm that's what these are
yeah so basically it's just climbing 150
degrees now once it's there up crank up
the pressure until I started see some
action now we're over 40 minutes into it
and the the thta's probably pretty well
bonded at this point and not likely to
accidentally use out hmm it's safer to
put pressure on fucked up and I cut this
just a little too short I can't mm-hmm
clip it up too damn magnet
move it right up to the edge of the
plate since it's so small and go see
otherwise see how incredibly viscous and
clear that liquid is yeah that's a first
way that's pretty cool you can see it
pretty well on your phone we'd live
literally clear
oh I smell it now Oh
oh man that stank
mmm really both the garlic and mushrooms
and the grandpa house brought the
grandpa mouth right out come to call GMO
yeah you didn't miss a whole lot as I
was saying earlier jots is a really slow
process on this start here but it's
starting to ooze up pretty good now it's
just her peens basically right there
I did my job
all the thca is still in the bag and
that's just the terpene fraction losing
out that pure
good the strings you got running the Sun
and job what you running deep purple and
golden goat just I just asked my
correctly if I remember correctly and I
meant to ask you what what that golden
goat is but if I'm crazy so ministry
haven't you heard of that one
yeah am i right is that that is Red John
okay gotcha
Oh an IT guy see okay golden girl goes
out the purple and raw cookies yes he's
gonna shit
what's up sounds like a nice nice
harvest on your horizon there fuck yeah
yeah I remembered because of the golden
goat and the deep purple he said I have
a great memory I'm not strange but I
happen to remember that but Frank does
have a really good memory okay
golden goat that's an interesting one
though both of us at some time we never
heard of that
that's dream new to me star fans kind of
a plant encyclopedias I was surprised to
hear him say as well unknowable yeah I'm
no plant encyclopedia fuck yeah yeah is
that more on this a teabag Purple's from
rip
yeah one thing I've grown by him was uh
that Apollo 13 law school but I know is
there's at least now as well back to
well now yeah 150 degrees now we've been
doing this for about 45 minutes just now
starting to actually eat out hell yeah
he said yes the steamboat leaving
however I remember perfectly 16 - 17
Dave finisher nice nice mmm yeah I like
those uh pineapple Citybus well some
really good pineapple taiwan citizens
fucking bee's knees
i have nine exists but yeah this Frank
knows I'm not the biggest fan of three
strains but a couple of them every now
and then hit right I like those uh
stinky foot you know
burnt rubber diesel fuels like those
things that stink
but yeah you like this GM oh boy uh than
ever it's just so funky literally it's
like uh uh you know this is the only way
to describe it in word I'm pretty sure
that's effectively descriptive of it
funk aroma 150 bumpin temps bump intense
at this point we're ready to just go
blasting away at it with you know it's
not gonna blow up now we're just gonna
put the pressure on I'll be back in the
chat in a minute I'm gonna use my camera
really brought the grandpa mouth right
out he says all right we are at full
blast at this point
heart rate swap heart metallic case
oh boy
and that's just crazy
really yeah literally very clear clear
now and that's technically terpene
separate right yeah that's just a sure
play there should be fairly low in THC
compared to everything else okay I love
them kept all the Terps or all the THC a
in the in the back school all I can say
if you want to make a good diamond sauce
yeah you mix this back in with that okay
get multiple runs of this after it cool
off a little bit you can get hopefully
get it off of the parchment sometimes
they're a little more staffing this one
looks like it's probably like so we got
a question from Joe or one one he said
what strain have you guys press that at
the best return uh sfv or this GMO
honestly this GMOs it's a six star we
pressed it had a 77 percent from hash to
rosin but we'll find out what the yield
is on rosin ca ca in the past my highest
yield on th EA was I got like twenty
percent so it's usually like I get like
sixty percent or something fifty percent
maybe from hash to rosin and then out of
that you know a 20% of that to go in the
form of THC a
so that comes out in the form of this
goopy stuff on the parchment paper but
I'm feeling like this is gonna be a much
higher yield because of the actual
percentage of THC in the rosin was
higher this probably was 88 90 percent
THC a rosin it's a traditional market
source so there's no testing though on
it but it is pure let me tell you that
you know test to its purity there's like
no particles in there they shouldn't be
in there so listen my Jimmy the tool
scraping I call right now it's already
still really just doop
that's clear oh man that's crazy the jar
oh my goodness wow that is a Wow wait at
certain angles you can see that it's
just a little pissed rip of fucking
nothing
oh my god yeah right there it's clear
it's a bird
oh my god it looks just like the mouth
it was like attacking this hmm
yeah it's not working off through the
paper though it's like way to biscuits
to get off the paper don't take yourself
either huh smell that Wow yeah that's
the whole garlic
that's crazy
usually like a lot more shattering or at
least of that waxy kind of pliable
material or you know you can play with
it kind of hmm this is just straight-up
liquid I feel like freeze it so I get it
off that way Oh
can't see shit
listen now because it's all white it out
yeah that's too close to the light now
oh yeah yeah yeah that's crazy yeah
like I'm hanging out at Black Oak branch
and really good bands on the stage and
you know Saturday night people are just
doing all that Saturday night stuff that
they do like over here then the band
says something about yeah it smells like
somebody's cooking popcorn out there in
the crowd sure would like to smoke some
pot I mean eat some popcorn this
security guard comes over and he's like
dance we could smell popcorn
oh okay everybody all right fuck yeah
security guard enjoy some popcorn and
then Karen comes over she's like y'all
can't do that here this is Kate Wolfe
teach
I mean that happened to a friend of mine
golly so it's still part thing - mmm
yeah uh we'll get a little bit more
Terps next time or I mean sorry a little
bit less turps each time after this now
ya know how well we're gonna be able to
do this song that was dining this also
well pretty much what I thought
we're getting more in the form of THC a
in them sauce what I was thinking
originally also is like I don't know
what the room is from them but it's like
it looks like it's like whipped rosin
that just has the diamonds in it I think
I think it's really rosin it's it's a
probably a proportion of terpenes rosin
to th EI and then whipped while heated
oh Jesus and then the Diamonds added
after ours she's hard to say so yeah the
proprietary tech is their own method
it's hard to recreate but they're the I
feel like it's some form of those
combinations of things heat whip
proportions of ingredients okay so now
we're doing full pressure full heat
which is a hundred and seventy
there's allegedly happened other cables
allegedly ladies unless you'd leave the
glove did not fit what's the quick
actually I will do another
did not have inhalation relations with
that woman miss Merrow in ski
[Music]
I'm getting my night and scandals all
mixed up hold on
[Music]
this is my monetary a buddy
[Applause]
[Music]
like the only thing
straight up
the parchment actually it's angled so it
kind of pulls up all right now at this
point it's just cleaning up we'll just
do this one more round and we'll call it
at that point okay that would be a hour
and 10 minutes cool yeah and then I
think we're just now had an hour in 10
minutes actually since it's 5:14 we
started at 4 right you know yeah so yeah
any any bit of time from here now isn't
really gonna do much else except for
just change the color of the TCA a
little bit it's why it gets lighter so
like I said right now there's still some
terpenes stuck inside the bag mm-hmm and
slowly over time you're gonna push all
of those out and then you'll just end up
with a purer and purer the8 I meant I
guess is that terpenes come out of
darker as you're gone oh no they
actually get lighter too
Oh crazy yeah it's okay in my experience
it's just like less of it each time but
it didn't like clear so that little bit
of color that is there isn't gonna be
there that's for me okay but yeah it's
probably not even gonna be enough to
actually collect it's just pushing it a
little bit further out of the inner bag
into the second bag at this point then
sometimes what I'll do is I'll actually
pull apart and collect it all the THC
out of there and put it in a clean bag
and then repress it again at this point
and that gets like at this point the bag
is just being a sponge pulling extra
Terps out of it that would be in the
ga mm-hmm that's how you end up with the
clearest most pure crystals well we
don't have to go that far into it I'm
sure it's just so he's stupid as is mmm
and for the sake of brevity let's just
call it now in the middle of the cycle
you see this like I mean basically
nothing yeah but each time you do that
it's just a little bit comes out of
there it would be in here
Oh guys I think so now this is the goods
it's the goods you're right back in the
chat I'm gonna be videotaping it so like
I said it's like a sponge almost of
sorts it's it's soaking up the turkeys
at this point okay home amount of the
inner bag in the bag will be a lot
cleaner
[Music]
Oh busted out just a little bit Wow
that's crazy-looking no dude this is
already pure white at this point it's
already like oh my god here oh my
goodness dude so we're back from
Colombia with our goods
oh that's crazy-looking that's pretty
nuts
looks like the absolute
[Music]
all right I got the parchment tear it
out you can figure out how much we
actually harvest it here now that it's
on a brown paper he can see it better so
yeah almost exactly 50% it's probably
more accurate way of it ma'am 147 yeah
that's great
point four seven always one grand it is
really good
I couldn't maybe not went as hard on it
and could have Lily over 50% me just
have to slice it yell okay Oh
[Music]
just heat the press up to 190 degrees
and just let it sit there slowly over
time it'll get there but it's for Holi
actually have that was off I had no idea
so I just found that we can do it that
way
now here's the cool thing
if this was a little bit of light - Wow
no it's badass so here's the coolest
part about it is this is this is the is
the most stable THC substance I've ever
played with my life at this point once
it's solidified into this crystal just
whatever glassy type deal it takes over
200 degrees to reheat it so I could
literally just sit there and hold it my
hands forever
it'll never melt to my finger at all
even without gloves on this is the most
stable THC product I've ever seen
can you go grab those um other turf
players so fast yeah we're under the
freezer I don't have to breathe yeah hi
fuck yeah oh yeah do you know this year
still got some THC left in it it's hard
to get it all out but what I generally
do with that is just like throw it into
a little bit of tea you know at the hot
tea so I end up with like a little bit
left on there so we'll play around with
that and make them mix up and stuff and
then we'll smoke it later tomorrow or
whenever you're free wanna do that oh
I'm definitely down to do some salt
Atlas diamond dabs yeah fuck that
I'm gonna sapphire yeah fuck yeah
yeah this still is not coming off it's
like shitting on the tasty treats watch
the whole rosin press on that and the
Diamonds press yeah dude fuck yeah
that's awesome so I don't know that
we're gonna get any more actual in there
and what we should do is just get a
different jar and then put th ck
again you hear this oh yeah ASMR for you
the sound of THC a doobie down fuck yeah
no for joining us very much happy Friday
we'll be smoking some very soon but yeah
thank you very much stars I'm fucking
master of ceremonies here thank you sir