I have fun with the Commission since
December 1st of 2018 which happened to
coincide with the first day that product
was available to patients in Maryland so
I get blamed for a lot of things that
has happened since then I actually get
blamed for a lot of things that happen
before them but we're working on those
things so as background I want everybody
to know that I came from health care and
I had a unique experience in my
healthcare career I started at the age
of 17 as a nurse's aide in the nursing
home and I will tell you that the very
first day I went home with a migraine
headache and said me and I don't know if
I can do this you know I don't know if I
can do this and I went back and I grew
to love it
I absolutely loved it I loved helping
people I loved taking care of taking
care of people and so you know that
really wasn't an integration into
healthcare from there I became a
laboratory scientist I'm a medical
technologist from there I became multi
departmental managers and hospitals I've
always worked in small rural hospitals
so one of the unique opportunities is to
get to do a lot of different things
there's less people so you just kind of
got a pitch in and and learn to do what
needs to be done so laboratory
scientists I became a quality director
in charge of quality for health care
programs in the hospitals I became a
risk manager looking at you know
mitigating risk what does that mean for
patients what processes do we have in
place and then became director of
compliance and regulatory affairs which
all of those things really were great
building blocks for what I'm doing now I
am a regulator I look at things through
a regular
lenz and I look at things through a
healthcare lens the focus in healthcare
is the patient and what are we doing for
the patient and what processes are we
putting in place to make sure that our
focus is on patient safety quality
services and things like that so that's
really my background and how I come to
the Commission it's really excited to be
able to have an influence on rolling
this healthcare program out for patients
across Maryland the cannabis space is a
little bit interesting in that regard
and that's a little bit what I want to
talk about tonight I'm Brent Gaytan
chief operating officer of remedy
Columbia
Gavin heck I'm the assistant manager and
ideally that I'll just get right into it
and then we'll discuss have discussion
tell me what motivates you to work in
the medical cannabis industry and what
is the most satisfying aspect of doing
that I have a 20 year history of working
in IT as Quality Assurance professional
was calling and I have a sister who was
a programmer and became a nurse and I
was interested in kind of going into
healthcare but around the time I was
taking off prereqs from nursing I went
into a clinical trial at Hopkins matter
radiation injury so it kind of swerved
me away from being a hospice nurse and
then deer and two years ago finished a
master's at UMBC in the instructional
systems development so I wanted to kind
of apply my degree to a field that needs
training in the in this kind of process
okay thank you it's good for me I come
from food manufacturing supply chain
logistics the most recent venture was
right down the street
if you smell any brand and I used to run
the H&amp;S
agree there I used to run so with bread
comes a passion for all things and with
food comes a passion for all things my
passion is helping people helping people
and being a healer for them my
background with cannabis is I played
football in college and played football
you see a light back in the 90s and back
in the 90s if you recall gentleman by
the name of Jack Herer helped lead
proposition to California I was there
with him on the corner of Wilshire and
so verna in front of the Federal
Building protesting passing out medicine
enjoying medicine teaching and helping
people all about playing football UCLA I
enjoyed that lunch Miss Korea UCLA came
back to Maryland and have many people in
my family that have suffered from cancer
in different forms and different stages
they have been patients in Maryland and
across the United States so I have a
true appreciation for this medicine
dating back to the early 90s so tell me
what is the most satisfying aspect of
being in business when someone comes
back and says that it worked and they
had been I'm also of that and I've
started once on the effort one here
thirty years and I finally personally
found something works for me
relief that they've been seeking for
decades from institution or an entity
that really should have been able to
help them and then you kind of become
that enemy thank you I'd agree with that
and say that when patients definitely
come back and you see them at first and
they're using a walker or some aid and
they come back with the help and hate of
cannabis they no longer need that locker
that crutch
whatever it is and they come in they
thank you on the way into your
dispensary they stop and they give you
doughnuts I mean I don't bring my wife
doughnuts on there on a regular basis so
you know that that to me says that we're
doing what we need to do is serve our
patients comments I so remember one of
our first cases though we can of course
we do a month later he came back and
said you know you saved my marriage
I can get on the couch again I can play
with my kids during a human being and
I'm off of the scripts and even a loyal
patient could even walk into the store
or the shop
[Music]
okay through my like regulator lens my
next question comment first yes some of
the things that I've seen in this
medical only market are absolutely
shocking to me
so tell me breath yeah what business
strategies do you use in differentiating
your business model to focus on medical
only versus an adult use market whether
that's well if you're a grower out the
audience whether that's choosing
genetics whether you're a processor and
choosing the products you're going to
manufacture or if you're a dispensary
what are you gonna recommend to your
patients so for us I can tell you that
remedy Columbia we have a long history
of holistic of net and natural
healthcare dating back to 1974 when
acupuncture was illegal it was illegal
every state the nation except for
Maryland and Nevada our president and
founder mr. Bob Duggan who is no longer
with us on this earth founded the Tyson
PETA Institute in Columbia Maryland back
in 1974 when acupuncture was illegal
acupuncture and canvas or riding
parallels right now so for us our
definition of medicine is anything that
helps maintain or can't bring you back
to homeostasis we start with that as a
basis and then levitate from there this
is us and our approach to the medicine
so
based off of our definition of medicine
medicine could be a smile medicine could
be jogging medic medicines anything that
helps you bring you back to homeostasis
so off of that our business practices to
use that as a guide and have a
conversation with people come in to
speak with us and let's have a
conversation about what we can help you
with what elements do you have that we
can help improve your life and your
well-being while your buyer with us
that's kind of that's kind of our take
on it out the guy answer your question
directly but indirectly that's who we
are and that's you know over the 7,000
patients that we've seen and continue to
see on a monthly basis that's our
approach and although I didn't really
shake it I was just tired a couple
months ago so the basic idea of the kept
stands for knowledge is power the idea
that if you don't have them in fun
customer informed patient they're not
going to be able to really negotiate the
process of being medicated properly the
other thing is we hired of registered
pharmacist and we have we encourage
everyone comes and if they have any
questions well to take the time to have
a consultation with them which is free
and them can be as long as they like
we've had people come in and talk to him
for five months who have people come in
and talk to him for two or three hours
it really held it and then we also have
a patient handout where they've got a
couple pages to track you know track
what he you know does to do the strains
and we encourage people to come back to
us but we also a policy of trying to you
know follow up with them if they want to
so glut will actually tell people and
that's kind of how I was going you know
encourage them to just communicate with
us early okay drivers
they're shooting the breeze and he was
watching people come in and someone lot
said and he goes that's a refuse someone
comes in he goes that's a rent user and
I realized two things one obviously had
a bias and I realized that I also had
that bias and for me it was like turning
a key I came to understand things from a
different perspective so just because
someone has been using this medicine
because it wasn't available legally or
because they got it from other ways
doesn't mean that they haven't been
using it for very important reasons
whether that's sleep anxiety pain but
absolutely and so I don't even think in
terms of rec and medical anymore I think
in terms of unguided and guided and I
think that what we want to do is
advocate everybody using this medicine
in a guided way instead of an unguided
way regardless of how they get it now
when they can get medicine in this
program we know that they're getting
clean medicine we know that it doesn't
have be junk in it and we know exactly
what they're getting and I think that
that's also an important distinction
between what they can get on the street
between what they can get from any of
our dispensaries but I think we need to
rise above this idea of RAC and really
just think of it as we would any other
herbs you know if I had a patient that
was using kinko I'm going to use it I
want them to use it in a kind of way I
don't want them to get their medical
advice from the 17-year old clerk at the
local GNC I want them to talk to
somebody that has an education in this
medicine a person's not guided
rather you just tell you if you steal
something for because at least twice
though so the follow-up to that question
is do you think the Maryland market
overall is specifically tailored to
medical only yes and based on proper
definition of medicine knowing that I've
been using his medicine since 1992 yes
somewhere I think the definition
ultimately becomes less meaningful when
you see someone come in who hadn't using
it for decades and they finally are able
to really dial it in and whether they
yeah often we don't even know the
specificity of all their illnesses but
we much of a way that them you probably
know this about the some traditional
medicine like the pink alloy voiceover
them often cultures have been using
medicine for thousands of years and then
Big Pharma catches up so what was a
local medicine to people in South and
Central America
now let's become a big Christian or and
lasting than those used for chemotherapy
so I think work we're finally catching
up with cannabis so I can expand on that
there's a gentleman by the name of James
Duke anybody ever gave that name of
course you have your graduating class of
either so James Duke has anybody seen
that movie medicine man so James Duke is
a Howard County native he'd lived right
home in Howard County he was on our
advisory board until he passed away last
year
so James Duke was the one that Sean
Connery he Sean Connery played him in
medicine man and he would go down into
the indigenous regions of the Amazon and
find all these herbs and he eventually
brought the big pharma companies in they
eradicated all the herbs it made modern
medicine and this gentleman who was on
our advisory board who live in Howard
County who still has a
garden that represents the eastern
hemisphere the Western Hemisphere has
divided he has every herb there that you
could imagine he's taking people from
McCormick on tours tours of his garden
they have never seen herbs grown
naturally they've been to his garden
this man was remarkable at what he could
do with the plant and to see what you
know some of these companies came back
and just eradicated things because he
went down to the Amazon with indigenous
people for forever brought things back
his stories are amazing and I can't even
begin to tell you what about the
audience do you think our market is
geared specifically to a medical only
market what you're seeing day-to-day
what what you experienced I mean
whatever from your perspective I'm I'm
not framing the question I'm not
qualifying the question I want to see
from your experience it's just I think a
lot of philosophy you're hearing is that
anybody can be a patient even within the
regulations
patience and you know weather anxiety or
insomnia or anything any of these things
are on the list of qualifications we're
finding at dispensaries that people come
in for a plethora of reasons and they're
qualifying by their doctors by their
physicians for many many reasons of why
they're coming in pain comes in many
many forms both mentally and physically
most of the conditions are physical as
you know so I think it's serving mostly
as a medical you know but when I hear
that I think more regulations are
written for more you know medical
patients but people are finding
alternative medicine is the solution
versus the pharmaceuticals that they've
been offered for so many years so in
different forms people are slowly as you
know coming in and registering
self-certifying themselves to try
something new something that may work
better for them it's more healthy for
them that won't actually kill them we we
see it every day at remedy you know the
one of the things that we would say when
you're doing it for years like it's not
a cliche to say that we're saving lives
like we actually have people at our
store at our shop saying you know you're
saving my life you know so it's not for
me to say I'm saving lives it's them
telling us that what they are so I think
it's serving the medical market and it's
actually you know expanding slowly and
to other people's needs and
but I think this is there has been
legislation introduced at least the last
two years in regard to adult use and we
get that question a lot of the
Commission and I can just respond by
saying we are the mirror we are the
maryland medical cannabis commission so
we have no we have no position and and
no comment on adult use but i think it's
very well known that medical usually
comes first and then states get into
authorizing medical use
excuse me adult use in a variety of ways
i don't know that we have an idea of
what that program might look like in
maryland and i think those things are
yet to come but from my focus i really
want to emphasize and the reason for my
questions is we are a medical program we
are a health care program for patients
across maryland and i realized that
there are patients that we have now who
were not patients before it was legal
but they were using this self-medicating
it as you will but i think it's up to
all of us to really change that persona
and sometimes it's it's more difficult
with people who have been using cannabis
for years have a perspective of you know
i need to i need to hide it i you know
any i need to to talk about it in a
specific way i need to refer to it in a
specific way and it's up to all of us to
change that nomenclature those types of
things that I can see brought ready to
jump it please forgive me if that is the
case that violent down have
billboards and everything else if we're
trying to end the stigma well because I
will tell you very honestly and I know
I'm being recorded so I have to be very
peaceful the Commission the Commission
did propose regulations that did have
some strenuous bands in regard to
advertising that was in response the in
large part to examples that we were
provided from licensees that are already
out there in the industry who may have
advertised in a way that was not
entirely of a medical flavor sir in the
back behind Eric
appreciating medical aspect of eternal
death and that homegrown is something
that's being considered and adult abuse
and that every time that's brought up I
encourage people to at the point that it
would be amazing if you chose to grow at
home and get tested that you could sell
it to a dispensary and create a
legitimate market where people are
trading for teachers I'm is the one
coming I'm really interested you said
trading for teachers yeah yeah they're
they're creative the market is very
innovative
I can't make a decision for the
Commission the Commission did vote on
proposed regulations they offered at
least four or five opportunities for
public comment there are proposed
regulations that will be submitted
through the rulemaking process there is
additional opportunities for public
comment when it goes through the AEL our
committee I think that we cannot submit
those regulations until after the
blackout period for the AEL are so they
won't even be able to receive them until
late February early March that
rulemaking process takes four or five
months so they are not yet in effect
they are simply proposed regulations at
this point in time dr. Kerr Monta
[Music]
vii judicial proceedings committee is
interested in having discussions with us
regarding those proposals I think
they're going to have that opportunity
we may end up holding them based on on
those those meetings I I won't be
surprised I don't know but I won't be
surprised if there is some legislation
that's presented this session so who who
knows what comes out of legislation we
had House bill 2 last year so that was a
whole event enough in and of itself but
I think there is more to come on the
advertising regulations but I was just
explaining the timeline but yes thank
you for bringing that up we did give a
briefing to the Senate judicial
proceedings committee last week last
week yeah and they are very interested
in a lot of aspects of cannabis they are
a new committee in the Senate that's
hearing it and we were bringing those
new members up to speed on where we are
in the Commission
if if there's a bill presented on
advertising there are always our
hearings where people can have an
opportunity to speak you can sign up to
speak and offer testimony to the
committee I think you know going back to
the point of why was the band put out we
received a number a great number of
examples of advertising that different
licensees have been putting out there
and you know I can tell you having been
in health care for many decades that
didn't look like health care advertising
to me in some regards so some some is
perfectly was perfectly you know
acceptable from a health care seeing
point but others you know you're kind of
scratching your head and going how are
they advertising medicine so this is
what the commissioners were evaluating
when they were deliberating about the
new regulations behind Brian the
gentleman had his hand up
and everything's everything seems from a
legislative standpoint that is
reactionary its reactionary to a couple
bad billboards a couple of badass but
we're all paying the price for it and to
just be reactionary because the cup
there's a couple of big seeds out there
it's just the wrong way to do this and
we're trying to get rid of the stigma
that's been around forever
a perfect example for me is eighteen
months ago and we were planning our
dispensary people said I have friends in
the business and some idea that have
dispensaries that said to me are you
putting armed guards in your Lobby and
I'm like armed guards am I having a
party and they thought I was crazy and
my answer was I have a ball on my window
I'm telling someone I live in a bad day
we're gonna mom I'm afraid if I put an
armed guard in my dispensary first of
all I want a gunfight in my dispensary
that's the first thing and second of all
I'm not doing anything wrong and it's a
everyone's legal right to phone my
dispensary and get medicine and it's
their legal right that's passed by the
state so why am I going to project this
image I have a Whole Foods down the
store when I met with neighborhood
associations early on draw the money
come you know people are going around
you I'm like you should walk out of
Whole Foods with 300 other groceries
every day my average cells going to be
95 bucks and like people walk out at
Walgreens with oxycottons all day 800
bucks in their pocket they're not
getting robbed so it's this whole stigma
idea that you know we're all trying to
overcome because nobody's doing anything
wrong and when the advertising bands
come and all these other reactionary
regulations come
it just defeats everything everybody in
the room is working for and even using
the Commission and it's being so
reactionary so damaging to our business
we're a retail business like the world
that can't you know that's just one
issue but I feel like until the
regulators and even the responsible I
work in real estate before I did this
and people my honest people that come
out are the vocal minority and so the
loudest people come out of quite because
they saw two billboards they don't like
are the ones screaming there's plenty of
people that aren't offended by
advertising any other so if you know we
need to fight this essay how I got
everyone support in this room know you
know she's nodding and we just neglect
this stuff you go on the stigma keeps
going on and we're going to battle for
tomorrow
well I don't disagree with your comments
but I do need to say that this is a
legal industry in Maryland which is a
state that is right next door to
Washington DC which the regulators in
Washington DC
consider this a Schedule one drug and so
we have those considerations this is not
an approved of federal program like real
estate or Whole Foods or anything like
that so we have those things that we
have to consider as well the regulations
and the examples are not based on two
billboards I will tell you it was many
many many
many many more examples than those than
those two billboards and I actually only
can think of one that you might be
referring to but so you know we have to
keep those things in in perspective
cannabis is available for people who
sign up right now we have 80,000
patients we registered and we have
56,000 that are certified that is less
than 1% of the population across
Maryland so we have to be respectful and
consider all of the state that may be
subject to advertising including
children so we have those perspectives
as well and it's the job of the
Commission to listen to all of the
stakeholders in making regulations it's
not a personal thing you know I'm just
thing I know you have all this
I mean I appreciate that and I respect
that and I know that I just think is if
we let the stigma keep getting projected
through reactions you know we're keep
playing the battle to be called on to
play along
I know you have all the regulations and
I know it's been too long I know okay
Brian you had your hand up I I just
wanted to get a sense of how many were a
great number and I think you just made
that clear
got a lot of screenshots I do I think
that those were I think those were part
of the I thought they were posted but
maybe I'm mistaken it was many months
ago that we went through all that so I
can't remember okay I think what Brian
is Lou into is that if given the
opportunity we would sell police if
there were examples of that we as an
industry were concerned about that a
more reasonable response would be let's
let out let's let's set out the rules of
what is acceptable and what is and
instead of saying you can't talk about
this which is basically what the
recommendation seems
I'm just wondering what health care
looks like to you because you're saying
that certain things don't look like
health care standards to you but you're
also talking about the difference
between recreational and medical and the
same stuff where you have a medical
industry I'm wondering just what do you
expect this industry because for me I
don't think it's pill oh I don't think
it's pills either I'm not a decision
maker so I don't get a vote
I'm you know I think that and this is me
personally again I'm not a commissioner
and I don't get a vote I think it is
entirely fine for people to say I am a
medical cannabis business and here's my
location and here's my website and
here's how you find me I think that's
perfectly fine so for example there is a
growing on 95 that has a billboard
and that's all it says that's literally
all that it says I can only offer you my
personal opinion I'm not speaking as the
executive director of the cannabis
Commission okay one more question and
then we're gonna know that the
regulations on advertising address
pricing at all we do not have any
authority to regulate pricing markets in
Maryland other than the regulations say
you may not give away samples I I'm not
sure where your questions coming from
but I don't think the proposed
regulations address headed off so the
next topic we just finished out 2018
first year 13 months of working in
Maryland obviously a tremendous year
tell me what was the biggest surprise
that came out of 2018 for you that I
finally got a job in the industry
everyone probably hungry
I think I echo this for everybody the
way that a canvas year is ten years on
your life so the work is extremely hard
people think that cannabis business is
oh you're gonna surround smoked cannabis
and tell jokes no it's a lot more than
that dealing with patients ISM is a
responsibility that everybody in this
room knows and welcomes and it doesn't
come to those that don't have great and
I'll leave it at that okay other
surprises from our first year standing I
mean I think to get here but I think we
did it right and I think you know the
testing and all that is great and things
affect we become the terpene profiles
and things to do it's a testament
the fact that we have a limited number
of licenses allow people to spend a lot
of money these and few things right so
joy I have a question I'm going to flip
it what's the biggest surprise from the
Commission perspect all those laughs
here how do I pick only one ah I can
tell you one of the things I'm most
pleased with and it it is a little bit
of a surprise when I started at
Commission Li at 17 employees we now
have almost 40 and I think we have some
of the best talent and the most
committed employees that I have ever had
the honor to work with and I am so proud
of the work that my team has done the
projects that were brought out to us in
House bill 2 were enormous and we ended
up having to hire about six people just
to work on the House bill two projects
they did a tremendous job just just
great talent and very very committed
people to the quality of product across
Maryland so there was a gentleman over
here in the bulkhead Richard Richard
[Music]
well as you know dispensaries were
awarded based on senatorial district 2
for senatorial district or a grower or
and a grower could have the opportunity
to apply for dispensary for any district
that they chose eight of the growers
took advantage of that and so the
Commission in 2016 no yes
2016 awarded a hundred and two
pre-approved dispensaries those hundred
and two are either licensed 71 of them
are licensed or the remaining 31 are
still in that pre-approval stage the
list hasn't changed it's still the same
licensees that were awarded
yeah you're absolutely right and eight
of you who actually met the deadline
only eight dispensaries met the deadline
well there were eight open on December
1st so there could have been a few more
license part okay so well we continue to
meet with those individual dispensaries
and I will tell you that I met with a
dispensary two weeks ago and they just
received their zoning permit in May of
18 we required every dispensary that was
not licensed to come and meet with the
Commission and explained to us and
several of you may have been in those
meetings explain to us the efforts that
you have been undertaking to become
licensed we have to deal with them
individually because we know there are
cannabis friendly areas and there are
cannabis unfriendly areas there are a
lot of zoning boards that took liberties
and changing rules and things like that
depending on the areas that you were in
every one of you knew going into this
there were going to be a hundred and two
dispensaries you have had the luxury if
you will of a non competitive market up
until this time
well I appreciate that because patients
need to have dispensaries that are open
but the original intent always was to
dispensaries per senatorial district
that has not changed there's been no
changes in the program the Commission
has not made any discussion or decision
on resending any dispensary licenses
they I can tell you they have all put
thank you they have all put efforts and
energy into becoming open even though
they're behind the time my last question
is I'd like to hear one suggestion for
improvement and one item or story of
success and what a successful fight to
you okay bourbon more question how can
we help get the more than 50% of the
market that's now thank you to get
certified how can we help you make that
go faster because basically you know
30,000 beat whatever suffering and
waiting to get their cards and event
employees it's been more than two months
so it feels like employees for two
months believe in the please applied for
their cards their medical cannabis cards
and they're still waiting after two
months so they're also potential clients
are you talking about the completed
cards the age of registration
factorization okay more than 50% of our
market now sitting in the queue can
purchase
okay I've seen seems like that lag is
getting longer rather than sure
this massive work flow that's the wonder
if there's any way we can help her help
you know lubricate the process is there
any automated solution versus throwing
people at the problem not an easy one
that fast one no there's a period I'm
working on the automation piece but
that's not going to help us today or
tomorrow or next week this makes us be
paired up with it's not the same product
I don't look for if you apply for a
handgun permit to purchase a gun in
Maryland they give you a flipper and a
preliminary approval after about a week
and then do the real background check
that's deeper after that so if you
consider cannabis less harm harmful than
gums so I think it might be a model that
look at discus to keep people waiting
for months and months when they're
suffering and it so many times been
suffering for decades the pending bucket
is divided among many different
situations one of the situations is we
haven't been able to touch the
registration yet the applications been
put in we we haven't been able to get to
it the other bucket is we needed to send
it back for some reason usually in a
photo that's the biggest problem is the
photo the other is they've received
their registration from us but they
haven't gone to a certifying provider
and then there is another bucket that I
think we are remedying with a new
process is there's a bucket where people
just apply and they never intended to do
anything with the program because of the
fact that people could register without
a cost they would just sign up what we
have seen prior to implementing the new
card ID program we were getting 320 to
350 new applications
today 300 and 350 average about 320
since we implemented the $50 card fee
paid at the time of registration we're
at 200 a day so serious serious people
are now registering for the program and
it's going to help us clear out that Q
so the the pending queue is not all
registrations that we haven't been able
to get to some of them are some are
patients who need to go get certified
some are patients who need to get us
back information I can't I I don't work
that desk I don't I think in from from
my perspective is the is the photo
subjective or is there an automated
something behind it or is it and at a
desk looking at a computer screen
there's criteria about what that photo
needs to meet and there are individual
agents looking at the photo if you've
already got a driver's license
[Music]
we don't get answers or call back where
there's stuff coming in and I thought
think what I was originally told by the
Commission was once somebody is in the
registry because that is already like a
list then those people are going to get
pushed in the front of the line but I
have had a lot of issues with hospice
patients and having them have submitted
but not getting believe it if a patient
indicates on their application that they
are registered hospice patient they do
not wait in the queue that's why we
don't make them wait we do not have that
it's my understanding I'm not aware we
have access to the hospice registry it
is when a patient applies they tell us
they are in the hospice program I would
think access to the hospice registry
would be a HIPAA issue
[Applause]
if you have particular patience I'll be
glad to follow up on them what's that
well if if we know that they're hospice
patients we process them right away
how's that doing it on that on the
registration I haven't is there a filter
on them I'll have to ask this I don't
know what I'm asking because I see the
frustration on this young lady's face
there's a bottom line here but I will
check and see I got a new number today
again the pending hospice will be in the
same this the same circumstance except
we do not require a photo from a hospice
patient but if they have been registered
and have not got gotten certified
they're still in pending if we've asked
them for proof of residency or some
other information and they haven't got
that back to us yet they'll still be in
the pending I'm not aware I'll have to
check my numbers and when I get on my
phone so I can see today's numbers so I
got a report this morning
so joy thanks so much for coming yet
mister this is so it's a pretty
energetic panel and I really appreciate
you coming in today we had a great
session today and thank you for being
here and talking there right here so
thank you for asking
[Applause]
[Music]