my name is Nate Bradley I'm the
executive director of the California
Cannabis industry Association and um the
the topic for this panel here is 2018
January 1 what's next CU as you know
with the State Medical laws were passed
last year the um the date for license
for the licenses to for the whole
process to start was January 1st 2018 so
we're going to get different
perspectives from everybody on the panel
and then we just had our special guest
added on
Congressman Dana roacher who will
be giving us a a federal update on what
he's been working on on medical cannabis
and for cannabis issues for us in in uh
in Washington DC the last couple years
so first let me
introduce everybody else uh to my left
we have uh Boe board
member Fiona ma who has been a
champion we
have I'm also proud to have um we proud
that we have assembly member Reginal
Jones Sawyer who was a a key author last
year to make sure that these met laws
even happened in the first
place and we also have Michael uh
Michael Stevenson from um from um
Horizon water and and environment and
we'll we'll be talking about
the water permitting and and and and and
a lot of those the other issues that
they are working on first before we get
into talking about though 2018 I'd like
to hear from the my my panelist to my
left um about how we got here in the
first place as one of the key authors on
the bill a lot A lot happened over the
last year I mean the bill almost died a
few times it it was till two days before
the end of the legislative session
before we even knew if anything was
happening so why don't you kind of give
us an update of how how how he got here
hi um I'm Reggie Jones Sawyer and I
represent the 59th Assembly District
with the South Los Angeles and uh you
know
now I when I was in college I may have
seen some people do marijuana but
marijuana was not my thing when I first
started in the assembly and what I what
bothered me more than anything else as
someone who worked for the city of Los
Angeles for 25 years and like I like to
tell people I am a recovering bureaucrat
it always bothered me that it took us
all this time for us to come up with
rules and regulations and one of the
first things that we realized there were
many attempts by individuals
individuals who had the best at heart to
create regulation however they just
couldn't get it across the finish line
and so with the other five members um of
what I call the team uh assembly member
Rob B assembly member Ken culie assembly
member um Ken uh Lackey assembly member
Uh Wood and Senator McGuire and myself
we said this is a big big big big lift
and if you know anything about
legislation and I'm sure the congressman
can tell you how difficult it is to get
legislation through
uh it required every last one of us with
different skill sets and different um
parts of California represented um as I
said I'm from South Los Angeles but we
also had Dr Wood who's a dentist but
also was from Northern California knew a
lot about the Growers along with uh
Senator Maguire uh Mr bonter was from
Oakland area Mr kolie was from
Sacramento and is an ordained minister
um and Mr Lackey is a former Marine um
ex- highway patrolman and a republican
so we had a a large constituency that
represented I think most of California
if not all of California and that was
important for us to move this along um
we nickn named ourselves to sexy6 and we
we went at it as hard as you you could
possibly go um when we first came up
with the original um recommendations for
how to regulate U medical marijuana um
everyone had their own ideas of what it
could be we learned early that it wasn't
about we it was about I I want this in
in medical marijuana and I want that
which kind of
alienated a lot of our constituencies
and we couldn't get to a a number where
we could ultimately get it P and so we
made a concerted effort to put in the
bill as much as we could believe would
get past so where where for example I
use Mr Lackey who's a highway patrolman
for him it was very very important for
us to have regulation on when people are
driving while under the influence of
marijuana as all of you know in this
room um proper testing had not been done
yet and we don't know what kind of
regulations we need to do to to make
sure that if someone's Under the
Influence we can we can capture where
they are whether or not they are they
can drive or not and ultimately what
their impairment level is we put in the
bill um research so that the University
of California will go out and research
um different Industries and
methodologies for how you determine
whether or not a person is under the
influence that satisfied him and
ultimately I think it satisfied a lot of
Public Safety individuals who are
definitely against um any type of
marijuana leg legislation and we were
able to to get them on board along with
um several other groups because we went
out and actually talked directly to each
individual ultimately um we were able to
get the legislation passed through
overwhelmingly um in the assembly and
the Senate which the the government
ultimately signed um but what you need
to understand every aspect of this that
we could possibly put in with the
understanding that we would have to come
back with cleanup language was done
because at the end of the day it was
about all of us we make it a
conservative effort to finally have
regulations um on medical marijuana
cannabis so that if in the future if in
the future like November we have uh
adult youth marijuana hopefully that is
the Baseline that we use to ultimately
regulate that now that we know kind of
how how how how we got there um I'd like
to actually hear from the congressman
for a moment sort of on what he thinks
of because we've got it at done we've
have regulations here at the state level
obviously the big question is DC um
we'll talk about Banking and finances in
a little bit but from your point of view
you've been sort of a CH one of the
champions in in DC the last few for for
years on this what change have you seen
and do you think there's hope in the in
the future to get more legislation
passed look we are winning this war it
is a war for people to live their own
lives and for our country to reaffirm
that freedom is the fundamental value
that which our country was founded upon
we are winning that battle when
uh it took a but it took more than just
being righteous or right it took the
right
approach for this issue to get us over
the hump and I've spent what 15 years
voting the right way but for the last
three or four years now we've been
winning those votes and it came down to
this you uh we actually challenge the
Republicans who claim to believe as I
believe in individual Freedom who claim
to believe in the doctor especially
since Obama came in the doctor patient
relationship the same people who claim
that they believe in states rights and
limited government all of those things
are are principles that would lead you
to the belief that mer that the idea
that the federal government should get
between a person and a plant like this
is absolutely absurd and a violation of
everything that we supposedly believed
in Principle as Republicans so how do we
get the Republicans to actually wake up
and acknowledge that because I had all
the votes from the Democrats all along I
mean they by the way that was an easy
vote for them because they were simply
doing what they thought was politically
right for themselves because their
constituency believed that it should
there was no price for them to pay to do
what we consider the right stand on this
issue so the Republicans had to
supposedly buck that and what uh what
happened is we changed the debate over
what the issue was the issue was should
medical marijuana be legal no it became
should the states and the people therein
decide whether or not medical marijuana
will be legal in their state and once we
did that I'm have brag I did come up
with that strategy once we actually did
that we won we won the first time and
every time since we've been gaining
strength and what's been making the
difference a lot of you have made the
difference but let me tell you the
specific people who made who's made that
momentum that Dynamic and it still is
growing on our side first of all the
veterans veterans going into seeing
their Congress person and saying why are
you keeping us from something that will
help us why you know so God bless your
that and
uh you know how stupid was it anyway to
say oh we can't let you use medical
marijuana because it might lead to Opium
here have an opiate you know I mean give
me a break so uh anyway the veteran
groups were important and here's another
group by the way just so older
Americans you know we uh what is wrong
with having an O and this isn't just for
medical purposes what is wrong with
having some 80-year-old person you know
enjoying themselves uh with smoking a
joint big deal
and so you've got you know so we're
going to spend billions of dollars
billions and by the way we'll borrow
them from China which makes it even
worse okay we're about billions of
dollars on something that is so stupid
as that and uh so I mean there's a lot
of things they do stupid in Washington
but this has got to be one of the worst
and you are helping bring rational
thought back to this issue and between
the seniors and and you folks and the uh
I I will have to tell you that I believe
I've talked to Don Trump uh he is uh uh
he will not at least from what he's told
me and others is that if the states
legalize marijuana he is not going to
interfere with the states and uh so I've
heard him say that a couple times but of
course with Don you never know what the
hell he means
so all of that but look we're in this
together we have made a lot of progress
again I think that uh uh this whole
issue over the years has has downgraded
the value of freedom in our country you
know when you have uh law enforcement
agencies who think they can just come in
and take money and property away from
people not even having to have search
warrants or or justification or having a
conviction before they steal property
this is outrageous it's never would have
been accepted by the people who founded
this country and wrote into our
Constitution and wrote Into the
Declaration of Independence about how
they were opposed to confiscation of
property so this is a uh we are we are
the
Patriots there you go we make oh I like
this look at this here he goes make
cannbis great
again I'll try to get this I'll try to
get this to Don right on but anyway it's
up to but as the way democracy works and
democratic government works be very
clear that it doesn't work simply
because the principle is right it means
people have to go out and get that job
done with the hard work of making sure
you're getting the attention of the
members who the people who were elected
to make decisions and then the people of
the United States all I can say right
now and all but the bottom line is the
momentum is on our side
the momentum is on our side and we will
win this but it will won't be one on its
own it be because the effort and time
and energy and commitment that we all
put into this and uh I'm with you thank
you very much God bless you thank you so
much wait one last thing one last thing
okay this is I really have to say this
uh look I was the reason I'm here is I
had a doctor's appointment I had a
doctor's appointment this morning and uh
my plane that was I supposed to go at
1:00 was cancelled so here I am okay and
uh uh anyway I want to at the doctor's
office because you know I spent 25 years
really heavy duty surfing
okay I'm yeah I'm the guy down there hey
man let's go surfing man how about a
dude okay okay I'm the guy out in the
water there having fun for 25 enjoying
my Freedom all right and what I did is I
I exercised I surfed away all of the
cartilage in my arms and I have severe
arthritis so here I am putting on some
of that uh uh cannabis Sav on my arm uh
well I mean I'm really in pain real pain
so here I am I'm putting this cannabis
Sav on my arm and by the way a lot of
seniors who are not Surfers get the same
sort of arthritis pain that I've gotten
whatever it is they've been maybe
they've been working rather than surfing
okay but so here I put it on and it's in
about 15 minutes pain goes away but then
it comes back in an
hour now here's what I want to tell you
I know how these things work had
marijuana or say cannabis been legal by
the way not only would our Farmers be
making billions of dollars growing hemp
for rope and Metal medical marijuana and
you know using for fun marijuana as well
but the the bottom line is I only get an
hour's worth of comfort from my pain
right now had it not been illegal by now
there would have been genetic cross
breeding and you would have had a
marijuana plant that would give people
suffering pain an alleviation of their
pain for maybe 10 hours what a wonderful
thing to do for someone who's suffering
in dramatic pain but to increase their
level where they don't suffer that pain
for hours our bureaucrats have stolen
that from all of these people suffering
from these type of diseases and uh we
it's not too late we'll recapture the
ground and we will crossbreed cannabis
and that cannabis will go to help
alleviate the pain for hours and hours
for senior citizens to come so I just
thought I'd share that thank you for
that
so the next two questions uh first will
be at Fiona and then we'll we'll we'll
bounce over to uh uh Michael in 2018 you
know a lot of these businesses are going
to be coming forward for the very first
time if they're coming to you with with
with tax paperwork with things like that
what kind of things should they have
ready ready to go and what should they
know and be prepared to do when they
come to file their taxes for the very
first time yeah so um
hello hello yeah um so uh my name is
Fiona Ma and I uh started my political
career on the San Francisco Board of
Supervisors uh so like the congressman
said in San Francisco it's all about
relieving pain and making sure uh
patients have access uh to cannabis
that's affordable when they need it and
when we got to the legislature I serveed
from 2006 to 2012 we never talked about
cannabis um I don't know I didn't really
think it was an issue until I got on the
State Board of
Equalization where all of a sudden the
Board of Equalization is supposed to be
collecting sales taxes on dispensaries
and one of my first questions when I got
on the board January
2015 was how much are we
collecting and everybody at the agency
looked at us and said we don't know
and I said well how can a tax collection
agency not know how much we're
collecting from an industry well it kind
of makes sense now right we are not
keeping lists at the Board of
Equalization because we don't want the
federal government to come and say who
is in the Cannabis business how much are
they paying where are they who are they
so we don't keep those lists but we are
also saying you need to be compliant
with your taxes right that is so
important under prop 215 one of the
requirements is if you are a dispensary
you're supposed to get a seller's permit
and collect and remit sales taxes now
some of the more sophisticated larger
older dispensaries have been complying
um so they have been doing you know the
right thing uh some of the newer players
in the industry have not necessarily
been doing that and so that's one of the
reasons we are here is to say you need
to get your seller's permit if you are
selling to the public you need to
collect the proper amount of tax based
on where you are located and then you're
supposed to remit it to the Board of
Equalization um and I think that's
important in
2018 that many of the local
jurisdictions are going to be issuing
the licenses and one of the criteria we
believe is going to be compliance how
compliant have you been in obeying the
laws have you been paying your taxes
right and if you say no but you've been
in business for 15 years that could be a
problem right so I would say it's never
too late to start get your seller's
permit if you haven't gotten it um
definitely you know we have a lot of
information on our website we go out and
give seminars uh I have a lot of um
staff members here who can help you with
that but I think that is first and
foremost there were a couple bills in
the
legislature um this past season and
we're hoping they pass assembly member
Mike Gibson has uh AB
821 to remove the 10% fee on licensed
cannabis operators and as the
congressman knows uh banking is very
very difficult uh for this industry yet
all of the tax agencies assess a 10%
penalty if you pay in cash how is that
fair that you are penalizing an industry
and giving them no other option but
paying by cash so assembly member Gibson
has a bill on the governor's desk right
now if you want to weigh in it's AB 821
to remove the 10% penalty if you pay uh
your taxes in cash um the second one is
also by assembly member Gibson AB
567 which would create a tax amnesty for
any business that comes forward
voluntarily in a certain window in 2017
so if this bill passes there will be a
small window companies uh Canabis
dispensary operators should come forward
pay their taxes for this year and the
last three years to avoid any sort of
penalty now the Boe we can legally come
in and audit you and go back 3
years so if you don't have any tax
records it's going to be very hard hard
to defend uh what our Auditors are just
going to assume is your practice and
what we do is normally we will sit
outside your dispensary and count the
number of people that come in on a 3-day
period and we try to pick different days
like a weekday a weekend you know an
evening um and then they average out how
many people come in to your dispensary
they average about how much they think
they're spending and then then we
extrapolate back 3 years and if you
don't agree with that number but you
don't have any tax records you're
probably going to lose when you come
before us on the appeals board and we
are starting to hear cases now uh at the
um at at our Board of cannabis um
operators who you know disagree with our
Auditors but don't bring us anything um
and so that is just something I would
just like to give you guys a tip about
is you know keep records right if our
Auditors come out you don't agree and
you you have better records you know we
will use your records at least that's
like the
minimum Michael from just switching ke a
little bit from finances to to from
finances to farming yes come 2018 you
know what are some of the things from
your point of view you know that farmers
are going to have to be ready ready
ready to do if they're if if they're if
they're not if they're not doing it now
what should people in in world do to to
be prepared right that's a really good
question and um just by way of
background I work in Private Industry we
work on uh regulation development and
environmental impact reports for state
agencies on regulatory programs and uh
maybe four years ago my business partner
said to me he said wouldn't it be neat
if we did the environmental impact
report for legalization of of marijuana
and California I said yeah that'd be
great we should how would we ever do
that and here we are four years later
doing it so this is a very exciting time
for for us um so we are helping uh we're
right at the outset right now with the
Department of food and Agriculture and
their medical cannabis cultivation
program and identifying all the
regulations that uh they're going to
need to establish and adopt and have
ready to go and Implement on January 1st
2018 um and what I can say is uh as as
was mentioned before with lawmaking uh
developing a regulatory program like
this and the associated software that
the state's going to have so people can
apply for their licenses online and
establishing a track and Trace system
that's going to trace the product
through the whole production cycle
that's that's a heavy lift and uh the
state has a lot on its plate right now
so I would say their primary focus is on
complying with what the statute says
there's a lot of additional
functionality and things they'd like to
be able to do uh that they're not going
to be able to do on day one and they're
going to face that in over time so uh
they're looking at just basically
meeting the requirement that they're
able to take applications and they're
able to issue those uh licenses so um
some of the things that Growers can be
looking for if you are intending to
apply for a license um is first of all
you're going to need to have your local
approval in hand uh if you're going to
be a medical Canabis grower now that
that will change under prop 64 for
recreational Cannabis cultivation does
not require local approval but as things
stand now for medical cultivation you're
going to need to have that approval in
place in fact before you go to the
Department of food in agriculture to get
your license you're going to need to
have every other state and local agency
approval in hand Dem demonstrated that
you've gotten that and that may be a
streamed alteration agreement from the
Department of Fish and Wildlife it may
be coverage under the general order for
the regional water quality control board
uh but basically cdfa is going to bat
last um the second thing I could say is
that um a lot of the requirements that
are going to be um uh placed upon
Growers now um are things that maybe a
lot of Growers have not had to handle in
the past and these are really things
that uh many other businesses are up to
speed on but because cannabis production
has not really been a regulated program
by the state in the past many business
people in this industry don't understand
these and this includes C oia
regulations and workplace safety
standards for Farm Workers people who
are working on the Cannabis sites uh
people who are part of the trimmer
community and are coming for short
periods of time to different cannabis
farms uh there's going to need to be
proper sanitation facilities offered for
them uh places where they can stay so
there's going to be uh in addition to
just complying with the state's
requirements uh for that the department
of food and agriculture is going to
place there's also a bunch of just basic
laws related to um running a business um
such as having your Board of
Equalization uh sellers permit so um so
that's really in brief some of the
requirements one of my favorite
stories when I was first starting ccia
was one of my founding board members is
a rice farmer took me up to his property
and just said you know and showed me his
his his one acre of land he had ready to
go for that one day and and he looked at
me and just said Nate I've been filling
out these Department of food and a for
since I was 15 years old I know what I'm
doing most of these guys don't and we
need to make sure that they know what
what they're doing that they know that
they're you know so they know how to be
in in in compliance with all of this so
that so that way they all don't get just
get mowed down so it's it's going to be
key