with with um with that said I would like
to open it up to uh two two two
questions right
now are you relying on counties to
require an e are you just establishing
an ER to begin with are you doing a
master e or program e or individual IRS
per uh cultivation area can you go can
you expand on that sure yeah I'm happy
to talk about that that's a really good
question so um so the department of food
nag is preparing a programmatic eir
that's looking at the potential impacts
of the licensing program across the
entire State um and so uh by nature of
that that it's a Statewide environmental
impact report it is not going into a
gory amount of detail for individuals
cultivation sites or individual
locations it's just beyond the the scope
of what the state can accomplish one of
the real challenges uh for the sequin
analysis for the environmental impact
report is that uh when you do an
environmental analysis what you're
supposed to establish is the Baseline
what's happening today and then what
what's going to change as a result of
the licensing program and what the
impacts of that increment of change
might cause well one of the things we
don't have is a lot of good information
on what exactly is happening today I
mean we understand how people grow
cannabis but we don't know where exactly
everybody is how large their operations
are how long they've been doing it uh
what the specifics of how they in
particular so Baseline conditions very
difficult to establish uh and then the
increment of change how many people are
going to come under this licensing
program at what size are these existing
operations are they new operations so uh
Department of food and nag has
circulated some surveys trying to gather
that type of information and better
understand um what level of uh of
interest there is in the program how
many licenses are going to come online
so that those are some of the kind of uh
uh methodology challenges but getting
back to your question about local
requirements the state is definitely
looking to local government to address
issues that are most important uh for
the local communities and similar to a
state's rights issue the state is uh
looking at that zoning and land use type
of decisions those are decisions that
are made in City and County General
plans that's really within the purview
of local agencies to comply with a local
noise standard that would be something
also that would a local government would
establish and so when uh when an
applicant comes forward to the state um
and they make application uh the state's
going to be interested to see the squa
document that was done the environmental
impact report or whatever it might be uh
that was done for either the County
ordinance or that specific grow site and
they're going to have to independently
verify that all of the environmental
impacts between the state ydir that they
did and whatever the local government
did covers it now if it doesn't
um then there may be a need for the
Department of food and agriculture to do
an additional more detailed study or
perhaps push back on the on the counties
and cities they have not made a
determination as how to exactly to
handle
that uh there's the full range from
notice my from what I've heard local
governments have gone from everywhere
from a notice of exemption uh all the
way up to a full-blown e and you know
another thing for the Statewide e we we
understand that there's a number of
counties and cities throughout the state
that have outright banned cannabis
cultivation all fors of can all sorts of
cannabis Commerce um our fundamental
assumption is that that may change at
any time and we are not going to be
assuming that just because Fresno County
has a band in place today that ban will
be in place three years from now so
we're really trying to create
environmental analysis and a regulatory
program that's going to be durable in
the light of all the changing
regulations and laws and ordinances that
are
passed um in my in my misspent youth um
I was an assistant deputy mayor for
Richard Reon um and I was a Democrat
Republican my job was a planning Deputy
for him and in that role was to look at
er squa and ways to make businesses um
make squel less onerous on business more
important to try to achieve certainty so
when you go into the process you know
when you're going to come out and you'll
know what you need to do one the local
Authority has uh opined that you're
you're good and ready to go um when I
talk to a and the rest um of the other
governmental agencies I tell them that
let's not keep piling restrictions on
top of restrictions on top of
restrictions because we're trying to
figure out every type of problem that
could occur instead let's think of ways
that we can protect the community but
also ensure that that businesses are
able to know what it will take to
actually open that door and I think for
most of you if not all of you um that's
what you want you're not trying to get
around eirs or neg decks or any of that
you just don't want to get trapped in
some kind of spiral out of control e
that last 10 years or 20 years and so I
I plan to personally work with all the
enti ities involved to ensure that um
maybe for the first time we can come up
with some type of certainty on on IRS
and other things right and and just to
build off that because I think that's an
a really good point is is just the
endless cycle um the way the law is set
up is that the state standards are the
minimum standards local governments can
establish standards that are more
stringent but not less and so in theory
by the time you've come forward to the
state you already have met the basic
minimum standards through complying with
the local requirements which have to at
least match the states now that said
there's a little bit of a chicken or the
egg thing because many local governments
want to have people ready to go with
their approvals on January 1st 2018 yet
the state won have adopted regulations
yet so there the local governments don't
even know what the state requirements
are going to be um there is a first
draft of the regulations it's going to
be circulated early next year and
there's going to be three more rounds of
public review so it's our hope that
through that process people will have a
pretty good idea and can start to get
ready for what the state requirements
will
be obviously the banking issue is a huge
issue it's going to be a major issue for
the State of California so when will we
see action in Congress oh no there is
there's movement all along the front
along a wide front now compared to what
it was uh four five years ago and uh we
I would expect that there to be some
major
Improvement at least lay the found
foundation for this industry's financial
uh status sometime within the next two
years uh and that is let me just note
that is if the
Administration has a positive approach
to it and we don't know exactly what
Donald Trump's approach will be but let
me just make the Republican argument on
this and that is I have personally been
deeply disappointed in what so many
democ rat uh uh office holders and and
people with authority now that they
could do something uh have stepped back
including our own Attorney General of
the United States Attorney General's
office uh I end up look I wrote Into the
law I know I wrote the law that says it
is that the federal government is not
cannot spend any dollars any resources
on over uh on
overriding a state that has agreed to
make the medical use of marijuana uh
legal and how many times ignoring that
do we see the DEA and people from the
justice department going in and
attacking people in medical marijuana
operations and of course stealing their
property uh through you know
confiscation and and it's stealing I
don't care what to say that this is a uh
asset forfeiture is nothing more than
than theft of the worst kind and we need
to make sure that anyway to answer your
question uh I believe now and I hope
again this isn't
just you can't just say the Democrats
are liberals so they're going to they're
going to be on board and help us they
haven't been okay and I've had to write
judges I've had to threaten the Attorney
General the United States this is
illegal for you to do because I wrote
the law and a law passed and was signed
into the law I think that we are going
to see some major reform if indeed uh my
my Republican colleagues can look at the
marijuana business as they should it is
a
business and there is nothing more in
more some people have hurt themselves on
marijuana we know that you know some
people have just uh smoke themselves
into outside of a job you know Etc but
compare that to alcohol compare that to
gambling compare that to people who eat
too much sugar for feet sakes and uh uh
right now they're going to we're going
to have to look at the marijuana
business financially should be treated
like any other business and my darn
Republican friends should understand
what that means there you go
so so thank you Congressman I I hope
it's true two years I uh am very hopeful
but we have to prepare in case it
doesn't um this year Susan Bonia had a
bill AB 2149 that would allow the Boe to
collect the fees for all of these new
agencies who are going to be
licensing um all of you the uh
Department of food and egg the
Department of Consumer Affairs
Department of Public Health Department
of Fish and Wildlife now
if number one there is no banking access
and everyone is still paying cash where
is everyone going to go to pay all these
fees one place in Sacramento I mean so
we are hoping that the Boe we have 23
offices around the state that we will be
able to accept these payments and
unfortunately that bill got stuck but
we're gonna uh try to move it next year
because um we're hopeful but we also
have to prepare and I have been studying
this for a good year uh Tim Morland and
I have been trying we've met with
everyone talked with everyone have gone
through every scenario and unfortunately
until the Congress acts and allows
banking access we are kind of stuck here
in California unless we figure out how
we're going to create our own State Bank
or expand the service
of the Boe since we have been collecting
taxes right for 20 years um so that's
kind of where we're we're at right now
congressman and we look forward to your
leadership okay let me make sure I give
you a specific challenge anybody who
just agreed with the the things I've
said go and see your Congress person
make an appointment to see your Congress
person you are a constituent you want to
be more effective gets a couple of
veterans from town to go with you you
going to be more effective have a
meeting with your Congress person and a
group of senior citizens and some
veterans and yourself go and see them
confront them with what their
constituents are telling them and uh
that to get the business end done we've
got to make sure that that congressman
is confronted by their own uh by their
own
constituents hi there Congressman this
is geared to you I'm kind of a new uh
new mayor I just is reelected again but
we have an issue in Catalina as you know
and I'm sure you've visited us before um
transportation of any cannabis is a
federal offense the FFA regulates it the
Coast Guard the local
carriers um US Post Office so we're kind
of in a quandry as we move forward to
try to get uh medicine to our to our
residents of
Avon do do you have any advice on
anything we might be able able to do so
that we're so that every one of our
patients are not breaking the law I
don't have a u a Magic Bullet on this
this is a we are evolving out of the
most stupid law in the history of our
country and there's no way that we're
going to shoot through all of those
years of idiocy in which in which our
our public officials were spent spending
their time uh trying to control our
private behavior and especially the
private behavior in terms of consuming
uh you know
marijuana uh so that was and as we know
look Canada grows hemp and we've just we
can't even grow hemp to make a rope and
we're denying our Farmers a billion and
a half dollars a year where that's how
much Canada makes for selling the hemp
to us just for rope and not to mention
the other uses for for hemp and and
marijuana and things so look there's no
easy answer I'm sorry just going to take
day after day year after year reform
after reform we got to walk it back and
it's going to take about 5 years before
it's probably going to be a point where
we can all say well this is now
operating like a full regular business
well and then my question is then on
with regards the DEA is there anything
from a Grassroots level on up we can do
to get them to resched reschedule that
as a class one instead of waiting for
them because they just denied it again
well the secret is that uh uh we don't
want them to reschedule we want them to
deschedule
so
so yeah right this is a yeah but yeah I
know that's what you meant but that's
not what they meant I've got to tell you
right now they know that they know what
they're doing and oh yes we go to
schedule too that's wonderful they can
control all of us just as much and uh it
would disaster for everybody who's gone
out of the way to try to help people
especially in the medical marijuana area
a total disaster for the whole medical
marijuana option so uh uh no we listen
we got to walk it back we got to uh what
I just said you guys applauded you get a
majority members of Congress wouldn't
know what the hell we were talking about
and so uh you got to get their attention
go see your Congressman get the Vets to
go with you get the seniors to go with
you and uh uh and other people that can
just talk to them and that's the way you
do it and I'm sorry I wish I could be
more optimistic that there's going to be
one bill passed next year that's going
to solve the financial part of it so but
we will move forward we'll try our best
so thank you very much uh and I and I
just want to offer you know the the
congressman is right about getting the
right-minded individuals in Congress
that will ultimately move on this issue
now I I believe that hopefully after
November there will be a Congress and
the Senate and that the president that
she will be able to make the
changes that we
need to like the congressman
said deschedule it not reschedule it uh
because
ultimately uh any agency will only go as
far is what Congress the Senate and the
president will let them and so yes it's
important to go and in insist that your
elected officials are are on the same
page as you and deal with reality for me
why it's personal because cannabis in
the African-American Community Latino
Community has been devastating it's been
used to lock up more Latino and
African-American individuals in this
country than ever before and it's
another form of incarceration or what we
call the prison Plantation in a lot of
ways a form of slavery
and
we've got to make that change we've got
to get that message through and the
reason I talk about the public safety
aspect they're using it to not
reschedule it they're using the the
harms the supposed harms that come from
it to convince others that we can't do
anything or to paralyze elected
officials and I'll say both Democrats
and
Republicans um to not move on this issue
and and so it is imperative it's
imperative that as alcohol was way back
when was considered harmful and no one
wanted to to bring it
back it is our responsibility to ensure
that people understand what the true
safety aspects of it so that the DEA
will have the Comfort level to either
get out of the way or to advise the
Congress the Senate and the president so
that we can make some substantive moves
on this issue uh my question is
specifically to Mr Reggie Jones this is
uh regarding AB 2385 which I believe you
authored and the ucba have been the
backers of this is the same organization
that a couple of weeks ago in the city
hall meeting were the only opposition to
an opening up the licensing Market in LA
to specifically um allow for a more
diverse market and ownership rather than
just people that work for the 43 or 65
white dispensary owners um now since the
city of B has really changed their
stance on it and are looking to the
community to get feedback and are really
interested in a licensing system uh do
you plan on withdrawing that bill or
amending it so it will be a fair market
to everyone rather than a specific um
say leeway to a very select group so so
measure D is that the one you're
referring
to gives and basically waves the
requirement for a city permitting to the
people that had that were measured de
comped it and it also allows for the
local government the Cil Los Angeles
which I'm from the ability to open open
up the market to others right now they
feel that they're prohibited because of
the the the measure D law and in between
when we make the regulation when we've
ultimately have all the rules and
Regulation and now it gives the city of
Los Angeles especially the elected
officials there the city council and the
mayor and to some extent the City
attorney an opportunity to either go
back to the citizens or to create laws
so that they can become a little more
inclusive um their challenge is they
have as you said they very few
135 dispensaries but they're dealing
with close to 1,400 dispensaries in Los
Angeles and my concern is is is not the
legal ones or the potential legal ones
and the concern of the council are
probably the hundreds and hundreds of
the illegal ones that give all of you a
bad name that that that have been open
we've got to be a little more diligent
and we got to be a little more not a
little more we got to be a lot more uh
responsive to closing those down so that
those of you who are working here will
not be saddled with what they're
doing and that's what measure D is
supposed I mean that's what the bill is
supposed to do and I just like to say
the Boe we love
referrals so you can refer people over
to us I'm just
kidding Dana my question is for you um
and and an extreme amount of gratitude I
have for you for defunding the
Department of Justice from going after
legitimate um compliant businesses
however um we've we're now seeing some
Rogue agencies that aren't necessarily
the DEA um go into other counties
outside their jurisdiction raing
licensed facilities um I want to know
other than a lawsuit what are our
options to stop this from happening
happening it's actually called Trident
um it's a Sacramento County plaster
County and El Dorado County a Tri County
task force that went into Yolo County
with a plaster County warrant and took
down a licensed illegal Farm um 12 days
ago was there was there any federal
agents involved at all cross
sworn your state I don't believe so um
they showed up in unmarked cars and uh
they did identify themselves I don't
believe that there were any DEA agents
present they just pulled in people from
these Three
Counties this is totally
insane thank you
thank they got a bunch of people who
think CU they they got a badge they wear
you know where they go in and act like
like a criminal gang and like a bunch of
marauders breaking into people's homes
you know just you know one of the one of
the things we have a horrible situation
in our country right now and right as we
speak and it's not this it's that we've
got black Americans and law enforcement
in the in a dynamic that's a horrible
horrible Dynamic where they're both
feeding on each other's fear and they're
feeding on each other hatred Etc this is
police the more police officers get
somebody shoots at them the more they
shoot a bunch of people where then shoot
at police officers this is a horrible
cycle and let me tell you the marijuana
element of this is there's a there's
there's an element of huge element the
guy the fellow they just shot the other
day you know oh well hey he had some
marijuana on him well big deal you know
the bottom line is that this law has
done more to cause the hatred between
the police who should be there to
protect people in all every one of our
communities and are but they we put them
at odds with honest citizens and of
course what they say this the other guy
they also said well he had a gun I'm
sorry I'm sure some people disagree with
me on this who cares if he has a gun if
he's an honest person is protecting
himself I don't care if he has a gun and
I don't care if he has a baggie of
marijuana either the bottom line is that
he was no threat to anybody else and the
police a lot of police will use
marijuana as an excuse in the black and
Chico neighborhoods and you know of
course if if a kid from an affluent
neighborhood gets arrested we know what
happens his mommy and daddy get the
lawyer and this guy not only doesn't he
have it's expunged from his record and
and they be lucky if they spent even one
day in jail but in the in the poor
communities you end up with giving a guy
a mark on his record that will prevent
him from getting work 10 years down the
road and ruins his life so I these
people if there are groups of people
running around with uniforms and all
kinds of
badges molesting the people who are not
doing any harm to anybody else the only
thing that's going to do we've got to
rise up and make sure that the uh that
there's some basic change in our country
by the way I thought you were talking
about International things and there's
another look do not give authority to
International organizations
if you think that the oppression that we
suffer here are bad wait till you give
uh Global government the right to do
some of these things what a horror story
so I don't know if I answered your
question or not but yeah and and please
let us know because I'm looking at my
staff and we haven't heard about it and
a lot of times when there's raids in the
community um we do get calls and we're
trying to figure out who it is where it
is who authorized it who was on The Raid
what was the purpose who had the
warrants um um and we have not heard
about this one so um Tim Morin right
there if you can exchange cards with him
um we will follow up on this thank you
thank you next question
last this is the last
question well I want to thank you all
for all the work you've done on this but
I do have one question for Reggie Smith
I met you last year for the grower and
I'm a grower and I'm probably one of the
few people here who's a grower so I need
to represent them the biggest burden for
growers in the Marissa is the
distribution system and we find that
that is going to kill us all the law
says every movement of a product from
one lensey to another lensey must be
done by a distributor is that going to
change because if it doesn't all the
small Growers are just dead in the water
run out of business by the alcohol
industry
so I know when when that discussion came
up there was a
very cognitive decision that was made
about the
distributorship um we can talk about
ways that is not honorous on the Growers
but for for and I'll just use the word
bureaucrat because I I used I was one at
one time
um we have to ensure that the product
gets to the the the sail point that
everything is is not only legal but it's
safe and that we can tax and that and
and that's what that discussion was
really about I'm just I'm telling you
the reality of it um and I'm perfectly
willing after this to talk to you about
making sure that it's not owner on it um
I know law enforcement had a concern
about straight point to sale but we we
get not a butt and we can discuss it
right after this so I can come up with
some solutions for
you I hear you as as an association I'll
just speak on it real quick it's our
number one priority is to fix that as as
as soon as we can the reality is with
the distribution companies who kind of
came into like try and force some of
those issues on there didn't even
understand what they were getting on
them the amount of liability they were
going to have to have so there is a lot
of room to to to move on this we've
already been having discussions with
some of the labor unions who were
working on this and I me and you will
also have some discussions some more
detail but as as a trade Association
that's is our number one priority is
getting that fixed so um and that is it
for questions so actually there's
actually there's one thing I would like
to add to all of this um the topic of
this was what's going to happen in 2018
kind of like you with the goal being you
hearing what might happen the reality is
is you can actually help affect that
change right now the 3 agencies the
department of food and a the California
Department of Public Health the medical
cannabis no no it's B it's they changed
it not bummer it's now can now it's now
it's like big mker um the Bureau of
cannibal cannabis uh of medical cannabis
regulation they're holding stakeholder
hearings up and down the state you can
go to their websites you can also go to
our website CA Canabis industry.org we
have all that data there get involved
even if you can't attend a meeting take
the time to type up what your PRI what
your priorities would be send it in
because they are taking comment from
everybody and unlike in the past of
someone who's been working on this issue
for about six years and I've worked on
local ordinances State ordinances State
initiatives the reality is now these
Regulators want to hear from us I mean
these three agencies that are having to
write your create your your your
licenses understand they don't know
everything they are reaching out to us
on a daily basis I mean my members have
gone through numerous meetings with the
directors of all three agencies so get
involved now and you won't have to wait
to to 2018 to find out what what
actually happens and let me let me just
add that uh the department of food and a
is having scoping meetings tomorrow
night in Pasadena from 4: to 7: and also
uh Wednesday night in Desert Hot Springs
same time it's on their website if you
search mccp cdfa you'll find it uh so
please come out you can talk to the
director of their program
thanks F real quick and then on our
website we do have uh brochures and
information uh specifically to the
Cannabis industry
www.boe.ca.gov and we've also done a
couple of YouTube stakeholder meetings
on track and Trace
transportation and banking which is also
on our website excellent and I want to
make sure DEA Austin could you stand up
DEA she's from my office she has my
cards I plan to be intimately involved
in the regulations cuz that's what I
like that's what I do um and that's what
I have experience in and so I need your
input so that we can make sure that when
2018 rolls out it doesn't harm anyone
and it's the best thing since sliced
bread because we actually want to put
Oregon and Colorado out of
business um
so and and the and and he's not lying I
mean after he passed the bill we had
numerous discussions but he has a lot of
concerns on the way he thinks are going
to look I mean all these
people