why don't we get started here thanks
everyone for joining us today uh my name
is Brian hesterman with Inspire and I'll
be hosting today's webinar and Q a
session uh we're here today to talk
about mechanical systems for indoor
plant environments and as the title
suggests growing cannabis inside a
sealed room is a highly complex
interdisciplinary challenge that Bridges
engineering with Biology
we're adding and removing energy inside
these cultivation rooms to balance and
optimize the growth of living organisms
in our case cannabis plants whose needs
are constantly changing
and through the lens of increased
competition price compression and
shifting consumer preferences carefully
designing the facility will determine
the success or failure of today's
cultivators
it truly takes a village to build a high
performing cultivation facility and for
that reason we have a diverse audience
in attendance today
Architects Engineers contractors
cultivators owners investors consultants
and the network of Channel Partners we
collaborate with every day
today's presentation is part one of a
two-part series and will be focused on
the biology side of the equation the
plant
this will be new content for some and
review for others and we'll do our best
to lay a solid foundation of plant
science Concepts dynamics of a sealed
grow room an hvacd system sizing and
selection with the overall goal of
building better facilities and growing
better cannabis more efficiently
a couple of quick housekeeping items
part two will be on the mechanical
systems and cannabis specific sequence
of operations that we apply to optimize
the plants inside these cultivation
facilities we'll also talk through
setting baselines and expectations for
an application that doesn't currently
have any today's webinar will be
presented by inspires cannabis
operations specialist Anders Peterson
inspires Adrian giovanco will be joining
for Q a after the presentation without
further Ado I'll pass the mic over to
Durst take it away my man
thanks Brian uh hi everyone thanks for
joining me today in today's discussion
um my name is Anders Peterson
affectionately referred to as durs by a
lot of my friends and colleagues I'm a
biologist and have been working in the
Cannabis industry for almost 12 years
now with a focus on indoor cultivation
in part one of this webinar I wanted to
share with you some of the Core Concepts
about mechanical systems for indoor
plant environments that I wish I knew
was a cultivator at the beginning of my
career
but there's really no easy way around it
some of these are complicated topics and
there's even going to be a little bit of
math
so I'm going to try my best to simplify
everything and break it down over the
next 30 minutes or so
and I encourage you to reach out to us
here at Inspire if you have follow-up
questions or want to learn more about a
particular topic
so setting the stage a little bit this
Talk's going to focus on environmental
control for indoor cultivation
not greenhouses
many of the concepts still apply to
greenhouses but they have their own
unique considerations
keep in mind too as we go through this
talk that these are tightly sealed Grow
rooms with no outdoor air being
introduced to normal operation
everything is fully recirculating
because we are also supplementing CO2
into these spaces
and finally our talk today will focus on
the cultivation of cannabis but again
these Concepts can apply to pretty much
any crop grown indoors with their own
you know unique specie considerations
so let's quickly review the main
parameters of plant growth that we're
trying to control in these facilities in
one way or another your HVAC system
impacts everything you see here in the
shoot Zone we have light temperature
humidity CO2 and airflow and in the root
Zone water oxygen root Zone temperature
and nutrients
microbes as well while not essential for
plant growth they should be considered
with their ubiquity in our environment
and last but not least running down the
center of that plant is genetics the
foundation of everything genotype plus
environment equals phenotype or in other
words the genetics just represent the
potential of a certain variety the
better the environment to control the
better the phenotypic expression at the
end of the day
if you want to learn more about
phenotypic expression we actually have a
whole webinar dedicated to this topic on
our website and I believe Brian's going
to drop it into the chat if you'd like
to check it out
now none of these parameters exist in a
vacuum they all work synergistically the
plant's Health growth rate and yield
depends on which of these parameters is
its greatest limiting factor this
concept is called the law of the minimum
and it's often depicted by this Barrel
here leaking water or yield on the right
essentially you are only as strong as
your weakest link like the shortest
Stave in the barrel
and for each species of plant there are
Optimum targets and ranges for each of
these parameters to maximize the plant's
growth rate and yield and in these
Optimum conditions change as the plant
develops from a young vegetative plant
to a mature flowering plant and some of
these parameters the optimum condition
can change on hourly or minute by minute
basis
compared to growing plants Outdoors or
in greenhouses a Grower's ability to
control and optimize these parameters
indoors is exponentially greater and you
can really push plants to their limit
you know cannabis is quite an amazing
plant it will grow like a Toyota Camry
if you treat it as such or it can
perform like a V12 Ferrari depending on
how hard you push it and can dial in and
control these parameters
and so much like this law of minimum for
plant growth the productivity of an
indoor facility is determined by its
greatest limiting factor as well or its
most underperforming system
and in my experience the greatest
limiting factor for most indoor
facilities today is their mechanical
systems or their ability to control the
temperature and humidity of their rooms
not very long ago I would have said the
greatest limiting factor was lighting
but with the advances in LED technology
I just don't think that's that's the
case anymore
and that the Improvement of mechanical
systems presents the greatest
opportunity to maximize the productivity
of indoor cultivation businesses
and this is exactly why Inspire was
founded to develop purpose-built systems
and controls that are at assets and
tools for Growers and not a liability
so to maximize the growth rate of a
plant we must maximize the rate of two
main plant processes photosynthesis and
transpiration
I think it's pretty safe to assume that
most of you are familiar with
photosynthesis the conversion of light
energy into chemical energy in the form
of sugar so I want to focus a bit on
transpiration
so transpiration is the movement of
water and nutrients from the roots
through the shoots and then to the
leaves where the water then evaporates
from the liquid to a gaseous Vapor about
97 to 99 of the water a plant absorbs
through its roots is lost through
transpiration and gets added to the air
as water vapor
so therefore transpiration is the
primary source of humidity being
generated in a sealed grow room that a
mechanical system must remove by
dehumidification
and transpiration photosynthesis are
separate processes but are intrinsically
linked since they are both regulated by
the opening and closing of the stomata
which are little pores found on the
underside of the leaves that have the
ability to open or close depending on
the environment and are where all the
gas exchange occurs so CO2 enters while
oxygen and water vapor escape
as water evaporates from this stomodo
cavity there's what's called a net
cooling effect
as these molecules evaporate they are
taking heat energy with them and the
result is a cooler Leaf surface than the
air around it and you can measure the
leaf surface temperature
and if the leaf temperature is cooler
than the air around it it generally
means the plant is actively transpiring
for example an LED flowering rooms the
leaf temperature is generally three to
five degrees cooler than the air around
it during the lights on period because
of this net cooling effect of
transpiration
and the rate or speed of transpiration
can change it can be fast slow or stop
altogether depending on pest pathogen
pressure the amount of Light how much
water is in the root Zone if the stomata
are open or closed and the combination
of temperature and relative humidity or
what's called VPD
so transpiration this process of water
going upwards into the plant is not
going to happen on its own there's no
magical plant pumping mechanism to force
water up through its stock
instead the water is actually drawn up
through the plant by the environment and
the vapor pressure deficit around the
leaves
VPD typically measured in kilopascals or
kPa is the pressure the environment
places on the leaves to draw water and
nutrients the upper part of the plant
where it can then escape from the
stomata as a vapor I think of this VPD
pressure like the pressure you create
with your mouth when you're drinking
through a straw
technically speaking VPD is the
difference between the amount of
moisture in the air and how much
moisture the air can hold when it is 100
saturated
you can visualize this on What's called
the psychometric chart like the one here
on the bottom left by plotting the room
conditions and the leaf temperature and
then subtracting the associated Vapor
pressures of each condition to get the
deficit
there's an optimal range for VPD
depending on the stage of growth the
plant is in and generally for cannabis
from propagation to harvest we are
talking a range of between 0.5 and 1.5
kPa shown in that table there in the
center
so with a high VPD
the air is really dry and has lots of
room to accept more moisture so the
water in the stomata will want to
evaporate to an area of lower
concentration and the transpiration rate
and water Demand on the plant will
increase
with a low VPD the air around the leaf
is really humid and there isn't much
pressure being placed on the leaf to
transpire so the transpiration rate and
water demand decreases
research shows that the tighter you can
control VPD and reduce fluctuations
during a plant's life the more
productive it will be and significant
yield increases can be achieved with the
appropriate mechanical systems 24 7 VPD
controls possible and can lead to these
significant yield increases
lastly there seems to be a lot of
confusion around dpd amongst Growers
that I'd like to try and address
and it surrounds Leaf temperature VPD
charts and getting an accurate BPD
measurement
so when touring facilities I often see a
VPD chart printed off the internet and
taped up to the wall the grower then
checks the temp and relative humidity
from the sensors in their room and uses
the chart to figure out their BPD
the problem with the static chart like
that is they almost always assume that
the leaf temperature equals the air
temperature which we know is not always
true given the evaporative cooling
effect of transpiration
so they get an approximate VPD but this
can be pretty misleading essentially
most Growers are not measuring their
Leaf temps and factoring it into the
equation
and that's fine if you are in a
greenhouse for example where the
environment fluctuates so much more on a
daily basis than a modern day indoor
grow that an approximate VPD is good
enough
but with the highly optimized indoor
grows with good environmental control we
are pushing these plants transpiration
rates to the limit which increases that
evaporative cooling effective
transpiration and drops the leaf temp to
a greater degree
so look at these two example
calculations
on the bottom the one on the left
assumes the air temp equals the leaf
temperature and you get a 1.2 VPD
and on the right the leaf temperature is
factored in at five degrees lower than
the air temp and now you get a VPD of
0.7
so without factoring in leaf temp you
might think you are providing your
plants a good condition for Mid flower
when in reality your plants are feeling
a VPD more conducive to vegetative
growth a difference of 0.5 is
significant in VPD terms
and so somehow this kind of confusion
around using Leaf temp or not resulted
in the terms air VPD and leaf VPD being
coined where avpd does not factor in
leaf Temp and the lvpd does but in
reality lvpd is the true VPD and the
true pressure that the plant feels to
transpire
and I highly suggest all indoor Growers
measure Leaf temperature
so really quickly same type of example
but on a VPD chart
this VPD values on this chart assume
Leaf temperature equals air temp and the
blue region is a target range of 1.0 to
1.5 and our example room is sitting at
80 degrees 60 relative humidity in that
red box with a VPD of 1.4
okay
now look room is still at 80 60 but the
values on the VPD chart have been
recalculated taking a negative five leaf
temp offset into account
look how the blue region has shifted and
instead of a 1.4 VPD we are actually at
0.9
again just highlighting the importance
for indoor cultivators that leaf temp
should be measured and tracked
and help dictate your set points in your
room
okay moving on
with indoor growing we have all these
growth parameters and plant processes
going on within a very tightly sealed
box and this creates a highly Dynamic
space with a lot of rapid changes to the
environment
particularly
flower rooms generate substantial and
dynamic loads both on a daily basis and
over the course of a harvest cycle
compare that to an office space or your
home where the conditions are fairly
static they don't they don't change that
frequently or dramatically
and to design and operate efficient HVAC
systems we must understand the Dynamics
that are happening in these spaces
throughout a harvest cycle are left
uncontrolled these drastic changes in
the environment lead to poor Plant
Health Quality and yield
growing at the end of the day is all
about maintaining balance within the
system
within the room and within the plant
itself
so from a mechanical System point of
view the water balance in these rooms is
particularly challenging to manage
compared to other HVAC applications
there are not many other indoor spaces
that require as much dehumidification as
indoor plant environments
and this graphic highlights just some of
the moisture dynamics that must be
considered when designing and sizing a
mechanical system there's a lot going on
but all of this can be Quantified to
size the dehumidification requirements
by understanding the plant processes and
the variables that affect these Dynamics
we can engineer a solution to balance
them so for example growth phase and
plant age on the upper left
as plants grow and get bigger their
water demand increases and they
transpire greater volumes of water into
the space
transpiration rates can increase almost
40 to 50 percent over the course of a
flowering cycle so this is where
variable capacity HVAC systems with
modulating components and the right
control sequences become really
important so you don't over cool or over
dry the space during partial load
scenarios
in the middle the photo period also
affects the moisture Dynamics plants
transpire a majority of the water into
the air when the lights are on and they
are photosynthesizing
in a flower room about 75 percent of the
moisture needs to be removed during the
lights on period and about 25 percent
during the lights off period in a given
day
the lights on to off and off to on
transition periods are by far the most
challenging Dynamic shift that a
mechanical system must control as the
lights turn off the temperature drops
and the relative humidity spikes which
requires an immediate and significant
dehumidification requirement
this Spike can be overcome again with
things like variable capacity systems
appropriately sized reheat and
purpose-built controls which are things
that come standard it inspires units
ppfd or light intensity on the upper
right also greatly affects the moisture
Dynamics in the space
as the ppfd increases the water demand
and transpiration rates increase as well
with the newer high-intensity LED
fixtures today Growers are pushing their
ppfd higher and higher to increase
yields and shorten cycle times
so for many years a thousand to 1200
ppfd in flower was the standard but now
many Growers are designing and building
rooms at 1500 plus ppfd all the way up
to 2000 and push neglect limits so if
you are planning on a high ppfd strategy
your mechanical systems must be upsized
accordingly to handle the higher
transpiration rates where you will not
be able to maintain humidity control
so sensible and latent loads are how we
are going to quantify these Dynamic
needs of an indoor plant environment and
appropriately size an HVAC system for a
given room
inaccurate load calculations lead to
undersized or oversized equipment which
both present challenges
for most HVAC applications like offices
residential homes or even gymnasiums
there are published standards for
Ministry organizations that Engineers
can refer to for guidance when
calculating loads
however with the the nasancy of the
Cannabis industry
no good standards currently exist for
indoor plant environments for engineers
to refer to
luckily that is going to change
ourselves and a number of other
colleagues in this working on this
application with industry organizations
are looking to publish those in the
coming years
for now I'd like to go through an
example load calculation and the system
selection process to better prepare you
for your next facility build out
there are two types of loads we must
calculate to size a system the sensible
heat load which dictates our cooling and
heating requirements and the latent heat
load which gives us the dehumidification
or humidification requirements and as we
go through this example keep in mind
that I have simplified some of these
calculations for the purpose of this
webinar and other variables not shown
here are considered when doing this in
practice I didn't want to put you all to
sleep or scare you away with too much
math
so for this example we're going to use a
relatively small flower room
extensible loads include anything that
generates heat we can feel within a grow
room Horticultural lighting fixtures
account for 95 or more of a sensible
load in indoor plant environments
any other Appliance within the space
that uses electricity will also add to
the sensible load such as fans or
irrigation pumps
many rooms also have Standalone
dehumidifiers hung within the space
which generate a lot of waste heat while
dehumidifying the air at Inspire we
design and sell what we call Integrated
hvacd Systems that incorporate that
dehumidification capacity into the HVAC
system removing the need for Standalone
dehus in the room hence the D and hvacd
to emphasize dehumidification
and Adrian will discuss this in Greater
detail in part two of the webinar in a
few weeks
okay for this example we have 32 000
Watt HPS fixtures in our flower room
we calculate the total wattage of all
the fixtures and then convert watts to
BTU per hour which is a measure of
energy in the form of heat
and we get a large number
so we divide by a thousand to make it
more manageable to work with and the
result is
of our sensible load is 109.2 MBH or
what's called Mega British thermal units
per hour MBH is really the most common
use
but if we went with the same number of
more efficient LED fixtures at 700 watts
and do the same math we now get a sense
below it of 76.4 mph
it's a 30 reduction in the sensible load
compared to HPS
so I want to use those in my flower room
they're more efficient I'm going to have
a lower operating expense because of it
so the latent loads are where an
understanding of plant science
cultivation and room Dynamics become
necessary with with no published
standards
we came up with this formula inspired to
calculate the latent load the math
itself is simple but inputting the right
values for each of these variables and
understanding how they affect the system
sizing is why we built a
multi-disciplinary team of plant
scientists cultivators and engineers and
take a collaborative approach with our
customers to understand their
cultivation strategies establishing an
open line of communication with the
cultivators early in the design phase
goes a long way in right sizing these
loads and systems
the result of this calculation gives us
the pounds of water per hour
moisture removal requirement for a given
room it's important that we target the
maximum latent load that room will
generate over its operational lifespan
to Future proof the design and provide
the right capacity
the most crucial step in this process is
getting an accurate total daily watering
rate in gallons per day there at the top
while it's labeled watering rate it's
better to think of this as the maximum
volume of water transpired by the plants
into the air in a day you know for a
given room
seemingly what you would think as small
changes to this value can result in
drastically different unit sizes and
costs that these rooms get bigger and
bigger
the total daily watering rate can be
calculated on either a gallons per plant
basis or on a gallons per canopy square
foot basis the total surface area of all
the trays in the room
the canopy square foot route is
preferred because once these rolling
benches or multi-tiered racks are
installed it is a fixed variable and
doesn't change
while the plant count often changes once
the facility is up and running and
sometimes I've seen it fluctuate by as
much as 15 to 20 percent from the design
phase to what's actually being done in
the field
so why I like the canopy route
so for this example we have our same
relatively small flower room with 512
feet uh square feet of canopy
we have a 0.26 gallons per square foot
watering rate giving us 133 gallons per
day
next we plug that into the equation from
before and we get a latent load of 69.3
pounds per hour moisture removal
requirement so we have that 75 percent
moist removal during the day we talked
about the 12 hour photo period and then
we use the 8.33 to convert pounds uh
from gallon to pounds
so we can also convert pounds per hour
to MBH like in our sensible load to get
74.8 MBH as well and that is the latent
load of our room in two different units
pounds per hour and MBH
and in summary this example flower room
has a sensible or cooling load of 76.4
mph with those LEDs and a latent or
dehumidification load of 74.8 mph
Engineers would describe this room as
having a sensible heat ratio of 0.51
meaning 51 percent of the room load
requires Cooling and 49 requires
dehumidification
most Comfort cooling or human-centric
HVAC applications have an shr closer to
0.85 they they require almost all
cooling capacity out of the equipment
and as a result almost all HVAC units
today on the market have an shr of about
0.85 with 85 percent of their total
capacity going to Cooling and only some
going to demidification as a byproduct
of the cooling process
so this shr here is why we had to design
purpose-built integrated units to serve
indoor plant environments because they
really have a different need than most
other spaces
the final step in the system selection
process now that we have the loads
calculated is to find a unit that can
meet the required capacities that we've
run in our load calcs at the temperature
and relative humidity conditions that
the cultivator is realistically going to
run the room at
these are called the design conditions
during the system selection process
and can lead to over undersizing a
system as well
for all HVAC or mechanical systems it is
easier for them to remove moisture from
the air at warmer temperatures
so as selection temperature and Rh
decrease and room conditions decrease
you need a bigger and larger capacity
unit to meet that load
this table shows an example unit's moist
removal capacities in pounds per hour at
various conditions this is the
performance data for this unit
and from 8270 on the upper left down to
the bottom right to 65.50 following that
green line This unit's moisture removal
capacity decreases by 80 percent
there are significant D rates depending
on the design conditions and the room
conditions this equipment's operating in
but at 75.55 a reasonable condition to
run a room at this unit can do 77.4
pounds per hour which meets our 69.3
pounds per hour requirement from our
example
so this unit would probably be a pretty
good fit at the right design conditions
and has the capacity to meet that late
load now in practice this is done by
software that has the performance data
for every unit at various conditions to
find the best fit for a given load
the design conditions present a delicate
balance between the range of set points
or VPD targets
A system can achieve and the overall
cost of the system
as the design conditions go up the
temperature and relativity go up
the ability for a system to remove
moisture goes up and so the required
unit size goes down along with the cost
but the Grower's ability now to hit all
those VPD targets also goes down and you
lose some set point flexibility and you
run the risk of undersizing the system
and vice versa when it comes to
oversizing lower those design conditions
lower the moisture removal capacity of
equipment gets bigger the unit and the
connected electrical structural support
required the costs but you get some
greater set point flexibility
so you have to find a very good middle
ground to balance these things
you can have the most accurate load
calcs in the world but with the wrong
design conditions you really run the
risk of increasing the capex and Opex
for your project or undersizing the
system resulting in poor Plant health
and yields that are really hard to
overcome uh once the systems are
installed and require a much higher
labor cost to manage
the table on the bottom here are design
conditions I recently got from a
customer for an LED flower room and so
for the lights on period they wanted to
be able to hit 75 50 minimum and 85.65
maximum so as an exercise I calculated
the sensible latent loads for these
rooms and I ran the selection through
that software we talked about at both
conditions both 85 65 and 75.50
and going from 85 65 to 75.50 doubled
the size of the system and doubled the
cost
so at the end of the day we settle on a
middle ground of actually
78.55 for the design conditions for this
room which will allow them to hit 75.50
at the end of the flowering cycle when
they want to when transpiration rates
have started to subside
without blowing up their budget and
getting them too big or too small of a
system
and that folks is an overview of how
mechanical systems are sized and
selected for indoor plant environments
and some of the core plant science
Concepts to understand
I wanted to just introduce to you some
resources if you're interested in
learning more
um on the top there are some of my
favorite books and in the middle there
are some great industry organizations
that are doing valuable work we work
some at least one person in our company
is involved in one of each of these uh
organizations I highly recommend
checking them out and coming involved to
help push this application forward and
as well you can check out the resources
page on our website where there's a
number of other webinars and articles
along with some calculators with these
these formulas plugged into so that you
can you know play with them
and that really concludes today's
presentation thank you for listening I
hope you learned something today and
found this useful we're going to move
into some q a and answer some questions
before we wrap this up and I think
Adrian's going to join me during this
this q a session as well thank you
so let's see here I've got a couple of
questions sitting here in Q a that I
think we can start with that are really
good the first one is uh
do you have recommendations best
practices for measuring Leaf temperature
and particularly how to do it in a way
that feeds into a control system
yeah that's a good question
um you know funny enough I actually have
my high arc on here which is the manual
method of measuring Leaf temperature so
this is an infrared thermometer for
manual measurements of leaf surface
temperature
um a thing to note about measuring Leaf
temperature with some a tool like this
is
every service every surface out there
absorbs radiation at different rates and
reflects it at different rates and
that's called emissivity
and so uh when you get one of these guns
you want to make sure you get one with
adjustable emissivity setting
and an emissivity of 0.97 is conducive
to getting an accurate Leaf temperature
measurement most plants are between
0.95 and 0.98 and all the research I can
found suggests that a 0.97 emissivity
gets you the most accurate measurement
so what I do is you go through a room
and you stand with a gun about 12 inches
away from the leaf surface
perpendicularly that gives you about a
one and a half inch measurement diameter
on the leaf surface and you want to take
these measurements at multiple areas
throughout a room to get a statistical
average of the space I like to do that
in the middle of the photo period like
say six hours into a 12 hour photo
period to get the most consistent
results every day
and then I average all those
measurements and use it to dictate my
set points and how I run my system and
what VPD on that
now about integrating the control system
there are a lot of ways to do this
automatically without a manual
measurement
um
it's especially today as these sensors
in the iot is it you know things has
gotten so much cheaper and so there are
a couple different approaches there are
cameras that try and ignore the ground
and the benches and hit only the canopy
to get a good measurement at the right
angle and then there are also like Leaf
calipers that almost have a little
thermistor underneath the leaf to
measure the temperature you can plug a
bunch of them in around the room those
are both ways in which you can
automatically Monitor and data log it in
a space
yeah Leaf temperature I love it it's one
of my favorite topics so many cool
things you can do with Leaf temperature
in fact I even use it to time my
irrigation events like in the P1 events
of crop steering you can sit there and
measure Leaf temp or look at your water
content in your substrate but as lights
turn on and that starts to drop leaf
temp drops water content drops
transpiration has begun and you can
start irrigating your plants
very cool so and I think related to that
question is can your Leaf VPD change
every couple minutes within a room
with the stable environment
with a stable environment that's an
important distinction if the room
doesn't have homogeneous airflow
then delete the leaf temperature will
vary throughout a space
essentially that the faster the airflow
a plant is getting uh the more
convective uh buoyancy flux essentially
and the
transpiration rates will increase so in
areas of stagnant airflow you'll
typically see higher Leaf surface
temperatures
they can change
but not that rapidly actually so the
reason being is the plants have
developed these processes to balance
themselves and so the leaf temperature
is actually much more stable in a space
than the air temperature is because the
plants are using that stomata and
transpiration that cooling effect to to
bounce it
it's it's that uh concept that plants
are are immobile organisms right we
humans can get up and run if it's hot or
dry or too cold but plants have adapted
processes that allow them to to adapt to
the environment where they are because
they can't move
that's right yeah they've had to develop
these things like stomat opening and
closing to
protect themselves in unfavorable
environments where we can just run away
you know
very cool
my sweater let's see
do you want to uh there's one last one
on Leaf temperature and just differences
between very does it does it vary
between HPS and led Maybe
is a good finisher for that
topic
yeah sure
um so typically because of the
the infrared radiation or the radiant
heat that these HPS fixtures give off
oftentimes the leaf temperature can be
higher in HPS rooms or the offset be
less than in LED spaces but that is not
always consistent depending on the
lighting design and room design so
depending on the mounting height of
those lights
um how big the space is because uh for
example a
colleague of mine an engineer Chris Webb
he he has a great saying that the larger
the biosphere the slower the changes and
the smaller the biosphere the more rapid
the changes and so same thing with these
Leaf temperature and HPS first led with
a bigger space lights further away the
environment can kind of balance itself
and
respond a little bit slower to
environmental changes than in a smaller
space but I've seen in rooms with HPS
lights the leaf temperature be higher
than the
um
you know the room conditions and
therefore that's why a lot of HPS rooms
have to run their their set points a lot
lower to offset that and so one of the
big benefits of LEDs is you can run your
rooms a lot warmer and maintain the same
Leaf temperature and it just saves you
money on your you know utility bills
every month as well from your HVAC
system
and potentially the uh the the capex
spend up front if you don't have to size
your systems as aggressively
that's right yeah you don't have to the
design conditions are more amenable with
LED rooms than HPS to give you that
control
awesome thank you uh here's another good
question what are the advantages
disadvantages of having single or
multiple hvacd units servicing the same
cultivation environment you prefer one
large unit or multiple small units and
why I understand this may be dependent
on particular conditions for that space
yeah that's a really good question I'm
happy to touch on that a bit and I think
Adrian actually in part two in a few
weeks is going to go into greater detail
on that question but really quick
there's pros and cons of each right
having multiple units
um
can have a benefit in terms of
redundancy which is sort of a
what's the right term age like a uh
for 10 plus one it's a subjective term
right what redundancy means in the
Cannabis industry with equipment and so
having multiple units can have its
benefit but it also makes control and
compressor staging a little bit more
complicated and it increases the
installation cost because you just have
more ductwork to run more power drops
more gas drops
and you know can can make a little bit
more complicated but with a single unit
you can reduce some of those costs the
controls become a little bit more
simplified and you know yeah you might
have
less units in terms of redundancy but a
lot of redundancy can be built into a
single unit by adding multiple
Refrigeration circuits so that if one
goes down you still don't lose all your
capacity
um redundant you know and a critical
part uh like spare parts on the Shelf
just in case like and regular
maintenance so it really depends again
it's all a balance between
risk reduction and cost
basically
yeah yeah I think you you really nailed
it there Anders it's it's a it's a wide
range and it's really understanding what
what does redundancy mean for a
particular cultivator or cultivation
business
um really most importantly first and try
to start there understand what the
budget requirements or restrictions
might be around it
um I think this overall system size and
scale offers ability to
um in some in many ways more
inexpensively include additional points
of redundancy into a system
um than it may on a smaller scale or
with a hydronic type system as an
example compared to individual DX type
units package units or split systems
um so there's a there's a there's a lot
of different factors to consider there
and it really is is US putting on our
our owners hat and our fiduciary hat
um as if if as if it was our money and
working together with both the design
team and and the ownership group
um to really come up with the right
solution
um but it's a we see a really wide uh
spectrum of ways to combat redundant C
or backup risk reduction
risk mitigation really as it comes to to
that at the end of the day and I'm
really glad energy brought up
preventative maintenance
um and the the necessity to maintain
these systems these systems should work
and operate as designed for their useful
life all the time as long as they are
well maintained and that you know that
that's just that's the caveat there that
that you really always have to make sure
uh that you're staying in front of
you I can't set it and forget it yeah
just like plants you can't ignore them
they need to be cared for and service to
maintain just like the system serving
them
got another good question here on
the Dynamics of these spaces and the
transition between lights on and lights
off uh given the transition from lights
on to lights off is such a great
struggle for mechanical systems do you
see any reason why it wouldn't help to
dim on and dim off over a period
for instance the first and last half
hour of the photo period so the spike
and temps are not as severe
yeah that's a good question basically
sun setting and sun rising and
sunsetting your lighting fixtures to not
have such a dramatic and drastic uh you
know heat change or heat gain in the
space
um yeah I mean again there's pros and
cons to that from a mechanical system
perspective it can be a con a pro
because you are easing that load in and
allowing that unit to catch up a little
bit easier in terms of its capacity and
ability to
it's speed to hit set point
um however from a plant perspective or
an optimizing a cultivation perspective
every time you Dim your lights you're
sacrificing the total daily Photon
uptake of your canopy or What's called
the DLI and so every time you sacrifice
light you sacrifice yield essentially by
a little bit every time I personally as
a cultivator never been a phantom son
rising in sunsetting my lights I like to
go full bore at lights on full bore
lights off but that's if I have the
right mechanical systems
um
and I just want to maximize that DLI in
total amount of photons that hit my
canopy per day so there's situations for
all of them the way I think about it is
things like ramping up and down is a
tool and so if it requires it
yeah use it as a tool as a grower in
your back pocket if you don't need it
and you can maintain set point push your
plants push them hard and get that yield
that's awesome
it's a great great answer uh got another
one here is our significant heat gain
from the plants that should be
considered in the sensible load also the
sensible calc assumed all light wattage
contributes to the sensible lobe should
a factor be applied if a lighting
manufacturer can provide the actual heat
given off or just assume worst case
scenario
yeah so two questions there both good
ones
um
hey how about I handle the first one you
want to handle the second
sure
so is there a heat gain from the plants
uh for the sensible load well because of
the the evaporative cooling effect of
transpiration they actually have a
cooling capacity associated with their
canopy when they're transpiring plants
aren't necessarily generating any heat
they're actually cooling the air around
them I've actually as an exercise
um
calculated how many square feet of
canopy can equate to one ton of cooling
capacity you know and given like
theoretical Maxes and flowering under uh
of transpiration or a thousand ppfd I
think it was between 150 or 200 square
feet of flowering canopy at Peak can
equate to almost one ton of coolant
capacity obviously that's more of a
instantaneous thing that'll happen and
not be consistently cooling the room
um but to answer your question though
there's no heat gain if anything the
plant's transpiration rates offset
um you know our help the coolant
capacity that's required
that age you want to talk about the
lights and the
yeah I mean I guess I'm yeah I'm
assuming this is this is sort of
suggesting that the drivers would be
mounted outside of the the cultivation
space
um in that situation and um if that if
that is indeed the case then we can we
can take that take that first you know
percentage off I mean what are we
talking about 10 to 15 potentially
um of that overall
um heat load could be you know moved um
outside of the space
um I think it's important to consider
and make sure that you know that you now
need to include that heat load in that
uh calculation for whatever system is
serving that space outside of it
especially if it's a common hallway
Corridor you know
um interstitial type space or something
that could be open to potentially all of
the flower rooms and you know multiple
rooms of lighting at the same time you
know that'll start to add up
um so it really it is important to make
sure that we focus on what is inside of
the space there um and if there's
there's an opportunity to take advantage
of a little bit of reduction then that's
uh that's something that can be done
well and there's also driver losses to
be considered like an LED fixtures and
with hvs fixtures because they're not
100 efficient right and so there's a
number of ways you can get that you get
it from manufacturer
um you can try and reach it yourself
with you know a thick microwave Port
Joule efficiencies and ppf ratings from
cut sheets you can start calculating
these driver losses
I think a thousand watt HPS fixture is
something like 1050 Watts actually than
a day or something I forget exactly
right
okay good deal another question here on
on equipment maintenance what should the
maintenance on your systems look like
how often is it recommended are there
any special differences between your
systems and regular HVAC rooftop units
yeah that's a that's a really great
question I can jump on that one if you
like Anders
um in general uh technicians that know
and understand and refrigeration systems
and packaged systems or split systems
particularly that have hot gas reheat in
them and modulation and as far as you
know modulating compressors modulating
Hot Gas reheat valves things like that
um obviously that that expertise really
is required in order
um you know to I would use that as sort
of some of the early criteria when
you're vetting a particular maintenance
contractor
um outside of that of making sure that
you that you choose the right contractor
or somebody that has experience uh
working on that type of equipment
um the things that that we really find
into there's there's not a whole lot of
things that are so different in general
I feel like outside of the frequency
that you would want to be involved there
um particularly at the beginning of the
facility startup and really
understanding and making sure that the
systems are closely monitored and
maintained during what would be a
typical commissioning type process pre-
first run and then really uh you know
sort of a confirmation and a almost a
recommissioning or retro commissioning
of that system to make sure that through
that first run and once you plant for
the second run your system's still
operating the way that it was designed
and set up
um and a particular item that we see
often is Filters loading much quicker
than anticipated
um or not changing out filters from the
construction and having a lot of
construction dust clogging filters and
not you know not understanding why we're
not getting full capacity out of the
systems
um you know near near the beginning of
that first flower run or halfway through
the first flower run as they continue to
load up um so those are those are some
of the particular things that we really
see often that would be important to to
follow through with and focus on
um and I think you know in general you
know most most preventative maintenance
service Agreements are typically four
times a year like quarterly type
maintenance you know I I would expand
that to every other month or once a
month at least for the first six months
to really use it as a way to get to know
your service provider have the service
provider get to know you and your
facility and your operation and your
particular cycle and needs both during
cycles and in between Cycles
um and to make sure that they know if
there's anything that needs to be done
whether it be any sort of warranty work
or repair work that needs to be done
they'll know exactly when that can be
done and can be scheduled in between
runs in advance so that everybody's
coordinated those are the sort of things
that we find really really uh helpful
one last note there on that question is
another another good opportunity to
service equipment a good reason to is if
you're operating air-cooled DX equipment
in Northern climates or very cold
climates with this equipment being
outside like if it's a package DX you
know air-cooled system and you're going
to be operating that in low ambient
conditions during the winter just
it would be a good opportunity to
service and make sure that everything is
operating you know up to up to spec
before you enter those cold climate
months
yeah that's a great Point yes from a
seasonal perspective I mean another
opportunity situation is like large
large-scale curing drying and curing
potentially that may happen you know if
you if you have more of a seasonal
business where the systems aren't
running all of the year it's really
important to do sort of a you know a a
particular Focus pre you know operation
for the season and then somewhat of a
decommissioning of the system and
maintenance after the season and then
you know again be able to repeat that
cycle the following year
also choose a good contractor a good
experienced contractor with the track
record and commercial industrial trades
it's so critical to the
operation of your HVAC systems
particularly the way that they were
installed and the quality of the duct
work and uh reducing the static pressure
along those duct runs and
um we've seen good and we've seen bad
and uh it can have a very
they can play a very critical role in
the performance of your facility even if
the HVAC units are right-sized yeah
that's really great really great points
I mean it's you know that design is
perfect on paper until you get it out
and install it out in the field right
and and so you gotta you gotta make sure
you maintain those standards
um and uh we have a great a network of
service technicians um and service
companies across the country that we'd
be happy to refer Partners to
here's an interesting one uh what is
your team's perspective on how
Standalone dehumidifiers slash split
systems measure the room temp and Rh and
how does that impact the Growers
perspective on how the room is operating
standard dehumidifier some split systems
measure the room temp I think another
way you could think of that is
regardless of the type of system
measuring a room I think what you're
trying to get at is how does the
accuracy of a sensor the quantity of the
sensors in that room and the placement
of sensors affect a Grower's perspective
on how their room is operating and that
is a very important uh a very good
question and a very important point if
you have a single sensor hung in the
middle of the room and you're operating
you know thousands of canopy square feet
off that you're not going to have a very
good statistically significant picture
of what's going on in the space so
ideally you want to have sensors within
the canopy that are protected from the
radiation influences of the lighting
fixtures and protected from moisture or
damage from staff
and aren't completely surrounded by wet
plant material we want a representative
picture of what the plants are actually
feeling so as close most of the canopy
as possible to get an accurate
measurement and then having a number of
those throughout a room to then get an
average and run your systems at is much
better than operating off of say A you
know a thermostat that's built into a
mini split hung up on the side of the
wall I mean the conditions on the side
of the wall are not what I'm trying to
control I'm trying to control the canopy
so that's where I want my sensors to be
and also if those sensors are skewed and
not near the canopy then we're not going
to get an accurate VPD calculation at
all right and so getting those good
averages from the
broom conditions as well as the leaf
temperature and the space will get you
the most accurate VPD calculation and
then also having sensors that are
calibrated
um you know we use like nist what were
they like nist calibrated uh handhelds
you know these like
the calibrate every sensor and you know
everything so it's very important to
You're only as good as the data you
collect and measure you know and
if you're not getting good data then
you're making bad decisions I actually
think a lot of Growers perceptions on
how they were operating rooms 10 years
ago like myself were skewed based on
that information like I think we thought
we were running a room a certain way but
in reality it was a way different
condition than we realized because we
didn't you know back even 10 years ago
sensors and controls were significantly
more expensive so now with them being
more affordable we can get better and
more information cheaper and get better
results
yeah that's really really exciting what
what the Innovation is going on on that
side of it and the ability to
ability to get accurate data
yep it's uh amazing the difference
between uh the reading from a thermostat
on the wall versus uh temperature sensor
in the canopy what we'll read
and uh
and throughout your space and it's you
know it's more things that we'll we'll
touch on in part two around you know
sensor density and and the data as well
as airflow
um through the space but you know
there's really you know outside of going
through and checking on your own
periodically
um you know you don't have a way to know
how homogeneous that that uh canopy is
want to thank everybody for attending
today and all of the interactive
excellent thought-provoking questions
that came up
um of course Anders and Adrian thank you
for uh participating for presenting
today
thank you everyone really appreciate
your attention and for joining us today
thank you
[Music]