so my name is wait laughter and
among other things an advocate for
medical cannabis and it's my pleasure to
serve as the person who's going to
moderate a discussion between forests
third and dr. Stephen banister and I
personally am very thrilled to be doing
this because these are two of my
favorite people
dr. Bannister has been in medical
practice in our community for 42 years I
think you said and 20-some years of that
22 years more or less he has risked his
medical license because the California
Medical Board gets nervous about doctors
who actually practice with the cannabis
advised people to use cannabis and dr.
Bannister has for the last 22 years at
Highland Springs then helping patients
understand how to use cannabis in
treating the conditions that they are
subject to and that has been a scary
thing at times I would guess as he says
the the Medical Board can get nervous or
jumpy any time forced hurt I don't even
know where to start this gentleman is he
comes to medical cannabis out of direct
personal need in his own family and his
son is subject to most of the types of
seizures that have been identified in
the time that I've known for us that's
coming on for years now there have been
months at a time when Silas was free of
seizures thanks to certain cannabis
medications that we had access to and on
the other hand especially in the last
few months it's been a pretty relentless
nightmare of ongoing seizures and in the
midst of all of that in his own life he
has made time and space and put effort
into creating an entity called the
khalad rias Network which has been
providing cannabis preparations to
families
at no cost to those families and many of
those preparations are custom formulated
for the needs of those children and in
order to qualify for khalad Reyes the
child has to be in a situation of what's
known as catastrophic ly ill which means
Western medicine does not have an answer
for this condition and it is typically
fatal and that's enforced yes so today
what I'd like to do is hear from these
two people about the state of medical
cannabis in California today and some of
the exciting possibilities that are out
there of in therapeutic possibilities
and some of the dilemmas that are going
on and so with that
who what do you think guys who wants to
start I'm gonna shut up for a minute oh
well thank you
and we'll see what we get from there so
as Wade mentioned I started researching
medical cannabis very seriously about
seven years ago and with my son was
diagnosed with a condition called
lennox-gastaut syndrome which is
considered a rare catastrophic form of
epilepsy because it really intractable
type of epilepsy meaning it doesn't
respond medications they totally had
multiple seizure types to documented ten
different types of seizures and many of
these don't even really have a name with
him and you know he went from a healthy
boy - you know he had his first seizure
it was you know a matter of weeks not
months when he had his second seizure it
was a matter of months you know not
years when he was having seizures every
day and within a year year and a half he
was having hundreds of seizures a month
yeah by the time he was five
he was having around 2,500 seizures a
month so we just watch this is this
rapid decline and I had worked in
pediatric mental health for 15 years
with it's with different mental health
conditions environmental and genetic
causes of different mental health
conditions and you know my son became
ill that took years of experience to
really researching where the science was
connect dial because at that point they
didn't think he was gonna
at all they told us we would never live
to see they attend how could they say
he's 12 now but that that's how I came
into it so I studied it a lot more
feverishly the maybe most because and
out of that experience we started
working with local politics trying to
measure W hearing about how we defeat
you which we were able to do and that
type of attention that attracted other
families with similar types of kids
wondering if they could get help because
we weren't able to get services seizures
after a lot of work a lot of different
cultivation of specific strains of
plants to stop at one point they stopped
for six seven months and even with the
seizure she's having now compared to
2,500 miles we still have on average by
the 90% seizure reduction now my because
10% of 2500 is still a lot of procedures
right but you know if we're talking
about statistically as far as other
anti-seizure drugs and success rates it
blows every other context you throw them
in the water
considering they had zero that 90% is
pretty pretty incredible so the
coagulant worked was performance of
collectors like a lot of medical patient
collectives and what a lot of people
don't realize is when passed Proposition
64 we sunset the clock so it was a
constant SB 4:20 that was sunset to
expire on January
to 2018 so the collaboration will the
VCC was supposed to write laws and
nonprofits they said they were too busy
and didn't have time to get it finished
so Governor Brown allowed them to push
that date back to January 19th of 29th
of January 1919 but he didn't push back
the sunset at the collective model cuz
they were on the same day so what's
happening is the collaboost network was
forced to shut down On January of this
year in the time that we were working
what we were doing was working with you
know terminally ill children so
intractable epilepsy cancer and I worked
really hard with the skinny and horrible
skin condition called epidermolysis
bullosa which is probably the worst
thing I've ever seen in my life
if you look it up fair warning it's hard
you don't see it what these kids are
going so we were working with with
horrible diseases where kids typically
don't work out of their teens cancer
treatment and we were able to collect
front of the farmers here in Nevada
County we were able to collect donations
we ran programs at two for Tots program
to give pharmacists without to plants
and we collect them we were able to pick
those in do the extractions ourselves we
had a lab in Sacramento that was
voluntary new testaments we're able to
get all that safety testing done and we
I would make the preparations based on
the lab results in our kitchen for these
kids individually
especially with rare epilepsy
they really needed a specific
formulation for that specific ring we
get him to that point that is later and
I'm proud to say we worked publicly for
two years so we ran senators family some
parents belong a good man but when we
got to shut down I'm replying to the
breath and went back and look we were
able to donate 1.2 million dollars worth
of medicine to over a hundred over 150
of those families who wants to work on
home talk now the question was and I'm
getting to the point I promise what's
the current standard of medical cannabis
yeah I think that backstory is important
to understand actually how the same
about disease is true because it's not
one that we hear very off from my
perspective a no medical cannabis is a
spectrum right for a lot of patients
with with conditions that are treated
with simple or easy treatments like
flower wilting flower medical cannabis
is no good because here we have a lot
more access in legality than they have
before when we get into catastrophic
illness the illnesses that I'm used to
working with that my son has
it is worse now than it was
- it's hard now it's more dangerous now
as far as the legal ramifications then
it was since before proper 15 to 15 was
back and I think I'll let that hang
there for a while and talk about why
that is
it's we move on but as of today it is
there's no legal way at all for myself
to give the medicine silencers let alone
the individual meds all those other
children use yeah I think yeah prop
you sure that we really understand what
he just said yes the regulatory
framework called legalization in
California this is one of the unintended
side effects or consequences of what
legalization has done all of the
compassion programs of any sort in
California are facing the same
predicament that calabria network is and
what's really tragic about it is the
need for these preparations has not
stopped just the opportunity to do so
has become again Federalist in the
legalization framework so I'm gonna stop
and I would invite dr. Bannister now to
share with us we turned it on then
that'd be different all right that's
different
thank you wave at me back there go hey
you're not on the drug policy Alliance
is one of the several nationwide
advocacy groups there's several of them
I like most of them Marijuana Policy
Project all that anyway I just got this
from the drug policy Alliance in the
mail and it says marijuana is not legal
we've seen gains however marijuana
arrests for possession increased to six
hundred thousand and twenty seventeen
that's one arrest every 53 seconds so in
two hundred forty seven million people
still live in states where marijuana is
not legal so as forces and access to
this hugely difficult people have moved
to Colorado from Tennessee and all over
the country that their kids could get
some CBD which is the predominant one
that has helped see predominance of
these difficult seizures so yeah we
we've gotten part of the way but we're
still another huge
mess and that's yeah it's not good
so the Mike I didn't know what audience
I was gonna get to talk to you today so
maybe I'll find out as we go along with
small but mighty and one of the things I
wanted to put out is that I think
cannabis is the future of medicine and I
think there's ways to get there and the
ways are very important as we're seeing
the ways that we're going is not always
working right now it's working against
forests and these kids so that wasn't
the intention was to make this more
difficult but that's what it's doing in
this situation the the the way it
becomes the future of medicine is that
cannabis is so extremely useful so I've
been a doctor 46 years I've been every
kind of doc a ER doc and a family
practice doc and whatever and I've
treated most everything and I've treated
things with regular prescriptions and
and herbs and acupuncture and every damn
thing I could think of I found kenick
cannabis to be the most useful and safe
medicine I've ever used
you