speaking about how things have to be
helpful like I've seen a lot of
advertising when they were trying to the
OE so the question was we still face the
stigma as cannabis and is it helpful
versus harmful essentially and yeah
application is our is is our biggest
Boulder you know there's just a real
lack of everyone has a strong opinion
these days and not a lot of information
and the less information they have is
stronger their opinion it's the
dunning-kruger effect of the world so so
yeah it's really difficult and it's just
I don't know I mean I could talk for an
hour just on that alone but yeah I'm
sure you experienced as well same things
going on with vaccines is a lot of
disinformation so I'm doing exemptions
and I'm just getting fought like Oh
vaccines are safe and effective that's
the end of the story well it's not so
anyway with this it's it's if you really
research cannabis you'll find out that
it's very safe and effective but and we
keep running into the stuff like it's
not legal and and force getting blocked
because Governor Brown wants his taxes
and all that kind of craziness it's like
wait a minute wait what about these kids
so yeah I will say I will say also
though that that's like charities and
attach mark is so important because that
all changes when your loved one gets
sick so I've had people from the
Sheriff's Department who yelled at me at
one meeting and called me two months
later when their nephew started seizing
and we help them secretly because
they're afraid I've had families from
Beale Air Force Base call me terrified
they're going to give
that's scared for their loved ones life
I've had families from the fire
department churches or they're afraid
their church group it's a cultural thing
that really shelters they shelter
themselves against being educated about
it unfortunately and when they come to
us we help any child like you know say
no to right so what I will say is as
that happens their paradigm shifts
immediately when they start to see
results even if you know not a canvas
isn't magic it doesn't save every life
but it improves their quality of life
especially to those with terminal
illness so the kids who can smile again
ease their suffering even though they're
not gonna make it some brain cancers
very well success rate but the
difference in those days it's just as
powerful it's not all about if if it's
not gonna save you don't do it there's
something special will be said for just
easy suffering in our communities and
when you experience that firsthand all
that silliness goes out the window the
problem is the people with the strongest
opinions said who end up harming the
most people with those misinformed
opinions they haven't had those
experiences you know and it's very
difficult to teach that without that
person and experience especially when
they're unwilling to listen we have time
for what do we got
[Music]
okay well so high camera so we're shut
down
we can't I can't accept donations but
with that being said you can't give away
candidates in in products in California
and what we have to do and I'm still a
father whose son needs medicine and I
know a lot of families who do need
medicine so I think that legally we can
absolutely connect donations with where
they need to go it's just extremely
cumbersome because we can't function as
the middle man for that to help
facilitate that process so so what I
would say to people who want to donate
cannabis there's always someone who
could benefit from your gift and I think
that working with cannabis that's rooted
in the spirit of working with cannabis
whether it's kids what you know what's
your passion whether it's veterans
whether it's seniors whether it's
hospice care right whether it's mental
health there's somewhere that you could
take that work and a portion of that can
benefit and uplift your community and so
there's ways to do that and it's just
connecting with the patients and if you
have things that you'd like to get with
to families of kids who need it I could
we could connect you in a way where we
could do that legally and responsibly
I would like to make a comment see if
you guys are both comfortable with it
one of the things that I think is really
good about this being the first panel or
one of the first discussions of this day
is the medical use of cannabis really is
at the heart of cannabis the
legalization efforts that's happened in
California over the last 20-some years
started because of the medical benefit
of cannabis people's direct experience
showed them that the prohibitionists
propaganda was right in my
language and we've moved the
conversation a lot not just here in our
local jurisdiction but across the state
and across the world for that matter and
its medical that's helping to change
that story and we all appreciate I
appreciate the as it's called
recreational or inspirational aspects of
cannabis but the real movement on this
question around prohibition had to do
with legitimate medical use and one of
the real tragedies of California
legalization is despite 20-some years of
actual practical experience of seeing
cannabis work as medicine state law has
basically dismantled all that mechanism
that was created across our state and
you as individuals can reach out to your
elected officials both locally and at
the state level and make them aware of
this problem like I said the need did
not go away just because the rules
changed and they are supposed to listen
to us they are our representatives but
you need to stand up and speak for some
of these families some of our children
who need this as medicine and pardon my
little rant there but one last thing I
want to say is in the conversation about
CBD I wanted to pop up and just say I
tend to think of CBD and I've been
playing with it for a number of years
and
it is the part of cannabis that helps me
and others feel good there's nothing
wrong with feeling good it's actually a
good thing and there's way too many
things in our life that want us to feel
bad and scared and driven and this plant
is in fact truly a killing plant and so
that's I guess all I got on that and I I
would ask if either you want to say
anything else before we wrap up any
questions about anything else that are
we out of time or interest or where are
we at this point technically late
so so let me just try to wrap up with
some thoughts
one is that cannabis can treat darn near
anything especially if you know what
you're doing the research is coming
along slowly but surely a lot of its
overseas Israel is a real hub of good
research I've got some good research on
the effects of cannabis and autism and
in dementia and in a whole lot other
things and it's really looking good so
that's great we've got all these new
cannabinoids being discovered as we go
along I think one of the things that
needs to happen is that these plants
need to be bred for higher whatever it
is CBG as an example higher Mersin which
is one of the terpenes and all that so
that they're more effective CBD plants
are way more effective than then the
ones that didn't have any CBD in them
for CVD purposes or what about CBG
purposes or cbc all that all that stuff
what about the terpenes and all that's
anyway I'm looking for those of you that
are interested in this to keep looking
at this and go okay what's the next CBD
and how do I read it and grow it and
make it available at a decent price
because you will benefit well so will
the patient so we could have better pain
relieving cannabis better
anxiety relieving canvas a lot better
sleep cannabis then we have I think
wouldn't you guys with me on this and
okay good
looks like they're in agreement so good
I didn't go way out before good so
anyway that's where we need to go and
I'd say if you're in the game study some
of the science about this and see okay
yeah and if you need resources on that
you know talk to me or forest or wait
and there's some pretty good stuff out
there thank you so much
[Applause]