[Music]
hey everybody this is jason wilson with
the curious about cannabis podcast
thanks so much for tuning in once again
today i'm really really stoked to
have the guests that i have on today i
have dr janila chin someone that we just
recently became friends
we have a lot in common and i'm really
excited about our conversation thanks so
much dr chin for being willing to come
on the podcast
thanks for having me jason i'm looking
forward to this
yeah totally um so for those that
aren't already familiar with you um do
you mind starting us off by just
explaining a little bit about
your background and how that led into
working with cannabis in medicine and
then we'll just kind of spin off from
there
all right well about a thousand years
ago
right yeah i feel like it's so long um i
was a i was a patient
actually before i even became a
physician a medical doctor
um i was diagnosed with ankylosing
spondylitis
when i was a teenager and it's a
fancy big fancy name it's also called as
for short
and basically what it is is an
autoimmune disease of the spine
it's an inflammatory disorder there's no
cure
there's really you know no no treatment
that
that is long-term it's really just
maintenance and palliative care
and what ends up happening is your
vertebrae so the bones in your spine
start to fuse together they literally
crazy glued together and you lose
mobility
yeah so you might you might see people
on the street where they look like they
have a big rod in their back and they're
sort of turning
you know with their whole body they
don't have much range of motion
right and usually those are patients
with as
and i went through conventional
treatment as a teenager and
as a kid i had a lot of pain
but i did you know normal prescription
medications
i went to physical therapy for many many
years
did acupuncture um epidurals
i did a lot of injections and trigger
point injections but nothing gave me
long-lasting relief so i wore a back
brace while i was in medical school and
this was in san francisco
i went to school shortly after they
legalized cannabis in san francisco
uh in california and i would wear this
back brace all the time
while i was doing rounds and one of my
attendings pulled me aside and said you
know what's going on why are you
wearing this brace you're having a hard
time standing you know assisting in the
or
you know delivering babies i see that
you're sort of standing on the side
trying to sit down and you're in a lot
of pain
i told them i had a yes and that i was
really
disheartened i was really sad because
here i was training to be a doctor
you know i had at my disposal you know
hundreds of specialists
i was in this great university and no
one could really offer me any relief
you know it was sort of the same
revolving door you know here's another
prescription
have you tried an epidural have you
tried steroids
yes yes you know and there's a lot of
meds that i couldn't take
you know when you're working in the
hospital or you're studying you can't be
sedated you can't be altered in any way
so um surprisingly he pulled me aside
and this was an hiv and aids doctor
and he handed me this bottle okay and he
said
you know don't tell anyone i'm giving
you this don't freak out
but um this is marijuana this is
marijuana that's in a tincture bottle
and it helps my hiv and aids patients
with pain
he didn't call it cbd oil or anything
fancy like that he just said it's
marijuana you know steeped in alcohol
take it before you go to bed at night
but it really helps my hiv and aids
patients
um and i completely freaked out you know
i grew up in the bronx
and i grew up in a very traditional
chinese household
so there was a stigma surrounding
cannabis you know i
was a pre-med i had my eye on the prize
i didn't really experiment with cannabis
a lot but i knew
and he said it too he said you know
you're you're gonna work
80 to 100 hours a week and you have a
long way to go
and you really are not going to make it
you know with just this back brace
so i sat with it on my dresser for weeks
on end and i stare at it and i
i finally took it i took it over the
weekend when i wasn't on call
and to my surprise it did make me feel a
little funky
it reminded me of when i first had a
glass of wine
you know a little i got a little flushed
but nothing crazy
but you know by the time the weekend was
over by monday morning i knew something
was working because i was able to stand
and do the dishes
without the back brace i was able to do
some some light household chores without
you know pain
and i went up to him that next week and
i said what is in this
i said what is this and how come more
patients don't know about it
and he started explaining you know
cannabis to me and and you know what it
is what it isn't
um you know he basically took me aside
and he says you know there's this
journal club that meets there's other
mds
you know if you want to start learning
about this plant you know let's uh by
all means
let's let's start looking at these
different cases and i made it a point
for my career to learn everything i
could about this plant medicine you know
and this was
you know in the 2000s so you know a lot
has changed since then
but patients found me i didn't have to
advertise i integrated into
my holistic uh family practice and word
spread fast
because patients could appreciate the
fact that they could
tell me about cannabis usage tell me
about their other medication usage
without feeling
like um the doctor was going to dismiss
them from their practice
yeah yeah and that's
you know one of the huge challenges that
it seems like
you know we face right now with cannabis
is
getting people to one to get the doctors
and nurses educated
to know how to respond when someone
comes to them
saying you know i want to try cannabis
or i am using it you know
but then also on the the patient side to
have that
um sense of safety um
with the physician to be able to just
honestly share
what they're experiencing what they're
experimenting with and everything
um because i think uh and tell me if you
agree but there's a weird dynamic that's
happened in our health care system it
seems
primarily based on my own experience
that um the patient and the doctor don't
always feel like they're on the journey
together
um and so the patient even though they
may have
you know their primary care physician or
their specialist that they see regularly
they don't always
feel like i don't know they feel very
alone in their pursuit of wellness and
trying to
to get better um and so it's almost like
this
uh like the cannabis piece is sort of
raising a bigger issue in
healthcare broadly that stems from how
stressed a lot of doctors are
how limited amount of time they have to
spend with patients
um you know all these these other pieces
as well
um that i think we need to like really
seriously look at if we want to
improve our health care system and have
people feel that sense of trust again
with their
physicians and i know that i went
through a very similar
experience so i have like multiple
spinal cord injuries
and so i've been through i've worn the
back braces i've been on steroids
you know i've you know been on all of
these things i totally understand
and one thing that um before you and i
had ever talked i felt this
um like connection with you because i
saw
on a i think it's a different interview
or something you talking about your
personal background
i was like oh my gosh i've been through
at least a piece of that
and the same way i discovered cannabis
as a patient
before i ever got involved in like uh
testing labs and research and all that
sort of stuff and it was through a very
similar
sort of thing i was like literally stuck
to the couch couldn't move
had these like back spasms and extreme
pain felt like someone was like driving
a knife and my
spine you know just crazy so i can
i can very much relate to um you know at
least to some extent
of what you went through because it's
traumatic going through that process of
like
how do i find relief with a chronic
condition like this you know
um without being just knocked out all
the time it's really hard
absolutely and it ha takes a huge toll
on your nervous system
um you know you're you feel like this
can't be my legacy
i cannot live like this um and and we're
young
yeah you know we're young and we're you
know when you think of someone with
chronic pain you think of grandma
you know that's in their 80s or 90s but
chronic pain
you know hits even teenagers i see with
overuse injuries through sports
um through a lot of genetic disorders as
well
so you so being a chronic pain survivor
i really know what it's like when you
tell the doctor
i've tried everything and it doesn't
work
you almost don't want to go to the
physician because you know the the
things that they're going to offer you
right it's either surgery um
prescription medications or pt
yeah yeah exactly right you're like i've
heard the story
multiple times oh you want to do another
mri okay
yeah exactly what's going to change you
know my pain is my pain
yeah um but i mean really i think
this whole medical cannabis movement is
a wake-up call to our health care system
you know patients are turning away from
mainstream medicine
you know they're heading to forums to to
listening to podcasts like yours on
places like um
wendy's shop artemis um cbd shop because
they're giving them what they need you
know they're you know you
um as an advocate um they're listening
to these podcasts they're connecting
better
and they're looking for a more natural
approach to health and healing
yeah exactly and so coming back around
so you were
you're in medical school you discovered
cannabis
and were able to start to function
better
um where did your path lead after that
um kind of how did the rest of your
medical schooling go and then where
where what did you specialize in
so i specialized in integrative care
so what i knew was i i understood
that you know cannabis was part of a
holistic movement
and that it wasn't going to be the
end-all be-all even for myself right
i knew that when i integrated cannabis i
then i could get up off the couch
then maybe i could give a breather and
take my back brace off for a couple of
hours
but i needed to utilize those hours and
exercise you know do some foam roller
exercises maybe take a trip to the
acupuncturist
i'm an osteopathic physician so i also
use my hands to help heal patients i do
manipulation
you know i work on the fascia and the
tendons and the ligaments
so hands-on approach for patients
so so cannabis breaks that storm you
know it sort of parts the clouds a
little bit
and then it allows you to do other
things um
you know for me you know losing weight
was a big thing i had to lose a lot of
weight i gained a lot of weight in
medical school
you know the freshman 15 became the
freshman 50 right
right you know because when you're in
pain
you eat for comfort and
and you know that ice cream that hot
chocolate just feels so good
right when you're sitting on the couch
but you know an anti-inflammatory diet i
talk to my patients about it
i have a background in nutrition so
that's a really really big thing
so i incorporate all these different
modalities with my patients and i'm
realistic
you know might not all happen at once
but maybe it's a start with cannabis
medicine
and it's a 10 minute walk you know
getting those lymphatics moving
or maybe it is a massage you know
something like that so i
try to work around the patients and
that's how we created our integrative
health centers in in california and can
you
briefly describe to anyone listening
that's maybe not familiar with
like osteopathic medicine versus
allopathic medicine and all these sort
of things
um can you describe sort of what that
means to be an osteopathic doctor
um you know versus other other types of
physicians that sort of thing
sure sure so there's two types of
physicians in the u.s there's mds
and there's do's right and these are
medical doctors it stands for medical
doctor d.o stands for doctor of
osteopathy
now we have the exact same licensure so
we work in the same hospitals the same
privileges i can write all prescriptions
admit you to the hospital
mris insurance companies cover us etc
etc
the main difference between doctors of
osteopathy is that we take an
extra year sometimes two years of
anatomy and physiology
so we have a much more
deeper understanding of musculoskeletal
system
and some of us very few of us but some
of us go into what's called osteopathic
manipulative medicine
and that's what i specialize in
and we use our hands to help heal
patients now it's becoming
much more rare and rare as
pharmaceuticals
became the main you know the mainstream
so most of
most do's are just like regular
physicians and don't do any hands-on
medicine
but there's about three percent of do's
so there's a few of us left
that uh still still practice
uh osteopathic medicine yeah and it's
tradition
yeah and um what specifically kind of
drew you
into that route versus uh the md route
my pain yeah my pain so i
originally started as a physical therapy
major i knew
you know i i did pt as a teenager and i
saw okay well this
is helpful yeah you know maybe i can
become a physical therapist or a
chiropractor
i was very interested in anatomy and
physiology
so i was a pt at cornell actually
and i was going to get my master's in pt
um
as an um after i graduated as undergrad
and i met a do actually while i was
there and he
adjusted me he gave me my first
adjustment you know i was again
in pain in college already so i was
looking for alternative
uh relief and i and i said what what are
you doing you're not a chiropractor and
you said no i'm a do and i said you know
what's a do
and he explained to me about osteopathy
and he says you know
you're a physician so you can have all
the privileges as a physician
except you learn how to um manipulate
and you learn more about anatomy and
physiology
so i said sign me up i changed my major
i
became pre-med and
and the rest is history wow that's
really cool
and how would you describe your
experience
working with a patient that was trying
to work with cannabis
for the first time what was that like
so for me it was important having my own
experience
because i could relate to to patients
that were naive you know i was very very
cannabis naive i didn't know what to
expect oh my god my
my mother said i would get schizophrenia
right if i ever tried cannabis right yes
so
so i came from this really big fear
factor um
but for me it was number one was
education you know
what what does cannabis mean let's break
it down to
plant medicine plant sciences you know
what does it mean to even try
alternative medicine
dr andrew weil is one of my mentors
so i really you know looked at at that
realm
as education first acupuncture
is a really big part of my practice
i was a researcher at columbia
university
women's health center and we research
acupuncture and uterine fibroids so for
me
when you think outside the box and
you're seeing an md
the biggest thing is expectations for
the patient
and education yeah yeah and
what were uh people coming to you
uh to treat what were some of the the
common things that you were seeing that
people were turning to cannabis for
i imagine pain is one of them pain is
one of them
um but also i saw a lot of children
actually i treated
mostly children in california for the
first i would say five to seven years
um children and these were you know
these are patients that have tried
everything
you know like you and me they've gone
through the whole
you know 10 different md's 10
specialists and flew all over the
country
to different you know centers um you
know from maryland to texas to
and they've seen all the specialists and
i was their last hope
you know they heard that cannabis could
work um these were children with
epilepsy
children with cancer mitochondrial
disorders genetic disorders they came in
wheelchairs they were non-ambulatory
right they weren't walking they weren't
talking these were special needs kids
and then it expanded to adults that were
in chronic pain
you know adults with ms adults living
with fibromyalgia
autoimmune diseases als parkinson's
where there really is no there really is
no answer for chronic diseases no
chronic pain diseases
yeah and of some of the
let's focus on the children for just a
second because i think that's really
important to talk about
what what were some of the successes and
failures that you experienced working
with kids in some of these conditions
the biggest thing with children is and
it was important part of our practice
is to make sure that there was a team
approach and still
is so i i really want to make sure that
the child's neurologist the pediatrician
the psychiatrist is on board when
they're working with a
an integrated physician such as myself
so the having that conversation about
cannabis
having that conversation with both
parents caregivers guardians of the room
and the specialists so that they know
that we're all a team here and we're not
um you know
trying to say get off all your
medication you know
that that's not the point when they come
see someone like me
it's really an integrative it's the best
of both worlds
so that is the number one thing and then
working closely with parents because
sometimes the spouses are at odds
mom might say i'm full on supporting cbd
and
cannabis and dad or their partner
will say i'm against it this is not what
i want for my child
yeah so again communication education
um you know expectations is is key
and when you ran into those sort of
conflicts
where you might have parents that
disagree with one another
or or maybe even other physicians
involved in the child's care
what were some of the key sort of like
pieces of education
that would help sort of calm those those
fears a bit
the for my colleagues so for other mds
the biggest thing is
sending them you know research articles
you know talking to them about patient
cases
and sometimes i'll go and do grand
rounds
you know do a noon conference a journal
a journal club
and talk to colleagues on their level
you know what is what's happening on the
receptor level
um things like that and and you know
sometimes they go from you know sort of
folding their arms and and their
eyebrows are just furrowed
and they're really angry to like they
relax their face a little bit
and say okay this is not voodoo medicine
right there's actually some science
behind
it um and and also to reassure them
that i'm working with the parents so
they're not
off getting something off you know from
who knows where
you know there is some monitoring
there's charting
so i'm charting everything and and
documenting everything
my the parents that i work with are
keeping journals so we know
we know how it affects iep or how it
affects
you know what is the child's teacher
saying or the speech therapist or ot or
pt
so we document everything and we
monitor them very closely there's a lot
of follow-ups in the beginning
because i want to make sure that the
parents are
feeling supported that they're doing it
right you know titration of dosing
making sure there's feedback from all
the ancillary health practitioners as
well
yeah and what were the main
modes of administration um that most of
these kids would use were they using
like
um tinctures or raw oil capsules
in the beginning it was just tinctures
you know in the beginning the parents
were
and this is you know we're talking a
little more than 10 years ago they're
making their own
they're growing their own a few plants
of their own so in california parents
were allowed
to grow their own cannabis that was part
of the medical cannabis
legalization and they would steep their
own
sometimes smoothies they make teas out
of it
um sometimes they would put it in ice
cubes
and you know and just put it in their
juice and the kids juice
so parents got creative and parents are
very resourceful
you're a dad i'm i'm a mom so we would
do anything for our children and the
the forums and the support the community
was just astounding
um parents found that each other uh and
shared stories
and talked about anecdotally what worked
and what didn't work
um shared um you know sort of this like
trusted integrative practitioner list
things like that um and we all put our
heads together and figured out and tried
to learn from each other parent
you know parents patients teach me just
as much as i teach them yeah
and um going into what you just said of
like
trying to discover what works what
doesn't work and obviously that's a
loaded question because it depends on
the condition and the person and the
dose and the
you know all these different things but
what were some of those lessons that you
learned working with all these patients
about
what typically worked better than others
what forms tended to be
better than others i you know that sort
of thing
so for the biggest thing for children
it's getting them to take it
right the taste you know and and when i
when i'm treating special needs kids
they're very sensitive to taste you know
if
that a lot of these children are on the
same diet
because if if you veer from texture or
taste
they just won't eat it so that was the
biggest tricky
thing that's why moms will make
you know the ice cubes or they juiced it
or they steeped it in tea
or they were you know really creative
and put it in honey or something like
that
ice cream even you know whatever they
could
so ingestion just getting them into the
child was a big thing
and then also timing so some children
did better
taking it before school some children
after school you know before therapy
even
so we really looked at timing of the
medicine
for seizure children of course rubbing
it uh sublingually
you know in their gums yeah i was very
helpful or
a lot of the moms uh made a
suppositories
uh and this was you know in the very
beginning making suppositories and and
seeing if it would work
um and that was well documented as well
so
parents got creative because when you're
when you see your child
seizing and this is the only thing that
works and they've tried the conventional
anti-epileptic medicines um they
they tell 10 more families and then 10
more families come in
right yeah and um the cannabis that they
were using were these thc varieties cbd
varieties
uh mixture you know along the spectrum
you know what were they working with
there
there were mixtures there were mixtures
along the spectrum um you know the very
beginning we weren't calling it cbd or
thc
there's just so many different chemical
variants um you know
i helped connect them with different
growers different cultivators
and we knew you know this cultivator was
able to grow something that didn't make
the kid very sleepy
right so obviously it was lower in thc
but that's how we documented in the
beginning
and as technology changed as you know
more and more things uh
information was made widely available i
mean i use both
cbd and thc for children it really just
depends on what the goals are
what the disease of the symptom and not
symptomatology is
and also working with how functional the
child is as well
yeah and you mentioned titration um i
think that's something
when i was when i was talking with wendy
that was something we got into because
from her experience running a store she
noticed that a lot of people
are not exposed to uh that process
of trying to find kind of the minimum
effective dose and to know
you know what you're working with so can
you describe a little bit about
you know for instance right now with cbd
being so popular if people are running
out
trying to um you know find a product and
trying to find a dose what does
that titration look look like and how
low do you start
and kind of um how much time do you wait
to pass before you up the dose that sort
of thing and just describe a little bit
what the
process looks like so very different
between children and adults
actually with the pediatric community
the parents were very familiar with
titration
you know as you know even with your baby
tylenol everything comes in a liquid
and um even with anti-seizure
medications
things like that everything comes in a
liquid and they knew how to titrate
you know they knew they know they know
how to titrate they know how
to and as a parent if you look at your
child and they have this glaze over
their eyes you already know they're sick
right usually that doesn't take much um
they're
you know parents are very intuitive for
adults it's a little bit trickier
yeah you know i think we have higher
pain tolerance we sort of kind of just
power through things um so it or we want
instant gratification yeah
um and we want that cbd to work now you
know yesterday
how come it's not working right yeah
yeah no
exactly so it's easier to work with
pediatrics actually
it's easy for adults too to like i don't
know really confound
variables and things too when they're
they're sharing what they're what
they're doing
and what are the given that children and
adults are so different just in like
surface area and metabolism and that
sort of thing i know that in the early
days
you probably didn't have access to
really sophisticated dosaging data
because there weren't even i mean
i'm trying to think of when testing labs
really started to come along i mean
steep hill was one of the early ones in
california
but that still was not that long ago
but based on your experience now what
are some of those dosage differences
between children and
adults so with children um
it's i'm just thinking of kids that are
my autism
patients for example or kids that
ourselves have self-injurious behaviors
that accumulation of cannabinoids can
really take a toll
on them so parents might notice that
things are working really well for the
first
you know two to three weeks there's what
i call the honeymoon stage
and the child is really you know you
know
even keeled grounded really feels
comfortable in their own
skin and then all of a sudden it starts
to turn
at the 30-day mark maybe and you they
notice that
the child is just more hyper you know
the um
the motor ticks sort of amp up
or they um they just feel like they're a
little bit more
more like hand biting even or the
repetitive
um uh echolalia where they're saying
things over and over again
that might uptick as well and i find
that to be the case as the cannabinoids
build up in their system
so less is more and um
and i actually find it a little bit
harder now than it
than i was than it was when i was
practicing in california because
information is so readily available and
there's just
you know there's 8 000 products
available so parents are trying all
these different products
adding this adding that how come that
didn't work i read on facebook
that this brand works so i tried this
brand and i added
you know 0.5 milliliters another five
drops another 10 drops
and so it does get muddy but really
staying the course and and i mean i
sometimes i have to hand hold a lot of
a lot of these parents and just say no
you want to stay with
0.2 milliliters of this brand for a 30
days
you know just hang in there i know i
know you're not getting the results that
you're getting
but we're doing it slowly you know then
talk about sleep hygiene
you know talking to the physical
therapist or the speech therapist
you know sort of tweaking things that
way
with adults it's the same thing you know
being patient
knowing that to decrease inflammation in
the body takes time
and um and i actually really encourage
the adults let's say we're talking about
um you know chronic pain for instance or
even insomnia
um to to add in
exercise meditation you know sleep
hygiene getting off the computer
and electronics you know two to three
hours before bed
um so it really takes i would say
a lot of other approaches not just the
cannabis
yeah exactly and when uh
patients are going through that process
and trying to kind of fig
find the uh i guess sort of like the
plateau of therapeutic response
how long do you prefer them to wait
before
you know you would make a judgment about
what that
uh cannabinoid therapy is actually doing
a month
a month yeah mm-hmm i know everyone
frowns
i mean i don't want to wait a month yeah
i mean but that's you know
that's really common with you know a lot
of other drugs
you know when you're working with a
physician and trying to find you know
dosaging a lot of times you might
only see a doctor once a month or so and
that's usually you know kind of
how it goes um so it's
it's not that surprising but um i could
i can understand that
that's not necessarily the message a lot
of people want to hear
um because they do want to see those
results and
you know another thing you you just
touched on is sort of this um
like biphasic response that cannabinoids
have that
um at certain dosages they do one thing
but then as they build
or as you increase dose or whatever you
all of a sudden get to this other side
of this
you know curve this dose response curve
and you may be having less effect or a
negative
effect yeah and i think that's critical
i'm glad you highlighted that because
that's something that i think needs to
be talked about
more in the context of um using cannabis
as medicine
um and i think that's largely a
reflection of sort of this it's not just
the united states but this kind of
mentality that we have of like you know
more is better and
um you know if if a little bit was
helping then take more and take more and
um you know we have a sense of tolerance
but that biphasic response is something
i think
that we don't necessarily have a large
appreciation for
and some people when they might be on
that other side of the curve they might
think they've just built tolerance
and so then they add more and more and
you have to try to overcome that
exactly yeah exactly yeah exactly
and i mean and we when we look at
medicine you know we do that at the
doctor's office when you're being
prescribed
um blood pressure medication yeah or
diabetes medication you come back and
you retest you know maybe your sugars
aren't quite controlled so we'll adjust
it or your blood pressure even
antidepressants anti-anxiety medications
you know doctors will tell you it takes
six to eight weeks to
you know see if there's a there's going
to be a therapeutic response
and if it doesn't work they're going to
have to switch to another medication
so so same thing with pharmaceutical
medications and
and i know you had have um kevin
spellman on before and
i adore him but we're looking at this
plant that's affecting so many receptors
that
that's why everyone is so different
right exactly yeah
and as much as we understand now it's
still
only you know this fraction of a piece
of a puzzle
um that we're trying to piece together
you know one thing i really enjoy
talking to kevin about in that
in that interview is you know about the
endocannabinoid system and just how
complicated it is and that you know we
kind of have maybe some general
understanding
of some of the things it's doing and the
other
receptor systems it's connected to and
all the sort of thing but we're still
a long way and this came out in my
interview with ethan rousseau as well
that
we don't have good ways of measuring the
system you know
the definition of the system is like
rapidly expanding
as we learn more and so it's
it's really tricky and sometimes i think
there's a perception
especially within the canvas industry in
general that you know we know so much
and so we should be able to use that
information
to really target treatments and you know
make super informed decisions and we can
definitely make better informed
decisions than we ever could
um but it's just yeah it's just not
quite there yet so a lot of it is still
trial and error moving slowly um
trying to control as many variables as
you can and and proceed with caution
and yeah absolutely and i i see a lot of
women in my practice
um now and we we have to realize and
this doesn't get discussed
as often as i would like is that
estrogen makes women a lot more
sensitive to cannabis
you know and mostly thc so our hormones
interact with thc quite a quite a bit
and our cycle
can influence how how we feel and this
was documented through researchers at
washington state university
they found that women experience most
effects of thc when their estrogen is
peaked
right right when it peaked and beginning
to fall so this happens
at like about the day or two before you
ovulate so day 12
to day 14 or so and this
this interaction makes us more sensitive
to the compound in general
but it also actually gives us more pain
relieving effects
right compared to to males but also
we actually can develop more tolerance
to the thc compared to men
so for women i actually when they come
into my office
i will look at their cycle or non-cycle
you know so i'll look at their estrogen
progesterone levels
lsh levels fsh levels and i will
actually
create a game plan and i will dose them
based on their cycle so they take a
little bit more or a little less
depending on where they're at
uh and it's important i mean you know
we're we're not
represented in studies uh you know as a
you know as an ethnicity different
minorities or even as a female
which is unfortunate but i i do take
that into account when i see female
patients
that's really great to hear that was
exactly what where i was going to go
next is
um there's this like very little disgust
issue in biomedical research in general
that a lot of the way that we've come to
think about
uh pharmacology and physiology is based
on research in men
and it doesn't translate
um you know i mean some does but you
know obviously there are there are big
differences
and these hormonal differences drive all
sorts of
um nuanced differences in
pharmacokinetics and things
that um really needs to be talked about
more i mean
there's so many issues with biomedical
research right now so this is one so the
under representation
um between um ethnic groups
and and sexes and that sort of thing um
but then also we have a reproducibility
problem too so there's a lot of
biomedical research that's been done
that
we're having trouble reproducing and um
it's it's a great time to have a lot of
humility i think when it comes to
to medicine absolutely right yeah 100
i'm so glad you said that i mean when
you when we get sick
you're going to take the same z pack as
i am right
right you know so why aren't we dosed
differently based on our weight
our ethnicity based on our metabolism
right
yeah exactly and um are there
um i mean you just you just hit several
of the big
um ways that cannabis can affect women
differently than men or
really just depending on a person's
hormonal levels regardless of how they
identify
are there any other big differences that
you've noticed
in how people react to cannabis
differently that you think people should
be aware about
actually ethnicity is a big thing i've
noticed in my clinical data that
different ethnic groups um you know
depending on
genetic makeup um and where their
ancestors are from
will react differently to cannabinoid
medicine
so the hispanic population asian
population seem much more sensitive
to cannabinoids um and so i
i mean it's interesting because i'm i'm
looking at the data that i have
and i i i would definitely want to
utilize this set and figure out you know
where
or maybe maybe we can brainstorm offline
yeah
um but but really think about how this
plant is working
from you know a demographic point of
view
yeah i that's something that i have i
don't know if i've heard anyone
really bring much attention to that at
all um so that's
super super fascinating and something
that um
yeah we really need to look at and
once again this is one of those things
where cannabis sort of leads into these
discussions about medicine broadly but
you know this is research that needs to
happen across the board
um analyses of you know large data sets
that clinicians have and try to
understand how
different people are reacting to things
differently and how we can
drive medicine towards a much more
individualized targeted approach
rather than how we've been operating
since
you know i don't know the 50s where we
basically take
averages of medical research and
we apply therapies according to um
sort of an average sample population
that doesn't even exist in the world you
know you're always dealing with people
that are bringing unique things to the
to the table um so that's yeah that's
excellent to hear
um when someone comes to you and they
want to
engage cannabis what are some of the
things that you screen for
that could be problematic like other
like certain uh medical condition
conditions they may have that wouldn't
react favorably to cannabis or
other medications you know
contraindications you're worried about
that sort of thing
yeah so medications is a big thing um
because most of the patients that come
to me are on a lot of meds
right because you've already tried all
these different things and
um all your specialists have tried to
throw the kitchen sink at you
you know so they they might be on
antidepressants for chronic pain you
know
such as cymbalta for example something i
see a lot
and um you know patients are trying to
get off
of a lot of these medications so i don't
recommend
just going cold turkey and getting off
of these medications because
your body's biochemistry has changed
your brain biochemistry has changed
so if you've been on benzos
antidepressants if you've been on these
pain medications
you know for your condition for a very
long time
you know just haphazardly adding
cannabinoid medicine or even other
nutraceuticals
right other other supplements can be a
really
dangerous thing so i
make sure that i look at the medication
list cross-reference it
and sometimes patients
have to really wait and i start to wean
patients off
with their specialist so i don't i don't
take patients off medication on my own i
make sure to work with their md as well
um and help them wean off the medication
and then we fold in
the cannabis medicine or some of the
other integrative therapies
very very carefully taking into account
the withdrawals
both physical and emotional withdrawal
and
sometimes we have to compound the
medications
so for instance um i'm trying to think
of one
that's actually really ambien is one
let's see we have to sometimes compound
the medication so they're taking it i
mean you can only break the tablet so
much
right yeah before i just like used a
powder yeah exactly
so sometimes we'll compound into a
liquid form and help them wean off like
klonopin that's what i'm just
thinking of klonopin can take patients
one to two years to get off of
so we'll we'll create it into a liquid
formula
with a compounding pharmacy and just
drip by drip
drip by drip and getting them off little
by little as we fold in
uh the cannabis medicine yeah and have
you encountered
um any examples of um
adverse reactions between cannabis and
someone's pharmaceuticals maybe even
before they came to see you because they
maybe didn't have that
um advice at the time when they started
trying it
yeah yeah so so cannabinoids can work on
you know your serotonin
levels and if they're on other
medications that also affect that
patients will feel much more anxious
patients might have increased panic
attacks
they might feel more restless um and
just feel uneasy
they always say i feel like i'm crawling
out of my skin i did something wrong
i took too much you know or they're not
spacing it apart with
other medications or supplements you
know sometimes patients are on four or
five different supplements as well that
they think oh it's natural
so i'll just take everything at once um
and
that's not a good idea either so so we
really try and break it down for
patients so it's much more manageable
and cost-effective because that's a big
thing as well as you know the
cbd and cannabis is very expensive
nutraceuticals are expensive then they
have their
prescription medications on top of that
and then they want to do all these other
therapies as well
so we look at everything from a
practical perspective yeah
absolutely and what was your in
changing gears a little bit here but
what was your experience like
going from california's medical cannabis
system to new york's
medical cannabis system when you moved
what were the difference and what was
that transition like
well there's definitely pros and cons in
california
it was a free-for-all there was a
dispensary on every corner
uh more dispensaries in starbucks
you know you can imagine so it was very
difficult
i had a few of my favorite dispensaries
my preferred dispensaries where
the staff was you know wonderful and
they supported
my patients throughout the process but
in the beginning
i would actually talk to these
dispensaries and say okay my patient's
going to come in give you a heads up
you know without disclosing i mean i
kept full you know um
hipaa hipaa rules but you know giving
them a heads up that my patients are
coming and this is what we would like to
try
or not try and some of the really good
dispensaries
were very respectful of that and worked
as a team
some of them weren't and was just trying
to push product and just move things off
the shelf
in new york it's very different in new
york
every dispensary has a pharmacist oh
interesting
every dispensary has a pharmacist and
everything you pick up
is logged into the prescription
monitoring program
and this is the same prescription
monitoring program as if you saw your
family practitioner
and they prescribed medication for you
like ambien
or some pain meds they would log it in
so when you go to
cvs or walgreens to pick it up cvs and
walgreens log in and sees that you have
cannabis
as well that you picked it up from the
dispensary so we're all looking at the
same
database so that
they know that you didn't pick up too
much and the pharmacist at the
dispensaries here in new york will say
hey wait a minute
you're on blood thinners you're on you
know
oxycontin and then you just picked up
cannabis right
there's some there's some polypharmacy
going on here there might be some issues
and they'll pick up the phone and
they'll call me so there is some
accountability and cross-reference
so it is a very robust medical system in
that sense
but it's very cross cost prohibitive
here in new york
it's about i would say two to three
times the price is california
easily yeah and that's
such a shame when you have you know some
of these patients
being um children that are already on
you know sometimes really expensive
medications or like the elderly
and the poor you know that um
are already struggling to pay for for
health care
and then to have something like this
that theoretically could be really cheap
but you know making that less accessible
that's
disappointing but it is exciting to
hear about a medical system that where
they're treating
cannabis just like any other medicine or
drug
you know and that there's that shared um
information and that you can catch
things like that that there's um
it's a more precautionary approach i
guess um
and that's that's um exciting to see
i'm i'm not familiar with new york's
cannabis
laws in general so what are the
conditions that new york
um will approve somebody for for medical
cannabis
right so there's epilepsy uh there's
ptsd
chronic pain which is a you know big
umbrella term and that chronic pain
could
you know incorporate many different
disease states
als parkinson's irritable bowel disease
you know which is crohn's colitis etc
um also substance abuse actually added
substance abuse
so patients that are trying to wean off
opiates are qualified
as well um there's a there's a good
amount autism is not on there
um no um
but uh you know patients with chronic
pain that could be migraine
that could be pelvic pain um that could
be you know arthritis
and like for example the cost going back
to cost i have a patient who
is seven and he has seizures
he had about 100 seizures easily a day
and he is controlled now with cannabis
the seizures
maybe he has a handful a month now but
they spend about three grand a month
yeah they spend about three grand a
month on the on cannabis
wow gee whiz and
what's your experience been regarding um
the in getting more into like the more
modern work that you're doing where
you've
actually got this data but um so there's
this debate around
you know isolated cannabinoids versus
quote unquote broad spectrum versus full
spectrum which these terms aren't even
really defined
so depending on who you talk to they
mean different things but
have you had any um
have you noticed anything any trends
between different
types of cannabis products and their
efficacy
and sort of the dosaging and stuff and
the reason i ask is because i've had
some other clinicians tell me that from
their experience
they feel that they're able to use lower
dosages and get
fewer negative side effects with
cannabis products that have a broader
phytochemical diversity in them versus
those that are very
you know either isolated or like you
have you know distillates and stuff that
have
you know a very narrow range of of
chemistry in them do you have
any thoughts on that yeah so
for me um of course full spectrum
um seems to get a little more mileage
i find that the efficacy of full
spectrum
is a lot it goes a longer way
for patients and they spend actually
less
money because they need less
over time i think with isolates patients
tend to
need a little bit more um and
you know it's going back to that single
molecule right so
so you're pulling you know you're
pulling this out of the
the plant the full plant and taking it
out of context
so you may not get all the benefits um
but i can see why isolates are used in
you know food and beverage things like
that for taste
or if it's harder to standardize a full
spectrum right
uh plant right so you know the same
quinovar
in florida will look different than
that seed in new york or california
right you're just not going to get the
same thing
so i can see why um
certain industry professionals are more
comfortable with isolates
but i think full spectrum um
full spectrum is better yeah yeah
well you're uh another one to the list
pretty much every clinician i've talked
to has
has shared the same thing i'm yet to
find anybody that
um has had a more positive experience
um with isolated cannabinoids
than full spectrum well i think we can
all agree that we just need more
research
right and this research really needs to
focus on
the fundamental understanding of what's
going on with the whole plan
right and not just selecting out these
individual molecules
like cbg cbs you know like like we know
what we're doing
because really we don't so and and the
thing is we're still looking at this
field from a disease target kill model
exactly that's the thing allopathic
we're still looking at this from this
allopathic
uh reductive approach uh which is
separating you know disease into parts
right we're still separating it we feel
good about separating things by
element and element and component when
we see the doctor
you're going to your endocrinologist and
then
your nephrol you know nephrologist and
your neurologist and all these doctors
are not talking to each other
because they're operating in separate
silos so it's it's the same thing with
cannabinoid medicine
and it's a disservice you know really
there's this whole
universe of regenerative medicine
nutritional medicine
preventative integrative medicine and
we're not talking about that
yeah no absolutely and and this um sort
of segues into
a really broad topic that i kind of
wanted to talk to you about is just
like these um plant-based or even fungal
based
medicines in general in your mind
sort of stepping back and looking at
health care as a whole
how do you conceptualize medicinal
plants and those sort of things
um and maybe even um to an extent to
certain like dietary supplements and
stuff that are
you know basically medicinal some of
them medicinal plants that are just kind
of ground up and capsulized but
um how does that fit in your mind of the
whole you know picture of healthcare
broadly
well it's a it goes back to what kevin
spellman talked about in systems biology
approach
right this is really again a wake-up
care to our
our health system when we look at
evidence-based medicine
you know it really over emphasizes
randomized
double-blind clinical control trials
it looks as it as it's like the final
arbiter of clinical decision-making
but when you look at americans i mean
more than 40 percent of us belong to
again a racial or ethnic minority so
what are these differences in genomes
you know how do we take a closer look at
these these patients and how are they
participating in these clinical trials
um there's actually something that's
really interesting i want to bring up
the nih actually has something i'll send
you the link
it's called all of us research program
and it talks about
precision medicine and i think this is
the future of medicine
it's looking at all of us
to participate into this database
if you will and you it's it's basically
contributing your blood tests
your urine saliva test dna tests and
they're looking at this database to
start looking at how do we get
more precise medicine you know going
back to that zpac
analogy you know why when you get
bronchitis or you get a cold at you know
the
flu why are you going to take the same z
pack as i'm going to take
you know it might not work well and i
think this is where plant medicine
can really take hold as well because
precision medicine can take into account
plant-based medicine and holistic
healing
yeah absolutely and something i'd like
to see
from you know sort of maybe it that
would come from the fda but
some sort of better way of
um studying in a sophisticated clinical
way
how medicinal plants um can be utilized
in
you know any particular sort of like
treatment modality and you know
in other countries in some countries um
they have you know a specific sort of
pathway
that you could get um natural products
uh approved as medicines um and it's
it's
a lot harder in the united states i
don't know that i would say it's
impossible but it is very difficult and
it
costs a lot of money and a lot of time
and because of that it's not worth it
for a lot of companies to try to
you know create some basic standardized
botanical extract
and try to get that approved as a
medicine when they could go further and
get some isolated compounds create a
very unique formulation that has a much
stronger patent on it
you know that then they can kind of run
with for 10 years or whatever
um once they get exactly exactly there's
just there's not enough studies on
on plant pharmacogenetics yeah you know
we just we need to look at
you know really genomics more too i mean
for one big thing that i see
you know in my clinic is that african
americans and
puerto ricans for example they don't
respond well to common asthma
asthma controller medications as well as
as other
other um ethnic groups so
this might you know this is something we
might think about when we talk about
plant pharmacogenetics you know maybe
there's something in the genome
um that you know we we need to take into
account so we don't over prescribe
exactly yeah so that that is the that's
the future of medicine yeah it's looking
at these different
i mean we we don't know anything right
and we're acting like we know
yeah yep yep well there's that you know
that classic um
idea that i try to bring up time and
time again but
you know uh the more you learn and the
more you study
ideally what happens is you start to
learn how much you don't know
you know and and it and that's to me
that's what wisdom is
is like recognizing you know your own
um sort of boundaries and and
recognizing that there is
you know kevin put it well this dark
information dark data dark pharmacology
that we just don't understand and and
looking at studies
you know in vitro or even you know
rodent in vivo models
they just they don't give us the full
picture and
something so an interview i released
recently with
um jason miller he's a traditional
chinese medicine
practitioner he was talking about the
difference between
efficacy and effectiveness research and
you know that
going to something you said just a
little bit ago that most research is
targeted on
uh disease what drug is going to
influence a disease in a particular way
not what um treatment modalities
as a whole might lead to a better
outcome for a person
um because yeah you might knock out that
disease but what's going to be the
consequence for that person's well-being
you know then and you know long into the
future and everything and
that was something i really resonated
with when he said that is
absolutely like our just our focus has
been we've had such an extreme tunnel
vision
on disease and not overall
patient care and wellness um in its
totality exactly there's no
talk about prevention you know what
about the terrain that's breeding the
disease
you know why is it that certain you know
there's certain
people that will be more prone to cancer
than others right
so we we need to look at um medicine
from this preventative
perspective yeah and we don't we don't
talk about that in in healthcare because
there's no time you know my colleagues
are seeing 30 patients a day it's a
factory
you know maybe you have five minutes
with your doctor and um you can't get
all your questions in and you're going
to have to wait until the next visit
which is going to be two months from now
well yeah and i know just from my own
experience that i'll have questions
thought of that i want to ask my doctor
when i go in
and then in the moment when they say so
do you have any other questions i'm like
uh
i i guess not i don't remember you know
and then you get home and you're like
dang i wish i would have asked this and
that and
you know that's such a common experience
i think for so many people and
you know when you're in the room and you
know maybe the physician's sharing some
new information with you and so you're
processing that and trying to remember
you know
it's just it's hard when you've only
yeah i got like 10 minutes maybe a face
time and
and then yeah that's it it's it's
yeah it's really really hard
um going back to
um thinking about your interactions with
patients when they're coming in and kind
of getting on their purse their
perspective
what are some of the most common
questions that you receive from patients
um about cannabis and um and this leads
into another question i have about
um sort of common misconceptions well
we'll start just with sort of the common
questions you receive about cannabis
um the biggest thing is most patients
wanting to come in is
wanting to use them you know throughout
the day and at night as well
they want to be able to use something
without being impaired right
um i think that's the biggest thing you
know everyone is working everyone's
you know they might not have a nine to
five but they're doing stuff at home
they're
you know they're taking care of their
own parents or their children
um or friends so it's impairment
that's the thing they come in they say
okay i need something
for x y and z but i don't want to be
impaired yeah
and have you identified um sort of some
ideal
cbd thc ratios that help people avoid
feeling impaired most of patients that
take cbd or cbd dominant
formula are not impaired but there are
patients that do take cbd that feel
impaired
um and that's usually the same patients
that are sensitive to
you know advil for example um and so
i'll you know just have them switch and
have them take it you know during the
evening
but microdosing is the biggest thing you
know if you're taking
cannabinoid medicine maybe the first
couple of weeks you
feel different you might feel a little
bit groggier but over time your body
gets used to it
and you feel less of those side effects
yeah
yeah exactly and so leading into the
next question what are some of the most
common misconceptions
that sometimes you have to confront when
either
either from patients that come in and
sort of have a
rough understanding and maybe it's not
quite aligned with reality or from your
colleagues potentially that have
misconceptions about cannabis and it's
in its role in cannabis what are some of
those
that you run into a lot of
i think with all the hype and uh you
know this is really unprecedented
there's nothing in the world that's
taken you know both recreationally and
medicinally yeah
so i think a lot of patients come in
thinking this is going to be it
this is going to be the end-all be-all
and they have really high expectations
of it working because of everything
they've read online and
you know my neighbor took it and she's
free of cancer now
um or you know it stops the parkinson
tremors so it must be able to stop my
fibromyalgia pain too
so um it doesn't work for everything and
everyone
it's not that silver bullet you really
have to do
other things in combination with
the cannabinoid medicine yeah yeah
absolutely and would you say that's
maybe
kind of one of the big things that you
wish everyone knew about cannabis before
engaging it is that it's
not a silver bullet um absolutely
absolutely and you might not find um one
product will work
you know forever so i usually have
patients
like pick you know two to three
different favorite
cannabis products that work or close to
working and they switch off
you know every quarter because our body
gets sensitized to it
you know and i always compare this to
allergy medication you might find that
zyrtec works for one season and then you
got to switch over to claritin
um and same thing with your you know
echinacea or vitamin c or your magnesium
you need to take you know take a break
and switch off
um the good thing about um you know our
endocannabinoid system is that we can
exercise and increase our anamide levels
we can get acupuncture
massage and our anandamide levels will
increase
so there are different things that we
can do with cannabinoid medicine
yeah safely yeah absolutely
and um
what is something throughout your
experience with patients
that has surprised you either an outcome
or however you want to think about that
question but you know you've been doing
this a while now do you have any
examples of some things that went
differently than you expected or
that an outcome came about that you know
you really learned a lot from that kind
of surprised you
what's what's really surprising and um
really refreshing
is that patients that might not have
been
into holistic or integrative medicine
when they try
cannabis and it works
it's really empowering for them you know
for the first time they feel like
i can take control of my health like i
can have this conversation
where um it does a little bit and then i
can do other things
and it really opens their mind yeah i
think for integrative medicine and plant
medicine
and these are you know patients that
have been on you know maybe 10
medications their whole life
and and keep going back to the doctor
and says okay yes i will take this new
med
oh you want another medication yes and
they're very compliant
and obedient but when they've had enough
and they've tried cannabis and it works
and they start to get off the other
medications
they find that very empowering they find
that like
oh my god like i don't i don't have to
rely on pharmaceuticals
you know having that conversation about
nutrition and exercise
is very empowering because they don't
have to
rely on going to the md and
writing that next script yeah yeah and
that's that's something that um has been
really exciting for me too on the sort
of the educator
side is seeing you know when i teach
somebody
about uh the cannabis plant and the
chemistry how it affects the body
all these sort of things and um and then
i can use that as a stepping stone to
say oh and then there's these other
plants that have these similar compounds
and act similarly and
you know then it's like whoa i didn't
realize you know that
echinacea has these um alkalamides that
you know interact the endocannabinoid
system and
turkey tell mushrooms the you know
polysaccharide peptide is interacting
with
and flavonoids in general a lot of them
are you know tugging on that ecs
and um you know that uh beta-carotelline
which is in so many plant oils
uh you know black pepper is the most
common one that gets talked about but
like oh
that's you know now sort of being
thought of as a cannabinoid you know
it just opens uh this doorway
into appreciating
food and medicinal plants in a totally
different way that for whatever reason
they just weren't able to you know there
was sort of this invisible wall that
they couldn't get past
to kind of see how very real
all of all of those you know dynamics
are
and that's that's something that gives
me a lot of fulfillment as an educator
is like yes like
you're going beyond cannabis now and
that's i i've mentioned before that
you know this podcast and and the work
that i do it's really a trojan horse
to you know talk about these other areas
of
of health and wellness and and i i also
follow that up by saying i'm not the
best example of someone taking care of
their health
i i do what i can but there's plenty i'm
deficient on
so i have the educator syndrome of like
do as i say
not as i do please but um the
cardiologist smokey cigarette right
yeah it is yeah i'll teach someone about
medical plants and it's like all right
i'm running low on time gotta go grab
some fast food
um believe me i was at shake shack with
my kids the other day and i saw a
patient i was like oh my god i gotta
hide
exactly i'm guilty i know right we're
all human
there's only so much we can do but but
exactly and
you're right you're right and it is it's
exciting it's exciting to see
when uh people can connect those dots
and start to see
you know coming all the way back around
to like this integrative medicine
approach to
see their movement and their diet
and supplements and you know the tea
they drink all of these things as being
part of
healthcare and um is something i've
mentioned before in another interview
but you know we
at least it seems like it's changing now
and we talked about this
um earlier that a lot of times we grow
up thinking that
um you know you eat food stay alive you
take supplements if you have a
nutritional deficiency of some sort and
you take drugs
to get better from illness and that's
such a weird broken
model um that's it's going to take time
culturally for us to kind of you know
get past that but i know as a kid that's
what i
sort of absorbed you know from what i
was taught and exposed to
um and then i got older and i was like
dang okay this is all totally
right well what the great thing is that
you have platforms like this
to educate and to reach um so so many so
many people
and there's wonderful practitioners
ancillary practitioners i mean you have
jana champaign
epigenetics you know nurse practitioners
nurses
health coaches chiropractors naturopaths
ayurvedic medicine
um you know plant you know plant uh
specialist
you know look at calvin oh my gosh he
knows a lot more than your normal md
yeah yeah so you don't always have to go
to your md
all the time i mean there's all these
great resources that are at your
fingertips
right yeah yeah exactly and i guess um
so to get into another question i wanted
to ask you is on those
that topic of resources um what are some
of your preferred
learning resources regarding cannabis
oh my goodness well i have
i'm this resource oh my gosh it make me
blush
um there's there's some really great
resources out there um
it's the the also the thing is there's
also misinformation
right so a lot of a lot of cut and paste
yeah you know we're sort of echoing the
same thing um but there's there's some
really great resources
um i i'll i'll send you a link and maybe
you can put it in your show now
absolutely yeah that'd be great that's
something i always try to tease out of
my guests to try to understand what you
found most valuable and try to connect
people to that that'd be great
um and now taking a step back
and looking at sort of cannabis science
and cannabis research as a whole
um what sort of interests you the most
and what do you hope to see from the
future of cannabis research
oh my goodness that is a huge question
i mean for i mean the thing about
the thing about research especially for
plant medicine is that it and not
everything is going to fit into a box
and i just had this conversation with
kevin a couple of weeks ago
and we're trying i mean the thing about
i mean that's the thing about research
is that research has to be double-blind
right research has to be random
controlled and then what are you going
to make of a plant that has
different compounds that you can't
standardize
so it's almost like mother nature is
laughing at us right
yeah yeah right i i mean i i
and then you look at the different
receptors there's i
there's a really great receptor map that
i use in my presentations
of the ecs and how uh different
different phytocannabinoids affect and
there's just
it's just scattered everywhere i mean
you can't even it's like we're we're a
blip yes
there's there's no way to wrap your head
around it and that goes back to
dark pharmacology i mean look think
about plant medicine
there's there's no way to wrap your head
around this research and that's why
i i um talked about that nih
platform because we if we can contribute
the different information the genomics
you know our blood our urine our dna
we can really look at precision medicine
individualized medicine
and that's not what we have right now
yeah yeah and it makes me wonder
you know if we're in this situation
where
we're sort of like a bacteria trying to
understand
a human you know like there's this um
barrier to understanding that you can
just like really never get across and it
makes me wonder if
and i mean i know to an extent this is
true that you know the role of ai and
machine learning is going to become
really invaluable to help us
try to extend that sort of boundary that
we have to work with because you're
right like
there's so much data so much information
there's no one human brain that's going
to be able to
synthesize all of that and digest it and
and then work with it
um it's i think it's going to take some
help um from something
beyond what what we're capable of and
maybe that's a a good role for ai and
healthcare is like this nih
you know data gathering um initiative to
get all this data together in one place
where it can be you know manipulated and
analyzed and everything and then maybe
we sick the ai bots on it
and then try to figure out what wisdom
they can
pull out of it and and teach us um
because
otherwise i mean can you imagine how
much time it just time alone
not much you know i don't know if you're
like me like any study i read
you know you've got to read it multiple
times and try to like
understand the pieces you missed and how
things fit together and you know
um so just the time alone is an
impossible feat for
you know anyone to overcome exactly and
i mean the important thing also to know
as we scale up ai is that you know we
can't
simply base it on data either yeah you
know right so there there's a
there's a sweet spot and how do we use
ai successfully
right so we're not you know so that
we're not looking at false correlations
yes but we're really trying to
understand what's happening behind it so
i think
um i think there's i think that's the
future
yeah yeah i know i that's such a good
point to bring up there
there are things to our human experience
that we're not going to be able to
quantify that an ai is going to be able
to
to pick from so finding that blend and
maybe that's when we just upload our
consciousnesses into
oh yeah so we can make the ultimate
doctors
but yeah absolutely there's there's a
balance there for sure and there are
things to our experience and
um wisdom and things uh that you know ai
is not going to be able to overcome
so yeah absolutely well
um i don't want to keep you too much
longer you've already been very gracious
with your time we've been going for
almost an hour and 15 minutes now
but i wanted to ask you if there's um
you know in the last several minutes
that we have here is there anything that
we haven't talked about that you'd like
to
get into and if so let's do it and if
not then i'll just kind of
hand the platform over to you to talk
about anything
um regarding how people can learn more
about your work and
um contact you or anything else you want
to share
in your well thank you so much thank you
uh this has been so much fun yeah i've
enjoyed it
i feel like we can talk i know i feel
like we can talk for hours
but we covered a lot of really great
pertinent information
um i definitely would love to get back
on maybe in a few months and see if
things have changed and we can
chat again but patients can find me
at doctorjoonchin.com drjunchin.com
perfect awesome well once again
thank you so much and yeah i definitely
would love to reconnect with you and at
some point
i'm going to make my way out to new york
and then we'll have to um
get the other words and then get your
family over here yeah we're
determined it's just a matter of time so
um
sounds good awesome well thanks so much
and for those of you listening or
watching
if you want to learn more about curious
about cannabis you can go to
cacpodcast.com and you'll find
all the episodes as well as links to
like our youtube and
all of our social media platforms we're
on facebook instagram and twitter
and um thanks so much for listening and
tuning in and i'll talk to you soon
thanks bye
[Music]
you