[Music]
everybody in this audience probably is
hurt that research we need more research
about the medical uses of cannabis but
most other folks that aren't involved in
doing medical cannabis research don't
understand the unique challenges that
exist to try to get this research done
and so today I'm really delighted to be
here to moderate a panel that has some
real heavy hitters in the cannabis
research space and they represent both
sort of academic and non-academic
research so I think we've got a nice
breadth of experience to really get at
the issues of you know what are the
things that are inhibiting our progress
towards that that epiphany when we have
enough cannabis research so to for
example reschedule or other interesting
things that could could happen when we
get that magic amount of research that
we need so without further ado what I'm
gonna do is this is the structure for
today we're going to have each of our
panelists do a brief self-introduction
and then our first question will be sort
of open-ended and it will be from your
experience what have been the
opportunities and challenges in studying
medical cannabis and lastly we're going
to touch just a little bit on a federal
level policy which is the medical
cannabis research act of 2018 there's
some folks on the panel who have some
things that they'd like to sort of bring
forward on that hi guys I'm sue Sisley
I'm of internal medicine physician from
Arizona I'm the president of Scottsdale
Research Institute were focused
primarily on doing controlled trials
looking at Flour both smoked and
vaporize flour for you know trying to
put flour through the entire FDA drug
development process so we're best known
for this study you've probably heard
about the FDA phase 2 trial looking at
cannabis for treating veterans with PTSD
but we also have others study we're
doing a clinical trial with University
of Michigan looking at cannabis for
chronic pain
we have another study looking at we just
finished a safety study on cannabis
edibles and we're also building a
national patient registry which I'm
hoping to talk about later a canvas
patient registry very in-depth national
database collecting information about
how patients are reacting to cannabis
hello my name is Daniel O'Malley I'm a
professor at University of California
Irvine I have been studying cannabinoids
and endocannabinoids for the last 25
years more or less and currently I am
the director along with Professor Bob
Solomon in the School of Law of the UCI
Center for the Study of cannabis that
just created its a its mission is to
understand the challenges and possibly
provide solutions also for the
challenges there lying ahead of us now
that cannabis is being legalized
throughout the throughout the country
i'm magalie Holmes I'm the CEO of
Philo's bioscience or a cannabis
genomics and plant breeding company
based in Portland Oregon and so I unlike
I think everybody else here on the panel
who is generally focused on the medical
side of the research issue everything we
do is focused on the plant side and it
actually turns out that it's it's even
harder to get plant research done in the
United States especially in universities
than it is to get medical research done
so I was also the chair last year of the
the governor's cannabis research task
force in Oregon where we were charged
with putting together a road map for how
to how the state of Oregon could get
research done on cannabis and our
findings were that there was basically
no way at the time for Oregon
universities to do the kind of research
that we wanted to do and things are
starting to loosen up a little bit
especially here in the UC system where
people are more aggressive than they are
in in other states um but it is still
very difficult to get any of this
research done and especially when it
comes to linking actual plants and what
we know about the plants to medical
outcomes so that's what we're focused on
I'm Tom market I'm a professor of
psychiatry at UC San Diego and also the
co-director of the UC Center for
medicinal cannabis research I'm a
neuropsychologist by training just
briefly the CM CR has been around since
2000 so following the Compassionate Use
Act passage the Senate the California
Legislature put aside money to look at
potential medical benefits of cannabis
so we conducted seven clinical trials
Pathak pain chemist related spasticity
ended up having positive findings in all
of those studies back in the 2000s this
was primarily smoked cannabis or
vaporize and also THC only currently our
Center has for clinical trials either
running or getting ready to start so we
have a take home study looking at low
back pain this is an eight-week study
we're starting up studies looking at CBD
for severe autism looking at early
psychosis as well as essential tremor
and also have some observational
mechanistic studies looking at bipolar
disorder and HIV neuropathic pain the
other aspect RCM terrorism is Public
Safety and so I'm the PI of a study
looking at cannabis and driving and how
to accurately detect impairment or not
so we've been fairly successful in this
sort of era we have some funding from
NIH some from the state some from
private foundations and are using
product from NIDA the University of
Mississippi as well as synthetic CBD
from incest as you may have heard also
plant drive from
that was just announced that's me as you
all know we are really blessed to have
such a depth and breadth of expertise on
this panel and without further ado I
want to launch into sort of the primary
question that the panelists have been
asked to address which is what have been
the challenges and opportunities of
working in medical cannabis research and
I wanted to sort of jump in and give my
own sort of take on that to sort of kick
it off so back like like many people I
was introduced to cannabis in college
although what I'm really talking about
is about that time I was I was in
college the endocannabinoid system was
being discovered by folks like Daniele
and it really inspired me to want to go
do that work so as my first postdoc I
was working at the Queen's Center for
biomedical engineering in Honolulu
Hawaii in a Schedule one facility and we
were trying to do research on the
effects of cannabis on the immune system
and what I found out really quickly was
that it was really hard to get product
and it was really hard to get funding to
do this work nevertheless we did some
studies and it was a great period of
time in my life but I personally went
off and did some work in biotech sphere
where I've in my past I have done some
work as in R&amp;D and in quality and
manufacturing of pharmaceuticals but
then I came back to the industry right
now because it seems like there are some
opportunities that exist within the
state regulated programs so I I my new
experience in doing research is in the
context of working with GP sciences and
we have we hold licenses and stay in
both Nevada as well as we are working
with LSU AG center to be one of two
providers of all the the cannabis
products to the state of Louisiana and
so through these we have some
interesting opportunities for doing
research on plant genetics on things
like we've been doing a lot of work on
in vitro propagation techniques to
ensure the genetic fidelity of our lives
as well as doing chemo fire profiling so
been a really exciting time we also done
a lot of work to try to standardize and
we've done some basic science work to
try to link profiles to
specific disease indications we've filed
six patents and our lead our lead
compound is for the treatment of
Parkinson's and we were getting really
excited because we're getting close to
having enough data to try to file an
exploratory IND in this area but we hit
a snag which was even though we had
standardized or compounds at our
facility in Nevada to what I would
consider a GMP standard because of sole
source we couldn't use her own compounds
so we've had to source them overseas
we've had to use a contract manufacturer
farm it's Catalan Pharma is going to be
doing our prototype formulations and the
process is super super complicated
whereas if any other kind of drug
development we were doing we wouldn't
have to go through these mash Nations
just to get the compounds in the order
and get them into a trial so with that
I'd like to invite say sue to contrast
compare and contrast it with your
experience we're focused on flour so
we've had a real challenge dealing with
the DEA night of Monopoly many of you
know that the National Institute on Drug
Abuse has enjoy you know through
University of Mississippi licensing
they've enjoyed a government enforcement
aa police since 1968 on the only
federally legal supply of cannabis for
controlled trials so even what Andre
mentioned about growing cannabis in
Louisiana is still wouldn't be usable
for any controlled trial she can grow
the best you know most diverse team of
ours in the universe and none of them
will be allowed to be used for any
control trust which really is the only
thing that matters to the medical
community right we only care about
randomized controlled trials and that's
generally what what gets published in
peer-reviewed journals so until we have
diverse you know until University of
Mississippi is ever allowed to access
diverse genetics we're stuck with these
you know this really low-quality plant
material without any access to any
unique cannabinoids except batches of
THC and CBD and that's all we know about
it and so if you dare ask for any unique
team of ours that are that are widely
available throughout
the regulated markets you can't get it
and that's I'm not criticizing
University Mississippi I'm just saying
that this monopoly needs to end we've
been striving to start a national
conversation for the last decade about
the problems with this month the fact
that they they need to license other
growers for research
the DEA pledged to the public back in
2016 that they would finally end the
monopoly and license other growers they
haven't moved forward on that at all
there's over you know twenty six
applications that have been sitting on
the desk of the DEA for two years none
of them have been processed and in the
meantime you know we could be enjoying a
renaissance of cannabis research in this
country if we were allowing other
private growers to provide you know we
have all these expert growers here in
this conference who could easily be
providing important team of ours for our
studies and they're not allowed to and I
think we all need as taxpayers we need
to demand that the DEA move forward and
license other growers and I think Tom
can speak to the fact that what he just
mentioned about the the the notion that
tilray
a Canadian LP is now allowed to export
study drug into the US but yet we're not
allowed to any of our expert our
talented farmers are not allowed to
provide medicine for these studies is
just an abomination my friends my
colleagues at University ask me why do
you do this because I tell them what we
have to go through to just run an animal
study or an in vitro cellular study with
cannot be no it's plenty ripe
cannabinoids and if I walk them through
the process they look at me then their
mouths open and their jaws drop and
their eyes roll said why are you wasting
your time on this you all know what I am
talking about what you all know what I'm
wasting my time
I'm wasting my time I'm getting a
Schedule one license which means that a
certain number of things have to be done
before during and after due process just
in order for us to start collecting
preliminary results to write a grant
proposal which then will require another
year year and a half two years to be
funded am i saying that this is
impossible no I'm here and we have doing
this we just got a very large nine
million dollar grant to study the impact
of cannabinoids on adolescence so it is
possible but so much of that energy
could have gone to science as opposed to
bureaucracy to science as opposed to
useless red tape and so many of the
questions that we would like to ask are
just not askable we cannot ask them very
recently we were on the phone with Tom
Marquardt and now a colleague of ours
from UC Davis who is an agronomist is a
plant biologist so I don't want to steal
our thunder but he already when Michael
already alluded to the difficulty of
doing plant biology with we cannabis in
the context in the present legislative
context this person a UC Davis a very
experienced plasma plant biologist had
never done any work on cannabis so when
Tom and I introduced him to the steps I
had to be taken you know I think at one
point we were considering seriously Tom
whether it was worth the effort say and
you know say like well no no let's do it
let's still do it so eventually these
scientists we were able to I think to
persuade him that it was really worth
the effort because you know literally
the idea of having to grow cannabis at
UC Davis in the present context was so
so hard for a scientist who is busy now
you could have
even I also see it from this perspective
we are not in a for-profit start
structure like my two esteemed panelists
nonprofit or profit but you know you're
dedicated to to the study of cannabis we
can do other things and that's why my
colleagues my friends asked me why
you're doing it let me say just a few
words why I am doing this because it's
good to see the challenges but it's also
important to understand that these
challenges are worth overcoming because
what we have here I think is a
phenomenal opportunity I would say a
historical opportunity if it wasn't an
abused term but it is in a sense
historical because not so many times in
the life of a person or a country there
is the situation we have now where an
entire host of chemicals produced by a
plant have been closed to research into
perusal by scientist and by to use by
clinical investigators for almost a
hundred years and all of a sudden this
is opening slowly but surely because
that's the trend this is opening and we
don't even know the questions that we
need to ask that's I think that is the
amazingly interesting think about this
is that we are opening a new window on
the brain and the body we discovered the
endogenous cannabinoids system we we
have the opportunity of creating in new
classes of analgesics that could be if
not replacing certainly complementing
the operates which are causing an
epidemics that is destroying our country
we could be opening a window on new
cheers for new diseases like no new
cures for all diseases like autism like
forms of epilepsy and all this I think
you know because this brand and its
components and what it means for science
have been actually closed
to research for since 1937 you know
since the enactment of the marijuana Tax
Act under the FDR administration so this
is why I think we as scientists are so
excited about this I know I know Thomas
I know I am the rest the other panelists
I also believe are just like I am and
that's why I think we we can put up with
this BS because it's really if you think
about it's really BS it is BS and I'll
tell you why I tell you why because if
as a scientist I want to do research on
cannabis I have to go through all these
hoops but in an federally funded
institution in a public institution or a
private institution it receives funds
from the federal government this is what
I have to do everybody else doesn't I
mean you have issues cultivating I
understand that you have issues passing
the state borders I understand that but
if I was in a private lab in Irvine
California instead of being at
University of California Irvine and I
wanted to do any type of research on
cannabis I could if I had my own funding
I could so now why is that a problem it
is a problem to me because I believe
that the fact that the vast majority of
scientists in this country who are
funded at the federal government by the
NIH NSF etc cannot take a look at this
plant means that somebody else will and
those who will be looking and not
necessarily the people that we want to
be looking at this problem because they
come to the question with an agenda and
we shouldn't have that agenda we should
have no agenda our only agenda should be
get the data understand what's happening
well I could probably go on for another
hour so I better stop so after we had
this research task force in Oregon and
we know we're trying to ask the question
how can researchers medical researchers
who generally exist
at federally funded universities how can
they do studies that with human subjects
that actually use the cannabis that is
available to people instead of isolated
cannabinoids which we know act
differently or the terrible terrible
weed that has grown at University of
Mississippi and there really is no
concrete wait so many researchers are
getting really creative you know they
they're doing observational studies
they're pushing the limits of how much
they can suggest to their subjects of
the observational studies what kind of
products they should buy and there's a
group in Colorado that is getting people
high in a van outside the University
before they bring them in and put them
in the brain scanner but they have to do
it on the street there's some people are
getting very creative but in general
there's no way to get people the actual
plant that they're gonna be exposed to
and so what we realized is that we you
know we could get all that if we wanted
to do to plant work we could get it done
more effectively in a company where we
just don't face all those restraints and
also because you know we're not working
directly with human subjects we don't
face the incredible array of some of
them very reasonable restraints that the
federal government puts on how you do
human subjects research
but our job is to figure out how to
understand the plant and feed the plant
into those medical research pathways how
to make plants that have high levels of
these other cannabinoids that we want to
study and how to characterize the plants
in a way that makes the studies data
understandable so for instance we're
working with a group at that the Oregon
Health and Science University now that's
trying to do a controlled a semi
controlled observational study where
they know what varieties people are
taking they can't administer themselves
that the plant themselves but they they
want to know what people are taking but
as you guys know no one knows
what anything is there's thousands of
different varieties so we're genetically
testing the varieties to try to feed
those in the studies so that the
researchers can know that at least
everyone's getting the same genetically
identical plant so there are all those
problems to solve and one thing I just I
want people to be clear about is that
there's this whole raft of terrible
regulatory problems but that's not
that's only half of it the other problem
is that we're actually just dealing
scientifically with an incredibly
complicated subject
so the endocannabinoid system is really
really complex there are many receptors
that do many many things and then on the
plant side there are thousands and
thousands of different kinds of cannabis
and they have you know perhaps dozens of
active or potentially active molecules
at different ratios in each plant and so
it's just combinatorially a hard
scientific question to do control
studies with anyway and when you merge
that with the regulatory problems it
it's really difficult but I think it's
important for the industry to know I
mean a lot of you out there people who
are trying to make products and you're
making them without much knowledge you
know like right now there's this new
wave of people trying to make products
that have THC V in them because we think
that's awesome
we have hints we have a friend who
smoked it it was amazing but we don't
know right and we just don't know what's
gonna happen once we actually get data
about that cannabinoid and maybe it
works or maybe it doesn't it maybe it
only works if you also have this much
limonene and this much beta care you
finally mixed in in the same dose and we
just don't know and we're not going to
know for a while but the industry is
going to be reliant on researchers
figuring all this stuff out you know in
a big way it's the project of the
cannabis industry to map all the
complicated universe of cannabis
varieties and all the compounds in there
and all the combinations to map that
complexity to the complexity of human
reactions and human medical conditions
and we are so far from doing that and
the industry is so far out ahead of us
making stuff and trying it that one
whole other source of research data is
going to be from the industry and we
have this kind of unprecedented
opportunity to pull in big data from the
industry which is being allowed to give
people stuff and if we can find ways to
pull in that information for instance
the kind of study that Sue is doing
which is trying to set up this network
of patient data pulling in data like
that from people who are using all the
products out there on the industry
that's not a controlled study but
there's a new world of big data where we
can pull in so much data and it can be
messy and dirty but if it's big enough
we can we can tease out what matters and
feed that back in so so that's the other
thing that I just want to say is that
doing this research is really difficult
and we need the industry to care about
it and we need the industry to help
because you guys actually are in a
position regardless of what we think
about the the night of cannabis at least
in our studies many years ago we did see
a positive effect so it's not saying our
better strains etc but still even
whatever you think of the night of
cannabis we still saw th the effects on
I'm really difficult to treat conditions
since you just said that can I had one
thing so we just tested it genetically
we got a sample from one of the
remaining patients and we we sequenced
it and it um it is 96% skunk skunk it's
straight skunk and we talked to David
Watson who was the creator of skunk and
he said that actually many many years
ago um under a DEA license that the Ole
Miss had shipped some seeds to I don't
know how they weakened it so much but
yeah but it's real cannabis well it
might say
other strains produce I'm just making a
point but to echo sort of the challenges
of doing this type of research when we
wanted to do a study looking at a high
CBD treatment the night of the farm
ultimately developed a 16% plant and
that we ran into conflict with the FDA
who had concerns about the safety that
there wasn't adequate human safety
trials and vaporized and smoking high
CBD so then we had to go through a
negotiation to come up with a compromise
of to 8% set cetera but there are
challenges that getting high CBD content
out of Mississippi particularly when it
comes to being kind of oral treatment
they now have an extract I think they
have going and then the last thing I
just want to echo is the frustration
amongst all of us in terms of being able
to access real world cannabis so in
addition to the medical side which were
very interested at CMC are I commented
that we're also interested in public
safety and from edibles to infuse drinks
etc we cannot touch those products at
all to either see what's in them or to
see what effects are either cognitive or
medicinal a Bennett medical benefits and
so forth so it is a very frustrating
situation find out so I think we've
really covered the idea that the sole
source from Ole Miss has been a real
challenge as far as getting research to
the level that we'd like to see it at as
well as the challenges of getting
materials across you know across states
and into different territories well one
of the things I think that we didn't
really touch on I think is something
that's super key to the industry itself
is the idea of moving money right
cannabis companies have a hard time
moving money because you can have a bank
and so speaking from our experience as a
as a publicly traded cannabis company we
are fortunate to have relationships
where we're sponsoring its industry
sponsored research and we're working
with eight different come different
universities in the US and abroad and
the biggest challenge we have is what to
do with the money or how to transfer the
money and I imagine that all of you have
your own experience with funding or lack
of funding or moving money and I would
you any of you care to jump on that one
the Center for the city of cannabis at
UC Irvine has a legal component and that
component is heavily interested in the
issue of banking in in the cannabis
industry unfortunately the person who
runs the illegal part of the center is
not here his name is Professor Robert
Solomon and he's not here today but this
is clearly a matter that deserves a
conversation that must be started and it
has already started must be expanded
state-by-state
there are ways in my limited
understanding there are ways through
which we can overcome the current
restrictions they do not require any
major intervention from the federal
government however how feasible those
ways are is a matter that legal experts
adjudicate in very different ways so
what has predominated so far has been a
very conservative outlook basically
stopping short any attempt to change the
status quo but I am optimistic
especially because revenues are at stake
here important state revenues are at
stake and important issues are at stake
how do you pay taxes and we know that
our regulators our our lawmakers want to
tax money so I am optimistic that
something will change in that direction
I think pretty soon if I could also
bring my very very limited very small
experience as director of the Center for
the Study of cannabis we we reached out
to cannabis companies and we had a
overwhelmingly positive positive
response everybody wanted to help us in
some way or another and then we reached
out to our own University of California
Office of the President
and ask them and that was probably
mistaken I'm just kidding
ask them I always say it's always better
to ask for forgiveness than for
permission right but you know we did ask
their opinion honestly and they were
understandably very very cautious yeah
they they said well you know if it comes
from the selling the cultivating the
distributing of cannabis you cannot take
any money not even as a gift
so put a cannabis company work if they
aren't doing any of those things it's
that so but they to the interesting
anyone that goes on on a positive note
the interesting thing is that there is
money involved and when there is money
involved people get motivated so even
even the office of the president of my
great institution even though they are
very conservative they would like to
change things they just want to see some
light at the end of the tunnel and of
course I don't want to bring up this
issue a political issue here but with
the current political scenario with the
current Attorney General there is quite
quite hard it's a quite hard stance to
take when you have against you the
Department of Justice just globally the
research funding available in the US has
traditionally been available only to
study cannabis as a drug of abuse so
this is what we've been up against
trying to do efficacy trials on cannabis
we've never gotten government money to
study efficacy until just recently got
our first government grant from the
state of Colorado but again it's the
states that are taking the initiative to
study efficacy the federal government
there's very little more only recently
have we seen federal government money
available small amounts to study
cannabis as a substitution for opioids
and but those are fairly small grants
and I really applaud you know Tom and
CMC are there work I mean they have done
all the most of the seminal studies
looking at cannabis as as a medicine as
looking at efficacy and safety in the
same studies
so their work I don't we would hardly
have any efficacy at all if it weren't
for the California state funding of CMC
our many years ago and they're now
renewed funding so I'm hoping you know
the reason we have data is because of
these guys here that are doing this work
but I want to point out that you know in
Cal in Canada we see Canadian al P's
allocating millions of dollars to study
cannabis as a medicine now this is a big
game-changer I think that will help and
they understand that paying for clinical
trials means millions of dollars when
industry people in the US
tell dr. ple that they want to help fund
his research I think they're looking at
you know maybe a ten thousand dollar
grant or maybe you know five or ten
grand
they don't understand to do a controlled
trial is millions of dollars that the
study we're doing right now
a simple FDA Phase two trial with only
76 subjects is 2.2 million dollars and
that's a very you know low-budget trial
so you just have to you know industry
has to be aware that when they say they
want to fund controlled trials that
they're looking at millions of dollars
maybe not for your work but but
generally that's what it costs for human
trials I completely agree with sue about
the funding being sort of few and far
between we have been fairly fortunate
recently sort of this take-home study
looking at vaporized cannabis versus
dronabinol actually is funded by NIDA
surprisingly enough and this other
studies that are more mechanistic
looking a bipolar disorder and HIV
neuropathic pain are also NIH funding so
there's a little movement in the
direction to look at non sort of
addictive behaviors but it's still not
very much money so I just want to point
out from a high level that even though I
think it's really really good that
companies are trying to fund research
that was our decision was that we could
get this research done more effectively
inside a company than in any other way
and the LP is in Canada have enough
money and the universities there can do
and companies like GV Sciences are
pushing hard to do real research and all
of that is critical and it's gonna be
critical for a few years but I just want
us all to keep in mind that there's a
reason why in the rest of the research
world the government funds basic
research and then when that research
gets far enough along that it can be it
can turn into something applied the
private sector takes it over and brings
things to market and that's how the
world works and that's fine but the
reason why basic research is funded by
the government is because it's really
expensive and the first many stages in
most research programs are nowhere near
a product it's the basic research that
lays the groundwork and companies don't
want to pay for that basic research
because it's too many years away from
any product and if it gets done in
universities with federal funding you
can do those years of basic research and
you can do them in a way that is
impartial and not you know prone to
being shifted in any way by commercial
interests so we're going into this phase
now where a lot of the research on
cannabis is gonna be funded by companies
and I think up most of us are
well-intentioned but that's not how
research should really be done it should
be done by universities without
commercial pressures driving them to
come up with certain results so we need
to get through this period and
ultimately the research should go away
from you and me angel these guys agree
one of the things we were talking about
sort of as a group is that the cannabis
industry is sort of plagued by
pseudoscience and I think that's really
what you're talking about is because
there's that absence of a large database
of that basic science happening like in
other fields things fill in the gap and
so with anyone else like to talk if you
don't mind I have a comment on
I don't want to give this audience the
the impression that when we are dealing
with the federal government we are
dealing with a monolithic structure mono
ideological structure of course you know
the federal government is influenced by
the administration that's because that's
their boss right but it doesn't mean
that people within don't have their very
articulated and strong opinions that
they temporarily keep you know under
wrap but eventually can and will I think
I'm out I've been working with the
National Eastern and drug abuse for
example for the last twenty years and
been a member of their national advisory
panel I've been on study sections I know
very well and I'm friendly with their
scientific director with director Nora
walk-up I know where they're standing on
this matter they're concerned of course
about the use of cannabis but they're
also cognizant of the potential
applications the potential health
applications they are cognizant but
don't forget their job their mission is
not to fund Studies on the health
effects of cannabis the positive effects
of canvas they're called the National
Institute on Drug Abuse they have a
mission and they have to study abusable
drugs of abuse part is what they care
about so what we're really missing when
it comes to the federal government is
first of all political will that is the
first thing and second we are missing an
inter Institute agency through the NIH
through including the NSF Cancer
Institute the FDA the look says in a
unified thoughtful intelligent way and
has some a part has a portfolio so it
has the ability to access funding
because this is not something about drug
abuse or something about mental health
or something about neurological
disorders or something about cancer it's
something about each of those things
together and ultimately scientists
people with experience in the problem
must be able to make a recommendation
that can
be heard and that is where that's why
the National Academy of Science
Committee on the impact of cannabis that
was a member of decided you know wrote
as a recommendation the creation of a
research agenda on cannabis that brings
together all those federal stakeholders
and gives them a unified voice and
possibly unified portfolio as well so
let's be let's look at the at the
federal government with some positivity
I know it's hard right now but let's try
and make that effort because I think
that's that's that's really really
important the last topic that we wanted
to sort of address was many people may
be following the medical cannabis
research act of 2018 and one of the
things that it proposes to do is to
eliminate the sole source by forcing DEA
to admit at least two more certified
cultivator growers and also open up some
rights to the Veterans Affairs
Department I don't I would like at this
point to simply throw this one over to
the panel for those with those panel
members who would like to jump on that
and give their opinion I don't support
that bill even though I recognize that
this could be symbolically the end of
the monopoly with University of
Mississippi but the fact that they're
only agreeing to license to new growers
for research and they're probably going
you know this is just basically just
creating a corporate monopoly on top of
what is already an existing University
monopoly of Mississippi so I'm not a fan
of this I think the only right thing to
do is for the government to properly
adjudicate all 25-plus applications that
have been sitting on their desk and
evaluate all of them in terms of merit
in terms of quotas and and let's do this
properly when I apply for a de a
Schedule one license as a researcher
every single application gets evaluated
it's not like we just say oh we're gonna
look at these two application you know
just pick the the two best if you have
a properly approved protocol a
scientific protocol and you will be
approved for a DEA schedule one license
as a researcher which is what we have
but to say I'm only going to take two I
think it's it's a it's a bad model and
it's it looks like you know it this has
been created by some of Gates's donors
to to ensure that they get a license and
I think it's really unfair but we do
need to end this monopoly and I'm hoping
someday you know the same way till Ray
exported study you know or its planning
to export drug for Toms tremor study
maybe some day till ray will agree to to
export flower into the US and then we
can finally break the monopoly on flower
and force the government to license
other growers so I've been wondering um
even if they do license to other grows
aren't they just gonna aren't the laws
gonna be such that they have to get
their starting material from Mississippi
anyway that's assuming although I spoke
to dr. L solely who runs the University
of Mississippi lab and he said that he
refuses to sell starter material because
he said that that's their IP so the
University of Mississippi has it not
that anybody would want their genetics
anyway but the point is that that's
taxpayer dollars going that have gone to
support this monopoly and now he's
saying that it's protected as their IP
and they're not willing to share it so I
have no I think they in in our
application we had to list which foreign
entities we were gonna buy from so we
have to purchase genetics from outside
the US I like to make two points one is
immediately related to the previous
speakers and is not a scientific point
but I'll still like to make it and it's
the following so if we you know think
about the Soviet Union the Soviet Union
was a socialistic
country so property was entirely owned
by the state and then it became a
private country so in that process not a
lot of good things
happen right I think we have to be a
little bit thinking about about that
model as we consider the passage from a
state monopoly to now a new situation
where there is no monopoly and there are
private individuals bidding or working
to get to get a piece of the public of
the cake now the reason why I think this
is so important is because let's not
forget that a lot of the folks who were
growing canopies were folks from
minorities from underrepresented
minorities and these folks are more and
more excluded from the business and they
don't have a voice because the cannabis
industry has a voice can be more or less
audible but isn't is a voice but these
folks tend to not to have a voice and I
think I think the one thing they would
be terrible if I'm thinking petit about
the state of California if moving
forward we got into a situation from a
monopoly of the state to an oligopoly
from from large corporations and some of
the folks who have been part of this
industry forever now would be penalized
so that's the first thing there is a
scientific point that the thank you the
scientific point I think is I'd love to
hear your comments about it and also
your comments about it as if especially
as a geneticist because I am NOT a plant
geneticist so I read and what I read I
may or may not understand so here is
what I the problem that I have with
cannabis is that we have hemp and then
we have marijuana right with an H this
is how the federal government defer
divides the plant right marijuana in
hemp and they are knowledge it's the
same thing but I think they are
knowledge it at the same time they deny
it and to me understanding the diversity
of the plant before we take any measure
or at least at the same time as we take
measures to ant
pack this monopoly I think it's really
really important we still don't know and
Duke magalie correct me if I'm wrong but
we still don't know
if a plant has more THC than it does CBD
there is an enzyme that makes either of
them there's one enzyme for one and
other enzyme for another they have a
shared precursor why some strains have
one more of one and why some strains are
more than another is there how the
environment can affect that and how this
plays out with the other a hundred
Andrew cannabinoids number growing that
are present in the plant like an urban
are very we will kind of be devouring
that was mentioned before so there is no
talk even at the federal level and they
know because I've been talking to folks
in DC about this there is no talk of
looking at this from a scientific
scientific perspective and asking so
what is this thing what is this plant
how is it that he has these properties
those things we can figure out and we're
starting to so we know how many copies
of the THC synthase and the CBD synthase
are in those plants now and you know
we're tracking down all the metabolic
pathways and then in the future if we're
gonna have whole plant medicine it'll be
a genetically defined plant where we
know okay this is a plant that makes
these compounds because it has these
genes and those are knowable things
right yeah and we're getting there so a
while back the governor of New Jersey
said when they legalized cannabis in New
Jersey that it should be grown at
Rutgers Rutgers said they couldn't do it
because the federal government would cut
off their federal money and recently I
believe that Jerry Brown vetoed a bill
that would have allowed universities in
California grow their own cannabis I
wonder what you think about the New
Jersey recommendation and I wonder what
you think about Governor Brown vetoing
is this bill that about two days ago
Brown vetoed a bill that would have
allowed universities in California to
grow their own cannabis obviously that
would have put California on a collision
course with the federal government and
Brown apparently didn't want to do that
but the looks like the legislature
understood what dr. Sicily is talking
about that we need if we're going to do
research we need to let the researchers
grow cannabis in fact the DEA
administrative law judge when it came to
the University of Massachusetts said
yeah
let dr. cracker grow his own cannabis I
mean this is absurd we're talking about
research here we're not talking I'm
talking about crummy 4% cannabis that is
grown in the University of Mississippi
I'll just I'll just say that of all the
decisions that suck for all of us that
one I can understand because the the
reason why it's been so hard to do
research on cannabis in university I
mean correct me if I'm wrong has been a
feeling that you're a federally funded
University and if you piss off the
federal government too much you could
lose your funding and get no research
done and the UC system has been way more
aggressive than any other universities
anywhere but they've also been very
careful about it one thing that no
university has done is just start to
grow with the plan and and I think if a
university went that and that's the most
frustrating thing for me but I think if
any university went that far they would
be in concrete danger of being shut down
or having their funding stopped by by
the feds and so I think that was a
pragmatic decision different experience
so we're working with at LSU the LSU AG
center and unders the state regulated
program there the university is allowed
to grow and we're doing our private
vendor so you're a private banner okay
so there are models that but it's not on
campus a hybrid model okay but there are
let's say there's workarounds even that
blows my mind I'm really impressed with
with Louisiana for doing that maybe
right here in Louisiana I'm not sure if
you can if you're in California
but in my understanding of the veto
going back to the question and this
might I might be wrong but I read the
letter that Governor Brown wrote and it
specifically blocked a bill that was
authorizing expenditure of two million
dollars per year to my friends here at
the University of California San Diego
and the reason why the reason why were
they were they were made for vetoing it
was not in opposition to science was the
fact that there wasn't what Prop 64 had
explicitly explicitly stated and so
there is some politics behind this I
think the Bureau of cannabis control
which is the agency that has been
nominated to create it to really
implement prop 64 I think they for some
reason feel that they are in charge of
the entire part of money but this might
be my over interpretation of that the
fact it was my remote understanding that
that's why it ended up being this is
1996 vetoed what sort of complexities of
matching up what cm CR was gonna do via
prop 64 or other mechanisms and there
was some confusion I don't think as
Danielli says I don't think was specific
to cultivation and stopping that there's
a lot of people that are looking for
sources of cannabinoids outside of the
cannabis plant whether it's synthesizing
it in the laboratory growing it from
strains of hops or using East to grow
cannabinoids I wanted to get your take
and see if you think that this is
something that will pave the way for
more widespread open research or if it's
something that would keep it in the
hands of corporate research and
pharmaceutical companies so there's a
few different ways people are trying to
get cannabinoids besides the cannabis
plant there are companies that are
trying to put the genes that make all of
the necessary parts that can have
annoyed pathway into East it's hard for
me to imagine that those are going to
scale up in a way that adds up
economically because the cannabis plant
is an incredible production engine so I
don't know what will happen with that if
that becomes the dominant way the
cannabinoids are made
that'll centralize control of that in
the hands of companies but the plant
will still exist there is also now a
bunch of cannabis
[Music]