please welcome dr. Pierre frog's so I'm
delighted to be here truly it's a
wonderful city I'm really grateful that
I did take a taxi this morning to get
here I'm on the same page as you are
with with the homelessness it's tragic
to see and I'm really delighted that
you're trying so hard to do something
about it I think it's a real eye-opener
not to say that we don't have the same
problem in in Canada but of course the
snow and the cold does make it slightly
different
I'm also cloud proud to be here because
I guess so who's a basketball guys here
or ladies anybody follow basketball here
No
so our star guy and the Raptors is here
now right not too happy about that
that's that's really quite a shame so
I'm here for the next 2530 minutes to
share with you uh-huh
a little higher okay I'm here to share
with you my my experience as you know in
Canada we just recently legalized it
both for recreational as well as for
medical purposes
we tried before and and we had in 2001
regulations that led to some some abuse
of the regulations in terms of growing
and so on so then they changed it and
they the new regulations didn't allow
for personal cultivation and then
finally in 2016 I think we finally got
it right so a lot of what I'm going to
present to you today is an offshoot of
that a lot of the work that I do is in
nursing homes and of course even though
cannabis for medical use is legal in
Canada since 2016 as you can expect in
nursing homes policies had to be built
around the use so the data I have to
present to you is limited on account of
that but nevertheless I think it speaks
volumes about where
since it became an open field so we say
the number of LPS has has grown in fact
I have here 194 I think that recently
it's actually 196 it's it's spread
across the country which is kinda nice
but as you'll see it's it's spread
through mostly British Columbia and
Ontario and the Albertans I think are
discovering a new sort of oil cannabis
oil right there into oil anyway so the
LPS are at various stages of approval
some haven't yet built and some are
actually producing in Canada the federal
government and Health Canada have played
a very important role in trying to get
this moving
I think it speaks volumes and I'm really
quite proud of the Canadian government
and particularly Health Canada and if
you go to their site you'll see that
there's a load of information there
which is very useful now I want to speak
to you about that for just a few seconds
so if if you click on their site here
getting cannabis for medical purposes
and or prescribing cannabis to patients
you see that there's a lot of
information for healthcare professionals
right I think this is a really positive
step the federal government is actually
out there providing guidance to
physicians and other healthcare
professionals I want to focus however on
what it says below here so I think it's
a bit of a disclaimer cannabis is not an
approved therapeutic product which it's
not right it's not a therapeutic product
unless a specific cannabis product has
been issued a DIN right a drug
information number and a notice of
compliance then it's it's it's not a
therapeutic product the provision of
this information should not be
interpreted as endorsement of the use of
this product or cannabis and
cannabinoids generally by
Canada so the it's a bit of a disclaimer
but the reality is they're really there
to support physicians health care
workers and patients alike so if you dig
a little further and you you go to
information a summary of the essential
information about the use you'll see a
lot of information but what I'm very
interested in is this list here so
Health Canada actually has a list of
possible therapeutic areas for the use
of medical cannabis and I want to focus
a couple of on a couple of things so
number one palliative care and quality
of life as you heard earlier I went
through a number of phases in my life
going from emergency medicine all the
way to geriatric medicine and really I
spent a lot of my time now looking after
people trying to make sure that their
last days are comfortable and that I can
provide to them the most quality of care
as possible and that's where I find I'm
having the most success with with
medical cannabis so so it really
delights me to see this is at the top of
the list of course we've heard about
epilepsy I've I will tell you a little
bit about some experience I've had with
multiple sclerosis pain I'm interested
in particularly chronic pain and then
the psychiatric disorders particularly
anxiety sleep and and Alzheimer's is
what I'm going to be talking to you
about the most I wish I could talk to
you about everything here but
unfortunately I don't quite have all
that experience yet I do also want to
point out that no list would be complete
at least not from Health Canada if it
didn't have a few warnings and if it
taught didn't talk a little bit about
adverse effects so in Canada not
everybody is on board if you go to the
site of the Royal College which is the
site for the specialists you'll find
that if you click on cannabis for
medical use click it actually gets you
right back to Health Canada so so
they're not they're just saying mom
they're not saying anything about it the
College of Physicians
the Canadian College of Family
Physicians rather has stepped out
they've they've published guidelines a
year or two ago and and unfortunately
their view is very cautious shall we say
in fact they say the evidence indicates
the most consistent effects of medical
cannabinoids are adverse events a
variety of adverse events have a greater
magnitude of effect than the potential
benefits for the conditions targeted
which is very interesting the
conclusions drawn by this analysis are
not surprising study after study which
is not true because there isn't study
after studies I'll show you right
analysis after analysis and review after
review have all reported the same
findings cannabis has little place
within current therapeutic Arsenal's I
beg to differ I don't I don't agree with
that unfortunately and this is really
one of my key messages is we need the
research right we really need good
clinical research so moving south of the
border to the National Academies of
Sciences and engineering and medicine
it's it's quite the same cautionary tale
right so they say here despite increased
cannabis use and changing state level
policy landscape conclusive evidence
regarding the short and long term health
effects both harms and benefits of
cannabis use remains elusive I think for
those people who like myself are
currently using it prescribing it to
patients there's very little doubt of
the efficacy unfortunately it's just not
proven the way that we would like to see
it proven for products that are
currently marketed right alright so
there was this guy
Plato right and he said the mind is a
chariot steered by reason but pulled by
passions and in keeping with the
Hippocratic oath I strongly believe that
I have to provide my patients with those
things that are
to them that will help them in their
suffering and so it is that a more
modern physician said prescribing
medical cannabis should be steered by
clinical science and pulled by patients
needs unfortunately or fortunately
rather than the patient's needs are
there but I think the science is still
lacking and I'm hoping that after today
you'll all be convinced that we need to
go out there we need to push the
institutions private-public to get out
there and give us more research and and
really to fund the research that needs
to be done okay so in the elderly what
have I been doing well I've been looking
after patients and I'll tell you a
little bit about about dementia in a
minute but I've been looking after
elderly patients who suffer from
insomnia agitation in dementia which
I'll talk to you a bit more anxiety pain
and parkington's disease so show me the
evidence let's talk about what I was
able to find out there first of all I
think it's important to understand what
the constraints are on doing clinical
research right so need i say more about
that first heading there's limited
funding it's not because the money is
not out there it is out there it's just
who wishes to use that money for
clinical research very poor
standardization of product and and I'll
show you of what I mean by that in just
a minute
questionable compliance of subjects it's
very hard to do a clinical trial in
somebody with with cannabis if on you
know at home they're also also smoking
it so so compliance is a huge issue
there's a lot of confounders that are
difficult to to control of course
there's not just age and gender but
there's comorbidities there's other
medications there's activities and so on
and so forth so good research takes into
account the confounders that we need to
look after searching for an indication
here
I mean III think that you saw that list
from Health Canada there's an awful lot
of possibility but I think we're gonna
have to be really systematic here I
think we shouldn't be funding everything
I think we need to drill down try to see
what we think as a society are the
greatest needs prioritize and move down
the other thing is in searching for an
indication when you do clinical research
you have to say what is my outcome
measure
what difference am I trying to show it's
not enough to say that people felt
better and I think that's to a certain
extent been the problem so far
a choice of control arm are we going to
do the research compared to another fire
to a pharmaceutical or is it to a
placebo etc etc at the standard of care
and as I said just a minute ago we
really do need validated outcome tools
what are we studying what outcomes do we
want to look at okay so let me talk a
little bit about Parkinson's disease
Parkinson's disease is very interesting
because the the cb1 receptors are very
dense in the basal ganglia which is
where the substantia nigra is which is
where the disease of Parkinson's is I
think it's very interesting to see that
all those receptors are there and there
is some suggestion that the cb1 agonist
attenuate that levodopa induced
dyskinesia so levodopa is a medication
that's given to patients with
parkinson's disease to relieve their
symptoms it is not a cure and and to
date I've only been able to find one
study from 2004 that actually looked at
that and their study was frankly not
conclusive so I think I think more work
needs to be done in that area of course
the patients that I've been treating
with Parkinson's all have all are all
taking levodopa we have seen some
studies and I'll show you some of those
that that shown efficacy in Parkinson's
disease in treating some of the symptoms
of tremor rigidity and
Radek Indonesia which is that that slow
movement that they have and there's some
question as to whether or not cannabis
might not have neuroprotective effects
via an antioxidant effect so clinical
trials and again very difficult to
really pinpoint where they are if
they're out there they're not in the
traditional literature I know that
Israel for instance has a lot of
programs ongoing but trying to get your
hands on some of that literature is very
difficult there was a study that
appeared in the Journal of
psychopharmacology by show gas in 2014
they looked at 21 patients they compared
I think they had two patients on placebo
versus 75 milligrams of CBD and or 300
milligrams the patients were treated for
six weeks they found no effect on on the
symptoms of Parkinson's but on quality
of life questionnaires they found quite
a quite a significant difference so okay
you weren't able to treat the symptoms
but you did improve the quality of life
which which is important right I think
that's an important finding yeah go
ahead no sorry it's a good point good
question actually was just a 300 yeah
and then lo 10 and again in 2014 in the
clinical neuropharmacology they looked
at 22 patients it was smoked cannabis
that that was the the trial and at 30
minutes later they saw improved rigidity
tremor and Bretta kinesia
which lasted for up to three hours yes
please
yesterday they were yeah
so-so
oh absolutely yeah yeah I mean I mean so
so it's that's a very good example of
what I mean by looking at outcomes right
if we're actually not able to cure
something but if we're able to decrease
the amount of medications that people
are taking particularly in Parkinson's
where tolerance to the medication
currently out there builds and
ultimately becomes less and less
effective it'd be really nice to be able
to reduce how much they take Oh big-time
big-time
big big time yeah you're totally right
so so you can see right here that
there's a bit of a problem right and
we're talking about research here so
here we're talking about giving CBD
we're talking about placebo here we're
talking about cannabis smoked we're
looking at 30 minutes rather than six
weeks out and so I think that's one of
the problems right now with with some of
the researchers I think we're gonna have
to get it down and see where we want to
go with with with this I answer that I
don't remember oh yes sure so he's
asking if it was what what what the
cannabis was was it flower or whatever
and I don't think it was detailed in
there unfortunately and again I think
that that speaks to the issue that I
have with the research it's just not
consistent right okay so be PSD who's
familiar with bee PSD okay so so I
always forget what be PSD stands for
because I I use the term be PSD so much
that I you know it's one of those things
to just use the acronym so it's it's
behavioral psychological symptoms of
dementia and in the patient population
that I'm treating this is a huge issue
we are currently giving what I consider
to be highly toxic drugs so everybody
here has heard about antipsychotics
right and the fact that we're giving
either antipsychotics or benzodiazepines
or other drugs that that change the
behavior of patients suffering from
dementia these are toxic substances and
I think if nothing else if we can find
something that we can give to them that
decreases some of the symptoms and that
is less toxic
why not right okay
well we can get into that you you you
can but it's preferable not to but
sometimes really yeah if they're having
hallucinations and so on sooner or later
you do have to and certainly when you're
getting cannabis you don't want to
increase the hallucinations so in a
study in 2016 in the Journal of
Alzheimer's disease there was an open
label add-on which means that whatever
they were on we added the cannabis right
there were 11 patients with dementia and
they receive daily cannabis oil and the
findings were interesting but of course
when you're talking about just 11
patients
there's just no power so this is really
more or less an observational study
which is very much like what I'm going
to show you that I've been doing and
then in another study in 2017 of course
this is using products that are already
marketed again the studies are very
small but it does seems like THC was
able to decrease the severity of
disturbed behavior and I found this one
interesting because this is a big issue
right sundowning so later in the day the
symptoms become far worse and it would
appear that that there may be some
effect in nighttime agitation huge study
to patients okay and what about sleep so
sleep and anxiety or what - I think my
favorite indications for using this so
sleep disturbances as you know are very
common it's not just in the elderly
though as we grow older it does become
more of a problem but up to 70 million
Americans are actually affected with
with sleep disturbances of all sorts
right I think for the physicians in the
room you know if you send a patient for
sleep study they're going to end up with
a mask I mean so so I think I think it'd
be much nicer to give him something
that's a little less invasive than those
mask forces with CPAP so 35% prevalence
of insomnia in the elderly far worse of
course in patients suffering from
dementia and
again in a review by the National
Academies of Sciences there appears to
be moderate evidence of effect of
medical cannabis on sleep disturbance
but here's the evidence Dern a banal
versus ME trip to lean of course
amitriptyline should not even be used in
the elderly in this patient population
and they had a moderate effect there and
I can NAB alone in fibromyalgia it
looked at the quality of sleep there
there's just no Studies on primary
insomnia there are no studies in
patients with dementia who have a huge
issue with with sleep how am i doing on
time I'm not seeing a oh there you how
much time left
all right 18 minutes that's great yeah
I'll make a fact so finally in anxiety
there was one study that was done with
600 milligrams versus placebo 24
patients now here's the outcome measure
right they looked at the effect of this
on anxiety prior to public speaking so
how applicable is it to social anxiety
disorder or other anxiety disorders
again very difficult to say and yet when
we talk about anxiety if you look on the
web you're gonna find a whole lot of
sites that preach to how good their
product is for anxiety and unfortunately
the evidence just isn't there yet though
I think we all have a you know a good
feeling that that it it would work and
finally in pain mark we're from from
McGill did a study in 2015 they were
actually looking at the side effects of
of providing medical cannabis they had
216 control patients 215 patients that
received cannabis with 12.5 percent THC
up to 5 grams per day so again it's a
little bit all over the map right people
were getting at they could use a little
bit more
but less it's difficult really to
quantitate how much they were getting
but here's what they found they they and
I'll show you about the pain but what
they did find is increased functionality
and improve mood so when you're thinking
about quality of life increasing
functionality and mood and check-check
that's pretty important and then if you
looked at at pain now they said that
they had an effect yeah okay well we'll
go with that but as you can see if you
look at the average pain intensity it's
sort of evens out so I I don't see and I
think really the problem here is that we
would need to do trials with far more
patients and we can't just be looking at
pain in general I think we need to
really hone it down what kind of pain
are we looking at chronic acute back
pain knee pain headache whatever so we
really need to hone it down and then
finally if you look at this study that
was just published very recently they
had a lot of patients this was a
registry they followed them for six
months and they looked at pain intensity
it decreased but here's the thing 18%
were able to stop opioids an opioid
analgesic that to me is phenomenal that
I like to see and of course increase the
quality of life there were some side
effects I don't think that there's
anything surprising there okay so why
nursing home patients I'm going to be
brief on this essentially now we have
policies allows us to move forward why
because they take a lot of toxic
medicines that I told you about and
believe it or not extremely receptive
when I started talking to elderly
patients or their families about using
this it was yeah let's do it and when I
was able to tell them that no they're
not gonna have to go outside and smoke
it that we have oil they were very very
keen and and I'm skipping ahead here but
the uptake for me so we started with one
and two and three and now it's weekly
twice weekly and in the nursing homes
that I'm in and I look after close to
200 people
it's almost daily now that I'm getting a
request for medical cannabis and a lot
of it is just word of mouth
so it is a controlled environment and it
is a monitored environment so it's a
nice place to actually do this because I
know that everything else is controlled
and and that if I'm seeing an effect
it's probably not because of some of the
confounders okay cannabis oil
oops sorry the prana talked about the
cons a little bit with some slides later
on it is expensive but Moy my god it's
difficult for the patients to get it
really is and I'm going to show you that
in just a minute and what's more it's
impossible for me to prescribe what the
licensed producers are making we're
completely disconnected and I'll show
you that in just a minute alright what
are my objectives
I just want to relieve pain anxiety
insomnia loss of appetite depression I
want to give them back their
functionality and potentially a little
bit of independence with their
activities of daily living and if we can
relieve some of the bps D that would be
fantastic because it means less toxic
drugs and part of the way of my
reasoning is is if I can take care of
these illnesses these mental health
issues am I going to impact the the
agitation that these people suffer one
of the things about patients with DeMint
is they can't tell you my knee hurts but
they can act out if you're able to treat
their insomnia or their anxiety which
they suffer a lot from it may mean that
in the end you're actually treating some
of the agitation and some of the
symptoms of dementia that they have I'm
just going to skip through that it's
just to say that it's a very very
controlled environment we have to keep
in mind that endocannabinoids have a
huge role to play in in the
cardiovascular system and that elderly
patients might be prone to some of the
side effects in particular you can get
hypotension and some dysrhythmia so I am
on the lookout for that to date I'm
pleased to say that I've had no issues
okay so as I said this is relatively new
in nursing home so my numbers are not
great but I do want to very quickly tell
you about some of the research and some
of the results that I've been having I
say research in fact it's all
observational right so I've been looking
after patients with anxiety insomnia and
agitation my numbers are small this is
the dosage range that I've been giving
of of the oil and the success rate has
been just tremendous just tremendous I'm
so pleased at how this has has been
working on let's leave the questions for
after okay
okay can you change it because this is
alright I've also used it in pain I will
say that one patient with spinal
stenosis decided not to take the CBD oil
but decided to vape and she had a
paradoxical increase in in pain it was
terrible and she never took it again so
I don't know really what happened there
but I have been looking after patients
with various pains and again getting
some relief multiple sclerosis oh my god
I've had only two patients but they've
responded so well I do use higher THC in
Parkinson's I've been I've had three
patients really only one out of three
had an improvement in some of the motor
symptoms but again am I at the right
dose that I used it for long enough etc
TMJ incidentally one of my patients who
had MS had their jaw and actually went
away which I thought was very
interesting and in progressive
supranuclear policy which is another
neurological disorder I didn't have any
success there okay totally subjective no
controls some of my patients are
cognitively impaired so a lot of the
information is either observed or told
to me by family or nurses and
unfortunately there's a very wide
variety of products received and I want
to talk to you about that because this
issue here of navigating the the web is
extremely difficult if you go and you
look at various LPS and I've just took
them randomly you can see that there's a
lot of products look at this trying to
figure out what THC and CBD they're
supposed to get and the list goes on
right so the list goes on thank you I
think I'll just change the slides again
here you can see THC CBD THC various
write various amounts change the slide
again this is one company again now
we're going up into the higher THC s but
it's very difficult for the patients to
navigate next slide please
this is candy Med so I like to prescribe
one in 10 THC
you CBD unfortunately I can't find it or
my patients can't find it and then some
of the LPS are saying well that's not
what you prescribed well okay
what do you have that resembles that
guys like really let's get with it
I want low THC high CBD clear enough
next slide please
again this is another manufacturer they
have two oils this one is is low THC
high CBD or low THC much higher CBD
again if they go to that site I'm not
allowed to tell them what site to go to
they have to go look I do try to tell
them how to do it but next slide please
and again one more extract this one is
with tilray and this one's completely
different they say ten of eight THC 25
THC 10 + 10 + 25 and 25 so I can't even
get the ratio with these guys next slide
please
alright as I said enthusiastic
population consistent care compliance
and monitored that's why research in
nursing homes with the elderly patients
is a great venue for doing good quality
research next slide please
and I want to say one other thing about
something completely different
I do addiction medicine I have about 300
or so patients that are addicted to
opioids 90% of them smoke pot 80% have
concomitant mental health disorders it's
a huge issue they smoke because it
relieves some of their symptoms why
can't we actually provide them with good
quality oils that may actually decrease
the amount of methadone that I have to
give them let's face it methadone is not
a walk in the park it's a toxic drug so
to finish then oh one more thing let's
not go down the Avenue of taking
particular cannabinoids and saying oh
this one's good for this this one's good
for that use but this one or that one
there's just no evidence let's just
stick with the oils for right now so my
conclusions
there is increasing demand for medicinal
cannabis use in long-term care my
patients are keen on it they want it and
we need to do the research what I showed
you is not research it's observational
only but I think there signals there and
I think it behooves us to go down that
path further we do need to have
validated tools we knew do need to have
standard I'd center dite dose
standardized doses right I can't be
prescribing one in 10 and they're
getting 25 or whatever is out there and
finally if I didn't say so already the
nursing home environment and the
patients they're in are a wonderful
environment for doing well controlled
well-designed clinical research and on
that note I think I will end I will be
around most of the day but if my email
is there and if you have questions you
whatever ideas whatever you want to
share and I'm happy to hear from you
yeah we
I write either I dazzle do with my
brilliance or I bath will do with my
bullshit you said 1 to 10 10 to 1 CBD
THC is what you would like to prescribe
I yes I I like to you know I really I'm
a novice right and so so I started down
the path of 1 and 10 which seemed to be
what was available and and I can't find
it so so now I'm having to actually go
back and change so that I can prescribe
what it is that the licensed producer is
able to supply to my patient it's see
that the way it works is in Canada I
have to you use the Health Canada like
form they have to take that form go to
the web find the licensed producer that
suits them best and then send in that
prescription and then get the feedback
so the other day actually one one and
I'll say their name Green relief they
actually wrote they R actually called me
and we had a great discussion and it was
really nice to talk with them and they
made some really smart suggestions and I
was able to get the prescription right
so kudos to Green movie that up there
it didn't identify what the ratio of the
cannabis was it records mentioned the
dosage it would we assume it was the 1
to 10 on those or no it's the wrong
stuff it's a very wrong assumption okay
you know it's a little more way more
randomized each producer has something
completely different which is a problem
right and and if I want to do some good
clinical work it's difficult for me
because I don't really know honestly
what I'm prescribing I know it's gonna
be low THC I know it's gonna be high CBD
ish but in the end from one patient to
another I don't know
Oh
how could you get these studies that
you're doing and I know they're
observational is what would be the
easiest way for you to maybe work with
some type of organization to get these
actually looked at more seriously and
maybe change a couple of things is that
a possibility so I don't know you but I
could just hug you for that question
right now
because actually it's something I want
yes so you didn't hear the question what
would it take ultimately to get the
research done so if I went to a
particular LP and I said look can you
fund my research they kind of say well
what's in it with me because ultimately
they'd be growing the market without
necessarily growing their piece of the
pie
however if all the LPS got together and
said together we're going to set up a
real in achill Research Fund and we're
going to take a certain percentage of
our profits of our revenues and put it
into that fund and then we will have a
committee that will decide based on the
research in the same way that national
organizations do it
physicians researchers would ask for
funding they'd have a study proposal and
that organization with the funds from
all the LPS would then allocate those
funds for various research projects so
it's not just one LP it's all of them
because in the end I think it benefits
us all and and if if the LPS grow the
market necessarily write their piece of
the action grows with it absolutely
absolutely absolutely yeah don't forget
the right deals at the Alzheimer's the
numbers in Canada are growing by twenty
five thousand people a year so if you
multiply that by ten in the US which is
generally the race who we use you're
getting two hundred and fifty thousand
more patients with Alzheimer's a year
that's a lot of nursing home care
now just make a comment I appreciate you
preliminary findings sort of like Des
Moines the extension at the same time we
need to also be look at the elderly
you know I grunt an elderly outpatient
clinic and you know I'm thinking about
the patient with osteoarthritis who
can't take an NSAID because they have an
impaired clinic liver and renal function
and if I give them an opioid they're
gonna fall and break their hip yep
so we again I'm gonna call just like you
although they Eve although the ability
control variables is less we need to
think about what you're showing us in
patients who are older so I have eighty
eight year olds 92 year old extremely
accepting and exciting about the
improvement in their quality of life I
agree I agree okay thank you that's
that's our last question thank you so
much doctor
[Applause]