there's another interesting aspect about
Canadian law people don't really
understand if you take them to a small
trial in the United States and your your
formulation shows efficacy you are then
required to go the FDA render you can't
take it to the market it's now shown
efficacy you have to go through the full
whole-hog FDA testing in Canada and
that's hundreds of millions of dollars
in Canada we can take some of our
formulations do a trial a small trial
that shows that it's efficacious and go
a nutraceutical route it starts selling
it immediately and making claims of what
it does based on the documented study
that we did that's an avenue the United
States's approach keeps medicine off the
shelves keeps remedies officer