so why is that well it
look at cannabis there's about how many
cannabinoids are we up to now anybody
you know so you know people say 120
whatever pick a number but it's
something over a hundred now
cannabinoids are active ingredients in
the cannabis plant well so go ahead name
off a couple of cannabinoids THC CBD
they're getting the press but then
there's a whole bunch more like CPG in
CBN and CBC and THC a and all these ones
with funny names and turns out that if
you look at them closely and that's
starting to happen that the properties
they have multiple properties also so I
was just taking a look at CB G's can of
it all just for the fun of it and
noticing that if you look at the added
it's practically a match up for THC and
CBD
as far as that eight or ten properties
that have been recognized so far in CB g
well CPG is virtually an unknown player
right I mean it's and then CBC is it
they're all except for THC and CBD
simply take let's say there's a honey
there's 100 cannabinoids we have two
players okay and the rest are you know
ride the bench and or either never
signed up or I don't know you know if
you use a baseball analogy the rest a
bunch of riding the bench and then a
bunch of never even heard of the game so
so we're sort of partway into this and
let's take to CBD for a second okay back
to the good old CBD cannabidiol so you
all know what this is you haven't
putting those with CBD is right so CBD
was in for us help me out here if I
screw something up okay
CBD was was discovered to be in the
cannabis plant and in well centuries ago
is in pretty good amounts then plants
were bred for THC and CBD was forgotten
didn't seem to have a yes then it was
rediscovered then it was found that it
had all these amazing properties some of
which we can share with you
and then plants started getting bread
for CBD so I want to really emphasize
that plants were bred for higher CBD and
higher and higher so that's been
happening and that's going to happen
with other cannabinoids and it's not
only gonna happen with cannabis it's
gonna happen with him they're already
doing that messing around
breeding hemp nope there's also a source
of CBD well it turns out it's got a lot
of other little cannabinoids hanging out
in it and you can breathe that for those
in that there's people doing that too
just to keep your eyes open on that so
we got that going on so if you kind of
look at how far CBDs come well when they
start breeding CBG and XYZ cannabinoids
what's gonna happen well it's just gonna
I would I don't even know Drupal or
whatever quadrupled the uses of cannabis
and hemp it's like you kind of get that
kind of get that drift yet where we're
going with this it's like let's see okay
let's do the properties of CBD go ahead
call them out yeah yeah it's anxiety
uh-huh anti pain neuro protective
protective of neurons in the brain
neurogenesis is able to create help
create new neurons and on and on like
that so so now all those properties of
CBD were not known when CBD came out
correct and I think some of the one of
the more exciting ones if you're gonna
mention it yeah who we're gonna the
mention is it's what we're learning the
CBD has elite effects that we really
didn't know why because CBD actually
doesn't interact with a lot of
abra receptors in the same way yeah one
of the things that's been discovered
recently is CBD D is a powerful reuptake
inhibitor and some of that can you have
to be careful well do we find in the
kids with seizures because it'll
actually prevent some anti-seizure drugs
from being metabolized right which can
be a problem so CBD is not gonna harm
you but if we have the benzodiazepines
raising in your system that those to
potentially harm but what they're
finding with the anti-anxiety some of
the depression benefits people plant
some CBD it also works as a relay
converter for our natural endogenous
cannabinoids so you know I know how down
the science road we want to get but I'm
sure everyone here has heard of the
endocannabinoids system and we know that
our body produces endogenous
cannabinoids weaning from within the
body it's nothing to do with cannabis
people are relatively familiar with an
and amide and to Iraq the Dino glycerol
there's others Paul McCoy of'em ethanol
mine some other sits that are not as
well known but what CBD actually they're
finding is doing is it's slowing the
body's ability to react take Amanda mine
and to a record I know glycerol so
they're having this buildup in the body
that is actually allowing the body to
utilize your natural endogenous
cannabinoids
so it's indirectly raising the
cannabinoids in your body that someone
might be deficient in and has this
amazing effects because if your
endogenous cannabinoids are raised it's
gonna be able to correct at a higher
rate malfunctions of the pre or post
synaptic
nerves that could be causing the
balances and in all the hormones and
neurotransmitters that you know make us
happy make us sad make this function
right so if those if those errors aren't
happening correctly that's where a lot
of depression and anxiety and sleep
issues come from them by just taking CBD
as a supplement you're going to
naturally lose those endogenous
cannabinoids in the body and that's
really recent in the last year - they've
really really learned that what's the
excitement what well CBD specifically
that has that effect
THC doesn't have every application fact
that we know of
I mean we're learning something new
every day so by the time someone watches
this they go yeah it goes just
discovering revenue as far as we know it
doesn't have that effect so I would
think that you know if you're using a
mixed balanced strain you know you're
going to be the higher the heat the
plant can only produce so many
cannabinoids so the higher the CHC the
less CBD you're gonna end up getting and
other types of contaminants and I would
just have one more thing when we're
talking about CVG and CBC and you know
the variants are really exciting what
we're learning about THC and CBD B those
are also why it's important to realize
that not every patient is gonna benefit
from these ultra purified CBD products
whether they're from him or whether it's
epidemics because a lot of the benefit
is coming from things that we're just
we're assuming or CBD but then we
finally when we get into these purified
products they don't have the same
efficacy and I think we're gonna find
down the road that it is from the the
barians and the CBC's and the CB
and we haven't even gotten into
flavonoids and terpenoids but these this
see some Russo coin this entourage
effects of compounds that is flies in
the face of what the way we like to
think about medicine in Western medicine
you know is really also important to
realize why we as patient advocates
don't want to say well epidemics is out
so kids with epilepsy were fun right
because it's not that simple at all and
a lot of those kids my son included
don't respond the CBD alone at all never
did never help the single day it wasn't
until we started adding different ratio
medicines that he started to respond
Forrest is referring to the entourage
effect that Ethan Rousseau the a very
good neurologist came up with it's the
combined effect of all the ingredients
in a cannabis plant on a particular
person and at as we talked about there's
a lot of cannabinoids and then as you
mentioned there's terpenes so how many
of you know what the terpenes are just
offhand and yeah Turk means are the
aromatic part of the cannabis plant and
a whole lot of other plants there's lots
of them in in nature like in lemons and
black pepper and all that they give it
the smell off they also have properties
so terpenes have a busload of properties
what's ziggy several of more anti-tumor
some are anti-inflammatory some are
antidepressant what else we got guys
just offhand on the terpene I got my 13
list I ran it somewhere here we go
sedative let's see and some are anti
pain and things that you say like the
terpene thing is like a whole like here
we go kind of thing welcome to a new
world
good no I was just gonna say I think we
can add everything on the list because
we're talking about compounds that are
interacting with her and open advances
so everything that your inner family
system does which is regulate almost
every function in your body these
compounds are interacting
are going to benefit if they're
interacting with the area of the other
family system that is causing you
problems and you know that's like
cannabis and these terpenes and Long's
aren't a family system work as these
adapted but people see these very
different results and it's because this
system regulates so many different
things that depending on how our
physiology and biology are individually
structured you know we're gonna see
different results to it so malfunctions
in that system could be causing sleep
issues or not but it's it's the fact
that it's not necessarily taking a
terpenoid or a cannabinoid for sleep
specifically what we're taking it for is
to correct the malfunctions within the
system in our body and then that you see
the the benefits of it when that error
in that system is corrected and it ties
in those errors can be a spectrum of
things sleep pain etc so it really for a
lot of these we're gonna be able to list
all of the same things because these
different compounds are gonna likely
interact with what is not working for
specific people in different ways so
that can go into the genetics of that
person which everybody's getting more
interested in genetics which is great
and so some of these people are gonna
have deficiencies in there and the
cannabinoid system and they're not going
to have as many receptors in the gut or
the uterus that you have or whatever and
by the way there's a lot of receptors in
the body I think I saw that the uterus
has the most concentration of receptors
you get that somewhere yeah most
concentration of cannabinoid receptors
in the body which is perhaps why canids
works so well for menstrual cramps and
it even works I wanted to just throw
this in for the ladies as a salve
topically put it on your lower abdomen
of the women I've looked at about 32 out
of 33 benefited from using topical
cannabis on the lower abdomen at the
onset of menstrual cramps you know how
does that work
I'm not sure how the hell that works but
it's working really well so there you go
you need got all these receptors and you
got a lot of them in the gut which is
why cannabis has been working when I
take cannabis I mean in this broad sense
has been working for irritable bowel
syndrome and ulcerative colitis and
Crohn's and all that stuff
sometimes it spectacularly so the sky's
limit on this
everybody that's that's what what I'm
seeing and let me let me run you just a
quick list of some of the conditions
that have responded to cannabinoids
right well pain anxiety and sleep on a
pain anxiety sleep those are the big
players reason people have come in and
see me for years to get there
cannabis approval when we needed that
and then there's Parkinson's and there's
ALS Lou Gehrig's disease and by the way
it's a pretty decent science going on
with this all right
then there's autism bladder dysfunction
and spasm depression glaucoma a DD and
ADHD cancer psoriasis and dementia they
also did a recent of migraines it just
goes on and on they just did a recent
study showing that they took a bunch of
people I don't you saw anybody either
you guys saw the study I just saw anyway
interesting little study they took a
bunch of people who had a bunch of
medical disorders and on a bunch of meds
and they gave in cannabis 29 those
twenty to one four three three or four
months game a twenty to one CBD just so
you don't get lost the numbers on the
CPD's are CPD to THC so there's thirty
to one twenty two one two one two one
all that so just they don't get lost and
there we start throwing out the numbers
22 ones are real popular for a teen who
wants real popular variety and get some
study so they gave this for a while and
the people's brainpower their cognition
their thinking improved and they
measured it not only with these standard
these functional MRIs fancy fancy
scientific gadgets and their functional
MRI is got better and it's very
interesting when when brain starts brain
start looking different that's like
that's fabulous
[Music]
you