today is a topic du jour was you know
around corporate governance and what can
be expected of of companies how they run
their companies how they treat their
shareholders whether or not different
shareholders that are in different
classes that hold different paper you
know how they're treated how management
teams are thinking about their own
compensation how they're thinking about
the long-term viability of their
business versus you know are they
short-term greedy or long-term greedy
and I think that what a lot of people
are watching right now is as some of
these companies have these massive
market caps especially some of the
multi-state operators you know are they
gonna be around in five years or you
know they're gonna be attacked by the
market eventually for for not practicing
you know good corporate governance and
so you know what people are really what
I heard a lot of people talking about
today is what can we expect going
forward are these companies going to
mature are they really ready for
primetime did these companies go public
too early do they have the ability to
scale into being you know a fortune 500
style company are they going to end up
you know getting run into the ground and
you know forgotten about in five years
time and you know I think about this in
the same perspective of you know
thinking about tech in the 1990s when
you know you're having this massive
valuations from like let's say 98 until
2002 when it crashed
you had companies that you thought were
gonna be the hottest big next thing
because they came out of the gate with
so much bluster and bravado and then
within two years time they burned
through all their cash you know
squandered their first mover advantage
and no one ever heard of them again
where some other ones took a really
meaningful example or meaningful
approach to to how to address you know
their industry so you know you look at
1999 and you know Amazon obviously at
the time was everyone knew the name but
they weren't anything close to what they
are today
where's at the same time you had you
know companies like you know MySpace
that probably could have made it that
that didn't and then those companies
like pets.com there were the famous
flames and we're watching that happen
right now with cannabis of which
companies do you look at and say okay
well that that company is run by so much
corporate greed so much hubris that
ultimately they're not they're not gonna
be able to survive going forward whereas
you're looking at some of the other ones
and thinking okay have the
been really really careful about how
they structured their shares have they
been really careful about how they've
treated their shareholders how they've
worked their cap table how they've you
know controlled their float you know so
you look at a company like tilray that's
been really really smart about you know
not allowing all their shareholders from
privateer
to have an exit you know to date where
you have some other companies where you
know they flooded the market with their
paper and taking people off restrictions
too early that's gonna cause either
massive dilution or it's gonna cause a
massive downward pressure on their share
price and that's what people are
watching and and then they're also
watching who's at the helm and you know
how are they thinking about it and are
they are they being overly aggressive to
the detriment of their shareholder yeah
I think it's a very real fear and I
think that what's happening what's
happening right now people are starting
to you know the euphoria is wearing off
you know you had this great saccharine
sugar high for a while like oh we've
invested in this Kansas coming they're
everywhere and they're gonna do all
these great things and you know would
look they've taken such a great
footprint right out of the gate that now
is sort of the highest worn off and now
they're thinking about okay well you
know do these guys really know how to
run a business and you know now that
we've really read through all the
filings we've really read through you
know what what this company has you know
underneath its not not what we thought
it was and then it's a question of
whether or not those companies are able
to to overcome that whether they can
bring in you know good management behind
that to say okay well we've got some
we've got some issues we've got some
overhangs we're gonna find a way to
clean it up or do you have management
teams that are still so confident in
themselves that they think you know
they're impenetrable but I think those
guys you're gonna watch a couple just
gets slaughtered because you
the short sellers are gonna come in or
you're gonna have derivative suits you
know throwing up the companies for for
mismanagement of funds or for for you
know breach of fiduciary duty or you
know doing things that from a corporate
governance standpoint will be looked
upon very very unfavorably by any you
know Court that's uh that's examining it
so you know expect to see the first wave
of like mega lawsuits happening you know
in the immediate future and I think that
you're gonna see some pretty big marquee
names that you know people were talking
about all the time you know call it in
the last three or four months probably
not exist by 2020 and or if they do
exist they'll be you know a shadow of
their former selves right and we've seen
some of these lawsuits alight pretty
recently so a lot of these companies
have gone public so recently so if
you're thinking about the sentiment of
early and current investors based on
what they do when a lock-up period ends
what would you be watching for when
company aids lockup period ends and
they're a public company and you're what
you're watching or monitoring either
management or early investor activity in
terms of selling shares and on the
Canadian exchanges on everybody's
favorite Canadian exchange the first
thing to be watching for is you know
who's their banker you know who they
working with and what's that bankers
plan whether it's you know Canaccord or
GMP or beacon or the other Canadian
companies up there that are really
supporting these companies and finding
out from management you know what's your
what's your plan that when shares come
off restriction to have a secondary
market that's gonna come in there and
sweep up and purchase those shares so it
doesn't have just a massive hit to the
share price because some of these
companies you might have you know 10 20
30 million shares or more hitting the
market at one time this they come off
restrictions and boom some people are
gonna hold but there's a lot of people
that say hey you know I got in really
early I've already had a 20x I don't
want to risk that this thing goes down
I'm gonna take my profits and walk away
and by the way I want to be first to the
door because if I wait someone else is
gonna beat me to it and that's gonna put
downward pressure on the on the share
price and it's gonna keep you know
pushing it down so you know when these
shares do come offers
if you're a really smart management team
and you've got really good strong
relationships with your bankers you've
already thought about this beforehand
you're saying okay who's gonna go in
there and start buying large blocks to
support the share price or how much cash
we have on our balance sheet to
potentially buy shares back ourselves to
keep them at the the share price up but
you know watching these things hit too
fast in crater is it's problematic and I
think that a lot of times you have to
think about whether or not you're gonna
only allow a certain amounts of shares
from shareholders to bleed out in small
tranches specifically to prevent that
from happening before before it does
[Music]