how long has the company been going the
company yeah the company has been going
for probably about four years now got it
he started it but we have been growing
you know behind the scenes for sure it
just we're meant to wake up one day and
do that yeah in Michigan the whole time
yep okay I've been in Michigan the whole
time you know and then at the time I
went down to MSU and got my degree there
and just from there it kind of turned
into this beautiful thing where we were
able to just yeah start working with the
plant and creating new strains of our
own and testing them in there where
there are a lot of cannabis growers in
at MSU when you went to school with them
you know there weren't really at the
time there were the guys that were
growing in their closets or their
basements but a lot of people at least
that were in my graduating class really
focused on the organic farming and their
degrees and stuff like that but you know
now I see universities I don't know I
think it's like northern or something
like that they have a cannabis
production class actually it's a course
at the University that was funny how you
could at one point a couple years ago
get kicked out of college for cannabis
and now they're teaching you how to grow
cannabis you know the in Pueblo Colorado
which is just south of Denver on that
front I 25 Front Range there's a CSU
division or branch or universe
and they have a cannabis studies
master's degree program it's been there
for a couple of years and you're like
what yeah you're like what is this now
yeah it's funny back in the day you know
if they would have called it you know
hydroponics you know growing or like how
to grow cannabis in your closet you know
they would have had you know 10 15 20
people just be like you know what like
yeah I am here to grow cannabis and he
was saying a lot of people would show up
for his green house classes and stuff
like that and you know he could tell
they weren't actually interested in
learning how to do a commercial green
house of sorts they were just there to
you know grow flower but yeah we got
into the whole breeding thing you know
actually my business partner approached
me one day I was working at a hydro
store at the time and he was like you
know what man we should start a seed
company and I was like sounds like a
great idea and six months later I quit
my job and we started doing this full
time and we were growing at the time to
support ourselves and we just really
wanted to do something where we were
able to be creative and create a product
that somebody else could also experience
and that started about four years ago
and now we've got seeds all over the
world from Australia to Spain the UK
u.s. you know East Coast to west coast
and up into Canada as well so it's
really been you know a crazy growth over
the last four years we went from I think
two followers on our Instagram and now
we're up to almost 13,000 and we're
seeing pictures of plants you know that
people are growing of our strains and
it's it's cool it's it allows us to be
creative and you know we bar what are
you want to be known for strand like are
you guys
the trends are you going in your own
direction and saying they're gonna be
people who appreciate what we're creator
and I guess with what we're doing is
we're just looking to kind of follow our
own path we want to work with the things
that we've created to continue to
develop on those but at the same time
you know maybe take a step back and look
into more of the land race and some of
the original varietals that were out
there before you know all this
cross-pollination all this giant melting
pot essentially has come about and kind
of looked backwards and bring some of
the old strains into the future might
give you some examples so like with some
Death Star strains that's something that
we've been looking into working with we
actually ran across an individual who
has a plethora of heirloom land race
genetics that he's collected from
Colombia in India in Thailand and just
all over the place and they're you know
2530 years old and he's just kind of
been stashing all these away and he
approached us actually at a grow event a
couple months back and was like by the
way I have all this stuff and he busted
out his seedless then we just about shit
our pants when we found out what he had
you know he had original sin sea stars
there's all sorts of stuff that you
can't get anymore so I'd like to hear
something about the learning curve in a
genetics program how
of that education that you get at school
and how much was it on the ground or
from your partners and what are the big
hurdles I mean you think about breeding
programs taking a long time even decades
in traditional crops and you get F ones
and f2 is relatively quick in this
particular crop
what is the diligence and the challenge
to get high-quality repeatable genetics
from from your experience well it
definitely takes time and it's it's very
meticulous work in regards to you have
to be paying attention to everything you
know from vigor to the overall plant
structure you know how much does this
plant eat you know what's its terpene
profile what you know what does the leaf
variegation look like and so what we had
you know in our peanut butter breadth
project we had used the leaf variegation
on the edge of the leaf to be a real
indicator trait for us because the ocean
grown khush breath or the ogk bee has
that wild duck foot going on and you can
tell when you get something it looks
very mutant and not normal and then
there's you know the more dosey doe side
and so with our peanut butter breath
line not only were we able to decipher
you know what we were getting from the
physical traits but also the color and
the frost content but it takes time to
get there you know and nowadays like you
said the F ones and f2s are they're
easier to come up with and everybody's
doing it but to really truly you know
get an inbred line you have to get you
know many generations deep into your
project and it takes a lot of time and
MSU when I was there I had taken plants
plant genetic courses and you know you
get into the really intricate parts of
it you know more much further than the
punnett squares and you know all those
science experiments you know you would
do back in grade school but it it gets
deeper than that and to to see a project
come to fruition and you can see the
mother and the father's distinct traits
you know passed down to those next V
Lisle generations is really a neat thing
especially too when you're seeing the
same results in other
gardens yeah so it but it takes time and
yeah figuring out you know figuring out
what makes sense you know you're not
just gonna put two totally random
species of plant together and you know
be like alright this is the one that it
takes looking at you know the parental
lineages and figuring out what you're
really trying to capture out of crossing
those two you know without yeah I don't
want to want to call anyone out some not
an expert I'm not a horticultural so I
plan to notice is I'm gonna happen
gardner-webb grew up as a gardener in my
microbiology yeah completely different
how many people actually get genetics
relatively speaking to people that are
doing genetics I mean you sound like you
have some classical training you do you
want to MSU great University do most
people understand it how many people are
just winging it I would say probably 60%
of them are winging it
Wow yeah and not necessarily saying that
they're winging it just throwing pollen
in their room but they're not
necessarily you know making a decision
in crafting a experiment if you will you
know where they have a hypothesis like
okay this is my mail this is my female
this is what I'm trying to get out of
this and then doing the experiment and
following through on the conclusions by
testing the progeny and really figuring
out what you've got you know a lot of
these people will test up a couple times
and you know they might put it out on
the market and typically you see people
that are doing that they will sell the
seeds for cheaper you know they're 40 50
dollars a pack on certain stuff but you
know we we believe in our line and we've
tested ours you know for three years
consistently ourselves as well as giving
it out you know to our testers all
around the country and they're getting
the same results that we are so weird
confident you know in that we're seeing
the same results over and over again
it's still a gap in the at least the
adherence to an experimental design and
the follow-through of actually that
rigorous data collection and
and that repetition from lineage lineage
to validate you think that's the gap
yeah I do and not necessarily that it's
a gap because you know some of our most
popular strains they'll come dog I was
bag seat if you will
originally and you know everybody knows
that no and so who's to say the next one
couldn't be it's definitely you know
becoming saturated you know the entire
gene pool overall but that's exciting
you know and that's where I think there
will be new people that step in that
could potentially introduce the species
or a strain that no one's ever seen
before
just in terms of its physical appearance
or you know terpene profile or anything
like that so I think with the industry
at growing the way that it is and all
the new techniques that are being
developed and strains that yet people
are trying to come up with it it
definitely has the progress and I can
see it continuing to progress for the
next ten years so it sort of ceiling on
this for me you know I think there's a
lot of overlap and we it's progressed so
far how far will it go at this point I
think there's really no limit you know
we're still the innovators in this thing
you know I don't even think we've really
hit the growth stage yet let's kind of a
big statement compared to everything
that's going on relative to everything
going on right now that we have I mean
think about yeah how many states still
are you know not allowing us to do this
fair enough
from a production but I mean from a
genetics and a diversity point of view
is there things that just haven't been
tapped into yet you know I think there
are and I think a lot of those traits
that we may be looking for
lie back in those land race heirloom
rubber
you know who's to say that yeah it
couldn't come from something new but I
think a lot of the stuff that we're
looking for or that was originally
created you know on this planet by
whatever that may be you know those are
true genetics and those are true species
you know if they're poor and you don't
find a lot of that any longer so you
know I have a question that someone asks
me again and I don't know but we talked
about genetics I love talking about this
topic so I'm not an expert in it so
everything I've talked about and getting
information in is new kernels of
knowledge and so thanks for doing this I
have a question for you how do you pick
males so selecting our males is pretty
much how you know you would select a
female in terms of you grow it start to
finish you have multiple clones on it so
you're gonna run yours select it and
then you're gonna run it again and in
that second run you know you can stress
test them you know you can just ask for
disease resistance a lot of people you
know they'll experience issues when they
let their male go it'll start to her
mout on them at the end and that's not
necessarily a indicator of stability you
know letting it run a long time so
really running your male start to finish
and then again like I said where you're
looking for you know a stem rub or a
certain leaf you know variation pattern
around the leaf margin or just structure
overall you know bigger all those things
come into the equation it's kind of
analyzing and you know making your best
educated guess on what you deem the best
and then obviously you know you can get
the plant tested as well at the end of
its growth cycle to kind of determine a
average percentage that's actually
really helpful for me it's because I'm
always under
on females or certain traits at least
and a lot of people chase the THC for a
long time and so like get that measuring
trade and it seemed like it was harder
for me to understand conceptually how to
measure or what to want what I would
want to measure out a melon we have we
have high CBD farms reason for
agriculture purposes mostly for our
inputs and looking at certain metrics of
chemical constituents CBD cannabidiol it
in general terrine and then yielding
growth and maybe routing or whatever
we're kind of targeting but we don't
have a breeding and we don't do that
it's more of agronomic
and for for growth patterns and
different inputs natural inputs and
because that's what our wheelhouse is it
makes sense to me that you could really
do diligent stress test resilience tests
on the males to make sure you at least
have some of those pest resistance
traits
those are ease more easily conceptually
measured in the males it may be
structure and morphology that's kind of
what I heard and the females you want to
couple that along with some nice
characteristics of the flavor qualities
and whatnot right yeah and then - yeah
and then after you put that all together
you know your final product is the mix
of all that and you're able to identify
that and see that and that's that's what
it's all about at the end would you
measure terpenes or cannabinoids in a
male yeah oh yeah that is actually you
know one of the ways that we select
males we do stem rubs if one's more than
the other or they may even be the same
strain but they do have a slightly
different smell to them and it's like
well this one's more appealing than this
but this one might smell more you know
prominently that did they teach you to
stamp rough technique in school ah no
they did it
no no they did not
unfortunately yeah
the cannabis industry technique
nomenclature horticultural go so there's
a lot of people you know that are
classifying things as what they say they
are but when it really get down to it so
in terms of you know feel I'll
generations or doing an inbred line or a
back cross I think nowadays people are
trying to catch on to the lingo it's
something where you know I had learned
it a long time ago so it all kind of
clicked for me and you know it made
sense in terms of what we were trying to
accomplish and really it's it's
something worth getting to know you know
for every grower in the industry so yeah
you can properly classify your plants
and you know if you're trying to sell
your seed stock especially being able to
tell people exactly where it is in its
breeding process you know first second
third feel I'll generation in and then
so we're talking f1 f2 f3 and that's a
proper nomenclature for that first
generation second bred generation third
bred generation and that would be having
perhaps a static pollen donor with the
reoccurring mother breeds and then
taking seeds from that yep and so you
can work your way down and then yeah it
depends on how yeah you're looking to
breed back and what your end goal is you
know if you're looking to at the end
ultimately create that inbred line that
you've just been putting back into
itself or if you're looking yet to do
you know an f1 or an f2 and then use
something from there to do another
project once you know if you feel that
that plant that you're using is stable
and you better have it seems like you
better have a real vision as a plant
breeder because there's just a thousand
directions you can go with any one
generation yep and that's it's just you
know like anything like if you're in the
stock market or if you're starting a
business you know really having a plan
to to put into action and following
through on that and ensuring that
everything is taken care of you know in
the same manner and you know we grow and
breed organically so you know having
microbes like what you got
in the soil and having that symbiotic
relationship is really key to ensure you
know success from start to finish on
everything and so that's where we feel a
lot of our really good germination rates
come in
you know we're near ninety nine percent
on all of our germination rates you know
male the female ratios are about 50/50
and then typically with our phenotypic
ratios we'll see a three to one and that
three to one on basing that on color
specifically so the dominant color gene
came through from our male so more
likely than not you're going to get
something that's a dark purple as
compared to a green but at the
probability game right exactly yep and
then you know with our females a lot of
them had a dominant terpene trait
and so that was able to carry on down
that lineage whereas the peanut butter
breath male that we used it had a
recessive gene for terpenes so that was
the last dominant and that wouldn't
carry down and so yeah like I said it's
neat to see the creations come together
you know at different stages different
generations and see okay this is what's
here where do we want to go with it now
you know I spend a lot of time in Europe
and they talk about feminized seeds a
lot yeah and you can chemically
feminized seeds and it's very common
practice and seeds a big business as a
souvenir business in Europe you know
that's the legal term for selling seeds
I don't understand maybe I should but
still how is that bad
the ultimate plant or is it just for
birding in a safe stable layer I want to
hear your opinion on it
so with feminized seeds essentially what
you're doing is you were creating a
mutation within the chromosome so you're
essentially creating a triploid which is
a mutation in chromosomal binding that
is caused by the application of like a
kaleidoscope or product or something
like that thus giving you a feminized
seed and so by not allowing that
chromosome to bind it's guaranteed that
it's female but it could also create
instabilities down the road potentially
you know that's just nature I mean there
are transgendered people in the world
you know it's not an uncommon thing and
so it's the same with plants we're very
similar to them in terms of our genetic
code and our breakdown it's a for true
breeding program you would recommend not
doing that because of the introduction
where do you feel that it's not that big
of a deal well I think it it depends on
your application you know if you were
ever going to try to do a breeding
project you wouldn't want to use
anything feminized it would it you know
be worth even trying it but for people
who are getting into this a lot of
people want an easy route and you know
it's just like the auto flower thing a
lot of people shy away from that and
don't want anything to do with it but
there are other people that swear by it
because it works for them so I think
really at the end of the day it just
kind of comes down to what you want to
do as a grower and the creation of
feminized seeds it's essentially yeah
Akal idol silver which is a natural
compound I mean you can drink it
obviously you probably wouldn't want to
consume the flowers after your colitis
over has been sprayed on it but in the
end I think if you're you know following
your initial intention and applying it
at the proper times and really watching
your plants develop and determining when
is the right maturation time for you
to call it and you know start drying
your seeds and properly you know
creating the seed then there's really no
health risks I would say associated with
you know the seed directly in that plant
that would be grown from that seed got
it awesome that's really helpful if you
guys hate that yeah no problem you know
I actually have another question I keep
on thinking about things all this is new
so at some point we're gonna get shut
down but while we're still on you know
we talked about in Colorado the lack of
genetics for hemp farms where you know a
lot of the genetics they're they're
marketed as legal and you can grow them
but then they end up going hot you have
to be at that point three percent THC or
lower to be within that realm and so
that's a big opportunity and right now I
guess the only way people are getting
around and it's still challenging is
buying clones
is there a near-term future where there
are going to be seeds and this is a
two-part question that comply and you
know one of the challenges I think is
when you get down to that low of THC you
really compromise other cannabinoid
development where you can have a point
seven percent THC strain and have in the
titan CBD or the cannabinoid you know
CBD a relative abundances and if you cut
that down for every tenth of a percent
you really decrease the amount of CBD
production right
is there is that a real correlation and
and and where's the line do you think
that's just lack of breeding lack of
effort or is there a real limitation
there you know yes and no I think it's
something where there is the potential
to you know create through breeding a
strain that is stable and will
consistently be below the threshold but
also there is genetic variation and
there is that chance for a gene to you
know put it above that point three and
so with I think all of the stuff that's
going on right now you know really
focusing in on getting a certified seed
to start with is what's going to be the
most beneficial as compared to going you
know through any Jo online that has hemp
seed that says hey this is what the
cross is you know but I know they've
been doing it in Europe in Canada for a
very long time and I feel like those
regions are going to be the areas that
we're looking to going forward you know
more so than Colorado and California you
know that they're new and everyone is
just getting into it there and these
guys have been doing it for yet damn
near 100 years or longer over across the
ocean so you know do you think there's a
big difference you know China's the
number one Purdue
of hemp as an example we'll call it just
low low THC cannabis but it's mostly
bred before I think fiber and rarely
bred for its amount of seed production
or quality of nourished seed because
that could be an interesting food source
or obviously for flower and an
extraction purposes and so if you find
most of the certified seed in Colorado
as an example they're certified but
they're certified under a fiber and a
couple are certified under a seed but
none are really certified as a strong
producer for extract cannabinoids I
think that's interesting I think mostly
because those have come from Europe do
you see that changing in the near future
where we're gonna have really strong
strains that are certified for CBD
production and extraction I really hope
so and yeah with you know with the way
that the industry is going I think
there's a lot of potential for that to
take place and now that they're letting
us do this legally you know there's
going to be a lot more closeted
scientists and people that want to
experiment and learn and really you know
figure this out and figure out what the
best way is to utilize this resource for
our future going forward and I think
it's a beautiful thing and I think we
will definitely see that from companies
here in the next couple years they're
gonna start coming out with products
that are superior to others or what is
the current status quo
CBD or THC a bigger market in the next
five years
CBD you think so for the next five years
I think everyone's trying to hop on that
train right now and get involved with it
in one way or the other but you know for
our industry obviously THC is the game
and I think there's a spot for those two
circles to overlap in the middle and
there's going to be a huge market that's
interested in finding that that golden
ratio you know that one to one where
they're really getting the relief that
they need from the products that they're
consuming you know I used to send this
law and I think I still believe this
there's this THC customer base market
and it's not going anywhere and it's
huge yeah but then there's this CBD
market that might encompass everyone
else on earth that might not necessarily
be interested in the THC aspects of
cannabis but the CBD aspects are way
even for your pets
the healing aspects it's incredible th
she's a part of that but it's not as
much as a psychoactive as it is a
activator component where we know we
need a little bit of THC I think that's
right that's what we all think yeah have
had a little activation in there yeah
Auto flower is
is coming into the US market are you
guys breeding any auto flower strains or
this great song
we're staying away from ruderalis we're
yeah we're we said we weren't gonna do
feminized and we're finishing a
feminized project right now actually
we're doing one to one CBD THC cross
with mousse cookies that was bred by
light sky farms and we're crossing that
to a lot of our strains and mothers that
have you know proven themselves to us
over the years so we're excited about
that and that line will be released and
probably about five to six months you
know we've got testing and stuff like
that to finish up and checking in with
people and you know putting our brains
together and being like alright let's
look at the data on this how's it
looking but that is something where you
know people want the Otto flowers to
they don't want to mess with the time
change people want it easy and so some
aren't willing to do the work and some
are and I think the ones that are
willing to do the work and really put in
the time to get to know their plants and
the genetics that they're working with
they're going to be the ones you know
reaping those benefits a little bit more
in the end in terms of quality yields
and just overall performance of their
plants seems like the Otto flower a
phenom
phenomenon in Europe has been very
strong yeah that's actually starting to
fade away where people are realizing
they want the non ruderalis version of
cannabis and so I see that with a lot of
the people that I work with over there
and it's funny to see this drifting and
here something that's kind of fading out
of Europe thinking that the United
States non versions cooler and
the US is adopting some of it right and
I think no matter what I've heard people
that grow out of flower there's
something about the ruderalis that you
can sense across all the autoflowering
strains it kind of ties it together it
makes sense but it might not be as
desirable for some people it's become
the feedback I've got and I think yeah
just yet what you said and it just comes
down to what you're growing style is you
know what works for you how much time do
you have to devote to looking at them
every day and watering them and you know
what yeah what product are you looking
for at the end of it all - so