I wish I had the original Durbin poison
I mean that went to Amsterdam became
something entirely different
not entirely different but quite
different but the first one that I had
had the one that I really liked
actually I just lost it it never went to
Amsterdam
well when today I had two different
lines of the Durban I hadn't in a and B
and the a happened to be the one that I
liked the most it had a a real licorice
flavor it had purple stigmas which you
just don't see you know purple was some
of them with lavender that I wish I had
you know what you have now is a much
more commercial kind of rendition of
what went to Amsterdam part of that
problem was that I made a mistake it's
really embarrassing but I gave skunk me
and Sam Afghani one I gave him the
Durban the beeline but the beeline had a
little bit of her Africa's aminute and I
I didn't realize it when I gave it to
him at the time and I didn't find this
out until many years later when he told
me you had to work with it work with it
work with it they get rid of their
magnetism right so that was part of what
changed that that lying a lot but it's a
heavier yielder now it's not as sativa
like as it was when I first got it but
it was the most unusual plant that I I
would say variety that I grow I've seen
individuals that were pretty spectacular
but as a variety it was just very
different from anything else the main
thing was this is what a short season it
was you know I agree that you are
harvesting it here in Oakland in
September and when I brought it to New
York this is about 60 miles from New
York City we were having some of that in
August it was that that early so in
being from the east originally my whole
thing with breeding when I came out here
was to develop cultivars that could
mature back east before the terrible
weather came in
because the people I knew who grew up
back there they were basically growing
leaf are really crappy Mexican that had
some flowers right
I saw a situation out there where I went
back I already had hybrids F ones of
things like Afghani and Congolese
Afghani in Nigeria and Afghani and
Durban and so forth but I went back and
I took those sativa crosses and I caused
him again to Afghani to try to make sure
that we go out the shortness of Afghani
in there and they did fantastic out
there I mean those people couldn't
believe how strong that pot was they had
never experienced anything like in their
lives