that year was a very successful year we
grew of a 500 pounds of top-notch that I
mean really top-notch sinsemilla and
these guys wanted to do it again the
next year and they were bringing in
money people right who were just drug
dealers and I didn't feel good about it
I didn't like the people I didn't like
the fact that they wanted to upscale so
much you know it all became it all came
the money you know I was more interested
and the actual growing and seeing what
happened and all that so the next year
they they they bought a 140 acres
further away from where we originally
grow and went at it and I was back in
California when I got a call in July to
come out there and help them and I
didn't really want to do that but I I
relented because of the few of the
people they just like everything they
had into it
so in fact he had a rescue him and this
was hard to believe they had gone
through a whole year of growing up this
very successful crop and didn't see who
haven't learned anything because they
went from a place that we were growing
in in like Bottomly and really rich
beautiful soil I mean we had to do
nothing to soil really you could put
your hand and it was and just reached
this beautiful soil so it was really
easy to grow the iron so weird they
would they buy this land they bought of
that you know another thousand fifteen
hundred feet higher where the soil was
rocky and Sandy in additionally New York
State that yeah and at a drought so yeah
you come and look at the plants they
have no no dude it's an award I know
what it they're not growing so anyway I
kind of remedied that and got them
growing well and sometime in late August
I had to come back to Oakland and it
does so I said you know I'll be back and
it will be right of the harvest and that
this crop would have been over at time
would have been over at time
but as I was flying back they got busted
okay
so they lost everything none of them
ended up in jail
partly because New York didn't
understand growing at that time like
they didn't understand the air before I
was standing in this this wonderful
field
and one of the guys came out he showed
me a local newspaper the headline was
that they estimated that the New York
State marijuana crop that year would be
worth a half a million dollars right and
I'm thinking it's worth more right here
you know
I'll be that's how little they knew
about it so when they got busted the
next year they didn't end up in jail
they just lost everything they lost a
fortune so they were lucky lucky for
that but you know I mean I never got
busted in my life
never been arrested and a lot of it had
to do with luck and a lot of it had to
do with the fact that I didn't
personally sell marijuana I didn't sell
seeds I didn't sell anything you know I
made money from my writing in my
photography in the other was that I
didn't take accept you know all these
offers that come to the Y he come to
here you know you know do the growing
for us you know you'll make a lot of
money and that wasn't really my interest
so much you know I really was fascinated
with the plant the botany and that's the
way I went