[Music]
i'm shane mosley and i'm with glass
house farms in Santa Barbara County
I'm Brian Malin vital garden supply and
vital grown vital garden supplies
headquarters is Nevada City California
and vital grown farm is in Willis
California Mendocino County but I traded
that's that's an epic one that's an
old-school you know it's funny is I
actually the plant that we have in our
booth yeah that's cool that's I think
that's like a really easy place to start
with we don't we know we know we don't
know each other but as cultivars that's
that's an easy one to go back is like
just some old school strains like when I
started growing I could probably name
all the strains on my fingers and toes
you know and pretty much everything has
come from there since then right no I
mean I went on Leafly and I think there
was a close to 5,000 strains listed on
there that's like get out of here I
wonder how many of those have the
original og cush as a backbone of it
because there's a lot of Kush heavy
strains and I'm pretty sure that the
world loves that OG Kush fuel flavor
yeah it's not that gassy mercy interpret
feel like dot Durbin poison like you do
a lot of yeah those all those crosses
well the gelatos are from their pushes
too right there pure fucking Hindu yes
yeah it's good stuff yeah very
interesting times
we have a few we have several strange
some gelatos some we drew a bunch of
skittles actually that's what this jar
is right here that's some depth skittles
right there so are you pulling your
point like four turns probably really
only three because of the elevation
we're also like no electricity up there
we're bringing power in so we're still
like crafts Towe cannabis farm and we're
also you know at the at the mercy of
PG&amp;E so you know what happened with all
the fires and all that because of all
that everybody's like backlog and
bringing power into properties so due to
that we're running generators just to
keep plants alive and vegging during the
early parts of the spring late parts of
the winter so this one it was very
interesting because it just kept going
on and on and on so it just gave that
everything a little bit of a push back
as far as like timeframes go that's uh
when I got here yesterday when I got
here yesterday I was laughing about that
you just diesel everybody's got transfer
tanks I miss it moving down to suck I
was like you know you're back in NorCal
cuz everybody has a transfer tank you
got to get that generator going it's
good stuff for sure it's been a way of
life for a long time now but we're
looking forward to having power I mean
talking before like for 20 years you
basically just sold locally to go
outside
so in terms of like you surviving as a
company and a brand and a farmer well
not you can concentric Li start with
your home turn my well my situation is a
little different than a lot of the other
farmers because I'm also in the nutrient
business so I've always been on the
nutrient side of things supplied a lot
of grows black market back in the day
then the gray market medical and being
being that I love the plan so much and
wanting to be involved is that I always
had my backyard grows and different
situations helping out different friends
and and then you know once things came
to be then I was like well I need to
have a piece of this you know beginning
of history you know the cannabis
industry began here in Northern
California at least for the u.s. anyway
I don't want to say began but the
culture from California cannabis in
Northern California is super strong and
because of my relationships and love for
the plan I felt it was important you
know enter the legal you know market
prop 64 and be able to sell licensed
recreational cannabis
absolutely I know we saw our dancin
organic organic soil fertilizer
amendments yeah I make soil we have a
soil line that that has you know a bunch
of really good ingredients that is
something that we sell so people could
just plant right in it as far as like
history of building soil you know that
goes back to like the farmers who've
been doing this for many years reusing
the same soil amending it when you're up
on the hill literally trucking in soil
if you need it so the best way to do it
is do that once every three years or
whatever and amended twice and make sure
you know what you're doing and we've
been big on selling worm castings
compost houmous back one oh that's
that's been my backbone of what our
company is yeah I think that's like a
really big I don't know overlooked part
of old school growing is is the the kind
of had that mentality of they're just
just some dumb pot car up in the hill or
whatever right but they're still even
back then there's still a lot of science
to it you know and everybody that's
where the uniqueness of those strain
profiles comes from you're gonna get a
way more Turkey earthy strain like taste
wise to like because it was grown in a
certain way with a certain exactly my
culture exactly so that and that's so a
glass house were where the other end of
the model but I come from that
background in glassware 100% cocoa is
our medium and we usually nutrients but
it's the same thing
you find you've developed those recipes
same thing through with the strains and
that's how you really accentuate the
terpene profiles and and I think as
science kind of like develops a little
bit more we talked about this last time
that I really believe it's like
potencies a joke on how you get high
right like so many people are so locked
into the number what percentage of THC
this stuff probably only
like 18% right but it is you it'll get
you loaded and and but your metabolism
just like anything you know you have
your own endocannabinoid system and
that's what's that's what's really
regulating how you get high and the
combinations of the terpenes combined
with the percentage of THC and the CBD
in the CBG you know there's way more to
it than just the percentage of THC one
to I think with like the new market for
me at least when I see that's the new
market when I see that's where we get
like actually educating people you know
the goes back to the stereotype some
people are just like pot heads would
ever know no actual knowledge of the
plant that it's one incredibly powerful
but it's a medicine and it's just like a
pharmaceutical you got to go into that
like a budtender is basically a
pharmacist you know it's it's they need
to develop that would that person knows
what works to that person you can't the
old model of Steve will make you clean
your house and indica put you to sleep
is like it's got to go out the window we
got to figure out that it's individual
to each person especially with so many
high res right now between the hybrids
and the strains and the hybrids and the
humans you know we're all freaking
different and there's a million
different combinations of strains and
terpenes and CBD THC concoctions that
we're all different and it just goes to
show that what an amazing plant this is
and nobody's ever given any other plant
this much energy you know what I mean so
I feel really lucky to be in this place
right now for sure
cannabis is like it's getting its day
it's the it's in the Sun finally you
know after many years of hiding it in
the shade
so what are you trying to do we're
working on a little bit of breeding we
have a we have something that we've been
working on a few years now it's actually
cross with skittles and lemon tree and
we're just working the kinks out of it
doing Fino hunts every round and just
trying to find a few that we really like
before we really like get it out there
to develop there's there's signs of
things that were really seeing that are
positive but every now and then you'll
see one that does something that we're
not real happy with so if we oh just
like shapes of the flower or sculpture
the plant mold resistance exactly all
those he said it I mean breeding is like
greetings not really to be messed with
too much and that's it goes back to the
how many strains there are these days or
so many people that think that they
could read something and then that's a
strain and you just said it it's like
you need like three to five years of
running the same cut and maybe they're
it's breeding that's it's just like
otherwise in dogs they're called a mutt
if you just have two great it's not
another you didn't create a new breed of
dog I'm always amazed these days when
like a new strain comes the market and
it's like oh wow have you seen this and
then it's out and it's on the streets
and it's available and then before you
know it there's another across of that
and you're like wait has it even been
two months and that's change routes are
already rights and then white runts and
then purple runs who just go wait what
exactly so for me the breeding side of
things is like you know we're not a
genetics company but we obviously have
genetics that we really feel desirable
and when we hit that mark with that one
something that we really feel good about
and want to bring to the to the world
will let people know but we also don't
want to be premature about it
I mean my whole approach that everything
has always been from the high quality
side of things high-end vital garden
supply products aren't the cheapest
products on the market that are the best
products in the market and we that's our
approach for growing cannabis - we want
to have high-end quality high terpene
profiles different things that you don't
necessarily see everywhere right I feel
- like we've before we're on camera
meaning we're talking - that's more like
you're gonna get that from like the
legacy grower if you will fish you know
and I mean somebody that's been in it
for 15-20 years like us it's not it's
the other thing is the new the new guys
just worried about their their bottom
dollar it's actually not not that 100%
quality over everything that's that's
pretty good cuz it's your blood sweat
and tears because it used to be for us
right it used to be if you didn't make
it good your kids didn't need you know
you want to own it and you want to be
proud of it and say hey I did that yeah
please please for me for sure for sure
definitely back that that type of
thought for sure
[Music]
like what's going on sure well it's
definitely it's it's tricky right now
Mendocino County has a cap at ten
thousand square feet and everyone in
mindo who has a 10,000 square feet has
to compete with people in other areas
that may not have any caps or they could
be an acre cap or depending like
Humboldt County there's a few acre
projects a few people have up to even
four acres that I know of up there Lake
County's starting to get some multi
acreage licenses as well then of course
Santa Barbara
you know multi our current cultivate our
current cultivation is one hundred and
thirty four thousand square feet and
they just are about to start up are an
extra three hundred and fifty five
thousand square feet so a half a million
square feet it's like and that's I mean
it is it's epic it's it's the dream yeah
but it's also challenging it's also
challenging right because that's also
the dream right that's that's the dream
for for tons of growers up there and but
the reiterating what he said I really
think that any of these legacy guys that
are in it all right
they have the chance because the quality
right he said the quality and the
consistency and knowing that you really
got a cut of OG as opposed to buying in
a cut of Gorilla Glue and it ends up
being Sour Diesel or something you know
because that that's a that's another big
thing is sourcing you know these days to
its it used to be you asked where that
came from and he came from a guy you
know and I'm gonna tell you where it
came from it came from from somebody and
but not actor source right and now you
go to a big nursery though you know so
it's there's a big change in that that
aspect of it too in terms of sourcing
sure and due to my relationship in the
industry I am a partner on a pretty big
project down in Salinas that's over two
hundred thousand square feet a specific
reserve we have a hundred and forty six
thousand square foot all-in
area that's like a multi bay greenhouse
and then we also have a light assisted
one it has like six hundred lights and
it's like 40,000 square feet and that
were able to really put out some high
quality product Salinas being the
temperate zone that it's in it's like
you know a dream to be able to grow down
there and be part of that as well and
use some my products and show what you
can do on an organic large scale you
know and that's been a fun fun
relationship and fun project also we
definitely have several Salinas people
using a lot of our products some using
the full line some mixing in a little
bit of organics with a little bit of
synthetics some will use our soil and
not and use different nutrients that's
the one thing about our product line is
it is diverse like we saw humic acid
that's good for synthetic or organ or
organic fertilizer we saw a calcium
magnesium that can be used synthetic or
organic it's certified but it would go
into any reservoir you could run it
through a drip system you can run it
through a dosing system and then our
soil is definitely pretty universal yeah
it's actually actually really with what
we use I really really like it you know
we use the elite line in nutrients and I
don't I don't know too much of the
science of our liner nutrients but it is
an organic based it's it's salt organic
right it's it's a mix basically but it's
an eight-part thing and and the results
have been have been phenomenal from what
I've seen and obviously obviously like I
mentioned before in recipes and certain
strain profiles is really where where it
shines right you get good results with
everything but there's certain terpene
profiles we've kind of broken it down
into gaseous fruits and sugars but
especially the sugars just love the
cocoa and the elite it's like I mean
that there
so so THC rich or try trike rich you
know what I mean just so sugary with the
cocoa like I said it is just so trike
rich and and fun to look at we have a
couple of cultivars particularly I've
mentioned you a hell's fire before that
I really like to grow and it's just it's
just so concise it's so consistent with
with that line so but but I grew I grew
in soil and you know organics and simple
mixes and complicated mixes for years
too and and personally I think that it
kind of just goes in line with how the
system is already I really like soil and
organics for big outdoor plants for you
know I'm for huge outdoor plants that's
to me that's the way to go but when
you're doing DEP or anything I do at
this point kind of prefer the cocoa
because I like I said I don't have to
manage it as much really it's really
where it is to me it's like you know
what you gave it and that's it and then
if it's missing something easily
adjustable right that's another
beautiful thing about cannabis there's a
million ways to grow it and you got to
do what you're comfortable with you know
like by no means am I gonna tell this
guy that he's doing something wrong he's
grown in 300,000 square foot greenhouse
they've been successful so I respect any
sort of cultivation style if somebody
wants to come to me and reach out and
say hey I'd like to make some transition
into some organics and of course I'm
here for them but you know everyone's
got to do what they what works for them
I'm obviously a big believer in the
organic style and it works for me and
works for our farm and that's you know
that's the path we decided to choose
what are you getting the price per gram
down to in terms of cultivation costs
for a large scale greenhouse Santa
Barbara cultivation operation versus a
small Mendocino outdoor farm we're
working on figuring that out yours are
going to be
it depends I mean I think that I think
there's a little bit of a misconception
there I think people always think that
organic is more expensive than they
thought
depending on the nutrient depending on
the amounts of nutrients depending how
many times you feed a day I mean soil
holds nutrients so I mean we have grow
we have big grows that at Pacific
reserve they're feeding only twice a
week and they're they have soil that has
nutrients in the root zone all the time
so when you add water the plants getting
nutrient so they've actually gotten
their nutrient costs down quite a bit in
the beginning they were feeding 3 4
times a week and then they were worried
that it wasn't enough and then they
started bringing in some synthetics and
going back and forth and then they
realized when they just cut back and
became a little more minimalist they
were actually getting better results so
you know like I said every every
different person has to go with what
works for them they found a system that
works they have a couple dosatrons they
run humic they run calmac and they run a
grow and or bloom and that's it and they
do a foliar when the plants are young
they have a serious IPM schedule of
course right but you know like I said
that there's a million ways to skin a
cat and you'd be surprised how far
nutrient can go in an organic system
yeah the soil food web is is that that
goes back to me the soil food would be
saying outdoor that's why I'll always
loved it for outdoor because it's it is
its nature right it's a song
those big beautiful plants and and yeah
that like like you said it fit the guy
that the guy that's 65 and saying he
can't figure it out and he's been
growing for 45 years that's here that's
your real grower right the guy that's
like this is the only way you do it
that's stick-in-the-mud and that ain't
going anywhere
so I so resonate with that statement
that you know there's there's a million
ways to do it and it's and it's always
changing - you know it's cannabis that's
that's that's the beauty about it it's
it's it's an individual man it's got a
personality it's fun we we just finished
up depth and we're probably about four
weeks out from fall harvest right now
we're not we're not disappointed at all
last year is about half pretty close to
double yeah I think I you know I haven't
messed with outdoor in a while but I
think last year that was probably packs
going for like 700 bucks which is it I
mean I I can't even figure that out you
know I mean it's it's rough so hard to
pay the bills at that right this
tributes are aggressive in there being
very friendly for sure a lot of dm's
yeah yeah and for us it's different when
he knows - you like Pacific reserve I'm
sure we don't you know it's not not that
classic season right we're perpetual we
harvest we if you do the math we harvest
about once every six days perpetually I
think we're on our hundred and
thirtysomething harvest right now since
we've you know since we open the doors
almost two years ago so it's it's it's
ever going you know there's and we're
lucky to be in Santa Barbara County -
because the microclimate there is it's
very stable you know
it's not they're not a lot of huge
seasonality in terms of climate your
your your D Li is all that's really
seasonal you know your your light index
you're having a little bit there
obviously you get less light in the
wintertime but same same kind of
microclimate all year round I have to
admit I am jealous of your weather down
there I mean I think there would have to
be like some alterations in the amounts
of water or things like that size pot I
mean I think it would still perform well
a little more humid down there so we'd
have to be a little bit more careful in
the oh geez that are sensitive and that
are potential to get p.m. but you know
being an experienced grower and growing
in multiple different places I think I'd
be able to figure it out right and
that's that's what we're saying too it
goes back to yeah it's cannabis it's
always gonna change you can never really
predict what its gonna do you can go and
try it and they take a round or two to
really hone it in but why are you
offering some space