[Music]
so what is it so Tom I want to share
with you the ballot initiative measure
AF in Mendocino County ballot measure
for work ballot measure in Mendocino
County for this election coming yes
remember 8 that's right
in California we're all gonna vote for
legalization of recreational cannabis in
Mendocino County specifically we're
gonna vote for protecting the small
farmers and that's because big AG is
already coming in and trying to dominate
the field
we don't want cannabis to be just like
every other crop that's been dominated
by big agriculture and big corporation
we want it to be the small farmers and
the family traditions they've had for
generations protected you're one of the
only people he cares about a small boy
was it talks about that so true so these
guys all grow pot y'all grow pot they've
been doing it for generations son groans
oh I haven't been in jail that's right
so they really believe in it back it up
and so this initiative will keep the
small farmers from becoming adopted by a
big farmer and this will protect them
from having pharmaceutical companies
coming and buying the property and going
with big agriculture you'll have a lot
of places doing that already
we're just saying let's protect the
heritage strains their heritage
practices farmers in this region so by
Chung's choice herbalizer and we'll
donate a big portion of the proceeds to
make sure this initiative passes both
YES on measure AF AF yes
you
[Music]