[Music]
metric is seed to sale tracking so the
concept of that is what it sounds like
that that every bit of cannabis in the
commercial cannabis chain supply chain
is going to be tracked from seed to sale
once that system is on-boarded that
means that when a seed is grown a clone
is made those start it with they get a
UID which is unique identifier they're
tagged at that level they get to be
tagged in lots of a hundred plants and
then there's a hundred tags reserved for
which of those plants make it into the
next line of the chain and from that
point that unique identifier is gonna
follow that product through the life of
through the life of that plant when it's
manufactured into a manufactured product
it's still going to be related to that
original UID when it moves to a
distributor they're gonna know which
batch which lot which unique identifier
is related to those products and when it
goes to retail and is sold to a consumer
we're going to know exactly that product
contains cannabis from this or these
plants if there's multiple plants that
are aggregated into a product those you
IDs are going to get combined and all of
that history will be captured in the
track and trace system every bit of
waste has to be documented in the system
every change of the disposition of a
plant has to be tracked in the system
when it goes from clone too immature
plant to flower in plant to when it's
harvested - if it's disposed - if it's
manufactured any change of state those
are all checkpoints in track and trace
where it has to be logged so once people
are on
bordered on to the system the entire
history of every bit of cannabis and
every bit of product it becomes is gonna
be recorded in that system which is
pretty amazing when you think about it
but it's also a monumental task to to
get all of that information in there and
that's where a lot of money questions of
how this process is really gonna work
come up because we have this difficulty
now of you have operators operating
under a temporary license with the
temporary license you're not able to get
on to track and trace yet only with the
issuance of annual licenses would an
operator get to take the training for
track and trace and then they have 30
days to onboard all of their impress
product into track and trace you have
this 30 day period of time where you're
gonna do a massive inventory and you
have to represent everything that you
have in track and trace after that 30
day period
everything starts with seed after that
like you do not get to bring in any
in-progress products at that point that
aren't represented in the system the
challenge that we're going to have is
you're gonna have different operators at
different places on the supply chain
getting their annual license at
different times so how the huge
challenge that the agencies are facing
is how do you onboard everybody at the
same time because if not you're gonna
have a cultivator who isn't on track and
trace still using their temporary
license and giving paper manifests and
documentation to a manufacturer who is
on track and trace who's gonna have to
input all that stuff into their system
creating it within the track and trace
system who may be selling to a
distributor who may or may not be on
track and trace so then they couldn't
complete the electronic transfer of that
system and then that distributor could
sell those products to multiple
retailers who may or may not be on track
and trace yet so so that I think is
going to be
one of the huge challenges of onboarding
is how are they going to complete the
life cycle of these products in track
and trace when there's inconsistent
adoption of it and I don't know how
that's going to be rectified unless they
put everybody on even with temporary
licenses to get all of the products in
there so that you can have a consistent
supply chain on track and trace or they
wait on the issuance of annual licenses
until you have a real critical mass of
license types that represent enough of
the supply chain to have everybody on
board in that same 30-day period of time
but I think that's going to be one of
the big challenges that we see is how
that onboarding works and what how I
mean what the liabilities are whose
responsibility it's going to be to input
that information when you're working
with some people on the system and some
people who aren't on the system what a
lot of people may not be aware of is
that even before track and trace becomes
active as an operator you are still
required to fulfill all of the
record-keeping requirements of what will
be on track and trace so those
record-keeping requirements are really
extensive even before track and trace
the shipping manifest has already been
published by the CDFA and other agencies
to say here's the shipping manifest you
should be using when you're transferring
product between licensees I mean those
if you think about when you look at the
record-keeping requirements for for
track and trace it does say that at a
minimum you have to be keeping these
things on on paper on invoices Matt you
know that you can have a spreadsheet but
you have to have your records maintained
in some way that you could give them to
the agencies upon request either in
hardcopy or electronic form is the way
they put it in the regulations so so
pretty much if you think about every one
of those checkpoints where you're
supposed to be doing you know
reconciliations event physical inventory
every 14 days you're supposed to have
really detailed information
on any sales invoice when you're
transferring before between licensees
you're supposed to be keeping contracts
with your distributors on file you're
supposed to have you know really
detailed inventory records in terms of
there's there's columns of here's the
information that kind of constitutes an
inventory and what I've been working
with a lot of people on is going over
those record-keeping requirements
because you know much like with the
transitional period and everybody
feeling shocked and surprised by the
packaging requirements when that day
hits and they issue your annual license
and a clock starts ticking and you have
five days to complete the training and
then 30 days to onboard all of your
products and to track and trace those
record-keeping requirements are in
effect so if you don't have that
information to to onboard your products
you're gonna be in this huge crush of
having to suddenly create systems and
protocols and checkpoints and keeping of
records and where did you where do you
weigh it and training your staff into in
terms of all of these different moments
of transition and if if you as an
operator haven't set up that you know
culture of compliance and system of
record-keeping yet it's gonna derail a
lot of businesses and in right now
there's a little bit of wiggle room you
know with keeping your paper records
with how long you have to reconcile your
inventory do you have a little bit more
flex when that is being logged in a
government system that is going to
reflect every single time that your
inventory doesn't line up every single
time that the weight isn't right it has
requirements of reconciliations for
different business types every 24 hours
every you know so many days notification
requirements because that's when it is
critical that you have developed these
processes and have already enough of a
handle on how to keep these records
and how to make sure that you're
ensuring the accuracy of the information
that you're inputting so that your
business can continue to run because
there's different states they handle at
different ways in some states when
you're track and trace goes off and it's
not if it's not synched up with your
physical inventory or your POS system
your system shuts down like if you and
you can't transfer anything until you
reconcile where did this go and and
that's one of the systems too is you
can't just say oh I don't know where it
went we we lost the pound of weed I have
no idea like you have to be able to you
have to be able to explain everything
that happens and and I would think that
most operators in the cannabis space in
California are not used to that level of
rigor and oversight on every single
activity and every single thing that
happens and it's gonna be a learning
experience for the agencies as well
because that you know they're I don't
know if they know out of a hundred
clones how many really get lost and how
much waste is created and how much
weight shifts between states and you
lose water weight at this point and I
think that we're going to see a lot of
changes you know with taxation with you
know what's expected in terms of how
products transform and how the supply
chain really works but that stuff's
gonna take time and unfortunately you
know the early licensees and the early
adopters are gonna be the guinea pigs in
that process of creating the data that
they need to see how this system really
works so it seems like if you were
walking into a brand's office or a
dispensary and they haven't started
anything would basically be like you
know have a point person who's gonna be
like your metric guru yeah
don't have it be one person because of
they leave your company then you're
screwed
yeah have multiple people but like
basically it's gonna be a full time or
like half day job for somebody if I was
to be working with their consulting with
a brand that has
of this ready or thinks they have some
of it ready and maybe it doesn't line up
all the way I mean some of the first
things to do there's there's a there's a
part in the regulations that I say
should always strike fear into any
licensees heart which is that more or
less to paraphrase the the actions
omissions or failures of any employee
are taken as the actions omissions of
failures of the licensee themself so
that is the huge justification in case
for employee training and for why it is
so important that your entire staff
understands the the necessity and
consequences of this culture of
compliance that start I mean compliance
is like the big buzzword right now in
terms of cannabis because it's that it's
what makes the engine run it's such a
we're entering into I mean we're not
entering we're here into such a
regulated environment that this this
aspect of record-keeping or inventory
management is not one person's job we're
used to say well I'll have it is my
inventory manager and that's his job and
its and its really it becomes
everybody's job because so much of the
activities that used to be you know
completely acceptable you know at the
retail level for example it's totally
normal in so many cases for for a
budtender to say oh well we're out of
this product so I'm just gonna sell it
as this product because here it is in
the POS and it is the same amount and I
can't find this where that becomes
utterly unacceptable at this point
because if you have you know your your
software data that goes out of sync with
your physical inventory that goes out of
sync with your track and trace those are
really difficult reconciliations to
backtrack and figure out what happened
and that's like some of what everybody's
awakening to is that now suddenly a lot
of people you go from maintaining one
inventory or two that was your physical
and from inventory and what's in your
POS to now you have three different
inventories that you're trying to keep
in sync at all times which is the
physical
taury your POS or erp whatever you're
using your in-house system and then the
track and trace system and all of those
have to match and all of those have to
be reconciled on a daily basis and
you're not you don't want them to get
too out of sync
and there's a lot of challenges because
there's a lot of POS companies that are
saying like you'll never have to log in
to track and trace and we'll handle
everything and we'll just do it all and
in one of the things you you're gonna
want to log into track and trace
occasionally because you don't want to
discover two weeks later when you do
your 14-day reconciliation that things
have gone out of sync and then you got
to be a forensic archaeologist to figure
out what happened you know and go back
and and reconcile each of those
instances of where did this Graham go so
those aspects of and and I will see for
a lot of operators it really helps to
bring in a compliance person or to have
somebody come and kind of drive home
that this is not just some crazy stuff
that the bosses are making up to make
your job horrible and to make you do a
lot of extra work it's a real necessity
and I think some of the you know the
creativity and opportunity of this
moment is to figure out how do you use
these requirements of the regulation to
actually help to improve and inform your
business and give you better data and
give you the ability to make better
business decisions and give you the
ability to you know feel more
comfortable and confident with your
staff because you there's been a lot of
operators who have fear of theft and in
diversion and other issues where this
just kind of introduces a lot more kind
of checks and balances to help everybody
to to do their job and to help to
maintain inventories in a more cohesive
way but it is but I think that there is
no under estimating how big this onus of
record-keeping is when you
look at the regulations across the
different agencies and see how many
instances there are of where that
record-keeping obligation is and how
many things are supposed to be keeping
all ready and that you have to maintain
all these records for seven years you
know that this becomes an enormous part
of your business
is how you're going to maintain these
records make sure that they're accurate
like it's the responsibility of the
operators to enter accurate information
into track and trace and make sure your
employees are entering accurate
information in the track and trace and
and just again that that obligation of
that record-keeping doesn't start with
track and trace it started back in
January the employee training is going
to be a huge part but in order to train
those employees you're gonna have to
have some really clear SOPs protocols
best practices I call it I'm a big
checklist geek so I call it like flight
checklists like for any activity as
simple as it seems there should be a
checklist to help your employees to help
the managers go did you do X Y &amp; Z you
know when you're conducting a sale did
you get this information when you're
receiving a product did you check and
log all of these things when we're
transferring a product did we do all of
this when you're when you're beer a
cultivator and the plant is changing
state did you log all of this
information did you issue the right
certificates did you you know log the
things in the correct place and then
update track and trace accordingly
there's so many discreet check points
for these things like I have so many
chocolates because every activity that
you do as an operator you know it kind
of has these emergency flight checklists
of if you don't do these five things you
know we're gonna have some critical
errors down the road and and some of
that stuff I always think with like with
checklist with pilots it's not to be
insulting to be like you don't know how
to fly a plane so
you have to use this checklist it's
because in these in the most mundane
activities is kind of where we go dead
sometimes and we think we know these
things and we think we do them by rote
or we think I know this person I don't
have to check their ID or whatever it is
that there's kind of the more support
you can give people by just having these
you know easy-peasy little a few step
checklist to make sure that those
critical points are being handled
correctly is is really important and
then and then some of it is just knowing
the regulations because I think that
something still there's so many of them
they change you know we just got a new
set of emergency rags we're gonna get
the language of the full regulations and
to really understand and go through them
to see what those record-keeping
requirements are and I also think it's
critical for operators to know that not
all of the regulations that impact their
business are in the cannabis regulations
the cannabis regulations reference many
other regulations and you have to know
what's in those and what record-keeping
requirements or other requirements may
be contained in these other you know
codes and public resource things that
affect your business and then just the
normal stuff I mean the normal stuff of
any business because I think that's
where you know for a lot of the
operators in this space it's a whole new
world of suddenly you go from having
volunteers at your collective to now
you're a commercial cannabis business
you have to contend with all of these
regulations you have to contend with all
of the HR and labor code regulations of
California which isn't easy you have to
contend with OSHA you have to get like
any of these things that impact any
business are now the onus of any
cannabis operator regardless of the size
of your business so what percentage
brands retailers and cultivators do you
think have made significant progress on
their understanding and implementation
of best practices related to track and
race I'm not sure how many California
operators are prepared for the reality
of track and trace State there's some
brands in California that that have come
to California from other states that are
kind of fully adept and conscious of you
know the requirements of that system
so I think they they come with a very
different perspective but that's a small
percentage of operators for what you
call it like the legacy operators of
California who have been you know in the
collective model for a long time or
cultivating kind of outside of the
regulated system for a long time it's
it's the ones that I'm working with it's
a real rude awakening in many ways to
suddenly see just how many things that
they have to do and in some ways it's a
real disruption to you know their
natural organic processes that they have
a way that they've been doing things for
decades at this point and and that that
I mean that's why I try to tell people
as much as possible when I'm working
with them like to start practicing these
new requirements these checkpoints these
where you have to weigh things and when
you have to report things and when you
have to notify the agencies of certain
things to start practicing that as much
as possible before track and trace kicks
in because just when track and trace
when it's active the stakes are higher
the the logging is more permanent and
it's harder to backtrack it's harder to
change things at that point
and and that you're kind of on this this
real ticking clock at that point so it's
not as easy to test new systems and
adapt and be like oh well let's try it
this way or maybe this person would be
the best to do it like all of those
changes after track and trace require
notifications to the agency of whose
your track and trace manager and like
you can't just make those pivots as
swiftly or organically as you could now
so I think that you know as much as
possible for the operators to really
start practicing that as much as
possible before they get their annual
license and and that happens is really
critical I mean I couldn't venture a
percentage of booze who's ready but I do
think I do think you're gonna see a lot
of changes in you you know for POS
companies you know what they're
advertising points are cuz right now
there's been a lot of stuff that's about
like user experience and you know that
it's cool for this or it looks really
good on the iPad or how it manages you
know front facing inventory but I do
think a big shift you're gonna see with
with the release of track and trace is
what the selling points are for POS
systems and that people yeah and making
sure people understand what compliant
means with it with a track and trace
system I mean with the POS system many
POS systems will say you know oh we're
approved we have the API for track and
trace we interact with track and trace
but what they mean is it at the end of
the day you can download an Excel
spreadsheet and you can physically
rearrange the columns and upload it to
track and trace yourself and that 90% of
the time it's gonna fail and then you're
gonna sit there in the middle of the
night you know ticking clock you have 24
hours to upload your information for the
day and you're gonna freak out and and
and try to get it to talk to track and
trace and maybe there'll be errors and
maybe they won't so so the POS systems
that are gonna have an actual true
automated real-time update of track and
trace are going to be
referable in some ways but I've still
seen operators who are like we'll do I
want real-time because what if it makes
a mistake and then I have to fix it and
it's like understanding like it's it's
like it's it's like operating inside of
an x-ray machine like anything you do
that's a mistake they're gonna see
they're gonna see it's gonna be logged
and it's okay to make mistakes in some
ways there's there's a process for doing
it but you just have to report
everything and if you're making 50
mistakes a day then that's not gonna
look good on the system so so that's why
there's gonna be this real demand for
precision and accuracy and you know
inventory management and those aspects
are gonna become critical in the
operation of businesses which is I think
just for a lot of the operators in
California like I said a level of rigor
that they are not used to one of the
realities that operators should be aware
of is that even now the agencies could
come and at audit your records to say
you should have been keeping paper
records of every transfer every receipt
of product from a licensed from a
licensee all of your contracts with
distribution with license distributions
that all should have been happening
since January so they're anticipating
that you've got all these paper
documents for every record-keeping
requirement that's that sitting in your
cabinet that they could at their
discretion come and say like hey let's
check out where did this product come
from where's your shipping manifest to
which licensed you know manufacturer
provided this product like they could do
that when your annual licenses issued
you have five days to do the track and
trace training and then you have 30 days
to onboard all of your product during
that 30 days you still have to be
keeping all of your records on product
that's coming in and out but that's just
a time span that you have to represent
in the track and trace system every
single prod
that you have at whatever level of
production it's at so if you're a
cultivator you're inputting how many
immature plants do you have what's in
your canopy right now what's drying and
harvest that you got 30 days to put it
all in after that 30 days you can't put
any more in progress you can't go back
and be like oh I found you know a
hundred more clones we forgot about over
here and we want to put them in the
system now actually that's a bad example
because clones technically you can put
them in from the clone level but you
can't be found like a mature plants and
her like actually there's more can see
than we thought then you can't bring
them into the system at that point after
those 30 days anything that wasn't
represented in your system starts at a
seed or a clone and then and then you
follow it through the system so we're
gonna have a bunch of on-boarded
products that'll be in progress so you
may be a distributor at that point
that's receiving an already made product
from a manufacturer that got on-boarded
into track and trace up until definitely
July first is there were no permanently
our annual licenses but now as I sew I
get my license I get my annual license
on July 1st up until now I just have to
keep records here at some point and so
this is my question at what point and is
it 30 days after I get my annual license
do I proactively have to get on a
computer and enter data and submit it
into the government metric system versus
just keeping it on set yeah ok so once
you get your annual license and you have
that 30 days to onboard your product
from that point on everything that
happens is communicated to the
government agencies through track and
trace that every activity that you
participate in anything you receive
anything you said
anything you do anything internal
everything is recorded into track and
trace and there and for different
operators there's a different timeline
of how long you have from the time of
the activity to notify the system in in
in track and trace and that can be
anywhere from 24 hours for certain
activities to three days for certain
activities that that you have these
timelines that are established in the
regulations of from the moment this
thing happens you have this long to
report it in track and trace and if
those activities go out of sync and
things are not represented in track and
trace where suddenly a mature plant
appears that wasn't tracked from clone
or suddenly a manufactured product
appears that doesn't isn't connected to
a UID from from a seed or a clone you
have a problem because everything from
that point on once once people are on
track and trace and those products are
being tracked from seed to sale it has
an entire history that's embedded into
its its unique identifiers and it's
gonna get a lot harder to bring in
products that are not part of the
license system because it will because
there will be no way for it to be
inserted into those systems without
those identifiers that after that
onboarding period start at seed so two
takeaway for me is once you've on
boarded and you're in kind of your
steady-state operating mode you'll
pretty much be almost daily entering
system and entering data into the metric
system and hitting the submit button and
that data is gonna go from your computer
to the government servers and they will
now have access to your information and
if you get lazy on that there will be
consequences like you can't fall behind
on that
yeah from the time that operators
complete that onboarding on to metric on
to track and trace I mean there's gonna
be a new job at your facility which is
your track and trace manager you know
somebody has that job and and it's in
the regulations that you have to select
somebody to fulfill that role and that
they are you know fulfilling the
obligation of monitoring all of these
requirements and everything that has to
be entered and then the syste and in
fulfilling one of the things too is
fulfilling system notifications the
trick is not just you telling the track
and trace system they're gonna tell you
stuff too and if you get a notification
from the track and trace they're gonna
say how long you have to respond to
whatever the request was and whatever
the notification is from track and trace
and that's something that that person
has to stay on top of and I think that
that's a new reality that that very few
people are prepared for in California of
having this relationship with this you
know direct channel to the state
government who's going to be monitoring
every activity that every operator in
the cannabis chain conducts so if I am a
track and trace manager in Washington
State or Colorado I'd probably have a
lot of job offers today yeah I would
imagine I would imagine that we're gonna
see a lot of a lot of hot job market for
people in other states you have a lot of
experience dealing with track and trace
who are those track and trace account
managers from other states for
businesses that have not been you know
audited failed or penalize are gonna
become kind of like hot properties for
California of really wanting to tap
people who have the expertise of dealing
with these systems and who really
understand the demands and the scope and
the rigor of
what it is to communicate and keep these
systems synched with your your physical
operations one of the one of the biggest
shortcomings I've found in all of the
audits that I do and all of the ongoing
compliance work that I do with people is
this record-keeping piece where I think
that it mean it's very difficult I have
a great deal of empathy for operators in
terms of the fact that it's it's
impossible to comply with every single
regulation that's put out there right
now
and and I think that they move through
them you know in in you know
prioritizing them in a certain way and
some of the stuff that operators have to
do is just to survive to pay their bills
at this point and to make sure that
their businesses don't collapse and go
under while they're trying to deal with
all the costs of becoming a compliant
operation and that in that this piece
the the record-keeping piece is kind of
so far down the line of what's
forward-facing for your business they're
like ah I know yeah I mean that it
doesn't it doesn't you know hold up much
water for them right now but I think
that that profoundly changes as the
specter of track and trace in metric
come closer because you start to review
okay well when I go in to track a trace
what a minute what is it that I'm
putting in there and then you see how
many points of contact there are and how
many representations there has to be in
that system and how necessary it is that
there's nothing I mean that the product
can't move from location to location
with a distributor without going into
metric and doing a shipping manifest and
receiving that shipping manifest in
metric so my understanding is even POS
companies that are like you'll never
have to touch metric it's not true
because you have to go in there for
certain activities such as the
descending and receipt of the shipping
manifests for any transfer or product so
and it's in part of it too is
you know like I keep saying is that the
the big trick is to figure out how to
not make the this process for cannabis
operators just a horrible experience of
stuff that's happening to them to be
like Oh God and to actually you know
really confront these things really dig
into these regulations and see how you
can make them serve your business
because because few people would argue
that having super accurate inventory is
a terrible thing for a business so and
then when you see it that way and see
that that's all really that that is the
function of track and trace is to make
sure that everything stays in the supply
chain and that you're not losing product
and that your employees aren't stealing
from you and that you know if something
is going terribly wrong and you're
losing a huge percentage of your plant
what's happening like that it gives you
these opportunities to to you know be a
business and see like how can I improve
my efficiency and how can I make this
system work and in and then that way you
know it's not that scary I mean you know
the scariest thing about metric is that
it's kind of like looks like software
from the 90s I think that's gonna say
words like it would be nice if it was
like a little more you know 2.0 we'll
see so it's kind of like telling my
three-year-old daughter yeah there's a
positive in this which is you'll be big
strong and healthy yeah definitely
definitely metric insight into your
inventory to what's selling what's not
selling yeah I think the cannabis
industry is definitely having an eat
your vegetables moment that's like you
know this is this is how the industry
the licensed industry the regulated
industry distinguishes itself from an
illicit market is all of these things
that feel horrible in some ways are
absolutely not
Cerie it is absolutely necessary that we
have rigorous testing of products it is
absolutely necessary that we fulfill
packaging and labeling requirements what
those are can be changed and adapted and
evolved you know to hopefully have less
impact on the environment and but it is
absolutely necessary that we have
standards for for this industry and it's
absolutely necessary you know and in
effect we're we're part of a crazy
paradigm shift we're part of a change in
cultural consciousness about the
attitudes towards cannabis and the
attitudes towards a lot of different
kinds of things in in part of our job as
the cannabis industry is to help people
confront their fears and to help
eliminate those perceptions of what they
think the market is so it's you know
it's tough times for us to have to go
through it and be so over regulated in
and rigorous about things but what we
get to do in that process is demonstrate
that this is a business like other
businesses and and it's not some crazy
free-for-all where every operator is
feeding the illicit market and we're all
doing they say you know by onboarding
onto track and trace by showing the life
of a product by show like helping to
educate the agencies and the government
in terms of how this stuff really works
that's the ways that we actually
influence the policy in the direction of
the industry and help to relax some of
those unfounded fears and some founded
fears about how this industry can be
wrangled
and
[Music]