[Music]
I'm Brett Hartmann I'm director of
operations for alternative medicine
group located in bel-air and I oversee
purchasing project management for Green
Cross of Torrance
I am community liaison for de la moda
cannabis cultivation company and I'm the
founder of my cannabis trainer which is
a consulting company that works from
everything from compliance to
cannabinoid recommendations for to
physicians and veterinarians I work
primarily with getting our stores ready
through licensing preparing the storage
for licensing we have received our
temporary license last year and February
we were one of the first stores here in
Los Angeles a alternative medicine group
and Green Cross and we are working on
getting our state full certification
which will come in in September at that
time we'll be requested to meet these
metric track and trace situation we're
currently right now we are handling our
manifests just like we should every time
we get an order in it's coming from
somebody who's legal and compliant we're
getting their COAS every single time
that we get an order but these were
actually protocols that we put in place
before January we were already working
with vendors that we knew were going to
be compliant and then in February we
were put in this situation where once we
got our license we couldn't buy product
really from anybody and our stores were
pretty empty yeah we were the first
stores to really be legally open in
February on February 5th when the stores
got their license prior to that we could
order from about 30 or 40 vendors which
was a massive reduction from who we
could order from prior to January so
we've been having these periods of time
where every time we go through
regulations we have an abrupt smaller
amount of product that I can buy for the
stores and that means less product for
the patients which also means less tax
revenue for the state so in February
that was a situation we we were met with
in July first a lot of people were taken
off-guard because everybody got
temporary extensions on all of these
things but they did not extend the the
packaging and lab testing requirements
which a lot of people had anticipated
that they would and that's one of the
issues that I see in the cannabis
industry is that we don't have foresight
into what is the me coming down the road
for us you may not think you may think
that they're gonna give you an extension
but you should always prepare that
they're not you that's the problem with
why stores were not prepared for July
first is because we were dealing with
vendors that were telling us that they
were going to be compliant however they
were not they weren't for packaging they
didn't have the lab testing the phase 2
lab testing and it put us all in a
situation where as of July 1st a lot of
stores had zero product and those were
stores that had no foresight they did
not prepare until the last week of June
like oh I can't sell my own product
anymore let's clear off all of our
product that we have so I don't have to
send any of it to be destroyed and then
we'll just buy product well that it
wasn't that easy everybody was already
cleared out of stock and so July 1st you
went from 30 so when we start on July
1st we probably had max eight to ten
vendors that we could that we had on our
shelves that we can work with some of
the brands that we had were island up
north floor cow for flour products and
then for product wise we had heavy
hitters for vapor pens pure vape and
tincture wise we had Popham Berkeley
edibles we had Kanako's so we had a
vendor for each category but the product
diversity was so minimal that people
were coming in the door on July 1st and
just terribly upset that you don't have
this so you don't have that and it's our
obligation to the patients and to the
customers to explain to them the reason
why is that they understand that their
voice can be heard as well not just as
angry with us but angry and you know
talk to your representatives talk to the
government go in place you know a lot of
people still don't want to come out of
the green closet but this is a situation
we're in and then we've made it through
each of these milestones and we have
survived every step of the way
and then here in September when we have
to go for our metric track and trace
training we'll have 30 days after that
to comply and to be completely on metric
which our point-of-sale system we've
switched to a point-of-sale system that
will be fully integrated into the system
however it's still our obligation to
verify that everything is in there
properly and we are going to be hiring
and training an individual that is going
to be our compliance specialist for the
store because there is no way that we
can put that on any employee that we
have right now without that proper
training in place and it is we have to
do our due diligence because even if my
employee makes a mistake I can't tell
this day oh my employee made a mistake I
let them go and you know please forgive
me it we're still fully responsible for
anything that any of our staff members
do here so we have to be compliance has
always been a huge issue for us because
we were a pre ICO property dispensary so
if we ever stepped outside of that we
could have our store shut down so I
think for us we have always kept
compliance as the foundation of how we
were moving forward in this in this
industry because it was the only way to
survive and that's why a lot of
companies have not I remember when we
passed legalization and they came out
and said you know 90 percent of the
companies that exist right now are not
going to exist into the future and I
believe that and I actually think that
that was not correct I think is like 95
percent what point of sale software
previous to being licensed we switch
from bio track to trees and there was
many reasons why we switched to trees to
meet a lot of the needs that we had for
a growing company we needed an inventory
system that was going to be integrated
into metric we needed an inventory that
we could do online menus and that was
going to be a lot more user friendly
than the system that we had I evaluated
multiple companies when we when we went
down that route and I can't every
company is growing every company is
learning from their mistakes and I feel
that trees is doing that another company
that I really recommend to people is
green bits I've been a big supporter of
them as well I think to have an awesome
team and an awesome platform but right
now that's what we're currently using
for our stores is trees because they
will also be metric track and trays
integrated to where at the end of every
night I'm not going to sit there and
have to upload all of ourselves to
metric the system should be doing that
automatically every 10 minutes the
requirements for us as a retailer for
corresponding information to metric is
at the end of every day we have to send
our cells that we have to the system
every two weeks we have to apply our
inventory to the system which the way
that we do is we do a we do a different
inventory every single day so either
it's vapor and extracts and we do that
so basically we will be supplying that
every week to the system and we have the
opportunity that trees will update that
information into the system to metric
and it's our responsibility if we want
that to go smoothly is to make sure that
we're always on point that we didn't
make any mistakes we've entered manifest
into the system and that is the point of
using a system as integrated as theirs
is that it will do a lot of that work
for us to where we are pretty much just
auditing it constantly and we are
required to send ourselves every single
day into the system some store
specifically in Colorado where there's a
little bit more time with some of this
is they have been sitting there for
hours at the end of the day just
uploading their sales into the system
and if one of those 24 digit numbers is
off it kicks back to the entire report
and then you have to go
through there and find out why this
number is incorrect and where it ended
up being incorrect is when it was
received into the system to where
somebody did not properly put in that
number and that's why it's kicking back
the report so for us our obligation
throughout the entire thing is to just
audit every step of the way to make sure
that the end of the night we have a
smooth transition to where we're
literally just closing out our system
closing out our drawers and go home and
where it's uploaded everything verify
everything's uploaded because if we have
one situation where it didn't upload we
are no longer compliant we are no longer
meeting metrics track and trace
standards and that puts our license at
risk
it's huge fines all for what are going
to be is very simple mistakes and that's
why I think it's very important for
stores for every single cannabis company
right now having a new department built
just around compliance so things that
we've been doing to prepare for Mack
metric track and trace is obviously
inventories are crucial to our store
and we've been doing that since before
we even knew that metric track and trace
was going to be going into a vector when
it was going into effect a lot of stores
don't do inventory like they should be
they do well you know an all-over
inventory once a month or they they do a
half-assed job doing it and for us it's
I take my experience doing track and
trace basically with control drugs from
the veterinary world where we have to
send in a report every single month on
what is how much fentanyl we have and
where was it used and why do we have the
loss that we have I'm taking those
inventory best practices from the
veterinary world and then from retail
when we would do that in clothing when I
oversaw stores and retail and applying
them all into here and I think that
that's what I'm really excited about in
cannabis right now is now that we're
legalized we're starting to be able to
bring professionals from other
industries and bring their best
practices into that and that's what
we're integrating right now is I have my
cells managers from Nordstrom my
inventory manager has a strong
background in shipping and shipping
manifest so this is all going to be a
benefit to our store and we're taking
those best practices but we've been
doing a lot of this stuff for when we
require it when you ship me a product I
want to see your manifest I need to see
these type of things before manifest
even
and I you were not delivering anything
to my store without a paper invoice
without who it was going to without you
sending me your license beforehand and
it was in your file and every time you
bring me this it goes into your file and
we're going to be continuing to evolve
that system to where it's you know we're
going to be able to just scan it as soon
as it comes in the door and then we'll
have an e-version of it we'll have a
paper copy and just doing our due
diligence that every time we get an
order delivered we sit there and take
our time and count it out with a
delivery driver and I think that that's
been an issue in the past there's a lot
of delivery drivers you know just drop
it off and you don't they're just out
the door and we require that you come in
through the back door that you wear your
ID badge you check in at the front and
and that when you deliver the product
we're going to sit there and go through
every single one to make sure it matches
that manifest so that when we bring it
into our system that we haven't missed
the stuff there we're not putting
something in our system that isn't there
and then I'm gonna have to do an
inventory loss report here when we go to
the metric track and trace and honestly
it's keeping a tight inventory system to
where there's a checksum balance it's
not just one person checking you know
where if you count that it says that
we're supposed to have ten can of coke
cookies you make sure that there's ten
if there's not you have another person
count it to make sure where it's at and
just using those best practices from
other industries on inventory to to fit
ours because we're gonna be under such
tight control that no missing product is
going to be acceptable when I got into
this industry four years ago I was
shocked that we didn't have requirements
on lab testing and that we did not have
requirements on packaging and we didn't
have requirements on tracking you know
if a product is grown with some chemical
in it we need to know where it ends up
at and even though you know everything
that's being track and traced if
something comes back that there's a
recall on it we know every single
product to every single patient to every
single customer that we need to contact
and I'm a big proponent of track and
trace I I feel like it is what is going
to professionalize this industry to move
us into a national and international
platform and that is where cannabis is
going it is going to be cumbersome it's
going to be difficult for us to all get
through learning how to use a new system
is anytime you have to learn any new
program
it's gonna be difficult that you just
have to go at it with confidence every
time you have a training opportunity
deal with it
explain it to your staff member so they
know more about it as well so
everybody's feeling confident with it
some of the things that I would like to
see with metric where it's gonna put us
into that same issue as January 1st and
February 5th for us and July 1st is that
here in September when I'm able to take
my track and trace training
I'll have 30 days to comply so does that
mean that at the end of that 30 days
that here in October I'm only going to
be able to purchase products from
vendors that I already have metric track
and trays and that is going to again
reduce the amount of product that I can
have on my shelves which will again
reduce the amount of tax revenue that
the city and the state are is gonna see
from cannabis taxes so for me what I
would know will penalize compliant
operators oh for sure it will definitely
it's just another penalty for us however
the way I like to think of it as is that
you know as being a pre ICO property
dispenser both of the stores are and
we've kind of gotten to have this in
this we're ahead of the curve in a lot
of ways we've gotten to to work in this
industry long enough that we should have
learned by now that this is how our
industry is going to continue to be it's
not going to be over in October it's not
going to be in January there's going to
be constant updates to this and I feel
that the state will see some of these
hindrances that they've put on us and
see that it's hurting to things it's
hurting patients and customers from
being able to get their medicine and
it's hurting tax revenue so I really do
hope that the regulator's see when we
start to move into Trekker track and
trace that they're just gonna set a date
in the future say January 1st 2019 we're
all on metric everybody's in the same
boat everybody grab a paddle let's swim
you know and I really do hope that that
is what's gonna happen however it
doesn't look like that and I'm not gonna
feel I'm not going to expect that to
happen because I feel that you know
we're gonna be presented with the same
thing so right now what I'm doing is I'm
working with all of my vendors now
updating their files on when do you
expect for you to be moving into track
and trace so I know who to order at what
times because it's not I'm also the sole
buyer for AMG and I oversee buying for
grain
cross and without product our store
can't be open and that's where a lot of
stores are currently at right now is
they just were not ready for July first
and that's why they have no flour on
their shelves or they have no product on
their shelves and they're having to shut
down temporarily while they get these
products in and I think that's what's so
important also about networking in our
industry is making sure that you're
getting out there and you're going to
events and that you are going to you
know available training seminars so that
you can meet people in this industry
that are going do you have product
available for you may even possibly be
your next compliant officer for your
company and I really do hope that the
state feels what we're going through
right now in regards to they're gonna
see the tax revenue drop from just this
month alone because no stores are having
they are able to sell what they would
normally be selling I also hope that
they see that you know on average they
were saying each manufacturer had over
two hundred thousand dollars worth of
product that were unable to move well
that's two hundred thousand dollars
worth of product for them that equates
to forty eight thousand dollars worth of
excise tax revenue that equates to over
twenty thirty thousand and basically tax
revenue for the city on medical and or
adult use taxes and that was a
significant pain that each manufacturer
is feeling right now in the state is
gonna feel it that way
I hope that they're able to see like we
need to make a extensions at times when
they're needed but at the same time
let's get through this together we'll
move forward and when we get into metric
track and trace we do that together as
well you know I think that a lot of
people are really scared of it happening
and they don't want to learn about it
because they're scared of it and it's
time to just like just suck it up you're
a pioneer in this industry and keep
doing that if not you're gonna get left
behind as I have with countless friends
and colleagues and companies they have
been left behind because they were too
scared to really move forward with how
do I get licensed how do I get my
permits how do I get a distributor
license or work with a distributor who
to work with and that's what this
industry the the regulations are
cleaning that up
you know before I'd have to set a
meeting with a with a vendor so that I
could ask them everything from how was
your product cultivated from the
beginning
what you know what is your lab testing
where you know basically all of these
standards that I set in place and now
with these new regulations it's a lot
easier for me you can go ahead and send
me all of your license all of your lab
testing results all of your menus to
where I don't necessarily need to have a
sample of your product to be able to
know that this is going to be safe for
my patients just as there is an issue
right now with getting compliant and
quality products on our shelves there's
going to be a big issue with finding
people that want to work in our industry
or that already work in an industry want
to come to California too to help us
with this that we can hire on is our
compliance officer for our stores and
for our companies and there's going to
be a you know that's definitely going to
be a demand for those individuals and
that it's also something that a lot of
stores are not budgeting into their into
their annual budget is bringing on
somebody with that kind of ability and
it's something that our industry here in
California doesn't do a good job of is
is keeping people on their their payroll
but you know this is something that for
a long time where it's paid cash at the
end of every day we do not build our
workforce to be a place where we foster
the type of environment that is for
productivity you know we don't offer
health insurance we don't offer paid
vacations we don't do a lot of these
things and this is going to kind of
force us to step outside of that because
these individuals that are professionals
in Colorado and other states are getting
those type of benefits and if they're
going to be willing to move to a state
such as California with such a high cost
of living and taxes we're going to have
to pay for that and but it's also going
to be a necessary requirement you need
to have somebody who can do this and we
need to do our due diligence on finding
those individuals so I'm a big proponent
of LinkedIn I'm a big proponent of
networking because this is where you're
going to find those individuals a
majority of the time my hiring practices
I usually do a group interview and then
a one-on-one interview and then I do a
working interview where you come in and
we just you get to meet with all the
staff members and kind of see what your
job is going to be and make sure that
the entire staff is cool because anytime
you add somebody to the team it causes a
staff dynamics
shift and that's what we need to be
looking into when we're going to be
bringing on another manager is basically
what a compliance management officer is
going to be for our stores we need to
know that they're going to fit with our
current methods or we need to change our
current methods to meet their standards
because this is going to be the
foundation of our industry moving
forward if we do not have somebody that
we can fully trust and that is doing
their job and it may be that we hire
somebody that with the experience from
out of state it may be that we hire
somebody with it from another industry
that is able to have the critical
thinking skills to develop a metric
track and trace version of what they
were doing and that is what we're going
to be doing it's what we're going to be
finding every single one of our
directors four four stores or four
companies needs to be just as competent
in metric track and trace as their
officer and that Officer also needs to
train have a an assistant to because we
are going to have to give these officers
a break and a vacation and they can't
always be there and that's something
that our industry has a hard time too
it's like we find somebody who works
hard and works long hours and then we
work them to death and then they they
have poor work productivity after the
first year and then we lose them and we
got to hire another workhorse basically
and so it's going to make us have to
professionalize our working standards
and one of the things that I really try
to implement is a more European business
model to where we have you have
quarterly breaks you have you know I
would love to implement health insurance
for our staff to where they can just
focus on being happy and healthy and
happy healthy people are the most
productive people my personal movement
in cannabis is to make it a place that
really fosters what the cannabis plant
is about is about homeostasis finding
that balance to where you can have your
own life and still come into work and
take your time and to rejuvenate because
every time you come back from a vacation
you feel back you come back and recharge
and you were able to look at your work
from a different perspective so I really
do hope that with metric track and trace
and all of these things it's just
pushing us forward and making us more
professional and there was going to be
people left behind and there's going to
be stores that are going to shut down
and there are going to be companies that
do not make it into this next realm but
you got a fight what what what are the
requirements for who on your team you do
put through the metric training and then
what are you gonna do are you gonna do
more than that number of people so
currently for both of my stores we have
a full management team of an inventory
manager a sales manager a purchasing
manager to where and to where each one
of those individuals we're gonna push
through metric where we're going to make
sure everybody is metric on our
management team so that matric training
so that make sure that every single one
of them is able to give information to
the other one so like in college we I
know a lot of people hate working on
group projects but I always felt like
the classes I did best on is where I had
a core group of people that I was with
that we would divide up the work and
then we would cross train each other on
it and I feel like that's what we're
going to do here is each one of them
brings their each one of my management
team each one of my members of my
management team brings a special to the
special specialty to the group that
they're going to look at this from a
different angle and we're going to be
able to train each other and think that
that's where we're actually having
issues right now as is just the the
interpretation of the new regulations
they came out so just Matt you know just
written down to where everybody's
interpreting differently it's in my
comparison is it's like it's like the
Bible where it's this person is
interpreting over here and so I've got
some Roman Catholics over here I got
some Jehovah Witnesses running around
over here you know everybody's
interpreting these the this regulations
as as their Bible as though this is the
way it has to be or this is the way it
has to be and there hasn't been a lot of
oversight from the government saying no
no this is how it is because in a lot of
ways the government is learning they're
they're interpreting it their own way
with their own preconceived notions so
what I'm going to do is I'm pushing
myself all of my management team is
going to be going through training we
will have a compliance officer for each
store and that is how we're going to be
moving forward with metric and every
single employee is going to be added to
their training manuals where they are
going to understand which metric is and
why the importance of doing their due
diligence when they're doing inventory
and when they're selling product and
when they give the receipt to the
patient verifying that every single
product on their
is what you are giving to that person so
even the bud tenders will have some sort
of training maybe not the full metric
course but at least in their training
manual yes the the foundation of our
store and our training for every
employee here is compliant so every
single employee with the stores will be
going through that avery even with our
security companies we will apply they
will have a training manual a training
portion added to their manual over what
is tracking trays so that they know what
their responsibility is when we have a
vendor coming to the store or when
patients are leaving and how they're
leaving the store with their product
every single person in our store will be
briefed on it and will be trained in the
way that fits their position best some
individuals will have significantly more
training and some individuals will have
it understanding of how the product
leaves a store and how it's in the store
and how you do inventories but everybody
will have metric added to their training
and that's something I actually don't
see with stores very often is that they
actually have training manuals or
training modules for their patients to
to work I mean for their patient
consultants to work with and that's
something that I'm big on SOPs I brought
that from the veterinary world is is
standard operating procedure development
a lot of stores don't have this for
regarding this is how we do every step
by step by step from our management team
to our employ all of the employees how
you clean the restroom how you do
inventory how you sell a product
everything needs to be streamlined so
that when we bring on a new employee
it's not like the bet the old days where
it's just like to get them on the floor
and just see how they do and see how
they can do it's like it's not that any
more you know training takes a full 30
days for every employee before we let
them go on on solo I just really look
forward to this next this next chapter
in cannabis history I feel like we are
about to launch to a national platform
metric is going to assist on making a
national platform so that when we're
able to sell California cannabis all
over the country that we know where it
came from this is what metric is doing
for us and though metric was built on us
to track strawberries in Florida many
years ago it is now grown into the
system that is going to allow us to have
a
properly regulated national cannabis
market and soon after that international
cannabis market and like what we're
seeing in Humboldt County where they
have sick ba which is their version of
metric it's a way for them to track
everything that's coming from Humboldt
you know the champagne of champagne is
basically what Humboldt is and it's
going to allow us to make sure that we
know where every product came from that
if you're selling product on a shelf in
a store in Texas that says it's
California cannabis you know for a fact
it was grown in California and
California has always been the biggest
producer for the United States for
cannabis so I'm just really looking
forward to us going national and
international and metric is a component
to making all of that happen and if you
don't jump on it you're going to get
left behind
you
[Music]