[Music]
chatting about people's experiences with
metric and integrating onto metric
that's something they're starting to
roll out Provisionals and annuals and so
more and more people are starting to get
experience with that and we are in the
process of that as well so just really
trying to oh right
flowing reviews super easy yeah and
really kind of how it's working with
some of the so as a retailer we were not
anticipating to have to order tags and
tagging products because tags were
supposed to be applied at the cultivator
level but not everybody has an annual
license which is when you get the tags
or provisional so the way that they're
handling that because the rules state
that anybody with a provisional or
annual has to be on metric they they're
making any part of the supply chain get
tags so how it's where I'm just
wondering how people are making it work
and and I want to talk with you about
this later if you I don't know where you
are in your
so we're just getting started with our
Account Manager training so as
Provisionals we're coming on board and
we are planning all-nighters with staff
to QR code the world in terms of for
retail stuff writing it's just to get
all of the tagging done is going to be
really challenging right we're just
preparing for the initial tagging of all
of the inventory to be the big mountain
and then hopefully once everything in
inventory is tagged then we can tag
things as we receive it and it won't be
as much of a challenge and that will
start to become integrated but I think
the first time when we get everything
into inventory and metric is gonna be
the hardest because some of our issues
are not all of our vendors have
Provisionals or annuals and therefore
are non metric and don't need to have
tags and some distributors do some of
the products that other distributors
that don't have one do and so we're very
much gauging like the number of actually
provisional or annually license vendors
that we work with and versus how many
products we're gonna have to be tagging
ourselves and that was something that
was never anticipated that kind of
defeats the whole point of track and
trace in my opinion because we're just
it's just going one more step and it's
supposed to come from the cultivator but
I think that nobody anticipated the
rollout and the sort of the imbalance of
temporary licenses to provisional
licenses and so making that work at this
stage has become a little bit more
complicated than
originally thought for sure there's
there's been some guidance about if you
are working with vendors that don't have
unique identification in metric yet what
you do mm-hmm but it remains to be seen
what that's like when we're actually
doing it yeah and so that's I'm trying
to find somebody that's been doing it
but there's so few people most people
are in this exact stage that were in so
none of us really it's kind of like when
we first started with the manifests and
the excise tax and like when that first
rolled out and we were all there all
figuring it out as we go and and not
everybody apparently saw that there was
a sample form that was on a website that
people could use so people were making
their own forms and then there were
discussions on or maybe debates between
the distributors and retailers over like
who collects what and how much and who
keeps what records and and how that
whole thing works and I feel like this
is probably gonna be very similar to
that process one thing that I stay up at
night thinking about in relation to
metric is our planned dependency on our
third-party software providers for POS
and for our seed to sale tracking at
cultivation and distribution and and how
we've received promises over the last
year or so as we've on-boarded these
different tools that they are going to
integrate and that moment when it turns
on yeah how well it really integrates
and and if that is going to add to the
complication or be a support because
obviously when you are using a
third-party software provider to
integrate with metric the hope is that
that added cost is gonna bring you
benefit operationally it's gonna be more
efficient it's gonna save you time it's
gonna give you better business
intelligence but we don't really know
right and the software tools our company
because we operate across the supply
chain we have multiple different
software providers that we're using that
are all claiming that they'll integrate
with metric right but then they all are
positive they were at the same moment
they're also all rolling out new
versions so the metric integration works
[Music]
so yeah yeah I'll be asking people of
meadowlands if they have any experience
with that yet that's that's something
I'm very curious to hear and I just saw
one of our vendors is has a on metric
and has a code and I I get sort of I
asked I was it's very very long code I
don't even know how many digits there
are but there's a barcode too and I
think there's a question of whether or
not the POS system or inventory system
can actually I'm like I hope it reads it
can read the the barcode because that's
gonna be a lot of manual input no
they're all issued by metric or if you
if you aren't on metric yet you don't
have a metric ID right but you said yeah
which implies that you've seen other ID
numbers that very much
no I'd never that was actually the first
real if I ever saw yeah our buyer just
sent me a picture of it because I was
asking and it was it's it's long and and
then I saw I was like okay there's a
barcode I just hope that her spinner can
breathe for all intensive purposes early
June 2019
you're literally seeing your first
metric
bar code whatever you want to call it
we're not on metric yet we're going
through the training process right now
but mid yeah I mean very soon but I one
of our distributors is on metric so and
I was I've been asking like did anything
change with their process and how they
were dealing with us and just kind of a
lot of information gathered you're
trying to learn
nobody really it's too new we'll get
there within 30 days after you get your
provisional vari-angle and did you just
get your dollar annual recently yeah
okay so you're in that the clock is
ticking for you yeah but there's
different phases going on in the supply
chain so all of the cultivators their
temporaries expired earlier before the
retailer's so theoretically a lot of the
cultivation licensees would have been on
metric yeah now but it's taking a while
for metric to onboard people because
while the licensees have 30 days from
when they get the invitation to do the
accountmanager training there is a bit
that is dependent on the state inviting
you to that trainings cajoling the
onboarding and the the supply chain just
not everybody's on it right and and
because of that the retailers are gonna
have to be tagging products for
distributors or supply chain members
that are not on it
well the ones that have provisional
licenses it's very complex
[Laughter]
interesting but it's definitely the next
but this is what your like your slide
digital what about I mean you were
talking about certain things where I
feel like in an ideal world a phone call
to the regulators to get clarification
on my confusion is like the different
regulatory agencies have different
interpretations of different lines in
the law right and some of you adhere to
one regulatory agency so you're going to
listen to what they say whereas you have
a reached out and the brain right yeah
but I don't I'm not seeing regulatory
agencies having different
interpretations of the law luckily I
would say that there are regulations
that might be challenging for businesses
that we have to navigate but I'm not
having the BCC tell me one thing and
CDFA tell me something that conflict
with BCC you are well I went in just
strictly looking at the regulations as
written a was worse in a previous
version of regulations they've done a
lot of really good work to clean that up
and and be more consistent across the
board so the the issues that were really
outstanding to me aren't they
those have been mitigated now at this
point so there's nothing I mean I could
still see certain conflicts when one
might be able to argue and like between
state law and some of these regulations
I think you know it depends on what
lawyer you ask on what day well okay so
in in mal curse' it says that all
cannabis and cannabis products have to
be in a child resistant tamper-evident
resealable package so cannabis the
definition of cannabis means everything
and although I so the regulator's they
say and I think rightly so are exempting
clones and seeds from
portions of that rule one might say that
it's you know kind of differs it wasn't
it all addressed or clarified in the
previous version and they were different
between because CD pH didn't address
clones or seeds because they were mostly
focused on manufactured products I think
the closest was pre-rolls with extract
Cena was the closest thing so there was
no pre-roll regulation we were having
debates with vendors about whether or
not the universal symbols applied
because they were like well you only DPH
it's only responsible for these things
and they're the ones that say universal
symbol and we don't have to have one and
then we go well no this is the law says
you do and the way I look at it is the
MAL curses like the Bible and the
regulations are like the gospel so like
when in doubt go to the law and then go
to the regulation some people work
backwards I think it depends on the
situation too like you really it's not
black and white there's there's a lot of
nuance and a lot of like the if you're
in line with the intent of what the law
is and what 64 is and and you work
towards that which is something I said
on the panel like you can prove your
intent to comply be within you know the
letter and the spirit to the best of
your ability then that's that is the
best approach in a confusing complicated
ambiguous developing industry
she's really smart