so we've created a line of
self-contained vaporizers that blend
organically-grown essential oils with
cannabis oil for the first time to
create a more holistic and complementary
medicating experience and we've done
this by selecting organically grown
essential oils that enhance the natural
properties of each cannabis variety so
for example sativa which is a energetic
and uplifting experience we have blended
with peppermint lime cypress and
cinnamon essential oils all uplifting
and energizing for indica which is a
more physically relaxing sensation we've
enhanced the relaxation properties by
blending lavender chamomile orange
essential oils we have a hybrid pen
that's blended with just a little bit of
coconut essential oil and a
non-psychoactive CBD pen that's blended
with frankincense ylang ylang tangerine
and geranium and what these essential
oils do is all kind of prepare the body
and activate it in a way to make the
experience of medicating with each of
these cannabis varieties more impactful
for the medicator
you