so let's talk some light right okay so
but people what people sorta forget is
that when the sunlight hits that plant
50 to 60 percent of the photosynthetic
energy is used not to produce the
cannabis flower not to produce the
leaves of the stem but to produce carbon
extra days to drip out into the soil so
the quality of light has everything to
do with the quality of the Exodus and
the efficiency of the plant being able
to produce those exudates
okay those exudates are what to attract
the bacteria and the fungi to feed the
plants you know blablabla teeming with
microbes if you have bad light and you
are not impacting the plant properly a
bee
some of these microbes are sensitive to
light some of these microbes are
photosynthetic some of these you know so
that light has an impact on them as well
and the other members of the soil food
web are impacted by the light in similar
ways and they in turn have impacts on
the microbes which end up so the whole
thing Cascades as a result of the Sun
hitting that plant now if you use an LED
it's missing green wavelengths because
most of them are green well the reason
why they say that is because they can't
produce it yeah so it's missing the
green flame well then you know that
means that deep down in that leaf there
are chloroplasts that aren't operating
the way they're supposed to yeah the
ones on the top are but that green stuff
is a that's a wave and it goes into the
plant and it does stuff way down deep
you know and so if you're missing that
you got a problem and that's why I like
the plasma lamp because it's it's it was
invented specifically to mimic the sun's
spectrum
sounds like a process of sitting there
for thousands of years
without Danny Hills well it's not just
yeah for everything and and and not just
the plants but us as well I mean you
know we react to somebody you know I
always I always think about people that
are out in there under the indoor grow
you know working under the LEDs and
centers in the center you know no these
are these are called a plasma light it's
just like a plasma like you know there's
a special gas amount these are really
unbelievable the little teeny light they
report one light replaces five or six of
these you know big you know gravida type
lights and what I like about this plasma
light is talk about to war let's assume
you want to go Durbin poison in Portland
Oregon you know or Anchorage Alaska well
now we can dial in the exact sunlight we
can get the exact wavelength from Durban
Africa latitude longitude dial it in on
this plasma lamp and give it that laughs
and then get the soil from Durban get
the Seas from Durban bingo
plasma lights have been around for less
and you used to have to have a you know
a one for flowering with a bit no not
not with this one this the guy who's a
Swiss guy invented I just met him this
weekend and he his goal was to match the
Sun so now when you test a solar panel
you use this light to test the solar
panel you don't have to use the Sun you
can test it in the factory there's
nothing else I know that does that
period now you know these are not cheap
lights but the efficiency is
unbelievably last two three four hundred
thousand hours and they use no wattage
as far as I know like in Massachusetts
scissor oh my god and no heat some
believe they mimic the Sun but I mean
you know what the you'd have to be
incited to get the heat the other thing
about it is it is that the form factor
can be changed so that you can you know
you can make it you can dependent the
boxes you know middle but you can make
it
for you to make it its patented its
patented is being used and it's being
tested it's on the market it's being
used for the film industry it's just as
a light it's being used growers growers
are using them
hospitals are testing them because of
the menthol it has an HOH television you
know venues because you feel good
Anderson so it's all not headlights out
and what I can't get them to do yet but
they're working on is to make a little
teeny Marvel size one for my in hosts
6x4 grow tent that's what we really
wanted i it's the only lead I know that
that I would ever use in Massachusetts
which has a wattage you know your
stretcher
[Music]