I talk about me even though even if I'm
not talking me too
you know like I was hoping for hope I
hope she's doing good and like those
things for our friends and then when we
see each other like we get we're like oh
man I was thinking about you but I
didn't tell you but like I was yeah yeah
and then when we get together too many
or never apart it's so good
I feel like hopes like this is I think I
really do care about you so much
I do think actually then I've seen you
at different stages of your life and
that's right so great is like hope is
like on her peak theme and like seeing
that like uprize
and like all just peaks and valleys cuz
like you've seen mine I'm like I'm not
hot less getting divorced you know or
whatever seeing that and being able to
love their rise because you could you
could inspire your friends to do what's
in their heart but nobody can do
anything but you like yourself and like
seeing like her being inspired and like
being inspired by her own fuel is the
shit but my dragging me down I want to
be around and with people that are
genuine - is why I love her actually you
genuine genuine and passionate I have no
doubt that she turned on the whole what
do you need what is the mom yeah I was
mom and I was like man I haven't had my
kids to take care of for two whole days
just yes
ah well what right yeah so I am seen a
talk that Jane's given I think it was a
year ago now yeah and so and it was very
extraction focused this particular talk
what grabbed me about it was it was a
lot of buildup into what makes great
extraction is good product what you put
in matters and then not just to stop not
just to say that and stop but to go into
how do we know what is good that we're
putting in
starting with seeds and clones and then
the pros and cons of those and then the
hash tag give a shit and it speaks to my
heart because I swear like a sailor
because I just well and this is just who
I am and it's how I grew up and it
doesn't always have to be the most
scientific words to drive a point home
it can be very direct and
straightforward and it's like look if
you give a shit means you're gonna pay
attention to what the plants and the
crops are saying and I'm gonna give a
shit when I'm buying those finished
products and making the products that I
love and that drives my business yeah
and then now seeing you become a grower
yeah how has your given a shit actually
changed because were you very I mean you
I know always loved the plan but has it
changed even more so being a grower now
well I think it's brought it a little
more into that commercial wavelength
that I wouldn't have thought of before
because I didn't it was so focused on
the quality of the medicine from
before that's and so I'm in Colorado and
California yes so for me to be able to
say okay I've got my little plants in my
little backyard and and I'm gonna have
this one that I grow for this friend
that suffers with this ailment and I'm
gonna do this one and then this is like
because it's freakin awesome right and
stuff like that so seeing me going from
12 plants to right now there's 1,200
plants in the ground which is a very
indicative of how our industry went from
exactly I mean very feeling that more
than hearing that and what has happened
was having to have the huge pre-planning
of where every plant will go and how
that plant goes into the ground and what
that plant has to be fed and multiply it
out instead of like well I'm gonna make
this bucket for this plant it can't work
that way with 1,200 plants and 800 foot
beds it can't do that and so it has
changed from less individual love with
each plant which gets frustrating but
more hands-on the plant which can be
good and bad I just had that
conversation before I left the built
that room that a woman went up to me and
was asking me about that so that that
can change because you have good and bad
energy else that's touching that plant
and not just yours and so not everybody
checks their intentions at the way that
that the way that I would check my
intentions of oh I'm having a bad day I
probably shouldn't
Deepti we've today or something that's
like too much touching yeah because they
feel bad you know and so I still have
that sensitivity but now it's multiply
it out so that's changed
yeah you only have so much energy to its
twenty hours a day and four people and
so in both states you're basically
growing cultivars that for extraction
purposes yes you like what they could do
whether it's yield or quality or
whatever this the commercial cultivation
in California will be for the purpose of
licensed flower but also we want to
introduce a concentrate flame that has
been close to my heart for me so it will
be for in the end for both what's in the
it'll be propane James extracts and
there will probably be a hydrocarbon
it'll be hydrocarbon extracts but in
that we're not going to seek out type
seven we'll be partnering with hash
making friends that have licenses in
California so that we can build each
other up yeah what everybody played
those drinks because you can't be good
at everything
but I can have input on that and because
I know the equipment and I know the
process and it's me so there's my pseudo
vertical there was so when Jane came to
visit me one time in Arizona it was
really great because I was taking some
she introduced a couple people that
ended up being clients of mine on a
short-term basis and we were driving out
to go see grow and I wanted them to meet
the chef because I knew that Jane would
instantly love this company the same way
I love this company and the reason why I
love this company is because this
individual has turned himself into an
analytical chemist because he cared he
used to be in the restaurant business
and now you know he's a chef and does
all the products for this company and
he's an analytical chemist because he
couldn't figure out certain things so he
would call our lab when I was at a lab I
used to be CSO for a lab in Arizona and
he would call all the time we'd be like
oh it's almost time for Francis to call
you know I mean and but we love that
because that is how you learn you you
ask questions when you're in
you're fighting with somebody something
for example he started in Arizona
there's no requirement for testing and
so because it mattered to you yeah
that's just it's gonna change now
finally but it's gonna be six months of
rules making so but yet all of this time
the best society and I love in Arizona
to support those companies that test
because they care right and so this was
and the and the consumers that care
that's what captured in my heart about
there is that people are coming in off
the street and testing their product
that they bought and in the state of
Colorado you can't do that you're not
allowed that's right that's ridiculous
yeah right so in Colorado you're not if
you buy something in the dispenser you
can double-check it yourself you cannot
and here's what's crazy to me you can
get your Molly that you buy at a
freaking feste and have that tested by
companies right there on site but you
can't test your cash as a consumer
that's bananas
that's CSS Arizona blew my mind for
Howard how open we yeah we had to and
and so we're amazing
yes so we're meeting with this company
and he would get stuck on something in
so he just would start on his own he's
say so what is your recommendation our
chemist would say tests the top of the
batch the middle of the batch and the
bottom of the batch and then you know
you're honing in on a you know an
appropriate and working SOP and he does
it all the time
still for every batch and so we get
there we're visiting the clients of
myself were talking about grow
operations and so Jaynes talking with
him about extraction and then they were
having some problems and she's like oh I
know that machine let's go take a look
at it you actually solved a massive
problem for them on site because you
know how the equipment works right I
mean it was just I sold that equipment I
still saw that equipped so they're like
oh this is all we need you're like yeah
just ordered this part talked to this
person and then handle it so when when
you work with people that value and it's
reciprocated it is not just taking
advantage of oh I know you it
we know that there we each bring value
to each other and I would rather work
with people that I can trust and then
there's a mutual respect and then I know
your product I know your work ethic and
I want to continue working with people
like that I want to continue working
with people like you and the industry
and that's give a shit
Eamon we're a lovefest
the peanut gallery
what's an extraction innovation like
either technologically or new
methodologies that you're kind of is
either imminently coming or it just came
and it's exciting you
I'm thinking of Murphy right now color
remediation
well chromatography so Jets and it's and
it's and it's pretty it's it's simple if
you do it the right way and it can be in
line with your attraction so people that
are because it does aid in pesticide
remediation so that's a big thing that's
hot right now of like you know how when
consistencies of hashed change and
Shatter was all that mattered and then
you know if it if it doesn't shatter it
doesn't matter and then it moves over to
sauce and sugar and diamonds and all of
the and right now you know diamonds are
still big in the market and I would say
CRC Tech is as far as something that
people are really getting into right now
and it's just media filtration and you
can do it a few different ways and and
people already do that with distillate
and everything and it's just a same
concept of being able to make your
extracts a nicer color and to be able to
clarify some of if there are pesticides
certain things like that that would pull
or attach to so
or clay and being able to make your hash
better have you seen any in your talk
you talked about the right time for
harvesting for based off of your
trichome coloration so clear milky amber
and I am was wondering are there any
technologies that actually can from an
image do a based off of pixelation and
the colors of pixels are there apps out
there that can actually measure that so
you can say take a picture of let's say
go out take it be a computer vision like
recognition and then it will say okay
there's a certain ratio of red and then
it can do a gradation of you know from
how milky and you could kind of set it
well just shit just and yeah so it'll
just give you an X percent clear X
percent Amber experts and milk what
percentages and stuff like a seven CBG
if you want if you're trying to do
something for extract that maybe you
want to have more of a docile effect to
it or yeah I mean just to be able to
take an image let's say just from a
single Cola right and you just have you
take a picture so it's then going to
actually identify and if you can do a
micro image so then you microwatt no
skin but like it's a colas it's a Cola
skin that's trademarked colas can but
yeah so if you do a micro Cola Cola skin
and so then it'll say okay you know the
amount of Reds the Mount of Browns the
amount of yellows right because you're
gonna amount of white also harvest coal
isn't
that's from a commercial scale that
would be huge but you could actually
from a craft perspective you know from a
smaller and then you're like really
picking and then say if I really want to
do specifically for extraction and I
want that creamy color then I want to
stop once I start to see this percentage
of Reds start to appear and then you
could just do that with an image I was
just curious if you were coming home so
that's something we're gonna talk about
that next year microscope right we'll
talk about that next year that's what
you're talking beyond next the colas
cancer hope Jones rule over that gosh
I'm so proud
remember when you started talking about
Driscoll's
yeah and my talk and you talk about that
and then like the relevance to cannabis
culture propagation tissue culture so
something I didn't talk about in my
presentation and I'll just introduce
here's I am starting a new company a
Davina and what a Davina is doing is we
are going to be selling clones and I'm
in Arizona and worked really hard to get
him passed which finally passed
anyways so but we're going to be selling
young young plants and and also unrooted
cuttings and all of those mother's stock
will be coming from tissue culture and
it is very similar to a Driscoll's model
where most are all strawberries are
highly susceptible to disease and
viruses and so every six months or every
year they'll go back to their germ plasm
their their their cryo gene bank and
then they will start new plants and then
they will grow up and then they can take
cuts and they treat each of those plants
as moms in the same way we do and then
that's a really good efficient
commercial model but the and the reason
why that matters for driscoll's in a
absolutely should matter for us is that
they're clean they're clean of diseases
they're clean of pathogens they're clean
of viruses and so by starting with fresh
mother's stock all the time and pushing
the grow and the right way we can
actually harvest a large number of
clones per plant in a very small
footprint and then to sell them actually
as unrooted cuts is an advantage for a
lot of people because with him we can no
longer be bound by the state boundary
lines we can ship everywhere and then
you can stick and a lot of routes and
your climate and your environment what
horrifies me is when i here in arizona
they just started him production they
everybody was getting their licenses in
June and July and they immediately
rushed out to plant and it was
horrifying if they were working with
clones they were wrong they were way
past their peak they should have been
you know topped and and allowed to wait
but everyone's so excited to get in the
ground but then nothing lives what's the
point and so and then it will also be
advised it's not just a transaction it's
I give a shit and my 18 we give a shit
so then it will be assisted by us along
the journey to ensure success what's the
point of selling a bunch of clones if I
will never ever ever have you back
what's the point
and so by assisting in that process and
then if it's just a stupid idea if you
want to plant in Phoenix Arizona
outdoors in July I'm just not going to
sell to you right I mean there's just no
reason yeah I can't let you have like
offseason you have like an offseason you
know like you know we're closed for
winter months or whatever you're closed
for summer months to the public it is
doing your smart
and people call today's outdoors in
Arizona yes and tell me about like the
different like here you know it's like
emeralds right you know tumbled down
here to pink like what what's the where
the look is like you wouldn't do it in
Phoenix like where it's desert humid so
absolutely you can you just have to do
it right and it's not going to be a
year-round for outdoor unless you have
some sort of technology like so I'll use
what I did previously as an example when
I started growing in Arizona it this
particular company had an indoor grow in
the Phoenix area and then kind of about
two hours away from Phoenix
there was a greenhouse and then when we
were hired they said we want to start
growing outdoors and we're like awesome
that's a great idea the Sun is free this
is a beautiful growing environment
year-round if it's done right and it
depends on the crops there it just
depends and they said well we want to
start growing outside in July and all of
our clones have already been taken and
they're a transplant and they're ready
to go from the greenhouse outdoors and
we're like yeah I would not recommend
doing that what we did instead was we
invested in a retractable roof structure
it's manufactured by crave oh but that
has the sides that are screened if
you've been into any plant nursery a lot
of times they'll use those for the
bedding plants area where you shop
around but it also has a retractable
roof and what's great about that
technology is you can actually go ahead
and screen your plants you have
beautiful percentages of shade screening
and so you can actually close that up
during the hottest time of the day but
you can also close it up during the
winter months to trap the heat in and
after that instead of letting it out
because we're a desert but we also get
we're a high desert we get below
freezing on a regular basis so you
couldn't grow year-round in Arizona
necessarily unless you were able to trap
the heat in some way and I will say
there was a haboob that that came
through
you know what a haboob is those dust
storms that you see somebody comes
running out and I'm working out in the
grow and someone's like haboob haboob
and also awfully haboob holy shit and we
were working on the roof of the
structure the craven structure the motor
was down for whatever reason what's not
the company's fault it was my dumbass
company's fault for not paying to have
it install properly
anyways so yes I had there are two guys
they threw up the tallest ladder as you
could see and they're pulling 70,000
square foot of roofing as fast as they
could and I'm recording this whole thing
and I was like ah fuck it looks like
hell here it comes it's that wall of
like dark brown orange cuz it's just
coming for us right and I was like fuck
and then over here it's blue death and
destruction gorgeous holy shit we gotta
close just in time and it was like a
windy day inside our entire crop would
have been destroyed we would have lost
everything and this wasn't him
don't love her yeah it's also one of the
important things that I services that
I'll be offering I've spent the last
couple of years working on SOPs so
you're not gonna find me on Instagram
and Facebook I just don't do that
because yeah yeah yeah yeah I mean it
ends you know what I just want to make
sure that when we get going it's as
optimized as I can get it at least for
right now based off of the technology in
hand but it's the fires if you're in the
California areas to be able to preserve
your genetics with cryopreservation
whether it's seed banking tissue banking
if you're in Florida or Texas with the
you know natural disasters that are
happening to be able in that nursery
everything we had was basically toxins
raining all over them from houses and
commercial buildings burning down stuff
when we don't have insurance you know
within companies now hopefully like the
insurance will be real who knows like
we're still figuring that out for crop
insurance but there's nothing to protect
anybody in the event of these losses and
you lose everything in yeah we we had
multiple insurance policies but it's a
and proving that you did things their
way that that would have you know they
have like a crop loss for pests or
something they have to prove that you
fed your plants a certain way and did
all of their outline of things would be
able to show it we need redundancy and
and and certain securities and I think
that will also go towards being able to
pull something out if there's a you
mentioned you know nobody's doing blue
dream right now but maybe they will
later right well let's get going back
it's coming back everything's gonna come
back who knows so if we're not
interested let's not lose it let's
preserve it and then we can pull it out
when we're ready and then we've
preserved it when it was already
certified clean of what we could at
least test from a panel of pathogens and
viruses at the time we can pull it out
and be like it's the flavor of the month
disco came back again everything comes
back I'm old enough to see that should
happen I've seen all the fashions even
going this time shoulder pads entire I
thought my boobs are too big it just
doesn't work you know you just don't
need to emphasize works for her
we're actually like the questions that
were being asked at the end can you talk
about some of the cut like without any
interesting questions they were
interesting questions oh one of the
questions that was really interesting
how long will it take to rescue a
particular strain do I really think it
will take you know upwards of a year to
do a true rescue think of it it has an
identified disease yeah and so I thought
that was a really good question and it
also allowed me to share there's a lot
of Rd still to do you know nobody no lab
no consultant right now is going to have
all of the answers we're going to have
what are the best practices and other
industries that we should absolutely
start with we don't we're not
reinventing the wheel gonna ask do you
study other plants - are you like
cannabis is my jam
certainly cannabis is my thing but from
a I used to study a lot of other plants
so I actually used to work with
strawberries and orchids and then I'm
also very interested in other medicinal
crops of value not just for the cannabis
industry but I'm certainly interested in
pursuing mushroom actually cultivation
kava you know some of the other products
that so yeah basically if there's no
protocol and there might be some sort of
value I'm interested in it because I'm
interested in like cheating my cell
phone for two years to figure out how to
do it and then maybe you know somehow
offer that information that's what I got
smart is barter and science together
like smarter - that a - I want to know
but yeah they asked why you know and
they really also wanted to know why do I
think it's going to take so long and so
what a year to clean something up let's
say
what is your favorite strain right now
what's yours right now oh boy let's see
well always Rosetta right let's just say
but let's use Rosetta then right it's
your mom
something's punky something's going on
I'm gonna come out and then I'm gonna
take some cuts or maybe you bring your
mom to me and then I immediately start
doing crop maintenance I'm flushing it
out I'm collecting the drainage taking
it into the lab anything that I have
defoliated I collect and I immediately
take the lamb I put that Rosetta plant
in quarantine right everything should be
quarantined when you bring anything new
into your facility quarantine everything
quarantine everything yeah yeah I even
see popping yeah
so it goes into quarantine until I get a
clean test report if I can't get a clean
test report and I at least understand
what I'm dealing with
then I will take clean cuts propagates
actually and put it into a separate
quarantine and I get rid of that
original mother right away because I
don't want the substrate mess whether it
be soil and all of the bugs that that
brings in and I just want to start
actually taking the fresh new cuts
because for me and tissue culture I want
as many nodes as I can get but a lot of
times with good propagation techniques
we can outgrow a lot of things that
might be you know just like a little bit
bad and as long as we are treating it
with preventative biologicals whether it
be biological pesticides or nematodes or
whatever the problem may be but we don't
know what to do until we have a diagnose
you know a test diagnostic to say this
is what you're dealing with so start
with a whole new set of cuts and then I
immediately get it into culture and if I
again don't know what I'm dealing with
and I just end up with contaminated
culturing so then I want to I can't do
nodal culturing I'm gonna do
meristematic culturing meristematic
culturing takes a little bit of time
underneath the scope and then you are
just taking a very very small
very small cut and you're placing it on
media that's going to take a period of
time let's say everything just to route
use a round number everything let's say
takes four weeks just as a general rule
of one month so just one month to get
that meristem to all of a sudden be like
I'm living and now I something that
looks like it could be a shoot and it's
very small then I'm gonna transfer that
into another media recipe and put it on
the shelf for another month and now I'm
starting to get growth and development
if I don't get contamination but I have
to grow that enough and get enough
product that I can sacrifice so let's
say I have a hundred vessels of this now
and it's taken me a couple months to get
to this it's probably several months to
do that because it's cereal every time
it yeah so four weeks to get to
multiplication and then let's say it
started at one and now I have two that I
can dissect to two shoots that I dissect
that let those go another four weeks and
now each one of those have two and I
dissect those out so that's four weeks
four weeks so that's now three months
but we're growing the number of material
the amount of material that we have and
so before I actually have enough
material to send out to the laboratory
for analysis we're looking at about six
months if the meristem was viable when I
actually harvested if things work along
the way and so I think we as labs should
not over promise we should not say I
absolutely can rescue everything is
salvageable that's not true all the time
and again it depends on if I can work
with you as a grower is this your only
plan that can I keep coming out to take
fresh new cuts can i if I'm failing in
the laboratory can I come out and start
again because again
relationships yeah and we need that time
in the laboratories to actually work
those methods out if I'm good underneath
the microscope it's gonna take a while
to train my staff to get good at a
microscope and be able to translate that
knowledge and so everybody is new and
everybody's building and I just think
that US labs need to be transparent
about where we're at and what our
challenges are and driscoll's I remember
asking one time what is your viability
percentage for meristem and they said
50% and they smiled they're like and I
was like fifty percent fully shit and
they're like you just need one you just
need one to take and be successful and
it's like well I understand and it
helped me put in perspective because I
felt like I was failing all the time if
I wasn't at 100% viability in my
meristematic culturing because it's hard
you have to pull every single little
primordial leaf off and then just get to
that little embarrassed of those little
cells and then somehow pop that out and
not lose it in the microscope right and
then plate that and that takes practice
and time and then even with with the
best of them it doesn't work all the
time and so it takes time and it's
expensive not what we're doing in the
lab as much as it is working with the
third-party laboratories to do the virus
and pathogen indexing it's expensive
part of our conversation and salia by
Tony
remember but you're basically adding a
nursery operation to what you're
currently doing tissue culture but the
logical next step is to have clones
ready to go so that's the company you're
launching yeah okay and then will that
be a balance between kind of the host
cultivars that you guys are doing mad
science on and breeding and then say the
clients we can also score your genetics
that you
and get them flown ready and climate
acclimated for you yeah all of all of
that and one of my partners actually is
a as an attorney in Arizona and his
specialty is intellectual property and
so if you were a breeder and you want it
and we do want to sell your genetics and
so our attorney part of the service is
to work with you maybe you just want
trademark maybe you want licensing or
maybe you just want to sell us your your
your stream but all of that should be
upfront and delivered to you as the
breeder to have the option of what you
want to do and even if it's a royalty
for example something that I think we
haven't heard enough in our industry is
how do we reward the breeders and how do
we pay yeah and so in the horticulture
industry when you breed something if
it's the hot new petunia and it's got
this orange that is a new hot shit in
the market for the spring that is a
licensed strain and then every plant
sold a royalty goes back to the breeder
or to the company that bred it these
breeders have been working for a long
time on their genetics and I I fuckin
want to pay them for that and I think
there's nothing wrong with having a
business model to do that as long as
we're transparent and we say we do have
these services if you just want and need
some tissue culture or preserve your
stock then that's all that's gonna
happen with it right if you want to work
and actually sell your strain and it up
and it's a strain that we can offer in
our library and then we can help you and
work with you on that on that licensing
or trademarking and make sure that
either how do you want to be paid do you
want to just be paid you know a lump sum
or are you good with a royalty and then
if it's 10 million
unit so comments like where I want to
give it away but I don't want someone
else to drive it that's right so it's so
important to me and and and the people
that I'm working with and so to make
sure that anybody can make money doing
what there have been building and and
working towards their whole careers just
be transparent and then let's all have a
good business and enjoy what we're doing
right and so it's been a long road and
when I say long road you get this
there's been a lot of characters that
have come across and said hey do you
want ten million dollars do you want
this and you want that or hey why don't
you come work for me and I'm gonna
promise you the world no I'm not I have
not because it's not been the right
alignment it's not been the right not
everybody on the team gave a shit yeah
you know and so everybody on the team
needs to give a shit we're here because
we enjoy what we do we're not here to
rate the industry of all their knowledge
and and so I think yeah intentions
that's my that's my discerning factor as
I age not as gracefully as hope but as I
age into my future I do it loud and
messy okay but I'm like oh that just
sermon of does that person is that
person helping me be the best version of
myself and that includes my work because
my work is
yeah it is what we do what what are some
of the so imposed a walk here in
California to so California Colorado
Arizona give a shout out to some either
breeders or cultivators that you guys
like I love coming to the show and as
soon as I come into this show there are
two people that I immediately contact
Jane I'm coming to the show you can be
the show you contacted me i Adam Adam
Shox yep out of Oregon and he does a lot
for the children and the whole universe
and he's amazing and he knows how to
bring it he understands how to get to a
stable P one he understands the number
and the time it takes he's a breeder and
he understands you're not going to just
do one cross and say there you go and
sell a bunch of unstable seed lines
a good breeder oh you had a very other
slide about it so in my mind a breeder
knows that you need to start with two
parents that have been back cross and
are a stable p1 meaning all of the you
self to itself until you get rid of and
you try to get to either all big a big a
or all Lille's Lille's right if you
think of your punnett square when you
have a one parent you get a set of
chromosomes from each and so you could
when you do that you have the
probability of getting big a big a big a
little a big a little a and Lily Lily
what you want to do is you want a back
cross until you really have a very pure
line for both your p1 and your p2 and
then you cross and then you have to do
back crosses again before you have a
stable ff1 hybrid if a breeder actually
talks like that you've got my attention
and that's just to breed but what
happens after the breeding also and that
you covered that in your talk today yeah
just the female but I have data is a big
one for me and I know that is for you
also just your reputation I think that
who you are as a person goes into your
work the same as it does for all of us
and the outcome that that person
produces coupled with data because a
person that is passionate about what
they're doing they want to do a really
good job right so don't put in the work
so when you were when you were sourcing
the genetics for your
Colorado rose to resourcing in front so
that's it that's what I was going to say
who some of my favorite breeders were
Dominion seed company and nerds genetics
are a bulk of our garden Dominion seed
companies what I love is that he has
some really fun mom's like I hope it
doesn't care if I say but like some
stupid guy yes we're sure yeah that's
actually that's my love Nathan and
that's that's my partner in the project
on his property in Trinity in California
but we love Duke and we love Dominion
seed company he's he's he's he's done a
lot of the work and he's a perfectionist
which most most breeders I know are that
they won't put their name on something
but they haven't really put so much work
into but he has really cool fun genetics
like a hash plant from Lebanon from 1977
you know like really crazy medicine
medicine that has fun stories behind it
but that also just produces these really
intense unique profiles like a you know
an original skunk the original skunk you
know things like that and so he adds a
lot of loud to the garden same with
nerds genetics they are all very
brilliant people the guy that I'm really
close friends with Robbie went to
Colorado College by me which is a really
well-known college for it you can't be
stupid and go to that college they won't
let you it and I see stupid coming and
the name like nerds genetics because
they do so much research behind their
stuff I had processed some product for
him
in Colorado and what was amazing was he
gave me back every little number on my
job and he said well just so you know
you beat this extractor this extractor
this extractor in this extractor by this
percentage in your return and you did
this this and this and this profile was
high and I was like wait you were giving
that stuff to other people too and he
was like oh yeah you know and we're
talking about it and he was like wow you
just gave me almost double the return on
this and and then I'm like oh shit I
probably describe those extractors in
trouble
but being able to see somebody that
they're they're breeding for the purpose
of producing concentrates and their
seeds are for the purpose of producing
concentrates they're like breeders for
hash certain types of chirp chirping
profiles that will come out come in we
were talking about limonene or whatever
it is for flowering but how it comes
through and concentrates you know there
are certain things right now I would
love like an herbal herb line I want
that old sage that Adam Dunn had I want
those kind of fun lavender you know and
there's a beautiful opportunity for
these breeders to to target there's such
a huge need whether it be for full
terpene profiles whether it be for
architecture and hemp for mechanical
harvesting right you want a certain
plant architecture that goes in the
ground that can be harvested there's a
lot of opportunity to actually are we
wanting particular strains that are
focused purely for processing do we want
strains more focused on flower and
different profiles from that regard like
there are huge opportunities as breeders
to target those markets everybody's in a
goddamn rush and it's now
I mean a really a good turnaround tree
turnaround time for breeding new strains
that are stable true to type we're
looking at three to eight years
depending and that takes time and so I
think there's been a lot of good
breeders out there that have gotten
started and are going and I can't wait
to see some of their new strains coming
out here in the next few years that's
what I love yeah cuz that now people
like Adam it could be any many
cannabinoid except for and so now people
are making head again you know they're
like oh well look this this fits
everybody on the street right because
there's CBD so it's not so scary and
then we've got this extensive flavor
profile just the same as cannabis but
that fits into holistic health care and
even though I've totally believed THC is
holistic health care also it just I tell
my style it ends a lifestyle and and I I
see now how I love that they've taken
that and just on to hey let's do this to
be able to expand the places that this
medicine can go in a safe space that
everybody can understand and then we'll
move on to that reintroducing that THC
heavy
and I'm really excited to work with
breeders in the lab that so there's a
way to actually breed and vitro for
example with we can use pollen but also
protoplast fusions where you actually
digest the cell wall and you can
actually go or be it and have cells
plant cells that are you know haploids
basically and you can actually merge
them together and make a diploid and why
not play with that you know and again
this is normal things that are done in
other industries that I'm excited to see
and play other crops absolutely and so
I'm excited to know those whatever
why not why not and work with I don't
come from you know his you know a long
pedigree of black market you know being
part of the original cast of characters
that have come out and and created this
industry I am I'm a noob and I hate you
and I want to work with those characters
who understand the characteristics and
and the passion and oh you don't want
that that's just this that's junk like
people who are truly knowledgeable at
such an in-depth level historically who
understand the plants so well those are
the people that I am excited to work
with and a lot of those people are craft
we're talking larger stuff here but that
also craft
yeah yeah I'm able to able to yeah the
scalability of on the entertaining
quality everything and that's why I love
having an R&amp;D lab is because the lab is
not focused on commercial production R&amp;D
labs shouldn't have that focus the R&amp;D
labs and I will always have R&amp;D lab
whatever happens with the
bread-and-butter of cloning but the Rd
lab is where we get to play you know how
like within a couple years people got
like the CBD from three percent of to
20-plus percent with with minor
cannabinoids and you see any movement on
getting like the obscure cannabinoid
counts like from 0.01 percent one
percent or two percent it's a matter of
time nobody's focused on it and so it's
just a matter of time and do I see any
of that I'm no longer one breeding in
that direction to explore this minor can
happen they are yes
yes they are they are no longer being a
part of analytical laboratory I don't
get to see just kind of the blind stuff
that randomly comes in and be like holy
shit you know that is a crazy high on
THC you know t8 cv or something along
those lines so I don't get to see that
anymore but I have been talking with and
have clients all over the US and Canada
and Colombia and they all are on the
hunt for that or have that to a certain
extent and so now everybody's excited
focused on trying to create strains that
have a different profile than just THC
s-- and we now also get to have fun with
some of these real clinical studies and
have an idea of more than just anecdotal
evidence of what they're doing I want to
know for myself of THC V is gonna help
with wheat like I'm your first sign up
for that right you don't like where's
that study I want to be a part of that
study but I mean but it's hard to get a
hold of those products necessary unless
she knows somebody and it just takes
time to get it into the marketplace and
make it more
available outside of the small little
circles in the niches and that that's
going to happen it's happening that on
the extraction side you can need a ton
of biomass to get enough of the super
obscure
like a concentrator and then that puts
you in different extraction methods
because hydrocarbon then if if if it
pulls a higher percentage with less work
higher hydrocarbon is great but if you
have thousands and thousands of pounds
that you have to run then ethanol
becomes you know a better thing
something I'm really interested also
from an R&amp;D lab are certain cultivation
practices and and and feed regimes
influencing the you know the the
chemical profile could we as growers
actually adopt oh if I'm more interested
in bringing out and enhancing this
plants potential on a secondary or what
we think of secondary cannabinoid or you
know focus on how to grow towards a
desired terpene profile a lot of that I
believe we can will find that there are
certain cultivation strategies and
certain nutrient feed regimes that we
can do to skirt that and accomplish that
without breeding even and so one example
would be with Tomatoes this is some
earlier research I did when I was an
undergraduate and the the PhD student I
was working for was working on
increasing the sugar content of tomatoes
by increasing the salt concentration of
the nutrient solution and what that did
was actually creates a more concentrated
flavor of more concentrated sugars in
the tomato and you can measure that by
Brix by taking the tomato off and then
crumbling it and just juicing it onto
the Brix reader and that gives you a
Brix content and that's how we can
measure sugars and there are ways that I
think as cultivators that we can
actually manipulate and drive and steer
plants the plants chemical profile we
just need the ability to
people meet and then to do the Rd that
says you know what this is really
working let's tweak it just a little bit
but we then also need to count on the
data that we get from the analytical
laboratories so we need to do tissue
analysis of the plans through its growth
and development and of the yield not
just the flower but growth and
development because we're going to see
certain parameters that we can measure
throughout the growth and development of
the plant so we don't have to always
wait for flower to tell us how to steer
what to do and so there's just a real
need for that our de would be a easy way
to actually oh I had no idea this plant
had this potential yeah
what could you you clever girl you
clever clever girl let's do that yeah
just matter of time of money right and
space