I think of it as like nutrients and
microbes and stuff like that like Scott
I think of you as someone who like eats
books and does research and then you
poop out digestible intelligent coherent
thought bites for the community yes
that's actually been my role the entire
time people I think the and shockingly a
lot of people don't want to eat your poo
but I've been eating that since day one
there's no let's just clarify there's no
faeces involved but no that's totally
what happened like you know I come from
Southern California from a pretty
diverse neighborhood and you know some
of the homies from high school went
really hard on the indoor og cultivation
and so I used to come along and check it
out and it would be me and like a bunch
of homies and I'd be like well why is
that happy and someone be like the
plants need the proteins a and I'd be
like the plants need the proteins like
the plants need the proteins a I'm like
why are we doing this plants need the
brokens
and I'm like none of you motherfuckers
know any reason why we're doing stuff
and so I know no disrespect but like
they were doing a great job but like
nobody knew why and my compulsion and
obsession was the why like I have to
know why I'm doing something if I'm
gonna tinker with it or else it's not
worth my effort and so I would just
think works yeah that's the work so I
just would you know try to figure out
why something was happening or what was
the new like what did the nutrient even
do what does Nitra didn't even do what
is potassium even do and how do we solve
these problems and that just carrying on
that same energy brought me here I guess
trying to figure out and I jest
complicated I loved learning about the
minerals and the spray the minerals from
you and Sam from soil scape like that
whole mineral attitude or doing that
spraying is often like you were doing
down at that nursery like I mean if more
people would do that and like even the
big facilities I'd like to somehow like
slide that in
you know you know yeah yeah no man he
check it out too and I needed it for my
Hill because I have such an aggressive
wind that I theorized that I wasn't
getting calcium transport adequately
through the roots because the
environment was so aggressive and I was
just like you know what I said I think I
really have to run a foliar program to
offset my environmental issues and I
talked to Sammy's I can I got this
killer program I want you to run it
and so Irena last year and I mean the
the plants have never looked so good I
had so few issues it just kept them on
point you know and it is it's a it's a
gift to be able to be around people who
are working on all the fringes that's
why I always love hanging out with you
because I'm like you you've been
touching the hook the hoops since before
people knew what hoops were well sit so
can we stand this as kind of a coherent
topic which is spraying minerals final
escape program is a soil skate bot of
Arcada
and it's just really a good
comprehensive mineral nutrient spray
program and what I went into it for is
that you know my situation is I have
such a rough environment up the hill
that the finished product is excellent
but I never get the growth out of the
plants that I wanted because they're
working so hard to work in that
environment and so I theorized that I
needed to go into leaf foliar
development so that I could get around
having to have the plant go through the
metabolic process from the root zone up
and one day Sam gives me a call says hey
we have this beautiful program coming
out I'd love to talk to you so I went
down the shop I took a look at an
operation that he had been using it on
and the quality of that it was it on an
indoor that he was shooting and he was
stunning and so I said look let me let
me run it on my Hill so I picked the
program up and I had the best run last
year and like I said when I ran those
varieties on that white label there was
at least 25 farms that ran the same
exact plants that I ran and I had
overall any
California using those varieties I had
the highest Terp levels and highest
cannabinoid levels and I had zero
problems with the plants growing and I
used beneficial insects in terms of
inoculation so that I had releases
throughout the season so that if I had
any problems come in I would have a bank
of beneficials to do the job for me
because I didn't I don't like to use any
kind of spray especially in tough
environments sprays are tough on leaf
surface and if the Leafs are going
through the beat and they take up on the
hill the plant stresses out because of
it and that foliar program gave me
incredible growth the end product came
out beautifully it came out so good that
I picked up enough to do the 18,000
square foot this year so I'm gonna run
in the second season because I had such
success with that foliar program I
believe in it because Scott turned me on
to it and I got some clones that had a
little spider mites or whatever issue
and the first you know like we were
talking about earlier we're really
spraying for war all the time but if
more people were spraying for health
they would actually see a better result
in the plant health and secondly the
bugs don't like getting sprayed with
just plain water anyway if you do it
every day and there was a certain point
where I was trying to mimic what Scott
was doing it at nursery where in the
evening time I was spraying like five
six nights a week with a different
mineral throughout those whole programs
you know I hadn't done any soil analysis
or water tests I just said fucking I'm
gonna spray minerals and have fun with
it and one of them was just one of the
things he had me spraying was cocoa and
aloe and so I mean the plants just loved
it and the bugs hated it and they went
away so I never sprayed any type of you
know pesticide I just sprayed through
the whole time and the plants got better
the bugs didn't like it was just this
win-win situation and I feel like that
can be done more at scale it's just hard
to implement and get people to jump on
to that you know swallow that pill
because we're so forced into the IPM
program of actually the warpath and you
know the health has to be part you know
has to be there too obviously but
you know I think we could make a big
turn in some of these you know bigger
facilities if we could incorporate some
more health sprays Oh
guaranteed I fully agree you have to be
proactive and for me it was ever he was
three times a week so Monday Wednesday
and Friday and I would either get in at
4 o'clock in the morning or I could
shoot the evening too so it had time to
penetrate in and it it made such a
difference that the people who've been
up the hill prior and saw the plants
using that treatment couldn't believe it
because we've always historically had
transplant issues in terms of just
slower growth and I know that I'll never
get giant plants up there because I have
such a wind load all the time that when
I run my test crops down low say it 550
feet at my spot or I run it up at my
farm at you know 23 under feet I get you
know two to three times bigger plant
down below same mix same media same
operator same cultivar only difference
environment so I know that that
particular place has an impact on the
plant but when we utilized that foliar
nutrition program to to just assist with
the plants uptake so it didn't have to
work so hard to pull it through the
vascular system from blow up the plants
just exploded and and my friends that
came up and saw it they were just like
what did you do and I mean it was so
dramatic and then the quality the flower
was phenomenal and when I got that when
I got hit up by the company and I said
hey they said you just clean house on
you Terps in you Canada near the
cannabinoids and I said well nice so not
only was the plant healthy but because
of his healthier it was able to actually
go through its chemical process and
generate what we want which is those
desirable chemicals yeah for sure I mean
that's what we want so just quickly
Kevin you mentioned frequency which is
three times a week Scott can you talk
about kind of what minerals are in the
mixes that you're recommending and then
do those does do that
do you change it based on different
stages of plant growth like you'd have
different mixes during the early stages
veg and so on yeah so I guess the
further clarify the kit that they're
talking about is yeah it's defined as
the file escape that's the name of the
product and there's like 11 or 12
bottles in the kit some powders some
liquids it's made by soil scape
solutions out in Arcada which I'm you
know one of the things that I say is
like this kit that Sam came out with I
will say we'll look back in history and
say this was one of the more dramatic
impacts on the organic sector he assures
me that everything in there except for
one product is all organic and it's used
with amino acids it does look like
chemicals you know some of the stuff's
blue because coppers blue and so it does
look like chemical nutrients but I trust
a trust Sam that all of them except just
the nitrogen phosphate product are
organic but it gives you the flexibility
of hydroponics which is what I like and
so a standard kit has two recipes that
you do three times a week and alternate
it that has worked everywhere we've used
it I use the kit in a little bit
different way I personally use it as a
toolkit for hitting ideal math numbers
and that does change slightly by the
farm I also don't use every product in
the kit because we have some other
products that I use in substitution but
in essence what Sam's kit allows me to
do is you can formulate a full-year
nutrient that has ideal values of almost
every main nutrient and I have not seen
anything else that compares to that case
at all there's nothing on the planet
that I think gives you those
capabilities and so I mean everywhere we
use them with the hydroponic farms we
using at the leading soil farms I think
every single commercial farm I work with
at least gets a sample kit
and so which is a funny deal I think it
shows how much I believe in that product
is that by definition Sam
is an exact competitor me we both make
soil we both do consulting with both the
mineral analysis and we both do
biological analysis and I enjoy that kit
so much that I send my competitors to
his office to order products like you
know and that's I think that's more I
think that speaks to Sam as well you
know I don't feel threatened by him and
I trust him and I respect him so so far
nothing's good from turning our clients
into him as well so which i think is
rare in the industry good products that
support this industry and what we do
energy yeah exactly that kids extremely
powerful
so I guess to more clearly define you
know I'm more go for a full fertility
approach every chance I get because I'm
trying to be simple and scalable most
farms that hire us have an ultimate goal
of allowing to cross state lines whether
that means they invest further in their
own business and go across the states or
they find outside investment they create
set whatever that means to them most
farms that we work with are ultimately
looking to expand and take advantage of
the open market they're the open borders
when that comes in the United States and
in order to do that you need to have
scalable techniques and so far most
farms that we've worked with there's you
know one two or three key components
that makes that system work and you
can't scale yourself you need to scale
processes that are repeatable and easy
and predictable and so you know we take
an extremely simplified approach to
cultivation and try to just provide full
fertility at each step that we can while
monitoring biological activity in the
soil and when we do that then your
cultivation experience is actually
scalable and so what it's what it starts
to do is it simplifies the process so
that any employee can execute it and it
and we choose process that have really
low volatility and really low chances of
going haywire so that it keeps it within
the comfort of Health
and then you know the way that you can
then scale that to multiple properties
is that the initial analysis is being
moved to a data point if we take all the
data points of a farm I can sit down and
aggregate all the information of
multiple facilities and identify where
the problems will be that's the biggest
obstacle to scale right now is if your
strategy for cultivation is spraying
everything three times a week and you
keep adding more square footage how many
you know at what point does that become
the breaking point and so Sara and I
have learned to take key data points of
soil nutrition you know the nutrition of
the feeds and foliar and then the
populations of the organisms in the soil
and by taking a look at those data sets
you can make very clear correlations as
to where the problems will be and you
can focus those efforts and then you can
either determine is the reason for the
distant dysfunction of cultural practice
like our employees doing something
that's leading to problems or is there
an imbalance problem that we need to
correct and still that allows you to
then maintain those one two or three key
key employees that make the facility run
but they can then scale their focus and
I based on what I've seen from you know
very intensely watching cannabis
operations because even from the first
day I went into a cannabis growing
facility I was watching it in extreme
interest of how to make it successful
and so I've kind of watched these
obstacles of scale and even in those
early black market days of buddies
trying to scale the same problems that
my buddies ran into going from a couple
houses to a 20,000 square-foot building
are the same obstacles that every
cultivator everywhere is running into
and you there just becomes a certain
point where you can't do everything the
way that you've always done it and
that's tripping up anybody that's going
up in any scale whether that's from four
to twelve lights or from four facilities
- 26 facilities you know Sarah and I
have you know provided advice and
consulting to
arms with as many as I think the largest
group was 26 different properties and we
have we have to provide solutions that
can be emailed to 26 properties and come
up with something that will work and
those same strategies apply to a tenth
grower it's the same systemic imbalances
that lead to headaches you know that's
just moving the ball to prevention you
know and getting to the cause of things
when we talk about these IPM strategies
versus you know always chasing your tail
and spraying spring to kill we always
say sprayed a hill not to kill if you
can have if you can help it at all yeah
which is what Eric was talking about
like and that's what Eric's really
champion that phrase and that's the
thing it's like everybody's mindset is
what do I do to kill these aphids and
you know from our standpoint now that
accountants are involved counting
everything about our process and
everything that the cultivator does the
determine if it's financially viable
well one of those things is sending
employees to spray something and so
those employees can either spray a
pesticide or like in Kevin's experience
he sprayed a foliar nutrient that led to
more terpenes more potency more
saleability higher velocity in the
market all those things like you know I
hated the bugs don't like they don't
water even exactly yeah it's like what
how do you how do you tornadoes affect
reproduction reproduction rates of
humans how do you hurricanes affect
reproduction rates of humans like we can
see it in our own life like you know
babies slow down a little bit when
there's a major catastrophe and a wave
coming over the shore and it's like I
can only imagine that the same thing is
happening to a bug like if you go in
there three four times a week and spray
anything you're at least pissing them
off and killing a couple eggs you know
like you might as well spray something
that can increase yield spray something
that can increase health spray something
that can increase quality markers that
will ease your product selling on the
market you know
Oregon and Washington all these markets
that are completely destroyed by
percentage points is really unfortunate
but it's really shown us a lot about our
process and what leads to higher numbers
because of that it's the focus that's
what we're being put to work on like how
do we increase potency numbers well you
definitely have to decrease a fat
problem x' that's the first step you
know and then provide supplement that
increases those numbers invested in you
know the bugs are doing their job you
know the insects and diseases are there
to break down that plant material that's
not thriving that's the purpose and
that's why those things occur in the
first place as we all agree and so
watching watching that develop and as
the industry moves more towards a
greater understanding of what's going on
on leaf surfaces around roots you know
understanding how to that the process of
you know individually picking out a
specific you know indirect Oh
mycorrhizal fungi and and choosing
whether or not you know your company is
able to grow all that up and of that and
make it into a you know a uniform
product that people can apply that's a
completely different type of system than
understanding the the minutiae of of
being able to figure out your own
compost pile right and knowing like the
conditions of the place where you're at
and the different materials that you
have to create you know new soil new
materials to be able to feed the plan is
sure surely it does take longer and
surely there are different types of
facilities than others but you know if
you're dealing with plants that are not
healthy or sick you know or they don't
have fans you know they don't have the
right amount of air circulation there's
like a very there's lots of things going
on that can be causing these issues in
the first place each one will watch out
before they get started