[Music]
we ran into each other at state of
cannabis
I think it's CWC be a new West Summit
now here at CCIA in SoCal I'm now based
out of Southern California you're still
based on Northern California but you
have been going to show we've been going
to show us for years oh yeah and it has
changed huh it's just like the
demographic the traffic yeah it seems
like not quite as busy because I think
partly because there's so many more
shows like yeah like I said we've been
seeing each other every week so I mean
it's hard to keep up in run business if
you're trying to go to shows every every
week as well so I think that brings the
attendance down per show when you're
scrambling to go to so many shows and
then we got to start to see an
oversaturation of the elements that are
at that show you know everybody needs
insurance but I think half the booths
here are insurance brokers and there's
only one or two companies that even
write insurance policies so between
insurance and packaging it seems to be
what what the majority of what goes on
to these shows these days are where as
I'm looking for innovative product
packaging retail outlets type stuff
definitely yeah I agree and it's you
know we talked about it been doing the
show circuit since 14 myself and and
2016 is kind of when we felt like it's a
point of saturation like to your point
all of a sudden it was this show this
show this show you know I'm always an
advocate for supporting the
organizations that are supporting the
industry so like I love CCIA I love NCI
a you know even new West Summit with
Jim's doing I mean what Peter's doing
with his with his series with bringing
the right people together I mean those
are the shows that really make sense to
me well you have some shows that they're
johnny-come-lately they've done
conventions in the tech industry or the
diamond industry or the this industry
and they see it as this is such a played
out term you'll agree the green rush so
they want oh we can do this show so
we'll do that show
and it doesn't have the same but you
said grit we're talking just now and
you're like I like New West it had the
grit like it had like Jim bring some
edgy stuff he brings tech he brings
media he brings innovation and then you
come to other shows where it's cookie
cutter you're like how many more
insurance how many more marketing
agencies
how many more packaging companies and I
was one of the best when I was down here
last with one of Peters events I think
focusing on one like criteria or
developing a panel or something super
specific because going to this that
breeders panel that you did down here in
Venice was always epic and yeah it's
just I think it's finding more unique
niches to do shows or panels or
conferences about and just fill in those
niches you know like so around growing
and breeding is something that I'm
really interested in packaging just kind
of fine-tuning what everybody's doing I
think yeah I agree we watched that show
I tend to that show and I love how he
even did it in a speakeasy as ironic I
don't think a lot of people absorb that
yeah that here he had it in a venue that
was a huge part of the original
prohibition in this country the whole
alcohol situation so for it to be back
in the basement yeah it's back in the
basement and then to get people like
eyes I was very impressed because Kevin
Joe jury who's a good friend who I mean
I love Jorge Cervantes not very good
friends with Ed Rosenthal but someone
like Kevin Joe jury who you know he's
been working with people like Gavin
Newsom one of the few politicians that
came out of the proverbial green closet
to support us with prop 64 you know and
then people like Mowgli who's just this
almost dare I say cyan't you know kind
of mad scientist he's so so brilliant
and what he's doing with the pilot
project and the people that were in the
room made a few friends like Tom Himes
from mg a couple others you know or like
this is the 2.0 stuff like this is a
next-level stuff that this industry
needs yeah enough of us know cannabis
101 we grew up around at uni from
Northern California it's been around us
for years but that's the kind of stuff
that I agree I feel like I get out yeah
cuz I already have any folks right back
to the plant the plant
so yeah and genetics and variety and
where that's all going it's super fun
yeah that's like a moving target that's
never gonna end
yeah you know what's the hot new genetic
profile that's going into everything you
know yeah that's that's exactly I was
just talking actually to Tom from mg and
you know I did this show in Utah we did
the Utah can first-ever canvas show out
there it was kind of cool because of the
whole it's an emerging market right so
there one like Michigan and Oklahoma you
know that are voting in November and it
was cool to see that energy and there
was such a it's an you know it's not a
mature market so everyone was so
open-minded to learning things and to
learn him the right way right you know
which again that's something I thought
was kind of cool was when there's like
real thirsty for information and it was
like wow this has taken me back to and
again not to date ourselves but we were
both I know I was of legal age to vote
on prop 215 back in 96 you probably were
to us clothed so I mean but for us to be
around that and then of course seen
medical just kind of take off from there
in the states but they see that that's
still something that's evolving yeah
that people are doing I think it's
pretty cool as well super cool so so
where to after this what are you where
you head to after trying to buckle down
and back home and handle the harvest
season and get all the packaging and the
branding and focus on hitting the market
sure one of the guys hustling I mean
you're yeah we don't see a lot of guys
literally individuals that are making
the trek down from NorCal to SoCal and
that's I think is interesting a lot of
people don't know when I think a
California they they get just this one
state that San Diego's right next to LA
LA is right next San Francisco but I
mean you're coming from the triangle I
know I went up there for HCG AI think I
saw you at Humboldt County growers
association another great show no local
supported show and I drove it was a
five-hour drive I had to fly in Oakland
Airport and I drove up from there and
you don't see a lot of people that you'd
see at a venue like that down here
getting out in front of these customers
and in this instance your customers mean
dispensaries right yeah yeah next saying
hey I'm bringing
fire from from the epicenter to your
front door right you know and we think
of like oh it's all in California but
when you think about it say to the East
Coast it would be like I'm coming to a
chill event in Georgia and I'm from New
York that's exactly and I think the fact
that you know a vast majority of
northing people aren't aware of yeah we
have 39 and a half million people in
this in this state but again a vast
majority are in the LA basin I think
it's something like 26 million people
alone in LA so you look at that compared
to San Francisco metro or Sacramento
Metro or even San Diego I mean this is
where a majority of the buyers on ya
know so you're smart for making that
track down it taking it to the largest
audience yeah I just got to break those
doors down into the hardest Barbara
[Music]