what the heck is a PhD doing in the
cannabis industry well there's actually
a lot more of us than you'd think my
journey was kind of accidental one on
purpose I had actually left chemistry
for a bit and I was I was an MRI tech
you make a lot more money as an MRI tech
than you do and as an adjunct lecturer
but but I always miss chemistry
I was always committed to medicine and I
really really really like the smell of
weed really really really I think I have
someone yeah a little Roman therapy on
my fingers there and so I decided to
take a plunge and just go out there and
Nate Ferguson over there gave me a
chance said you know we're gonna bring
this guy on board and see what he can do
so it's been an adventure since then and
let's go ahead and get started with the
talk get the slides okay looks like I
have the slides
okay so until very recently most of you
if you knew about me knew me as dr. Jack
Hughes a little bitty Instagram page and
because of I'm in it in my medical
connection I could not reveal my real
name
even though Kaiser will actually
prescribe cannabis to dying patients
they won't let MRI techs who use
cannabis be employed there so you know
that's what's that is my name is Wyeth
Calloway like I said we're going to talk
about the study in the expansion of
production through technical
improvements and innovations so Geddy's
changed a lot since I first walked in
the door and it's not just been me it's
been a team I just want to emphasize an
entire time I've been kind of like let's
let's let's make the nerd analogy to the
Starship Enterprise I'm pretty much like
Spock
okay so I will you know say things like
this is an illogical course I am 100%
certain this will fail things like that
so let's let's move forward where's my
clicker there we go so so here's Jenny
this is some pictures of jetty who we
are and right up there is our nice
reception room here is my a messy R&amp;D
corner and this is actually a column for
column chromatography you know I like to
run kilo scale and over here is what
used to be the rotovap area so talk more
about that and last but not least is the
bee who greeted me on my first day at
jetty when I didn't even know what honey
oil meant so it was very ironic okay I
know what bubble hash was I've been
making bubble hash here we go so who are
we so we started in 2013 this started in
2017 r-13 and were founded by a group of
surfers in San Diego so Nate Ferguson
Matt Lee
the Rob Ferguson and ronger Shoni okay
we were about a hundred thousand in
revenue in that first year since then
we've roughly doubled more more or less
every year we're a distillates and
concentrate company and one of our
trademarks is up there you can see the
tops water clear pen the trademark is
actually the cedar the the sandalwood
tip so sandalwood is very renewable in
terms of a tip most places have metal or
plastic so that's one of our signature
jetty things the next thing is an
applicator the dab locator is a way of
dabbing that you can allows you to
control a little bit more than sticking
a scoop into you know a little jar and
then just tapping that so you know it's
got a little clicking mechanism and you
can more or less get a decent dose it's
a little cleaner so really great product
okay the last thing I want to talk about
jetty who are we the shelter project so
the shelter project is a compassionate
care program started in 2014 by our own
Lindsay Friedman and at one point we had
a thousand patients that we were giving
formulated or unform elated cannabis
medicine - for free
we gave her a over a million dollars in
free merchandise free product and you
know unfortunately SB 64 decided that
they would impose a tax on donated goods
and this really affected compassionate
care probably some of you out there
actually know about this
so Lindsay's first efforts and
everybody's first efforts actually
failed uncovered on Jerry Brown's desk
he vetoed the first compassionate care
bill and now we've got SB 34 in the
works so call your Congressman Congress
person and tell them you support SB 34
because that's gonna make things more
rational we're not going to be able to
have to pay taxes it's gonna be a lot
more easy to remote people in the
program so I don't know if anybody's a
fan of jeti but did you know he used to
make edibles and they were from
2016-2017 called skews
Jenny mine tricks okay
and that's cannabis infused toffee and I
have no idea
to this day how they got the name
perhaps opium on here could tell you
these are not the droids you're looking
for
Jedi Mind Tricks okay I actually do know
so what am I going to talk about today
cannabis cannabis distillate production
the it's basically what we do and this
is sort of a summary I feel like I'm
preaching to the choir here probably
absolutely everybody in the room knows
everything about this topic but
nonetheless here we go
so it's first step is biomass
preparation then we have extraction
winterization filtration and
concentration decarboxylation which a
lot of people just call D carb but it's
also a D volatilization process we have
final distillation of the cannabinoids
and then as a side note we have actually
cannabis essential oil production and
this isn't really necessary to the
distillate market because there exist
all sorts of flavor elements that are
out there including fake plant derived
terpene profiles which will have the
name of a king of cannabis Kiev are you
all probably know about that so here are
a few examples of my work on the top
left there is God Only Knows I believe
it's reclaim not super proud of that
color the next is our d8 Reserve Delta a
pretty high ratio there and then the
last is the water clear delta line in
the corner there so who worried before I
came to jetty we were prop 215 compliant
okay we're using co2 supercritical fluid
extraction and ethanol extraction
capabilities at that time for the
winterization slash precipitation we had
a cold room we had to do carbon
scrubbing we did vacuum filtration with
large fretted funnels I'm sure you've
all seen these Buechner funnels that
kind of things a little bit of iteration
we had one small rotovap at first for
the co2 we just needed a light
winterization and you know you've heard
the story about a thousand
he's with thousand typewriters and you
know they can write the perfect novel
well early in the early days of cannabis
you know what I've seen and been told is
basically if you had a machine and it
was working you just bought five more of
them you know and that that would do it
so we started with that then we were
doing a manual decarboxylation we
weren't d volatilizing at that point and
we had a two inch Pope's a white film
system we had to do two passes so I
wanted to remove the quote unquote Terp
fraction talk about that a little more
later and we had done some research on
short path distillation but never used a
production and initially short path was
how I learned to deal with all of you
pretty much knew how to do before I was
you know cannabis was a twinkle in my
eye or whatever how you put it and so I
had an old legacy short path a two liter
and a five liter okay we were doing
small-scale production of cannabis
essential oils as soon as I arrived at
jetty we were doing cannabis essential
oils just want to make that clear
because when I walked in I didn't have
these plant or I profiles to smell as an
example of what cannabis tasted like in
a vape pen I had the real McCoy and so
what after I dried that you know you
know it was revealed to me there were
plant profiles and so on and I tried
that and I was like Oh yuck Oh yuck this
won't do but I don't want to knock it
some people liked it but in the early
days of our cannabis essential oil
production we had small similar off
flavors in every batch okay so we were
using a technique that I'll get into in
a second but there was a problem in
Denmark there and one of the things
about jetty that that I'm gonna
emphasize in this talk is we don't stand
still we always critique what we're
doing we always try to be better we
don't look at the competition we look at
what we are doing okay because these
guys who founded the jetty they loved
the plant I love the way the plant
smells I loved vaping okay I love this
company and so we put so much love in
our products that we actually talk about
this will actually sit and talk about
intentionality and this is you know
something my before I met my lovely wife
that I'd really never heard about it
engine allottee it was my intention to
get to my molecule the quickness that I
could so when you know this whole
concept of intentionality it sort of
brought me to this community and this
whole idea of plant-based medicine so
enough asides I will do a lot of them
let's move on to the next slide here so
where are we now we're prop 64 compliant
hydrocarbon is our main method of
extraction with UX and capabilities we
have precision grinding instead of just
the cold room we also have a minus 60
cryo freezer we're no longer doing any
scrubbing we have large capacity
stainless steel filtration we only need
large Road of apps we have a VTA which
is a very nice continuous white film
system you can do in two passes just
like the Pope at a lot higher capacity
we in February we acquired an HP 1hp two
hot condensing short path and
distillation device and it's amazing
people I don't know if anyone's use this
or seen this on at breaking dabs website
but it's a game changer and now thank
God it's my R&amp;D piece and I got to
retire the old 5 liter Summit bastard
you know we'll talk about how fast that
one was but you know what it's you know
you always got to love your you know the
first thing you trained on but this
thing's a Cadillac now and you know with
with work we just we devise scaleable
production of cannabis essential oils
and we eliminated the off flavors okay
so you may see me stop and take a sniff
of these if I'm feeling like a little
woozy something like that later we can
talk about it but one of the things I
love about my job is I get to walk into
a place where I have a fridge full of
cannabis drive terpenes somehow no
matter my mood there's something for it
okay so we're just started talking about
prop 64 there's one thing we got to
really talk about a prop 64 which is
probably my biggest contribution to
jetty I would say in the machines
Department okay and that is analytical
testing okay
there's two types of analytical testing
that I've kept broadly categorized in
the cannabis industry and one's accuracy
so cannabinoid potency and also terpene
testing if you want to put terpenes on
your label in California you gotta have
them tested you all know this within I
believe it's 10% of the printed value on
your package or you fail compliance and
that's as you all know a very bad thing
safety as well so I have on the right
the it's not the 62 it's the 58
pesticides that can be tested by HPLC
there's 62 and of these there's category
2 and category 1 does anybody know the
difference between category 1 and
category 2 I do if you even see category
1 on your data you're done fails
compliance mainly this is because these
pesticides that have been used in the
cannabis industry before are not
designated as safe pesticides by the
state of California to be used on food
production so that's where that came
from so below is a little nice ninety
seven point one three percent total
cannabinoids that's one of our nice oils
there so that's an idea of sort of the
potency testing so along with safety we
have residual solvents okay and so back
in the day and I'll talk about this
there was sort of a different category
for residuals but now they compromise
solvents that are deleterious to human
or that's the right word are bad for
humans to inhale okay or eat we also
have mycotoxins so these are toxins
produced by microorganisms that are
dangerous to human health we really
don't have a problem with these in
distillate and then of course heavy
metals cat3
you have on the next slide
we've got arsenic a clm a CL me that's a
little MRI thing the ACL people tear it
so our snick cadmium lead and mercury
okay we've got to keep those two parts
per billion levels so what do I talk
about this about Jani well we're ahead
of the curve even before I got there
before they were even asked to do this
JD was doing potency and pesticide
testing and the records go all the way
back they're kind of fun to look at
steep hill was the only game in town
that's what we used in July 2016 started
with CW did terpene testing and also
residual solvents and here's the thing
about residual solvents it was less than
5,000 parts per million of flammable
solvents okay flammable solvents which
is funny because ethanol is really
flammable too and although it's not
great to inhale it's not going to kill
you or give you cancer like chloroform
dichloromethane no dichloroethane so
these really gnarly chlorinated solvents
so you know by the grace of the chemists
who worked with the BCC whatnot we got a
new list of residual solvents include
the chlorinated solvents and also
benzene xylenes things like that
although those are flammable so let's
talk about the heavy metals because I
don't think the industry was ready for
this are you guys ready for cat 3 right
cat 3 hit hit everybody like a kick in
the pants the reason is is the equipment
that the labs needed to study cat 3
isn't done ducted coupled plasma ok it's
an expensive technology it's very
accurate the old technology atomic
absorption wasn't quantitative enough so
who even had an ICP who even had the
working capital to spend 150 grand 200
grand and figure it out and have a
chemist figure it out how to do it ok
these guys as you know these guys and
gals in the testing labs they're backed
up you know a week sometimes so you've
got to pull somebody off to get that ICP
running ok so when I came to jetty we
have all these things that are mandated
and we've got to figure out what
is going to be our response okay so the
two pictures on the right the top one
that looks like something out of Star
Wars is a triple quad hplc mass spec
mass spec and it's used for those 58
pesticides the other four I didn't
mention you need a gas chromatograph on
the bottom there is the HPLC uv-vis that
I would have been able to afford so you
know you just dial it in and pumps it's
great so in-house analytics so that was
the first thing I was asked to evaluate
we went around and we looked at stuff
and the HPLC uv-vis was the standard for
potency okay it still is and we were you
know interested in that but it was about
40 or 50 grand to get in that and don't
know if you know the SHPO sees a limit
ography technique so now we've got to
have organic solvents and we've got to
have a place to deal with organic
solvents we didn't have fume hoods at
the time so we decided against that one
next option triple quad and a GCMs like
I said there's four pesticides you can't
do with the triple quad so that was
about 300k used plus as you heard
earlier I'm not an analytical chemist
I'm an organic chemist I'm a
jack-of-all-trades
that's my Instagram name so you know I
told the guys you know if we're gonna go
for this
you know HPLC triple quad I'm gonna need
some training you know I'm gonna need
some training and it's gonna be a lot of
my time on this thing and I want a
service plan etc etc so the numbers
started rising and we just kind of
decided you know that's not really what
we need to do for just one category so
in there at the bottom I'll mention it
was the ICP you got to put that there as
a joke because it really can't do
anything else for us but heavy metals so
the middle thing is what we settled on
the GC fi D because it can do pote
potency of the neutral cannabinoids THC
and then to do tht a and all the other
acid cannabinoids you have to do
something called derivatives a ssin
but I believe there still is to this day
a testing lab in California that uses GC
to do its pesticide testing ok GCMs you
can take a GCF ID it's flame ionization
detector vaporized particles hit or they
hit a flame and they're counted by
basically a detector counts ionized
particles were really good at measuring
small electrical signals and so that's
how that works forms a peak every time a
substance comes out of the machine Union
I can go into this a little bit more at
the end of people who really want to go
into these techniques but we could add
residual solvents and we could add
terpene profiles just by slapping
something on the end of the machine
there was only about 10 15 thousand
dollars and I would probably beg for a
service plan but you know it's better
than the 300 400 thousand dollars okay
so the best return on investment
remember what I said jetty we're all
about running lean we're all about
intentionality and so I would have loved
to have all those instruments absolutely
loved out my own lab like that and have
jetty pay for it we scientists we love
to have toys y'all and we love to have
you all pay for it so what we decided on
was a GC flame ionization detector so we
got a quick potency method for oil from
res Tech and in four minutes four
minutes I had my answer and in fact it
two and a half minutes I had my answer
because pretty much all the cannabinoids
that wanted you know would aleut we're
done after two and a half minutes I
don't know if anybody knows about thin
layer chromatography the old-school
method you have these little plates we
use them to monitor reactions and purity
will they take about you know two and a
half minutes to run GC I can actually
get percentages and ratios and man I'm
telling you you know I almost never ran
TLC again but GC went down for a little
bit so we had to do that but anyway so I
really liked it because now we could we
had a machine that could do really
quickly potency
testing we could monitor monitor our
distillation 'z we could monitor
incoming material you know just sort of
things yet everybody has to know like
how it was just insane to me that people
were producing distillates with all
these procedures and didn't have their
own analytics it was just like what
yeah man looks good bra looks it's
yellow yeah look at that it's good bra
well little did I know I mean you can
actually do a lot with a visual
inspection and chemists have been for
hundreds of years have been doing that
but I come from a fancy little graduate
school and we have all our machines that
you all paid for so useful reactions
involving basic cannabinoids so
everybody now is on to these these minor
cannabinoids right THC V cbn right dt8
teach the acetate THC hemi succinate
hexa hydro THC well guess what if I want
to go into the lab and make these things
I can actually watch my reactions
proceed and decide that if I have my
head up my butt or actually found
something really really quickly so we
wanted that capability and we were also
be able to do terpene profiles it's easy
to operate no solvent and then of course
the upgrade that I talked about
okay so GC succeeds where HPLC fails
alright this is an interesting story
that I want to kind of tie in a little
bit later we're gonna come back to it at
the end I probably want to bite into QC
a little bit to talk about this but you
know you're we're to talk about
production innovations and this is a
little bit of science okay
so we're gonna go ahead and skip past
that let's get past the data and we're
gonna talk about go back into my outline
biomass is the first step so we found
biomass preparation necessary for co2
everybody knows that you can't just take
you know a mallet and start jamming the
co2 thing full of full of a biomass it's
not efficient and if anyone knows who
Marcus Rogan is
at the time I met him he was outcault he
actually optimized particle size and a
number of other concerns with co2 and
his co2 oil it looked amazing
so anyway back to when I back off my
tangent we used ninja blenders actually
you know I would say Nate did they went
out they told me they'd go up to
Humboldt County with a bunch of ninja
blenders and they would hack that crap
out and everybody's going what blenders
are you you know and they you know what
the really funny thing and this is what
dials back to Marcus Rogan is guess what
grind is best for cannabis terpenes and
co2 the freaking ninja blender the ninja
blender
that's a tidbit from Marcus's talk okay
when we moved to ethanol we found that
that grinding was unnecessary this was
the early days and we were getting a lot
of chlorophyll from a biomass okay so we
really needed no advancement in grinding
technology co2 or the when we got into
hydrocarbons we had to ditch that a
ninja neo farms told us ditch that ninja
we've got you bro it's uh it's it does
this stuff really fast you know and it
beats the ninja blender and it kind of
looks like it looks like a snow making
machine to me and much like a snow
machine making machine it love to blow
Keef all over the room okay many of you
probably used this one so we had no dust
control and I would not go near that
room when that thing was running just
allergies like crazy so we had no
control of particle size we had no speed
control and there was like I said a
heckuva loss of mechanical material so
at that same conference where I met
Marcus Rogan he introduced me to a
company called I believe it's called
fridge okay that make these Cadillac
hammer mill grinders okay so it's not
like it's amazingly new tech it's just
kind of new to cannabis but those things
being a Cadillac are a lot of money so
we did our usual jetty research and we
we kind of
got in you know in the room and Spock
was asked what he thought about the
grinding and I mentioned that I'd seen
this hammer mill tack and then our
lab manager Kurt went out and he just he
just scoured the earth for an affordable
solution so that's how we got it to the
the hammer mill technology and let's get
to the picture of this so this is our
key Froome and this is our fancy grinder
now we have positional blades we have
air assist if we need it because Keith
gets sticky we got sieve screens we can
control particle size and boy howdy look
at those numbers 45 minutes before to
process not precision process 50 pounds
get that hammer mill running 10 pounds
in 50 minutes or having 50 pounds in 10
minutes see a lot of stuff backwards
okay so this really really kicked it up
a notch extraction okay this is kind of
the big thing that I really don't feel
like I need to talk to about a ton
because everybody is super passionate
about the way they do things but you
know a jetty we do a lot of stuff by
trial and error small scale and at the
time there was just some disadvantages
to these these these other techniques
that we had the main the main message
here is throughput in regulation co2
couldn't do the throughput we needed and
ethanol
while it was good if we wanted to scale
it up which we did we were growing we
had to change our chemical manufacturing
status because we needed more than a
thousand gallons in process so what we
had was we had one of these little
waters guys that's actually a pretty big
water sky we had a single tube and then
we got the Delta Co P and that's what we
used and when you you know they helped
we were we were cranking out oil one
last thing I'd like to say about the
ethanol is she was filtration and
bottlenecks everybody knows solvent
recovery is crazy and also if you I
don't know about the cryo technique but
when we were doing it the
article size this stuff would coagulate
like crazy these fats and waxes and so
we had to you know it was a bottleneck I
mean you'd be scraping it's we tried all
kinds of different iterations so it was
nice when we finally got the hydrocarbon
and we were able to see a much more easy
to deal with process so the decision to
do hydrocarbon summer 2017 to 2019 was a
decision driven by regulation we got our
type seven license and so we're ready to
go and before we went a little crazy we
got ourselves a little bit busy bee and
I'm not sure we even it owned it and we
just started doing what we do we started
doing experiments and and it's like I
said it's what we found that the
processing post-processing went to
almost nothing you know there's all
kinds of post-processing that everybody
knows about here and I'm not going to
belabor the point it's all on future
4200 and that's where I learned it all
but for us speed okay the more you can
do with the less labor is more efficient
you're faster to market and you know
that's really important to us we're
growing so we decided that we would go
with hydro carbon deliberately okay when
I first got into this I was like well
hydrocarbons really bad and then I was
introduced to the process and I realized
the only thing left in these extracts is
ethanol from winterization and anybody
who win arises or uses ethanol is gonna
potentially have ethanol in their final
material so that faded so we got Betsy
up there in the corner I don't know who
named her but she's a workhorse and we
did this because at the time ethanol
distillate can only do ethanol could
only do distillate and we wanted to
branch out we you know these guys these
guys have been doing this since 2013
nan-oh and dispensary we knew about the
variety of products that were out there
the diamond technology was just starting
to come on these cookies has anyone ever
seen cookies these little cookie things
okay we brought on a guy named Tran and
he is
butane artiste he loves making pictures
and stuff with butane so don't do like I
did and assume they're Nilla wafers in
the break room
don't do it thank God the metabolism of
THC a right is very very slow in your
body and it's not deep carved yet or I
would not be here talking to you they're
not Nilla wafers but they are delicious
and we'll be releasing them fairly soon
the c1 d1 room and I guess I should talk
about this a little bit with jetty we
literally doubled in size when we were
getting our hydrocarbon in our intake
apparatus ready because we knew
hydrocarbon was going to kick ass and do
a lot of trim so we acquired there was a
whole nother company here when I started
we acquired that side and we were able
to expand so we actually have two c1 d1
rooms and one of them we use for
pesticides and filtration so quickly
let's talk about winterization not going
to belabor the point used to use a
walk-in freezer got this sweet-ass cryo
freezer - 60 48 hours goes down to four
hours and with the the hydrocarbon
precipitates the fats and waxes it's a
lot easier to deal with
okay so here's like I said thousand
monkeys or the thousand typewriters
mentality so these 15 mil Buechner
funnels they're really great and you can
you know take that amount of activated
carbon which we needed and you needed
about 500 but it looked like an organ so
it was pretty awesome and if you believe
that I have a bridge to sell you
we had much larger ones 2000 now here is
what we ended up buying this stainless
steel filter skid table or stainless
steel stainless steel filter table with
basically on a skid and eventually the
idea is you know as everyone's done and
Heisenberg's done you basically you want
to go to manufacturing that's simply
never sees any buckets or anything it's
all in line okay so this piece of
equipment will eventually be able to
integrate into this type of thing so the
great thing about this is we went from
40 kilograms a day or I'm sorry 6
kilograms a day with that nasty goopy
stuff to 45 kilograms a day and we're
still under capacity like if anybody
needs to filter in the Bay Area I'm sure
we can tell a process Nate that will
total process your filtration so we did
this with half the labor and if anybody
wants to know it's an infinity
manufacturing concepts okay
concentration okay I'm accused of not
having a lot of concentration sometimes
but concentration simply solve it
removal and you've got our first little
guy up there in the top a bukey rotovap
2 liter and then you've got the 20
liters and then the road of apps are
retired
okay there are D road of apps now you
know put colored liquids in them
whatever but anyway so we started out
with it the 2015 with the 2-liter and
then 2016 when we moved to ethanol as
you guys as you all know the capacity
that you need to do solver rules just
crazy
so 2017 to 2019 when we move to
hydrocarbons we were able to drop back 2
to 20 liters but we also needed 5 to
litre Road of apps that we already had
to do the final processing to get it
ready for the D carb okay and so that
whole boot that workflow was based on
the D car workflow
okay April 2019 is when we initiated the
new D carb which is what I'll talk about
next we retired the little road of apps
ok and we're doing an average of 4
liters per hour of solvent removal ok ok
I know I'm looking at the time I tend to
ramble so let's try to pick it up 2016
2019 for the dank ages we're talking
about atmospheric D carb this is a
picture of how VTA told us how to deke
arm they said put it on a hot plate and
stir it for 8 hours ok
and that's fine though it works it
actually works really well ok but it
just kind of gives off a lot of volatile
zuv a lot of dank but it does work
really well
and we wanted to do it a little bit more
efficiently because the reason it's on
there for eight hours and we knew this
is when you're doing manual d car but
only took about an hour for the bubbles
to stop why the heck are we doing this
for eight hours well it's those volatile
x' and just let me kind of divide up
cannabis if I if I you know I will just
since abroad categories so for
distillation so we have basically we're
gonna have an insoluble amount of stuff
that we're gonna remove in winterization
or we're not going to extract then we
have the first set of volatile as
cannabis drive terpenes essential oils
the next the next half or what I call
the volatiles and those are all the way
up to the boiling point of the
cannabinoids what we really want and
then afterwards you have what everyone
calls I think calls for 10-day its the
goop okay so we have to get rid of that
those care those volatiles above the
cannabis derived essential oils a lot of
them we did do quite a good Terp runs so
some of the higher volatile is right
before the distillation point of the
cannabinoids okay we could we could
strip those out but the lower volatile
would really mess up the white film so
we had to get rid of them but you know
being a chemist and having been cut my
teeth on short path distillation I
decided that we could do this under
vacuum oh and I know people were doing
this way before we were but as jetty
goes I had to prove concept I can't just
walk in and be like Al this is a logical
this is just illogical no I had to show
him it worked I just show him it worked
took me about on and off three or four
months messing around with systems and
then I finally got a system that retired
I wrote of apps and made a 24-hour
process into eight hours and
unfortunately the delicious tangi smell
was gone
okay so distillation this is one of the
large largest capital investments okay
I didn't even get to the dank ages so
this is what I was talking about
okay so distillation the largest capital
investment decision time we decided to
go with white film instead of short path
because basically it was just easier
short path takes skill and I learned no
more mimosa ever learned about the
skillet took was from this man breaking
dabs over there because I really thought
I had gotten short path you know I'd
made this beautiful water clear oil and
and you know I thought it'd be and I got
this down you know I can do one liter in
seven hours this is cookin and yeah so
[Music]
anyway so we decided to go with the Pope
its produces actually a pretty nice oil
you can do two passes or you have to do
two passes and the picture over there
czar is an example of it that's probably
a six-inch Pope actually but you know
the distillate comes out on one side of
a tent eight on the other and you do
your two passes or its chirps and so
then we decided to add another pope and
we added the four-inch pope and although
we were able to load more this is kind
of a funny contradiction there was no
change in speed okay we didn't have
continuous white film distillation
system and so we had to have operators
loaded unloaded so we went to one of the
you know really famous consulting firms
to get an auto feeder well in those days
I want to say the tech wasn't ideal and
unfortunately the dream of running the
thing overnight and continued his
extraction failed so that's when we
started looking at these continuous
extraction white film and I just want to
say that I guessed wrong i I I just got
to put this out there I I've been on the
wrong pony and they override admit I'm
glad they did so we decided to go with
the VTA instead of an American brand
that I really loved and I've heard a lot
of bad things about since then but
anyway this is a really passionate topic
so I'm not going to go into it
we got route Sciences German engineering
once we can do thick and with all they
can what is that Sivan
no finesse okay that's our model we can
do 8 liters a day we could probably push
this and break it and that's what 2
passes so we have a better color
distillate and we're consistently I put
it in the 90s but you know what it
honestly depends on the biomass team
that we're getting and at least always
at you know in that in the middle high
eighties and so this is a beautiful jar
the oil there and this is our I don't
even know lab manager Jones and that's
our beautiful root science right there
so it's amazing you load the material
here and all under vacuum for the wiper
and then the oil just comes out here so
it's pretty cool technology and I know
there's a lot better stuff but right now
a jetty it's working for us and we will
make the investment in the next step of
technology when we go to that continuous
flow through process that I was talking
about and so right now you know we're
kind of looking at that and how we're
gonna do it so I've been sneaking a
recorder and a camera into highs in
Bayer manufacturing and you know just
click click how do you do this click
okay so let's see where I'm at and this
talk Travis I got a time check 10
minutes can I do I'm sorry so I really
wanted to talk about this a lot because
this is this is one of my favorite
things to do this is my research
instrument and this is was the biggest
breakthrough in short path as far as I'm
concerned it was called wide bore and
hot condensation and he developed it in
2016 I really can't go through this
slide as as much as I'd like but it's
gonna you're gonna have it available to
you a long story short we bought one and
there's me with the system and that
allowed us access to d9 water-clear dat
TV and now I'm doing 2 litres in 5 hours
ok and that start to finish with D
carbon the pot I can do a second pass in
two to three hours so this thing rocks
so that takes down the resident time
which is really important okay
so really quickly let's talk about
cannabis drive terpenes so this is my
thing and I want you to call them CEOs
cannabis essential oils because they're
more than just terpenes
there's hundreds of turpenoid and non
typing compounds available in the
volatile portion of this plant and one
of them is no no no it's not non anal
get your heads out of the gutter and
it's flat so I got a floral and orgy
smell and it is in no way a terpene it's
an aldehyde c9 unit okay but actually
it's one of the highest contributors to
the odor of cannabis if you take
cannabis and put it in a duffel bag for
68 hours known and Alan you sample the
headspace around it known and Al is
actually one of the strongest scents and
we were training the dogs to do
carolien oxide okay so where were we at
jetty we were doing steam still steam
still is what everybody's doing doing
the Rd then we bought a big one looks
like this water goes in here biomass in
there heat the steam comes on out the
steam cools and then is caught in here
the terpenes will float on top to
cannabis oils float on top and then you
can separate them okay
so what you're doing a hundred pounds a
day pretty good okay I want to show you
really quickly the difference between a
profile and a cannabis derives essential
oil it's in the grass is what I said so
this is a profile of granddaddy purp and
probably see about 20 beats maybe this
is a cannabis essential oil of an OG
Kush and my GC isn't even that great
it's not even that great and look at
alphap I mean this is this is on my
method so I can only sample boiling
points around here in a headspace I can
go more alphap I mean there's compounds
in front of it okay and we know roughly
what these compounds are we know that
there's about 400 of them so if somebody
wants to finance me they start getting
some standards that
I would appreciate it and we'll start
figuring out exactly what this is or
we'll farm it out okay so the next
iteration now that you know what
cannabis essentials oils are and how
complicated they are is to do it under
with a vacuum assist so you can do at a
lower temperature well this was better
ish when I smelled student steam so
loyal it was it really all smelled the
same to me and it had a burnt caramel
and a grassy smell and then we got to
atmospheric and the smells were still
there and I so hated them that that I
would just be super picky about it be
like this is just not acceptable this is
just no and by the way I studied in
France so I'm not trying to insult the
French people I love them so it also
took days to dry okay that was a big
thing we had have a drying room we turns
brown snarly you can't go in there
without a mask you know it's it takes
too long and we still have those off
flavors so I just went in the lab and
like I said we always try to do better
and better and better and through Marc
ones remark for I finally was able to
prove to Jetty we love the essential
oils we were making but we're only
making them on small scale so I was able
to prove to jetty that we could do this
finally we got to the mark for the the
real the real kicker for us was when we
did a water-clear skywalker OG Penn and
Noah and Travis tasted this among others
and they were like whoa whoa yeah and we
were like whoa whoa and when I said no
about accidental medicine is we actually
gave these pens to you know all over the
convention and I had a patient or a
person write me back and said this is
the best d8 water-clear I have ever had
for pain and I wrote him back and I said
it's not d8 it's t9 and he was like well
I don't know why I've tried every d9
product and get my hands on and so we
were like crap must be the Terps we're
not sure but it's something we'd like to
study anyway so it's been implemented
chedi we're making cannabis drive
turbines at scale and we can get broad
profiles we can we can control the
profile if we want the drying room is
gone and the mark 5 is in development
and probably
hi okay so it's happening this is this
is the year of cannabis essential oils
this year or next or next year folks
that's my prediction
other methods you can look at these we
looked at them didn't like them
microwave and then I call Pangaea attack
just go ahead and go through that that's
from biomass
yeah Pangaea was a IC mag so woot-woot
open sourcing okay IC g IC mag he or she
I don't really I never even really met
Pangaea designed a system you can go on
and you can google it and it's actually
makes really nice water clear good
smelling kind of essential oils okay now
here's the Mina potatoes of the actual
events we have a timeline from 2018 to
May 2019 and here shows what happened
with the implementation of these
technologies so when we got to hydro
carbon we increased our production 50 to
100 percent and our capacity increased
hundred percent the VTA the cryo freezer
we got in August 818 same time and I'd
like you to understand the numbers are
kind of melded together but when you go
from 48 hours to four days
that helps the VTA four hundred seventy
percent increase in production capacity
up eight hundred percent filter table 13
percent increase in production in
January 19 and then we excuse me the
capacity increased 750 percent in half
the labor category three screwed us over
I think everyone over output dropped our
input in so production dropped and that
meant input also dropped okay
significant events as well the mark 4
came online and we all right we were
able to access these essential oils in
our products I don't know if anyone's
noticed a difference I hope you have and
3:19 we we instituted the SPD tech we
were able to do jetty reserve okay it
actually has a 4% increase in production
of these specialty products and if we
max this thing out we could get 12 D
carb P volatile is a
another 12% er and the thing about that
is 24 process our process goes to 8
hours and we no longer need this large D
car barrier we no longer need the the
road of apps we've got a lot of space to
expand ok this is great
our D space I wish so over this period
over this 15 month period we had a
tenfold increase in the amount of
material we were able to bring in so the
technology just fed exactly you could if
I had the line here I didn't want to put
it but it's basically follows this trend
exactly and now we're kind of in a
little bit of a period where things are
kind of cuckoo and we can talk about
that later if you want
in summary I just wanted to say that you
know just Geddy's ahead of ahead of the
curve usually we work together we do
things intentionally and if you get
anything about of my talk it's something
you already knew that extraction and
distillation methods determine capacity
we run lean the largest acquisition that
I made was a 35 K short path everything
else I did the Terps that he carved
everything else that was done under
$10,000 the GC was done around 20k okay
so our commitment to cannabis essential
oil has upped our game we have great
capabilities to I mean this is this is
just it's just the tip of the iceberg
just making them as the tip of the
iceberg folks if you have the tech to
make them you can do so much ok and that
the last but not least sort of my deal
is that manufacturers with their own
analytical even if it's just a GCF ID
are more agile okay do I have time to
talk to a little Tucker a little bit
about the story about about the d-10 why
this famous more agile okay
so first let's go talk about that okay
so does anybody here know what Delta 10
th she is okay good okay this is Delta
10 th see I've got there's no chiral PI
indicated here this is just a general
structure the double-bond has moved from
this position to this position different
molecule different shape different
activity on the top there is a molecule
called D 6 ad 10a okay
it's another cousin of cannabis so let's
talk about this story here so well I'm
clicking back well we were short passing
in these old five leaders and two
leaders with long residency time we were
getting what we noticed low potency oil
and we couldn't figure out why because
more passes is more better the color got
better what's going on here well hope we
have a GC you guys so we could actually
see what was going on and what we were
finding is that there are these two
peaks and that's about the
sophistication I had with the GC there
because we didn't have standards for
those compounds we knew they fell in the
cannabinoid range so we weren't really
super worried but you know this was
lowering our potency and we couldn't
have that so here is a product that we
had one of our orange anis products with
these two peaks so if you can see you've
got CBD and then there's question mark
d-10 d-10 a 6a THC the reason that I can
actually put those question marks there
is because I thought it was an isomer of
THC I wasn't sure if was d-10 or any of
the other things I didn't know well
lucky for me I met Noah cook and he gave
me he's like here here's some d-10 what
yeah d-10 might be your mister EP and we
took that sample back to the lab and it
was 80% pure and thank God it was
because I got two peaks he just given me
a hundred percent pure delta10 that
would end this story which gets a little
more complicated but so we had it so we
went and we took some material that had
these Peaks in it and we spiked it a
little bit of d-10 and lo and behold we
saw those Peaks rise no new peaks we
knew that we had Delta 10 and it was
lowering our potency well these these
people went even further they figured
out the potency loss was due
in part to high retire high residency
times in short pass but also because
there was fast check out there that crap
they sprayed all over California during
the wildfires and y'all probably got
some cheap trim right so but when you
process this trim you ended up getting
oil then had these breakdown Pete's this
is what the oil should look like so it
wasn't in everything okay
so we had the GC and now I can monitor
for this peak I know now when I'm doing
crap short path okay I know it's t10 and
now I know that I can monitor all of our
processes and see if d-10 is happening
and be like hold the presses everyone so
that's how agile we are so we we don't
have to take in bad material there's
tests for ammonium phosphate and
ammonium sulfate stuff like that now
before I want to end with this really
quickly so the d-10 story gets a little
more interesting what about that second
peak okay everyone was talking about
d-10 d-10 do ten Yatta Yatta and I was
like on futures 4200 I like which
diastereomer which enantiomer and they
were like what what are you talking
about well molecules have shapes and
even though they have the same exact
chemical structure and bonds there's
something called handedness like they're
like mirror images some of them okay and
they don't have the same shape they
don't have the activity and actually
there are four potential compounds for
d-10 so I thought well you know these
that other peak is probably an
enantiomer or a dynasty remember diester
say enantiomer diastereomers because
they have different boiling points and
here are two diastereomers at mesh well
I'm at out made in 1984 it's all out
there sometimes we just don't know where
to look for things because it's in the
scientific literature okay so I did a
little bit of an experiment
I read the literature and I found out
that there's a difference in boiling
point or melting point by a hundred
degrees on these things and like well
guess what
it's not a diastereomer Wyeth because
they would show up completely
differently on the GC so I've said okay
we got one of these guys what's that
next peak read the literature and you
see that if you heat them like crazy
they go to d6 ad 10a it was known in
1984 right and I had this paper and it
was only until we got an NMR of this
material that we had a little bit of a
clue and also I want to share with you
this experiment that actually clued me
on as well so I had some low potency
short path oil and we have all this crap
sitting around and I wanted to fix it so
I thought hey let's just throw some t41
clay in there it's a city let's turn it
all into d8 let's watch what happens
folks two hours into the reaction Delta
nine actually does start going down you
see a reduction in the d-10 peak and
then this new peak starts rising up and
so I'm like well this sucks because
that's actually where the other shoulder
lines up to so da eight and that they
might be on top of each other I don't
know what's going on three hours of
reaction is pretty much finished D nines
almost gone and then look at the D 10
ratio almost completely gone okay so I
was like got it
d 10 you're out I've gotten on I've got
a way to create Delta 8
I've got Delta 8 right from junk and
people are interested in this well I
send it out for lab testing and
unfortunately and this ties into the
other story ygc was better
I got a result back that said it was D
10 plus CPC as everybody knows that
Peaks bs the cbiit there's no CBC and a
lot of your low potency oils it's Delta
10 but guess what folks it ain't just
Delta 10 and that's me going out on a
limb okay so what we learned the result
I got back D 10 plus you know I go
thought I got rid of it was 30% okay and
if you go back and you look at you go
back and look at the starting material
the ratio of these suckers was
about 30% okay so nothing changed there
and I was really bummed and I kind of
set this aside and then an NMR came up
and on the NMR there was a small side
product this was very pure stuff it was
Noah's stuff and on the NMR there's
these two little Peaks out in a region
where US chemists really know what's
going on easy to see from everything
else and actually what it turns out is
there these Peaks right here so they
match up perfectly with Delta six a
delta 10a okay
guess what I haven't proved shit okay I
haven't proved anything I've got a I've
got a hypothesis what do I need to do I
need a pure standard of Delta 10a I need
an NMR of this I need a GC of this and
what a fine mess we've walked into folks
because all these potency labs
they've got HPLC UV vis as their their
method to do potency on your stuff guess
what d6 a and D 10 a may be sitting
under the same peak in their method so
they can't tell you the difference so
they can now say oh well it's d-10 a d6
a 10 a and 10 yada yada and
diastereomers and actually when this
product is formed it's actually not just
one compound it's two it's the right
hand in the left hand of d6 8na it's a
racemic so boy we've got cannabinoid
soup so I really hope that they can
figure out a way to redo their method so
they can see this stuff and top stop
telling everyone at CBC and if not well
I've got a GC method to sell them
I mean rats deck does sorry about that
okay so let's let's finish off with
acknowledgments I'm just gonna brush
over this really quick thank you all for
your patience god I talk forever
so basically here's who made it all
possible and if these guys Nate Rob Ron
and Matt hadn't been here I wouldn't be
up here Kurt didn't offer up there
because like I said I'm Spock well Kurt
is oftentimes Scotty and
check off and hora and everything else
including the captain sometimes and he
just does amazing things so I made my
make my scientific recommendation we
look into stuff and then as a team we
decide what we implement
okay so just here is a production team
Lindsey of course shelter project and
then over here is everybody else that I
just would like to specifically mention
and just a tie-in to our last proposal
you guys I wouldn't know anything about
cannabis as quickly as I did without
open sourcing and I'm gonna put this out
there and this is another reveal I am
going to put my new terpene technology
not Jetty's technology open source as
soon as I figure out how to scale so
y'all can hear yeah I'm gonna put it out
there I literally could not control
enough biomass in my dreams to make the
amount of cannabis drive terpenes that
people are going to want to use for
medicine and recreation so that's my
promise to you guys there's my email you
can follow us on IG at jetty extracts I
am at dr. Jack Hughes and it's been a
pleasure speaking to you guys and I'm
sorry I went over give it up for dr.
Wyatt Calloway
[Applause]