whoa dude
we're smoking weed and listening to
jimmy
oh
whoa what do you think
what do you think
yeah we look ridiculous
we totally look like we're smoking weed
right now
oh thank you i'm playing with stickers
and playing with stickers
see the crazy things it makes us do
it's gonna be it's gonna either be a pro
or anti-marijuana video baby girl
when you smoke marijuana you
you play with stickers
you put stickers on each other look i'll
put it on you now you put it on me put
it on me yeah pat pat pat
thank you
oh no it got stuck to your hand
dude
look
it's stuck to the bottom of your foot
and you're gonna freak out
usually you freak out when it sticks to
the bottom of your feet oh yeah and are
you even putting it there
pat pat pat
gemma smell your feet smell your feet
oh yeah
can i smell
i love the smell of you oh you want me
to smell that one too i'm sorry i didn't
i didn't mean to me i didn't mean to
leave that one left oh you want me now
you want me to go back to the first one
[Laughter]
[Music]
okay you're not getting tired of me
the oh one
okay okay i'm done smelling feet
although they are pretty amazing
thank you for giving me both feet
multiple times i appreciate it yeah no
they were awesome they smell really good
they smell really cute oh okay
thank you
thanks for the smell
uh-oh
what are you gonna do
oh you're not done okay
why don't you just put your feet okay
okay i will smell i will smell
[Laughter]
you're very abusive when you look at
what you want
[Music]
oh my god that is the cutest i chew ever
ah
aye
am i ready
what do you say
oh apple now you want apple no we went
through this before
i love how you know how to say apple and
achoo as separate and distinct words
but you know what the last time you made
me get an apple all you did was
yeah all you did was chew it and then
spit it out and i would have to like
dive and catch it as it
came out of your uh mouth because one
would never know when it was gonna next
come out of your mouth
that was fun for everybody right
i had fun
high stress moments like that
or
you found my beer fortunately it's not
up but it's still cold baby girl i
totally forgot
that i have so earned how about ah
have i earned this beer
[Music]
you have not earned any beers today
you've earned like treats and stuff
because you brought the cute today
the gun over there
me
i got to beware
oh
ow
what's that sound
are you climbing on me again
hey
when everybody is wrong
what's that sound everybody look what's
going down
[Music]
oh yeah let's eat the stickers ready
i'm always nervous that you're gonna
like bite my
nose off so you do like to bite
you
you are a biter
you get
great joy out of biting
[Laughter]
you get giggly
[Music]
when i was saying you're easily amused
with
the simplest of things over oh wait now
what are we gonna do you up what do we
do
because like
why don't you just spit yours on me
thank you
where'd it go
okay thank you
[Music]
all right
you got
what's next
she's back
sitting on me
so you know anything is one of your
favorite activities right now
sitting
exploring the many different things one
can sit on
you find a lot of unusual objects to sit
on
when we're in stores you'll sit on
pretty much anything
bottom shell empty bottom shelves you'll
try to stick your butt in
alright
oh thank you okay
so anyway that was seven minutes and
the life of baby girl and bubba on a
sunday afternoon
while it's just starting to get sunny
out after raining all day long
and i'm debating whether we should go
outside of the park or
i guess we could it hasn't rained in a
while it's supposed to rain again but
anyway all right