I'm mr. sole creator of Cinderella 99
and the founder of Brothers Grimm seeds
Rick we were talking about basically the
Rosetta Stone and how you at first
achieved getting it and it kind of would
you like to talk more about that story
it's yeah I think it's a good one
because when people see that it's
popular now it's been in the news and
highly-rated like that you want to know
well more about it right and another
interesting wrinkle to the whole story
was back when Brothers Grimm first
started in the late 90s around 2000 I
think it was I released a rosetta stone
but it was a different formula but I
loved the name so much and I found the
new combination that I put together this
time to be something that I thought
would eclipse the old version and people
would just forget about that one and say
or maybe never have heard of it you know
because it's been such a long time well
the old version did make it into the big
book of buds and for a lot of
connoisseurs in the early ages that was
our biblical standpoint for genetics I
mean it's it definitely turned some
heads well that was one of the sisters
that came from the bud of Jack Herer
from Amsterdam where Princess and genius
came from and there was a third female
that I called cafe girl and she had a
ginger ale flavor and so that rosetta
stone original combination had that type
of a profile and people liked it
apparently more than I ever realized and
so when I created the new version of
rosetta stone I liked this I repeatedly
have the jack harries original cut that
was presented to him of the Jack Herer
strain from sin sea seed bank and ben
dronkers supposedly gave this cut to
to Jack Herer himself so I love that
female and crusted to my best Cinderella
99 reversed and so we have a feminized
rosetta stone now it also we also do it
in the regular but that's how that came
about and it's a amazing improvement
upon the parents you know I really like
to think that whenever I put a seed line
out if something that isn't just the
same as one of the parents it has to be
an improvement has to have some reason
for being and so in the case of rosetta
stone I have if you could kind of put it
in a nutshell to say it's Jack Herer
flavor and high but in a much bigger
yielding faster flowering more stable if
you will in other words more uniform
plants come out of every pack of seeds
than you would ever expect from a real
the old school Jack Jack Arab so that's
what I've been doing lately and well I
did recently grow the Cindy 99 and I was
very impressed people are still coming
back to me all the time of course and I
never will tire of hearing the stories
old and new of people who say you know
I'd always heard about Cinderella 99 now
it's available again as a you know is it
the same and how did you do it and you
know they have to answer all those kinds
of questions and explain to people and
you and I have talked about how by still
having the original clone of Princess
that that's the mother that creates the
seeds and we were talking earlier about
when you create a seed line that really
works you should maintain that same
mother and father and use them over and
over as like a formula to create that
seed or a recipe that a chef would use
or something and some people get a
little confused with breeding and they
think that well those seeds were great
you know and I want more of them and
maybe I should cross a brother or sister
from those seeds but that's not the same
thing as going back in breeding those
seeds from the original parents so
what I did to recreate Cinderella 99 is
having that original female not having
the original male but having the seed
pact that the original male came from
and then regrowing them and finding a
new male that would be a brother of the
original one it's not a very big
difference and in the end I feel that
the Cinderella ninety-nine today just
stands up every bit as good as the old
one did because they're virtually
identical you know so I love to get that
feedback from people that they will say
wow I didn't think that after all this
time it would be possible to recreate a
seed line and you know done right yeah
it's very possible so we've seen that
around the industry too especially with
a lot of reputable reputable breeders
with their older genetics not producing
the same quality for different phenols
are actually coming out to 30 40 all
kinds of different numbers that have
just destabilized not necessarily their
brand but definitely that genome the
uniformity of the plants you're getting
out of a pack of seeds is influenced a
lot by the variability on both parents
sides you know and then it just makes
more of a lottery ticket you know out of
each seed that you're getting because
all those genetic possibilities coming
together creates a variability but by
having parents that are the same as well
as not having a lot of variability in
their own gene backgrounds you know
you're going to really ensure that
you're gonna get the same thing every
time reliably right which might not be
that important to some people because
there are a lot of people who believe
like oh I like to buy you know a bunch
of seeds and have a thino hunch and look
for something special out of that group
well now nothing wrong with that if
that's your goal but many people are
really serious minded professionals
coming into this and saying well I want
to grow a crop and I don't want to have
to try
you know do a lot of guesswork or
testing before I find the plant that I'm
going to reproduce and clone and make
for production so they would like to be
able to say isn't there a reputable
place where I could buy packs of seeds
where they're going to perform as
advertised on the description on the
pack
you know and I can count on you know
nearly all the females being the exact
same thing and that's what I try to do
you know that's what I have on the
market and that's why my menu consists
of maybe what eight strains is twelve if
you count the feminized versions of the
regulars or something like that because
I feel keeping control over a smaller
menu of strains is a lot smarter than
trying to keep up with fads and whatever
is popular now and chasing that sort of
thing I have heard of us they call it
the Hedgehog effect right or the
Hedgehog principle that Hedgehog has
only like one defense but it's a perfect
defense and so when you have that one
thing that you do really well
concentrate on that specialize in that
so well I like the way that you do that
because ultimately with that kind of
destabilization we see a lot of limits
hitting the market and really that's
almost a lazy man's breed and in a sense
you'll get great things out of it and
it's not always that way but if that's
your business then ultimately if you're
a one-and-done there's no real art to
that the real artistry in breeder ships
comes to the long-term stabilization and
the recreation of your genetic to make
it a timeless genetic and that's what we
see with you that I've really enjoyed
when we've cracked the Cindy
ninety-nines I saw three different fie
nose out of 20 seats and that's what you
expect out of a regular seed pack back
in 1995 1998
I mean these are things we don't see in
today's market and the other thing
that's important about when you do have
slight variations in the Cinderella 99s
that it's really not anything that's a
major trait it's usually like awesome
color like this one got a little more
purple and this one didn't you know big
deal can you tell the difference when
you smoke it no you know so I'm
pragmatic
yes and I would say like that the things
that are most important the potency the
resin production you know the flavor
yield all those things should be a
really tight grouping right but then if
there's like okay this one had a little
more color of this or color who cares I
had a guy write me this is a funny story
I had an email from a guy who said I
really question whether these Cinderella
99 seeds that I got from this
distributor are real because he's still
in veg mind you you know he hasn't even
flowered the plants and already he's
convinced this can't be real Cinderella
99 why because the leaf serrations on
the edges of the leaves didn't look the
way he remembered them from the last
time which was like over 10 years ago or
something like you know hey your memory
is probably fault even even if you had a
photograph of it nobody breeds for leaf
serration uniformity I mean that might
vary all over the place in my whole
genetic traits but it's not necessarily
your goal inbreeding for that trait it
doesn't prove you know that it's one
thing or another when the breeder has
concentrated on creating finished
flowers of a certain quality
this is Kanak on so the that was
actually pretty cool to have him pop in
like that and drop a little reality
reality-tv effect on the whole interview
but yeah what was I saying
your that just maybe we were we were
basically talking about the phenotype
and how important it is that there's not
much variance because when I did say
that I had the three different fee knows
I had a teen females now mine doing what
slight differences were those three fee
knows it's like one was a little more
chunky and one was a little more
triangular with the bud formation and to
be honest they could have sat in the
same bag they had a very similar odor
and they were very very subtle and I
mean like single percentage changes on
the Rita this is what I'm trying to say
that was what my point was earlier when
I lost track of what I was talking about
but the really important characteristics
stay true throughout all the females you
get from a pack of seeds and that's
that's what I take pride in and I try to
do in all of my strains is give people
something that where you buy the pack
the seeds it's a uniform result that
it's as advertised on the description on
the pack
you know and there's and there's a
there's a place for that really
translating the old ways to the new days
and that's really a big important thing
that we don't have going forward we've
got a lot of people getting into this
game without we'll call it an under
education of what they're truly dealing
with they don't even have an association
to plants as people some of these these
folks and that is really the biggest
kind of connection to genetics that I
found when I can sit here and say these
two parents have kids well yes these
kids all look alike but if the mother
goes and has a child with somebody else
that kid may look completely different
and that goes back to what Rick was
saying about making sure that the
crossbreeding goes back to the original
parents because with that the
consistency of the genetic can stay more
true over time and to be totally direct
it's one of the only real safe lines in
this industry that is of a more
naturalized methodology to get that
consistency and to be totally direct the
more natural we can remain in this the
more healthy it remains as well so I
have a great respect for the way that
Rick does his genetics
one of the reasons I'm a long time
runner-up I appreciate that
I'm really looking for terpenes and so a
lot of my terpene inductions have been
kind of moving into the higher THC
strains one of the things that you'll
see in a lot of the 30% plus strains is
yes they're 30-plus they'll knock you on
the floor whatever but they're gonna
have a very waxy overtone in most of
these strains and it's very rare to get
one over 30 with strong terms and so
that's kind of something that we've been
working on breeding in and it's been a
project of mine and to be honest I'm not
sure the limitations yet so it's it's
been an exciting adventure that's a you
know very ambitious and bold thing to be
diving into so kudos to you to be even
trying that and I think that just
touching back on I don't want to make
this all about you know mr. soul and his
strains or you know the best thing or
anything like that because in fact
what's happening currently with this
wave of lots of variety and different
hybrids and so on is that it exposes all
the possibilities there are in cannabis
and maybe the person who created the
strain if he's humble and honest with
himself says you know hey I'm no great
breeder but I lucked into something you
know I lucked into something at the
beginning but then inspired me to learn
more and work harder over the next few
years and so on but the benefit to the
public that's out there that's now
coming into this and saying well hey I
have a choice I can go with like the
gentleman said earlier agricultural
standardized kind of mentality for
buying seeds where you get what is
advertised and expect to get you know
uniformity and the seeds that you grow
and so on and then there's this other
opportunity or a possibility that's out
there for people to say hey I could also
go for the grab bag you know like hit
who knows what I'm going to get and it
might be wonderful and I see a lot of
strange stuff come up and very little
who really said it makes me sad sit back
and take notice and say alright that's
something I
know more about but people know in the
past year so I've gotten interested in
the Mack from Kappa later and I really
think that that's in all my 30-some
years or whatever in this business it
stands out in a way that I sit up and
take notice and there's not many that do
that so if it really yeah I couldn't
yeah look why good question that's the
great following the the terpenes the
aromas from it are really unique and
different and very to me desirable and
there are strains like Gorilla Glue that
you know you'll never forget Gorilla
Glue after you smell it once and it's a
really amazing heavy-hitting I call it a
heavy strain it makes me sleepy it
knocks me out it's like a couch lock
kind of smoke Josey Wales and the the
group from Gigi they called himself Gigi
strange now right that's a heavy strain
but the aroma to me is so gassy and
heavy that I wouldn't want to have that
all the time you know and and that's the
thing with the turkey strains is there a
double-edged sword because they will
mark you for life but you can't sell
them every day or it can ingest them
every day
I find it a little yet almost
heavy-handed a little over overpowering
but that Mac maybe I'm the sucker for
like subtleties and lots of notes in my
nose like wow what is that I can't quite
put my finger on it and that's how this
max train strikes me in terms of my nose
it's all about like wow what is that I
feel like I sense something familiar but
I can't quite put my finger on it I've
called it like play-doh like when you
were a kid you open up a new jar of
play-doh it's got that strange salty
kind of bicarbonate smell yeah but also
with like a floral fruity thing going
through
I mean it's just so sweet I'm not gonna
lie there was a time when I grew up
where I ate play-doh so I could there
are happy tones to it and I didn't mean
to make it sound bad by saying that
because no I think play-doh is a great
as I recall it was a lovely aroma so
anyway so your question was what about
the Mac attracts you so much the aroma
is just to die and then the the plant
itself when it's growing that grows
rock-hard nugs that are both like
sparkly with resin as well as like
purple splashes come out and it flowers
a little long it's probably 65 to 70 day
you know but that's not exceptionally
long either for what you get but the
yield is so amazing in the sense that
the buds are so dense that when you
harvest the cola that is of a certain
length in diameter and you compare that
to the say another col of a different
strain of the same length in diameter
the density on the Mac is so much
greater it'll weigh for example I
usually dry cure and trim my weed and
put it in mason jars as many people do
and then you'll weigh the mason jar when
it's completely full and a typical jar
is like 60 grams when it's full the Mac
I've had it hit like 90 grams when the
jar is false yeah half again now 50%
crater just to go from 60 to 90 you have
to take 50% of 60 and add to it right so
that's a 50% increase in density over a
typical strain so that pays you back big
time on your investment of having grown
it and that when it hits the shelf and
it's weighed and sold
you've got gold there right and add that
to the fact that it looks super
desirable and smells super desirable and
the high is sublime and lovely it's not
a sleepy high it's not like an energetic
I just drank two two shots of espresso I
have the Durban tie and that's what I
use for Derbent I see 99 and that one if
you smoke the pure Durban tie
it's like you just shot of espresso and
you're running around waxing the
ceilings and yeah that's where the race
enos comes from see you know I always
say my sending 99 is really nice and
heady but it's also like a really wonky
cup of coffee and you know it's one of
my favorite daytime smokes as a result
Cinderella 99 was always known for that
you know in those days you didn't find
too many strains where it gave me that
up high and the energy boost but that
definitely as well back then they were
also associated with being lower THC
volumes when they gave you that feeling
which today's market actually and with
the help of your breeding techniques it
kind of astounded Lee changed that resin
production the expectation for resin
production is so much of a higher bar
now you know it's been raised a lot from
the days like in the 90s or whatever but
Cinderella it's funny I've seen some
really great posts where people go
there's nothing outdated about this you
know I thought that wasn't the cutest
things they could say but I should get
back to the booth because there's people
sure sure they're coming to buy seeds
and I'd like to be there for that