[Music]
I would like to first we have chairwoman
Tina Braithwaite she she is joining us
from a - not - way to Paiute Tribe and
she has been remarkable in working with
C naka and a be 924 which we'll be
seeing about this evening we have Dave
Yelp and oh who I visited some years
back he was very kind letting me visit
his facility he's the executive director
of the cannabis regulatory agency for
the Santa Isabel Botanical Center he
also has another title for the Gaming
Commission he has 35 years in law
enforcement experience he brings to the
table he's also a published author
Ariel Clarke attorney with Clark
Newburgh Clark nubert farming it she's a
founding partner and we have max legal
onus he's our guest of honor this
evening bill ad 924 was brought to
legislature by Bonta who he previously
worked with as a member of the staff
he's daft prop 215 and has been no
Merstham occur so you staff Marissa
Marissa and has been instrumental in
drafting regulations himself he's also a
legislative advocate and a dear dear
friend we're so grateful to have you all
here thank you very much thank you I
want to talk a little bit about why
we're discussing Native American
cannabis in the regulations as they
stand it is required that tribes
renounce sovereignty to be a part of our
legal cannabis industry now if you're
aware of history in any sense you might
feel a sentiment that that is a
disrespectful request like a song or she
is very important for all of us and
especially tribes
when I first saw this in the regulations
I was very much dismayed
I spoke with everybody here and
mentioned that in writing a press
release for our panel this evening
I started look through some of the
issues that I've been following for a
few years now jurisdiction is a major
issue in addressing how we will
facilitate operations for cannabis with
tribes outside of the state regulatory
authority and that's a difficult nuance
there's also public law 280 which talks
about again who manages jurisdiction in
terms of federal law local law tribal
law there are very complicated issues
but in the very simple context we're
going to present to you this evening
that you have a vested interest in
supporting Native American cannabis and
tribes as being a part of this industry
potentially cultivating doing lab
testing distribution to our licensed
retailers and there are opportunities
for revenue for the state we're also
going to talk about what the
possibilities are for legislation y89 24
didn't work and what kind of solutions
we can put in place how we can affect
policy to make changes for the future so
with that I'm going to start just by
asking our panelists if you all would
each speak to the this point how how do
the tribes feel about cannabis industry
are they ready for cannabis industry are
there are there tribes that maybe aren't
ready or feel apprehensive as them right
now cannabis has been a part of tribal
industry in Washington since 2015
so California's had some time to look at
this the tribes have had to some time to
look at this what has the initial
response spin and has it adapted over
time I'll start with chairwoman you know
Braithwaite hi hi thanks for having me
my name is Tina Braithwaite and I am the
tribal leader of the Benton Paiute Tribe
we're 40 miles east of Mammoth Lakes up
in the Sierras and we have the first
state recreational dispensary on our
tribal lands we opened for 20 2017 and
since we've opened we have not had any
incidences on our tribal lands at all as
far as our dispensary
when we first legalized and passed
cannabis on our tribal lands we have out
of a hundred and forty tribal members we
had five notes
we were able to educate our people on
the positive side of cannabis and what
it's doing for not just our people but
people across the nation especially with
the opioid crisis you know our
government they feed people opioids
every day and get them addicted so I
believe that opioids are the entrants
drug and cannabis is the exit drug and I
have approximately 15 elders on our
reservation we make a topical with
cannabis through that topical it has
eliminated a lot of their opioid use and
now I have elders from other
reservations that have been asking you
know they come out to our dispensary
they purchase their products and they
leave we haven't had no issues with law
enforcement we have our own regulatory
body they regulate us sometimes I think
they over regulate us but we are in a
better situation than you all no offence
California who would have thought that
California would be behind Nevada when
Nevada ten years ago you went to jail
for six months for internal possession
and now here we are California was
supposed to be the leader in cannabis
and they're way behind Nevada but you
know hopefully the state will get to
where they need to be you know we've
just you know been doing our own thing
we manufacture we grow we manufacture we
have extraction and we send out all of
our products for testing to this nice
gentleman and his facility and we make
sure that our packaging we try to mirror
the state as close as we can you know so
that we don't have any issues and the
state they've been that the counties
have been real respectful the states
they haven't been to too good to us you
know they locked us out of the industry
we have no legal pathway and we're
forced to do a nation a nation right now
we cannot sell into the California legal
market which is it's you know it's awful
because you know we have you know we
support our own people you know we have
we're government's we have you know our
obligation our reservations our people
and you know so we're just doing what we
need to do when we're creating our own
tribal market thank you i as well I'd
like to thank thank you all for the
invitation as Cortney mentioned I'm
executive director for the tribal
cannabis regulatory agency for the IPE
nation of Santa Isabel it's a tribe on
fifteen thousand five hundred acres
about nine hundred and eighty some odd
members in East San Diego County a
little town of Julian San Isabel that's
where we're at in rural San Diego County
the question was what's the position of
tribes in cannabis I also serve as
executive director for the California
Native American cannabis Association see
NACA us is our website if you'd like to
visit
we have 23 member tribes you know the
myth is that tribes across the country
particularly in California are rich off
of gaming right we make a lot of money
off of gaming
well the tribes that are interested in
cannabis
primarily or tribes that don't see
revenues from gaming they've been
marginalized into rural areas such as
this bishops such as Death Valley for
timber Shoshone or rural San Diego
County as ours is we don't have Gainey
we don't advocate you know we had a
casino I was a chairman they gave me
Commission up until we closed it in
February of 2014 so the myth is that
tries to make money off of gaming that's
just not the case for most of the
hundred and ten tribes in California and
sanaka we have 23 member tribes only
three of those tribes are gaming tribes
and they're exploring cannabis
absolutely it's an economic development
opportunity for tribes but most tribes
that are interested in cannabis like bet
and pie you'd like santa isabela are not
gaming tribes and we're not making money
we're not making money from a lot of
things and so canvas is an opportunity
for Santa Isabel we've been in this
business almost three years as soon as
the Wilkinson memmer memorandum came out
the tribe took a look at its
constitutional process passed the law
passed an ordinance created a regulatory
agency and we're now just south of 50
million dollars of non-tribal tenant
money invested in developing our
facility at Santa Isabel we have nine we
call them tenants nine enterprises
separate enterprises non-tribal owned
enterprises three of those are
manufacturers one is an organic waste
processor one is a certified testing lab
and I heard you talking about testing
regulations we predate the state of
California in every single area of
cannabis regulations including
laboratory testing so you said there's
one lab no no there's two the other ones
at Santa Isabel now they can't get state
licensed unfortunately due to the
bureaucracy here in the state and
intransigence but it is testing all the
way through the state's level three
regulations that we adopted over a year
ago we're doing it now we have an
organic waste processor for cannabis way
and the rest are cultivators and right
now as we said if all that cultivation
space were occupied with plants we'd be
looking at a quarter million plants
right now today so the tribe has a
substantial investment in cannabis we're
regulating 24/7 your Bureau of cannabis
control how offered how often are they
at your property we're there 24/7 I have
a regulatory staff that's there right
now because our facilities 24/7 we have
a 24/7 Mann surveillance room Mann
surveillance room not just the server
the DVR servers but live people watching
everything that's going on
bs is certified security guards armed
and unarmed our pesticide regulations
transportation regulations
laboratory testing regulations cannabis
race regulations as I mentioned predate
the state of California we're very
serious about this as many other tribes
in California the unfortunate thing is
when we get to talking about a benign 24
the state has thrown up a roadblock to
tribal participation in the California
cannabis market and this isn't a
government lesson but let me tell you
what sovereignty is the tribes it's like
asking a person to give up their
identity who you are as a person who you
are as a people we want you to give that
up and defer all of your culture all of
your laws all of your regulation all of
your government to the state of
California there's three political
subdivisions mentioned in the
Constitution the feds the state and
tribes says nothing about cities does
nothing about counties right we're on
par with the state the state should be
negotiating in a respectful
government-to-government basis for
tribal participation in the cannabis
market so let me explain to you an
answer your question how serious tribes
are Tina alluded to it we're creating a
tribe to tribe market what does that
mean for you while santa is about we
already have a handful of tribes
very close to us in some faraway who
want to be the recipients of that
manufactured and cultivated product that
we're now producing on our reservation
they're going to be selling it they're
going to be selling it to California
citizens now Santa Isabel Saint mention
we have a very robust regulatory
framework but imagine that there's a
tribe out there that says you know what
who needs regulations we can do anything
we want on our reservation no pesticide
testing no laboratory testing no child
proofing no ingredient levels help
customers come to our reservation
we'll sell you whatever you want so what
the state of California has created by
keeping tribes out of this market is a
tribe to tribe market with some robust
regulation like Benton Paiute or Santa
Isabel and possibly less than robust
regulation that actually puts California
citizens at risk those consumers at
risks that's what the state of
California has created tribes aren't
going to walk away from this market
we're in it too far there's too much
money involved so there will be a tribe
to tribe market know by the way none of
the revenues generated from those
transactions go to the state of
California we don't participate in that
all of that money comes to the tribe and
tell me that we aren't going to be able
to offer our product a whole lot cheaper
than anyone else in the state of
California so we're pretty serious about
cannabis all right Dave you covered a
lot of topics here one testing Truman
Braithwaite and I discussed that with
lab testing we now have a blockade where
in order to be testing with a licensed
facility in the state of California you
need to be a licensed entity so there's
some complications there obviously
they've found a solution by testing in
San Isabel Botanical Center you also
touched on how you're approaching this
in respect to the ability to distribute
to the state market so now we have an
institution where the tribes are working
together and what does that mean
the greater the greater enterprise that
we have within the state of California
if you are not complying with
regulations you're creating your own
regulations there's something to be
noted in fact that historically the
federal government questions whether or
not tribes could govern themselves and
the gaming tribes showed that that was
definitely possible and the Santa Isabel
Botanical Center has shown itself to be
regulating beyond what the state
requires
in one instance Dave and I discussed
that there was a dispensary in San Diego
a state-licensed dispensary and one of
the inspectors came in and said every
product on this shelf is failed
compliance except for this one and it
came from Santa Isabel Botanical Center
so the tribes are showing that not only
can they meet the needs but they can
also regulate the on what is required
for the state we also should address how
we are approaching this in terms of the
money that you mentioned so in
Washington for example this is going
back to sovereign nations creating a
compact in Washington the state
government and the tribes came to an
agreement and they said ok we don't
necessarily want people going to the
tribe and getting or the reservation and
getting a deal because we're concerned
about how that's gonna affect the state
market so they came to an agreement and
they said ok everybody's gonna charge
attack the state will charge this amount
and the tribes will charge on par but
the money that the tribes charge will go
back to the tribes and then they're able
to use that money to support economic
development which is one of the reasons
that we're talking about this because
we'd like for the tribes to have that
opportunity so with that money chair
when chairwoman Braithwaite and I
discuss that she had proposed the
possibility of a healthcare system for
the tribes where the descendants would
have access to the healthcare system and
in addition it would release a burden on
the state and here in California we have
what some would call a welfare state so
any opportunity
that burden would be welcomed chairwoman
Braithwaite could you potentially talk
to us about what your what your
challenges were there what you proposed
and then maybe max can talk to us about
what those issues are surrounding that
and why potentially that wasn't an
avenue for us to take okay so in the
beginning when we tried to get that
government-to-government consultation
with the governor's office and we were
refused we tried to create a program
where the tribes with charge attacks
equal to the state and those taxes will
go into a pot like the rst of monies and
they would be used for healthcare
hospitals in California there's not one
Native American Hospital in California
that IHS facilities that's the Indian
Health Services the federal government
claims they have a federal trust
responsibility to the tribes for health
care well where 400 years from now where
we'll see our first Indian Health
Services facility clinic excuse me
health clinic built in California so we
were trying to in the beginning create
that health care system for all Native
American people whether you were
enrolled member of California or not you
could be Cherokee you could be you know
sue wherever but if you could show that
you were Native American and you lived
in California you could go and be
treated at these health facilities for
free health care hospitals mental health
substance abuse aftercare which really
lacks in this country there's no
aftercare education elders programs
youth programs and we were going to try
to create after like a treatment not a
treatment but like a halfway house type
program for the Native American
prisoners that come out of the federal
prisons they could come in they would be
in a transitional house for 90 days get
on their feet get their birth
certificates their driver's license get
a job 90 days they would transition out
you know into their new you know
on their feet and on their way just to
try to help you know our Native American
people but that got killed in the
beginning the state you know there was a
lot of kickback from that nobody wanted
to do it it was like who's gonna manage
that program you know there was like how
are we gonna do that you know and then
the state just you know it just got
pushed to the side you know if we could
have created that structure how could
the state have said no to us we would
have took a burden off of the state
financially because every Native
American in this state would have been
eligible not to mention their
descendants and you know because right
now if you're a descendant of a tribe
and you're not readily recognized you
don't even qualify for education you
know you're just you you can apply for
grants but they want you to be a
federally recognized Native American so
you know we could have helped our own
people you know created our own health
care system but it got kicked out and
you know it's really unfortunate that
you know nobody really thought that that
would be a positive thing for you know a
win-win for the tribes and the state
well if I can just add one thing to what
Tina mentioned just so you understand
where tribes are at tribes are some of
the poorest communities in California
with the highest rates of unemployment
one of our counterparts Stuart Golson
that chairman from temperature Shoshone
didn't miss any opportunity at the
legislature with meeting with the
legislature around a benign 24 to
explain that our community is so poor
that we have to pass the Hat just a bury
our dead and and you know from gaming
there's a thing called / kappa / kappa
is where you take the revenues from the
tribe you divide up by tribal members
and each tribal member gets a check it's
San Isabel when we structured our
statute we put a prohibition on any per
capita means every single dime generated
from cannabis by the tribe went to
tribal infrastructure and government
services much as Tina mentioned even my
fines and penalties fund because we do
fine are our tenants when they violate
the regs goes
the tribes general fund that's allocated
for drug prevention and use skill
building programs
none of that fine money even comes the
regulatory agency it goes for tribal
infrastructure sorry I started working
on tribal cannabis and work primarily on
terrible cannabis when I was working in
the state legislature
I've been lobbying for a year and a half
now for case three consulting K Street
does have tribal clients as in casino
tribes as well as we have one tribal
cannabis business that's on Isabel
territory and so we have you know those
angles but then from going back to the
beginning working on the first tribal
cannabis bill the one remarkable thing
was that how how divisive the issue was
and how when we had all these different
state goals made the League of Cities
with the police chiefs we had the United
Food and Commercial Workers and the
Teamsters labor unions we had CCIA the
cal growers we have whomever else and
and also all the county organizations
that station State Association of
counties the rural counties urban
counties this issue United everyone else
like no other issue and Arab League
United them in opposition because every
single other stakeholder saw some waving
beliefs from allowing this to happen and
integrating this into the state
marketplace fundamentally the state and
federal rules and laws and jurisdictions
are different on tribal land and the non
cannabis specific rules you know will
apply in different fashions I have a
brief example on labor laws there is
currently I think federal litigation and
stuff that's gone up to the Supreme
Court if I recall over that whether you
can go and organize workers on tribal
land or to what degree they follow the
NLRB process
organizing so it's fundamentally a
different creature and it's
fundamentally a different system of
governance beyond cannabis and because
of that it's so incredibly difficult to
fit cannabis regulations into a tribal
box or to fit tribal sovereignty into a
state cannabis regulations box and what
I appreciate admire about what the
chairmen are what the chairwoman and
what suhaka has done is a bee 924 really
eliminated and worked with all the
opposition I listed before and bring all
of them you know if not you know some
support many neutral and as close to not
opposing as they could and they did a
really admirable job crafting that
compromise and yet it still got torn
apart and it still got rejected by the
committees and with without really
understanding the steps and hard work
that gone into it I feel the feeling
wasn't recognized the one thing is that
next year we have a new governor we have
a new legislature some legislative
changes for more so we have a new
governor and I am hopeful that the next
administration will be willing to engage
more actively and thoroughly and early
on rectifying this tribal cannabis issue
and trying to solve it and trying to go
come up with the compromise than the
last one get when Ariel Clarke started
her career she didn't nnq focus her
efforts on tribal law some attorneys
spend their whole lives just completely
focused on this one subject this is
quite complicated and Ariel's been
working with the California in Native
American Association she understands
what some of these issues are she is
Native Americans can you speak to us
about some of the issues that we're
facing in regards to Native American
cannabis in the state of California and
what some of the issues are that we
should address
in creating a pathway forward thank you
so much um so our i-i've been focusing
also on cannabis and we work with a lot
of growers and dispensary operators and
lots of people who are in the cannabis
industry and then I also have a
background in Indian law and we work
with tribes on developing their tribal
cannabis programs and this intersection
between tribes in California and
cannabis is one that I just want to take
a moment to kind of talk about what this
looks like we all know that California
is the fifth largest economy in the
world nearly half of the cannabis market
is in California there are a hundred and
ten tribes in California and thousands
of acres are within the jurisdiction of
California Indian tribes these tribes
have been here since the beginning of
time I talked with an elder larry
benegas who actually passed away a
couple of weeks ago who really was
involved in cannabis and healing for
Native people and he told me that
cannabis has been used in California
amongst the native people for thousands
and thousands of years so here I am
maybe I don't know I started working
with cannabis businesses in 2005 and
encouraged all of my clients to support
regulations and pass a whole series of
laws in California so that we could have
a regulated cannabis market and by the
way grow cannabis on land and sell
cannabis on land that are the I'm a I'm
from Michigan my tribe is in Michigan
but that are on these people's lands and
the absolute outrageousness that tribes
in California do not have the
opportunity to enter into the regulated
market and sell into and sell between
tribes
and the California cannabis you know
that the larger commercial market is
completely outrageous other states have
figured that out through a compact model
tribes clearly I mean listen to what
Dave has said it and and and and
chairwoman Braithwaite as well tribes
can clearly regulate themselves
incredibly well we and with these two
and many other people involved in
Senecas efforts and other folks went
kindly went to the state of California
and said look we will you know here's
here's a way that we can work together
on this and that has been rejected and I
also I have to say max your statements
about you know this unifying issue it's
really amazing
I saw people clients of mine who were
California cannabis operators be deathly
afraid of tribes getting into cannabis
because they looked at it like tribes
will have some sort of edge on the
market or these operators that are on
tribal land will have an edge and that's
unfair to me
and you know I'm think looking at this
guy and thinking you hmm
you care about your stakeholders so much
and you don't understand or let me
hopefully I can help educate you and and
help you understand how this will
benefit these communities where
literally most people are at or below
the poverty level like when when do we
decide that being completely
self-interested and money obsessed is
something that is like maybe not the
move forward globally you know and when
we've had these opportunities in this
state to create laws and rules and
regulations in a culture and this is
what's happening is really a pourraient
so on that happy note the reaiiy I
really I just want to thank you Courtney
so much and theater so much and
everybody for coming here and paying
attention to this issue I guess
I know I'm not really answering the
question but I just you know this is it
there is still an opportunity to create
some sort of change around this and I
fully support tribes having you know a
little bit of California if people can't
get it together and let the tribes I
mean not let you will and excellent and
I am cheering you on and so are we all
to have a very thriving cannabis market
but let me also say this for our clients
that our cannabis we represent a lot of
legacy cannabis operators in California
and what an opportunity it would be to
be able to think about it they're only
15% of cities and counties are giving
cannabis licenses so now I'm talking to
you guys who want to have a you know if
you aren't already licensed or you want
to expand your footprint in California
to have the opportunity to grow on
tribal land and these folks are you know
your your within their jurisdiction
under their very regulated whole a
tribal cannabis program there is a
massive opportunity when 85 percent of
the cities in counties in California you
guys don't give a shit about giving
cannabis licenses you have tribes that
are art would be very happy to open
those doors but there we need to have an
opportunity for those businesses to sell
into the regulated market so you know
when we think about sort of how do we
all win in situations that is is a nice
thing to think about with public safety
yes with having products that come to
California consumers that are tested and
well regulated but also opportunities
for businesspeople to potentially work
with tribes and our firm is works with a
number of tribes and and developers and
folks who are anyway all in the tribal
cannabis context so there's a lot here
so thanks for paying attention
so I just want to bring ease a few
moments where it might be really lovely
to go to the reservation and experience
cannabis
yes healing is very important medicinal
opportunities Native Americans hold
sacred the healing medicine of plants
I'm reading a book on Native American
plant medicine right now and it's
something we don't all know about
because it is sacred we don't get a hear
of all these matters there's also the
opportunity to go to a cannabis resort
there was a team in South Dakota that
wanted to put together a resort and it
was shut down by the local government
here in California we've had several
tribes that tried to create operations
and we're shut down
over the course of the last few years so
we're in a moment now where we're trying
to create a space where everybody is on
common ground and is happy and finding
solutions sharing women appraised it
would like to speak to this so as I said
earlier we're 40 miles east of Mammoth
Lakes up by Mammoth ski resort and we
are looking at doing a destination
resort cannabis friendly destination
resort where you can come and get a
cannabis in Hugh's massage you can maybe
have some cannabis cuisine maybe you can
have a cup of cannabis coffee with the
THC infused edible you know we're just
trying to get out there and do you know
some positive things around cannabis
because it's all about education you
know that stigma of getting high and you
know it's a it's a gateway drug you know
those days are gone
we just need to educate the public on
the Metis medicinal side and the healing
properties of cannabis CBD and you know
I I heard you guys's issues about those
the festivals and the consumption well
guess what we don't have those issues on
the reservations
so you know if you don't want to do a
music festival and consume a little bit
of cannabis by all means reach out to
some of these tribes because I'm sure
they'll be open to that as an event
producer I will go ahead and say yes we
already know whenever when it opens
absolutely absolutely okay so now that
we're all on board we all want to
support Native American cannabis what
are the solutions what can we do now to
create a space we know there were some
issues with a benign 24 not everybody
come to a good a good agreement on that
there were some issues some education
that needed to be happening also we
needed more panels like this do you
shine a light on Native American
cannabis and what we want it what's next
what are our next steps and how can we
all come together how can we convince
everyone that this is the Avenue this is
the pathway we can all work together
it's not it's not an infringement on the
existing owners and operators within
California it's not an obstacle for
those who wish to license their entity
it's an opportunity for all of us to
create a beautiful cannabis industry of
the future how do we get there what are
the next steps as of right now max
you're talking about next year we're to
have a new new government in place and
regards to legislation so we have some
new players what do we need to be
sending you there and say and you tell
them that we want Native American amis
what what are some of the issues that we
can address and how can we put everybody
on the same on the same a line of I was
the offense
well you can send me there but it's to
be determined what I can actually say
and and part of that is something we
haven't talked about as much in this
discussion which is there is all this
industry opposition or law enforcement
or local government or all the other
stakeholders they weren't cannabis
friendly or that weren't oil cans
friendly the other question though is
how are we getting or working with the
larger tribes and the large tribes
smaller tribe interactions there because
that you know my firm represents several
larger gaming tribes and for me to go to
work on this issue requires me to not
have a conflict on this issue it
requires me to educate and work with
those larger tribes so they recognize
and appreciate respect their work being
done and the goals of the smaller tribes
that don't have that I think just so I
think that's part of the big question
for me and with this is is the
engagement with the larger tribes along
with the engagement of the Newsom
administration from some conversations I
had with the state licensing authorities
maybe it's too close with the state
licensing authorities is that this rule
and tribal cannabis came from on high it
was a it was an order from the higher
levels of government than the state
regulators to go and put in their
regulations a waiver of sovereign
immunity a pathway to licensure for
tribes which isn't really a pathway
because of the labor and because the
local authorization requirements but
that wasn't their choice they didn't
have statutory supposed to thority to do
that and
ultimately we've got ultimately a new
administration can give a new order and
you don't change that conversation and
so I think that is it's about a a large
tribe strategy educational strategy and
a new sim administration strategy and
I'm fairly confident will be Gavin
Newsome and not Republican John Cox
because yeah certainly sanaka has a seat
at the table we are gearing up at the
end of the month to renew our efforts to
revive 9:24 or something like it for
those of you that don't know tri-c NACA
member types of 23 member tribes that
back nine twenty four were gave up a lot
there were a lot of compromises on
behalf of the tribes this woman
late-night rants what the hell are we
doing yeah beat up quite a bit but the
design was tribes agreeing to come under
the same regulatory framework as the
state as any other entity in the state
of California without having to give up
our civil regulatory authority and our
tribal sovereignty so the pathway is
convincing folks that a consistent
regulatory structure with the California
cannabis consumer first and foremost in
thought is in everyone's best interests
at the end of the day so when we first
started the negotiations when you know
with the state our main goal was to
preserve our sovereignty that was never
nothing was going to ever take away our
sovereignty because the way I explained
our sovereignty is if the governor of
California wanted to waive the rights of
every one of you people in the audience
he could not do that with
a vote of Europe of the people right
you cannot waive your rights he could
not waive your rights in California to
Nevada and say okay California residents
you're all you have no rights now
because I just waved them to Nevada
that's how sovereignty is with tribes we
are peer jurisdictions to the state we
are not below the state we are not below
the counties or the cities we are equal
to the states we are our own sovereign
nations so for us to waive sovereign
immunity was not even at the table we
cannot tribal leaders cannot just waive
our sovereign immunity with a signature
it doesn't work that way I would be hung
by my toes by my people so that was
never an option so we tried to preserve
our sovereign immunity at all costs we
did try to make a deal with the state
saying that all sales on reservation
tribes would keep those taxes once our
product leaves the reservation it goes
into the retail market then those taxes
will go to the state I'm like Washington
where if a product leaves the
reservation and well if a product is
sold on reservation Washington state
keeps those taxes and once the product
leaves the reservation and goes out into
the retail market those taxes go back to
the tribes we were not trying to do that
we were trying to be fair and allow
California to also get you know their
tax money and the states and the
counties will get their tax money but it
never worked that way you know we
weren't gonna set bad presidents by you
know allowing you know the tribes to
waive sovereign immunity and we did not
agree to the state coming into our
tribal lands and taxing our non tribal
investors and those taxes going back to
the state because those taxes need to
stay with the tribes anything that
happens in our sovereign nations need to
stay within our sovereign nations that's
the way it is we're not sitting back
presidents and yes I am the
the villain and all of this because I
said no we're not doing it and hopefully
the state we can educate them on tribal
sovereignty that tribes our governments
and that we ourselves have our own
people that we need to support and you
know through insurance and you know
programs essential programs substance
abuse we have all our own programs that
we need to support you know and you know
if we could do those things we would
take a big burden off the state you know
we would be self-sustaining the state
went we wouldn't have to worry about all
these poor tribes you know we would
support ourselves you know so that that
was real important to us to you know
maintain our integrity because at the
end of the day when we die that's all we
have is our name in our integrity and
you know if we start setting bad
presidents in Indian country you know
what does that say for our future
generations every decision we make right
now as a tribal leader affects our
future generations and if I waive
sovereign immunity for cannabis the next
thing I'm going to be waiving sovereign
immunity for this and I'm going to be
waiving sovereign immunity for that and
I'm not going to have sovereign immunity
and we won't have a sovereign nation
when my future generations you know are
leading our country our nation's so
that's why we said no I think that
you're touching on on something and
that's that there are matters here there
were actually bigger than cannabis
cannabis is bringing subject matter to
our cognition and saying you know these
are issues that have been here they've
been here for a long time and cannabis
is giving us an opportunity to look at
them and speak about them in public and
to the government and it leaves me to
point out that the climate for Native
American cannabis and cannabis in
general at the federal level has not
been supported in December of 2014 we
had the Wilkinson memo and when I read
it I interpret it to mean that given
certain jurisdictional concerns tribes
had sovereignty and they could cultivate
cannabis when I called the governor's
office and spoke to their
they are liaison for native or tribal
affairs I was told that they don't
interpret it in that way that to me was
a little bit of a trigger I was a little
bit taken aback by that that what seems
so simple to me and and I have studied
law
I was clinical science major in
University I'm not an attorney all my
best friends are attorneys but I'm not
an attorney so if I'm interpreting it
this way and it seems very
straightforward to me I'm surprised to
hear that the governor's office does not
support that as an interpretation so I
don't feel like the the big climate has
been very friendly to cannabis in
general but more so for a tribal
cannabis so I would say to anyone that's
watching for all of you that have taken
the time to join us here this evening
please do your part to support tribal
cannabis and our ability to not only to
purchase but also to distribute to test
and to find a way for all of us to work
together so that we can have a greater a
greater industry of tomorrow we have
probably a few minutes to take some Q&amp;A
before we do this is a very passionate
conversation that we're having when we
talked in private it would have been
much more dramatic so you're not
witnessing that here today we're really
toning it down but it's a very serious
issue for us we're grateful to have this
platform to speak to you all about it
does anyone have anything they'd like to
share before we reintroduce QA about how
we can create a legal framework or
create a space to bring another bill to
the table that succeeds so right now
there's a bill and it's a federal bill
it's called the s30 3 to senator
Elizabeth Warren is authoring this bill
and it's called it States Act I know a
lot of people aren't aware of this but
when the Wilkinson memo was rescinded it
didn't just affect the tribes that
affect everybody across the nation
because it's federally illegal
everywhere so what this bill is gonna do
for not just tribes but for everybody
if the state has legalized cannabis in
their respected states then the federal
government cannot come in and enforce
they cannot enforce and that language
includes tribes so once that if that
bill gets passed you know the big gaming
tribes are going to climb down off their
fence and they're gonna dive into some
cannabis because right now everybody's
fearing federal enforcement so if you
guys can you know see your way to
support that bill it's s 303 to
Elizabeth Warren is authoring it and you
know I think it would be a good positive
thing if we could get that passed I just
want to mention that in rescinding the
Wilkinson memo sessions recently the
Vulcan semi MO and the Cole memo in
doing so he gave all the district
attorneys the opportunity to decide
their own priorities for enforcement so
does anyone have anything they can speak
to you and we're going to sue our own US
district attorney and what the climate
is there so I went up and spoke with the
assistant US attorney in Sacramento
about three months ago and I was told by
him that we are not on his high priority
for enforcement list so you know they
have a lot of bigger fish to fry out
there they're looking at the bigger
cultivators so tribes aren't really I
mean we're on their radar they're
watching us but as long as we do what we
told them that we were do and follow and
regulate self-regulate we're testing
we're trying to mirror and be respectful
of the state even though they weren't
respectful to us we're still trying to
keep that you know we're testing we're
packaging you know labeling we're doing
everything to mirror the state as close
as we can we promised we wouldn't take
our product out of state you know so
we're being respectful in that way but
you know I mean they're watching they
know what's going on they know what
tribes are doing what and you know as
long as you know we do what we say we're
gonna do because like I said our
in our integrity you know that's
everything to us and you know if I have
I asked him when you know if you decide
you want to come down and enforce on my
reservation you don't need to come with
your 50 guns and your officers are
blazing just call me I'll come back to
Sacramento we'll have lunch we'll
discuss it like adults and you know but
don't come down there trying to act
badass because it's just not gonna work
for us but yeah so he was respectful in
that way sure so the three words the
watchwords that we used for our
enterprise and count in in Santa at
Sandersville collaborative cautious and
conservative we started very small we
move very slowly and we have an absolute
open-door policy when it comes to
properly credentialed law enforcement
state local or federal I came from law
enforcement 35 years I spent 20 years of
the Bureau of narcotic enforcement
probably targeting it anyway never mind
won't go there a lot of the folks a lot
of the law enforcement coats in Southern
California in the Southern District
where we're at in San Diego I know
firsthand they come up and visit we've
had DEA agents DEA investigators I just
had the sheriff's lieutenant for our
local region there two days ago because
we're team teaching a class at Pechanga
gaming class at Pechanga next week it's
it's just not that big a deal if you
stay within if you're a tribe and you
stay within the envelope that the state
has constructed even though state law
doesn't apply on the reservation we
found that if our regulations if what we
allow is consistent with what's allowed
in the remainder of the state we're fine
and so far with our US Attorney with our
DEA with our sheriff and other law
enforcement folks it's just not an issue
we're yesterday's news
and with that we can begin our QA anyone
have any questions for the panel I have
one here in the back and I'll paraphrase
your questions that everything here
sub-tribes will span multiple states so
in regard to the question we might ask
how are you transporting across state
lines
how are you potentially creating
distribution channels yeah that's easy
easy so if your tribe goes into two
states like say California and Nevada
you can actually open operations in
Nevada and in California you would have
to get a compact through Nevada
the governor has compacted with 27
tribes of Nevada so all you would those
the lands in Nevada would fall under the
structure of Nevada and then of course
you know you could do California but why
would you want to because probably so I
mean that's how it works whatever the
state if it's legal in that part of the
state where you know part of your land
is then I would if you were gonna do
that I would do the research to see what
what's the structure what's the what are
the state laws and you know how hard is
it you know to get it either a license
or your compact with regard to
transportation Sandersville we have a
prohibition on any cannabis from Santa
Isabel leaving the state of California
in fact it can only go to a jurisdiction
a dispensary of retail outlet that
allows cannabis so we don't even allow
our cannabis to go into local
jurisdictions that prohibit cannabis
with regard to the multi-state tribes
Santa Isabel consults for a number of
tribes tribes that are along the
California Arizona border Arizona is a
no cannabis state so our advice is
establish your commercial enterprise
within the state where it's legal not
within the state where it is not legal
because your
bound to garner the attention of the
federal government not the state
government but rather the federal
government if you're operating in the
state where it's prohibited
yeah Washington and Nevada and our
advice would be do what they did in
Oregon yeah in Oregon if we have all
these tribes across the nation what is
the opportunity for them to be unified
on for example regulations if the
federal government of the United States
is going to I think we all are on the
same page or that it's gonna happen
eventually if they're going to permit
legal cannabis there's gonna be statutes
that are uniform is there anything that
the tribes can do as sovereign nations
and win themselves to create a unified
platform in regards to regulations
public safety enforcement distribution
all the issues that we're facing here in
California and trying to and try to
trying to create a legal framework so we
formed the California Native American
California Native American cannabis
Association for California and we also
are in the process of creating a tribal
nations cannabis Association for tribes
across the nation so that we can all be
uniform we can all help each other set
each other up with policies and
ordinances and regulations and that way
we're doing it right you know tribes
want to just have the legal pathway we
want to do it right that's why we're
compliant with marrying this date as
close as we can
packaging testing flavoring all of that
so my vision is that if the federal
government makes this legal for tribes
that we can do a nation and nation
Network you know maybe I'm growing and
there's a tribe across the nation that
has is it a highly populated area where
they don't want to grow so that they can
dispense you know we all know how easy
it is I put our dispensary up in two
weeks I mean yeah it wasn't you know
where it needed to be but it is now but
I did what I call a pop-up dispensary
and we were off and running in within
two weeks we were had our revenue was
generating and yeah we had issues you
know as far as we did it and that's
where I see this going in the future is
tribes creating that tribal Network
nation a nation trying to you know
support each other and help each other
with the process so that we're doing it
all the right way I applaud the efforts
of su naka on trying to have the tribes
work together in a uniform and model
ordinances and such in Sacramento tribes
agree on very little they agree on
sovereignty sovereignty is an
overarching principle but in some of the
bills Eve worked on which should not
have been controversial there has been
one tribe is sponsoring a water bill for
example making a a specific change and
never try this concern about a precedent
that could set or infringement on
sovereignty or how it could go be
litigated out so well I applaud the
efforts to bring people together Green
tribes together from what we've seen on
the ground is there is a very fractious
and and not unified in opinions and so
if this can be a way for them to be
alignment that would be applauded
what are the implications for
reservations that allow cannabis when
they have a police department the tribal
police departments where the tribal
police officers have tools
I was actually one of those federal
agents when I worked so as I mentioned
we consult 10 Isabelle consults for
tribes we have our own Police Department
they are not federally cross designated
it's not an issue for us our advice to
tribes that have dual designated law
enforcement officers that they preclude
prohibit make sure that those officers
do not have anything to do physically
with the cannabis enterprise so there
isn't that conflict between enforcement
of federal law and the tribes statutory
authority to conduct cannabis business
so our advice is the rest of the
reservation not any patrols or respond
to calls for services within that
cannabis area what happens if one of
your transporters gets pulled over
California Highway Patrol been there
done that
there again and I'll answer the question
but just by way of instruction of where
the state is at as I mentioned we have
almost three years of experience
regulating in this space I've made at
least a half a dozen overtures to in
person to the chief of the Bureau of
cannabis Control Laurie Ajax who I knew
when she was at ABC I said look you guys
are just getting into this regulatory
business come on down to Santa Isabel
have a conversation with us because I
will tell you these cannabis operators
you guys are really creative about
getting around the rules and finding
those loopholes I'm writing regulation
almost every day to plug up those that
that innovation that you guys exhibit I
have yet to have the state take me up
and come down
although we have held classes we held a
week-long class for cannabis tribal
cannabis regulators we had a full room
but no one from the state will come down
and have a conversation with us about
regulating the space which is kind of
interesting the question was about
exportation so we have a very thorough
transportation permitting process
without boring you it's about six seven
pages long are and we have requirements
with the driver requirements for the
containers requirements for the vehicle
you know verification that the inventory
the shipment reaches its destination we
have had our transportations and I'm up
to sixteen sixteen thousand
transportations a cannabis product from
Santa Isabel in the past three years we
have been stopped by law enforcement CHP
local law enforcement they show the
transportation permits every single case
the officer said be on your way no
issues with law enforcement whatsoever
in the transportation of product all
right so in closing I'm just gonna go
down the line here and if you can just
give us just just a brief statement
about what the ideal policy would look
like for Native American cannabis in the
state of California
what would facilitate a greater cannabis
industry for Indian country and also
appease the powers within the state
government what does it look like what
is your what is your wish list for this
policy for this next legislative session
were to be possible what would what
would you like to see I would like to
see that legal pathway for tribes to be
able to enter into the legal cannabis
market with us tribes you know mere in
the state as close as we can be in
respectful and of all of the regulations
without having to waive our sovereignty
number one to be able to create our own
health care system for all Native
American people in California and to be
able to bring my tribe up to where we
are self-sustaining where we don't have
to rely on the federal government for
anything ever except to have our you
know
self-governance body and to be able to
you know just live in harmony and do
what we do because we are creating a
great product and you know we're doing
it just like all the other tribes want
to do they want to get into this market
and be self-sustaining and help their
people create programs short and sweet
for us the opportunity to play in a
level playing field and consistent
application of the rules whether it's on
tribal lands or off tribal lands if you
take a look at Sioux nacos website we
have our guiding principles and our
professional standards every one of the
23 tribes of Seneca has committed to
those guiding principles and
professional standards tribes want to do
it right those that are serious about
this business want to do it right and if
we had that mutually respectful
relationship with the state of
California and with operators off tribal
lands then those few tribes that decide
they can make a quick buck because they
don't have to create all of the
regulatory structure because
everything's on the reservation they'll
be outliers they'll be obvious and we'll
invite them out of this industry I said
and I would just like to add that I
think it would be really wonderful to
see a line of products cultivated and
manufactured on California tribal land
we're doing you know we're creating
Appalachians for cannabis growing in
different areas in California and it
would be really cool to see California
native trade association little like
brandings like little like stamps and a
very yeah a whole a whole line of
products from
tribal lands that would be really so you
know I understand the question Courtney
I'm not going to answer the question I'm
going to say you know I'm not sure we
talking really there right now there's
language in the regulations that says
the tribes that businesses on tribal
land can apply for a state license there
are the two biggest issues with that
there's a number of issues for the two
biggest issues with that language it is
twofold first there's a waiver of
sovereign immunity as previously
referenced which goes too far which
without consultation with tribes and
which is asking for tribes to subsume
themselves to cities to counties to the
state of California and it's very
problematic and so while this is
speaking individually completely for
myself it needs to be clear that the
business as opposed to the tribe whether
the business is waiving or choosing not
to have a sovereign defense placed by
the business compared to the tribe as a
whole and the tribes regulatory
functions and the tribes land use
Authority so there isn't that
distinction drawn right now and that
distinction could potentially in my own
personal view potentially alleviate some
of the conversations and concerns I
don't have to be the case but that's one
thing the second thing is this right now
the state only the state recognizes
cities and counties as local governments
the language in the regulations
essentially say if you want a tribal a
license in the state for cannabis on
tribal land you need city or county
approval for whatever surrounds that try
those counties do not have Sony approval
or land use approval on the tribes but
the state is asking them to regulate and
to have that authority which they do not
have if they try to do that they would
lose in court because it violates you
know if that violence the sovereignty
local controlled land use control of the
tribes in a ridiculous fashion so what
I'd like to do when I'm working on
trying to do and explain to the
regulators and those above them just
they thought they made a system that
works but it stinks it stinks because it
doesn't respect viable land use
authority and asks for an overly broad
waiver of sovereign immunity that
doesn't focus on the business aspects
itself versus the tribe as a whole I'm
just gonna piggyback off that and say
that yeah absolutely the tribe should
have should have the ability to retain
civil regulatory jurisdiction and and
and regulate cannabis we have seen with
one of the tribes that we're working
with the surrounding County bans
cannabis when we went into Polk with the
state the CDFA actually about whether or
what what impact that may have because
from our perspective the tribe of course
it doesn't matter that the county
surrounding it bans cannabis they have
no jurisdiction on tribal land we were
finally able to get some reasonableness
since well established law says that
counties have no jurisdiction on tribal
land so we are seeing some level of oh
hello awake and education around this
issue so I hope I hope that that you you
won't have to come up against that
because we've had that fight a little
bit so let's talk okay thank you
with that I will thank our panelists
each and every one of you I know that
you probably and gone through eight
plates to be here so thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]