the next person I'm going to invite up
is uh one of our sponsors tonight uh
National cannabis industry Association
otherwise known as ncia I'd like to
invite Curtis Stafford up here B bis Dev
for ncia and he's going to talk to you a
little bit about now thanks
Curtis thank you
Jackie um so my name is Curtis Stafford
I'm the head of Business Development for
the national cannabis industry
Association for those of you who are not
familiar with ncia we are the National
Trade Organization as well as the naal
lobing trip in DC um I sum that up in
kind of very easily in two ways we have
two main offices we have a Denver office
and a DC office the Denver office
handles Our member benefits our
associations affiliations State
organizations such as uh ccia the
California canus industry Association
amazing organization guys should be very
familiar with them um they have a
conference coming up in Anaheim in
September please check that out um but
anyways let's get to the point who here
thinks they're a good
person
[Music]
we I think you heard me say this before
all right so our attorney general Jeff
sessions says that good people don't
smoke pot who here still thinks they're
a good
person what do youall been
smoking who here thinks our industry
should have access to
banking who here thinks that our
industry should have the same rights for
uh tax deductions on the federal level
as any other industry
who here thinks that patience and
non-violent offenders should not spend
years in
prison so you guys all apparently think
the work that we're doing in DC is good
work because you're good
people I got of always say that ncia
we're kind of the bridge between some of
the nonprofits the local level and the
businesses it's an awkward place to be
sometimes but it's really the ability to
able to bridge that Gap and to make sure
that we're part of the community and to
hold our businesses accountable
as well as everyone else in the
community commandable on the same level
um if you guys have any questions about
our membership or anything else please
can find me I'll be in the back uh big
shout out to Jackie and everyone else
put on this event and uh support all of
your nonprofits from a local level all
the way up to the
DC