all right we're here with jacques and
amy from newcomb family farms jacques
amy hi how's it going
good good
excellent thanks for coming out i know
it's a track for you guys but i
appreciate it so let's talk a little bit
about your background and maybe
give
the listeners a co some context you're
originally
vegetable fruit farmers
traditional farmers then you got into
cannabis i don't know the details
exactly so maybe let me know you know
how you guys got started in cannabis
yeah well the um it's kind of funny uh
yeah 28 years ago
we started growing uh
peaches and tomatoes and lettuce and
that's been our you know sole source of
income
from the beginning
but you know here i am a certified
organic long-haired guy
in humboldt county and so every time i
tell people like yeah i'm a peach farmer
in humboldt county certified organic you
know and people would just kind of nod
and go sure sure
so after being like stereotyped for most
of my farming career as i was like
always like everybody was like that's
why he's successful he's he's a dope
grower you know grows weed and uh and it
wasn't true and so that's funny yeah and
so we finally got to this point where
like with lee you know like the medical
uh legalization happened and we didn't
jump on it we were like no no no we're
more fruit farmers and and then uh but
that stereotype or that like everybody
had me like pigeonholed and so then when
uh recreational came around we kind of
looked at each other and there had been
that the property we owned there had
been a like an illegal
you know uh
patch um in the back
and
we just kind of looked at each other and
we were like why not it's a
diversification for the farm like we
grow everything else really beautifully
i'd love to see what we could do with
that plant right and uh we've both had a
relationship with cannabis for you know
since i was 12. a long time been growing
it have you been growing it for that
backyard yeah backyard backyard growing
yeah you know just just for ourselves
and so we just like we've been like you
know tried to just stay totally white
market and um enjoy the plants and uh
because first couple of years we just
grew this amazing diversity like uh
through
diversity of cannabis strains yeah and
just really seeing like what the plant
was capable of for sure yeah you gotta
test it out in your soil and the soils
you have the certified organic soil you
guys are in truly native soils yeah
it's beautiful bottom land yeah you have
really nice that little
terrace it's probably like the alluvial
flood plain where it's like really high
grade soil yeah yeah i mean we on that
same you know we with all of our other
crops there we rotate our crops and
we'll
grow melons corn carrots like no water
at all you know it's just like dry farm
dry farmed yeah and so do you think does
your cannabis require any i mean we
water our cannabis but like
it's really about like what's your
definition of dry farming we water it so
little minimum yeah yeah and we use a
drip it's buried um and uh but yeah it's
um
we i think this year we're actually
putting a meter on it it's really the
um we'll go a month at a time without
watering it amazing yeah it's um
it's a beautiful crop it's it's
perfectly suited for our location you
guys have a perfect spot i i it's really
nice it's like that cutty little terrace
there's high recharge rates from the
groundwater
coming through and it just helps
elevate the water tables to where it
seems like it keeps you know the soil
moisture so it's really beautiful i love
that spot is i'm just curious with the
diversification of your other crops i'm
just for the record how many different
species of vegetables do you grow yeah
like i mean that's a hard question i
don't know like we you know with the
like with the you know one thing that we
committed to like we really enjoy like
growing the cannabis but we also said
when we started to do this we were like
we can't not we can't not grow food or
we can't slow down like we still have
that commitment to feed our community
and that's what the farm is like based
on is feeding our community you know
healthy food keep your community healthy
and so
um we still like
produce we actually produce more than we
ever have um so we have like um peaches
we have 18 different varieties
fruit trees in general we have like 1600
trees
so um
you know and then the tomatoes 20
different varieties um
melons eight different varieties you
know so it's just corn and squash yeah
15 varieties of plua you know do you do
other
root vegetables like potatoes or onions
or carrots ever
yeah it depends every year what we do is
we watch and see how the rain falls see
where the how tall the cover crop gets
when is our last
you know rain event all that really um
tells us what we can grow interesting
some years when it's a really dry spring
it's like okay no carrots you know yeah
wet spring great carrots interesting so
you're really truly reading the cycles
yeah we have big totes of seed and big
mason jars of pounds of seeds oh that's
amazing um so and in years we don't use
you know carrots we don't grow them at
all and then the next year it's a big
year so i feel like i want to talk to
you it's not the appropriate time to
talk about carrot cross pollination but
maybe afterwards um
so
as far as your cannabis goes i do find
it interesting that you're in basically
completely native soil
there's not many farms out there that
are in sometimes it's mixed with potting
soil sometimes but
to be in uh native soil if you found any
unique challenges with that or if you
feel like your plants like health-wise
have responded i think that's been
amazing only beneficial yeah
we
like
i have to go to neighboring farms to see
what
diseases and past infestations look like
like we don't our our plants like and
we've learned this with with other
things like the peach trees or the or
the tomatoes like
um
you know
when you start with good genetics and
uh
you and especially like growing from
seed like you get that that plant really
wants to have a authentic root system um
and uh when you grow something that
vital and that healthy um that's like 99
of uh you know keeping pests and disease
away you know not getting greedy
not not pumping a plant with a lot of
fertility that's what i've noticed i've
basically noticed like essentially when
you get greedy and you try to pump the
plant with extra water the root systems
don't develop as much because they don't
need to and then if it dries out the
plant's going to suffer or if you
conversely pump it with fertilizer the
plant grows too rapidly where it's
essentially immune system can't keep up
with itself and then it's attacked yep
and it also like with the root system
it'll if you put too much fertility in
the root system grows a little and goes
oh there's plenty here i don't there's
plenty of water right here too so the
root system doesn't really go for it
whereas like with that native soil you
really want to um
you know you want to get it like you
want to get those roots searching so you
want to have nice loose porous you know
we do like uh we actually um mulch all
our beds in a permanent bed system and
we actually harvest the hay
on the farm oh that's beautiful so you
guys are actually closing the loop
to that degree with mulch so you're
harvesting your hay is it on the same
plot or that on your other farm it's
like in the gym
same spot okay so you're harvesting the
hay and the haze used for mulch for the
cannabis and the hay is actually the
cover crop that we like get so it's like
yeah
right
oh yeah so there's yeah so some things
like the veg and the bell beans they'll
like melt into fertility really quickly
whereas the oats in the rye they provide
layering yeah they'll be a little more
residual it sounds like a really
interesting bio biodiverse system using
a cover crop as mulch that's interesting
i haven't heard i mean most of the times
every time you hear of cover crop it's
always tilled in
you know and i've i've definitely
mulched some stuff but i've only done i
don't like using grasses i didn't
because they will regrow
one it's scary too because you might be
incorporating like some uh perennial uh
grass with rhizome right that you never
know what you're getting so when you're
actually bringing it from your own farm
you know you know that's really cool huh
that's really interesting
and do you feel like have you noticed
like you know your the terpene
expression in the plants are better
because of these management practices
like are you just used to it because
well that's kind of some of the feedback
we're getting is that the terpene
are really
stellar nice yeah that's awesome we're
just you know we're just
working it yeah it's really cool and you
guys been doing it since 2018
17 17. cool right yeah that's awesome
that's really exciting there's probably
a bunch more questions i'll think of
later but i live like five minutes away
so i can always
i've always thought you know if we if we
didn't grow cannabis um in a in a
commercial way i would still want plants
around the farm like one of the things
that i've been amazed at is it's the
interaction with the environment that
that plant has and the beneficial
insects
is just like it's a benefit to the whole
farm like it's i would love it's too bad
that we actually have to keep it in this
very controlled contained like you put
it here yeah cause i'd actually love to
have a couple plants there a couple
couples they're like i love spread that
love i've been doing some autoflowers
with humboldt seed the last few years
he's been giving me some and i've loved
inner cropping
root vegetables with cannabis i had this
50 foot row of carrots just right next
to the cannabis the autoflowers and
it was insane i had no idea that the
carrots all of the above ground growth
could create such a bank for lady
beetles there were lady beetles the
whole the whole row of carrots and then
they all reproduced on the autoflower
leaves like then they all went from
there and the eggs were on the underside
of all the autoflowers i was just like
blown away
how amazing that inner cropping system
was of course it required a lot of water
and fertilization where i'm at
unfortunately we i got hit with the
gravel bar of the river terrace so i've
had to implement some other practices
bringing in fertility with mulching
but anyways
um so that's really i'm i'm just really
excited to hear you guys management
practices it's a really beautiful
example of like closing the loop and
creating more of a regenerative system
that's like
you know long-term regenerative not just
sustainable so yeah we're trying right
now we're actually doing this thing
where we're um we're aging wood chips
for about two years
um and then we're
putting other uh farm-grown green manure
cover crop uh putting that in with the
aged wood chips
and trying to do like we're doing uh
goat uh manure and chicken uh bedding so
chicken oh yeah that stuff's great and
uh we're putting that all in and making
a like a biocomplete compost using
elaine ingham soil food web really
that's actually so right now the um the
fertility on the farm is actually 100
from the farm from the farm so it really
is closed loop
trying and you got you said goats yeah
you guys have goats
yeah goats are tricky and that's really
fascinating walter was talking about you
know harvesting wood chips
and then letting them sit in the forest
and they would collect the mycelium and
then building but you guys are creating
like very unique biodynamics well not
biodynamic but yeah well there's you
know the wood chips and the in the
biology from the forest and the fungi
and everything like that's a huge part
of it you got to grow what is it what is
the biodynamic compost yarrow chamomile
valerian
yeah
yeah that's and that's even more
different that's like that's a different
spiritual path we grow up we grow all
those plants in our beds yeah of the
cannabis yeah they're they're living
plants all in different so there's
living under yeah under the plants
there's inner there's herbs in her crop
and there is
different kinds of valerian and yarrow
oh it's beautiful those things like in
underneath the plants oh that's really
cool that would make you guys have fun i
would love to see photos of that if you
ever do take photos i would put them on
shaw yeah yeah yeah that would be really
cool yeah that's beautiful
right on um all right well i mean i feel
like i asked you a ton of i bet you have
tons of really cool management questions
methodology questions that i could ask
you but i guess for time's sake maybe
let's think about um
uh your
what do you think would be the one thing
you'd change in the industry like if you
had to change something with education
or regulation we've been asking all the
farmers like what do you feel like would
most you know create the highest level
of impact
uh with for the small candidates first
regulation then education sure yeah yeah
less barriers to entry and then
you know then take the time to educate i
think i think they both the education
there's been a lot of talk today about
like education for the the dispensary
level where thcs shouldn't be as
important understanding or terpenes yeah
secondary uh minor cannabinoids and all
of that in education then for the
regulation side there's been all talk of
direct-to-consumer sales
that was been pretty hot
and then obviously eliminate cultivation
taxes and things yeah i think something
that might be unique to us is like we've
been um exploring
the new um ocal or ocan okay ocal
and oh yeah yeah and so the organic
cannabis and that's really hard because
we're just a farm and so
uh we need the distributor to be
certified you need the processor to be
certified oh really and if they're not
wow they can't they can't put that
seriously
in processor also
yeah everybody everybody online
wow so so the fact that we could get
certified and pay all this money to be
certified
um our cannabis would never never say
organic or wow
organic does it do they do that in other
agricultural crops well you know we've
been certified organic you know since
the beginning and since the nop the
national organic program and um
and we're certified our farm is
certified by ccof um
and
back when it started there were certain
things um
that like
they made allowances for things like you
couldn't get organic seed so they were
like okay if you can't find organic seed
you can use a conventional seed
organically
right and as long as you are growing
organic and you could still call that
you know if you grew a tomato from a
conventional seed you could you could
call it organic and so like little
tweaks to the rules like that make all
the difference and so right now they're
trying to get this organic certification
for cannabis off the ground
but they're being so militant about it
yeah it's like that is one foot in our
body right and here you know everybody
i'm sure has been talking about how the
small cannabis farmer is hurting right
now yeah and so here's something you
could really here's a a certification
that could really distinguish yeah
absolutely and it's like and you can't
go anywhere with it interesting wow
that's really lame i had no idea that
and processing and distribution also
don't forget don't forget they make they
not only grow really good cannabis but
they also grow really good peaches um
speaking of cannabis actually do you
have samples
can we get some samples
we can talk about the different thanks
that's the sapphire suit okay the
sapphire suit seven percent thc 22
cbd
now that sounds
pretty amazing i'm definitely as i get
older with all my sports related
injuries and my just like joint sort of
i've i'm leaning more towards the
higher cbd stuff and that's a one to one
oh man well that that at that test was
is basically kind of like a two
two it seems like a three to one almost
but that one test kind of it varies but
it varies depending on yeah sure yeah
the time when it was tested oh my gosh
it smells so good
that's a biovortex
this is a biovortex strain yep sapphire
soup that's like the farm favorite
that's actually anybody who comes and
tries that loves it do you guys are you
just doing flour that for that one
that one is actually made into a
a bho
oh you do yeah oh yeah but we didn't do
it but somebody else did it but then um
that this year is going to be for
pre-rolls oh okay yeah
um
yeah that's one that's like the farm
will always grow that one it's such like
the plant is so beautiful
that um it just we couldn't not leave it
off very easy to work with it's so fresh
nice takes weather
like beautifully another thing about our
farm is like there's there's nothing we
rely entirely on beneficial insects and
uh and companion planting like there's
beautiful
there's nothing this is probably why
i've got it's like i must have gotten
the download over the last few years
because that's what i'm in love with too
and the use of
an integrated system because we're
diversified as a farm we don't have to
rely on one crop so we've had years
where the tomatoes uh
you know get blight
but the peaches save us right and we've
had other years you know that the
peaches uh don't have a crop and the
tomatoes save us or the melons save us
so really so with the cannabis it's like
my concern about smoking other people's
weed is uh
like
if they have to pull off that crop
they're going to do everything yeah and
anything to pull off that crop yeah and
uh so with us it's like there'll be some
i'm sure there'll be some year where
there's nothing there and that's okay
because we've got all these other things
that'll save the key
this is you guys are the shining model
for the key for understanding diversity
it's true you know it's like i mean
really people that's the whole point
diversificate biodiversity is the
supreme ruler when you understand
if you're integrated if you're
integrated with all those systems
then you have the capacity for some to
fail and still be
you know saving and and maintain your
high standards
yes yes that's the thing we don't want
to spray anything yeah and like it would
not feel good to spray something so we
would rather deal with it differently
you guys feel like i mean i could talk
to you for hours probably what uh all
right i know we're not supposed to get
too deep but what are your
three or five favorite companion plants
which ones do you like the most for
attracting beneficials well
oh listen alyssa that's on my list the
top of the list
and then and then um this year i was
amazed at like the yarrow just kept
flowering it just loved the mulch and
the bed system love the yarrow but it
feels like it's invasive a little it
creeps a little bit but you know it
doesn't just pull little edges of it out
it's not like it's not a plant that's
like so hard not like comfrey yeah yeah
and then another you would never plant
coffee
she won't let me you know
but uh another one is it has this place
yeah but not in the cannabis okay
another one is uh oregano oh interesting
awesome amazing time
i love we have a ton of oregano and
thyme in our house too i like it those
are all antimicrobials yeah you think
about it on the spiritual like an
essence level yes in essence biochemical
it's like has a biochemical suppression
i've done some research that shows it
repels
insects pests they don't want to be
around that yeah and it's also got that
small flower that a lot of the
uh beneficials love yes i see oh my god
the honey bees too and the bumblebees go
nuts over it that's cool so okay time
oregano maybe one more three
rosemary we have a lot of rosemary yeah
yeah you know and you the thing is is
you just come in and whack it and it's
like thank you and it goes on to you
know another it'll bloom several times
in a summer which is really oh it's
funny because i've never actually done
that so you can cut rosemary back oh
yeah yeah we cut it and it's just like
roses and then we have some others we
have some um like whether it's day
lilies or that that i'm still like i
don't know what it does but it's
beautiful
or the um
uh japanese anemone is another one
that's in the back and that's nice
because it comes uh in the fall so all
of a sudden you have these brand new
flowers in the fall the successional
blooming of the flowers is the key and
the diversity of the flowers yeah each
you know insect that wants what it wants
totally yep i've been growing a lot of
calendula yeah that's been receding a
lot in forage
another one that i love on the farm that
i used to i actually hurt my back one
year pulling it because i it was it
frustrated me so and then i realized
fennel no chicory chicken yeah chicory
used to come up my lawn and i hated it
and i was always trying to dig it out
and then i was looking for something
like
what blooms late in the year that you
don't have to water you know and um and
i realized chicory the thing is that it
blooms it blooms every morning you know
by the afternoon if you're walking
around it doesn't look like anything
special but it blooms every morning and
the the wasps and the bees are
interested in it so now i i went from
being like on my most hated list to like
now it's one of the things i love the
most oh that's so fun it's funny how
that works
people if they get more in tune with
their environment they'll see that
things aren't weeds or bad things they
can have a lot of potential
is there anywhere we can find your
product that you know yeah so we have
been working with a brand called simple
and they have um created a little
i guess they're eights i don't even know
um and there is the canada dog
there's one we grew last year and then
sapphire stew
and the cherry lime dog they have
those at urban market urban market oh
cool where's that in arcata oh cool
nice
all right that's great local the
sapphires use the cbd and then i think
they also have it at the high times
dispensaries down in the bay area oh
cool area
yep awesome
we're really kind of waiting for the
market to catch up to us
the um
you know until like people
can
get that like
you know what's the label that says i'm
a mom and pop what's the label that says
it's grown in in the earth you know
what's the
you know once this whole thing gets
uh sorted out like
we'll be there okay um but but like
right now we have a a
fun contract with 710 labs
and uh
we had a really nice uh crop with them
this year um and then we're sitting on a
whole bunch of flour
and uh
but like yeah you know you guys are
diversified yeah all in due time yeah
and it's also it's like we said like
we're not desperate to get rid of it and
we also like aren't going to
take a price that's insulting and um
yeah it's understandable it's pretty
gnarly right now i'm glad we delayed
because i see you might have other flour
over there i'd like to yeah let's look
at that um yeah so this one is
strawberry cake and that is seed from
booney acres oh nice boonie's got some
good terp projects yeah that was our
highest like thc one is andrew is andrew
the one doing all the yeah i think so i
think he's doing a lot of it mm-hmm so
we traded them strawberry cake for those
seeds because they do the korean natural
farming they make the ferments so they
took a whole bunch of rotten fruit oh
hilarious gave them they gave us seed in
exchange for that oh my gosh so that
that turned out really nice yeah it's
beautiful it's like great structure hard
buds yeah
mmm smells delicious yeah that's nice um
yeah oh yeah i i she makes me do a lot
of the talking but this is really her
project the strawberry cake project well
no no the whole brand of this project
yeah
what other strains you got um
sherbet frosting is a happy
happy dream happy dream isn't it yeah
so that's that was a fun one too we
never did that one before we did oh wow
this year yeah it's nice so yeah yeah
it's pretty nice i like the the chirping
profileness
mmm smells
delicious lovely lovely and the last one
is a biovortex genetics cherry lime dog
that we've grown very nice this is our
third year oh nice finally i get to
smell it i keep seeing it all over
instagram
no i should get to it
and that's a beautiful one too it's nice
it finishes early
and it's just and once again like the
plant structure like it's almost like
you don't have to do anything to it yeah
just yeah it grows i mean yeah it just
grows but jessie's breeding like that
it's just designed for these systems
and just taking very little off the um
you know the branches before you hang
them there's not a whole lot of
water leaf there's not a whole lot of
leaf and
it just dry super nice amazing that's
great
oh
it smells so good
awesome this is amazing you guys
crushed it well thanks for your time
yeah it's been great
thank you russell yeah thank you guys
have a good one