okay
right on welcome to the ridge sesh
everybody
uh uh the idea behind this was that you
know the the seed swaps have been kind
of a fun thing to do and it's a little
bit of a lost
uh treasure that we don't have as much
anymore keeping the genetics and all
these different uh
things going around so that they
continue to uh
you know
bring us what we what we need which is
the medicine
we have we have assembled the og panel
basically and we have a bunch of people
locally uh we have brian malin's going
to moderate right here from vital garden
supply uh most people know brian locally
he's been our local organic uh supply
store for over like 20 years and are
close to 20. or 16
we've known each other that long but it
just seems like
uh and so brian will introduce or do all
that stuff but i just wanted to say
thanks for coming and it's great to have
all these guys here these are some local
legends our og panel they literally have
been doing this longer than all of us
and it's appreciate having you guys here
to tell some story and i know that
someone does have to leave early every
day at a certain time they have to be
home for some reason and so he's gonna
probably go over his story first because
it's almost that time
thank you eric thank you joey thanks
everybody for
including me in in this event and uh
love for you guys to introduce
yourselves and let's let's get on with
this because i know uh brian has to go
uh duty calls you know
we're committed to this plant and this
is a perfect example of somebody who has
to go take care of them so i'm going to
pass this down the line and let
everybody introduce themselves
and then
sure just keep it quick if you want and
then we'll get some questions in
yeah hi i'm brian from fudu farm have a
10 000 square foot um
farm right here on the ridge just about
a mile and a half away and yeah it's
coming up to be uh that time of evening
and got to close things up but we're
gonna get some fun here and talk to gary
good friend of mine right here i'm gary
from uh mandolin gardens over in venice
city just outside of town um lived here
for about 35 years moved here from
humboldt and i'll maybe tell some
stories about pre
nevada county just to frame things in
reference so and i'll hand off to wade
here if you don't know weight laughter
you should here he is
thank you gary
um
yeah this is a wonderful event by the
way thank you
eric and joey for putting this on and
everybody for coming out uh my name is
wade laughter and uh
i don't have a permit in nevada county
uh our local ordinance uh doesn't allow
me to
and there's been many days lately when
i've been really happy about that
actually
because
the people i know who are trying to do
this in the legal system are really
having a lot of trouble
um
i i'm i'm a cannabis patient i
i'm a big fan of access for all
and um
i first came into cannabis uh because i
have glaucoma that was back in the mid
90s
and
long story short yeah i've spent a lot
of time
looking at the different versions of
cannabis
uh the and the effects that those types
of cannabis have on people and their
well-being
um
so yeah i have a few stories but i'm
really looking forward to hearing what
brian has to say so i'll pass the mic
back thank you
anyway this this is an event for you
guys to talk i'm just helping to
deliver the message but i'm glad to
share some stories too
but i i feel honored to be amongst all
these guys here and they've definitely
been on the front line
um gary let's start with you since you
got to get going
um no brian sorry sorry sorry sorry um
let's let's talk about
i should know that my name is brian
anyway um
tell us a little bit what what drew you
to nevada county and then also what made
you stay and um
tell us some of the reasons that you
think it's a good place to grow cannabis
all right yeah well just like wade said
i'd like to say uh thank you to the
organizers of the event it's a pretty
awesome event
um but yeah i started growing back in
1981 up in mendocino county i went up
there to um some family friends were
building the house and turned out they
were growing some really good weed
and i was right out of high school so i
did that and learned did that on the
north coast mendocino humboldt sonoma
county
during the 80s came here in 88
bought my land in 91 and
built a house and raised a family and
i've been
building houses and growing weed all
along
and
nevada county has come a long ways it's
been an amazing place there's a lot of
really intellectual people really arts
and artsy people creative people
and so
the
i felt like what really drew me here was
the people and the yuba river and just
the whole vibe of the place was like um
like going home as a kid to some fantasy
place
but um growing weed um was not always
easy like in the 80s and 90s there was a
huge um you know task force is trying to
chase us down and and you know hiding
from helicopters we did all that and you
know lots of folks got arrested and and
um and
helped helped us get to where we are
there was a time in nevada county when
there were um posters like at mother
truckers and at um the post office in
north san juan that were like turn in
your neighbors for a five thousand
dollar reward
and um that was literally a thing right
right up into the 90s
um i know from personal experience
because like i know folks that got um
got
marked on like that and for five
thousand dollars like you know you would
have paid those guys
five times that to not turn you in
you know like please right you know but
that was a thing and people would fly
around and they'd look for grows and
then they'd they'd collect their their
reward
but that's like one of the negative
things there was a lot more positive
things on the ridge here especially the
san juan ridge because
um people there was a really tight
community and we took care of each other
there was always um you know people that
were in need that would um have a
donation jar at but the gas station and
that jar was always full like people
were always putting fives and tens and
twenties in it because like you know you
could feel for these people you probably
knew them and if you didn't know them
you know you knew they were good people
because they lived here so
um a lot of good stories about that like
here's a big one um in uh in the 70s uh
this school on oak tree road burned down
and um
so a bunch of growers and local folks
with some money um
built rebuilt the school just rebuilt it
right and but like in the state of
california you can't do that like that
when the school board got involved
they're like wait you can't just rebuild
the school but they had they had rebuilt
this school and but the union got
involved and all kinds of folks got
involved and and um so
another local just kind of got
disgruntled and burned it back down
and
and let the state rebuild it so that
school that cute little school over
there on oaktree's oaktree campus
that's the story there but it was it was
the growers money that helped um keep
this uh this
ridge and our whole community alive and
well economically and just like you know
helping out one another um
yeah i mean um i i don't i don't want to
ramble on but that's my story 41 years
in the trade and um and oh wait
a really important thing came along um
like we we always anticipated that at
some point samia would come along and
help us build this
community that we envisioned like this
strong thriving cannabis community
and my wife barbara
was going to start going to these
meetings down at um and at the haven
underground in nevada city and they were
started out as like what became the
nevada county cannabis alliance and
these were the people we were waiting
for
i like to tell this story because it was
so touching like we were like barbara
came home she's like hey you wouldn't
believe what we're talking about we're
talking about like starting an ordinance
here in nevada county that allows us to
grow you know like out and open
and we had been already like we had the
you know we had a script we were sort of
we were making the rounds of the at the
clubs in sacramento we were we thought
that was kind of quasi-legal and it felt
legal but it wasn't really legal but but
um so when when we started hearing what
these folks were talking about we
started getting involved and helped
create what became the nevada county
cannabis alliance and without the nevada
county cannabis alliance we never would
have gotten
through um the whole writing of the
ordinance and we wouldn't be sitting
here today having this event probably um
like that's the story of my farm we were
lucky enough to be
like one of the first farms we took the
the transition permit when we only could
have a thousand square feet
a thousand square feet like where we're
sitting here right you know and uh
smaller and um and 25 plants it's pretty
hard to make a living on 25 plants
and a thousand square feet yeah you know
so but we took it because like if we
didn't take it we were afraid they'd
take it away and then and then and then
we'd be back in a no ban or a total ban
community like it was for a little while
so but it was through a lot of strong
activism through the nevada county and
cannabis alliance and folks like wade
laughter here and gary and all of us
kind of step into the front and putting
our faces on the line because like you
know um for all those years we couldn't
be out front but now we felt like it was
important that people in the community
see that we were you know their
neighbors like i was also a contractor
so chances are i may have built your
house and then i coached soccer with the
kids and i might have coached your kids
soccer you know so like i'm i couldn't
be that bad you know oh yeah i also grow
cannabis
you know oh you want to buy some
yeah so it turns out that you know that
probably a lot of people suspected that
all along but it feel it felt really
good to be able to finally like come
walk down broad street in the parade and
say yeah i'm a cannabis farmer yeah so i
don't want to ramble on but thanks for
your attention you guys i gotta grow go
home and pull tarps because i've got
i've got that going on yeah so this is
og cannabis uh farming at its best but i
love you guys and uh here you go gary
thanks brad
thanks guys brian thanks for giving us
some story that was awesome
thanks to the nevada county cannabis
alliance too we definitely need to
appreciate them they've helped push this
along here in our community
hey if anyone knows allen from obsolete
genetics he's supposed to be on this
panel too and
i saw him earlier today but then i
couldn't find him when it got close to
time so if anyone sees them
bring them on over otherwise i'm going
to pass this on to gary and
say same uh
same format you know tell us some
stories tell us why you love nevada
county how you got here tell us some of
your humboldt story too because that's
going to be fun too all right take care
hi i'm gary sabanya um
i thought i'd start maybe at the
beginning like when would i did i first
plant a cannabis seed i remember now i
had to try hard i was 15 and a half
years old in 1970
in ventura county
and i think everything we grew was male
and we threw it in a bag and smoked it
and it got us more stone than anything
that we had had so far up to that point
at 15 years old
um
but when i went to college i moved to
humboldt county where i met my lovely
wife and felicia back here
um
and we grew a little bit of weed there
we lived close to town we had a
greenhouse with maybe you know i think a
huge crop for us back then was 15 pounds
of weed
and our daughter was born there and we
decided we were moving out of humboldt
county because we didn't want our kids
to grow up in a cannabis society
and we moved to nevada county
so
just think about the irony of that
sometimes
we were a little naive
and
so the first few years we lived here we
weren't doing anything with cannabis but
as you know things would happen we
needed some personal stash and planted
our own from seeds we brought with us um
but that so that's just a background of
where we came from
um
now our 32 year old son works in the
industry as our partner on the farm it's
all great i don't know what we were
thinking
but
so we have now a 25 100 square foot
license in the county
and
i have to double what brian said about
just all the hard work of
many people here and i mean wade and
diana and we were all working for
several years to get to the point where
we're at now just
just to where we could take a deep
breath and not worry about the sheriff
coming down our road every day i mean
that was my own setup was
to get rid of that anxiety and we have
different anxieties now but but it's
definitely a lot better than it was
um
let's see what was the other other
anecdote i thought about too back in
humboldt when we were growing there
there was no indica there was no girl
scout cookies there was just bagweed i
mean we planted uh wahawkin and
guerreron seeds that you know we had
leftover for years
a friend of mine knew someone who
imported afghani hash
into humboldt county on fishing boats
and he used to pluck seeds out of this
hash for years so a friend asked me he
won't try these afghani seasons like
what is that you know i had no idea what
it was
um
and the rest is history i mean several
years later that all came to humboldt
county and we are where we are now
because of those people who went around
the world and found those strains and
brought those seeds back so
i have to thank them
but again back to the
cannabis alliance and the
the whole thing with the county
so many people worked so hard and stuck
their faces like out on the line and i
mean i think we were both in the front
page of the paper a couple of times
right talking to the board
all of us
and um i i have to give credit to to
those people there's just a i couldn't
even name while there's like a lot of
people that worked hard so
[Music]
i'm glad we are where we are today and
this is wonderful to see you folks i'm
going to pass it off to wade
thank you gary
um
well
i'm kind of a rookie in this
lineup
i started growing in 1996
and
i lived in san francisco at that point
in my life
um
started growing for my own needs for
global glaucoma
uh pretty quickly realized the scale i
was doing it was not worth doing
and
after a series of steps ended up in a
small warehouse
in the south of market area of san
francisco and
uh worked there for five years
um
and then in 2010
monica and i started my monica's my wife
here and partner and hero
of all sorts of wonderful
um we started talking about we wanted to
get out of san francisco
and because we had a lot of friends up
in the mendocino humboldt area we went
up there and looked around and
not unlike gary's sense of it it was it
seemed like it was a one
trick
pony kind of town if you will
that the only thing that was really
happening there a lot of beautiful
people but cannabis was all that was
going on
but meantime here in nevada county
uh
i think the first time she brought me up
here was to the
wild and scenic film festival
and i was really struck by the kind of
people that i saw
and
i i was struck by the idea that there
were three different live theater groups
with their own performance space
in a town of 5 000 people
and very few towns in california
5 000 people have one theater group but
nevada city has three
so you told me there was something
really special going on here and
we came here we bought we rented a place
into the spring of 2011 found our
beautiful little farm
in the fall there and uh took possession
in september of 2011. so like i said i'm
fairly new to the county
but i
have really come to love
this place and the people that are here
and
yes i want to call out the cannabis
alliance and the work that the cannabis
alliance has done but even more
specifically i want to call out each of
you
[Music]
a thing that has really bugged me a lot
lately i'm sort of straying off of off
topic here
is the idea that
the court decision known as roe versus
wade might be getting overturned by our
supreme court
and it seems impossible to me but it
sounds like that's what's happening
and
i'm sure there's a lot of people who
feel like making signs and marching down
the street or maybe even burning down
buildings
but i would
really encourage every one of you
to register to vote
if you are not already registered to
vote
and vote
as soon as the elections happen vote if
everybody in this country votes
we can overturn
and make law that protects the privacy
of a woman and her right to choose how
her life is going to unfold
i really think this is an important
thing not just for women for all of us
but especially for women it's ridiculous
that we've come to this and the only
real power
that we as cannabis people or as human
beings in this country the only real
power any of us have
is the vote
and if enough of us vote we can make a
difference
and i'm not going to tell you how to
vote just get out and vote
and
i'm going to stop there that's politics
and i'll sorry for straying off but i
really think this is important
and if you and part of how
nevada county came to have the ordinance
it does
is if you remember back in 2016 at
january of 2016 the board of supervisors
created a they passed an urgency
emergency ordinance didn't know there
was such a thing but
after the vote it became law right then
no period for public review no nothing
and it basically prohibited all cannabis
businesses in nevada county
and we made enough of a noise that they
said okay well we'll put it on the
ballot
and we were fortunate that election that
was when bernie sanders and hillary
clinton were running against each other
so a lot of people voted for that reason
a lot of people voted because
the people who became the nevada county
cannabis alliance registered almost 4
000 new voters in nevada county that
year
and a lot of those people turned out and
voted
and we changed this county
with the one power that we actually have
and so
again i
i'm going to stop there i just say this
i love the plant i love what we've done
so far in nevada county and we're trying
to change the ordinance to allow more
license types
more events like this
and again the one power we all have
is the vote
and even if you don't think the system
works even if you think the democrats
are messed up even more than the
republicans or the republicans whatever
you know i don't care about your trip
just vote
because i think if enough of us do that
we'll get the kind of government we want
instead of the circus
we've had lately
[Music]
wow
okay
[Applause]
i'll close by this i care a lot about
cbd
uh harlequin house of harlequin is the
business that monica and i have created
with our partner uh it's an education
platform we want to help people
understand about the benefits that
cannabis can offer
not just for health but also for economy
and for
the well-being of a community like what
we have going on right here in nevada
county and increasingly across northern
california
um
and
it is my sense that
uh and i'm sure i'm slanted this way
because of harlequin harlequin's a plant
i discovered back in 2008 2009
turned out to be a real special plant
got it out to as many people to as many
places as possible for a number of years
since then i've really been focused on
versions of cannabis
that are helpful
for conditions like epilepsy childhood
epilepsy
and i want to say if any of you know
silas
a little boy who has seized for years
silas has been free of seizures since
september
which is a really big deal because he
used to have hundreds of seizures a day
and now he has been free of seizures for
going on
eight months nine months
yeah he's going to school
it's a really beautiful transformation
the whole family is doing well
and i know for a fact that cannabis kept
that little boy alive
to get to the point that he is now
i don't know that cannabis is involved
in
him not seizing anymore because i know
people who
grew out of having seizures as children
when they entered puberty and became
adults they no longer were seizing that
might be what's happening for silas
but when he was seven and eight years
old
his parents were told
he wouldn't live to be the age of 10
so they should get ready for that
and he is now
13 or 14 years old going to high school
having a normal life the families having
a normal life
this is huge
and that's a small part of what cannabis
can do
in the lives of
all of us actually i really think that
cannabis is an essential
nutrient that used to be in our diet
because our farm animals ate it and it
was on our farms and it was in our food
chain
but not for the last few generations and
i think that what we're doing here in
nevada county is getting that going
again
we're making we're normalizing cannabis
and helping people understand that it's
not a dangerous bad thing
it actually is good
and helps us feel good
so
i don't know i think i'm done
i'll pass it on
thank you wade you're a treasure buddy
we're so lucky to have you in our
community wade
thank you so much
i want to introduce alan to everybody
alan is owner and founder of obsolete
genetics some
definitely some foundation
to a lot of the genetics that are out on
the streets today
and he's got a recent position as
director of
genetics or
at uh styses so
he's been able to
grow and and do a lot of cultivation in
nevada county and then turn it into you
know a career and really be successful
so i'm proud i'm proud to see members of
our community
stepping it up and you know taking it to
the next level
so i'll let allen introduce himself a
little bit and
the other guys we've all talked a little
bit about what brought us to nevada
county and what makes us love growing in
nevada county in general so we can touch
on that
alan
originally from the bay area
got my start a little closer okay so got
my start in cannabis
because i like smoking this was maybe uh
just out of high school
um
this was before any kind of outdoor
growing that we knew about
this was before indoor growing so one of
my friends had this crazy idea let's
scale the poles at the bart parking lot
and we'll steal the lights off the
parking lot poles and try and grow
cannabis
and damn it worked you know so
and shortly after that a couple years
later berkeley indoor garden started up
and then we started having access to
actual grow lights and and uh
general hydroponics or you know that was
about it at the time um
i came a little closer sorry
if anybody can't hear just raise a hand
and i'll speak a little louder or
something i been i'm like 50 dabs deep
so you have to excuse me so
everybody i go walk by they're like bro
you gotta have a dab come over here so
which
love it but so anyways yeah um i came up
to this region originally because i had
a four-wheel drive company
and uh
the trails are up here so anyways that
went from that to restaurant industry
had a barbecue restaurant in town here
and
none of it was fulfilling and it just it
wasn't what my passion my calling was
i'm actually third generation of growers
out of humble and um shelter cove area
and uh
so once i was up here i've like fell
into a good group of local people up
here on the ridge that all grew outdoor
and i was like wow like i've only done
indoor and i didn't know you can grow
these giant plants this was a long time
ago so uh
but i
became a grower in the passion of loving
the plant and i i
my early history of breeding was that i
my stepfather was a grower and humble i
asked for some seeds he gave me seeds
and then uh the next year i didn't save
seeds i didn't make seeds so i went back
and i said dean i need some more seeds
and he slaps me upside the head and he's
all bro don't you know that you just
have to just make seeds and you can keep
growing every year every year this is
before we knew what cloning was so
next year he showed me how to make seeds
and that was in 1983 so i've made seeds
for myself and friends since 1983.
pretty much exclusive and uh
you know this has opened a lot of doors
cannabis is
a lot of great people a lot of
shady people in it too but um
i'm really
blessed that i was able to turn this
into
a way of life and
recently becoming the director of
genetics at a really big company
i never saw myself as a cannabis grower
being able to have 401k but as of this
week i have a 401k which
i i don't even know what it means but
you know
i have one now so
yeah it's definitely good but so the the
point being is that you know this is a
maturing industry and
and we go through the growing pains
obviously through this you know people
um we had it good for a long time and
with legalization it's made it pretty
difficult but i believe there's still a
lot of opportunity and if you do a good
job and you focus inward on yourself and
do the best that you can do
for the plant and the plant gives back
so
that's a little bit about my history so
i don't know
thank you thank you
thanks alan that was awesome little
intro
definitely you know she goes to show you
put your mind to it and you concentrate
on something
you stick with it and
you get somewhere
um
let's let's take it to be a little bit
more specific about growing and genetics
and and and
you know details like we talked about
how great our community is and
not to take away from that that's that's
also a really important part of why
we're all here but let's talk a little
bit about the weather and the growing
season and and what it's like in in some
other reasons regions because it sounds
like everybody all of us have grown in
different areas so
i mean i've i've grown on the central
coast i've grown in mendocino county
and you know for me
nevada county is like it's a breath of
fresh air it's like perfect amount of
moisture perfect amount of dryness
you know yeah the season could be a
little bit longer that would be great
but on the other hand compared to all
the other regions in the state
it's pretty cherry so
you know one of the things i really love
is the fact that we get these long
beautiful falls
so i'll just pass it down the line and
everybody just
say a couple things of why they love to
grow here and
and compare it to maybe some of the
other places you grow you grew and why
it seems like everyone's grown here
right now so
what brought you back and and keeps you
here
one of the best things about growing
here is the yuba river so if and no one
here has been to the yuba river you got
to check it out it's one of the most
beautiful places on earth other than
that the climate here is it's it's like
growing grapes in napa you know we have
a
special microclimate here that just
produces
incredible cannabis um the weather and
the late season i mean i don't even know
if we have rain anymore until like
december so
we don't worry about rain and molds and
things like that it doesn't seem for at
least the last 10 years but
um yeah the community here that's uh
that grows and
um just this this is this country's just
beautiful so um
yeah that's why i'm here to grow
cannabis
um speaking of microclimates we live on
a north slope where they it's actually
got a nickname of little siberia to the
old timers around here so we actually
have we do have problems with powdery
mildew that i never used to have when i
lived on a hill
where the air drilled away but um
in general it is it's just a perfect
climate um
and i think it's just going to get
better
what do you think wayne
yeah i
i agree one of the things that's really
lovely about cannabis and really diving
into the genetics of cannabis is
genetics from a place like afghanistan
where it's high elevation and they get
10 inches of rain a year are going to be
different they're going to act
differently in your garden than genetics
from places like the cloud forests of
colombia for example that could tolerate
a lot of moisture that like you'd find
on the coast of mendocino
but what's beautiful about nevada county
to me is depending on what part of the
county you're in you can get completely
different elevations our farm our little
four acre farm where we've done a lot of
good work over the years uh is it about
a thousand meters above sea level and
there's places in nevada county that are
you know
100 feet above sea level
and you're going to have really
different growing seasons really
different
opportunities in those different places
and
in my specific case one of the reasons
i'm really excited about living in
nevada county is we were fortunate and
maybe smart enough to buy a good soil
because there's a lot of good dirt in
this county
and if you take care of your soil and
you feed it and you know for years our
garden got compost and
certain uh
korean natural farming type amendments
and water
never anything on the plant surfaces
itself because we were making medicine
we wanted to make sure that there was
high quality material free of any
contaminants
and meantime again
the the elevation
the length of the season the dryness of
the summer the heat in the day the
coolness of the nights
cannabis is very happy here
that's my experience and that makes me
happy because i love the plant and
when you see them flourish it's a
beautiful sight
speaking of breeding wade i know that
you've done a recent project with the
guys at humboldt season i noticed ben
just walked over here so
um tell us a little bit about tell us a
little bit about that project and um
then we'll move on and get get a little
more specific with both these guys too
uh yeah that's that's a a wonderful
thing that's happened here
um a couple of years ago um
a mutual friend between ben and i
uh said that uh
you know you should really consider
doing something with these guys and so
uh we sent over uh
four different cuttings
of things that i was working on in the
summer of
2018 i think it was
and uh ben took them in and
grew them out and uh
mothered them and
and then meantime yeah we talked about
what was going to happen what what mail
we might use to get and i my interest
for years has been primarily cbd and
what's called the minor cannabinoids if
you will
so um
yeah we ended up with three different
lines that are almost guaranteed to be
relatively high in cbd not much thc at
all
and there will be other cannabinoids and
there's going to be some really
interesting terpenes
in some of those seeds
so
and i love the model of humboldt seed
company of getting genetics out to
people and let them find the things that
are special for them
because we're all different
you can take us the same plant and offer
it to different people and you'll get
different responses to that plant
because our systems are different our
needs are different we should respond
differently to the cannabis plant and
it's my sense that it's important to
give people the opportunity to grow
their own
and find something that really turns you
on really gets gets your boat going and
i gotta say if if you're looking for
things that are gonna get you high
the cbd trifecta is probably not the one
you're looking for
but if you're looking for something that
might help you feel good
help you join snot ache
help your digestion work better help you
sleep better at night all those things
are definitely possible in those mix of
seeds and i'm really excited and pleased
that
ben has done all of that because it's
it's always been my goal if you look at
what happened with harlequin it was
about give it away to as many people as
possible same thing is happening with
the seeds thankfully
i'm learning how to do business
and ben is selling them for us which is
really fun it's special i gotta say you
know after all these years of giving it
away uh
and and the goal there all along was to
give it away so i'm excited by it i'm
looking forward to hearing reports
that's awesome wade i'm glad to hear
that you're monetizing your
love for the plant and it's getting back
to you and when i heard that you were
working with ben and humboldt seas it
made me feel good because i know it's
two great members of the community and
just two really class acts and that's
one of the things i love about cannabis
is it brings people together it gives us
opportunities to collaborate that's one
of my favorite things right now is to be
able to collaborate with other people
that are like-minded
grow genetics and have like a plan like
not just throwing some wheat out there
and growing it and hope we're gonna make
some money but like with intention and
like hey how's this idea sound like
let's grow this strain and do this with
it and make this product with it and
it's gonna help this group of people and
it's gonna be great for this this and
this and
that's that's what's pretty awesome
about this plant
thanks for embracing it
um so gary i wanted to get a little bit
specific on on your genetics and
situations you spoke that you're on a
north face and
you know that's that's makes things a
little bit more challenging and you know
we're all faced with different issues
when we grow and um you know tell us a
little bit what you've learned about
genetics and like what works for you and
what doesn't work being on the north
face and like
also like how's that affect when you
start and when you finish and things
like that
on our farm we tend to not be in a hurry
to plant
um i mean it's like when you see people
buying tomatoes here putting them out in
the first of may
it happens every year the people who
sell tomato plants do a really good
business in may and june
with the second or third uh yeah that's
true
second or third wave of tomatoes but um
so i usually probably don't put any full
term plant out until about the first of
june i know a lot of people do earlier
than that but that seems to work for us
every year is just so different here in
the fall too you talk about the dry
falls i mean we've had those and we've
also had rain knock everything down in
august
and uh
so we've gotten really really creative
with support i'm sure everybody out
there understands what i mean um
and we've started growing smaller we
used to grow gigantic plants and you
know being on a ladder when you're 65
working on your plants just doesn't work
so
so being compact really working on
pruning all that stuff is so important
and we all know that i'm talking you
know preaching to the choir so um
that's about all i can say about that
uh genetics like everybody else we're
trying new stuff all the time i mean all
these folks at this event here the
people from finest i didn't see purple
city genetics but they're great humble
seed company is great
we've tried a little bit from everybody
and
it just it's such an evolving thing it
and the market is so fickle so
just having all those options out there
from people and and
working towards what really works on
your own farm
is all you can do i mean it's a it's a
education every year for me so
thank you to you know the breeders and
people coming up with those genetics
that we can have such great stuff to try
now so
gary this is alan allen has a strain
that finishes in 43 days you guys might
want to talk
actually
the next thing i was going to get to is
alan tell us a little bit about some of
the new strains you're working on
um tell us you know
your what like really gave you your like
boost
um into um you know
people really knowing who obsolete
genetics was and and like gave you your
like
you know the genetically like pushed you
into the you know big big time so to
speak
so genetics for me have always been like
what
what i just i
i wanted to always smoke like what i
grow and what i breed and a lot of times
like the market dictated something else
for many years everybody wanted just
like og gas and i was more into like
fruity strains and things that are like
sipping wine or something and
so for the very beginning of when i was
breeding it wasn't really successful
because everybody they wanted that this
was before extracts came along extracts
came along and changed the game
but the fuel was all that anybody wanted
og sour diesel that's it and there was
so much um
that people were breeding that were all
homogeneous that were the same and it
just it's it's like taking all the
colors on the palette and just wiping
them together and that's what they came
up with and a lot of breeders that's all
they had was just
another copy of another copy of another
copy so i i tended to go a different
direction for what
i wanted not what everyone else wanted
luckily though that came around and
changed
i did a string called
alien kush
um some years back which was this las
vegas purple kush to this
um afghani strain that i had got from a
friend who
brother came back from afghanistan and
had a handful of seeds and
and they're just a land race afghan i
crossed to this las vegas purple cush
and at the time on the forums on the
forum boards online
there hadn't
no one had seen anything that had as
much frost that early on
and that kind of literally just lit the
fire under my ass as being somebody that
had something different and new and
fresh
other than that what really kind of
pushed me further up into
i don't know
i don't know how to say it but the
orange cookies basically
um
became famous because of
the jungle boys who are a big grower out
of
los angeles and they were doing a lot of
promotions and we had this opening night
where we did a orange cookie tasting and
this was the first time we'd seen like
people like lined up for blocks long in
downtown l.a to come to this
this tasting because it was so hyped
online so
what began after that is like this high
almost like um
i can't say all breeders but a lot of
breeders were just chasing the next
thing that people wanted and it's i
don't think it was necessarily something
that they
were passionate about it was just more
of like um
a money grab so to speak because
when the price of cannabis started to
crash
a lot of people stopped growing cannabis
and jumped into
the extract
game like all of a sudden now we got
millions of extractors you know
everybody converted from being a grower
to an extractor and then from that that
market got flooded and then the next
thing was everybody became seed breeders
and so you had a lot of people that were
buying a pack of seeds from
a breeder it doesn't matter what breeder
but now that one pack of seeds has
created a brand new company and so they
really didn't do a lot of their own work
they furthered someone else's work and
that's where i say that everything
became homogeneous because they were
using the same shit that everybody else
was using
it's tough now and if you really want to
make a living you almost have to find
yourself
chasing what it is the market wants
currently it's
purple rock hard
smells like gelato i mean that's the
only thing that sells right now so if
you're on at the mercy of the market and
you're not vertically integrated you
have to chase what that
in flavor is that's dictated by
people in new york or you know some rap
star or something so
but
i still do what i like to do because i
just hate falling into just doing the
same thing that everybody else wants to
do i do flavors that are people like oh
that's that's like jack or something
like yeah but i like it you know so
that's why i do it because it's what i
like and what i want to smoke and i just
like flavors too like i probably have
200 jars of fresh wheat at home all
different flavors and and it never gets
old every day with dinner popping in
different jars like sipping wine you
know that's what genetics are to me is
like the variety and and stuff that you
know obviously is different i do like
the new stuff that everybody likes the
gelato purple stuff it's it's pleasing
but it gets boring so
um
that's pretty much what genetics are to
me as far as you know
um what's going on currently uh
going to work for steezy and going to be
doing their entire palette of genetics
i'm excited because i don't have to fall
into just one category to breed for
or to final hunt for so they have a
they want anything and everything as
long as it's good so it
it's it's nice to be able to finally
break out of these these like lanes that
you have to stay in to be a a super
successful breeder these days and and
just chasing that one flavor and and by
the time
a lot of people get this flavor it
changes and then you're you're behind
the gun again so
i uh
i think that uh the flavors are the
spice of life and i'm not gonna
find myself just hunting one thing
because some rap star says that's what
everybody should be smoking
what's going to be the popular strain
gelato
it's gonna be the same
that's funny i was i was just thinking
when he was talking that i was gonna
bring up that you know you know and i
think gelato is a great strain and
there's some great things about it but
what i'm seeing right now in cannabis is
like
everyone's complaining that things
aren't selling and the prices are down
so people are like changing the way that
they grow to a cheaper way and maybe
using not as good ingredients
and and now what we have right now is a
huge amount of mediocracy
so like how many people can grow a
gelato cross with athena
and then wonder why it doesn't sell
i mean
let's mix it up a little people
so just recently i had the pleasure of
um judging flowers at the ego clash
which meant that i had to smoke 30
joints within an hour and judge this
stuff
and
it was brutal but uh it got to the point
where you know we everyone that was
judging also had entered i could not
pick out my own weed because i grew for
what the market was
demanding some lemon cherry gelato
every of all 30 there was only one that
stood out different everything else was
some kind of a gelato it was like one
big
pool that everybody just threw their
butts in and it all came out the same
like
we sat around the table and like could
you recognize your weed and like none of
us could it was all the same so there's
definitely a need for some
something to change
yep so
if you're looking for um a quick easy
scheme growing cannabis isn't it
um
and if you are even just wanting to have
longevity in cannabis
you gotta really think outside the box
you gotta mix it up you gotta you know
the thing that all the gentlemen here
are just saying that really resonates is
that they're doing it for their love for
the love of the plant and they're doing
it for the right reasons
like like alan was saying like they're
these guys who breed to try to like get
ahead of the curve and and think that
what are people gonna like next year
you know sure as a business you gotta
have that in mind but on the other hand
if you really love cannabis and you
really want to like
take it to the next level you gotta
diversify yourself and not necessarily
do what you think that clout is and do
what you think is right and go with your
heart
so
you know
follow follow your passion and
you know i think the people
right now who are struggling in cannabis
are probably the ones who are the most
passionate about it that it makes it
hard but i think if everybody just
you know stick sticks with it
don't let it bring you down because
push comes to shove
someday people are going to realize that
you know the difference between craft
cannabis is going to be like the
difference between
budweiser and craft beers so i'm not a
huge beer drinker so i'm not even sure
if that analogy is great but
i think there is i think there is a big
differentiation and i think
that when when that you know when people
realized the difference between a good
beer and
you know a course
like it opened some minds and cannabis
right now the way the way i see it is
you know it's such a new
industry and it's so new to like the
public and people walking to dispensary
and they're just like
what i can go buy cannabis on the shelf
and there's all these cannabis products
and
it's just kind of like
so wild that they're not quite in the
mindset where they are like when they go
grocery shopping
so i feel like that's one of the things
i personally want more as one of my
missions and
if you know who i am you know you know i
like i'm pretty true to it
is like convincing people that using the
right ingredients
growing organically
is like really important because number
one it brings out what the plant has to
offer number two it's better for the
environment number three you're not
supporting
some you know huge chemical industry
that is going to be the downfall of our
planet
so
you know be mindful of your purchases
and be mindful of how you grow
so
i don't want to talk too much because
i'm a moderator so
let's let's uh pass the mic and
other things i was thinking about on my
list of questions
um
if you were to pick another place other
than nevada county to grow
where would that be and why
anyway
probably rogue river or humboldt
somewhere
yeah just north anywhere north i don't
like south i like north
i i'm going to decline to state i'm
going to stay right here i think we've
got it made here
yeah i tend to go with gary i traveled
the world quite a bit when i was younger
and
this is a special spot
if i had to be someplace else it might
be spain
because they have a pretty good cannabis
thing going and
some really beautiful people
[Music]
but yeah i'm kind of with gary this is
this is the winner for me
right here in nevada county
well i guess it's unanimous
yeah i think we're all pretty blessed
and whatever it was that attracted us
all to this great area and great
community you know
we're we're lucky we're blessed and
it seems like everyone feels like
they're putting roots in and
i think long-term nevada county is to
make make a serious impression on
california kind of how napa and sonoma
did in the wine thing
you know i feel like we're the underdog
because people think of outdoor cannabis
and they think of humboldt and
mendocino until they see our flowers and
then they're like whoa
so uh
you know i'm not sure if anybody else
has anything they would like to talk
about but
i feel like we've covered a lot and
we've got a great bunch of people here
growing in nevada county
i feel honored
and yeah that's good great idea alan
let's open up the um
the field to some questions anybody out
there have a question they want to show
throw at any of these gentlemen
uh your go ahead right here in the front
yes
thyme oil
yeah i have some
um i mean
for botrytis i think you know one of the
most important things you could do early
on is getting a really good microbial
population in the soil
regalia is a great product to prevent it
armory is also has like six or seven
species of bacillus
i'm not familiar with that one but
time oil isn't necessarily a bad thing
you just got to be careful that because
it could be phytotoxic it could cause
phytotoxicity
so
yeah i was going gonna say even like the
first week of flower
get get an application in keep the rate
low so you don't have it on there the
oil on there like
in the hot sun just turning into a
magnifying glass making it you know
worse
yeah
the moisture is definitely always a
challenge
the other thing is do a little research
you know there's some strains that are
more botrytis resistant than others
um because you know i've seen i've seen
in the same garden one strain have it
and one not so
that's one of my suggestions you guys
haven't yet anyone else have any
tips
just kidding
that's
uh luck
i don't a friend of mine up here his
good friend that he went to college with
is director of operations
we were at a park had a barbecue and i
brought some nuggets and he's like oh my
god i got to show these to jay so
he told us he said jay i got this guy
that does genetics so they vetted me
came
looked at my history and
and uh
came at me with a good offer so shrine
group yeah
all right
probably have my genetics in there very
soon
goes the show flowers opens doors go
ahead sir
so the the orange was an old school it
was
called orange juice that came out of
garberville my mom was a bartender in
garberville and my stepfather was a
gorilla grower up in that area and
in high school i went there and i said
you know i need some i need some seeds
dean that was my stepfather and he gave
me these
orange juice seeds and then so which i
think is probably california orange bud
um or what became california orange but
that was i think orange
butt was pretty prevalent in humble in
that period
so uh
i had those seeds for years and years
and years and then i got the forum girl
scout cookies and at the time i was like
wow this is some great stuff you know so
one thing led to another i popped some
of the the orange juice bud seeds and
and i i had a few strains at the time
and i put that on the girl scout cookies
and
man it turned out phenomenal you know it
was just one of those things it was kind
of an accident but it i mean it was
it was an accident but it wasn't an
accident i don't know how to explain
that you know like it turned out because
a lot of times you can put two good
things together and think that they're
gonna create magic and they don't they
just don't and then that's like having
you know
uh
two ugly people that have a beautiful
baby or like vice versa you know two hot
people come together and the baby's butt
ugly you know like and no grandma ever
says like oh that kid's ugly and they're
always like oh that my grandkids the
greatest kid in the world so uh but
anyway so um yeah that was orange
cookies
in a in a nutshell so to speak
yeah
so obviously you had intention for what
it to be but you know when you when you
breed you never know what the outcome is
and
that's that's one of the things that
keeps us all going is like the
excitement of it all
as far as breeding goes like yeah you
don't know the outcome but in years and
years of experience you can start
estimating what the outcome will be
closer and closer
so um
and it is it's it's kind of uh art and
it's also kind of science and it's a
little bit luck
there's heartache and tears like
especially if you start doing feminized
pollen
um the the success rate's low at first
and
you spend months like flowering things
out and then wow you get no seeds out of
it so and it's it's a a room filled with
you know 40 different plants and there's
not enough to make a pound of anything
so you can go broke real fast trying to
be a breeder
um but you know and it just ta it was a
big leap of faith because i did flowers
to you know like most people
in the white market now they started
somewhere wherever we do we all did we
grew flowers and out in the field in the
greenhouse indoor to put a roof over our
head
and and our meal on the table
but it was uh
it was pretty scary when i decided to
stop growing flour and just do seed only
and
i'm glad i did it because it just opens
so many more flavors and that's really
what i love about the plant in the first
place is just being able to
um
understand it better through this
breeding process and seeing how the the
progeny come out from what you think is
going to be good and then when it
doesn't come out you just have these
high hopes and you're like why didn't it
work maybe i go the opposite direction
and reverse this one or try some
different pollen but it uh it takes
years of of watching the plant and
and doing having a lot of failure to
breed in order to figure out what really
works and
and
what will be desirable not only for you
but hopefully
the the community accepts it well too
i wanted to add on with what alan was
saying just a minute ago about what
works for you
because i think that's part of how you
find something unique it's
not just that it's different than the
other things that you've experienced or
looked at or played with but that
it
like for me there's been
i don't know half dozen times in my
breeding
where a specific plant really called out
to me really spoke to me loud and clear
pay attention
work with me
and i think that's some of what alan's
referring to that there's something
within you that responds to that plant
and i do think there's a back and forth
communication if we are open to it
and i think
nevada county is the kind of place where
folks are open to that kind of
conversation
yeah i was going to say that sparked a
word that popped into my mind the
intuition of a grower and of a breeder
and
like having that connection with a plant
is a pretty special thing and not
everybody has that
but if you do have that you know it's a
pretty amazing feeling when you have
that connection
and when things work out how you
expected it
any other questions out there
sure let's let's all give a two quick
couple seconds about that
thanks great question obviously
everybody always wants to have that you
know conversation with people i really
love og strain i love sour diesel
og's definitely like something that
really resonated with me always and
still does
in fact i'm growing a bunch of og this
year and i feel like the world we need
to bring og back
there's
no disrespect to gelato but
we've got to break it up a little bit
and then
way back i used to grow a couple strains
that took a really long time and i
haven't grown them in a long time but
i've been really getting the urge um the
ds i don't know if anybody remembers
that it was colombian haze people called
it the dog shit or the dreadlock strain
and it took uh it took like 10 12 weeks
to flower
but it had a super unique nose like
really pungent
and and then i at the same time when i
was growing that strain i grew the cough
which is the nl5 crossed with the haze
and that took around the same amount of
time and
amazing flower like it was pretty
popular in this area for a little while
some of us people have been around a
little while remember the days of the
cough um you know you used to be able to
like
grow a plant in a 15 gallon pot and it
would take you know
three months four months to
grow at four months i guess
and um but you know you get so much
flour and back then it was like so
unique and
there wasn't a whole lot of people
growing hazel's then and
so
i feel like i need to get back to some
of those things i've definitely
experimented with all kinds of stuff
growing lots of cookies lots of gelatos
skittles and all those things and
they're fun
but
og and hazes are definitely something
that
reaches uh
something special in a bone inside of me
i'd say the
the one thing that marked me for life
was malawi gold which is a it was a
african land race that took 145 days
indoors to flower
it looked terrible
but
it got you so freaking high was that it
was like being on the verge of starting
a mushroom trip
and it had this really distinctive
grated carrot smell
um other than that the the chem dog d
when it first came to northern
california just like rock my boots like
most potent shit ever and smelled like
some old bum sock or something but
the the worse the description of the
strain the better it is to smoke so
but yeah those are my two
i've got some uh older uh cherry pie and
i just love the cherry pie man that's
just got the the terps on that just are
just like i want to eat it
so i keep that one going and then i'm a
sucker for old school blue dream i mean
blue dream just the way it grows you
know it's just seems spindly and like
you're thinking well i'm going to pull
those plants and the next thing you know
they're just ginormous
and
it's just a great smoke too so those are
mine too
um
well back in the days when i smoked
flour
um
i had a cultivar
called genius that uh was pretty popular
and i enjoyed smoking it and it was very
intense high experience
uh down in the bay area
like you allen
then started working with
what's now known as the pre-98 bubba
kush
and then when i started making hash
seriously
tried to make a living growing sour
diesel indoors
because it makes such great hash
uh
glossy black beautiful
anyway
uh
so nowadays yeah i uh all of the
the currently popular uh flower types i
mostly
again look for the extractions and the
the hash or rosin that's made from them
and i don't have a specific particular
favorite flavor there i recently tried
some strawberry banana rosin that was
very nice
i also like the fruity things
and long answer here but i'm a chatty
guy
obviously i like the cbd strains
harlequin flip to name one maddie hayes
uh ac dc some of the others don't try
and grow ac dc in nevada county
it's not good here it's much better on
the mendocino coast
tell me this um i have a cross that's
acdc and um blueberry from uh dj short
he calls it rosa berry and i that one
grows great here but it's just a it's a
half and half cross huh
those sound very interesting gentlemen
anybody else have any questions
well
i'm sure we'll share
yes sir
so you know i know we all kind of run
different fertilizers and different
inputs and stuff curiosity
i'm 100 organic always as as most people
uh know about me i own vital garden
supply
so
i recommend using rs fertilizers
i'll pass the mic down the line so i
don't look like i'm
doing too much of a commercial here
i use a lot of vital earth products
but i also use a lot of other stuff too
so
no bad chemicals but i do like some of
the production stuff is done with
rockwool and salts just because the
it's just it's brainless simple it works
and it's just for production it's not
for smoking or anything like that
um
uh yeah
if there's a way to grow i've done it
like bury a body in the ground and bear
grow over that i've done it like you
know my grandfather used to bury a dead
cat and a dog doberman pincher and an
apple tree grew like crazy so i figured
it's got to work so
we're we're totally organic here too are
we planting the ground um our foothill
soil are you from up here do you live up
here
yeah up here at you know our soil mostly
came from decomposed granite so if you
just don't add organic matter or a good
compost to it in a couple of years
you've got like sand
so i always organic compost every year i
top dress with that and um i don't know
if you guys sell this or not but there's
a compressed chicken pellet that
stutzman makes two three four or
something like that for a low potency
but uh
yeah very similar but um but low you
know not heavy on the fertilizer at all
just just what they need and uh what
else do we use
up here we need oyster shell lime and
soft rock phosphate
um
because i'm no longer a production
farmer it's what i'm going to say is a
lot easier to achieve
but
because i have always grown cannabis for
making medicine
i wanted to make my own inputs i didn't
want to buy things because
like one of my favorite lines is what
does inner ingredients mean
right you're going to spray that on a
plant that you're going to make oil from
and give it to a child no
so uh i do a lot i uh lactobacillus
cultures
uh knfimo one and two is mostly what i
do i haven't gotten into three and four
yet
uh because i get such good results with
those
um and those and again the soil here i
have red clay
it's no longer red it's dark dark
beautiful brown soil in our garden
because for years
we've just added layers of compost and
mulch
occasional worm castings cover crops top
and drop more mulch that kind of thing
making a lasagna bed
where when you take a plant and plug it
into a spot in the ground its roots will
find
the layer in the soil that works for
that plant and then they take off and
they they will literally make a net
that ends up a net of roots in the soil
that ends up being as big as the plant
is above the soil
and so
uh for years we haven't tilled our
garden we just do the things i just
described and so
once in a while we'll add azomite
you know
to supplement some minor minerals that
our soil is somewhat deficient in uh
soil tests
several times say our our particular
soil is
they say the best fertilizer is the
farmer's shadow