my own background on this issue is I was
contacted by three different NFL teams
technically I was hired by a criminal
defense lawyer in in in two of the cases
who was working with teams because what
we saw going on in the late 2000s early
2011 2010 2011 period was that you had a
bunch of doctors affiliated with NFL
teams who were a little bit wowed by the
celebrity of being around NFL players
and what we saw was just all the rules
went out the door security secured sort
of storage of prescription medications
vicodin was like it was you know you
talk about pill we talked about pill
mills being places where doctors were
just giving out the opioids they weren't
selling them on NFL teams they were just
giving them out and putting them in the
hands of players and not practicing
medicine they were debating just
enabling a bad culture so so if they Ana
if the NFL Players Association wanted to
work with me what I would say first and
foremost is we need the conversation
needs to get outside of just talking to
to goodall's office right that the
bottom line is the commissioner and the
league have been so myopic and so locked
down on the potential for cannabis to be
a difference maker and also to the
destructive role that opioids are
playing the role in which they're
masking pain serious nerve damage and
and and just and leading to a physical
dependency that's leaving so many
players both still in the league and
retired really suffering and so I I
think this needs to be a national
conversation and I think the Players
Association needs to take that message
to the American public right the
American public has stood with NFL
players on the concussion issues on
their concerns around concussions
there's a deep sympathy right everyone
was shocked when when when Nike created
like a campaign that was really heroic
around NFL players I know is divisive
but I'm saying for that was heroic
around players standing up for what they
believed in so I think that the NFL
Players Association should go to the
American public and really taken make an
advocacy advocacy
playing campaign that will get this away
from roger goodell and and in the hands
of and make this a concern that the that
the that the the league is you know
understands that viewers are unhappy
that the league is essentially
perpetuating the opioid crisis right and
missing a huge opportunity to offer a
new therapeutic and i think that is an
awareness that starts with awareness and
that starts with players sharing their
stories and and i'm excited to hear from
Cosima and i and I really think you know
hearing from players currently dealing
with the the stress on the human body of
playing football and alumni veterans who
are living with the effects after the
extent to which people are sacrificing
their bodies and and the role that
opioids are playing I think would be
just mind-boggling for and I think I
think people would people care right I
remember 1996 I was I was just a baby
lawyer back then but when Brett Favre
was addicted to vicodin when that came
out that just like blew my world like I
I and and it was amazing to me to think
back how that didn't register with
everybody you know it was just another
story of one person's addiction we
didn't think about it in a systemic way
so what I would say to the Players
Association is you've got such an
opportunity this moment in time we're
just we're really just beginning to wrap
our heads around you know how big this
crisis is and to take people who so many
Americans look up to to might you know
my own kids I have four kids you know
who are really like their heroes are I
don't want to be unpopular in LA I'm
from a Detroit Lions fan I know Kasim I
know you spend a year or two there but
uh but but to be able to like I think I
think that's an issue that gets through
to people and that would move the needle
and getting away from just letting the
league a you know tell its own story on
this would be all the difference in the
world