[Music]
Lance Lambert coming here from Barcelona
Spain for spannabis 2019 we're on the
final day here I've got a special guest
next to me Nick Denham
he is a true master of rasen was a
recent judge of the Masters arroz in
which we sponsored that just went down
last night but it's been kind of a
week-long thing did welcome give thanks
for having me man just blessed to be out
here in Spain for real the masters of
rosin has kept me high for a week
seriously the amount of entries the
amount of quality entries that I wanted
to go back and retry has been insane you
know a lot of quality increase since
last year the year before just traumatic
quality increases out here in Spain well
now and man it's funny because although
you look like a younger guy to the game
you've been doing it for a minute we
were talking we're talking a few decades
and being a colleague I - which
obviously you're close to the source of
some quality in itself yeah you know
I've been doing this more than half my
life this is my life I'm super blessed
to have parents and family that
supported everything that I've done all
the moves that I've made I started
operating in Colorado back in 2009 and
started the first tax-paying hash
company in the u.s. essential extracts
I'm just blessed to still be here dad my
man and I recognize that name once I had
to kind of put it all together we were
talking about similar ties for our
California Colorado back to California
for both of us and in knowing that we
recognize the differences in the market
over there how do they compare though to
what you're seeing here you talked about
such things are getting better but how
is it compared to back home would you
say fresh I mean the increase in quality
this year is insane it's creating a
competing market to the US really and
we're seeing it you know like not to put
anybody on blast but we see a lot of US
companies bringing product out here to
Spain
and last year I think a lot of the
California flowers here in Spain were
selling really really well this year I'm
looking for the local flowers because
the local growers are stepping up game
seriously so yeah I'm seeing the same
thing man and that's one thing I was
just talking to a friend over loud seeds
and he was kind of talking about the
whole convert yeah yeah yep you know
James and talking about the whole fact
that you know you've got these genetics
guys that are coming down from from the
Netherlands these guys who are coming
out from the west coast and just just
collabing not competing but collabing
right and as something that's carrying
into obviously into your craft as well
definitely definitely you know people
out here are really really hunting fee
knows it's something that I've noticed
that the European market really does is
they're popping a lot more seeds than
we're popping in the US especially in
places like Morocco and places where
they have a large agricultural area that
can do such things we're seeing of
amazing female hunts and with that comes
fee knows that are yielding way better
in hash so I mean you know big up my
friends at Lok colada big up grateful
seeds big up la Sagrada fam a lot of
these cats are really really pushing the
boundaries of what they can do out here
and they're finding amazing fee notes
that are really really proper for
solving this hash do that and that's
excellent to hear and for some of you to
do a bit of homework Gino is one factory
the whole genotype of the phenotype is
next level and exactly an x-point it
just brings so much more craft to the
culture just brings so much more flavor
to the experience because it's not about
the race to the top and THD that's a
furthest a lot of us that really respect
this plant wanted to be about so tell me
again I mean you're a master in your own
right what are some of the other hash
makers or who I should say even more so
are some of the other hash makers you
almost kind of look up to or maybe
mentored a little bit from out there um
you know out here actually in Europe one
of my mentors and one of the women that
taught me so much about making hash is
Mila Jansen they call her the hash queen
so big up Mila each and every time you
know I've learned so much from so many
different generations back in the day
full melt bubble mark aka bubble man's
website was a huge learning source
more recently about 10 12 years ago we
created a website and forum called
extract artists which I've been teaching
in but I've also been learning in you
know there's a lot of different avenues
I think that we've we've all been
learning via a lot of oral tradition you
know originally when I first went out to
Amsterdam to study under miele in the
early 2000s there wasn't anything
written about this I had to go bug Mila
in her shop in her production facility
and be like hey you know how do I get to
this color how do I get to this
consistency is this rinsing thing that
I'm doing good you know and and nowadays
we tour all throughout the world Mila
and I teaching each other and teaching
people as well you know Mila gives me
credit for bringing fresh frozen and the
idea of running fresh frozen material to
Europe and I really give her a lot more
credit than that a lot of the credit
came from Mila for the whole rinsing
thing just briefly mentioned but the
technology of rinsing your hash after
you've collected your hash back in the
day when I learned that is really really
up my game you get rid of a lot of the
impurities by rinsing out those
trichomes after you've collected them
and that's one of the texts that I
learned from Mila that's cool man and
you mentioned fresh frozen which is
something that it's almost can I take
him back home not too big on Kalle but I
see I become a more popular seems to be
it guys it's a little bit easier to turn
the crops if they're able to just set
some stuff now there's a whole
refrigerator I mean it's a whole other
category right as far as being able to
have a place refrigerate but you're
probably like fresh frozen we're seeing
more of that I mean I talked to one of
our friends as growers 25% of his crop
went straight to the chillers so that's
something you're seeing more of - in
your space yeah there's a number of
reasons we're seeing more of it number
one we're able to take a cultivation and
go in there and help consult and get rid
of an entire room where they're trimming
and drying material right all of these
employees that don't actually work for
them but are coming in on a hire basis
to trim the material that you know
creates a lot more issues with theft and
quality control and things like that you
get rid of all of them we can turn that
room into another flowering room or a
mom's stable to keep all your genetics
right you're not having to pay all those
trimmers and we're bucking the material
straight from the fuckin field right
into a freezer so it saves a lot of time
and a lot of money for the grower
that's one of the big things that we're
promoting and you know it's crazy to
talk about fresh frozen cuz I think it
really started in Colorado with that
legal market and the regulated system
out there kind of pushed towards fresh
frozen and then the live rep Rose Live
resin guys grabbed it right after we
started promoting it and saying hey
we're running live fresh material
they're like oh shit maybe we could run
that in our closed loops and now we're
seeing the live resin the live rosin and
it's really cool to see those are some
of my friends on the live resin side
that kind of coined the term live resin
and I got nothing but love for them it's
just creating higher quality for the
whole industry so big up fresh frozen
heats and every time for real you're
retaining a lot more terpenes when
you're using fresh frozen especially
when you have a lot more of these air
volatile terpenes the gassy terpenes the
Kem's the diesels those are escaping
immediately if you fresh freeze that
material we're able to lock those in a
lot easier and I've noticed here that's
exact
exactly got the rise into my pocket it's
all about the fresh frozen your point
because it's just a totally different
from a turkey standpoint for someone who
appreciates really I know it's a
played-out term but the full spectrum
not just again all about the the you
know loudness of the cannabinoids it
really does preserve that and you don't
lose it through the rest of the process
like you said so that's awesome to hear
so what are talked about some of the
different styles whose mentored you
what's your style like what what is it
you mentioned rinsing but I'm sure
there's a few other jump to share all
the secret sauce but but what have you
found to really make your own to make
you so unique and as popular as you've
done and become really you know I think
a lot of it is my openness my my
communication skills is I think a big
part of it you know because I think
there's a lot of amazing hash makers out
there but I don't know if all of them
have really utilized their skill and
promoted what they're doing and really
taught you know the industry and that's
really what I pride myself on is
creating a higher echelon for the end of
and not just teaching the people that
want to learn but I mean I'm teaching
what people are calling competitive
companies and they're not competitive to
me the more education that's out there
the more that those competitive
companies are also teaching solvent less
methodology the more my product sells so
I think one of the things that's really
you know made me stand apart is my
willingness to teach and learn the same
way you know I'm not ever gonna stop
learning myself so that's where I'm at
man I'm just I'm just blessed to be here
yeah yeah and again stoked that we were
able to connect and catch shot me in
this some Nick clearly we're on the last
day final hours were you'd be able to
come by and get some time and man I know
you had a crazy my team I said we've
over to sponsored last night's my whole
team was there and I don't even they
they got our bed till 11 o'clock so
definitely applaud you I don't think I
went to sleep until seven or eight I got
home from to the Airbnb like six seven
in the morning so yeah sounds about
right but it's one we look forward to
man had something in HQ obviously
supports it being back in it and the
whole week just building it up building
it up building it up and this something
again I love that it gets the attention
it does you know yeah man it's been a
great vibe a great year spannabis 2019
hairdo from Nick alrighty guys thanks
again for sure cannabis project in this
land slammer