[Music]
let's open it up to Q&amp;A I mean what do
you guys I mean we've kind of covered in
most of the major issues within the
industry what questions do you have for
our panel any one question yes in the
back okay so the question has to do with
entry level if you're a smaller player
if if it's becoming really difficult for
a small business person to enter into
the industry what's the area that they
could enter into laboratory testing it's
state mandated every products got to go
through a laboratory to be tested for
for purity and and that it has the
appropriate levels and it's free from
pesticides it's it's state mandated no
matter how many businesses are out there
they all got to go through the labs so
you still have to the laboratory
equipment in hiring the scientist is
expensive I mean it seems like
extraction is is really because you
could buy an extra no no the the states
the states like to keep that firewall
where they have the labs totally
independent from and in some states
producers in some states it's the state
that does the testing there are no
independent labs like I think it's at
Pennsylvania that I think it's a
Pennsylvania maybe DC but there's some
places where the states actually well I
just learned this week that in Arizona
there is no license for testing yeah one
of our customers says we'd like to be in
your database like great you have a
license no we don't need one in this
state like okay we'll put you in but so
it differs by state in Connecticut you
need a controlled substances license so
if you go look at all those licenses in
Connecticut they're all the police
stations and the universities and then
you can find a couple that seemed to be
more corporate or just their own
business so but
just in transport you can test your well
that's you know I mean today I feel like
extraction you could buy an extraction
machine for what about sixty thousand a
hundred thousand right right right
and then then there's obviously well
distribution well that starts to become
but but but did the question about the
Jersey in New York I think the hard part
is those are still oligopoly is there's
only a handful licenses out there and in
New York the licenses are stacked so if
I give you a license in New York you
have to grow you have to manufacture and
you have to run five stores four stores
so you have to do it all so there is no
easy way for somebody to say hey I want
to do that too I mean and I think in New
Jersey it's the same way it's a stack
license so it's vertically integrated by
design every states different though
like in Connecticut they've stacked it
where you have to if you get a grow
license you have to manufacture and
there's four of those licenses but now
they're moving up to eighteen
dispensaries and it's just now we have
one license it actually managed to
vertically integrate but they did that
on their own
so the Cuomo proposal for New York very
much models the California distribution
change where there's gonna be cultivator
licenses manufacturer license
distributor license retail and
laboratory testing manufacturer are the
guys who take the raw cannabis material
they extract it out and make a product
or oil or whatever that you have to keep
the to grow and the retail separate like
right now it's vertically integrated
right but I was reading that that Cuomo
doesn't want that he wants the grocery I
know it's either New York or New Jersey
I can't remember which but one of them
in their proposal does have that quark
where if you're a retailer you can't
have your own cultivation license which
is I don't know what the rationale
behind it we're Colorado they have a
specific license it does just that which
is like a captive license so it's every
state is different and comes up with
their own peculiarities I was gonna say
at least for the California experience
and the retail market is
extremely competitive and one of the
ways that like brands have set
themselves apart is to be like a really
great cultivator have a retail location
in your name where you can only get
certain products like it's a sneaker
drop and there's a line you know two
blocks out there to get the latest
harvest if they actually a cottage
license they call it a cottage license I
think in California for those kind of
scenarios where people are you know
really craft growers and sellers I'm
just so like wherever we are now in a
couple of years I mean there's certainly
you know a lot of people only want to be
self-employed and don't want to work for
someone and I certainly respect that I'm
self-employed but there's tons of jobs
you could check out Thanks
va and GST indeed actually post cannabis
jobs now if you look at some of the MSOs
most of them have career sections on
their websites whether it's acreage or i
anthis cure leaf you know some of that
the new york's even locally i think that
one of our clients KD s staffing there
in new jersey and they're recruiting for
him and they've built out a cannabis
practice there nearby so question over
here mary's list
sign up as an employer so Mary's las'
independent contractors flower hire okay
flower hire thank you thank you another
question
know anything about Monsanto's role in
the cannabis industry as it relates to
cultivator and what type of protections
actually have you heard any government
officials talking about rolling out
protections for cultivators farmers and
growers who do create a certain strain
and being able to own I keep very good
question about first starting about
Monsanto but then really going into like
patenting strains I was out in Humboldt
County and I know California you may
know better than me but they were
talking about kind of creating in
Humboldt County this this standard which
would be similar to what you see in the
wine industry that you can only claim
you know champagne is from the champagne
area and it gets thank you appellation
and that you know you can only call
yourself Humboldt finest if you're from
Humboldt County and then it gets into
the tour yeah so that is what I've heard
I know that there's been a lot of
discussion about trying to patent
cannabinoids and such GW Pharmaceuticals
just got rejected on that they tried to
do that I know different people have
come out
had to patent different strains and I
don't know if they've been so successful
I think it's hard to patent a plan
that's the problem
I think and and we've also seen a lot of
while you can call something Sour Diesel
that when they've tested it cloning and
all that that they've determined that
half the time when you think you're
buying you know cherry diesel sour it
isn't even really that's something like
with lab tests it really has to go a
step further besides pesticides and
contaminants and all this I mean you
they really have to figure out how to
really test for these strains that
genetic testing the whole package yeah
really long way to go there's that this
industry has a lot of growth there's a
company out in Long Island a does DNA
mapping and they did it with cotton and
that's how they determine what pima
cotton is versus not pima cotton and
Egyptian cotton and all these cotton
varieties and that's what they've done
is they DNA mapped it and that they're
they're trying now to get into cannabis
so that they can map the the cannabis
plants and and we resolved that well
know everything Deborah
somebody else accidentally Stacy gelato
and calling it something else and it
wines that they the same thing like to
be heard did your Grover have concerned
about and he kind of like this person
clearly doesn't understand genetics or
the plants because
that is fascinating you're saying
stealing
company does have technology
because that patience
that there Derek said there's the hope
and Canada's project there's pylos
there's with this one genomics at a loss
there's a lot of yeah
right love that
well and I think that that's you know
there are some strains that are very
popular but you have to wonder is it
just marketing is it really the strain
you know I think that the one thing that
I really haven't seen a lot of work on
was the THC V which is the cannabis that
doesn't give you the munchies and
apparently it was extremely hard to
extract it's very expensive you don't
see it very often that's the only one
that I've heard about that hasn't really
had a lot of success you know I was at a
conference I think in Toronto and they
had a person who really was starting to
talk about all the tests and trials that
were running in Israel and he shared the
number of terpenes and other elements
that are in these plants and he said
they're like decades of research left to
do because there are so many
interactions to try and figure out based
on what's in each of these sort of
fingerprinted plants as she said I mean
there's so much work to do that there's
gonna be a lot of research and you know
hopefully a lot of great discovery but
it's it's incredibly complex so when
people just sort of boil it down to oh
its THC or CBD they're missing out on
the other you know hundred and ten
things that you need to yeah the whole
spectrum that you really need to look at
so the question has to do with vaping
what we're hearing I know that it's
clearly becoming a product of choice
that the consumers are gravitating more
towards vape products that gives you a
mood description sleep relax action
inspire whatever versus a vape that is
Sour Diesel like apparently that's where
the shopping is going that's according
to ease data that will be coming out
this week and a report that I have
written that will publish on Wednesday
but I thought that was super interesting
that the sales are gravitating to that
mood related vape product versus the
strain related bait product and vape
products are definitely on the rise and
overtaking the say
of flour in a Deborah's conference a
couple months ago one of the speakers
that you had their tracks does a lot of
market research like consumer type
market research and her point was that
there has been such an increase in the
number of vape companies and and the
point was sort of like how many can the
market support so the specialization
that you describe makes a lot of sense
because now the market is starting to
specialize and certain ones will win out
but I think her point was you know we
have 485 vape companies do you really
want to be number 486 and how will you
differentiate yourself so you marketing
yeah but still only if you will win I
think the interesting thing that we're
seeing with vape companies or in just
manufacturers in general is that in an
open I'm gonna call it as opposed to
like a closed state like New York where
it's a very small number of licensees in
an open state like California where
there's you know hundreds or thousands
of manufacturing license issued and
they're making oil is that folks aren't
ready for the level of manufacturing
hygiene practices that that the state
requires in order to maintain your
licenses because you're we're
transitioning from an industry where it
was just a bunch of guys in a warehouse
with a machine processing cannabis flour
to now the states looking at all right
well is your facility facility design
logical what quality control measures
are you implementing in place to make
sure that there's no cross contamination
or allergens in your product and and for
a lot of these folks it's a huge wake-up
call because they're they're used to you
know running retail shops and now
they're manufacturing they're putting
hundreds of thousands of vape cartridges
into the marketplace and with that comes
products liability what happens when
something goes wrong what do you do when
you have to implement a recall and just
you know we talked about this you know
constant tension between the multi-state
operators the big business the deep
pockets and then the regulatory for the
regular people who are working within
this industry and that's like a real
point of regulatory failure that's
to happen is that a lot of these
mom-and-pop manufacturers they just
aren't going to be able to keep up with
the quality control standards necessary
to produce you know clean products and
put it into the marketplace I would say
though that you know it doesn't take
that much it doesn't take that big of an
office or factory I don't you know to
produce this because your extraction
machine is really not that big and you
know it's maybe the size of that bar
area you your biggest inventory areas
where you've got all your raw product
that's because it's so chunky and and
all these like bins and such your
scientists your lab people you know it's
really I've been to many of these
operations they're not that big but
they're churning out tons and tons of
babe and a lot of the big vape companies
private label for a lot of people so
like open vape private labels from
numerous companies they'll just come in
and say hey I want you know green marker
report vape pen and they're like yeah
sure you know we're going to charge you
an arm and a leg to do it but yeah we'll
do it and they make your vape pen for
you and they slap your label on it and
they distribute it for you and you're
good to go but of course you're probably
given up 50% of your your revenue for
them to do that but you're immediately
in the market and very easy it's really
super quick but you're paying through
the nose for that but I'll tell you
right now they're a private company
they're doing over 100 million in sales
a year
[Music]
I'm John I'm just saying that it's it's
big business I mean there's there about
the only one I know that has really said
how much money they're making off of a
pence now they were early to the market
they were early on in Colorado they do a
nice operation it's a really well-run
company they take very good care of
their employees and they've had no
desire to go public
I think they'll eventually go public
just because yell yeah why not I mean
I've worked hard I you know worked long
long hours week after week month after
month year after year yeah I'm tired I'm
ready to get out and I think that may be
why they go public but listen they've
only had to raise money once and they
did it with one investor open babe no
they bootstrapped it's an incredible
story they bootstrapped
and now they're doing over 100 million
in sales a year and they're really smart
about loyalty programs they're really
smart about working with the bud tenders
they have loyalty programs with the cup
customers they have loyalty programs
with the bud tenders
so that would they were one of the first
companies that figure that out
and now almost all the dispensaries have
loyalty programs but I don't know that
that many of the product companies do
that I've talked to a bunch of them and
I usually ask him if they do that you
know does Popham Barkley do that does
can't doesn't do that and most of them
say no and it's just crazy it's like why
wouldn't you do that the other thing
we're seeing with vape sand and if
here's like your side business if you
don't have the capital to get a license
is just counterfeiting like they're
they're they're you can go on Alibaba
now and buy the packaging for any big
vape brand in the United States and and
they're you know being sold wherever
it's it's low quality product that
they're putting into it but but folks
don't care some of these brands have
built up such a brand recognized
and status symbol associated with them
folks just want to you know get it as
cheaply as possible to have the look
we've gone from counterfeit Yeezys and
counterfeit Gucci to counterfeit vapes
now so there's a market and and product
security like whatever that technology
is going to be so that folks know that
they have like the real vape cartridge
because folks in California are losing a
lot of money to copycats they're not
being sold in the retailers they're
being sold on the streets and unlicensed
stores they're being shipped to places
where cannabis isn't allowed as if it
were the real thing right so the point
I'm making is is that they're people
just want to have the look of the
product and it's being counterfeited out
there so people are willing to buy the
bootleg knockoff version of these
manufactured products because they don't
want to pay the cannabis tax and all the
costs associated with the real thing why
buy the $70 dosis pen when I can buy the
bootleg dosis pen for 25 bucks who knows
what's in it it's never been lab tested
but it's white and it vibrates and it
looks like doses it's like that weed van
that you see around the Union Square I
mean that thing is so illegal and it's
so bright when I've walked up to that
van before and just asked a few
questions the minute I started asking a
couple of questions they were like no we
don't sell that at all like when I first
walked up yeah we got that and then all
of a sudden I'm like but you can't do
that because that's illegal right we
don't sell that like and they're
complete their blatant they're just
driving around thinking humor man no no
ice cream truck but mr. Safi one thing
they like about these vape products from
my experience like a few of them are
made in China and they're all made in
China the hardware really really poor
quality and they're it's almost like
you're sucking in chemicals of some sort
like they're not healthy there's clear
there clearly is a health risk with some
of these products
and the ones that don't have that
problem they leak I've had some just
busted in my pocket in which markets
well there I've gotten I've had this
experience pretty much across the board
but some units if you go to em jape is
that the big conference in Vegas got
that there were there's so many Chinese
and they their signs are all in Chinese
like there's heart they hardly speak any
English some do well that's the actual
cartridge it has to be tested the actual
product I'm talking about like if you
think of it as the battery and the the
component that you actually put the
ceramic heating that's good so we have a
question over here
and the concerns that that causes for
lung cancer or bubble bones and that's
not hit the industry as a publicist that
kind of like blows my mind that views
reporters just like when after my
clients and the whole thing we have to
you know help out and it's not hit
cannabis or mates yet and so I think
that anybody who is going to have a
vaporizer it does need to be prepared
for that because it will eventually
happen and there is the heating coils
depending on the quality of the
manufacturer some of them are you know
like for example Joule those heating
coils are much stronger and harsher on
the lungs than right and I think that
her point you know is that we still have
a long way to go to know what is going
to be the effect of all these vape pens
and you've got a variety of products
because you do have like a dry material
type of vape pen where you put the dry
material in and it heats it up and then
you had that combustion and and you're
basically smoking a dry product whether
it's tobacco or cannabis but then like
pax pax has the dry herb product and
then you've got the actual vape pens
with the oil which is a very different
product but very convenient but yeah I
don't think we've really seen very many
studies on the effects of these items
anybody else all right well I think
we've gone over a lot
I thank my panel for being here on this
very cold night and I thank you guys for
showing up on this very cold night and I
think it's been very and I check out
remarket report.com for the best
journalism a thank you unbiased
[Applause]
[Music]