he's asking what's the major differences
between the Northern Lights cuts you
hold because they were all named numerix
what's the significance of that and what
does it mean to you and how you use them
so that's a very good question so we
would really need the guys here that
originally bred the northern light
strands to answer all these questions
but from what I've read and understand
and what I've heard through the cannabis
culture is Northern Lights number one is
the pure form two three were crossed
indicas NL five six seven eight nine
were crossed uh sativas the hybridize NL
v has the best bagged peel and the best
marketable bud NL two has the strongest
most indica a lot of Juniper just real
cush smell Northern Lights number one is
the backbone of all the other ones you
can smell it in there it was the
building block it's what Neville used if
he had a clone and he wanted to recreate
that clone he that was the male he used
when he wanted to make a pure hash plant
off the hash plant cutting he back
crossed off of the Northern Lights
number one when he wanted to bring big
bud to the market and he just had the
big bud clone he back crossed off of
Northern Lights number one it's in it's
a real building block as far as it by
itself it's great smoke but it doesn't
have the back appeal