[Music]
the other thing to say about those
management teams that Deborah referenced
is that I've seen a lot more of them now
being people with a lot of consumer
packaged goods experience they come out
of Procter &amp; Gamble they come out of
molson they come out of other Wrigley so
we're starting to see you know the
management coming in from these other
traditional big company industries and
really start to take some of the senior
roles in in these big brands right I
mean I think the one that bugs me the
most is green growth brands those guys
were all like laid off Victoria's Secret
folks out of Columbus Ohio so they come
into the industry and they're like ah
man all these cannabis dispensaries they
don't know how to sell we know retail
because we sold bras and we're going to
show them how to do it and they buy a
dispensary in Las Vegas the source which
is already doing 17 million dollars a
year so thinking well apparently they
know how to do it because they're doing
17 million dollars a year which is not
too shabby
but yeah their their claim to fame is
that they're all from Victoria's Secret
which in my opinion was a bunch of men
selling bras to women and over
objectifying the women and hyper
sexualizing them and it was awful and
they lost sight of the fact that there
was a whole hashtag me too and college
rape and they were not paying attention
to that and to me they were not really
good retailers and to come into the
connect cannabis industry a little late
to the party and to say that they knew
how to do it and no one else did really
bugged me but what's interesting is that
they just made a bid to buy another
company and that kind of brings us to
our next topic which is consolidation
we're seeing a ton of consolidation
happening in the market right now I feel
like every week I'm talking about
another
acquisition that happen is happening
let's let's talk about that cuz Matt up
obviously your you pay a lot of
attention to all these acquisitions as
you're following these companies yeah I
and I think we're gonna continue to see
that because if you think about it you
know
the way it is right now early on it was
the mom and pops and some of these well
capitalized companies came in and then
they got bigger bigger bigger and they
went to Canada and they listened they
got additional capital and now they're
just scooping up all these licenses but
the smaller guys really don't have a
chance in my opinion of sustaining so to
your point yeah would you rather just
get the license off the cut out of the
gate and then get tapped on the shoulder
and be cashed out of twenty million
dollars yeah exactly that's exactly
what's happening we just saw in
Connecticut there was GTI's in
Connecticut now thirty something billion
not a million dollars there's all kinds
of those plays going on and this is to
the point I made earlier is that that
thirty billion or thirty million
valuation that could be cut in half
tomorrow if the state decided to you
know issue additional licenses and I
think you're gonna see a continued wave
green wave of these type of you know
plays do you think it makes sense that
these states start to limit that Crisco
labs or an acreage Holdings can only
have X amount of licenses per state so
that so that we don't end up with you
know America coming in and buying twenty
of the licenses because they got some
money the thing is - right so you have
to be mindful of the future of the
industry right so we're sort of kind of
near the end zone sort of maybe when
prohibition ends so you know whatever
happens now like it's gonna change when
when federal laws change and the federal
government could have a completely
different view on how this whole entire
markets regulated so it's really hard to
call how you know what any state's gonna
do and if it's favorable or unfavorable
because it could change it could only
have a limited life
and mergers and consolidation is
happening like it's huge what's
happening and and if they tried to limit
the number of licenses that one you know
one entity could hold them they're gonna
move to a management model or a
franchising model they're gonna hire you
know high-priced lawyers to figure out a
way around it you know if these states
you know want regular people to get into
the industry I'm gonna harp on this
point hoping some state regulator sees
it you need to lower the barrier to
entry because the timeline to get a
cannabis business off the ground is is
18 months to 24 months and to the vast
majority of people to hold on to a piece
of real estate pay rent on an empty
building go through the costs of putting
together plants architecture drawings
operational plans whatever you need to
submit to your state all of these
thousands of dollars add up to a quarter
million dollars or a half million
dollars which is completely unattainable
to these regular folks and and the
states that pay lip-service saying you
know we want to prioritize social equity
we want to give opportunities for folks
who have been harmed by the war on drugs
then do something meaningful because you
know telling folks without money that
they're first in line is completely
illusory unless you're actually
providing meaningful funding or
assistance to help those folks get
through the program and and that you
provide a real way for them to qualify
to get licenses that's part of the
problem what happened in Massachusetts
they were the first state to champion
social equity but very few applicants
were able to make it through due to the
capital cost involved to go through the
licensing process and until that happens
you know it's just going to be big money
big capital who are either going to play
a predatory role and and you know set up
really bad deals for the social equity
applicant in order for the company to
get priority or we're just gonna see
consolidation will continue to seek
consolidation rather than new folks you
know entering the marketplace and that's
that's the biggest challenge that we're
seeing because more
more of the cities and states are doing
competitive licensing they want to they
want to find the best operators who who
have tons and tons of experience and and
who are going to be you know low risk
for the city you know low risk for the
city and setting up shop if you've never
run a cannabis business before you're
just automatically disqualified because
you know you don't have the ability to
be in California first or you haven't
been in Massachusetts before now you
know the the states need to think about
you know you you did actually following
through and not just just talking about
raising people up and providing
opportunities for people it needs to be
broad low-cost entry into the regulated
market otherwise the unlicensed market
the unregulated market it's just going
to continue to thrive building on Erin's
point as we watch licenses build in
Massachusetts the state would actually
tell people how long it might take and
some of the timelines were 300 to 500
days to get through the medical license
process and you know I know this isn't
in this region but one of the biggest
stories in the fourth quarter last year
was Oklahoma which started issuing
licenses kind of like crazy I think I
took today they issued about 2,500
licenses in the course of 45 days and
the cost per license is $2,500 I think
the state raised six million dollars
just in licensing fees so they were
pretty happy and now they've got you
know hopefully a licensed infrastructure
there now with only four million people
living in that state and close to 700
dispensaries do the math it's like 5,000
people to a dispensary but at least it
lets the market decide who are the best
operators who are the best retailers who
can make a go of this from cultivation
to manufacturing to running retail so
that's you know sort of a study in
contrast but you know we'll see how it
goes a lot of people are looking at that
state and a lot of my customers are
selling into that state you know they're
selling insurance and other products so
it it appears to be a market that may
have some vibrancy you know what's
interesting though like Vegas or Nevada
like they were six months boom they were
ready rocking and rolling they talked
about how
taxes I went to that planet 13
dispensary the world's largest yes and
yes it was expensive yeah it was crazy
expensive I went I I you know picked up
some flower go to the ring it up and I
think it was like 40 bucks or something
dumb like that I was just bringing home
to my husband and that the guy ring
stopped he's like okay well that's $55
I'm like but no no it was no it's like
40 bucks and he's like that's the tax oh
my god it's killer Wow
yeah no wonder the black market does so
well you know I think it's you know I
don't know I got it kind of feel like
the mom-and-pop ideas gonna is not
workable anymore I mean I think that
that was quaint and nice at the early
days of Colorado but I just don't think
it's well what's interesting is in New
Jersey the last the last round it mean
most of them were multi-state operators
I mean I I think that's going to be the
trick you're not gonna see like the
small guys winning these licenses so
it's the big guys are here and they're
gonna continue to grow
yeah I would say in California we still
have a large number of mom-and-pop
businesses and the trouble you know at
least with California we love California
but they've overly complicated it I
think a lot of those mom-and-pop
businesses though won't be around two
years from now because the the cost of
compliance is so high the amount of
unlicensed competition is so high and
many of those folks who are here today
you know they're they're probably not
going to be here because somebody's
gonna come in and say look it it's it's
easier for me just to buy you then go
through this process myself because it's
so long and cumbersome and and there's
just you know dozens of high net worth
individuals and and public companies
from Canada who are just going on a
shopping spree in California right now
because this historically has been a mom
and pop industry like that like the
cannabis industry up until now has been
a mom and pop industry and and and the
implementation in California has been so
slow
that you know it's easier for people to
buy businesses now then go through the
process but at least in California there
there's a strong push to keep it a
mom-and-pop industry we'll see how it
plays out but all of the multi-state
operators are there or they're coming in
right now as part of that shopping spree
well you made a good point with some of
those regulations I mean some of the
regulations make sense if you're
creating an edible product you need to
have some kind of food standards and
certain standards within your kitchen so
that you are not selling an edible
product to you know people that it might
go bad on the shelf or something like
that but I know that when the July 1st
regulations kicked in a lot of the you
know established companies they just
went out of business they just said we
can't afford to do that I think was it
Mary's medicinals was that there were
some that were really really popular
that that just said yeah we're not gonna
do it but the ones who were ready and
who were remaining on the shelf in that
month after July 1st they're killing it
right now and like canned Essen is one
of those companies where they were way
ahead of the curve and took compliance
seriously and we're ready for that July
1st transition and you know well every
every retailer was like you know
destroying old products or having fire
sales you know on July 2nd canned essent
was there in every store Popham berkeley
is there in every store and and I'm not
doing it to plug those brands but but
they were the companies that like
understood compliance and actually like
read the regulations ahead of time and
built their business strategy around
these dates so they were ready to go
where whereas a you know I would say 85%
of the license cultivators and
manufacturers they just woke up one day
and we're like you know gee whiz we got
to change our packaging in two weeks
otherwise no one's going to buy it at
the retail level so the lesson from
those those really good mom-and-pop
operators is is that look at if you read
the rules you follow them you implement
them in a meaningful way
the
the rest of the industry is going to
provide opportunities for you to rise to
the top because most folks don't take
those compliance deadlines seriously
from the regulatory compliance
standpoint when California started
issuing licenses last year they wanted
to do it by year-end and they started
like middle of December so my partner
and I got off a plane and like we got
the emailing oh my goodness they started
doing it already so we had our research
and start getting the information
together there was one company perhaps a
client appears because they were
impressive that they managed to get
eight licenses from three regulators
within like two weeks so I would see a
systematized was the the name of the the
company so they got a med and a rec
cultivation med and a rec distribution
med in a rec dispensary in a retailer
and maybe delivery I mean but they were
able to line up eight licenses across
three regulators in a short amount of
time so they obviously had a very good
you know set of professionals helping
them and they took the compliant
seriously I mean that they were
certainly an outlier but they really
jumped out at us because they had to
navigate a lot of really hard compliance
work I would imagine I think over time
they like this whole concept of in a
bifurcated market of a medical and a rec
license it's just gonna go away it's
we're already starting to see that
Colorado is really the only state that
continues to track it separately makes
no sense because you have two agents to
authorities within the state regulating
basically the same market right in
California or I'm sorry Massachusetts
that's starting to yes settle out and in
an Oregon the dispensary lists you stab
like five hundred stores on it now it's
down to four that our dispensary only
and in most cases it's a retailer that
has sort of a checkbox on their license
it says yep your permission to do it and
at that point it just becomes like an
SKU at the cash register yeah yeah and
and in every state where a rec market
comes in patient counts go down pretty
steep well they go down but then I've
seen the data that about six months to a
year after the fact they start to come
back they start to haven't seen yeah I
mean they're still down like from the
there
MJ freeway had that data that I don't
know yeah I I see from the states I mean
I'd know what you're talking about I
would disagree with that because it
doesn't it doesn't reconcile with what
the states are reporting and I'm gonna
count well you know that I think we'll
shift gears and start to talk about the
actual investment of these companies
that's something that we really haven't
touched on is some of you know the
valuations on a lot of these companies
most of them are publicly traded it's
getting to the point where there's very
few that aren't publicly traded right
now they've all gone into the public
markets in order to raise money to get
capital and they're either on the CSC or
the OTC there are a handful that have
Canadian companies that have gone on to
the Nicene the Nasdaq the valuations
have been all over the place wildly
volatile right now it seems like we're
in a real down cycle we ended the year
2018 the stocks were way off like down
30% some down 40% and then 2019 we
started to kind of really you know
rebound rebound thank you what do we
think that we're gonna see this year
what do you think I think there's gonna
be continued volatility and I think you
know maybe toward the back of the end of
the year we'll see some rationalization
as more countries make announcements in
the and the world becomes more on board
with with marijuana but like Canada the
big hype was like they were gonna export
to the whole world and there's a huge
oversupply in Canada or there will be
and so you know I think when the market
realizes that that's not they're not
gonna be supplying the whole world the
stocks will contract accordingly there
are starting to come out do you think
that that the prices are really more
getting more in line with what the
companies are doing ie revenue and such
that they were just wildly inflated well
I think it's still too early to tell
because we don't have a lot of history
you know under our belts to really look
at Plus you also have to remember
we don't really have real audited
financial statements yet I mean we have
these I don't want to say subpar firms
but subpar no I don't mean that no I
mean no I don't know I don't I don't I
mean I mean like I mean like mom-and-pop
I don't mean there's a lot of OTC names
that don't I don't mean that against
anything you know they have accountants
that are doing their bookstores not
really yeah securities law accountants
you know audited financials yeah and I
think also like there's still a lot of
like uncertainty in terms of accounting
standards and there's there's no
consistency in the reporting that is
true I mean I have seen various earnings
reports coming out with issues about
valuing the biological assets and that's
become a real issue is how do you value
these biological assets and if you've
had to destroy a crop or throw out a
harvest how do you recognize that on the
books because they haven't dealt with
that before and I know we've seen a lot
of situations come up with med men who
have had accounting issues and you know
they're like we're trying to figure out
if we've got a Canadian stock that we're
trying to then give to our employees who
are American how do we calculate that
and it's something that's not
necessarily been done before and so it's
all new stuff and they're right I mean
there's not that many American companies
who have gone public in Canada who are
now trying to give their American
employees Canadian stock and that's not
a simple process and so they you know
come under fire for things like that but
then to be fair it's it's new territory
it's not easy to figure out how do you
actually calculate all that and they're
certain metrics that investors
especially when the institutions step in
that will be relevant that will move the
stocks you know the yields and and
certain things that are really going to
be more important for
UPS then the revenue or the Ibarra price
well like the cash cost per gram yeah
all that kind the efficiency and how
efficient the operational efficiency any
metrics related to that may move stocks
and I think we're gonna see a lot of you
know this year it's all gonna be record
revenue every quarter is gonna be record
revenue and that's all we're gonna hear
for a year is record well we did hope so
cuz they're making all these at but yeah
it's brand new exactly Spencer ease it's
new markets and so it's gonna be a while
before we get an apples to apples
quarter to where we can tell are they
really operating well exactly and then
one thing to look at I can't remember
which company but that a pretty sizable
accounts receivable balance so how do
you have an AR balance is that
supporting your sales number I mean I
there's a lot of things yeah I think
canopy growth had a harvest that they
had to destroy but it they were
criticized on how they recognize that
and their earnings and so exciting
accounting talk let's talk about the
international market because we you kind
of touched base on that a little bit and
that's really been discussed quite a bit
I think mostly was a Fria I don't know
if you guys have followed that drama its
cannabis industry so there's always
drama but there was a lot of controversy
with that company over its international
acquisitions and you know a lot of these
acquisitions I mean who knows what's
gonna happen in these countries I mean
that's still a real crapshoot still the
Wild West the Wild West
we've started to look at the
international licenses just to see
what's out there and in a lot of
countries we're actually seeing a
structure set up in places like Denmark
and whatnot Colombia has quite a few
licenses for cultivation and Australia
New Zealand so it's definitely starting
to happen but what's interesting we're
talking about this earlier is you know
how each country decides to do things
like delivery and sales like here in the
United States you need to dispenser your
retail you need a store you need a
business you need a license for that you
go up to Canada we're the population
density is a lot less you can just go
through the mail just you get it in the
mail and whereas in Europe you can often
buy it in pharmacies in some cases
insurance will cover it as well health
insurance so very different models so
we're very intrigued to see how this
plays out but we think it's gonna be
about wild wild west but definitely WOW
wild continents there well there's a lot
of expectation that you're going to be
able to set up cultivation shops in
Colombia and export here to the States
and it's oh it's going to be so much
cheaper but I think that's a long way
down if it ever even happens we and and
that's part of it goes back to the
federal prohibition you know where we're
talking about you know maybe companies
having an operation in one state two
states five states the rest of the world
is like looking at this global market
that as of right now and we're not going
to be a part of and we're not going to
be a part of anytime soon
I mean in that whole a free deal that
really surprised me they sold their
florida operation to get the money to
buy the international caribbean stuff
and then the florida people they the
money that that they got they just
flipped those properties and turn around
and sold them and made a ton of money
and i just and now a free has come under
a short attack you know that's kind of
an interesting thing too that we've seen
in the cannabis industry
I feel like more in the cannabis
industry that I've seen in other
industries with the whole short attack
where you got short sellers that find
the company
and they start writing tons of negative
reports about them even if it's true or
not you know the negative reports
central stop down it goes spiraling down
whether it's true or not it's hard to
say but we've seen a lot of that happen
in this in this industry yeah and I
think we'll probably continue to see
more of that as well because I still
think there's plenty of characters still
bad actors that are still remaining and
I think that there's going to be a
plethora of just irregularities
litigation all kinds of things
licensing happened even in the states
where they restrict the licenses it sort
of goes through this phase of just like
groups it's forming storming performing
and norming and you see all those laws
will be yeah exactly exactly so you see
that where there's always a lawsuits
from the people who lost the licenses
and then people wind up not doing the
thing not putting one seed in the ground
but they find a willing buyer Erin got
the license I'm gonna buy it from him
and the transaction happened so I think
we're still gonna see more of this
especially as more states come on but I
think a lot of regulators are learning
from other states and and have tried to
course-correct and make sure that they
come up with a better set of regulation
so that they don't get necessarily you
know tagged with some of the same
problems that the last state that went
through licensure did so maybe just
shorten the storming part hopefully
we're certainly starting to pardon the
pun weed out a lot of the bad players I
know like five or six years ago when I
was writing about these companies there
were so many dodgy people they were so
sketchy and so shady I mean it was it
was easy it was low-hanging fruit for me
as a journalist because all I had to do
was go to a filing and see that you know
the husband sold the wife all the stock
and they're housed in their
brother-in-law's office park that
there's giving five thousand dollars a
month for rent and it was all so easy to
just look at and go this is so shady and
I feel like now that because we've have
some of these MSOs that are polished and
Corp
that it's shaken those people down to
the bottom and they're not just winning
off of having the word cannabis in the
company title anymore they they're
having to really prove themselves and a
lot of them can't do it and they're on
they're truly a penny stock so I think
that that's you know certainly we're
starting to see that maturation of the
market where we're getting rid of those
some of those shady pay and wouldn't
look like the big guys come in like big
pharma big alcohol whatever like it's
just gonna be totally cleaned up well
and I think with the multi-state
operators you know as they go into
different states it's a lot like other
companies decades ago when they go
international and what international
international men or in this case
crossing state lines is you may be
exporting people brands expertise that's
really what's allowing Columbia care to
move from let's say New York into other
states like New Jersey or Virginia
because they've got a track record
they've got people that they can then
move around and say we're gonna put you
in charge of Texas and I think we're
gonna see more of that as they just get
better and better what they do and I
think their metrics in terms of you know
cost program etc is is just gonna be way
better and from a financial standpoint
that'll be a better bet or investment
multi-state is good but at the same time
we're also seeing a little pushback
against it and in the world of
competitive applications you know in in
some of these like sexy cities around
Los Angeles Mad Men wasn't selected in
West Hollywood that they have to close
down their West Hollywood location at
the end of March Mad Men wasn't selected
in Santa Monica for their little
beachfront location a lot of these its
but an out-of-state operator that was
Hollywood things a very weird situation
because I I was given a lot of the City
Council's discussions about that and so
now West Hollywood is going to have no
dispensaries because the existing
players were all all they exit now and
wasn't just been men all the existing
dispensaries in West Hollywood
were rejected for dispensaries that they
might not
be able to open right away because they
had no experience and so West Holly West
Hollywood may have no dispensaries for
several months because the City Council
made that choice it was very strange
I I loved West Hollywood we scored
number one in West Hollywood so I think
West Hollywood got that one right and
but but but that's the pushback and and
it's it's a question for these like
multi estate operators right now they're
just barging into people's community
saying we make billions of dollars we're
publicly funded in Canada you need us
and they're getting a little blowback
from cities and cities are saying you
know what we're in the driver's seat
here what are you going to do for us and
so you know my message to the big guys
the multi-state operators is what are
you doing to be a good corporate citizen
you know you're you're you write these
applications like you're writing to your
investors on how much money you're going
to make your rate of returns how great
you are at making hundreds of millions
of dollars cities don't care about that
they want to know what are you going to
do for that neighborhood what are you
going to do about local hiring and
that's where I think the big guys are
kind of tone-deaf and they're running
into roadblocks getting into these new
sexy markets where the local regulators
are in the driver's seat underscore that
where that really happened was in
Arkansas of all places where none of the
multi-state operators got a license and
as we looked at all the scores the
big-name companies were way at the
bottom and you could see you could see
the scores where they lost out on and
sometimes it was sort of what are you
doing for the community there's usually
a community or you know how are you
gonna help you know the local state or
town and I think that's often where they
were probably scored down so but there's
a whole state jumping in there and
saying
like in New York when five licenses are
issued and then immediately they're
flipped
are there any states that write clauses
that say you can't flip if you went you
can't flip well I well this is your area
but the one thing I can think of in some
states is that you actually can't sell
the license right away I know like even
in New York when that one that men men
got they weren't able to actually buy it
there was like a step that had to happen
intermittently or something like that so
some places really do seem to restrict
that but I seem to my colleague here so
I think is unless there's like a
financial distress because wasn't
Bloomfield about that deal but most of
these states you know they they require
a new application or they specifically
change the rules to allow for changes of
ownership for the longest time in Nevada
they wouldn't allow like changes of
ownership until the legislature stepped
in and created a pathway to it in
California you know if you had a change
of ownership of your business you you
had to do like a brand new application
there they've loosened those rules up a
little bit but you know at the local
level is where they're really like
tightening it up there's a number of
small cities around Los Angeles that
have said you know the folks who apply
on paper those are the folks who get the
license and if you're changing I'm
ownership structure then you forfeit the
license the the problem is you know
there's creative lawyers out there if it
says no change of ownership they'll put
a management company there and run it
like the hotels do and so one way or
another you know the the folks who want
to buy their way in there they're gonna
find some way to do it they're they're
doing that in in Toronto and Ontario
right now like the folks who were
selected in that lottery out of 2,500
applicants you know they can't sell
their license to somebody so I imagine
you know all of the lawyers at Denton's
or whatever law firm they're using
they're coming up with whatever creative
solution to let the big-money guys
multi-state operators multi province
operators multi country operators figure
out a way to get control of those
licenses or they keep some of that old
company within the new company in the
board or in the c-suite so that it looks
like
we still have the residents in the
company and know that early days New
Jersey the what was it the Green Green
dispensary not purely that they're one
of the original three that was faith
they were from Colorado and it was the
father in the son team and they you know
one of them had to move to New Jersey in
order to make it work but they they're
still in business but they yeah it was
kind of an odd situation that I remember
and I went to the dispensary is a
wonderful wonderful operation really
nice but because they had the experience
from Colorado they had already been
doing it for a couple years in Colorado
they were able to really easily
transition to New Jersey but one of them
had to live in New Jersey and that was
apparently an issue I can't imagine why
you wouldn't want to live in Jersey and
not Colorado
you
[Music]