our topic of course for the next hour is
once it's legal I'm getting into the
business and we're lucky because we have
a good panel here this afternoon those
panelists come from a bunch of diverse
backgrounds for better for worse there's
three attorneys up on stage right now
but we'll do our best to keep you awake
for the next hour so let's get started
Matt with perhaps and grab a microphone
if you would please please give us a
perspective very very general overview
perspective on how business and land use
issues come down upon the marijuana
industry when you're a new operator I am
a primarily a corporate and tax lawyer
and have some regulatory experience but
I rely upon my my partners and our
government and land-use practice groups
to kind of do the heavy lifting in that
area if we're focusing on California
only is that is that kind of what we're
talking about I think California is a
good aspect of it but let's talk
generally because I think folks here
really want to hear about what's
happening from a broader perspective as
well well I think the you know people
are calling this a Green Rush they want
to jump into this industry and I think
it's important to take a step back and
really explore the regulatory land-use
side of the equation before going
full-bore and submitting applications
and raising funds from investors or even
worse spending your own money yeah is
that better thank you so I mean it in my
personal experience and doing deals
because that's what I do i do deals like
Donald Trump I guess and we we've done a
lot of transactions in multiple cities
in Southern California now
in desert hot springs in cathedral city
in adelanto in Santa Ana doing some some
transactional work first of its kind in
lynnwood Cudahy but the common
denominator is really with the land use
piece you know most of this stuff these
are discretionary entitlements in some
cases you don't even have permits or
licenses you have development agreements
and it's it's complicated stuff and I
think it's very very important to grasp
that side of it if you want to be a a
regulated you know legal cannabis
business whether you're a producer you
know retail testing you know extraction
processing type stuff and you know every
especially now while we're in this sort
of new regulated world that's coming our
way every local jurisdiction is
different and we've had a lot of clients
that have you know tried to go about
this on their own or went to kind of
like a criminally sort of a criminal
lawyers you know / repurposed cannabis
lawyer and they've they've been gravely
disappointed in in going down a you know
sort of a circular path and spending
lots of money and then either running
afoul hula or simply not getting
entitlements to do what they want to do
so just as a general recommendation
survey the landscape and make sure you
have a really really good regulatory
sort of land use professional to to
guide you from from the beginning so so
mad that's a good point ultimately when
you're looking at legal services for the
marijuana industry one thing to think
about is and this sort of happens in a
standard way state by state by state and
that is
at the beginning the attorneys that tend
to be popular if you will in the
cannabis industry are those that were
criminal defense attorneys or perhaps
activist attorneys or perhaps folks that
worked in various local government or
state government offices and those folks
are our quality and you need them to get
along the way but as these issues become
more complex when you have a regulatory
structure and local regulations you
really need to drill down and find that
area of expertise expertise to apply the
different standards that apply so Leslie
let's talk about standards why our
standards important for the cannabis
industry moving forward and perhaps you
can start with what to standard how does
the standard to differentiate from a
regulation or statute sure and so the
difference between a standard and a
regulation is the regulations are
created by government agencies licensing
agencies and they have the the force of
the law behind them standards are
actually guidelines that just give a
business owner the right foundation to
assure quality safety and consistency in
any other industry outside of cannabis
if its food drug pharma device
ag-related there's a division of the
federal government that licenses those
businesses and they do that through good
manufacturing practices because cannabis
is scheduled one the federal government
has stepped out of this situation so as
the industry has developed across the US
state by state state regulators and
business owners are left to decide what
the rule should be how we should do this
without any guidance from a good
manufacturing practice standpoint so
what we've done is create good
manufacturing practice guidelines for
all aspects of the industry whether its
cultivation retail extraction infused
products lab security sustainability
packaging and labeling to help business
owners protect their liability to reduce
costs and to ensure that they're
producing a safe and consistent product
as well as to help regulators understand
how to better regulate because
if the regulation is based on a standard
your very standards have to be
continually updated every three months
so you don't have to change the
regulation every time the industry grows
you just change the standard so is
everyone in this room ripped by a show
hands familiar with the nutraceuticals
or the natural product industry so the
nutraceuticals industry is a good
example in terms of a model for where
the cannabis industry is going for folks
in California you might look at this
top-down regulation with mercy and
ultimately the potential don't use
recreational ballot measure in November
and how that will affect things what you
need to understand is when you
effectuate this top-down regulation
things are going to change but going
back to the nutraceuticals model now
this is an industry that's effectively
self-regulated self policed how did that
happen it happened because it created
its own standards it created its own
rules so that consumers were protected
so that there was no miss classification
or misrepresentation of what was in the
product by way of labeling and those
standards ultimately what they became
adopted by the federal government as the
regulations for the state so it's
critically important to a embrace
regulation but even further than that
these local governments are going to in
effect create regulations that are
minimal at the beginning it's important
to embrace the idea that standards need
to be enacted and achieved across the
board so that the regulations can can
actually be meaningful and so that you
can police the industry yourself and not
ultimately have things imposed upon you
that will you know make the cost of
business the example I always give of
that is if you look at the fracking
industry right nobody really thinks
fracking is a good thing its fracking
bad right but they've got tons less
regulations than anybody in the cannabis
industry why because as an industry they
got together and adopted standards and
then the regulations are based on the
standards so
and sometimes it's not good enough to
say for example they want to treat us as
the cannabis industry differently that's
something to be cognizant of but they
are going to treat this industry
differently and you have to embrace that
god yeah i'd really like to ask a
question of exactly what you're dressing
I think there's a situation going on we
can categorize as blowback okay there
are people who are just angry about the
fact that we're getting what we want and
so that's preventing them from it's just
it's skewing their thoughts from having
sensible regulation and I think that
going into this we have to be a little
bit wary of that as well that we are
being prejudiced against and that there
is no other industry that they would
consider taxing twenty five percent so
I'm all for rent regulation legalization
through taxation same as any other
industry but I would just like everybody
to be aware that we are with we are
being being prejudiced against and that
we have we we can't be weak or modest
about that we have to be able to stand
up and say twenty-five percent how can
you do that to us what you know I just
wanted to why do you think we are
getting proposals that are so so you
know truce in the amounts that they're
asking us to pay big black yeah well
that's right that's very well said thank
you so the point was we're going to be
treated differently for those of you
that may not have heard that and
fundamentally it is something that you
need to recognize me cagas it up but you
can be on the leading edge of it if
you're creating standards on how the
industry moves forward at the same time
these regulations are being created so
let me move on down the line here and
shift topics and then all of this will
tie together over the next 50 some odd
minutes Mary talk talk about the the
fact that we now have a legal industry
or we should we certainly will here in
the short term in cali california with a
top-down regulatory structure why is IP
protection so critically important
well first let me start with defining
what the acronym IP is for those of you
who might not be acronym friendly IP is
intellectual property there are four
basic forms of intellectual property one
is patents the second is copyrights and
the third is trademarks and the fourth
is trade secrets I'm a trademark and
copyright expert so I will focus on that
mostly but but in terms of answering
Bob's question you are creating new
business models you are creating new
products you are creating new
manufacturing products and so
intellectual property is really
important because that is the area of
law that is going to protect you now
there's a few there's a few twists here
so patents and copyrights were
referenced in the Constitution so they
have their own basis and it was
basically so that creation creativity
would be fostered and that there was an
incentive for the creators to create
trademark law is a little bit different
and I overlap a bit with with Leslie
because trademark law comes from a basis
of public policy for consumer protection
and so it's not a strict property right
the way patents and copyrights are and
it's a different animal patents and
copyrights are also only exists under
the federal law trademarks exist under
both federal and state law and
international but I realize we're not
going there right now and trade secrets
is also something up until recently that
was only state law protected but that
has recently as i mentioned changed so
why is important because your creators
and you have business models that you
want to protect and you have brands that
you want to protect I felt like Steve
DeAngelo mentioned earlier today about
competitive intensity that is the
industry that we're in he talked about
the bell curve and you know we're all
we're all moving forward and that's
really great but you need to really
think about what you're
tentative advantage is going to be in
the marketplace going for forward so it
could be something like a patent that
you own and that you can exclusively
control that's a competitive advantage
it could be your brand and that's
another competitive advantage in terms
of how you are viewed in the marketplace
so that's why I think intellectual
property is so important because this is
a emerging industry with a lot of
creativity going on so I'm going to ask
you what I think is the perhaps million
or maybe the 10 million dollar question
in the room and that is can you get IP
protection for a particular strain of
cannabis it's genetics if you if you
have some thoughts i'm sure you do on
that topic ah i actually can't answer
that question as a trademark attorney
I've been focusing on the well you did
say intellectual property protection
I've been focusing on the branding
aspects of strains is that an acceptable
absolute direction okay so here's the
thing Leslie your favorite favorite
strain oh you said not to ask you that I
don't have one okay gentlemen in the
front GDP okay we got we got a volunteer
her GDP GDP may not be GDP when you get
in a dispensary that's what somebody
said it was when they brought it in to
the dispensary but that may not be what
it is and so a lot of what trademark law
is about is about quality control and
standards we want a patient who comes in
to get GDP to get GDP we want a patient
comes in for GDP to get GDP that's been
tested for THC and CBD and every other
cannabinoid that we're testing for as
well as mold and pesticides we want we
want to have strong quality controls and
that's what trademarks are about so
what's happened over the decades because
it was an industry that was more or less
completely underground for a very long
time and now is really bubbling up over
the radar there are lots of people who
set
there's no quality control over the name
GDP so if you're going to start out and
you're going to want to develop a strain
or if you're going to want to sell
exclusive strains there's things that
you need to know to make sure that you
can have the confidence that what you're
selling is what you're what you're
saying you're selling and if you look to
another industry like the horticultural
industry in terms of strains in terms of
protection if you look at roses or if
you look at tulips there are many brands
that are well established so it's not
that it's not it's not impossible but it
is challenging particularly to kind of
claw back something that's been in the
marketplace for a long time but if
you're starting out going forward there
are some steps that you can take and I
am actually in the middle of writing an
article on protecting strain names no
well said and it's my understanding i'm
not a patent attorney but we have a
patent attorneys that work in our office
and botanical strains in other context
are something you can protect from a
patent perspective huh can you apply
that same standard to cannabis is is in
fact that a big question listen common I
just want to add sorry I just wanted to
add that part of being able to get a
patent IP whatever kind of copyright
that you're looking for is being able to
produce that strain the same way over
and over right so everybody's making all
sorts of girl scout cookies or you know
blue dream or whatever whatever it is
and it's different but it's also
different in the dispensary from the
person growing it because they don't
have standards in place that control for
all the individual variables from people
to electrical failure to training to
anything else and so that's what
standards do is they allow you to
control for outside variables so that
you can do something like a patent
because that's you'll know that your
product is going to be the same over and
over no that's well said so the topic
for this hour again now that marijuana
is legal what comes next Matt let's
start with the concept of what is legal
I mean ultimately legal could be medical
marij
on illegal could be the collective
system legal could be don't use
marijuana how do you recognize that and
then what steps do you take to protect
yourself well first time I start out it
may not be the most popular view point
especially from a lot of people in this
room but i think what and I'm never too
praiseworthy to people up in Sacramento
I don't think he generally did a very
good job but what I think they've
finally done here with mirza an adult
use was a monumental step in moving this
industry out of the shadows grey market
the the you know cartel drug trades all
the things we don't like here in
California without any without any tax
increment revenue you know just just the
bad things and what what my colleagues
here talked about in terms of of
standards and doing what's best for
consumers and making sure you're not
consuming products that are written with
mold and pesticides and you know what
kind of THC concentration levels are and
CBD etc etc so my point is that you know
the speaker was in here earlier saying
you know this is this is terrible
fifteen percent excise tax plus you got
you know state local county level City
level taxes and you know then you got
nine bucks and change of foot tax on
growers and it's going to make
everything more expensive and people
won't get their medicine etc etc so
those are all you know sort of valid
viewpoints but in terms of the system
actually working and benefiting the
people here in the state of California I
I don't know what we were doing for 20
years with our heads in the sand with
prop 215 and 420 watching Colorado
passes by I think we've we've taken the
best of other state statutes and
ordinances and we've given it a lot of
thought and
think the the latest initiative is a
pretty thoughtful 60 Plus page you know
fairly well reasoned attempt for
comprehensive regulation taxation and
you know control of use I think it's a
challenge for businesses now to set
themselves up for what's going to be in
the next two to three years and whether
they want to focus on medical whether it
will focus on recreational assuming that
passes whether medical recreational
willfully merge at some point in the
next few years so I personally think
it's it's incredibly challenging and
that for now I think trying to do
something as legal as possible in a
jurisdiction that you're comfortable
with that does have a comprehensive
regulatory scheme in place is probably a
good start but you're going to want to
be pretty strategic about this and there
are no perfect answers but a long-winded
way of saying that I think we're on the
right track and we're going to have a
fully recreational west coast you know
top to bottom very soon so I'm pretty
enthusiastic about it especially as a
lawyer you know if we have legal
cannabis business operators here in
California then they're pretty aware of
the nonprofit sham is really what it is
in terms of you know organizing your
business that way in a mutual benefit
corp thats really taxable as a c-corp
and you got to have an arms like
management services agreement in place
and a management company and that's
fraught with risk and you don't have the
the certainty you want there so as a as
a deal lawyer as a corporate tax lawyer
I'm very excited to switch over to
for-profit still get the patients the
high quality medicine they want but you
know be able to legally profit from the
business and advise our clients with you
know reliable
predictable structures you know that
that are regulatory compliant here in
California so let's face it the cat was
out of the bag before state regulation
right so how do you take literally
hundreds if not thousands and thousands
of these businesses and then jam them
into a state top-down regulatory model
and get folks license how do you do that
so maybe you can kind of Matt just
briefly on the idea that there is a way
to sort of preserve your place in line
for state licensure there is you know
and again I regulations not my strong
suit but but certainly there is this you
know a piece of legislation that's
that's ready to be once it's funded that
that fixes a B 266 that you know cities
aren't going to necessarily have to have
an ordinance adopted today in order to
get in the queue then we've got there
you know you're September first deadline
that passed for for adult used to be
legally compliant to get first in line
to get a recreational type license I
mean I think the key is there there will
be some some preference and deferential
treatment if you're operating today
period you know is sort of like measured
d here in City Los Angeles if you were
if you had your tax registration
certificate than and you you know you're
at a location where our landlord accepts
you and you know you're a prop D client
dispensary there's a pretty darn good
chance that you're going to continue to
exist postma MRSA post adult use so in
other words it's it's entirely up to in
effect the local governments to provide
you some sort of licensing or
certification that you're operating
lawfully which in fact preserves your
place in line for state licensing and
what I've been told and you know
that talk to you some of it some of you
folks after this what I've been told is
less than thirty three percent less than
one-third of existing operators in the
state of California will be licensed
under the state regulatory scheme what
the heck is going to happen litigation
our folks just burning the midnight oil
making as much money as they can closin
up shop moving on elsewhere back to the
black market a variety of things are
going to happen but it's going to be
really really interesting but i think
this also segues to why sort of having
standards are important but if you want
to comment on that well and it's the
same comment i was just going to say
that you know this industry has
developed quickly without regulation on
a national level but it's not the first
time that that's happened when i sat
down to figure out how to write
standards for an inner industry
internationally I had no idea I have a
pharma background and a non-profit
background and I opened the first
licensed in Phoenix so I started looking
to other industries well in the 80s when
the heroin epidemic swept throughout the
United States methadone clinics had
popped up all over the place and within
two years they were in every state
working under different state city &amp;
county regulations and the federal
government took a look at that and said
whoa there's no way to protect for
health and safety here we need somebody
to develop voluntary consensus standards
and a third party certification system
so that these businesses can assure the
regulator's that they're doing things in
a safe quality and consistent manner so
standards and making sure that you're
and it goes back to Kyle's question even
that came up about stigma right
everybody is a little bit afraid of this
industry there even the people that are
pro-cannabis on the regulatory side
still are fearful they want to do it
they see the benefit you know some
better than others but they're still
fearful and so the best way in my mind
for us to move this industry forward as
a whole is to be able to prove that we
have quality safe consistent products
that were responsible business owners
that we're not ending up with another
news story about you know this happening
or that happening that looks bad for us
so what is the right time to start
talking about standards is it when the
we've got our legs underneath of us for
a couple years as an industry or for now
so there's never a wrong time we have
businesses that have been in operation
for five or six years that are now going
through this process with us but
certainly at the beginning whether
you're a regulator or an operator you
want to start as early as possible
because we can help build out your
structure and make sure that it meets
the standards we can control for all the
variables within your facility and it
will save you money in the long run
versus having to go back and do that
Mary what about go ahead if you'd like
to comment on that I also have a
question for you I want it to comment so
it's it seems to me based on my
experience with trademarks and branding
something that would be important for
you all to know is that if you want to
expand you have different if you have a
business you get a business you want to
grow the business and you want to expand
you have different options of ways that
you can do that you can partner with
somebody in a different state to get the
license you can you can partner with
somebody after they've gotten the
license before they've gotten the
license or you can license your brand to
them and that means you're going to have
to have some levels of quality control
and that goes back to the issue of
whether its GDP or dr. green thumbs jet
fuel oh gee you need to have some
standards for growers and for others to
you know to follow and that's so it this
whole issue of regulation and standards
really flows through every aspect of
your business so let's talk about Mary
the difference between branding creating
a brand and creating something that can
be trademark protecting domestically yes
yes yes sir
how big is that industry how many are so
the question is who are the standard
bearers how do you establish who the
standard bearers are how many are there
etc Leslie you probably get best common
sure so there's definitely other
organizations out there that have worked
on standards for the cannabis industry I
to differentiate a little bit there are
certain types of standards called
voluntary consensus standards that are
suitable for adoption into regulation in
fact in 1996 the fair trade and
Technology Act specifies that the
federal government has to use voluntary
consensus standards when writing
regulations for an industry if they're
available and then it goes so far as to
say they can actually make the standards
the regulations so focus is the only
organization that has designed voluntary
consensus standards that meet those
guidelines I'm just going to throw this
in because I do pro bono work for
Americans for safe access and they have
a patient-focused certified program that
addresses various aspects of industry
including cultivation retail and others
and i would say who are they not to
slight define california companies but i
would look for folks that are operating
in multiple states if you can achieve
licensure in more than one state that
suggests something very significant
about you it suggests that you can be
capitalized well if you can be
capitalized well you obviously have a
good business plan and a good business
program it would demonstrate that you
have good corporate governance it would
demonstrate that you understand the
importance of complying with regulations
so the standard bearers are those folks
that operate in my opinion in multiple
states and I think many folks are on
that path but Mary let's talk about
branding let's talk about the difference
between trademarks and branding and I
guess a tandem question is can you trade
mark anything related to cannabis yes
and yes okay uh so we'll start with the
first part next question first
the first part of the question which has
to do what's the difference between
branding and trademarks so anybody out
here have a vaporizer okay when you
chose that vaporizer there were various
aspects of the vaporizer that you were
looking for did you want it to be
something that fit into your pocket or
your purse did you want it to be
something that that was battery operated
or something that had you didn't have to
deal with battery operating did you
wanted to have a indicator on the front
of the vaporizer that had numbers that
showed you the temperature as it was
rising or did you want something really
simple simple that the light just went a
certain color when the temperature was
reached all of those are aspects of
branding it's the product itself it's
the way that you communicate about the
product to your potential customers or
patients it's the price it's the quality
it's everything about your product that
interfaces or connects with the consumer
and so that's what a brand is what's a
trademark a trademark is one portion of
the brand and it's the shorthand for the
brand because when i say that i use
analyzer solo some of you might be
nodding as a light right that i liked it
i don't like it la but some of you are
thinking on you know i'll stick with the
volcano you know and and the point is is
that the brand name becomes the
shorthand for all of the factors about
the brand the quality the price the ease
of access the ease of use and so on and
so forth so when you think about your
brand which is very important in this in
this area of competitive of the this way
this marketplace is changing to be so
competitive because there are so many
new entrants you've got to think about
every aspect and have have a sense about
where you're going one aspect of the
trade of the branding is the trademark I
used to be Mary L Shapiro law until
earlier this year because when i left my
big firm I felt like what I was selling
was me because I had these relationships
with with clients and so forth
I just rebranded this year to evoke law
because i want a i want to follow the
guidelines that I provide my clients but
I also wanted to say something so what I
always tell my clients do is choose a
brand that is distinctive and exclusive
and it's not just because I think that's
a great opinion that's what the law
wants you to have that's the standard
you have to be exclusive and distinctive
so when I looked around at other law
firms and I looked at other names I
can't you know I ended up settling on a
vote because I felt like that was like
you need to tell your client you need to
evoke some response from your customer
or your patient about what your product
is so that's the that's the difference
between branding and trademarks would
you like me to answer the second part
part 2 so I mentioned earlier that there
are two at least two concept trademarks
or state and federal state trademarks
provide protection in a given state and
it's for intrastate commerce federal
trademarks are for interstate commerce
so a lot of folks have a little issue
about getting into that federal land but
there are different ways that you can do
it but the question is can you get a
trademark and the answer is yes there
are just different ways of going about
it so if you are only operating
intrastate the thing that you need to
look at is only a state trademark okay
if you're in California you are screwed
for lack forgive my french because
California Secretary of State is still
voluntary all entirely following the
federal guidelines and so the feds will
not issue a trademark registration to
any product that touches the plant so if
you are offering education services your
you're good you can talk about cannabis
but if you are retailer you cannot get a
trademark for your brand for retail
services so as I mentioned California is
one of the outliers in this though just
about every other state that I'm aware
of where there are cannabis regulations
it's permitted do offer state trademark
registrations so unfortunately as you're
used to already you've got a patchwork
quilt of local and state and federal
laws this unfortunately this area of law
is no different and you have to wind
your way through and find the right
strategy of how you can obtain the
maximum amount of protection so the
topic again it's legal now what yes
question so the question is you are the
comment you had recently been in touch
with someone in Washington DC from a
trademark office at the federal level
and they effectively told you about this
problem as Mary described would that
it's anything about the illegality so
it's really interesting I think I think
Matthew said it or maybe Bob are both
said it and I refer to navigating the
waters of the cannabis industry in terms
of the law as the Maslow hierarchy of
needs for those of you know what it is
if you don't know it's basically like we
need food and shelter like first before
we can like you know and at the very top
we can have exposition existential
happiness so in my mind there's a same
triangle and at the bottom you've got
criminal lawyers who help people in this
industry navigate sorry whoo help help
people in this industry navigate through
the criminal aspects I think the next
place that most businesses went were for
a corporate lawyer and a tax lawyer
that's my my my anecdotal presentation
someplace above that you start to get to
places like employment lawyers and
intellectual property lawyers and at the
Pinnacle I see that you have created a
business that has revenue and income and
equity that you can leave to your a
charity or your family and that's where
you need trust lawyers so that's my
little thing but to get to your question
I think unfortunately because of all the
intricacies having a trademark lawyer
can be really beneficial I've seen too
many cases where people have applied for
goods that are unlawful and they get
refused and at the federal level okay so
you've got the money that you've spent
the time that you've spent and the
frustration
and I'm going to admit that it happened
to me in California I applied for five
marks for one client in California and
this is what's really crazy California
sends you back the application they send
you back your check and they write this
really long letter and tell you what's
wrong with your application and it's you
know it's just it's kind of its kind of
the I don't mean to be critical of
government or bureaucracy but I do mean
to be and so it also offends me now I'm
going to get on my high horse but it
offends me that in California where
cannabis has been legal for medical
purposes for such a long time in an area
of law that is about consumer protection
that they have this total disconnect
because again if you're a medical
patient you want quality and you want to
know which retailer is going to give you
that quality which cultivator is going
to give you that quality and it's really
important I am a founding board member
of the National cannabis Bar Association
and with the National counters of our
association we went to the see the
Secretary of State to try and start this
dialogue and the sea CIA has also done
that and other people have done that we
just haven't seen the change coming as
fast as it needs to I would just I would
just add that bureaucracy is part of
this industry and I you know if you're
thinking about getting into it based on
what the topic of this conversation is
today you got to be ready to get no at
every corner you have to be ready to
come back with an argument and you have
to have the right people around you that
understand how to navigate those waters
I I feel like colleges like that right
colleges like this bag college you go to
you have your learning what you're
learning your degree is great but at the
end of the day if you can't meet their
requirements and you can't figure out
when things need to be turned in you're
really not going to be successful at
college even if you understand the
content of the course okay now you're
reminding me of the dream that I have
all etat all the time that I have an
exam tomorrow and I haven't been to
class I'll sesame ok so so I was there
was a similar topic i was in laying in
bed in a hotel in chicago may a year ago
was david letterman's last
on TV and I got to thinking about what
what do you need to know now that the
industry is legal right how can you
package that so I decided to come up
with my own top 10 list not nearly as
clever as his old Dave but let me give
you my top 10 if you will things to
think about now that it's legal to get
into the industry first and foremost the
Controlled Substances Act we are talking
about a federally illegal substance
simple and plain right there a part
there are policy memorandum those policy
memorandum create rights for this
industry to operate those rights are not
necessarily enforceable in a court of
law unless you're referring to the
federal budget there was a great case
from the northern district of california
called the mam case the marin alliance
for medical marijuana we're at district
court federal district court judge said
to the Department of Justice you cannot
spend dollar one to enforce against man
because the federal budget prohibits it
so there are safeguards in place but
remember please start with the
understanding of the legality federally
but also understand your state legal
structure which we touch down a little
bit that's number 10 number 9 cash and
banking you're going to have a lot of
cash you're going to have few banking
options so think about that in Colorado
we've solved the banking problem states
have solved the banking problem in a
variety of places through due diligence
through software systems through
compliance by third parties it's not
solved everywhere so that's going to be
a problem number eight state and local
regulations sorry not just marijuana
business regulations environmental
regulations land use regulations
something in California called sequin
Pamela Epstein who works with our law
firm knows this stuff as well as just
about anybody in the state and when you
begin to talk about it people's heads
spin
understand the environmental issues in
the compliance side of things number
four number 67 thank you with the law
school for a reason math is not my
strong suit publicly traded companies
SEC has shut down trading on publicly
traded companies most states don't allow
publicly traded companies to operate so
think about your structure think twice
in my humble legal opinion about
creating a publicly traded company to
hold a variety of holdings isolate your
liability isolate your licenses get the
notion of publicly traded companies for
the foreseeable future out of your mind
unless you're an ancillary business due
diligence it's highly specialized in
this industry you need to do due
diligence I was on the phone with a
client this morning who we said we will
get you numbers we will get you this and
that for a dispensary that they're going
to acquire in Phoenix I don't need to
see that stuff the numbers are fine I
don't need to see that stuff people
throw stupid money at this industry with
don't with no due diligence don't be one
of those people absolutely this is one
of the areas where we're doing a deal or
this is one of those areas whether
you're doing a deal to acquire something
or merge with somebody or whether you're
doing a licensing deal for a brand it is
so important you need to know who you're
getting in bed with and I hate to use
you know that metaphor but you really
need to know the people and it's not so
it's not just about the numbers you need
to know what their values are what their
ethics are what you do you know what the
morality is before you get into business
with somebody i also just okay welcome
back to my i'll go ahead well i just was
a sort of natural segue to me one of the
things i see happening when new
businesses form is they don't think
about their intellectual property and
they don't think about what's going to
happen if things go wrong between the
people and I'm that is just a general
principle you need to always think about
what's going to go wrong and so I
mentioned that because that's another
aspect of thinking about you know well
what's going to go wrong we can't just
assume like we're like we've known each
other for four months and we're still
like dating and it's all good but you
know when you when you start to do you
know
run a business together questions come
up decisions get made and you can be
unhappy or happy and so I only wanted to
mention that I think that's a the due
diligence is so important about every
aspect of this it's not your
grandfather's due diligence due
diligence is unique in this industry
because it takes into account your
standard business due diligence but also
the compliance aspect of it what and how
seriously from a compliance perspective
do these folks take that seriously yes
sir look in Washington state washington
state in effect did away with its
medical marijuana program and it merge
into an adult use program why i think
this is important and trust me this is
not coming from a position of a lack of
regard for patient rights what's
happening in the united states is you're
going to see federally regulated
cannabis-based medicine based on
rescheduling whether that's a two or a
three in the future these are
pharmaceutical products these are
pharmaceutical grade companies that are
producing cannabis based medicine
regulated by the FDA at the federal
level then you're going to have this
divine and on the other side of the
divide is the natural products marijuana
industry this is the industry we all
operate in right now it's the dispensary
system it's very very different it's it
is not going to merge into
pharmaceutical it's going to be its own
thing so to have distinctions like
medical marijuana and adult use
marijuana when it's all the same thing
its natural product marijuana and its
simplest sense is a way to open the door
and create regulatory structures so
policy makers see that it works and when
they see that it works they will
ultimately merge but the divide is not
between medical and adult use the divide
is between OTC marijuana and federally
regulated cannabis-based medicine
because think of it this way even though
most hardened zealot anti-marijuana
crusader like chris christie for example
and i could say that from my home state
of jersey this guy would sit back and
over a beer he would tell you he would
say Hoban we are not going to send 50
billion dollars of business black back
to the black market because what is the
marijuana industry and it's in its most
simple of sense it is the most
organized well-funded institutionalized
drug distribution system in human
history and it's happening in broad
daylight they're not going to send that
back to the black market I can assure
you so to figure out and to understand
that distinction between natural
products and pharmaceutical base which
by the way can be based on natural
products is really going to be an art
but that's why I think that they merge
I'd like to add to that too when you
look at standards people ask me all the
time are your standards for medical use
or for adult use right and I just looked
back and I say well we don't want to
turn all the recreational users into
patients because their cannabis isn't
safe right so at the end of the day it's
about producing safe quality consistent
products regardless of what marketplace
you're in like to add oh I just want to
be the cynic of the panel that's my role
the fact of the matter is beyond you
know patient rights and quality and
standards both the federal government
and most state governments spend a lot
more than they need to be spending and
so we continue to have a spending
problem and we're running out of revenue
tax sources two things to tax and we've
gone so far down this path of having
insufficient revenue to fund big
government that we're not going to
return to the black market it's only
going to get more and more regulated and
more and more text and eventually like
you said we'll see addy scheduling good
a change in the scheduling and and we'll
have yet another tax at the federal
level at some point maybe it's three
years from now maybe it's 15 years from
now but it'll probably happen it all
depends on with President Trump allows
I'd like to go back to the notion of
intellectual property though because if
if you if you create something and you
get a patent on it that is some big
protection and it can help you navigate
your through the big pharma and natural
products as well I also want to say as a
patient
I feel as though it's going to be really
important and even more important to
have qualified people in dispensaries or
whatever it turns out to be that is
providing advice and counsel to patients
because when adult uses is I'll say when
adult uses authorized in California a
lot of the stigma starts to go away and
so people who never considered using
cannabis to treat arthritis or glaucoma
or whatever the illness is are going to
want that kind of support because now
they don't have to sign up and get a
card you feel like they're on some
database and they're all worried about
it they can just go into a dispensary
but it's going to be really important to
my mind to segregate the kind of bud
teen budtender that's going to give
advice about medical cannabis versus
recreational no well said well said all
right so let me buzz through my top five
and then I've got a question for Matt
real estate is another key number five
zoning land use this at its heart you've
probably seen articles out there the
cannabis industry at its heart is a real
estate industry in its most simple sense
at the beginning now that evolves as an
industry matures from a top-down
regulatory system but understand the
regulatory structure understand what the
local governments are thinking before
they think it and some of those folks
are in the room so get get close with
them make sure you have a liaison for
government local government in
particular number four you can't
generally have a security interest it
makes really hard to lend to the
cannabis industry because folks that are
going to be deemed finance ears
quote-unquote or lenders it's not your
your traditional industry where I can
have a security interest in the money
I'll end and in fact if you even can
under the regulations is that
enforceable in a court of law so that's
something to think about and by the way
if anybody has a comment on any of these
things please please feel free to jump
in number three capital capitals hard to
come by you can't get institutional
lending of course you have
to go to groups of investors you have to
go to friends and family one thing that
has opened up we hired a specialist
about six months ago for reggae plus
sort of crowdfunding raise for this
industry very popular and it's proven to
be effective and I tell you you can't go
to banks but there are a number of folks
that'll throw that quote unquote stupid
money at this industry number number two
the FDA claims and labeling may 2015 the
FDA issued a q-and-a on its website
regarding marijuana there were 16
questions 13 of those 16 questions dealt
specifically with marijuana and rather
the FDA regulates marijuana the other
three had to do with hemp hemp gets me
really excited so I won't go down this
road but let me tell you something the
13 questions about marijuana of course
say that the FDA does not consider
marijuana something that they should
have the purview over because it's
federally illegal with that said be sure
to comply with FDA labeling requirements
it's a step I was going to say and I'm
actually on the FDA Committee for
cannabis so while they say they don't
regulate it that goes back to the
Controlled Substances Act and giving the
power to Congress not DOJ or FDA to
change things so the FDA is absolutely
involved in this they have many many
meetings many phone calls about it don't
kid yourself to think you do not need to
meet those guidelines so comply with
your state guidelines for labeling and
packaging at a minimum but look at the
FDA guidelines as your standard to
operate because it's critical and don't
make claims can I good I just want to
say too just so it's clear the the focus
standards and I'm not saying that has a
selling point but I want to make sure
that you guys understand that all we've
done is taken Code of Federal
Regulations Pharma guidelines
nutraceutical guidelines OSHA hasem
everything that's like you know
agricultural guidelines World Health
Organization guidelines and created put
those in together into a standard for
each of the areas that have then been
specified specifically to cannabis so
you don't have to go seeking out
what do I do for here with Pharma or
with nutraceuticals or agriculture or
whatever and that's the benefit to a
business I think if we're talking about
starting a business right you take the
guesswork out of it by doing something
like that and I would say the same thing
is that I want to focus on the claims
and the labeling I am all about consumer
safety and it's not just become a
trademark lawyer or just you know just a
human being I'm think about the patient
first or the consumer first and you're
going to probably end up doing the right
thing as long as you have some guidance
you know as to the law but claims are
really interesting and I'm not an expert
in this area but I you know you have to
be really careful about what you say
your product is going to do because
you're going to step over some very
important law that's going to put you in
a real bind and I just just wanted to
throw that in so so even if for example
your edible product produced in
California from your company even if the
FDA technically technically doesn't
count because there's no interstate
commerce or there shouldn't be over that
product although any lawyers in the room
understand that interstate commerce is
really everything that's neither here
nor there when that chiva choo makes it
to New York and it's got a label on it
that says something wrong it says it has
too little or too much of what it
actually has in it if it says and a
medical regime this product is intended
to treat prostate cancer don't do it
don't let anybody do it it's a bad move
from the beginning and back to your
question sir those people will certainly
not be the standard bearers so be aware
of that number one taxes audits state
tax local tax federal tax Matt segue
talk about taxes as they apply to the
cannabis industry if you
well cannabis industry not like no other
industry really there's there's not a
whole lot of difference there I'll talk
about 280 but fully heavily taxed state
local and federal level you know
cannabis products in California
generally subject to BOE sales tax all
these mutual benefit corpse that are AB
nonprofit charters are taxable see
corpse generally speaking so they look a
lot like any other industry a lot of
these businesses management companies
are set up as pass throughs as LLC's or
partnerships and there's nothing
different there there is one code
section which I'm sure everyone's heard
of or maybe not be familiar with but
have seen it and that's 280e and that's
the differentiator the game changer for
the legal cannabis industry in terms of
the anything that's a schedule
controlled substance Congress passed
this law you know 30 some years ago and
their infinite wisdom but you know it
was really targeted towards you know the
cocaine trade the Pablo Escobar's of the
world not being able to take itemized
deductions and business expenses for
what is federally illegal drug
businesses and so we all know that
marijuana is currently caught in that
web and that still applies to state
legal cannabis businesses which means
that you're really getting a very the
disallowance and deductions is is
significant you're really taking a cost
of goods type deduction whether you're a
retail dispensary or a or a grower or a
producer of cannabis
the there's a number of cases in this
area the champ case is well known case
in those cases under IRS audit
dispensaries were taking deductions that
were disallowed ultimately they the Tax
Court got them up to somewhere around
call it seventy percent of what would be
a hundred percent of a non cannabis
business in terms of deductions but in
and kind of cramming everything in the
cost of goods but you know there there's
certain guidance that we give our
clients in this area to maybe sort of
doctors you the lesson that the burden
with respect to i-280 and that might be
you know for example a retail dispensary
selling non-kin was probably useful
whether that's glass pipes t-shirts
paraphernalia and their whole other set
of laws we are familiar but you know the
extent you can allocate some of their
expensive dental perfect day I've got
one hour nine sorts of controlled
substance yeah I'll be they'll really
touch minutes we're going on and it's
only a deadly property or whatever it is
you there are planning opportunities
from a tax standpoint to to work around
to some extent to it
so some of those strategies puerto rico
puerto rico 280e doesn't fly puerto rico
we're working with a number of folks in
puerto rico in other words you can
deduct expenses if marijuana were to be
rescheduled despite what I said before
the impact rescheduling would have on
the existing dispensary or natural
product over the counter system is that
the 280e exception goes away based on
the scheduling so rescheduling don't
quote me on this because I have a tax
lawyer I rely on but I believe it would
have to be a scheduled three for that
282 to no longer apply Matt your last
piece of wisdom for the audience today
consider other states besides California
over the next few years I'm a big
proponent of oregon and i would i would
definitely diversify your risk in your
exposure and so it's a fun new market
but you know we're years away in
california from having that regulatory
certainty we're all looking for the
business development council for the
city colorado just ripped Matt's resume
up so thank you Matt thank you guys
thank you all