[Music]
but you have just been doing some
research and you're about to write an
op-ed on Interstate Commerce and are you
for or against it
well the I've been collaborating with
Adam Smith who's been a strong proponent
of interstate commerce in the cannabis
space for quite some time and he just
recently wrote a report out of the
concord current i believe that talked
about interstate commerce in the
cannabis space he and I are co-writing
another article talking about the
economics of this and so that should be
out in the next couple of weeks and so
but what the numbers say is that as
people don't have access to traditional
financing in order to establish cannabis
businesses you have to cash out your
401k or you have to get funding from
friends and family and so if they stand
up individual state by state industries
then it doesn't necessarily bode well
for those investors assuming full
federal legalization occurs what will
happen is that the folks in the West
Coast that have the competitive
advantage on cultivation side they will
overwhelm the market because they supply
close to over 80 percent of the supply
and naturally anyway they'll just
overrun those markets and it'll create
wealth destruction as a result and so
what I do on the analysis is I provide
the numbers and then I let Adam opine
about it but from a purely economic
perspective it makes a lot of sense to
allow for interstate commerce of
cannabis so that you don't have this
potentiality of wealth destruction
across the United States I feel like
those were conflicting statements right
you're saying in a market let's say like
Michigan or Ohio or Indiana if
California cannabis could come in it
would dominate the market
yes so that would destroy the wealth of
the people in those markets who invested
in indoor operations greenhouse
operations even outdoor cultivation yep
that's right
so there would be wealth destruction for
those people yeah I have a question so
after a federal legalization if that
happens and the market has settled down
is the scenario that you see that there
is robust cultivation in every state
supplying you know a nationwide or will
certain states be better agricultural
suited to produce cannabis right like
avocados aren't growing everywhere yeah
Ian as assuming full federal
legalization occurs there will be a room
for small niche markets in each and
every state there'll be the indoor
growers the trafic growers and the like
but from a commercial perspective the
supply will come from the states that
have the greatest you know viability in
terms of the climate and the soil
composition and the rainfall and the
like so look for California and Oregon
Washington even Hawaii to be too big be
big players in the space on a national
basis in international basis and they're
already starting to position themselves
accordingly from a branding perspective
from a regional perspective like
Humboldt or you know Southern Oregon
grown son grown all those brands are
coming out now in order to cement that
for me you know a lot of the craft
farmers up and let's say that let's say
California Emerald triangle globally it
has brand recognition people would love
to smoke Humboldt weed obviously they
can't get it even in Ohio or wherever
the LA market doesn't really appreciate
Emerald triangle weed they want their
indoor so for those small farmers I feel
like if they could sell nationally it
would alleviate a lot of the issues that
are facing now and the
California market and then couple that
with things like you know for example
used to be able to do farmers markets in
California where Emerald triangle
farmers could bring their amazing
harvest and December down to SoCal and
smoke everybody out and sell it and
people would love and appreciate it and
that could they could sell a good
portion of their small harvest and be
set for the next season so can you talk
about the data you had mentioned earlier
about how much cannabis is produced I
think we had talked about just humbled
or the Emerald triangle in general yeah
so I recently put together a calculation
of the entire output of cannabis in the
United States both illicit ly and
legally and bifurcated that between
indoor outdoor and greenhouse roughly
fourteen million pounds of cannabis are
cultivated and produced in California
alone and that's by far the largest
amount and of that fourteen million
pounds twelve million of that is
actually exported to other markets so
they say 2 million is going into the
regulated California market track and
trace yeah 2 million pounds will satisfy
the legal demand in California at the
present time
not all of it necessarily is making it
into the market right now you know
because of the limitations that have
been created by the California
regulators and you know all those
obstacles but you know roughly 2 million
pounds still pretty significant it's
larger than most of other markets around
the United States but like I said that
12 million pound figure that's being
exported to every state in the country
and elsewhere that's a significant
amount that will and those growers will
benefit from the either full federal
legalization or for the allowance for
exports out of California so this
interstate play to allow interstate
sales what would it look like would it
be and first of all do you need federal
approval obviously you do to do it right
because you're crossing state lines or
how would that work yeah I I guess to
follow up in that question like you
can't have California and Nevada
agreeing that they'll do interstate
commerce between them and the federal
government would be ok with that
right well it's still kind of in a gray
area right now essentially because of
the legacy of the Kohl memorandum
there's an opportunity that says that
you can't have funding if you're doing
things legally in one state versus the
other and so so it's still a gray area
at the federal level but what it takes
at the state level is one to say hey I
want to export to you and then the
governor and the other state saying
assuming it's legal there as well that
they'll be willing to receive it but but
but but actually on that what if you
have to go over other state like it's
easy when it's state next adjacent but
what if it's what if California strikes
a deal with New York State and you have
to transport that by air well I wanted
to follow up on that too because that
would make sense now if you had Oregon
in California those are two cannabis
mature markets but in your in your world
in the economic world do we want to
develop those relationships between a
California and in New York or a
Californian of Florida less less
developed to Canada's market yes you
definitely want to establish those
relationships now and to develop those
markets and those relationships in order
to say your supplier in California
Oregon or what elsewhere to establish
your distribution channels in New York
now Governor Cuomo has already kind of
laid the foundation for this he's going
to his adjacent markets and Pennsylvania
and Massachusetts and elsewhere and
saying hey we need to harmonize our
rules and regulations in order to allow
for something of this
or at least not to have a you know one
state having more favorable policies
than another state but they do they also
want to up their their regional leverage
like like a NAFTA of the northeasters
exactly well I'm not sure about the
intention but European Union but what is
interesting though is I've talked to a
lot of state regulators executive
directors and that level directors of
these regulated programs and they really
want to have these harmonization of
rules so that the packaging requirements
in one state is identical to the
packaging requirements in another state
and they're trying to harmonize this via
the state-by-state meetings where we
were where we were was kind of the
harmonization of like the different
markets and you mentioned like packaging
like examples of things that they would
kind of coordinate on yeah labeling
dosage packaging license requirements
and like because the intention of these
regulators is to lay the foundation for
full federal legalization at the state
level so that when it does go federally
legal the feds don't come in and try to
mandate rules and regulations in a
market that they don't understand so a
lot of these regulators at the state
level like this oh my god there's one
right there there's Massachusetts come
on wait wait actually can we ask you one
quick question no no we come sit come
sit
no she can't okay j-just quickly are you
trying to harmonize
Massachusetts state regulations with
your neighboring states as we go gene
requirements and things like that yes as
we go forward all of the states are
talking to each other obviously the
states near us are just coming online
like New York and Connecticut Rhode
Island has an existing market and New
Hampshire and Vermont are more consumer
focused rather than a commercial focus
but yes we've worked well with Maine and
we look forward to working with the
other New England states as they go
forward all right thank you I actually
have a fall what does she mean by
commercial focused as a place she's I
think she meant meant medical right no
commercial like in the production and
manufacturing and cultivation versus
because some of these some of these
markets are only just retail right so
where do they so source for are you
serious so they're legal retail but
they're they're like going like this
like where it may not have in state some
are vertically integrated right so you
have to be vertically integrated versus
like and that's an interesting topic in
itself because in Florida they they
ruled that vertical integration is
unconstitutional in Florida and so they
blew up that whole system but what these
as was validated and do you agree with
that like do you do like that Florida is
not letting people vertically integrate
it I do because it it gives more
opportunities more jobs more wages more
economic opportunities for city and
state and local municipalities to
benefit from the cannabis industry and
so yeah I'm I've been a big fan of
spreading the wealth as much as possible
so which market gives some grades to
states that are making it possible for
mom and pops to thrive like who gets an
A and who get like who gets a C and who
gets an F
that you know that states you know given
the fact that I have these great
relations with all of these regulators I
think it would be a little bit difficult
to grade but you know but who can
improve Oh like the Wild West right like
they're just like let's let everybody
play how's that going what Oklahoma has
done is that they've allowed for greater
access and so you really just need a
note from your doctor in order to get
you know access to cannabis and really
not a whole lot or a limited number of
qualifying conditions so they've
Oklahoma has opened it wide wide open so
it's medical but they're very lenient on
what like my knee hurts I need okay
exactly but but I guess where I was
coming from was the the entrepreneurial
side where Oklahoma like if Tom and I
wanted to start a tincture company we
could started in Oklahoma and like get
go see this is like I said earlier I'm a
firm believer in spreading the wealth
out to as many people as possible but
because each state is a closed market
there's going to be limited there's
going to be a limit to the amount of
economic opportunity that each state has
and a perfect example of this is Oregon
where they issued licenses out to a
large number of cultivators a large
number of retailers and like hoping to
draw in folks from the illicit market
and do things legally but what they
didn't do effectively enough is balance
the supply and demand elements and as a
result of all of those licenses they
sure they spread out the economic
opportunity but what happened is it
created this tremendous tsunami of
supply and it really took the prices
down substantially and ended up hurting
those small businesses that they were
actually trying to support so in
California we California does allow
vertical integration licenses but not
everyone gets them
the retail sector some people have the
micro licenses and then others don't do
you see that as an uneven playing field
or have you taken a look at that yeah
you know oregan allows for vertical
integration as well and you know so you
know if you can get your license then
great but it's just the fact is that you
don't have to write in some states like
Florida you had to up until just
recently and so that's what's different
and so the value of those licenses in
Florida were worth tens of millions of
dollars I think I did a valuation of one
of them I think it was like 50 million
dollars for that license because it was
vertically integrated and you had to
source all of your supply from yourself
whereas the value of a license in Oregon
was maybe one fiftieth of that amount
just because there were more licenses to
be had can you actually talk about how
you approach putting evaluation on
licenses yeah sure a lot of people are
like we're gonna be an MSO and we're
gonna roll up a whole bunch of operators
and you know then it's like okay what
are you gonna pay for those operators
and on the other side people are like
we're gonna raise money and we're gonna
start selling stuff and we're gonna have
a hundred thousand dollars in sales and
exit for a ten million dollar valuation
the consistency of the value of those
licenses which we're seeing can
fluctuate and change according to
regulations or other factors so how are
you putting a valuation on a company
there's a number of ways that you can go
about it and what I try to do is I try
to use multiple techniques and then look
at the differences in the values that
come as a result of it but generally
what you do is you look at the past
history and the future forecast of a
company you look at how much revenue
they've produced how much their cost
structure is what their margins are and
then you assign a multiplier
to that value right so some in nascent
markets there's not a whole lot of
comparables or comparables and so
there's you can't have there's not a
great deal of consistency from one
evaluation to another to another but
generally in the nascent markets you
look at the top line revenue and assign
a multiplier to it time with that
multiplier be higher than in a saturated
market like Oregon like the multiple
that accompanies trip like the multiple
of earnings that ik that a company is
trading at well a lot of the valuation
or would be sold at yeah it you do have
to factor in the environment and the
regulatory and all that right so there's
a there's a risk factor or a beta that
you assigned to it as well
right so you do your valuation you say
for example if you go this approach
top-line revenue assign a multiplier and
they're different between cultivators
and processors and retailers processors
generally have higher multiples than do
retailers and like and there's there's
reasons for that and what are some of
the reasons well retailers for example
they have a different cost structure
different taxation there there's much
greater costs associated with taxation
because there's not as many write offs
that's 280 right but but but could you
factor in that potential like if that if
280 changed down the road it would the
multiplier would increase right the
valuations would definitely increase
because another strategy is looking at
your profitability and by looking at the
profitability then you assign a
multiplier now with a change in 280e tax
law that would immediately impact your
bottom line because you wouldn't be
paying as much taxes and as a result
you'd be potential for greater
profitability which would make you more
valuable in the marketplace so if the
feds don't seem interested in giving up
that
money at all well that's interesting
they're getting there three years ago
when President Trump came into office
the group that I work for a new frontier
data presented my two ad analysis to a
health policy advisor for President
Trump his reaction was why would I give
up six billion dollars in tax revenue
right but if you think about it it's a
valid question but what you give up
quote-unquote you pay for more than via
employment via social security's and
payroll taxes business taxes and like
when you're supposedly a business
friendly republican administration right
what you're saying that argument is is
gaining traction the argument they'll
make up more along but you said they're
coming around yeah they're coming around
and so now the conversations at the
federal level on tax reform and banking
those conversations are heating up right
now and so that I mentioned in my speech
earlier that there is a briefing that
we're we're helping these folks prep for
on the Senate Banking Committee and
Senate Finance Committee that is one of
the data points that we gave them was
the impact of 280e
the impact of doing cash-only business
and the risks associated with that just
just can't can you name some policy
sensible politicians in Washington like
some of the people who are like this
just makes sense not from Oregon what
we're seeing is that as the mainstream
population gets more and more accepting
of cannabis use in their day-to-day
lives as states roll out reform and
legalization either at a medical side or
at the adult use side those states that
are represented by those legal states
that are represented
a tend to have more favorable views and
influence in Washington DC right and
because now 98% of the citizens of the
United States have some form of access
to cannabis either through CBD medical
or adult use and given the Pew Research
and other surveys that show there's
sixty four sixty five percent in favor
of legalization these types of
statistics are helping politicians get
the traction that they that they desire
on reform policies but but are there
specific people and either the Senate or
the house that are like Dana Rohrabacher
was a friend to cannabis right like he
was out there championing like who's the
next wave of people that we should all
was a big fan of Russian cannabis
Russians and Kant Russians and cannabis
Putin yeah it's it's really tough to
call out names per se that are more
favorable than others but what I will
say is that you know now that you've got
California online for the most part and
all of those votes in the House of
Representative representatives now that
year
you've got New York and the East Coast
starting to consider cannabis reform
then those folks that traditionally had
so Nancy Pelosi is now supportive and
Chuck Schumer I'm thinking of people in
those states she's out here Nancy Pelosi
she's wacky she's in Washington but she
represents right yes so there's like I
said there's a greater propensity
nowadays to support cannabis reform it's
even coming up on in the presidential
campaign I mean because it gets you
votes how many times have you heard
either that somebody consumed
previously or that they're in favor or
in the first day of their presidency
they're gonna you know do a presidential
mandate you know D scheduling I mean
this is coming up in practically every
debate that we're seeing now whereas
even four years ago or eight years ago
it wouldn't even come up it wasn't even
an issue so a lot of the politicians
that I've talked to are saying that this
is actually a bipartisan issue yeah but
it can be used to differentiate one
candidate over another in these
elections especially in the primaries so
just quickly getting back to the initial
conversation about Interstate Commerce
so when I think of like the Kraft
farmers who you know their stuff is
appreciated by people in other markets
it's obviously also the large scale
growers in Salinas and Santa Barbara who
also see a benefit of being able to
export globally yeah the you know the
benefits are those that have that core
competency in a specific task right
either cultivation or processing for
that matter if they have that core
competency then of course they're they
have a leg up relative to other people
that are just trying to start out you
know in the market so yeah by allowing
interstate commerce of cannabis it would
be very beneficial to those that are
producing large quantities especially on
the west coast it will really help with
standardization as well in a big way
right now if companies want to go into
other states do you have to create their
own footprint or have partners and and
and those are all extremely difficult
tasks that all these companies have been
doing for the last three to four years
in order to expand their brand
yeah for sure and you know it's with the
with regards to MSOs multi-state
operators by establishing that brand now
and being allowed to export it of course
it's gonna you know it's going to
benefit those guys here's my question
and maybe we can kind of wrap it up
because it rolls in to a de and the
states and inner Syria tightest well I'm
gonna try to and coming back to opening
up the market when you look at the
nascent markets or states that are about
to come online you're like sometimes
when I look at them it seems like you
have to be a conglomerate or a
multi-millionaire in order to enter
those markets and so is that an
impediment to the establishment of
creation of the type of Industry that we
want to see that that has players at all
different levels and where the cost to
entry is is is not absolutely
prohibitive well yeah because they have
a vested interest and keeping it do we
see do you see that do you see that that
the value or the appreciation for a more
diverse economy in the nation states
yeah it each one of these states though
it the success or failure and how
widespread the economic benefit is is
really determined by the regulatory
structure and it's really unfortunate
in some states you know you have to lay
down two million dollars in order to you
know be considered you have to have a
certain amount of that two million
dollars liquid and so that's a huge you
have an example of one of those days
that was I think that might have been
Michigan or Ohio right and so you've got
you've got those huge barriers to entry
at a at the very time where a lot of
these communities minorities people of
color have been impacted negatively by
the war on drugs those are just creating
these barriers to entry and not allowing
for access to those folks that could
really benefit from it you know and so
that's the unfortunate
and so but as interstate commerce occurs
the intent of that type of policy and
legislation would be to actually reduce
the harm that would otherwise occur to
these small businesses these minority
businesses and alike that would occur if
they just get wiped out due to full
federal legalization right so it's more
of a preventative measure which will
actually benefit the communities right
you'll allow for four people with core
competencies and growing to export to
states where there's a core competency
and distribution and retail and so
that's the model and the model makes
really really good sense do you guys
have a like a an idea about how this
might come to pass like a timeline or a
hopeful like road to interstate crystal
or a crystal ball like what's the plan
what's the strategy for federal
interstate or interstate commerce like
one year just lobbying lobbying and
lobbying I think that there's two
absolutes in cannabis one is I don't
know how many 19 year olds I've met with
twenty years growing experience
everybody has 20 years and then the
other absolute is everything is gonna
take five years
I mean I've heard for five years that
it's gonna be fully federally legal
right and so I think my default answer
to your question would be in about five
years but but in in reality I mean it's
it's it could be accelerated if a couple
of these large states like Pennsylvania
like New York like New Jersey if they
deploy legal programs and they drive
this policy because they'll be greater
representation in the Senate greater
representation in the House of
Representatives
so that could create a cascade effect
which accelerates the pace of reform so
is it going to happen in two years
probably not three maybe five for sure
I'm speaking on camera here as Bo
Whitney of Whitney economics and not as
a representative representatives of new
frontier data but new frontier data
doesn't do any advocating at all they
don't take a legal position on you know
the legality of cannabis they don't we
don't propose legislation or anything
like that
what we do is we analyze the market now
under Whitney economics I have a greater
flexibility to take on projects like the
interstate commerce bills and in writing
on that because it could take on a more
advocacy like tone and so that's why you
know I've been you know doing a lot of
work under Whitney economics yeah it's a
consulting business out of out of
Portland Oregon it's a company where
I've done the business valuations the
expert witness testimony I'm currently
doing a analysis of retail op retail
chain in Washington and I'm going in and
optimizing their operations to drive
greater revenue and decrease their cost
structure so I do all that under Whitney
economic you talk can you talk about
some things how you've whipped them into
business shape like some specific
concrete recommendations you've made to
them
I've made some recommendation they're a
little bit proprietary but what I have
the capability to do is I can dial up an
address say this location right here and
I can tell you how many people stood in
this location and for how long and if
they've come back over the course of
three months I can tell you what your
foot traffic is what your pattern and
how long people have stayed and then
also I can tell if they went to another
dispensary two miles down the road and
how long they stayed there and so so I
should turn off my geolocation
you know my cell phone is what you're
saying well there's other ways to get to
that data but that's one of them will
still track you and so yeah but and then
in addition to that you can see whether
geographically they're in a good flow
location like foot traffic if they have
if they have recursion right so if
people come back when you recurring
customers or if they're just you know
one and done and then I can look at
these other locations and see if they're
one and done and then or if retailer
number one it's losing business to
retailer number two so I can do all that
analysis but then I can also talk this
also looking at point-of-sale
information to or it's my question about
that where their data derives from is if
you can do it in some markets it's
different because point-of-sale data
like in Oregon has to be redacted by law
and so you can't like anonymized
anonymized but but in other states you
have a lot more access to data do you
have access to metric data only if it's
provided to me by the retailer and so
some of the upper level metric stuff I
would I'd love to get my hands on
because I could tell you through pretty
simple quantitative analysis who are the
good actors and who are the bad actors
you know this is actually a great
question to ask you is data in the
cannabis industry and you the silo
effect of data and what is what is your
impression of that subject it's it's
before we get to that can you tell us
how you could tell who the bad actors
aren't the good actors well you know
I've I've basically run a vertically
integrated company before I was the CEO
of a company and took in public and did
all that right so I know the
nitty-gritty details of cultivation of
processing retail distribution right and
so that's what I leverage in a lot of my
consulting work is because I I know the
operations are practically better than
they know it themselves right
and so on some of the bad actors right
you can look at their production output
you can do a time-series look at what
they're doing two years ago three years
ago versus what they're doing now you
can see their yields you could see I
mean there's a lot of ways in which you
can ascertain you know who's consistent
and a good actor versus who is somebody
that's you know potentially taking stuff
out the back door there are these hybrid
models and that's the unfortunate thing
about what's going on in California
right now is that the way that the
regulatory structure is set up the
barriers to entry all of this stuff it's
really forcing people into that hybrid
model of represent everybody is selling
out the back door just to be able to put
food on the table and live to for
another day all right well hey thanks a
lot great questions I appreciate it I
could have kept going but let me know
when you publish this and I'll stop you
on the street and be like I recognize
you from YouTube