[Music]
hi I'm Beth Schecter I'm the executive
director of the open cannabis project
which as many people know is closing on
may 31st 2019 I'm joined today by Dale
hunt who is on my board and also who is
a patent lawyer and botanist
we're at the cultivation classic we just
had our first and last legal advocacy
legal and advocacy clinic you know part
of the reason we decided that we wanted
to do this clinic is because you know as
open cannabis project has been has been
happening for the past year and a half
one of the things that we've identified
as a real need is a need for connecting
growers and breeders with with lawyers
and legal resources lawyer fees are
expensive and so part of what we wanted
to do with this legal clinic is to
really create a resource that made legal
content legal educational content
available to breeders and growers make
it available make it really affordable
it was a you know 12 to 24 dollar
sliding scale donation all of those
proceeds are going to the craft cannabis
Alliance and to vote hemp OCP is not
taking any of those donations at this
time or ever because we're going away I
felt like it was a success and for
people who aren't there you know we
covered licenses and patents for strains
including some open source options we
covered interstate commerce and we
really talked about hemp and FDA all of
these all of these matters all of these
laws are really complicated and they
surround us every day and they impact us
every single day and you know part of
the Botto 'pn cannabis project closing I
mean as people know there has been a big
controversy that has been involved in
FiOS and that absolutely and you know
coming to light with some of the
information that came through on that
was a big reason why we closed that's
not the only reason though another
reason just had to do with like ongoing
financial difficulty which I think had
to do with people not trusting us which
then had to do with this controversy
which was all the more reason to just be
like
that doesn't seem like a battle that's
worth fighting but really also on top of
that part of the reason why we decided
to close is because the conversation is
shifting and what we are realizing is
our reality in cannabis is shifting part
of what's happening right now is that we
are grieving the death of an ideal an
ideal that mainstream cannabis would be
a reflection of the people who brought
it here that's not what's happening and
because that's not what's happening we
have to take off our rose-colored
glasses and do a better job of working
together and organizing ourselves and
that involves not only one looking at
the landscape very realistically it also
involves understanding what the law is
and understanding what the law is is
hard
understanding how technology works is
hard understanding genetics and genetic
data is very hard and so it is you know
it's it it's understandable why people
don't get it at the same time if we are
going to organize from the ground up and
if we are going to really try to succeed
right now then part of what we have to
do right now is we do have to have
educated conversations and we do have to
understand the law and so you know we
have in order to have these educated
conversations we need to have lawyers
help us to understand like what the eff
is actually going on in this country and
the state and this jurisdiction
everywhere and the fact that things are
different by state by state in
jurisdiction my jurisdiction just
doesn't help so you know our hope had
been prior to this legal clinic that
this would be a key part of our
programming going forward and even
though we're going away there's
definitely still demand for this and we
are talking to lawyers who are
interested in helping with legal clinics
like this
we had also begun a project where we
were putting together standard open
source and also commercial licenses for
breeders and growers who wanted to
license their strains that work is also
going to continue and it will likely
continue with new partners and new
directions and certainly be as you know
Democratic from the ground up as
possible but in any case you know that's
a very but you know talking about legal
resources
breeders and growers is a different
conversation than open source your
information open source sure strains you
know not to say that open source is
really giving away your stuff for free
but a lot of people see it that way it's
just a different I had an idea just at
lunch and I thought hey let's put this
in front of a camera because I have said
in fact I said this at Emerald cup when
the panel that we were on that there's a
fundamental difference between open
source copyright open source software
and open source seeds and I think that's
the problem with everything people have
have promulgated so far with open source
seed licenses and that is that people
are doing that in some way that sort of
like an alternative to intellectual
property protection and here's the
difference with open source software
that is that starts with a fundamental
pre-existence of intellectual property
rights because software software has
copyright as soon as you create it
copyright exists as soon as you create
software and that's because there's an
international convention to that effect
on the other hand people don't have
intellectual property as soon as they
create a plant right that's the problem
and so it's it's yeah you have to have
more process right right and so if you
just optimistically or altruistically
put your seeds out there in some sort of
an open source system there it's an
honor system it's a trust system and it
requires some kind of community
operation a cooperation that is only as
strong as all of the members cooperating
in that system so this thought I had at
lunch was this this whole copyright
system didn't exist until there was an
international convention to that effect
and that's only a generation old maybe a
little bit more than
generation exactly exactly when I was in
law school or just coming out of law
school that was relatively new at least
in the u.s. it used to be that you had
to register your copyright before you
had any copyrights so why not
why don't we agitate for some breeders
rights that exist as soon as you do the
breeding in other words you know we
could we could create some massive
system where there is this you know huge
honor system among everybody who
participates in an open-source breeding
system but it's only as good as the
least honorable member of that system
and G are there any dishonorable members
of the cannabis community well there
there might be a few or you know as long
as we're lobbying for change
why don't we lobby for some kind of an
International Convention for rights
inherent rights of plant breeders that
they have a right to the ownership of
their cultivars as soon as they're
created just like copyright it might be
crazy but why not I mean that is an
amazing idea and I think that that would
help
I wonder though are there I mean now I
know I wondered like law student
questions not that I'm a law student but
it's like okay are there existing is
there an existing reason in place why
you know inventor ship does not
automatically assigned to other things
anyway including plants like is this
something that head that has been
considered and rejected because of X or
Y you know I don't know it's it could be
hard to prove but on the other hand I
don't know maybe nobody's just ever
asked the question I don't want to give
myself that much credit for being
original but I see one of the one of the
differences between a utility patent and
a plant patent is there's quite a bit of
debate with a utility patent about
whether what you think you invented is
actually new right and so that's a
purpose of a patent examiner you have to
go through this whole elaborate
examination process to prove that what
you think you invented is new
you have to they have to this
examination they do a search they they
look at all the so-called prior art and
you establish whether it's new on the
other hand if you breed a plant pretty
much by statistical definition
whatever you do in that breeding process
is new the genetic act of doing a sexual
cross and creating a new new cultivar a
new cross it's not necessarily a
cultivar until it's stable but that new
strain that f1 is genetically new
statistically it's impossible that it's
not new
and so that's original and but it's the
same theory of copyright if I create
something if I write something new as
long as it's long enough to be new its
original right so the originality is
what constitutes that it's it's
deserving of a it's being deserving of a
copyright and to me at least you know in
my post-lunch addled brain it seems like
yeah
it seems like at least theoretically
you've cleared the novelty her the
originality hurdle there's no
examination process needed so as long as
you can establish ownership you should
be entitled to your rights just like a
copyright and if you have the automatic
existence of some intellectual property
then you should be able to have an open
source system that would actually work
and so then you know I've been dubious
about open source systems for seeds
which is why I haven't really jumped
into it not because I don't support it
just because of its workability I
I mean I'm in favor of it in concept
it's just I've been dubious about its
workability because it's only is because
it's only as workable as its least
honourable member but you know this this
could work in this in a very similar way
to open-source software well that is one
idea there are many ideas out there many
ideas out there and I know that people
have thoughts feelings we've heard from
a ton of people who've said that they
are sad that open cannabis project is
closing we hear you
we're sad too and I think we're also
ready to let go of some baggage and move
forward and some nimbler ways and to do
so from the community up and so for
people who are interested in thinking
about these ideas being part of the next
step one go to open cannabis project org
slash surveys there is one very simple
survey now that we are going to be
putting out some more going going
forward because it's simple sort of
sunset survey right now and if you have
thoughts about what we should do when
after we close we'd love to hear them
and you know if you have just general
thoughts send us a note at info at open
cannabis project org we look forward to
hearing from you and to building
something new together it's already kind
of the seeds are planted things are
happening
[Music]