so they just gave you this topic and
said this is what you're gonna talk
about so I spent some time really
locking it down what does that mean what
is open source how does it apply what
we're doing are we really open source I
can't tell but that's what we're gonna
call it so the check check check check
check check
never check check check check check
all right I'll try again there was never
a war on drugs it's always been a war on
people on the little guy this war did
via
yeah good point so took the government a
whole long time but we the people the
non-centralized offensive guerrilla
force have the ability to change at a
moment's notice point point made because
this time the people have a tool more
powerful than any government corporation
this time we have the ability to freely
communicate at a global scale
this time we have the open source model
[Music]
[Applause]
don't take my word for it though let's
take a look at Microsoft circa 1990s and
early 21st century executives at
Microsoft were terrified of Linux and
the open source model for good reason
they claimed that it was a cancer to
their business internal memos at the
company acknowledged open-source as a
methodology capable of meeting or
exceeding proprietary development
methodology so basically their entire
system that they built this company on
was that threat of losing to this wild
open-source thing that they couldn't
even put a pin on there's
non-centralized didn't know who was
running it how do we stop this
Ballmer called this new threat communism
Microsoft developed intricate proprietor
intricate strategies to lock customers
into proprietary software embrace extend
extinguish was their model conquer all
flash forward 20 years Linux is the
backbone of the internet and most of
your smartphones Microsoft still makes
plenty of money and not only owns but is
the number one contributor to github one
of the largest communities of
open-source software on earth and
nobody's living in communes
unfortunately that's a different that's
a different speech so what happened
Microsoft realized that they couldn't
compete with shared development the
flexibility and capability of a global
network of contributors far outpaced
their ability to keep up when they
accepted this they also switched a good
portion of their business model to Mir
this more successful model Microsoft now
makes
more money on Linux based cloud services
than they do on proprietaries Windows
software adapter dies at work but that's
software not cannabis processing
formulation or science so what does
open-source actually mean to us let me
tell you about skunk farm so once upon a
time I was just a guy in the garage
doing my black market thing trying to
figure out how to extract cannabis oil
without killing myself like all the
people on the news we had one of my
friends had a really successful edible
company in Washington captain cosmics in
the good old medical days yeah there's
the good stuff these brownies holy cow
2000 milligram brownie and that was like
a we were just guessing we weren't even
testing everything it's probably about
2000 based on last time they were strong
but we needed to refine our extraction
method and he put me in charge of
figuring out what does that mean how do
we do that
so as anybody at the time could to tell
you you you search anything extraction
on the internet you're gonna come across
skunk farm so I scoured skunk form I
spent you know I've got this weird thing
that's where the data dump came from
where if I get on to a track I'm just in
a wormhole for a long time
so I spent weeks refining my craft based
on skunk farm use that to build that
company into something great move ahead
a couple years and I've bought land out
in the middle of the woods to be my
bug-out I'm done with society I've gone
off the deep end on conspiracy theories
and I realized that there's no point
thinking about them so I'm just gonna go
and find my own personal liberty I'm
gonna grow food and I'm just gonna be
done with it all six months later this
little bumfuck town i moved to is where
the first 15 licenses in the legal
marketing kit in washington come and my
partner and i looked at he tried to say
hey here's a sign we should get into
this so I become the general manager of
a shop and I get positioned to set up
the lab of which I know nothing about
again this is this is a little while ago
the first thing I do is go to skunk farm
and find how to contact them and I give
them a call and I said hey would you
guys do consultation can you come set up
a lab and they said surely we cost a
whole bunch of money but if you really
need us to hold your hand we'll come and
do it right there is like one of my
major pivoting points by the way is like
oh okay if you give away the information
people are willing to pay you whatever
because you're the guy so they ended up
poaching me out of that position and I
go start working for gray wolf and I
wasn't big on icy mags so I wasn't
really sure who it was it was Joe that
poached me and I end up working directly
under the old grumpy bastard for 18
months and I learned more than you could
ever imagine and one of the most
important things I learned from him is
all of this information that he'd been
sharing for free all of this how to
build extractors how to do all of these
things safely and effectively
he had also started a business selling
those exact things he was giving out and
so that was another pivotal point for me
was okay how is it that this guy's
giving out everything for free and it's
not only getting paid to be this source
of knowledge when when people need their
handheld but he's also started a
business selling the things that he just
told you exactly how to make piece by
piece where to buy the parts everything
because people will pay for the
convenience and that's kind of a you
know a core model here where you can
give everything out for free and still
make a lot of money because people
always pay for the convenience like the
open source Linux platform and Microsoft
great example they still put in the work
and their customers still pay them
because the customer is not going to go
out and build their own Linux based web
server that runs on on Windows it's
crazy that I work for skunk farm under
farm gold they have their own issues
I left that because of management
disagreements and the way that the skunk
farmers were getting treated but from
that I had I took those lessons and
that's when we got into pesticide
remediation I started looking an error
in listening really to what are the
problems and as I was coming down to
California for work I started seeing
more and more people with stockpiles of
distillate I started asking alarum why
do you guys have so much distillate
everywhere and I said oh because there's
poison in it and now we can't sell
poison anymore it's full of my club you
know I said oh wow there's you got a
million dollars worth of micro butanol
distillate right here I bet if I figured
out a way to get that out you'd probably
pay me a decent amount of money to turn
unusable product and usable product so I
partnered up with nug farms in Photon
and got a little bit of help from some
other people and we
put that into trials and discovered
pesticide remediation through you know
what is novel to cannabis but what is
really elementary chemistry and and I'm
not a chemist so you know I was walk
through what is chromatography how does
that work but what I retained through
all of that was the IP to the entire
tech and in I went through this little
moral dilemma
do I keep this tech to myself and sell
it if I do how long till someone just
bootlegs it and gets rid of it maybe I
should just release it out because
really the goal my goal always has been
can how do we get people more high for
cheaper safer with better product right
so those are kind of like core tenets
and so we I released the pesticide
remediation wrote up an SOP some little
half-assed scientific journal entry and
let it out and that was really when the
flood wave came that was the that was my
first interaction with the open sourcing
of information based on you know these
lessons I had learned and it worked to a
tee my social media following exploded
all of a sudden I was getting calls left
and right even though I had given out
all this information completely for free
the people with the money they didn't
care they wanted their hands held
they're willing to pay whatever it was
that I would charge to come down and do
it for them
so we took that model and applied at the
ethanol extraction falling film
evaporators and this all culminated in
the form that Travis had mentioned
earlier so future 4200 calm as anybody
in the room not never heard of future
4200 calm maybe no don't want to say
okay I don't believe you but all right
the forum has become really the number
one place on earth for the open
communication of ideas revolving around
cannabis processing a platform for
people to present refine ideas with
their peers a symbol of how an open
source of data can thrive and empower
its contributors several industry
changing revolutions have occurred there
the first big one in my eyes is the O
TSS crystallization so in the early days
of the forum I get hit up by a guy he
had identified all these models that I
just told you which as a permaculturist
I love because it's all about
identifying successful natural patterns
and repeating them so out of the blue
this guy says hey we're making these
diamonds that all these big companies
are making and I'll I'll tell you
exactly how to do it if you if you'll
put it up on your forum and give me the
credit for being the guy that told you
how to do it so he sends me like a 2,000
word run-on sentence and says here's the
SOP and I said oh my goodness
this is okay so we spend like a week
refining it and we let this out giving
him full credit not the other first
group of every told that I proof read
that wrong sentence and man did it work
thus it the model repeated itself
beautifully here it is here's the
information for free 90% of the people
went grab the information went home and
made diamonds on their own but that 10%
that wanted to have their hands held may
Bob a rich man on his free information
Travis the next really big one and this
one is huge this one is one of my
favorites color remediation cartridges
again novel to the cannabis industry
some really basic basic chemistry
chromatography using a different solvent
nothing crazy there but nobody I guess
people had been applying it nobody was
talking about it that was the big thing
and the same with the Diamonds he didn't
invent the diamond tech' he was just the
first guy to tell you how to do it and
same with this so a combination of endo
fabs and dread pirate now we get a lot
of input from
Marie and we're watching this this time
it's much bigger last time Bob was
really the only one that came out of
that as a paid man now we're seeing
companies formed out of open source
technologies multiple people have formed
very lucrative consulting businesses
they're teaching classes because people
are willing to pay for this open source
knowledge but this is bigger than
cannabis yeah this is like a holistic
thing that we're facing right now and
it's kind of getting back into what the
the host of this venue it we're talking
about before I got up here is this open
source model is a community thing this
this is forcing us to interact with each
other which is really the true nature of
being a human and I'm a capitalist to
the core but I believe that we need a
cycle capitalism I bit I believe that we
need permaculture based capitalism your
capitalism has to be based on taking
care of the earth and taking care of
people first and I trust me if you do
that you're gonna be more successful so
more importantly than the creativity and
innovation open-source thinking can
inspire is the defense against a closed
system when we allow closed systems to
rule the world we give away our freedom
inevitably closed systems control
information and data and with data you
can control people with the money you
can derive from this data you can
control the government when one company
controls both the people and the
government we have serious issues closed
systems allow power to consolidate
closed systems are why the majority of
existing cannabis patents are currently
held by a few large companies companies
that don't give a fuck about the plant
or you or any of the things that we've
built over the last 70 years of
prohibition patents that were acquired
during the depths of that prohibition
for the long-play before any of us were
even thinking about before a lot of us
were born but before any of us were even
thinking that this is going to be
something legal that we might build
businesses and put our whole entire
lives into these companies were solid
aiding power
they acquired these patents knowing that
it would be nice to control that as well
so I don't suggest to have the answer to
the serious problems that face the
cannabis equipment manufacturer
regarding open source same way I
couldn't have answered the music
industry's problem with Napster at the
turn of the century I do know that
Chinese companies are going to steal
your ideas replicate them ship them back
to the US for cheaper than you can
imagine
regardless of what model you take sure
you can fight the Chinese maybe even
leverage the government to shut down
trade with them not that any of the
other multi-billion dollar industries
have had any luck with that approach but
good luck but just like shutting down
Napster led to Kazaa LimeWire and much
worse torrents fighting the theft of
intellectual property in the 21st
century feels like a short-sighted
approach perhaps if we focus on the
things that we can control things we can
leverage through the same internet
channels that seem to be leading to our
destruction we can tap into what people
really desire corporate trust
transparency and personal relationships
with customers things no foreign company
can provide but building community
within we can all level up together see
that's the real solution here the only
way to protect the plant and our
economic futures involving said plant is
to work together open-source is probably
the wrong term for this idea but the
point is that we need to open up to each
other to build a better future for
cannabis professionals for the canvas
plant and for society as a whole
[Music]
thank you Thank You Dustin we're gonna
take a couple quick questions if anyone
wants a show of hands but is a question
for Dustin you know this you're getting
a free question usually it cost you a
truckload of money anybody in the back
there no and I never will I'm not a I
don't sell equipment he asked are you
are you selling CRC tech er or the
equipment
I'll sell you the tech if you need your
handheld but no the equipment there's
multiple industry or manufacturers in
the industry right now that are selling
that MBO ler endo fabs busy will
probably jangle you something together
really any of the stainless
manufacturers can put you together a
cartridge I think open-source steel is
still around I also think glacier tanks
is probably still around killa on the
forum is will put you together one
really cheap if you if you want China
parts I'm really gonna probably be
getting China parks wherever you go of
it so not me there's lots of people if
you need me to repeat any of that feel
free to hit me up you know how to find
me
anybody else thanks again Dustin
appreciate you for seeing your time
[Applause]