so jackson you're in charge for the 250
people
still watching at midnight
go to bed but that's i
actually i want to just can people like
type in
where they're watching from because
we're on the west coast time zone and
it's already midnight so i'm like
are you people in boston are you in
south africa
you want to talk about that uh i
can yeah i mean um i just didn't so get
give us our learning moment for the day
all right one little
one little teachable thing here so um
over the years
you know we we started i think i kind of
break it down all of this but
you know usually like when when we
started growing everything was kind of
in small pots and you kind of taught
like keep them wet you can't over water
that's why you use good dirt
if you have bad dirt it's too dense
maybe you gotta watch out but you just
use good dirt to start it drains well
and you keep it soaking wet
and uh i remember guys over the years
who would just take a dripper and stick
it in there and it would come from
gravity feed from their spring and they
would literally just have water going
all the time just put a pile of some
food on top and
let it drip through and um and
everything was always fine and then
we started to grow um you're allowed to
grow
six plants and then you're allowed to
grow 25 plants and people try to stick
to it
and you figure oh wow okay i put them in
a
now i tried putting them in a i put them
in a you know a 65 gallon pot and then
they outgrew that so you try 100 you try
300 some people use 600 gallon pots now
you know they make fabric pots
um grassroots fabric pots are a killer
killer uh fabric
pop company um i'm not sponsored by them
but they're
you know i recommend their their pots
are cool but you get these huge pots
um or you grow in the ground or whatever
it is but you get this huge volume of
dirt
and um one once they get really once
once you get really uh
deep soil and it's far from the outside
you know like uh
when we used to do a little bit of
mushroom growing they would tell us you
know don't make your container bigger
than about 12 inches across and 12
inches deep because when you get further
than
that to the inside you tend to meat your
your
your substrate tends to get um anaerobic
you know and you lose the oxygen in
there and you start to get different
decay and stuff which you know
is is similar if you have soil that's
really wet
and um so we started to notice there was
this thing that would happen where we'd
look at the plants and we'd be like damn
it seems like
the beds of the plants are so big and
it's so hot out like the plants aren't
getting water at the bottom anymore or
the food's not reaching there because
we're getting the deficiencies at the
top of the plant
and the top there's food and there's a
lot and it's wet but what's it like down
below and you know sometimes you
somebody would like pop off a board off
their beds or
dig down in their pot to see what was
going on and all this different stuff
and then uh um i had a thing maybe
four or five years ago or something when
um
when pretty much no one had heard about
rude aphids and then i had root aphids
in my pots and
um it was and then i noticed you know my
my pots i had 65 gallon pots and i had
300 gallon pots
and the 300 gallon pot so i had root
aphids all over the place and the plant
started to look a little weird and the
top of the plant kind of starts to
yellow the leaves curl down a little bit
when they flower that flower develops a
little slower it usually winds up really
killer because it's technically it's
under fed it's not getting the nutrients
and a lot of times that's good
uh tasty weed like in jamaica what they
call italy when you plant it you don't
feed it
and so um we were
kind of like well what so what's the
deal here is it under watered over
watered underfed overfed is it
accumulating salt at the bottom
what the hell is going on you know and i
and i would see it at different people's
places and a lot of the time
it would be like one plant so yeah i
don't know you know whatever and
we'll figure it out but everything else
is killing it so you don't want to
change your program that much
um and the plants are still huge it's
just this little tip you're like this
should be the biggest buds but they're
not they're a little bit more lean and
they're not really what they should be
so um at a certain point
um i i because i have the 65s going and
i had the 300s going i i actually um i
actually hit up bamboo because
bamboo you know is uh he's a
smart dude he's experienced with a lot
of stuff and he's he's uh well educated
he has
you know a better education than me and
uh and a lot of experience to go along
with it and you know he goes to
davis and does classes on breeding and
talks to a lot of
a lot of people and uh and uh
you know sells beneficials and all this
kind of stuff so
i hit him up and i go you know what's
the deal with these things and he goes
well you want to do nematodes and then
he goes you know it's usually a sign if
they're out of control that you're over
watering and um before this i had
already kind of known a little bit about
the over watering causing the yellowing
but you get the root aphids and it's
exasperated it's just much
much higher levels of the same symptoms
when we
get root aphids and then i thought oh
it's the root if it's causing these
symptoms
so i noticed that my 65s that dried out
on a regular basis i couldn't find any
root aphids in them but the root aphids
came
in bags of this particular soil that i
bought
and it and i had used that soil for
for five and a half inch pots and so all
my starts had come from the same
infected soil so i
was having a hard time going okay the
65s they don't exist in
and the 300s they're just rampant so
what's the difference here
and luckily i had that little bit of
control to look at so
i realized that you know this because
bamboo was the one who mentioned he goes
you know it's usually over watering if
they're really out of control and i was
like okay
and um so i try all this stuff but then
i just
realized that then i see that it's
definitely the watering thing so i back
off on the water
well the root aphids basically disappear
and these symptoms disappear and
um and so uh
i'm throwing this in there because this
is a little bit of bonus information
because people don't really know this
about root aphids
root aphids don't really hang around in
soil that drains well like that's how it
works
in vineyards and things where they can
be a huge problem
if the soil is different then they just
kind of peter out
and they don't um keep a population and
they and they eventually
um eradicate themselves so
anyway um the post was basically just
saying hey you can buy this 40
water meter you stick it down to the
bottom of your pot and you can tell if
that's the reason because
you could be getting the same symptom
from it being too dry
as well at the bottom of your pots and
people who
really have their shit together a lot of
times will elevate their pots and put
them up on like some big
rock like some gravel so they can drain
extra well
and that will help with that size pot so
that instead of it being
um up against something that's wet all
the time there's air underneath them and
you know the
kind of thing about fabric pots is they
cause air pruning so your roots hit the
side and then they branch extra
and if you have a regular pot made out
of plastic and you go to like like in a
seven gallon or something you go to pick
it up
you'll notice there's not a lot of roots
around the stock the roots have
circled around the outside but in a
fabric pot
or an air pot or a root builder pot what
happens
is they reach the outside and then they
branch
and so um by actually putting them up on
some rock then you gain
that same benefit at the very bottom a
little bit more because they
they root prune what happens is they hit
the air and it sends them a signal that
don't go any further you know branch out
and they bush off the same way as if
you're to top a plant for people who are
familiar with what happens when you when
you top your plants you know
um so anyway the post was just telling
people like hey
if it looks like this get a water meter
a moisture meter because it's likely
you're over watering and then sometimes
you discover
like you'll have you'll have plants
and and you'll notice like one leaf will
droop
and then another leaf will droop and
you'll be like the whole plant looks
beautiful but there's like five leaves
and
that are drooping and it'll come and go
and you can't figure out what's going on
and a lot of times what will happen is
you have in the roots you have
you have dry spots that are in there and
you can't tell you
take the moisture meter and you probe it
around and you go okay
i'm giving it enough water but right
over here in this little
area it's not getting enough water so
you need to kind of make a little
make a little uh a little recessed area
and let the water go there extra to even
it out then you'll notice it goes away
and
so anyway just watering it's funny
because you can be super experienced
working in one way but then you go to
try to grow these monster plants
or you hook up drip and you're used to
hand watering or you change emitters or
you don't realize it but where your
emitter goes in the line
um there's a leak so you're getting
triple the water
and you don't know it because you
haven't been inspecting it all the time
because you just figure your stuff works
um so it was just a heads up to people
that watering winds up being
um really although it seems like
the simplest part of growing something
give it water
the water levels are huge and um people
who monitor it
um really scientifically you know they
they let that they let it swing they go
okay we take the moisture up to 80 we
let it drop to 20 and
you know in veg you do it different and
in bloom you do it different and i'm not
somebody who does everything monitored
really carefully like that
but i do like to monitor it well enough
that i'm not having
i'm not taking a big hit you know i
don't grow
under gavita's with least space so it
doesn't really matter to me if my plant
gets this slightly different yield but
what i can't have is just
um is a uh um
you know a failure where the plant is
just all messed up you know
so uh that's what the post was
it's a good summary so
this is uh you had posted something
about
tobacco right yeah and so
actually i think steve razor dropped off
but these are from
seeds he gave me and so i have like this
little one
and then
like this one
and i love i love so what i love about
these things is at night
they get totally erect and they just
like
all the leaves shoot straight up and
then in the daytime
they all just droop and get super lazy
like
lounging which is kind of interesting
um yeah i've noticed uh what's trippy
is that uh i have mine
in an area where they're shaded for part
of the day
and then it's like they um
adjust their their um
their uh level of water
uh uptake and transpiration so it's like
you put them in the
i have them in the shade and then
they're like really happy
and then the sun hits them and then they
start to wilt
and but then if i put them out where
they get the sun really early in the
morning
um then it's like they can stay more
level and they know it's it's like
they're ready for it
and so then they just look normal um
all of the time and that was something
that i didn't i didn't really realize
and it happened kind of with all the
different plants that i had
that were in the shade and then the sun
hit them when it was already intense
which was kind of like
pulling up almost like pulling a plant
out of a greenhouse
um when it's hot out they want to freak
out a little bit
and stuff um can i add to uh
the uh the over watering thing so
yeah really good point to make you know
over watering is probably the
most common mistake made by growers you
know from expert
to beginner it's just really easy to do
and for outdoor growers
when i'm when i have like new people on
a farm that i'm running
and i'm you know trying to take people
with very little experience
and try to cram all my experience into
them you know it's it's really you just
take everything you simplify
you know in the springtime it's colder
out your plants have smaller root
systems
they need a lot less water you know as
they grow
you know they need more but the biggest
indicator that i always tell people
because you know what jackson's talking
about where you see that you know i've
seen gardens where people have 10 pound
plants
and it's just one half of the plant or
one little branch
and if they don't catch it early and
start treating it with the right type of
you know like a nematode or other like
inoculants
um you know you can lose those plants
you know and you see it pretty commonly
so the indicator that i always tell
people when i'm teaching them is
underwatering and over watering both
have the same signs and the leaves
as your leaves are droops right and so
the only difference it's really common
sense and really basic is
if your leaves are over watered and you
feel right there in the leaf stem
you're going to feel that it's rigid and
then it's filled with
water inside it's nice and stiff and if
your plants are underwater
your leaves are still drooping and this
is going to be all fucking weak because
there's no fucking water in there
and you can feel it pretty easily so
that's kind of like a beginner's tip to
to seeing if you've over watered or
underwater they have the same look
but it's just as simple as seeing if
there's moisture inside the stem
and another thing that i think helps
guide people in learning
how not to over water is if you
underwater
and you're vigilant and you pay good
attention to detail in your plants
you can just add more water this is fine
if you over water
you have to fucking let it dry out
before you can do anything about it
so it's better to underwater than over
water if you had to make one of those
mistakes
and a good grower is going to be
vigilant pay a lot of attention to
detail catch it before it becomes a
problem
simply have more water if you continue
to over water
it will lead to you know potential pest
problems like the root aphids but
everything else from
viruses and really anything that can
harm a plant
from ph fluctuations and lack of
nutrient uptake
so yeah over watering big common mistake
and it's just as simple as just knowing
what to look for
you