future cannabis project welcome thank
you very much for watching this is Arjun
from Paradise seeds
we're coming live to you from the
spannabis expo in barcelona 2019 for
those of you who are not aware of who
paradise seeds are well actually we've
been here for a little while we've been
here for twenty five years we're
actually celebrating our 25th
anniversary this year here at spannabis
and it's a great celebration indeed
because we have entered a few of our
varieties in spannabis Champions Cup and
we've actually taken second prize with
our Olay amnesia last night during the
awards ceremony so that was really
really exciting one of the three
varieties that we brought out together
with Tommy Chong and Chong's choice with
the finest seed collection of paradise
seeds that brings us now to about 37
different strains in our catalog here
there's seven different out of flowers
we've got a few CBD rich strains in
there so there's a whole big variety of
different things that are nice for
different types of growers indoor and
outdoor there goes a little package that
I wanted to show you so here's our
catalog now you grab the catalog here
show me this package let me show you
just because we found out yesterday that
there's fake packaging going around as
well for Paradise seeds now this is of
course the evident thing that happens
whenever you're successful people start
copying your stuff right so in Russia
actually these Russian gangsters they've
copied our seeds and the package doesn't
even look anything like this so it's
very easy to spot the only thing that's
on that package is actually the logo
that's the correct thing but for the
rest the package is grey and it's square
so it really looks very strange but this
is the original packaging by paradises
this is the way it should should look
like so you zoom in to that I'll show
you the background of it as well the
back of it should look like this
there's a little bar code as well you
see now we got three five and ten packs
in our collection will very soon add one
and 50 packs to that as well so you will
have a lot more choice in in the number
of seeds that you'll find in the packs
and yeah so very exciting year for us
now the CBD strains today are very very
popular today in our portfolio we'll
have two strains that are CBD rich but
they're also still THC rich that means
they have a one to one ratio THC CBD
which is very interesting from a
medicinal perspective of course and we
are currently in the test phase just
before releasing them so hopefully we
will be releasing very soon CBD strains
that are high in CBD but low in THC so
they'll be between zero point two up to
zero point six percent of THC in there
but there'll be a high quantity of CBD
in there so we're very close to
releasing them so stay tuned for that
for sure that's a very difficult
question my man it's like asking a child
you know a mother was their favorite
child you know it's a little bit
depending on the weed you know also you
got good sativa you got bad indica I
love to smoke weed anyway it's for me a
sativa in the morning and an IndyCar
during the day but I'll do it the other
way around as well if it just comes like
that you know I just smoked liked to
smoke and enjoy good quality weed that
is clean weed that is preferably
organically grown you know that is a
white ash that is a pure nice flavor and
for me that is more important than the
indica sativa I think and I'm also very
fond of hybrids actually
have it yeah sure what are you going to
tell me about the background yeah man
that's amazing
look at this guys this is 150 kilograms
of white widow paradise seeds white
widow being grown in a secret location
obviously in the north of Africa in this
case and this is actually a few years
ago already but we're really really
excited to see this and well it's now
the background of our photo booth so you
can stand there with our photo booth and
then take a picture souvenir picture yes
so let me show you these packages this
is the good package right now there's
one other version of it it looks like
this
this is the Chung's choice so we bought
three varieties to market last year with
Tommy Chong and songs choice and a pure
indica 90% indica with the blue cush
berry and then we did a hybrid with the
Mendocino skunk and we did a very strong
sativa with the LA amnesia and that is
the one that actually won the Cup last
night at the spannabis Champions Cup so
come get your chunks choice seeds at
Paradise seeds these look a little bit
different so the package here with
obviously with Tommy Chong on there and
I got a little extra surprise for
everybody buying our seeds right now you
get a free a free extra seed celebration
seed from us this is the first seed that
we actually ever brought to market 25
years ago this is because of our
celebration our anniversary we want to
give everybody who buys a pack of our
seeds one of these for free so this is
actually one of the most expensive
strains in our catalog that we're giving
away now so that's really exciting and
these are a little bit smaller packages
right so you see the regular packages
are like this and the promo pack is as
the smaller one so with every big one
you get one small one so that's a real
good deal I think for you guys and
actually why don't we do something extra
why don't I give you some of these and
then you can give away to your viewers
right you can do a little raffle on the
people who like the video you just pick
three winners and you can get some
paradise seeds if you if you write all
up for that I mean if you like it
just back them in your luggage
[Music]