Montana was a unique opportunity because
there there issuances medical carts were
so restrictive that the people who got
cards were truly sick
there was no chronic pain
there was no PTSD Montana was unique and
it's its program and that they were so
highly restrictive that the patients who
came to our door were all truly truly
truly truly sick you know people coming
to us with baskets of drugs I am on
these 24 pills every day how do I get
off of them and we helped so many people
do that it was just amazing and one of
my favorite stories of all time in our
shop was we had this old couple who she
came in she's like I you know had cancer
I'm on these 26 drugs I'm a zombie I'm
not living my life I haven't lived my
life for a decade and her husband
old-school farmer cowboy hat his boots
came in with her every time she walked
in that door sat down next to her elder
had never said a word never said a word
just she did her thing we got her off
those pills I mean she was down to three
one day I'm sitting in the office I'm
doing my thing and I noticed this old
man this kind of wandering around
staying out of the way but you know I
can tell he's waiting for an opportunity
to talk to somebody so I'm like hey
what's going on how can I help you comes
over he sits down it's like I want to
tell you something it's like when my
wife and I came in here at first year
and a half ago I thought you guys were
for sure but I hadn't had a
conversation worth a with my wife
first over a decade
she's been it zombie I thought I lost my
wife it's like last night we're sitting
out on the patio in the rocking chair
watching the sunset and she's talking
yeah like she used to talk to me 10
years ago and she's smoking her pipe and
totally animated and engaged and she
walked back in the house and I sat there
in tears I had my wife back so I came
here today to tell you that you're not
and thank you and I mean I'm
saying they're going wow I didn't just
help her I helped the family you know
the family is better off because of what
we did for her you know that was what
you're doing in your agriculture
practices what we're championing is the
tip of the regenerative expir that will
influence the whole industry in the next
10 to 20 years yeah it'll be uh it's
something that needs to happen because
Vince draining of our water the salting
of our fields and I mean I suck because
I'm a farmer and I understand salts and
and it's easy and it's quick and it's an
instant fix and I get it from both sides
you know that yes using them long term
contaminates our soil but I'm down to a
quarter of what a normal farmer would do
you know and I mean I'm
still I'm using alfalfa pellets and it's
another thing I'm using in my soil so
you know I'm creating a rich soil of
nutrient based solution