[Music]
we ended up coming into an existing
space that was being used for cut
flowers a lot of pests were here when we
arrived and ideally you want to get to
the point where sprays become pretty
much unnecessary and that can be done
it's a combination of a handful of
different things first in my mind being
cleanliness keeping everything you
keeping your your environment clean it's
kind of the first step to that and the
health of the plants strong healthy
plants with with high Brix levels don't
tend to attract pests nutrition has an
effect if there's that there are
specific triggers that will send out
signals basically for pests kind of like
ringing a dinner bell
so you can actually draw them in based
on what you're doing
if they are here preexisting and and
trying to get rid of them
spraying becomes one of the options that
you can consider depending on the level
of the outbreak the conditions that
you're working in and the choice of
things to spray one of the reasons that
the industry is going to be subject to
such a substrate restrict regulations is
the absence of those regulations has led
to the use of a lot of things that are
not safe ornamental and you're seeing a
lot of a lot of people especially this
last year with the some of the lawsuits
that have been going around a lot of
that surrounding the use of things that
are not registered for this particular
use they're not registered to be used on
anything that's going to be consumed
they are ornamental only the choice of
things to spray that are safe for safe
for the considering where the plants
going to be on the plants going to end
up being consumed adding flame to that
even changes the game once again because
introducing some of the some of the
stuff that is used and considered
organic fruit for fruit and berry and
stuff like that production when you burn
it it changes it changes the consistency
of it to where it can become harmful to
human health I guess would be become
toxic so the the choice of things to
spray yeah everything from horticultural
oils to just straight poisons I tend to
gravitate towards the horticultural oils
they have in addition to whatever kill
rate the substance itself might have
there's a smothering effect as well a
lot of things mites and things like that
can be easily smothered if you add any
sort of put any sort of oil or anything
on powdery mildew you'll see it just the
powdery mildew falls apart so I tend to
lean towards things that are a little
bit more based on horticultural oils
than chemicals one example would be lost
coast plant therapy we've been using
this one for a few months now and it's
been working very well it's easy to use
its effective and it's non-toxic it's
completely safe to be in contact with it
you don't have to get all dressed up
this is peppermint and soybean oil
primarily peppermint oil soybean citric
acid the biggest challenge with a lot of
these things
and how effective their going to be is
determined by coverage how efficient
you're able to distribute this across
the plant material or over the plant
material things like backpack sprayers
can be really inefficient for even
coverage in an enclosed space like this
ideal in my mind is to be able to use a
fog one of the ways that you can do that
or one of the ways you can get close to
doing that that's still a little bit
more of a kind of hobbyist or Gardner
Gardner level not necessarily a
commercial level solution is these
atomizers which of course you see all
the hydro stores a little bit more
effective i feel except for the the
spray is all coming out in a direction
these things are spitting out a stream a
jet doesn't really doesn't really stay
suspended long enough for the air to
kind of move that around and and fog
everything out with the with a fogger
the idea would be that you're you're
kind of gassing everything almost your
your coverage ends up being a lot more a
lot more even and lighter you can go
through a lot less material as well not
have to spray anywhere near as much in
order for it to be effective
ideally but I like to be able to wait
till the end of the day and come in and
shut everything down and gas the whole
house and then come in in the morning
open it up and be using something that
that's soft enough that you don't
necessarily have an issue with people
walking right back into the greenhouse
and horticultural oils are kind of a
nice soft choice for that
so yeah this is basically just shooting
out in one direction
the authority getting dark underneath it
you know that's all dropping to the
ground right here
oh yeah right there yeah so you have
that spot directly underneath through
your spring with the majority of the
material it just kind of fell to the
ground and you can see while I'm doing
that it comes out just a little bit
finer than a backpack sprayer but
underneath for your spring you're seeing
this whole wet spot right so all that
material is getting shot out but then
the majority of it is kind of coming to
the ground really fast ideal would be to
have all of that stuff stay suspended to
where the circulation the air
circulation can push that around and we
end up with coverage in spots that you
wouldn't be able to hit directly so
instead of coming in and you know trying
to get up underneath the plant and spray
the underside of every leaf which is for
your coverage for efficiency and the
product you use and is as a factory
a lot more efficient or the the coverage
is kind of efficient together so to be
able to take that and put it in a little
bit finer particle to where our air
circulation would push that stuff around
in here and stay suspended in the air
for a while
means that you would have a lot more
thorough coverage what I was gonna ask
does that imply that a fogger creates
finer particles than an atomizer can
it's that's my understanding of them now
is that a fogger is producing a finer
particle the table in the stay suspended
longer got it so who is fogger do we
want to try out DRAM is the one that
we've been looking at the most right now
they make two products they make a pulse
fog which comes in two versions one of
them lends itself to organics the other
one is a little bit easier to use of
chemicals and then the cold barger which
is based on pressure
[Music]