[Music]
from guys like don't spray yep right
they just don't they're like we don't
spray we you know we had neem oil and
the base for revenge
we moved to trifecta you know and saying
or we moved to venerate or we moved to a
big-time exterminator you know all the
clean trim you know all the clean
pesticides we don't or we have garlic
clove oil
oh just 500 pounds you give it just
tested dirty and these guys like no it's
my god and and and and then you know
shit but I bought my clone from Kyle but
it even goes further than two because so
many times whenever a person that's
sourcing trim it to make it an extract
they themselves with their dirty machine
are what are getting the plant material
contaminated and so so they'll like you
know you know run them run you know this
material from this organic farmer who's
never sprayed or who who may have if
anything got a dirty clone but it
wouldn't show up in really that
substantial amount if it was grown
full-time outdoor the UV broke down the
pesticides and you know by that time you
know you wouldn't really see it in big
amounts where most people are seeing big
amounts of pesticides come through
because they have dirty extractors like
is whether you're doing closed-loop like
light hard carbon butane interaction or
you're recycling and recirculating
solvents whether you're doing like co2
extraction where you have this
closed-loop machine or distillation to
further purify that's the place where
the highest amount of across
accommodation for the pesticides is
coming from and so so you know organic
good farmers are almost getting pulled
into you know this dirty process because
it's like by the time somebody is making
extract sources a bunch of trim and then
concentrates it they don't know if the
pesticide that's in there is from the
farmer or from the dudes that they ran
right before and they didn't clean the
machine out yes yeah well that's where
that urine system would come in you know
it's like but have it applied to like
drift of culture too right yeah you know
like how practices drifted you know and
how clones drifted not just because not
all of us have free broadcast which I
mean I've
seen a crop duster on my Mountain right
you know but well no it's just to be
shocked if like my neighbor hired a crop
duster to come through and do something
so I'm not gonna get that type of drift
you know exposures to the Appalachian
thinks about what's happening to and how
certain Greenbelt the Green Revolution
like areas of California that hasn't
been so beat up and guilt over sprayed
are almost gonna not necessarily be the
most beneficial places to grow so that's
why it going to moving into it and
especially now that the flower market is
dying the you know the oil market is
emerging you know we need to have a
unified parts per billion parts per
trillion whatever the testing is it
needs to be fair I mean okay good the
uric is what's what's the acronym yeah
so uric you are EC it's it was an
academic created by the National Organic
Program to account for the fact that we
live in a toxic environment in certain
areas there's drift and and it that's
unavoidable and so it's unavoidable
residual environmental contamination and
it's and it's an exemption basically
that the the National Ganic program
allows organic certified crops to still
pass in the marketplace as organic as
long as less than five percent of the
EPA allowed level of pesticide for that
same crop so even though this is organic
and you can't use pesticides because of
drift you know safe or something like
michael--ah butanol or eagle 20 which is
commonly approved for grapes and berries
you know if you're organic certified
grape berry farmer you know and you know
there's their very real reality that you
know it's a drift happens and it
you know if one if the your neighboring
farmer sprays and there's winds and
carries over to your farm you still have
to be able to do be able to work and do
what you're trying to do and so to your
point I think it's such a big one
because you know from testing standpoint
we you know there's there never there's
never been any states that put in any
you know proposed limits for these
different pesticides you know we just
when we started testing you know back in
2010 we knew that you know there's these
specific compounds people were using and
they needed to be tested for and if
you're not testing for these specific
pesticides and - IDEs and fungicides and
you're kind of not really you know
offering much to somebody who's selling
pesticide test tube and so so then all
of a sudden Oregon came in and took the
list expanded the list and then they
created proposed limits that will
disqualify somebody if it's above this
certain limit so Oregon's limits we
thought we're the strictest had that had
ever come about all of a sudden
California in that emergency bill that
was just passed where they they put out
proposed limits and they went basically
20 times stricter than Oregon so in
Oregon where Michael beaten all eagle 20
is regulated at 0.2 ppm which is 200
part per billion California went to
regulated to ten part per billion so
point zero one so about 20 times more
sensitive amount you know just to
clarify sort of look at general
agricultural best practices yeah you
know Oregon the way they they looked at
all the compounds on the list you know
they looked at their you know they did a
lot of research into the toxicology data
of the different pesticides and
compounds and you know how they interact
with aquatic life and you know all these
things and then they they rated I'm on
these levels of like most concerning -
least concerning and then you know they
kind of they arbitrarily created the
limited action limits more based on the
labs up in Oregon
ability to pick up at those certain
amounts more than you know anything else
is really substantial and so so
California kind of went way and the
other direction went stricter than you
could have ever gone and so it's very
problematic is like from our perspective
a lot of the regulations around
microbiology I think they nailed it on
because they didn't regulate or they
took off things like aerobic bacteria
and yeast and mold levels from being
disqualifications and they more focused
on the pathogenic bad harmful microbes
like certain Aspergillus that brings
Micro toxins so we think they didn't
really get rid like certain other
testing regulations but with the
pesticides that went way too far so if
anything we're trying to lobby to have
the state recognized that there's a
happy medium you know where you you know
you create a zero tolerance policy which
essentially did having each pesticide
regulated at ten to twenty part per
billion which is such small I mean
residue amount you know all of a sudden
they're gonna make it almost impossible
to grow or in certain geographic areas
where there's a lot of high AG you know
because you know if they don't account
for and allow for this drift reality you
know by by by almost elevating the
limits of from ten part per billion to
maybe fifty eighty part per billion you
know then what they're gonna do is
they're gonna create too strict of a
system that's gonna put too many farmers
you know essentially out of business
consider well I mean you know I would I
would argue though to say that we don't
have that drift issue where we've been
farming for decades and that the drift
issue is happening in areas where there
should be anyway
they're you shouldn't be growing anyway
very that and it's like so if they lose
out like I'm not gonna I'm not gonna
shed a tear no honestly pet the
pesticide topic is where I'm most
passion and and you know because before
we open up the se labs I worked in the
hydroponic industry and I did a lot of
kind of consulting ongoing consulting
integrated pest management and how to
properly get rid of and prevent pests
and pathology but you know people always
you know whatever are busy don't do
things they get lazy they don't follow
the protocols they have other people
taking care of the plants you know and
then they get an infested moment where
they this huge outbreak of bugs or huge
outbreak of like powdery and then it
puts them into this and scrupulous you
know space where they'll spray or what
have you and and so I don't really have
a whole lot of I mean I think I think in
this new brave new world of cannabis I
think it's only the most organic fully
intentionally farming kind of folks that
are gonna really make it cuz it's like
if you haven't gotten hit by broad mites
if you haven't gotten like I mean the
the time where people can get away with
spring systemics is gone now it's like
if you're you're in a certain area where
there's drift you're almost even Mike
you know like stoked that that's
happening right that were you know they
were getting away we're really setting a
benchmark for quality and for standards
I mean it's yes so something somewhat
unobtainable you know by you know by in
some regions right in our region like
I'm saying you know it's what we do have
an issue tell us where you're growing
like how are going to Mendocino and one
of the issues that I have in Mendocino
now
is those systemics being sprayed on
mom's right like that's that's the main
cause or people thinking that they can
spray systemics and veg I didn't throw I
didn't do it in Flour like nope your
shits dirty bro and look that's that's
that's really where we get it from this
place we're like we're seeing this we're
not seeing and we're seeing stuff go
from one lab to another to another and
testing positive and then possessing
negative two like I've been to this
mother figures issues yeah I've been on
such a roller coaster ride on my phone
the last like three days with stuff
that's getting batch tested and like oh
it didn't pass here but it passed there
oh wait hold on when they kicked this
back oh wait no wait they're gonna put
it through over here and it's like so
the Kansas is like a pinball right going
between all these different x-rays man
they got a guy with a transit van
basically sitting on like you know 101
traffic you know in 580 getting shit
between Oakland's and
like all these Sonoma you know getting
all these things like the different
places then they're saying oh no we'll
take it we'll take it we'll take it
but there's nothing there's no
unification it seems like right well you
know and I think that's me also one of
the greatest things about regulation
because you know if there's gonna be a
robust process of regulating how
cannabis is grown and how its processed
and produced you know there almost has
to be and California learned this in
Oregon learn this you have to almost
hold the labs to a higher level of
accountability than even the produces
processors and so so what California did
and what organ is they required in order
for lab to even operate or to have their
services offer available to the
community in the public they have to
have gone through full ISO accreditation
not just on their lab but on every
individual test they offer to the public
and then further they have to go through
routine quarterly proficiency testing
where the state gives you a spiked you
know solution with a bunch of different
pesticides in it or a bunch of different
terpenes and cannabinoids and you have
to be able to pick up in this blank you
know in this in this completely unknown
mixture you have to be able to pick out
out the levels that the states are going
to be running to show that you can even
do that level testing and so that that's
the prerequisite is lobster so so I
think you know your frustration I think
is one of the biggest frustrations the
market is like how do you know who's
correct you know it's like you send you
some samples to all these different labs
and all these different labs different
results but it's like the lab testing is
a really complex thing cause it's like
is you know how old is the mass
spectrometer being used to test or pick
up pesticides you know it's like if it's
ten years old it might be picking it up
at ten Parker
you know as opposed to some of the newer
instrumentation that you know it picks
it up it you know - did - part per
billion level you know and and then you
know it's it and then I think I think
it's it's a the way that you can figure
it out as you know as as a client of lab
services you know it's like you can do a
bunch of blind testing on a lab you know
cuz if you know I think you're setting
yourself up for failure unless by
testing with a bunch of different labs
and expecting the lab results to ever
kind of really come online but if you
can do a bunch of testing internally
with each lab sending Neos you the same
samples labeled many different things
tested you know over a period of a few
weeks you know you can start to see
where and how often the lab hits the
bull's eye you know and and I think it's
a really important thing you know in
this lead up to regulation wall you know
people are choosing which lab works and
what lab is consistent and repeatable
and precise because unfortunately at
this moment there's not a labs out not a
lot of labs that are and so yeah so I
think that's a big problem that's gonna
you know mate really get alleviated with
regulation because you know the labs are
gonna be held to an account that they've
never had to be you know most laps in
the United States haven't had to be yeah
I think it will help to make it apples
to apples comparison among the labs you
know but but then the other thing kind
of is gonna mention about just the
passes I think into concentrations
one of the really interesting thing is
about pesticide residues you know
because I I used to work with in the
hydroponic industry and there's you know
a lot of common misinformation about you
know how long certain pesticide residues
would last residually in the plant and
so and you know and a lot of really good
even even trying to do the right thing
type farmers you know have in some way
or another in the past you know kind of
fallen victim to giving you an
infestation in some way and and and we
have resorted to using systemic
pesticides you know I mean I I would
wonder if you ever have you might not
have you know and that's amazing that
shows how that shows on the level you're
on but but what's really interesting is
you know there's always been this calm
and misconception that pesticide
residues like eagle 20 or flora might or
avid you know lasts like thirty to sixty
days and then they're gone and you know
just to kind of expand on the complexity
of the conversation you know one of one
of the biggest things that breaks down
pesticide residues whether they're
organic pesticide residues or these
systemic kind of you know Dow Syngenta
Bayer type pesticides you know is the UV
spectrum from the Sun so it's like the
UV a B and C spectrum from Sun grown
cannabis from the exposure of Sun to
your plants is one of the major things
that breaks down and determines how
quick a residue breaks down and so so
you know whenever people are talking
about how long these pesticide residues
stick around in mom plants and then
clones that people are cutting you know
in so many ways it become it comes from
people growing mothers in door
you know because whenever you have a
mother plant that's indoor under high
pressure sodium or metal halide lighting
you know most of lighting up to this
point
that's indoor lighting is is void an
absent of UV a B or C you know some of
the newer indoor technology lighting
like plasma lighting well is starting to
bring in certain UV spectrum certain
LEDs now are bringing in certain UV
spectrum but largely most indoor grown
cannabis are lighting exposed to kind of
the plant growing indoor is lacking UV
and so therefore you know what we see at
the lab is you know it's incredibly
extended pesticide residues basically on
mothers you know ranging anywhere from
six months to a year after you know is
originally used and that's what's
getting a lot of
they're sourcing phones from these
mother treated or these these treated
mothers that are grown under and you
know indoor lighting and so and so so
the residues that might the residue that
might kind of be broken down rapidly
outdoor you know kind of if anything
just stays down much longer you know
well it's also like I said you know
saying earlier it's not just the the
farmers practices it's the firmest
purchases right just a farmer purchasing
plants receive surgery oh man I need to
do this run and then what ends up
happening is you know we end up having
to get full batch testing right as I say
I mean you have a greenhouse filled with
the 250 plants and 50 of it came from
your farm
children came from various farms around
the county around the ridge you know
it's like you have you're susceptible to
whatever right and then the trim room it
all goes in the trim room it's already
trimmed up it's all getting thrown in
garbage bags I'll get in tight you know
and send down and one small you know one
batch testing positive for my feet off
might contaminate your entire arm and
kick your whole farm out you know you
know sale so you're like so you know
that's that's for our biggest issues
right now it's like you know how do we
educate the farmers into separating the
trim out from each batch how do we you
know you know if you're not sure that
that clone is pesticide free you know
like can we get that can we get on it
and you can test like before you commit
also so much into growing those plants
out you know like we test the leaf of a
clone or what have you you know that's
when you'll see pesticide concentrations
at the highest point they'll be also if
they've been treated you know and so
it's I mean what you're describing those
in so many ways it's fascinating cuz I
think regulation on cannabis
particularly around pesticides you know
know crop has ever been regulated
cannabis is about to be on pesticides as
strict limits as pesticides and Logan
and water and everything you know and
it's so fast into you because you know I
really feel like it's gonna reinforce
you know these this you know kind of
slow food movement ideal is like we're
talking about earlier of like you know
source can control and identification
you know I mean knowing knowing your
farm you know having the connection to
where your clones are coming from having
the connection to where your sourcing
your compost you know it's like it's it
you can no longer be detached from these
things you know or just have faith that
it's all going to be good because you
know it's organic you know cuz and you
know even on the pesticide thing it's
like I think it regulations are really
gonna be breeding and raising up such a
new caliber and quality of farmer you
know that's that is so precise on you
as medicine to the perfect of a perfect
you know perfect ability of it itself
and you know and and III wonder have you
have you guys heard of this it's a
syndrome except for one of the first
negative things that's happened with
cannabis and ret in regulated states
it's called cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome it's this really else is coming
our way I'll do this really weird rate
it's really well it's it but it's it's a
thing that's happening from improper
organic farming right so so basically
cannabis hyperemesis is this it's so
certain patients that well in inhale or
utilize cannabis we'll all of a sudden
have to go to hospital from this thing
that they're calling like this cyclical
vomiting syndrome so they'll just like
throw up and the count stop throwing up
and one of the only things against that
can chill the you know the reaction
whatever is happening even when they go
to the hospital is like if you figured
if they go into a hot shower or you get
exposed to hot hot water you know that
typically will mellow out some of these
the things that are happening from this
condition but what's really fascinating
is all of this specific you know kind of
side effects that are happening from you
know from this this condition that
people are attributing a cannabis now
that's this unknown in all these states
identically mirror what's known in India
as neem oil poison and and so so so as a
doctrine as a doctrine is a concentrate
off of neem oil so it so it's like it's
an isolated compound from neem oil that
what has with some of the more in
insecticidal properties and it's Omri
listed organic materials review
Institute
you know it's labeled as you know yeah
that you're able to spray it up to day
of harvest you know and we're not
talking about a leafy green
you know it's that you spray as a
doctrine like in the form of as a saw or
as a max you can't use as a troll
anymore because it just got pulled off
the market even though it's an organic
listed it had like these four unlabeled
pesticides in it you know yeah yeah so
as a trawl just got pulled off in Oregon
because it had like all these
pyrethroids and like some other
pesticides in new players so there is
organic
chrysanthemum fighters droids but then
there's all these synthetic pyrethroids
also but but you know but then there was
a chemical called pylon in there too but
but anyway the you know just I think
that just kind of shows it boiling
yep again it's great that Paganica is a
chrysanthemum extracted pyrethrin
organic listed everything's good but you
know it's like you can use that at time
where it shows up still you know but but
I think you know the big thing I was
talking about me more I was like you
know this new caliber farmer it's like
because not only are you not allowed to
use the conventional stem expres that
big farm has used big AG as used to grow
mono crop agriculture you are no longer
allowed to use those because they're so
regulated you might even see them if
your neighbor spray them right and so so
then you as a farmer are only able to
use like these organic approaches
towards keeping with pests and pathology
which is just this whole body of
awareness and integrated pest management
that you know I think is really what
defines you know you know everything you
were talking about the regenerative
farming it's like looking to nature for
a more efficient design and creating is
perfecting like the environment you give
it so that you can naturally keep it
away and I think that's really what's
going to define the new farmers and also
that you you know it's it even organic
products you can use improperly you
spray neem oil on the plants before
harvest you know you might actually do
harm
and this kind of hyperemesis things in
no joke you know and it's crazy that's
from an organic pesticide even that yeah
you know like I see so much of what it
is that we're doing is regenerative
farmers that's a duty their tools are to
to create these standards along the
lines of Virginia farming practices
there all of these things they're just
seemingly unfair coming down from these
regulated you know regulatory agencies
and these regulatory bodies they never
grow cannabis never never and you know
it's kind of like this mentality is like
oh they want to grow fine let them grow
but they have to do this and it's like
[Music]
you know the farmers are running into
these situations where we can't do
everything it is no right and what is
why you have to be realistic and that's
why we have to lobby the regulators and
you know the legislators to kind of do
it right because I mean you know I could
very much detrimental on the entire
community I'm gonna make it rain to
regulate so give me some specifics of
proposed legislation that you're looking
at and say that's totally unfair like
what are some of the specifics that you
disagree with and what would you like it
to say instead as far as what I see as a
weed hustler you know saying that's had
to shift from flour sales to trim sales
that it really sucks
what's what what the guy on the other
side of me is able to do to go to
different labs go to her things take all
of my products run all of it offer me
$15 a pound if it tests positive or you
know yeah it's like it's it's ridiculous
and all they have to do is show me a
test result God knows where that
Testament came from brick thank you
they'd have the same test result for the
same dude the test is positive positive
you know saying and just ship it off to
everyone else and just you know cut copy
and paste negative test results we don't
know where farmers right uh damn of shit
tested positive what am I gonna do and
so the regulations that I see and what
Alec was talking about earlier being so
stringent being possibly ten parts per
billion on residuals like that's
it's not just trips like I said we're
talking about being a cultural trip
right thank you feels like cultural
drift syndrome where you know just
something happened right whether or not
it's a little bit of p.m. whether or not
you know what is that specified what
whatever it is like to be regulated at
that degree with with very room a little
room or I mean if I take my stuff to go
to a refinement process and lose half a
micron I have my crop it half of that
sale will go down and hunters are fine
all everything all the residuals out and
so I went from saying oh I'm gonna make
ten thousand dollars off this little
trip to five thousand dollars off the
soda trip and I've got to split that two
ways and then you know and that's his
two ways on the other so everyone's
getting like 1,200 bucks and all because
one lab tested positive so these are the
issues I'm seeing personally as a
distributor you know for appellations of
origin and Oakland for appellations of
origin is you know we are going to
strive to have our own sets of standards
to raise the bar head-over-heels above
where the hand or hand above where the
state is right but we have to have local
hubs and processing facilities run by
local manufacturers that's my standard
never seems out either and then a run by
cooperating what's going on we have to
have testing labs within our
another nothis se coming up in setting
up shop and these hubs and processing
facilities as a partnership agreement to
some of these you know larger
collectives or cooperatives the the idea
is that we have our we have to have the
manufacturing the extraction industry
more accountable alright for the testing
right and for the responsibility to the
farmers for getting back fair pricing at
the end of the day like I don't grow
trim so finding is it but if I'm not
growing flower and I'm selling trim and
it's always coming back positive or
something I'm not making money either so
that's know a big time you know and and
you know and when it's so many ways to
get the most frequent conversation I
have like with people that we work with
within this testing community you know
so largely is around the pesticide topic
you know and and it's really fascinating
cuz you know a lot of a lot of my
mentors and you know the Giants whose
shoulders I'm standing on who I've
learned from you know people like Tim
Blake up in Mendocino County you know so
many people I know up in the Emerald
triangle like I've been doing this
generationally with their families you
know almost have this existential fear
that you know with regulations you know
this could come this big AG model that's
gonna come and smash the price of herb
and so many people are gonna lose in the
love livelihoods you know but but you
know if truly in so many ways like I you
know it's unlike romantic perspective
you know I see I see the regulations
like cannabis or you know I mean I think
that we have to get Urich recognized
this unavoidable residual they have
passed the limits have to get a little
bit raised you know but but but in
general I think the best aside
regulations as strict as they are
they're gonna most benefit the small
medium scale Appalachian kind of
mom-and-pop farmer who's been doing this
forever because you know it's like if
you've done this for 20 years and you've
gotten smashed by broad mites and you
have seen thrip infestation to its worst
and aphids and all these things
and you know and you're able to
understand how to grow and your
microclimate region without being
reliant on systemic use you know
fungicides to keep away powdery mildew
you have this almost built-in level of
insulation you know that I think is
going to be your biggest benefit in the
regulated market cuz like as the ships
over and there's this transition to
where you know only clean we will
eventually be allowed into dispensaries
and and and and you know and the whole
thing start shifting I think I think
there's an incredible crisis of scarcity
of clean material on the market right
now whereas there's an abundance of
dirty wheat and you know I you know
California you know the amount of weed
this ground here you know 80 to 90
percent of I'd say is going out of state
and probably well for a long time you
know even though there's a comprehensive
regulated market model Mike it's gonna
stop but the thing is is like I think
those that participate in the regulated
space you know I think all the big money
like johnny-come-lately folks that are
just coming in with all this VC money
thinking they're with all their
projections and their illusions of
grandeur about how much they're gonna
crush it I think are gonna be the first
crushed because it's like if you don't
have this humble reverence for the plant
and then being a steward and a servant
of the plant and like have learned the
lessons to do it right I mean because is
the the time where you could get away
with you know identifying you at broad
mites you know three weeks into flower
and you're facing potential entire crop
loss where some farmers back in the day
would bomb their room with a nuclear
option you know it's some pesticide like
forbid or you know these different Bayer
chemicals or whatever it's like the time
where that could have actually you know
gotten away with its going
[Music]