hello this is travis from the hip mind
um what you are watching today is part
one
of two parts on the topic of
photoperiodism
um i'm sure some of you who are watching
are thinking what the heck is
photoperiodism
but for those of you who are watching
who are currently in the hemp industry
or the cannabis industry this is a topic
that is not
discussed as often as it should be
and the reason that is is just because
of the
you know the nascent and new market
of of cannabis in general if we compare
it to other mature markets
what i'd like to do through this video
is for one
address the concept of photoperiodism
help you have an appreciation for it as
well as a basic
understanding of what it is discuss
photoperiodic classes
maybe connect some dots between plants
that you
you grew up enjoying and how
they um and how they're manipulated
to flower similar to how we manipulate
cannabis to flower and and then
go through some practical scenarios in
the greenhouse and in the field
on how you can use this understanding to
manipulate the crop
to your benefit ultimately increasing
your your bottom line
at the end of the season or at the end
of the cycle
[Music]
first before we jump into the
presentation itself i want to give you
just a quick
understanding of my background and why
why it's pertinent
to to what we're talking about um
myself as well as my business partner dr
alice and justice both of us have been
trained
in commercial horticulture i went to
school at clemson and virginia tech for
environmental horticulture
and then went and worked with one of the
largest ornamental crop
growers in the country if we think about
agriculture we have a branch off of
agriculture which is horticulture
right and this is shrub production tree
production flower production
but then from horticulture we have a
branch of flora culture
and that is the background that both
myself and my business partner have we
have an extensive background in flora
cultural crop production
um the reason i i bring this up is
because
you know i i think back to my my career
in the ornamental industry and i i
hold that experience of extreme
value you know this is a mature
market it has a
supply chain which has been completely
developed
and in many cases those who are in it
understand the potential
of it and the only way to secure more
business
or the only way to grow is to maximize
internal production regarding
consistency and efficiency
to a level that can benefit from
shoestring margins at the end of the day
in these mature horticultural and
floricultural markets
those that are dealing with such a small
margin
at the end of the year
they are incentivized to understand
crop physiology to a depth at which
the cannabis industry has yet to even
touch the surface of
but now let's let's bring some of what
we've learned from these mature markets
into the cannabis market okay let's
let's you know stop in some cases
banging our head on the wall saying
what's next
and start to truly be innovative and
utilize some of the concepts that are
already known within
mature horticultural markets and start
implementing them
in the cannabis industry
so through this video what i'd like to
do is i'd like to touch on what the heck
is photoperiodism
why does it matter to you what are
photoperiodic classes
what class is cannabis
um then let's
talk through some scenarios and examples
being indoors being in a greenhouse
being in multiple different latitudes in
the us regarding field production of
hemp
and ultimately equip you to
maximize the potential of the genetics
and of
the cannabis plants that you have
to increase your bottom line okay
and so with that said let's jump into
the meat
of this video moving forward into the
future the hip mind will release what
we're calling
our technical support series and the
first topic that we'll be
discussing is photoperiodism and again
like i said i will be
presenting on part one and later on
allison will
launch another video which will be
presenting on part two
so what is photoperiodism
just so that whomever is watching i want
us all to be on the same page i'm going
to read exactly what this bullet this
first bullet says
photoperiodism is a physiological
response in multiple different plant
species that dictates whether or not the
plant is focused on vegetative growth
or reproductive growth this response in
photoperiodic plants is dictated based
on the amount of
darkness a plant receives during a
single 24 hour period and then
consistently thereafter
i know many of you have heard the term
photoperiod
and this refers to the amount of light
hours in a given 24 hour
period you know humans work during the
day we see when the light is
lights are on or the sun is out we work
during the day
and so when we discuss photoperiodic
plants we discuss
the photo period the amount of time
light is on or the sun
is out we do not discuss the duration of
the night period even though we know
that the length of the night period
obviously correlates with the length of
the day when we're only focused on
discussing a 24-hour period
but we know that plants ultimately
perceive the length of the night
so moving forward when discussing
photoperiodic plants and i say
photoperiod i'm talking about the length
of the day
and not the length of the night there
are different types of photoperiodic
classes
and these classes include long day
plants short day plants
day length neutral
cannabis falls into the short plant
short day plant category
and what this means is in order to
maximize the potential of this
crop um based specifically
you know in in certain facets of the
market that you're participating
in we need to maximize the production of
this plant by giving it a
long day followed then by a short day
and this transition from a long day to a
short day
initiates flowering causes the plant to
go from vegetative growth to
reproductive growth
okay and so that's a short day plant
long day and then a short day
um and then for long day plants it's
flipped
in some cases in order to maximize the
the potential of
other species you have to give them a
short day
followed by a long day
and you know in the cannabis industry
there's also
much discussion around autoflower um
genetics and you know autoflower i
believe
is a little bit a little bit different
than day neutral but very
very similar concepts that you're not
subject to the
length of the day it's more of either an
accumulation of
of um an accumulation of growth that
triggers flower development
um but what we're going to focus on
today
is short day plants however i do want to
make one
one more thought apparent here there are
additional characteristics that can be
attached to these photoperiodic classes
right so it can go even a level deeper
in the complexity of these different
flowering responses
and so for example you could even have
obligate short day plants
or facultative long day plants
i'll give one example of this so a good
example of a facultative long day plant
is greenhouse vine vine crop tomatoes
in some cases it's been proven that they
are facultative long day which means the
longer the day the better
regarding flower development and fruit
set however
they have also learned that there is
something as too long
of a day so you know just keep in mind
that
that we're having to navigate through
these different flowering responses for
multiple crops and
it is certainly nothing new um
so growing up i'm sure maybe your mom
had garden mums on the porch in the fall
and if not had
you know christmas poinsettias on the
fireplace
but these plants have the exact same if
not very similar
short day photoperiodic nature to them
that cannabis has
and these plants have been grown for
decades and we've learned an
extreme amount from maximizing
the production of these these plants
and so one thing i like to just point
out is this is nothing new why is the
cannabis industry not talking about
photoperiodism
when it's how we dictate and forecast
production of these other crops
we should so with
a basic understanding of what
photoperiodism is and understanding that
cannabis is a short day crop meaning
that you need
a short day preceded by a long day in
order to trigger flowering
let's now look at it look at an example
of an indoor
schedule the schedule here is just an
example i will admit that
this is this schedule is widely used
within completely climate-controlled
medical marijuana facilities to
smokeable flower greenhouse hemp
facilities
but let's just break it down and just
walk through it so that we understand
um how to look at this from a crop
development standpoint as well as a
production stage standpoint so if we
look at the
at the top of the the graphic here
i have production stage so we have
propagation
then i have the vegetative stage in
other mature markets in some cases you
call this bulking
and then we have flower development
these are three specific different
production stages
under that we have week number this is
not year week
this is week number within this single
cycle
and so let's start with discussing
propagation
in propagation and i'm focusing on um
schedules that
uh originate from using vegetative
material
so in propagation let's say that you you
have
mother stock growing um and you take a
cutting
and for this example let's use a 72 cell
tray
you take a cutting an unrooted clone
and you stick this in a 72 cell tray in
a propagation environment
you ideally can route this between 14 to
21 days
for the sake of the example i used 14 in
a perfect world we could root everything
in 14 days
so we are in we have the understanding
of okay we need to go through
propagation first
we need to root these plants but what
crop
development stage do we want to keep
them in we want to keep them in a
vegetative state
so we apply a long day and
in this case we apply an extremely long
day
of 18 hours
you know if uh it's been interesting for
me to understand why the cannabis
industry
by default is using 18 hours is a long
day and 12 hours is a short day
and what what we've come up with is that
you know if you were to open a crop
physiology book and you
you were to read through i guess the
photoperiodism
section by the book
for most plants a
long day is anything above
12 hours so the day length of anything
longer than 12 hours
and a short day is 12 hours or
less and so within the cannabis industry
um it's widely used that 12 hours
is the photo period at which you should
initiate flowering with
and i i do believe that that's just
because by the book
that's what it says we also are using 18
hours
as a long day because that's an
extremely long day we're pretty much
guaranteed that that plant is going to
stay
vegetative so that's why in this example
i show 1812 because
in most cannabis facilities throughout
the world
they're using this lighting schedule
which i hope after we watch this video
for those of you that are growing
indoors
let's challenge this a little bit okay
so let's move from propagation and now
discuss the vegetative stage
of crop production and so from
propagation like i said we have a 72
cell tray that's been rooted between
14 to 21 days we're still under a long
day
because we want to keep the plants
vegetative now let's
transplant these rooted clones these
liners
into larger pots and perhaps move them
into a different room or
move them and space them out in the
greenhouse and keep them
again under long days for three more
weeks so that we can build some
size on these plants the vegetative part
of this cycle
is focused on these plants building a
root system focusing on
leaf development shoot development cell
elongation cell division making these
plants
grow in bulk and get bigger in size
ultimately influencing where you have
flowers being developed and ultimately
dictating the amount of yield
you get at the end of the cycle so the
vegetative cycle and maximizing it is
very important for cannabis
so we've gone from propagation we've now
transplanted we've gone through
vegetative growth
we've kept both production stages under
the same crop developmental stage
by applying long days now we do what's
called flipping of the photo period
all we do is we reduce the amount of
light hours
from 18 to 12 and what does that do it
extends
the length of the night right this and
short day plants
triggers them into flower initiation or
into a reproductive state and then as
you see here on week six we start to
initiate flowering
and depending on whether you're a
marijuana grower trying to produce as
much thc as possible
or you're a hemp grower that is trying
to push the limits with cbd why
while still making sure that you stay
compliant with 0.3 total thc
you would then take your cannabinoid
test throughout this
flower development part of the cycle and
that would influence when you ultimately
harvest this crop
so with that basic schedule understood
for
indoor production of cannabis or hemp
let's look at some pictures that have
been grown under a very similar schedule
so the picture that i just
brought up here this is an example of
what's called a sea of green
okay and so i wonder if my mouse will
work it will so
most likely they had two weeks if not
three whatever it took to root the
plants
they had that same duration as part of
what we see here on this example
but what they did is they didn't allow
the plants to get very big
before they flowered them and that could
be due to the regulations per
state if they're required to have a
certain amount of plant count
versus taking up amount of space
whatever it may be
they've chosen to have more plants per
their area
with less amount of a vegetative
cycle throughout that that production
cycle
so what they've done is they've
transplanted these plants that have
rooted
and they have a very high density
planting
that they give a very short window of
vegetative growth so the plants don't
get too big
and then they initiate flowering and
that's how you have a sea of green
in this example which i hope you can see
i could have cropped it a little better
but you can see that each individual
plant is
much larger than the plants over here in
the sea of green example
and what this shows us is that they did
the same thing
most likely they propagated these plants
in two to three weeks
they then transplanted them into much
larger pots
spaced them at much wider spacing
and they gave these plants a longer
vegetative cycle to build
mass on these plants and so
most likely this scenario has used the
two
has used the three to four week
vegetative period
versus here that most likely used one if
not one and a half to
maybe two weeks and it shows you the
difference in plant size
and ultimately it will influence the
yield per plant
all of what you see is dictated based on
understanding the photoperiodic nature
of cannabis
and how you manipulate its light cycles
all right so let's move on to
discussing production of cannabis
outdoors
this is where the hip mind gets quite
passionate because obviously we are a
hemp company
and our main target customer is a field
farmer we are working very closely with
greenhouse customers
but we ourselves are vertically
integrated we grow 60 acres of hemp on
we're on our third year now
and so we want to offer as much
technical support to field farmers as
possible
for one knowing the risk that we're all
taking going into this from the start
as well as understanding how volatile
the market value
of the final product is okay
so let's look at the map itself
so once this video was published you
will have a
tab on our website that is labeled as
hpm the hemp planting map we have here a
good description high level on how to
use it what to look for
and the purpose of the map but
ultimately this video is meant to show
you how to use it
i do want to shout out to joanne logan
at the university of tennessee
she was the climatologist that helped us
compile all of the data for this map and
also helped us put it into a
functional and interactive format so
thank you very much joanne for helping
us do this
and make this data available to farmers
so let's step back for a second and
we talked about an indoor crop schedule
we talked about the importance
of applying long days right to help the
plant
uh bulk in size um in
in the field you don't have the ability
to manipulate
lighting like you do in a greenhouse or
an indoor environment so you have to
strategically
plan your production outdoors so that
you maximize
the environment at the location where
you are
so with this said there are key
environmental factors that you should
think about
when determining when to plant at your
location
and these are your frost date or excuse
me your frost potential
the date at these different frost
potentials
and the day length okay so let's dive
into the map itself
as you can see if you press and drag it
is interactive
okay and all of these different dots
that you see
on the map are specific locations that
have environmental data tied to them
so for the sake of this example let's
look at lansing michigan
so i'd zoom in and you can press and
drag
right and let's click on i believe this
is
lansing so east lansing it gives you
some basic information in this data
table so it shows the latitude longitude
elevation the state
the city name but let's expand it so we
can wrap our heads around
what is the valuable data at this
location
so what you see here on the left it says
date
and then it has a percentage okay the
date right here is may 15th
but what's important to understand is
the percentage here
this is the potential of frost and so
we've given it to you pretty much from
to 10 so at 90 chance of frost in
michigan
the date would be april 12th but then
you would have a 10
chance of frost on may 15th and so it
shows you
kind of the potential of frost because
as we all know the last thing you want
to do is plant too early
especially clones and the frost come
through and
kill all of your plants and so then if
we scroll down
we understand the date that correlates
with the
frost potential now let's figure out the
day length
so you come down to 10 chance of frost
which we had up here
and we see dl this is day length
and so um on may 15th
we have 10 chance of frost and also on
may 15th
we have um a day length of 14 hours
and then 65 out of a hundred
regarding minutes and so let me dive in
a little bit deeper
to explain to you how you should look at
this
specific data point so that we we
totally grasp what it's saying about
photo period and the date length
so let me highlight this so that we're
all on the same page
um so on may 15th we have a 10
chance of frost but our day length as
notated here on the hemp mine
planting map is 14 hours 0.65
okay what does this mean it means that
we have
14 hours plus 65 of an additional hour
for how we had to format this we
couldn't make the 0.65 be minutes we had
to make it be a percentage of an
additional hour
so let's just break this down really
simply so it's not confusing
since it is a percentage let's turn this
into a pie chart
and in this case we could think of a
clock as a pie chart right because in a
clock
60 minutes equals 100 percent
and so what is 65
of a full hour 39 minutes
so there we go that tells us that this
photo period
is 14 hours and 39 minutes because 39
minutes
is 65 of one hour
okay so now that we understand this
let's look at two practical examples the
first one being
in lansing michigan like i showed before
and the second one being
in alexandria louisiana
all right so same location you can see
here in the clip
at the bottom right that i i chose the
exact same
data box that we were just looking at
when looking at the interactive hemp
planting map
i've put it into a format so that we can
run through this example pretty pretty
quickly
so what i have here up on the left is it
shows frost potential
the day length the year week as some
growers use that
and then also just the day the day of
the year okay
in this scenario if we were working with
a farmer in lansing michigan
and that farmer wanted to plant southern
cat daddy for outdoor
field smokable flower production we
would go about
recommending when he plant based on
this exact example right here southern
cat daddy has a flowering response time
of 14 hours right so that means that
any day length longer than 14 hours will
ensure that it stays vegetative
and any day length shorter than 14 hours
will trigger it into flower initiation
okay so we want to plant we want to make
sure that we plant when the day length
is longer than 14 hours
so that it can focus on vegetative
growth and continue that growth
throughout the majority of the season
and get bigger and bigger and bigger
so over here i show frost potential
and i started on april 29th
april 29th we have a photo period of 14
hours this is right at the line
right so i would not recommend planting
it 14 hours as that
is this cultivar's flowering response
time
exactly it would go into flower if
planted april 29th
also you have a 60 chance of frost
with the risk and investment that you're
taking up front anyway with this crop do
you also want to risk frost
i don't think so so we would not
recommend planting in michigan
in lansing southern cat daddy on april
29th
we then would say okay what's our next
best option we go a week later we have
may 6th photo period has increased
19 minutes so we could actually plant
southern cat daddy because now the day
length is longer
than 14 hours and it would stay
vegetative however
we have a 14 excuse me 40 percent chance
of frost
i again would say hey no we're not
risking it yet
what's our next option and so then you
see here we have twenty percent chance
uh may 13th 14 hours and 47 minutes
definitely long enough to plant but for
the sake of this example
i would recommend okay at 10 percent
chance of frost
let's get these plants in the ground
your day length is definitely long
enough
this is at the end of may let's not
waste any more time
time to get the plants in the ground
then
once plants are planted they're growing
they're establishing they're focusing on
vegetative growth
you have a natural distribution of
day length throughout the year right so
in the in the spring it
it slowly gets longer and then as you
hit the solstice
it peaks and then the day lengths get
shorter as you go into fall
and so if we follow that throughout the
season the plant stays vegetative
and initiates flowering when daylinks
come back down to 14 hours
and so on august 12th southern cat daddy
would initiate
flowering in lansing michigan because
we've hit 14 hours
so in lansing michigan this is when i
would recommend to this farmer with this
cultivar
when to plant because this would allow
them to have 11 weeks of vegetative grow
time
this would allow the plants to to really
fill out in size
and it truly should dictate the amount
of plants they plant per
acre based on the amount of vegetative
growth time that they do have
so now let's look at the exact same
cultivar
in louisiana a much more southern
latitude
in the city of alexandria louisiana so
we would look at the
the data from the map right here just
showed another shows another screenshot
of it
thankfully we don't have to worry too
much about frost but the day lengths
are much shorter than they are in
michigan at the same dates
so again i reference the same week week
17 the same
date april 29th we have 10 chance of
frost not a big concern however our day
length is really short at 13 hours and
21 minutes
definitely do not want to plant southern
cat daddy would prematurely go into
flower
so we would recommend that they actually
plant june 3rd
because your day length is right over 14
hours
and we would hope that this would ensure
that it stays vegetative if not planting
a little later
however their natural distribution of
long days peaks
and falls much sooner than what we saw
in michigan
and their plant southern cat daddy would
go into flower initiation on july
first and so in louisiana with the exact
same cultivar
you would have only three weeks of
vegetative growth this plant would be
much
smaller than the plants in michigan
however keep in mind
they're the same cost and most likely
other breeding companies are
recommending that you plant them at the
same crop density as well
that's not how we should do this
so what the hemp mine would do is
knowing all of this data going into it
also knowing the objective of your
production
and what final product you want to offer
to the market and when
we would allow you to
understand this like we do through this
kind of example but
offer a solution that would match
a similar grow time in louisiana to the
farmer in michigan and how do we do that
we do that through offering
a different cultivar that has a shorter
flowering response time
so in michigan this is the example of
southern cat daddy 11 weeks
pretty much of vegetative growth time
in louisiana only three so what we would
do is we would recommend a cultivar
named southern
sunset to lower latitude states and in
alexandria louisiana
it would allow this farmer
to have this vegetative crop schedule
instead of the three-week southern cat
daddy vegetative crop schedule
and that's because southern sunset has a
response time of 13 hours
and 20 minutes not 14 hours
so now the grower in louisiana can be
competitive in plant size and yield per
acre when planting the same crop density
as the farmer in michigan this data
dictates when to plant crop density per
acre ultimately
what genetics you should choose and when
ultimately to
start testing because this is when the
plants will
go into flower initiation
and so from here is when you should
count down
pretty much to harvest and when you
should start taking your first
cannabinoid
tests on week one two or three after
flower initiation
so this chart just shows you
the response time of each of our
cultivars we will expand on this we're
coming out with
a new catalog for 2021 um
and we will elaborate on on this more
with
actually having more cultivars as well
we
work very closely with a lab parture lab
partner excuse me kacho labs and with
them
we are able to offer our customers
discounts on cannabinoid tests because
we do recommend that you take
quite a few throughout the flower
development
production stage of your crop cycle
but ultimately what we would do for each
of our customers
is create a schedule like this for you
after we're on the same page with what
genetics you want to use for what
purpose
and at which location we create a crop
schedule for you helping you understand
okay when you need to plant
when these plants will go into flower
initiation and when you should start
testing
and give you all of the proper
information for how to test how to
sample
where to send your samples all of that
okay so this concludes part one
of photoperiodism
part 2 will be coming soon we will
release this before the
end of 2020 so stay tuned
for dr justice as we will dive a little
deeper into
the flowering physiology of cannabis
during our 2020 field trials we have
noticed some very interesting responses
which are leading us to expand
our short day plant understanding even
further