[Music]
dr. Wong I wanted to say it was a
pleasure you know hearing your talk
today it was very informative
I'm Paul Santos and I worked for a
private diagnostic lab called Waypoint
analytical and we're located in Anaheim
California it was very interesting to
hear you list a lot of the diseases that
you were talking about because we've
been offering this service for quite
some time - ever since cannabis became
legal in California and we were seeing
many of the diseases that you were
speaking about in your presentation so
it was kind of nice to kind of get that
confirmation that both of us as
pathologists were seeing the same issues
that are facing many of the growers of
this crop so some of the issues that we
see most often were repeated in your
presentation you know things like
Fusarium causing both no crown rot root
rot stem rot Pythium root rot we're not
dealing so much with the hemp production
side of the industry most of ours is
medicinal or recreational so we don't
get to see a lot of the field grown
things that you were mentioning you know
with the seed related issues most of the
clients that we service they're
obtaining their plant material from from
propagation houses or they're doing
their own clonal cuttings and rooting
their own material so we do see a lot of
that Fusarium that you were talking
about that can get transmitted you know
from infected mothers stalks so I
thought that was very important issue
that you brought up yeah and that's true
so I work for a state of Nevada
Department of Agriculture so as a parent
pathologist I deal with everything not
just industrial hemp and also marijuana
plants so for some reason during those
two years yes there's there's a lot of
problem with Association d'être hemp and
their cannabis production in the nevada
so we have a chance to locate those
issue would take a lot of sample we
accept sample so with two analysis with
to recognize thick and
also to the DNA barcoding to identify
what kind of past you in there so we can
figure out what's wrong with all those
issues so we would you fund a lot of
diseases which that's why I'm excited to
present in the in the Congress yeah I
agree totally with you because I think
you know one of the one of the one of
the benefits of legalization of
marijuana or the greater extent of
growing hemp as a as an industrial crop
is that now we're being able to open
that industry up to the much-needed
science because there's a there's a big
gap in our in our in the knowledge that
we have with respect to the diseases
that impact both marijuana and the hamp
crops so it's kind of exciting we kind
of feel like maybe we're on the cutting
edge right at the frontier trying to
find new things and discovering new
things that impact this crop and the
growers are trying to yeah I feel the
same way because every time we're
located Academy so he's a industrial
hemp or medical marijuana plants
there's nobody have done very much work
on that so anything funding from that
time across it could be no disease or
some kind of new conditions so the
growers need the information to to
resolve the problem so but unfortunately
not very many people will work on that
a lot of people contact saying they have
research facility they have a technique
advantage but they just don't want to
work on that for example I got talking
about virus there's something infected
by some kind of virus but we cannot
figure out what it is so they need some
kind of research to figure out so future
people welcome yeah I know I it makes me
wish that maybe I was more of a
virologist and not so much of a
mycologist
you know I don't know what your
expertise words are what you specialize
in when you were in graduate school but
I do see like a lot of a lot of clients
ask questions about viruses and I
honestly talk to Tonga you know aside
from hearing maybe you know him prosaic
I don't know much else alright yeah but
by training myself it's a new
mythologist also plant pathologists and
also molecular biologists so actually a
conservative nurse but is in there for
an apprentice knowledge as
I was taught more focus on the soil
fungus or numb toes and the virus or
some apprentices so you mentioned
nematodes room I did have one question
that I get it didn't get to ask you
during your presentation and maybe I
don't know if I heard right or not but
was it the the it's mostly the lesion
nematode is the one of primary problem
on him or we're not real sure yet the
reason I point out Tunisian themselves
which is called the Prater lenka's is
because we found this from the from the
potato field from from some fields
because I talked about tonight
root rot the reason why root was so
devastating is just because could it be
some kind of them thoughts take some
roll and to make Anna plants more
susceptible
so that's why I addressed it numb totes
you know in the disease complex I'll be
very interesting to be interesting to
see what you find out yeah but we walk
on there so oh yeah I think there's one
grower from New Mexico he asked about it
did you find that very senior very
senior wilt since we found for Sarah
will some other diseases but he's got
some kind of problem with releasing him
which is a big issue for some crop like
permanent is a huge right problem but so
far I haven't found any from the
cannabis here right so I still pay
attention to it because every time the
sample came in they kind of royalty or
some kind of disease go yeah
I always check for vertice to make sure
there's anything yeah sure sure yeah I'd
have to say in the samples that we've
received we've never seen vertice them
either but you know it's something
that's always on your radar for sure
yeah yeah that's that's that's good too
yeah don't have any vertice no no no no
nobody wants it nobody wish if there is
one disease though that that I didn't
see mentioned on your on your survey
that you've been conducting and one that
we begin we've been seeing of late and
that's a sale a biopsis
causing our
root rot but also invading the crown at
the bottom of the plant - I don't know
maybe if you've come across that or not
no no I haven't if across today yes that
would be very curious to know what
species it is because it's difficult and
it's much slower growing than Halima ops
is particular maybe that's something if
we had an isolate that if we sent it to
you would you be interested in maybe
determining what species it is
well we're conducting a bar coding so
figure out what it is so if you got
chance you can send me some image you
describe what kind of disease look like
yeah and then send me some sample or
maybe nice relates yeah oh yeah culture
plates we can figure out what species it
is yeah that'd be really cool yeah right
and then I don't have time to write
stuff up and I don't have a facility for
doing inoculations for Koch's postulates
maybe that's something on urine and you
could get a publication out of it well
yeah what kind of cooperates so it'll
kind of figure out what's wrong with
there was a crowd yeah
it's not very much information on the
canvass crop diseases so there's a lot
of grower in the u.s. they're gonna grow
a lot of hemp and the course of medical
marijuana plants in the facility they
need information on how to manage those
diseases so they don't have those
information and they don't know how to
manage it so let's be the issue and
people can do some work to figure out
what's wrong with it that's great like
couldn't helping them to produce how C
can be scrub well I would ask you one
question you know because both you and I
we kind of agree that you know we do
cannabis but it's kind of on the side
yeah Messiah is true there are a lot of
other plants and crops that we both deal
with right but you know what do you
think is maybe one of the most
challenging things the the faces the
cannabis industry with wrist art talking
about management of diseases what do you
think would be the most challenging
thing to growers I think the most
challenge is how the grower can get
healthy plants because I talked to one
of attending she said is any program
that really can provide healthy stalk
healthy plants and they can start from
the very beginning that principle they
have is healthy a healthy so let's be
challenged so I said no nobody really
really to this kind of scene so maybe in
the future there's a direction to do
that
our teacher coach on the generate
disease of free stock plans or gym
plasma whatever they call it
so you just get our work mean disease
free clean stock to start with cannabis
growing business right so that's
probably the best way let's call the
prevention so and once on the challenge
is that there's no chemical product like
pesticide or fungicide nylon label for
cannabis so they cannot use it for
cannabis crop so they have to use some
alternative product and they may not be
very effective depends on what kind of
condition the treat so that's allows a
challenge for them to you and so they're
almost forced to be organic growers by
default right technology it is no it's
gonna that's not so bad it's not that
it's impossible but it's it's much more
challenging yeah right yes challenge
well in order to do virus testing you
need to have specialized equipment there
are some Eliza based kits that are on
available on the market
but the biggest problem is that we don't
have a firm understanding of what
viruses have been described on cannabis
in the first place right would you agree
yeah that's true so even though we can
test the virus but we don't know what
kind of arts to test for so you have to
know what species you want to test for
that specific virus so a lot of time we
just don't know what to test for so
that's that's kind of people challenge
so when there's a way to do that they
call the next generation sequences so
that way you can you don't need to know
the target but you can detect whatever
it's inside the plants based on the
wrong way so you can test this specific
of a virus or even a novel new virus in
the plants so that's technology in there
but it just kind of cost too much money
time to do that so we don't know what
type of virus I have felt the cannabis
crop and it's still question mark
I would say that the diseases are
regional I mean there are some
commonalities but for example you know
in California and I would imagine you
here in Nevada that's probably the same
where it tends to be more arid you know
we're gonna see one subset of diseases
are gonna be more common to our area
whereas if you're a grower or say like
in Kentucky maybe there may be foliar
diseases that we were never gonna see
just because we don't have the rainfall
that's right that's right because in a
given region now see in the Midwest or
in the back of yeast they may be good
high humidity nikka some other diseases
which we don't see very much in the
Western like especially in Nevada is
pretty dry arid condition so may not see
very often like say powdery mildew you
may see very much in some other part of
the United States but not in Nevada
prominent so that's not something that's
environmental environment dependent
well as I present in the this morning I
said the prevention is a key so try to
prevent introduction any type of disease
agent into your facility so that's best
way to prevent disease and also try to
monitor your facility make sure you keep
track on that once you see the disease
you have to take action right away as
soon as possible before they spread or
overwhelming in the facility so that's
my takeaway message for those growers I
think that's an excellent point you know
that prevention through good sanitation
that has to be the foundation of any
program especially in in cannabis well
your options for control once disease
outbreak has occurred are so limited i I
agree told you know wholeheartedly with
that yeah
well me personally when I think back to
to my my days as a graduate student you
know I think that the number one risk of
growing something that's a monoculture
and is you know genetically uniform like
when you're using clonal stock the the
problem is that if you do get a path
into this introduction then and they're
all susceptible then the risk for for a
spread and for a greater loss in yield
is is significantly higher than if you
had a diverse cropping system although
I'm not sure I would argue that that
that crops that are planted outdoors are
any less of a monoculture than those
planet indoors even though there may be
other things around that environment
where these where these cannabis crops
are being grown outdoors I mean they
could potentially be sources of pathogen
inoculum we just don't simply know yet
well for sure them monoculture is really
make the disease to occur more easily
than the multiple species so the
academy's production indoor and it's
actually really favorable for some type
of diseases for sure so it's it's it's a
really big issue for monoculture it's
bad for disease
[Music]