[Music]
an associate professor at McGill
University I specialized in controlled
environment agriculture I have a bunch
of pretty pictures on the side there so
basically anything to do with controlled
environment from a greenhouse all the
way to NASA based stuff I've done work
on I like showing my farm that I grew up
on because I come from a flat land area
right there
so it's rural agriculture in Western
Canada if anybody's into ice hockey then
that's what we play there predominantly
and it it drives everything background
for solar energy most people have
probably seen this predominantly we have
the solar output of the Sun which is the
big tall red line that we see on top
here and then we have a little bit of UV
light that's being produced if we go to
the other side we have our far red and
our infrared that's all being kicked out
on this side the atmosphere has a habit
of breaking up or absorbing some of
these wavelengths and so you can see the
actual spectrum that are being absorbed
along this the part that I always find
interesting when I look at this slide is
that the human eye and plants both
evolved to absorb and utilize the
primary wavelengths of light that are
coming out of the Sun so it's the vast
majority of the light that's actually
coming to us and it's where majority of
that light energy is being produced from
that and it's within the same spectrum
so human eye and plants are fairly
similar and they evolved independently
as far as we know and so from this
perspective we have to be aware that
there is differences from this this way
but it is also something there is
similarities so we can tie through those
things over the history of humanity we
found different ways to actually produce
light solar beam the background that
everybody's aware of and then we also
have come up with different systems
ultimately as you look at this you can
see that none of these actual mirror
that solar light spectrum that's up top
but we also have our cool like
fluorescents which are a lot more peaky
so a little individual Peaks here and
they're more in the blue wavelengths a
little bit through the green area and
then our high-pressure sodium which is
the industry standard for most people
predominantly in the I call it amber but
between the orange and the yellow
spectrum of light incandescent which is
one of our first lighting fixtures that
we have metal halides and then our
LEDs I'm one of these guys that actually
thinks low pressure sodium should
actually come back at some point I see
some fun stuff on this and we are doing
some research on this people ignored it
NASA did one research project and said
it could be useful and then everybody's
ignored it ever since but I actually
think it has applications and at some
point I'll start ranting in great length
about why I believe that but the coolest
thing that's happened in the last while
is LEDs have come on to the field and
the part that's fun is that they're very
nectar narrow-spectrum they produce a
lot of a lot of light and they're one of
the more efficient systems that are out
there and you can see that the fairly
narrow spectrum out of this up until
this point most of them were 50 to 100
nanometer type width and in these cases
they're sitting down in that twenty nine
a meter width so fairly narrow light
spectrum and so we can actually start
tailoring different colors specifically
for growing plants one of the challenges
that we're playing with and I'll talk
about later on is that this is at 20
nanometers can we narrow it down farther
and what's the impact that we can do
could we ever make a one nanometer base
light and actually see what the impact
of that that's why I talked about low
pressure sodium it is a narrower light
source then the LED systems that we have
there so these are the most of the LEDs
that we have on the market you can see
that we go all the way from the UV range
on this side all the way over to the far
red infrared in some cases on this side
and then we have this area in between
one of the parts that I find interesting
is this area where everybody talks about
the green gap personally I think we kind
of ignore it's not as serious of the
effect for plant growth as people think
it is it's purely because we cheat and
we do the PC amber so the phosphorus
coated amber like production and we
still get light across the whole
spectrum the place that I have my
biggest issue is actually right here in
that 680 - 700 I can't seem to find la
le d-- lights that produce efficiently
or actually at all in that space and I
need them to finish off some of my
research so if anybody knows lights in
the 680 to the 700 range I'm more than
willing to chat with you because I need
them the basis of light and
photosynthesis basically is driven by
the principles of pigment absorption so
we have chlorophyll a chlorophyll B and
our carotenoids and so we've actually
tailored around these things these
pigments to actually determine our
photosynthetic efficiency and how do we
can
we set this up but McCree back in the
day so there's plenty of people before
McCree that actually worried about
photosynthesis mercury is the one that's
become the standard if we actually
overlay what happened with the pigments
with this we can see that the
chlorophyll a and B kind of line up
reasonably well between 400 and 500 and
between 600 and 700 is also our
chlorophyll but there's this big gap
between 500 and 600 where there is no
pigment absorption that we believe is
driving photosynthesis but yet we
actually get a fairly good activity I
like playing in that five nine five the
amber light and I will rant about that
quite a bit next yeah in two days from
now it's kind of a final thing since you
are all here human eyes did evolve to
actually measure light our problem is
that we're actually we were really good
at measuring green light so the primary
responses of a green light and we're
poor in the red in the blue spectrum and
so people come to me and say I have
plenty of light within my greenhouse or
in my controlled environment space and
like did you measure it with a sensor
and they're like no I can see it and I'm
like no you didn't you just looked at
green light and you have no real ability
to understand the blue or the far red
and that's where plants do a lot of
photosynthetic activity out of this one
and then ultimately we have our high
pressure sodium space on this space
which is actually has become the
industry standard and so if you overlay
that with that green line which is the
Makri curve that I showed you before as
I'm showing there the high pressure
sodium seems to be hanging out in that
amber wavelength space and it seems to
be the industry standard well it is the
industry standard and it's the place
that I find the most interesting because
ultimately plant pigments don't have a
good absorption capacity within that
space but yet plants grow really really
really well with it and so we have a lot
of questions that we're going to have
understood on this one so more in-depth
understanding of our different
wavelengths photosystem one photosystem
two and our different pigments and the
mercury and how all these things
actually drive this so that's a really
quick overview of the basics of
photosynthesis at least from a light
perspective and wavelengths that we play
with we have to be aware that high
pressure sodium is the industry standard
and so as such everything has to be
compared to that and so I hope that
these guys will all check with it from
that perspective so the first speaker is
actually going to be Dave Holley he's
works for fluence his exact title is the
senior scientist I believe you just got
that a little while
it's been from the beginning okay
because it was added on to your LinkedIn
account I saw so yes I wondered if he
was ever a junior scientist before that
point so and then we have two others
that will be coming up after him which
is Neil dirge it died Gertz was working
on out and so he's at solo too he's
based here in San Diego and so he'll be
talking about some of the systems and as
you walk down the hallway you can
actually see that and then the one that
I worked on is Cindy Rajan hmm let's see
moot moot yeah okay okay and so he's
gonna be talking about the biomimicry of
light and I'm actually really interested
in that I understand the other two
slightly but this is the one that I
looking forward to alright so I'm a
little bit jealous for this talk that my
name isn't Sun because nothing is more
appropriate than that I think so once
again my name is Dave Holly and I am the
senior scientist at fluence
bioengineering and yeah it's been senior
scientists the whole time but then again
haven't we all been junior scientists at
one point in life mark in some ways I
definitely still feel that way so the
intent for me today if you're not first
of all if you're not familiar with
fluence we are a horticultural lighting
company of course and we sell primarily
broad-spectrum light in an LED form
factor we're very present in the
cannabis market worldwide and
increasingly so in commercial
agriculture so if you imagine like fine
crop leafy greens berries things like
that that's where we're putting a lot of
our efforts now especially on the
research side now mark gave a really
efficient talk on light spectrum and
absorption and pigments and things it's
almost as though you've done it once or
twice before mark but I'm going to
expand a little bit more and go just a
little bit slower because I know this is
this is not a myth kind of a wide array
of backgrounds and so it could be
helpful to kind of set the stage for the
rest of the conference so when we're
talking about optimizing light quality
for plant development from an LED stamp
standpoint we're really talking about
three pillars of plant development so
this can be yield and that
drives most of the market whether it's
cannabis or leafy greens or vine crop or
anything else mostly people care about
yield then we're talking about
morphology people want certain canopy
architectures for various reasons and
finally we're talking about plant
quality and in the case of cannabis that
means plant secondary metabolism so
cannabinoids terpenes things like that
and it can mean different things and
different crops like in berries it might
mean sugar content and tomato it might
mean oh I don't know it could mean sugar
content again it could also mean things
like lycopene for a coloration in flavor
so if we dive into these three pillars
right yield morphology and secondary
metabolism we can look at how light
affects each one of these things
starting with yield yield really means
photosynthesis it just means taking co2
from the air and turning it into plant
stuff right and sometimes you get the
good plant stuff that can be leaves if
your lettuce it can be cannabis but if
you're in that industry it can mean
tomato fruit but it just means turning
co2 into plant stuff so how does this
work well there are these three steps
and once again I'll try to do this in
kind of a depth that's appropriate for
this group but we've got the light
reactions and then there's some
chemistry and then there's the dark
reactions that actually captures the co2
so if we dive into these steps first
we're gonna be looking at light
absorption and this is really where we
are playing most of the time ultimately
what you see here is a light harvesting
complex and we have these green dots
that represent chlorophyll we have the
yellow and the red and the orange dots
that represent these secondary pigments
so like Mark said chlorophyll really
good at absorbing light between the sort
of 4 to 500 nanometer region and the 6
to 700 nanometer region or in other
words red and blue light that's how we
all understand it and then there's this
big gap kind of between five and six
hundred and we're all kind of guessing
with our best understanding of how all
of this works but as we understand it
right now we do have these secondary
pigments like alpha carotene beta
carotene lycopene these all fall in this
category of carotenoids and there are
some other related ones called
xanthophylls but we think that these
compounds fill in that gap a little bit
and essentially they're going to absorb
light in that region pass it over to
chlorophyll a bunch of things happen
water gets split
hydrogen gets liberated and it powers a
bunch of full chemical kind of machinery
and plants grow mm-hmm and of course if
you look at this last graph here this is
actually what light absorption looks
like in a whole leaf right so the first
two graphs are showing light absorption
if you just isolate these compounds in
solution and then shine some light on it
and see what happens if you actually
look at a whole leaf though you get
something that looks a little bit like
this last graph and rather than kind of
doing a deep dive through each one of
these little points out is that the
yellow line which is kind of the one
that dips down the most it's
representing your isolated sort of
photosynthetic pigments your green line
is showing what a whole leaf whole
intact leave is actually absorbing what
you see is that again like Mark said the
plant does absorb light more or less
across the spectrum it does dip down a
little bit and that's why it looks green
but the plant is capturing full-spectrum
light this is the part where I say a
little bit of chemistry happens all of
that stuff that we just looked at in the
previous cartoon is that first ps2
molecule does this have a laser pointer
on it very good so right here this guy
were talking about ps2 and again there's
a lot of other stuff happening here but
essentially all of those compounds we
just talked about exist in here it
captures that light it splits water it
liberates this hydrogen molecule and
this hydrogen proton powers this protein
that makes ATP right so really what
we're doing here is we're tuning light
energy into biochemical energy and
ultimately what we end up with is NADPH
and ATP and these are very energetic
biochemical molecules it goes on to do
other stuff so this is where we get into
the dark reactions of photosynthesis
once again probably review for a lot of
you but this is where we take that co2
from the air and turn it into the plant
stuff so we have co2 from the air and
then we have these energetic molecules
that I just talked about and ultimately
they reduce co2 to make glucose or sugar
and this sugar goes on to do a whole
bunch of other biochemical processes but
this is really your primary metabolism
and actually from this point forward a
lot of what happens is really similar to
what happens in animal cells
you have mitochondria you have cellular
respiration and so on so that is
ultimately the first pillar of how we
optimize light for plant production
right focusing on yields turning co2
into plant stuff
the next pillar I'll move through these
very quickly because I'm sure again
we're going to talk about it a lot these
two today but essentially when we talk
about plant morphology we were really
talking about utilizing different
wavelengths of light to get a canopy
architecture that might be appealing for
a whole bunch of different reasons and
in very broad strokes short wavelengths
generally means short plants the shorter
the wavelength you get kind of a more
compact plant usually thicker leaves
often a little bit more robust and as
you move across the spectrum towards
longer wavelengths you get a longer
plant you get a cell expansion and you
get intranet expansion and so on so UVA
and blue you get really similar things
you get increased pigmentation it's kind
of like the plant getting a suntan just
like if we go outside and we hang out in
a bunch UV light we get a 10 the plants
doing the same thing its defending
itself from high-energy photons green a
little bit less morphologically
impactful but a lot of people are saying
now that you can induce a lot of the
same sort of physiological responses
with green light as you would get a far
red light so again it's sort of telling
the plant that it's in the shade and it
should stretch out and try to get into
more intense light red really good at
driving photosynthesis but again cell
expansion generally increased leaf area
but maybe a less robust plant overall
than if you had a higher kind of blue
content not saying Reds bad by any means
I'm just saying it's a little bit
different and far-red is kind of the
really extreme example of that one when
a plant is in pharr red light it thinks
it's in the shade and it wants to
stretch out and get out of that shade
and get into some brighter sunlight just
so it has more photons available to
drive yield last but not least we're
talking about plant quality and I'm
going to use this biochemical pathway is
a really good example of this because
it's very relevant to the cannabis space
and indoor agriculture in general right
so when we're talking about plant
quality we are talking about secondary
metabolism and I just want to point out
a couple of things right now so this
pathway that you're looking at or is
representing a few things it's
representing the biosynthesis of
carotenoids and that's what you see in
the the pinkish color towards the bottom
right
alpha carotene and beta-carotene and you
remember I mentioned these a little bit
earlier as the compounds that kind of
fill in some of that gap in the middle
for yield production what we have
represented near the top here are
cannabinoids and a lot of this audience
probably knows what those are they are
exclusive to cannabis they do
interesting things to your brain what we
have along here are all of the terpenes
that people think are probably relevant
to the cannabis space and also interact
with cannabinoids to induce different
sort of recreational attributes and also
medicinal attributes and what we can
find is that all of these things share
common precursors isopentenyl
pyrophosphate or IPP and dimethylallyl
pyrophosphate or addi map now what you
can take about takeaway from this is
that given they have all common
precursors maybe if you create a light
environment rich in some mid-range light
and the plant has to be able to absorb
it so it produces more electrifying more
alpha carotene more beta-carotene maybe
the way it handles that is by up
regulating these precursors and maybe if
you have more of these you can produce
more carotenoids I'm sorry maybe you can
produce more cannabinoids and maybe you
can produce more terpenes so this is
just one example where we take what we
understand about light and we manipulate
that light environment to achieve and a
sort of targeted results in our
production all right so with two minutes
remaining
I just have one more slide on here and
it's just a picture of a few of the
products as I say I understand probably
a lot of people here are of some
familiarity with fluence but if you
don't it is an LED company we have lots
of different form factors to satisfy a
few different markets but very briefly
what you see here kind of front and
center is something we call spider 2p
and this is most often what gets SPECT
into indoor cannabis facilities it's
designed to have very good uniformity
placed really close to the canopy it's
great because again you can play this
over tables it also works really well in
like a tiered sort of multi-level system
not exclusive to cannabis but that is
where we see it most a similar product
but a little bit different is in the top
left here we call this raiser and this
is intended for leafy greens kind of
vertical farms and you can mount this
again on kind of a racking system we
have a
version of this that mounts on the end
on a rack it's sort of canceled leader
of cantilever it off a wall and you can
have trolleys of plants kind of move in
and out of them and a few other things
this here we call Viper and in the sort
of commercial agriculture space we spec
this into greenhouses it's kind of like
our HP s replacement where it's just
this super bright thing that just blasts
out a whole lot of photons but again for
certain indoor applications depending on
how your facility's laid out that gets
SPECT in some times and this is just
called ray it's a single bar of LEDs
honestly this is mostly used for
research but there are some niche
applications where you can use this as
well you can have quite a few different
spectra of Ray's so you use it either as
a sole source solution or if you had a
broad spectrum and you want to
supplement some additional far-red or
some UV or something like that
Ray's usually what you would use so
without being too long-winded I think
I'll just pass it on and do you do the
next introduction no can speak for
himself all right thank you dr. Holliday
that was amazing thank you I've learned
a lot all right so good morning
everybody I'm Neel Tygart I'm vice
president of solty of international and
there we go hmm why especially is
actually light and the circadian
response to the ever-changing spectrum
of light especially is human vision
neuro chemistry and psychology of
perception but obviously plants follow
or use the same spectrum as dr. Lessard
already pointed out we use a or our our
daytime vision is uniquely tuned to the
the green portion of the the visible
spectrum but what he didn't state is
that we actually have some intrinsically
photo responsive ganglion cells that
actually drive our circadian rhythm that
actually almost directly match the blue
spectrum that drives photosynthesis and
that's what keeps us entrained in the
24-hour clock so we'll talk about that a
little bit I am here to talk about
daylight
so obviously daylight is the reference
light source that we use to compare all
electric lighting today and what we're
gonna see is that when we properly
capture daylight it up obviously
directly matches the Makri response
curve or desired action spectra that we
want for photosynthesis so traditionally
when we think about lighting there we're
gonna have three different ways of
emitting light to a building perimeter
glass so printer glass is great allows
us to have used the outside but
typically it's associated with heat
shifting patterns of light and just a
very dynamic environment not necessarily
something that we want for today's
growth environments we can have top
lighting as we would associate with a
skylight or the rooftop glazing of a
greenhouse again really good if we're
fully glazing a building but we do have
shifting patterns of light we have heat
we have leakage we have all sorts of
issues that could become problematic in
the growth arena what we're talking
about today or what I'm introducing you
to is a notion of optics so optical day
lighting so for the first time now we
have a product that is uniquely designed
to only admit the wavelengths that we
need for vision and photosynthesis it
actually extracts heat and UV that we
don't want in the buildings that would
be problematic we can also use very
small apertures to selectively harvest
light by angle so we can actually tune
it to admit light or to broaden the
number of hours per day that we have
useful illumination we can also capture
incredible amounts of daylight in a very
small aperture and drive it down into a
building and focus it optically where we
want it such as the plant canopy we can
do this without any heat so again really
beneficial in a growth environment so
just very quickly when we talk about
an advanced optical system we have the
capture zone which allows us to
selectively harvest the light and the
wavelengths of energy that we want
extracting the end of the wavelengths
that we do not
what in the system we have the optical
light guide that allows us to now duct
the light so whether it is a very short
distance or a very long convoluted
pathway we have wonderful new
technologies that literally allow us to
transport the light with virtually no
light loss and then ultimately we can
diffuse the light just like we would
with lighting equipment so we can
provide focused lighting to highlight an
object in a room that we that we want to
call visual attention to or in the case
of indoor agriculture we can now focus
it on the plant canopy itself we also
can provide full range dimming so we can
fully modulate daylight as well so
obviously for those of you familiar with
sola tube you know of us as a product
for lighting interior spaces that's what
we do we have done it for a very long
time and we've invented a lot of
technologies allow us to do this all
these spaces you see are 100% Dale it
even this this is actually one of the
very first Dale it Olympic venues this
is the martial arts venue in the Beijing
Olympics ever since then every every
Olympic building has had sold tube
products or optical day lighting systems
in the venue's here we're focusing the
light 60 feet to the competition floor
so production facilities again nothing
new to new for us
and then also we have been working in
the indoor agricultural field for quite
some time this project is about 10-12
years old this is actually an algae
growth facility and so these bioreactors
are daylit so the optical day lighting
system as you can see is pumping into
the top of the bio reactors to allow the
the algae to propagate okay so today I
won't really want to talk about some
pivotal research that has been ongoing
for the last few years so I want to
reference a foundational study done by
dr. cachet of CCV research and flourish
farms and really focus on what he has
learned relative to the application of
optical day lighting to an indoor growth
facility so in this study what we're
gonna look at is a fully optimized
system where daylight is the dominant
light source and then it's supported by
LED lighting on the shoulder hours of
the day where we might want to provide a
little bump up in daytime illumination
or actually the ppfd
levels on the plant canopy here's an
example of some of the growth chambers
that he was experimenting on these are
10 by 12 sheds they lit with four
optical systems each of these optical
systems can produce around 55,000 lumens
during the day this is the inside of the
growth chamber and what was kind of
interesting is that what he discovered
anecdotally is that the daylight
actually provides a different quality of
illumination in the space it actually
provides volumetric lighting so rather
than is laying the top of the canopy of
the the plants themselves it actually
fills the space with light so we
actually extend the growth the depth of
the growth area in the usable area from
an energy standpoint relative to you the
typical HBS system now if we look at the
daily energy consumption when we apply
the daylight what you see in the lower
green
barso we're looking at the course of the
day in the use of electric lights in
response to you or to provide makeup
ppfd
levels inside the growth chamber itself
we see that we're able to fully displace
the need for the electric light for a
significant portion of the day on
average between five to eight hours per
day in doing so we're able to
significantly reduce the annual energy
cost both for lighting as well as for
heat removal in the growth chamber so we
can keep the plants at optimal
temperatures and we can also provide the
desired spectral content that we want
for the plants to grow so we can reduce
the energy consumption by 1/5 or more or
more to dissociate we have a traditional
indoor agricultural environment so
looking at the spectral content of
daylight that back farthest most
spectral region is going to be for
daytime noontime illumination a DL 5500
sources we would call it and we see that
as a full spectrum light source we also
see that it peaks in the blue
wavelengths which is what we want for
photosynthesis the light sources in
front of that are gonna be the more
traditional electric light sources that
we would see in the standard illuminated
space and again we see that the shapes
are very different so daylight really is
the reference source that we need to
consider this chart the lower left hand
corner represents the Makri curve so the
the Photosynth photosynthesis or
photosynthetically active radiation
spectral response curve that we want
between 400 and 700 nanometers and then
the central curve in the center reflects
what we were able to achieve with the
optically filtered daylight through
optical systems and we see this
beautifully biased curve that is perfect
for photosynthesis so what does it look
like when we're actually growing plants
so again we concede that when we provide
this day light we can do so again five
to eight hours a day without the need
for any makeup electric light and we can
also see that we have very
our deep penetration of the growth
canopy itself while the plants are
growing in working towards maturation we
can see some early stages in the
flowering process and in the end you can
see the end result
now what was very interesting is there
is some discussion on whether we need UV
for growing plants now so tubes or I
should say optical day lighting is
unique and that we can actually start to
filter out the the UV that we don't want
and what was very interesting from these
studies as anecdotal information dr.
cachet was able to to discover or
discovered that without the UV we don't
have the browning effect of the flowers
so as a result of the flowers literally
have a longer shelf life here's an
example in a hemp facility so we're
going from a small-scale kind of
proof-of-concept
application to some large agricultural
applications so here we have cultivation
facility in Arkansas and you can see a
range of optical systems being applied
to the roof and what's really
interesting is that in the case of the
hemp growth facility where you're you're
growing seedlings and then preparing
them for planting you have a hardening
process that you normally have to go
through with electric growth chambers
that doesn't or is not required when we
use daylight's so the plants emerge
fully pre hardened ready for planting
okay so very quickly just again some
examples of the hemp cultivation
facility of these pre hardened plants
and a nice comparison side-by-side of
daylight date/time daylight illumination
to nighttime LED illumination and that's
optical day lighting we'll talk more
about it later
okay thank you
[Applause]
my name is Cindy Rajan mutia Lu so I'm
gonna talk a little bit about sunlight
and biomimicry aligning with aligning
with nature so I think to do this
it isn't just lighting we need a very
symbiotic relationship going inside
especially indoors so you have to
understand why are you growing this well
what's the reason for it you want full
nutrition nutrient value you want
cannabis that has all of the compounds
so you can actually heal and not be
extractive in the sense of just going
high THC as an example and not bringing
out all those beautiful compounds so
you've got to grow like Mother Nature
you have to preserve and really grow the
genetics and get genetic diversity
rather than putting genetics down
because in the way of cannabis pretty
much all started with Afghan many years
ago and people kept going down to the
point where we're down to a significant
amount of chemo VARs that are the same
so achieve full genetic expression from
optin nutrient grow junk you know
generality and beyond organic and then
produce really freshly and delicious
food cuz Sun is the energy you know it's
the the main source of the whole world
and a definition of science is seeing
how nature does it and emulate that
through biomimicry so we know plants can
heal and so the questions I'm interested
in are a little bit different than just
designing of light and this one here is
very controversial in the sense that we
believe from coming from a wellness and
sustainability come that if you're
growing with artificial lights you're
bottle feeding you're an asterick 'el
you know very sterile medium with and
then finishing off with things like
pesticides you get really a lot of
limited genetic expression because
you're tightening that plant down into a
very narrow place rather than mother
nature going back then obvious
nature yep sunlight true living soil
very hard to do indoors completely
organic healthy plant immune system has
to set and full genetic expression and
to get the entourage effect and
especially for things like well not
things like but cannabis so we're a
company that's really tech agnostic and
so nature is their reference point for
us so you have to have a biotic and
abiotic conditions to really have an
optimum and grow of plants to get
maximum expression and bioavailability
so from the plants point of view is what
you need to look at when you're growing
indoors not from the growers point of
view not from the soil guys point of
view but for what the plant once so you
have to do a very symbiotic kind of
system of looking at water transpiration
VPD the living soil so you can have
microbes that help and not flip the
whole room with co2 which by the way
thickens leaves and closes stomata often
so you want to look at it from the
plants point of view and I'm going to
talk a little bit different than the
gentleman have so far I want to talk
about outside of par and par it's really
only 43 percent of the sunlight we have
a lot of plans to grow outdoors that
gets everything so when we start
limiting it you know you limit the par
it's really artificial lighting in that
power range because that's what really
the systems can produce so you you
basically do that
more and more we're getting away from
that and getting more full-spectrum
light so when you have no ultraviolet
and no infrared you know it lacks the
uniformity and density of sunlight
frequencies and it really limits genetic
expression as well as diversity
for instance rather than talking about
McCree I'm going to talk about the
combinations of different light UV and
blue which you have to have UV to be
able to get a good immune system and you
want to get some secondary metabolites
as we were just talking about a little
while ago are extremely important as
well for the plant and infrared
circadian rhythms this like you just
mentioned a moment ago it's very
important for the plant how fast they go
to sleep they're growing when it's dark
most of the growing is when it's dark
it's just getting energy during the day
so I'm going to spend a little time here
the little two little dots at the bottom
there this is where all the lighting
technology currently is it's within
typically the par range there are some
that go out when you look at UVA I mean
when you look at the Sun which is the
yellow here our technology emulates that
a hundred percent the other is when you
look at HPS you see this range is
actually just here and also mostly LEDs
are in that same and it's very
normalized frequency which means you're
normalizing those dots to be able to get
the curve to match rather than then in
the way our technology every quarter
wave everything is present it's not just
trying to mix it or putting a filter in
front of it to be able to get the waves
wavelengths so what does that look like
in the Grove here's a five hundred
square foot grow with HPS you can see
all the air-conditioning systems
necessary and it really relies on doing
some things to your plant you really
don't want to do but you got to get it
to grow at forty things so here's so
that is twenty
four thousand watts twenty four lights
air conditioning to be able to cool that
room down we replace that lips with one
light that's eleven hundred watt light
now would we do one in this girl no we'd
probably do five so that we have uniform
you UV but that's a significant not only
savings and you can see the difference
here if you look at the the shadows even
compared to what you see here very clean
very Chris what does that mean even the
tie down here you can see it's just a
sheer number of photons coming out very
dense very uniform just like sunlight
and the reason it's just like sunlight
we actually developed this for sunlight
there's a lot of numbers here but
basically we just did an economic study
on a fourteen hundred square foot
facility and not only do you have a
savings in energy you get full plant
expression I'm gonna pass that one but
here's a grow of 2,100 square feet in
Oakland that's 66 HPS lights in here
sixty six thousand watts we replaced
that with 20 and the there was a leading
LED company that bid for this let's put
a hundred and ten LEDs in here so I can
imagine the amount of power so what are
those plants look like I have to say
that I am from the cannabis world have
been starting to grow in Berkeley when I
was 12 in 13 and it's definitely
cannabis and not marijuana to me so I
don't mind talking about it at any
conference so this is one some of the
things you can start doing is doing land
races when you can do completely living
soil
and full sunlight and you do lots of
different combination headband here is a
notorious for popcorn type of growth
rather than distance and so you can see
these things and this is a hoop house in
Oregon with no heat so you can see and
then the fruity pebbles here just wanted
to show you a little diversity we also
do food if anybody's looking at
trichomes take a look at that everything
here was grown by the Sun on demand and
except obviously the rice and the rap so
we can grow indoors that's it
so we'll open it up for questions if you
don't have any I can start posing some
but son what is the underlying
technology that's giving you twice the
efficacy of plasma it's a plasma light
so it's not a point source so it allows
for a lot of photons to come out so what
would the efficient like that micromoles
per Joule of your system be when you
start talking about ppfd it's the same
as the Sun 2100 electrical efficiency
meaning like how much electricity you
get per electricity or energy in ooh
that's a good question I would say from
I'll buy your question I'm sorry well
for light usually measured in you know
like a typical efficient fixture
efficiency would be 2.5 microns per
Joule oh okay so a number of photons per
energy and other like LED fixture or HPS
to be 1.8 yeah I can't answer that but I
can information to you okay
are you v's making a breakthrough on
life or are they still about the eight
to ten thousand hours on the led UV
dance who is the question directed
towards the panel okay guys so the
question is life of the LEDs source
itself yeah well yeah that's a great
question
there's still a shorter life span than
any of the corn of dominant LED
technologies so like anything within the
visible spectrum has kind of the
comparable lifespan whether whether
you're talking about a prospection diode
like I just a generic like a a warm
white or a cool white or or if you look
at narrowband you look at like a blue
diode and a red diode and a less so
amber in green because that technology
is also a little bit behind but yeah UVs
are still they have a ways to go
so with LEDs typically I'm a thin-film
engineer as well and we developed a lot
of diodes you're starting to about a
hundred thirty thousand hundred forty
thousand hours depending on which diode
you start start losing spectra and
typically cycle times three three years
maybe some people are now going up to
five but that's by cooling because
you've got a lot of heat dissipation our
lights a hundred thousand hours without
losing any kind of spectra so that's one
of the beauties of plasma any other
questions
oh yeah I'll pose one here um so we
heard a little bit about the costs and
structure but if I can actually do it
has anybody actually done a calculation
based on a number of units of light that
are able to be produced over a year
period using each one of the
technologies so if you're gonna be doing
the solar tube obviously there's an
installation capex cost and then
hopefully the light is free at that
point as opposed to the LED which is
there's a cost of buying the LED and
electrical cost as well as for the for
the plasma system has anybody actually
done that so we have I mean we've looked
at various systems for daylight
obviously the capex is going to be
largely climate driven so it depends on
where you are constructing your facility
that will determine how many day
lighting systems are required to provide
the necessary power lumination on the
plant canopy here in California or
anywhere where it's we have a nice
robust sunny climate actually we're
looking at something where based on
energy savings you're probably looking
at about a one-year payback to pay for
the the day lighting system and at that
point it's free there's no maintenance
of the the system and it's just okay
works wrong yeah so I think on the
operational expense side Nia is probably
going to have me beat at free LED can't
quite compete with that
as for the capital expenditure LED is
certainly more expensive than HBS on day
one but that that narrative tends to
fall apart pretty quickly and I'm not
going to pretend to be an expert on that
but I have a couple colleagues here
Corrine Wilder and Brady Namath are a
little bit more plugged in on a few
things there's some really interesting
stuff going on with utility providers
and rebates and a lot of the capital
expense that's associated with LED and I
probably shouldn't say this but I would
imagine probably some more efficient
technologies in general there are a lot
of initiatives to kind of encourage
people to go that route and governmental
bodies will absorb some of that cost so
you can work through your a utility
provider
really have the capital expenditure
become kind of a non-issue so again I'll
if you're interested in that part of the
story I can connect you with those
people after the fact well with our
systems the with the bulb of a hundred
thousand hours you don't have to to
obviously change bulbs all the time
for a new installation we actually pay
for the lights before a plant goes under
it because you're half the air
conditioning you're 20 lights versus
sixty six lights so a lot of
infrastructure goes away and I think the
other area is the use of materials when
you're doing it in living soil you're
buying less inputs you're doing less
pest control strips because you have UV
and you have all of the spectro
available just like outdoors right so
the plants are healthy and they're
immune so you also save in that arena so
I didn't know if you just meant from a
manufacturing perspective in total the
full system yeah yeah if I may I mean
certainly I think the important aspect
is that when we talk about a well
designed facility we want to integrate
all the systems and we want to optimize
them so they all work together so the
nice thing about a daylight enhanced
growth facility is that we're not just
talking daylight we're actually talking
about a fully integrated system where we
have the electric light source that's
providing the make up par or ppfd
intensities where we need them in doing
so though in when daylight becomes the
dominant light source we significantly
extend the life of the electrical
components so your facility actually has
might much greater life expectancy we've
increased the efficiency significantly
and we reduce the cost of goods
dramatically for the product in the end
so it's a win-win and also when it's
properly done as we've seen in the
research is that when you have properly
monitored or metered systems you can
actually prevent failures of electrical
components because you can start to see
where a problem
might be arising get it corrected before
it becomes an issue that damages the
crop yeah and actually I think probably
everybody in this room is picking up on
a common thread here which is that
although the three of us are
representing three pretty distinct
technologies the common thread here is
that we're all advocates of
broad-spectrum light whether that's
plasma technology which admittedly I'm
actually less well-versed in or sunlight
which we all have some familiarity with
or brought some extra LEDs really what
you could be taking away from that from
us as a group is that broad spectrum is
really going to be better for plant
quality in a whole lot of ways and
whether it's channeling sunlight around
or creating sunlight or using LED for
broad-spectrum light you do end up with
a more robust plant and whether that is
making easier to manage heat load or
mitigate pathogen stress or other
applications for plant hardening or
achieving certain chemo cars with
cannabis that's you know for good reason
that's the way the entire industry seems
to be moving to comments on the plasma
desert I'm wondering first if there's
any restriction on ceiling height if you
need a higher ceiling height than you
would for a LED or hyper Shore sodium
and also if there's any special
reflectance you need off the ceiling
reflective materials off the ceiling to
distribute that light sure sure you saw
that one didn't have a reflector in the
photo obviously you want to save photons
for sure I mean it's a lack of them
right you know a lot of people said to
me about your like the Sun really well
no Rinat really I mean that's point
three point seven four times 10 to the
37th watts
I'm 1,100 watts there's no way that kind
of power is going to come down so I
would arrest years question what was
that you had three Oh ceiling height
nine nine feet nine and a half feet
we're about a hundred two hundred and
four
four square foot footprint obviously
when you put him that way that one room
had 220 lights and so we do measure we
make this for a solar simulator people
put in a whole Mercedes to see in 1000
hours what 20 years does so yeah a lot
of a lot of area was there so so the
question was when we have utility
companies that are either requiring some
sort of size site-based generation to
account for the power consumption of the
facility or the utilities themselves are
having a ramp up power generation
themselves is there a benefit and
absolutely because we're able to
displace you know 50 60 percent or more
of the electrical consumption associated
with lighting and reduction in Kuta and
cooling energy as well so there is
definitely a benefit for the utilities
and certainly for the growth facility
itself we would definitely decrease the
need for generation or at least use of
the generation equipment over time so we
keep talking about solar spectrum but
for my understanding it changes
throughout the day and you can change
depending on what your latitude is on
earth how are you how are we determining
what solar spectrum is I mean we
presented multiple graphs showing a
different distribution it seemed like
some of them were different from others
especially in early on the presentation
so I'm just wondering if there's a
standard methodology for determining
what sunlight is so you're right the the
special content of daylight does change
to a certain degree the underlying
principle is that daylight is continuous
the it is always going to be rich in the
blue end of the spectrum where things
start to change is when we have
turbidity in the skies so we go from a
clear sky day to an overcast sky day
some of the reds may change during the
course of the day and so the general
curve may alter whether we're talking
about a 5,000 K like day light source or
a 6500 K day light source but the the
overall intensity of the light in the
critical regions stays consistent and
very useful
the other is that you have to have some
kind of a standard to be able to do so
sunlight outside is the standard that's
what we should be doing because that's
what plants how they came into play
right so we've pretty much ruined our
atmosphere so by the time you get to the
surface of the earth by the time you hit
all the water molecules especially the
smaller wavelengths you lose a lot of
that the reason use the latitude and
longitude make a big difference is the
amount of atmosphere it's going through
so you see the refraction of light as an
example a peacock is that actually brown
or almost a brown gray it's just our
eyes it's the surface that creates those
colors so it isn't color anymore it's
not luminous flecks it's electromagnetic
so if you look at a Class A bulb for
instance in Europe there's been a lot of
work in and looking at what is the Sun
spectra so that's the one you should
kind of take because in our marketing
material will make everything fit to
sell products right so you have to go
back to the real standard of what
sunlight is and then talk to lighting
guys what is that plant or what does
that product look like outdoors and now
show me you did the same thing question
first solitude for both your research
facilities like the the sheds that were
shown there as well as for production
facilities what ppfd have you been able
to achieve for specifically for
flowering cannabis great questions so
what we see from diffuse daylight the
research was able to show that diffuse
illumination or a ppfd
is in the 300 to 600 range over the
course of the day and then we have
transitory bright spot which actually is
beneficial for the plants which if I
recall correctly ranges from about 1300
up to about 1900 ppfd
so again that's going to vary based on
on whether it's a cloudy day or a sunny
day but so nice robust levels
and obviously the desire of keeping it
in the 500 6600 ppfd range is readily
achievable over the course today okay
there would be top of canopy yep okay
well I'd like to thank everyone for
coming to this session and hopefully you
enjoy the rest of the conference here
and I'd like to thank the three
panelists for spending your time son
Neil and Dave so thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]