[Music]
we are first going to hear from Wade
laughter on plans and solutions to get
medicine to our communities
keeping medical cannabis relevant
language marketing we can use that
supports patients and future medicinal
laws and we're going to try to keep it
to about five minutes for you speaker
okay if it has to be five minutes then I
would start off by saying that cannabis
as medicine works for in my experience
an incredible range of conditions and
the real trick is to to look at your
end-user the person who's actually going
to be using the product you have
produced and make sure that that product
that the chemistry that's available in
that product is appropriate for your end
user at a dose that's appropriate for
your end user with guidance to your end
user on how to use that preparation and
what side effects or beneficial effects
they should expect and I know that for
in my own life I started in this work as
a cultivator and organized a collective
that involved patients quote unquote
under the prop 215 law here in
California that allowed groups of people
to work together to provide medicine to
those who most needed it and basically
the one of the issues that I have with
in California we have commercialized
cannabis not legalized it we have
committed a heavily regulated commercial
activity and it's a shame because the
only reason that happened is there are
so many people who can benefit from
cannabis with those guidelines that I
just mentioned about dosage and
chemistry and guidance on how to use it
there are so many people that can
benefit from it that the laws that
prohibition were based upon have been
overturned in California you have a
constitutional right in California to
access cannabis as medicine if you need
it and yet we've set up these laws today
where patients the people who most need
cannabis do not have access for the most
part in my own life number of years ago
I I found a cultivar called Harlequin I
won't get into that story it's pretty
out there and if you
really want to hear the details ask me
about it later because I only got five
minutes but but where that's really
relevant is the among the very first
folks that I started interacting with
who wanted something other than getting
stoned was people who were dealing with
pain and at first again I was just
smoking and what was lovely about
Harlequin is it actually worked for pain
even if you were just smoking a joint
but pretty quickly folks with cancer
started presenting themselves and the
one the one issue that really flipped
everything for me personally was getting
involved with a family with a young
child that had protracted long term
issues with epilepsy basically from
birth this person had been taking anti
epileptic drugs when I met the family he
was on 15 different pharmaceutical drugs
totally locked up in rigor I know
there's a technical term for that doctor
so maybe you could elucidate but
basically in a wheelchair wearing
diapers blind completely disconnected
from the world and his parents loved
this child wanted him to be a successful
human being well today he is he's down
to one of those antiepileptic
medications he can see again he no
longer has to wear diapers he's 28 years
old by the way this person and he when
he has to go to the bathroom he has
enough ability to push himself up it's
like he's trying to get out of his
wheelchair and that's when his parents
know oh he needs to go to the bathroom
so he's no longer having to wear diapers
when he's able to when he's hungry he's
able to communicate that this is
something that he needs he needs food
and so you have to understand what that
must feel like if you're a parent
consider what you would be dealing with
if that was what your child was dealing
with and what's true is most all of us
take health for granted health is just a
beautiful thing it's a thing that
happens but as you get older in your
life or if your life is such that you're
presented with the
who has health issues or someone that
you love in your life comes in to health
issues this is where this plant can do I
I'm really reluctant to use the word
miraculous because it's not really a
miracle the plant is creating this
chemistry that mimics the chemistry our
bodies create in order to create health
in our bodies the endocannabinoid system
the way I think of it is it's the system
that our body uses compounds signaling
compounds to help our tissues talk to
each other so that the stomach and the
bile ducts and the gallbladder and the
pancreas and all of those things can
work together so we can digest the
breakfast we just had and take energy
from that food process it and make it
available to us so that we can live and
what's true is I think that cannabis has
become so important as a medicine
because the combination of food that
lacks proper nutrient and is
contaminated with all kinds of things
there's a whole conversation there
toxins in the air the stress of our
culture on and on and on our bodies are
no longer able to successfully make the
endocannabinoids that we need to enjoy
health and for that reason we are
experiencing all of the health issues
that we are experiencing as a culture
and what's lovely to me is so many of
them respond beautifully and perfectly
to cannabis and so as cultivators as
people who work with cannabis I feel
like one of the central responsibilities
when you talk about ethics in our work
is to make this met this plant and the
medicine we can make from it available
to those who most need it and ideally it
would be at little or no cost because
most people in our culture who are ill
have no money the medical system sucks
it up like a huge vacuum cleaner even if
you have good insurance so we all know
that when you set aside the rules and
the laws and the licenses and all of
that crap that we are all dealing with
today the
the the pathogen of paper as it was
described yesterday if you set all of us
that aside the actual true cost of
cannabis medicine should be literally
pennies on the dollar for what it costs
today and that's all I have to say
that's almost five minutes to the
patients or terms or tools that you've
thought about or looking towards in the
future to be getting this to the
patient's supporting the patient
supporting this movement two things
about that
the biggest one is changing the rules
here in California we blew it really
badly in terms of legalization because
it's not legalization again it's highly
highly highly recommended regulated
commercialization which is definitely
not the same thing so at the state level
an organization that I've done a lot of
work with the khalad rias Network we put
some effort into changing state law in
California khalad Reyes see al a d RI us
it's you'll have to go back to the
Wayback Machine online to find
information about our work because we
shut down state law required the
cessation of collective activity at the
beginning of this year and so the
collaboration network our mission
statement was to provide education and
if appropriate cannabis therapies to the
families of catastrophic ly ill children
at no cost to those families ever when
we shut down in January we've had a
hundred and forty six families that we
were helping directly by providing
products that were appropriate to their
child's needs and another 700 or so that
were in line if you will in our intake
process to qualify for what we were
doing and when we had to shut down at
the beginning this year we did a big
push to get those meds out to those
families hoping that we would be able to
rectify the situation by the end of this
year we did successfully get through
compassion bill at the state level that
excludes all cannabis products that are
donated from taxation which is a huge
thing so so really the model that we
used is collab in clavius network is
nurseryman cultivators manufacturers
laboratories distributors and retailers
to whatever extent they could
contributed some portion of their work
to our efforts at no cost to us so that
we could in turn pass those medicines on
to the families at no cost and again if
you are a cultivator and know lots and
lots and lots about cannabis and how it
works in your garden open yourself to
the idea that there are people in your
community who could benefit from the
material that you're making and I assure
you I knew nothing I I did not know what
CBD was when I learned that Harlequin
was as high CBD strain I've learned a
lot about what CBD does and what it can
do for people and some of the compounds
the chemistry that this plant is capable
of in the years since then and I assure
you that all of you can educate
yourselves about what cannabis as
medicine can do for people that you love
and what you can do in terms of creating
products and in Japan the last thing
that I would like to say about what you
asked for is to do with products
basically everybody that wants to smoke
a joint can smoke a joint you can find
joints all across the country around the
world it's a highly illegal drug and yet
without any advertising without any
distribution budget without any we have
put it all over the world you can find a
joint anywhere that's cool the problem
is most of the people who really need
cannabis aren't smoking joints start
learning about the products the ways
that you can prepare this plant into a
form be it a sublingual tincture or a
topical or nasal spray
or capsules that people are ingesting or
edibles there's so many different ways
the real trick is to get the chemistry
into the body at a dose that the user
not only can tolerate but won't be
frightened because one of the stories I
hear again and again is oh I tried
cannabis lost my mind for eight hours I
mean I ate it and it's a terrible drug
and I never want anything to do with it
again and that person lost the
opportunity to experience the wellness
that's possible from this plant that's
well it's a perfect segue because Mike
Frost is going to be talking with us
about products that have worked for
patients products that farmers can make
products that have medicinal value of
experience thank you very much
I really appreciate being here Wade you
covered a lot of good stuff already on
kind of the types of products but
getting you know how can you get that
into your body now switching it over to
what's easy for the farmers
well thanks you're straight activated
oil sticking in some topicals it's not
that difficult to get you know that
medicine out of the plan I guess the way
I'd look at it right now is what's the
easiest way to get it out and the
cleanest and more from a perspective of
a guess get get us out of the way of it
the beauty is sitting there in the plan
so you know we learn to you know move
away from the harmful methods of
extracting and get into what's you know
a little bit more clean but anything
whether it's you know ethanol you know
bubble hash you know squish and stuff
those are just great ways to get that
oil out once you get that oil out the
most beautiful thing to work with is
coconut oil people love it
yeah MCT oil is has been a huge deal you
know in all of us so that's how we blend
their topicals that's all make tinctures
the Pats right now we got coconut drops
that are just you know oil mixed with
MCT and and about a third of real
organic coconut oil and it's really cool
to have your dog come up and you know
you put a couple drops on your hand
and they come up to take the medicine
right off your hand you know before it
was you know try to get a capsule down
you know a dog's mouth that's just I
mean that's a traumatic thing for you
know a human or a pet but the methods
are really easy you can do a lot with
without a lot of equipment so if you can
get alkyl if you can get if you can get
coconut oil MCT you can put your plants
right in there heat up the oil you know
take some cheesecloth to get get your
material out of there and then put it
into anything you want but literally we
use that for our textures and all the
topicals when we first started making
the oils for the capsules so capsules
and lotions is pretty much you know but
you know our family started working with
and the capsules were they couldn't have
been more simple it was just get some
activated oil Rick Simpson oil style oil
and that's how I got into this was you
know I had I had three people tell me
about the cancer curing properties of
cannabis and I knew nothing about this
and so finally checked it out and learn
how to grow a plant and get some extract
out but what we did is get that
activated oil down suck it into a
syringe and then you have it you know
your ability to store it for the Rick
Simpson oil type of method of dosing it
came out to wear out of that syringe if
you had a like a half a half a grain of
rice you know for was it you have three
times a day for four days and you just
keep bumping that up and then you'll
build up your tolerance so it's not
freaking people out and because if you
can hallucinate I'm sure you know some
of us have been there but it's you know
it's traumatic for people that are just
looking for medicine but that was the
best way to do it and that half a green
rice coming out of that syringe that's
about ten milligrams of THC which ended
up being our and kind of a dose you know
in Washington and around as they get
going you know they can build up that
tolerance and the idea is you're gonna
take the whole syringe of that a day so
in a real quick couple minutes that's
kind of the range from a quick you know
quick topical to here's a full cancer
treatment
but the idea is that you're gonna take
60 of those grams
you know maybe over a course of you know
two or three months and really it's
about can you bring in that much
medicine without freaking out from my
experience and I don't know if this is
legitimate data but yes I should also
throw out the most of people that have
been working with or my age and older
and all the way up to an 83 year old gal
so there none of them want to get high
but at that time we didn't have the CBD
you know you know piece to add in there
and add value there so we would get
people ramping up and trying to build up
this tolerance but the male's I found
and it could have been just coincidence
but I could not get them to take the
full 1 gram deal the look and I mean I
understand it it's it's heavy you know I
you know I test it and I've never taken
a full gram of oil either but yeah but
I've taken enough to get me out of
normal smoking weed range and you know
get in some really cool hallucinations
too but that's yeah that's a different
thing
yeah yeah exactly
but but what I have found is we did get
good good get good results and the
females and the older especially older
females they were able to get to that
one gram no problem and I mean I'm we
can have some discussions afterwards to
see if there's anything that you guys
have experienced on is there a you know
male female element or not but we had
one gal 83 year old Gao accidentally
start dosing herself and got up to 4
grams in a day and she's a pretty
connected plant person I mean she's
she's been learning you know indigenous
stuff for a long time so I say you want
to go for it but she was she got
diagnosed with a real aggressive type of
cancer and she knew she didn't have the
time to just you know start trying to
stretch stuff out or will this work and
I just told her I think the best thing
and you know I really it said I think I
don't know I don't know a lot but from
experience
I think that there's more power and
blasting somebody and just putting them
down and you're gonna be down for a few
days just go through that through this
and I've seen you know we've seen tumors
you know nodules and you know lymph
nodes and stuff go away that have been
photographed I mean like within a month
and a half I did this with a guy at work
in the information technology career he
was literally dropping snake type things
out of this syringe into coffee right
next to me so I had to learn this while
I'm doing my other career and luckily
have been you know fortunate enough to
get out here and you know try to not you
know try to make it living it's know I
want to work with this thing this can
change people this hemp plant can change
their planet this is this can bring
people together you know it's possible
we could clean up water and air it's
possible we could have maybe a
replacement plastic I mean this thing is
a huge topic and you know if this is
doable the really switch you know kind
of the culture and get moving on this
hemp thing Holly I was talking with I'm
going casters like is this really doable
that we could switch and have this much
of a an industry impact on the planet by
switching just the topic of hemp to
regenerative farming I'm watching and
seeing two potential pathways going out
and one of them is oh my god if we
continue our you know same agricultural
practices to produce this easy to make
medicine we're gonna take something that
really has the potential to put us in a
better position to have sustainable life
here and then the opposite it's just not
cool so I guess you know when I walked
into this room and I'm pretty new to
this community to see how much power you
guys have and all of your knowledge and
the heart and passion which is the real
driver but take that heart passion and
drive it down the real pathway you guys
are giving me confidence that this
actually you know it can happen so
I want to add something I want to add
something the high doses that this
brother was just speaking of can be
really important and helpful for a few
conditions in your communities but most
of the people who are seeking help want
small doses they want a little bit we
don't need these huge doses and the
beauty of that point of view is in your
kitchen in olive oil or MCT you can make
concentrated preparations that will be a
benefit to most of the people that you
will encounter most people don't need a
whole gram of oil THC a day because that
is a huge thing a lot a lot of people
that we've worked with get benefit from
five or ten milligrams you know over the
course of a whole day and it's my Arnaud
Hezekiah is the analytical chemist and
for the Netherlands cannabis program and
he did a study on extractions what
where's the best capture of the terpenes
and cannabinoids present in the cannabis
plant and he found that olive oil done
on a kitchen stove is the best capture
of the original chemistry in that plant
the limitation is he could only get up
to about 10 milligrams per milliliter of
the material he was making but in fact
10 milliliters 10 milligrams in a
milliliter is a pretty effective dose
for a lot of conditions just got to say
again these people are not looking to
get stoned they're looking for benefit
available in that chemistry just wanted
to add in that you know yeah just
everybody coming together like this you
can look at is like okay it's a you know
synchronistic you know types of things
that are occurring and you know
recognizing that is just amazing but you
know we haven't talked you know we want
you know we're gonna have a little
conversation about harlequin so it's
it's pretty unique that i'm sitting here
next to you in and in this group because
Harlequin came into Washington State
and somehow it came to us and we spread
that as much as we could and so same
thing yeah nice so I appreciate your
work so I don't know how I don't know
how you know it got in there but when
the CBD piece came out and we talked
about the efficacy in the healing the
CBD piece brings in all of the anxiety
health the bipolar schizophrenia we've
stopped we've stopped suicides from
occurring with CBD that's super powerful
it's just a quick question about
efficacy of of those doses you're
talking about when you're when you're
giving a big dose like that would it be
more efficacious to infuse that into a
little bit of oil at least and then not
have to give as big of a dose or it
seems like having that fat would bring
it into the body faster so instead of
putting the snake of real sticky in the
mouth wouldn't you want to make that a
little more easy for them taking because
we've all put our sore or freako in our
mouths and it's like if you think about
a whole snake okay yeah just a quick
response on that yeah absolutely if you
can have some fats in there to deal with
the whole stomach issue you know without
getting too gross you know Nick that's a
helpful segue into that topic of that 83
year old gal who she started noticing
that some medicine might be coming out
of her before getting the you know
absorbed into the system and yeah it was
you know adding the you know the oil or
make sure you eaten some fats means it
fats are great ice cream I don't know if
that's a real deal but ice cream seems
to really really work well
and different cannabinoids and olive oil
has definitely produced the higher
cannabinoid batches time after time it's
good to then mix it with coconut oil but
the olive oil has consistently been the
winner hi so I'm a medical intuitive and
shamanic practitioner for 30 years and
I've been working with patients for the
last almost four years with exactly what
you're talking about
and titrating up okay so but what I also
do and I do this myself is I take it
suppository I make my own pills I
started out with point one oh I'm up to
0.5 oh that's that's my range so I
titrate it up until the next morning I I
was feeling you know really kind of
stone and I backed it off a bit and
that's my dose and suppository it put
surpasses your brain in your liver
pretty much so you don't get high and
you're getting the medicine in you I've
never had a digestive system better than
now my bowels are better than ever just
so you all know so you know so I mean
when I work with patients I work with
CBD crude I work with full-spectrum
ara so we call a ppm pure plant medicine
I work with THC a crystals I combine
depending on what it is like you know
Parkinson's patients I'm going to use a
higher you know CBD 1 or CBD you know
that's going to go into for the
neurological system if it's somebody
who's in pain I'm gonna use higher ppm
and you know maybe more of a THC a
mixture so you know again when you're
working with your plant you know the
person everybody's everybody's different
everybody cells are different so maybe
have them get an endocannabinoid test
that's what I'm having my patients do
first thing you come to me getting into
Kannamma Neri test so I can see what
your cells will and will not accept yeah
and so that gives you a start then you
know what to grow then you know how to
proceed with that particular patient
yeah so so that I guess I'm leading into
to to me on how my journey that brought
me here sorry
exactly yeah
so um as you as I talked about in the
first night I was diagnosed on January
24th of this year with Stage four
ovarian cancer my tumors were grew so
quickly they grew two and a half
centimeters in less than seven days I
had three masses one on each ovary and
one behind by the time of my surgery on
February 6th my masses were six point
four and four point nine and three point
four they debunked me meaning they did
they did a complete hysterectomy
laparoscopically they found they took
out pieces of my body and found I was
87% malignant so they opened me up and
they took eight organs out they closed
me back up and and no uncertain terms
said if you do not do chemo and
radiation you will die and the
fear-mongering that goes on is
incredible they said to Layton in front
of my children if you don't make her do
chemo you will kill her this is on you
so the fear-mongering that goes on is
terrible but that leads me to I found a
wonderful natural path I chose my
doctors my team of doctors I said this
is who I want to work with I did all of
my testing up front right so I did the
endocannabinoid test I did something
called the Charis test which showed me I
wasn't him I wasn't able to do
immunotherapy I did something called the
our GCC test which this is what told me
what herbs
News so I found a really good natural
path and he put me on 15 different herbs
I take a hundred and thirty pills a day
it's keeping me alive and this is what
I'd like to really talk about how we
could how you could help people like me
it's not just cannabis we need herbs we
need herbs we need whole food and so
think about it if you if you plant a
tomato plant and you put a pepper plant
next to it what's going to happen you're
going to have some of those properties
from the root into the tomato plant
right so the same thing what can happen
if you plant something like bin weed or
seek help or hi you know turkey kale or
that's gonna seep into your cannabis too
and the cannabis is gonna seep into
those you're gonna be able to make all
these other herbs which I need
desperately I'm spending we're spending
three thousand dollars a month on herbs
alone it shouldn't be like this
right so and there's a lot of people out
there that really want to do this route
but insurance doesn't cover it they
don't they look at me and go we we might
help you with your rent but we won't pay
for your herbs we won't pay for your
medicine so this is I think you know
something that we could really talk
about and come together as a collective
to say not only we are we going to give
the cannabis plant this beautiful plant
the sacred plant the medicine that we
can get from her but also all of the
other plants that go with it
that people like me who you know it's
these this is saving my life
and I take you know half a gram
suppository at night for my cannabis and
I have no scar tissue for months a
14-inch scar no scar tissue right that's
cannabis so I think an the way to get it
into our society is you know talk to
your local wellness centers they are
really into this you know talk to them
about what you have to offer and you
know maybe then do some lecturing and
some you know just educating
your community on you-know-what because
everyone knows somebody who has cancer
statistics one out of two men one out of
three women in the next year are gonna
get it so we really need to talk about
this because somebody you love is gonna
get it and so doing something you know
like really get involved with the other
thing I did was my first patient had
breast cancer she talked to the liaison
who was the liaison for the eastern and
western part of our Hospital we actually
had somebody like this intern this woman
called me we sat down and had a
conversation I taught her about
regenerative organic cannabis and
because we're in Connecticut I think I
mean the only place you can get cannabis
is in the dispensary and she was like I
don't want to get it here what do I do
I said but until it's federally I can't
even though I was like you know don't
tell anybody but you know but you know
talk to your hospital who has a you know
an alternative person and you know they
really believe me they've been thinking
about this for years
and they want it to come into the
hospitals so that I think is one of the
best ways we can maybe bridge or East
and West so that there's not so much
fear because you know as dr. Russo will
tell you the doctor is you know they're
they're doing their job and if they step
out of that box a little bit they're
gonna lose their license so until the
day that they get educated and and maybe
saying yeah go ahead and try that I
didn't tell you to do it but go ahead
and do it instead of if you don't make
her do chemo you're gonna kill her and
this is what I would like to see happen
with everyone you know working with this
plant and get out and to your community
and talk to these people who had can
help you make a difference yeah thanks
[Applause]
[Music]
real quick one of the things I add to
Pauline if you're working with someone
and you're going to provide them
cannabis as medicine make sure you ask
them if they are taking any
pharmaceutical drugs turns out there's
lots of pharmaceutical drugs that have
interactions some which are harmful to
the end-user with cannabis and typically
what goes on is those pharmaceutical
drugs do not get broken down and
eliminated by our bodies particularly
CBD slowed certain metabolic pathways
and so in stand what at the position
I've taken instead of trying to educate
myself in all of these different
pharmaceutical drugs is I tell the
person talk to the doctor who prescribed
your medication and two things happen
there one the doctor gets to sign off on
whether or not this prescription drug is
going to work with the cannabis or not
and two they're likely to get more
educated about cannabis which i think is
a really important thing doctors need
this education they need to understand
that it's not scary that there are
potential side effects but for the most
part the side effects are nothing
compared to pharmaceutical drugs Thank
You Valerie couldn't be here and she has
written something that Sarah is going to
read for us and this is about how as a
collective we can get out education to
consumers and how we can get medicine to
patients hi everyone I was given the
task of representing Valerie and it's an
honor and it's also impossible so I'm
just gonna be a conduit for her wisdom
and as I'm reading I'll maybe jump in
and give a little context so thank you
for indulging me and listening as my
lovely friend Sarah Russo represents
Wham during this time of evolution I can
feel the buzz of the hive even 300 miles
away and why I delight at the thought of
communing with you Buchan by the song of
mother cannabis I am called to be at the
bedside of my own mother so Valerie
chorale has worked for decades
in the cannabis space WAM is her
collective that started shortly after
the medical law was passed in California
and they're based in Santa Cruz and they
offer patients free medicine that who
are terminally ill and she also does
hospice work so she's been holding
people's hands as they transition for a
very long time and so she actually gets
the opportunity to do that with her mom
so that's really beautiful
um why everything cannabis in cannabis
is changing the thing that remains is
our deepening relationship with her but
nature reveals pathways to surviving in
such critical time when commercialism
threatens to Korean out-of-balance
displacing farmers and businesses
critically abandoning sick and dying
people but she reminds us to open and to
soften to listen more deeply to the
earth to each other's truths that she
expands our consciousness moves our
hearts and strengthens our resolve in
nature everything in the forest grows
symbolically seeking balance
interdependent as a necessary part of
the whole the demand that legalization
have brought forward around a rigorous
revealing that we cannot survive in
isolation from in competition with each
other but we may thrive in unity
reminding us that we are a part of
something greater than ourselves
serving the plants each other and the
earth so came the growing pains
stretching us to be creative and us to
reframe our work within the context of B
Corp dedicated the Wellness of our
members clients our staff in the
environment we have created Wham phyto
therapies this is a little diagram of
her Wham
B corporations are businesses that meet
the highest standards of verified social
environmental performance public
transparency and legal accountability to
balance profit and purpose B corpse are
accelerating a global culture shift to
refine success in business
and build a more inclusive and
sustainable economy we do this in order
to provide the highest standards of
service best quality organic cannabis
environmentally sound and modestly
priced products an unsurpassed working
environment for our employees and
compassion cannabis for the neediest
members of our community compassionate
access free cannabis medicine for the
needy is taxed as though is being sold
in this way we seek means by which to
still provide the same care for the poor
as we always have the potential for
healing is inherent in each of us and
requires that we can influence and
inspire our systems our work focuses on
the indigenous endogenous cannabinoids
system in this symbiotic symbiotic
interface with the other systems clearly
there is no panacea no magic potion or
simple solution that cures why cannabis
provides proves to provide an
extraordinary career to potential and
modality for healing is as complex as
each individual and is as interdependent
as the systems that reside within all of
us
and like the system our networks must
also work symbolically to flourish
prosper and serve strengthen through
this our same collective model for
service to everyone we will have joined
forces with an enchanted network of some
of the most storied experienced and
prolific producers to create a web of
service donating services and products
taking on the cultivation efforts to
serve and carry on our decades-long
mission the financial costs are great to
rebuild within this context but by
joining together to create a small
dispensary with a true community center
bringing the therapist from our
community that supports their work
educational sharing expanding the
framework of healing and offering many
upper alternative applications as we are
able to re-emerge as a truly
community-based an interdependent and
supportive system focused on helping
people heal themselves this is very
important meeting of the hive demands
it's the greatest opportunities arise
from sharing our skills and knowledge
and enhance our individual experience we
are all greater with each other and I
just want to say about Valerie that you
know as far as being a part of the
movement she's a foundational key player
in this whole scene and she always
reminds me of the need to first of all
work for the plant more than anything
and each other and hold us all in
integrity with that and I think that
right now it's really easy to get lost
and to feel like while marketing is
important and making money for your life
of the hood is obviously important that
to not lose sight of that so you know
there's been a lot of people who've been
doing it for as long as she had well not
a lot of people but the people that have
been doing it as long as she have some
of them have faced other routes of
success and she just stays true to her
integrity and her intentions in her work
so and just a personal story I wanted to
share about her when I was 17 I went to
my first ICRS conference and I met
Valerie and I smoked Halle weed for the
first time and it was her stuff and it
was amazing it was a definitely
different world and um we got to go see
her farm so was the first time I got to
see cannabis growing and of course it's
beautiful and amazing property and got
to be with family for a while and soon
after that happened they were raided by
the federal government and but actually
they got raided and then they sued the
federal government and then they won so
[Applause]
thank you and we're gonna move right
along to Martin Lee and Zoey Sigmund and
who are going to discuss with us ideas
on how we get the word out that we
support plant as medicine education how
do we do this you know I love I love the
hive metaphor if you will but I I think
that this group is more like a school of
fish because it sort of undulates and
hive is it it it conjures a sense of
such efficiency you know that that
insect amazing insect intelligence of
everybody working no I didn't say that I
said but and also you know a school of
fish so that has these very very movable
boundaries I kind of fit smart anyways
so education in a project CBD that's
what we are we would engage of this for
10 years since we were involved in
introducing CBD into the medical
community in California but in terms of
Education I think technically the word
means in Latin to lead out so what does
it mean if we're school of fish how do
we move the school of fish from where we
are to where we're going I think that's
the challenge of Education and it's very
tricky very very tricky sure we can have
lots of information we have lots of
information about her and on a website
about a particular minor cannabinoid or
a receptor and this and that's all
really oil really interesting and
important but I think at this point
given what we've seen how to transpire
over the last 10 years I think you know
we're looking at maybe sort of raising
the stakes a little bit more I'm
reminded of a circle that Wade was at
Sarah was at about ten years ago nine
years ago is right around this time of
year it's either December 2010 January
2011 where a group of people is about
two dozen maybe more were sitting in a
circle like this and taught and
everybody had some kind of interest or
involvement with CBD
which was very new at the time it was
barely introduced into into the Calif
into Northern California and everyone
went around the room at that point
saying well kind of where they're at and
what they thought this was all gonna
mean and what it might mean and and I
remember very distinctly when I when it
was my turn to speak I emphasize two
things I said that CBD is a social
medicine it's not just an individual
medicine and that what we were doing and
introducing it into into the community
was a lot like an acupuncturist putting
a needle in a body and turning it and we
were gonna see what energies were were
Unleashed
from turning that needle whoa I mean the
energies that were Unleashed were well
we're in the midst of it and not all
good obviously but for for project CBD
because we've emphasized CBD as a focus
of our work and I should say we we've
never been involved in privilege in one
compound over anything else in the plant
and we reject that idea but always
emphasizing a whole plant but with CBD
as a as important element it was a new
thing at the time so it really the
educational challenge was just telling
ringing the bell like the Hunchback of
Notre Dame CBD CBD what it is what it is
we don't have to do that anymore you
know now that Kim Kardashian is having a
CBD themed baby showers you know so what
what what is that what does it mean for
us it means that we actually you know
all the sudden got a very very large
audience with that just from doing what
we were doing and not just the numbers I
mean earlier in the air we were over a
million page views a month on our
website it's gone down quite a bit
because we we're not kissing Google's
ring properly apparently but and and and
you know that's just the way it goes but
what one thing that's really striking in
these just how unusual it is the
different the difficulties and
challenges when faces within the
cannabis industry as it's now called or
the kind of as community as I would
prefer to call it there's just some
unprecedented things that you have to
deal with from a business point of view
that you don't have to deal with in any
other business and a perfect example
sort of tying together some of the
things we've discussed you know I know
product makers where they they're very
concerned about organic growing and
getting good quality flour in they test
the flour the flour passes they do a
concentrate new there's always the
danger that whatever is in there the
residues you know could concentrate to
the point of being beyond allowable
limits they test the oil the oil is
perfect and then they mix it with the
chocolate and they have their chocolate
and then it fails why because of the
cadmium levels in the chocolate so you
have different standards you have the
cannabis product makers are actually
held to a higher standard than anyone
else and then you think about that we
could say on the one hand it's unfair
but then maybe there's an opportunity
here maybe we should lift the standards
up for everybody else so that the
cadmium levels aren't going to be in the
chocolate for everybody not just for
cannabis makers so that and that's the
kind of the spirit of what I want to
introduce in the few moments more I have
before I turn it over to Zoe you know
one of the things we're thinking about
at project CBD we actually started it is
- we put out special reports now and
then and oftentimes they're on more
medical science related things we just
put out a report on the the vaping
crisis where we identify it's synthetic
so called synthetic marijuana is really
a key culprit that's being ignored here
and and numbered we put out a big report
on CBD and THC drug interactions with
pharmaceutical we just thought this is
something that would be helpful for dot
for physicians but what we'd like to do
is put out a report on cannabis in the
green new deal and while I'm not really
fixated on federal level politics and
stuff there is an invert a invitation
that's been put out by AOC and Bernie
Sanders and others and saying we want to
hear from local communities we were
relying on local communities to drive a
green new deal so let's call their bluff
you know so what we intend to do is is
both emphasize you know some of the best
in terms of the experiment that is going
on when we think about cannabis as
laboratory experiment and democracy was
how Brandeis the great chief justice of
all
imagine if we had you know justices like
that today another thing he mentioned
that you can't have democracy and in
morbid inequality either the two don't
go together and the whole point of the
green New Deal is to address both
environmental crisis and and the crisis
of inequality and I think that the
cannabis the best of the cannabis
community as embodied here really in
terms of regenerative agriculture and
many other aspects really has something
to offer to speak to what what has been
called for in terms of a green new deal
and the same way I think the cannabis
industry has would benefit tremendously
if it would embody the ethos of agree
new deals because so much of the
cannabis industry doesn't so we intend
to put out a report that will examine
will look at both sides of it kind of
dispassionately saying here are examples
of what should be supported on beyond
even the local level oh that's what
counts most are the kind of things that
if you want to make a green new deal
real well let's look to what what what
work has been done in the cannabis
community that that really speaks to
that in so many different ways so to me
here being here listening to what people
are talking about I can give a lots of
examples just one yesterday jumped out
at me
you know you can't sell food and
cannabis at a car a farmers market you
can't sell anything besides cannabis in
a dispensary you know you can't sell
other herbs that's ridiculous you know
and given how such a key you know
vector driving disease is the processed
food industry wouldn't you want people
to come out to a farmers market because
they want to get their cannabis and then
look at all these great all this other
great food I mean you want to put the
two together and yet our policies are
all wrong in that regard
that's a state-level policy so I mean
but I think well what's let's lay it out
well what if you actually had good
policies what would they really be so in
addition to kind of examining examples
of experiment and examples of problems
also make some recommendations
specifically for what a green new deal
how how much it could benefit from
cannabis and how much it needs cannabis
and I think beyond that we also want to
do a second report on cannabis and
I could call a single-payer
medicare-for-all just health to the
human right of health and because they
we always talk about this stuff oh if
you you're taking pharmaceuticals then
you start taking cannabis and you take
less pharmaceutical as well I think
that's true and you hear in states where
there is medical cannabis laws is less
overdoses from opiates and so forth it
goes down a certain number well okay and
you hear some click conflicting reports
about that but let's assume you we can
arrive at a number well if it's 25% less
well how much does that mean in a state
that you save on funeral costs well and
then just add all the numbers up in
terms of well if you're buying less you
know what would it really mean to have
cannabis integrated into a healthcare
system I mean Bernie Sanders has said
that he's open to the idea that it
should be covered in insurance I'm not
here to promote a cow okay I'm in at
love Bernie but it's that that's but you
know that this is now being discussed
beyond our little circles in ways that
uh people who are good minded and have
influence it and may actually be
steering the ship to some degree
although I think shudder to think if
they can empower how difficult will be
for them but so that's that's some of
the thoughts that we had that we'd like
to do with projects even pushing it
beyond just the individual healing which
is paramount and in the ultimate of
course but to just try to take it to
another level because it might be one of
those transformative moments as it was
ten years ago when we're all sitting
around kind of just you know smoking
weed and say well what where we at oh
we're gonna we're gonna just let loose
some energies and see what happened oh
my and here we are
so I'm going to take it in a slightly
different direction I'm Zoe
I work with Martin with project CBD I'm
work I'm yeah I do a lot of things but
I've been thinking a lot about the
question of Education the way the last
thing I did before this was I was the
director of education at a dispensary
and so there's been a lot of talk about
education over the past few days and
over the past several years in the
cannabis community and the question
really is like what do we mean by
education and who are we educating so
there's all sorts of different answers
to this question you can be educating
consumers directly you can be educating
a business owners who are trying to open
cannabis businesses you can be educating
bud tenders you could be educating
doctors you could be educating policy
makers and each one of those groups
requires a different strategy for
education and and so I don't think that
there's a way to like answer how to
educate each one of those groups in in
five minutes but just know that like
there isn't a single strategy that is
going to convince all of those different
people that cannabis is is a medicine
and it should be treated like like a
medicine I think one of the things I
really wanted to share from my
experiences in this field and this is
maybe a little bit against the grain in
this room is um don't be afraid to admit
when you don't know I got to where I am
by working with patients and reading all
the research and saying okay I don't
know anything about science let's read
this paper together like this was done
on mice this is different than humans we
don't know if this is gonna help you we
don't know what the dosage is this is
how you're gonna approach it so many
people who come in who talk to you who
talk to all of you are like I'm dying
help me like that puts you in a really
difficult position it's also in a legal
position by the way to give medical
advice to someone without a medical
license not that anyone's enforcing that
but just so you're aware it is illegal
and the way to like help them and to
help change the industry is to try and
provide what information is available
like you can provide anecdotes for
sure like this helped me in this way you
know what Valerie was saying earlier
that is a story that she can share
because that was her experience that
does not mean that someone else with
cancer will have that same experience
even if it's the same same type of
cancer and I think that anyway
I'll get off onto a sidetrack but anyway
be familiar with the literature don't be
afraid to say that you don't know don't
be afraid to do the research I think
that it does much more harm to say oh
you take take 15 milligrams of this for
two months and you'll get better because
what if they don't get better what if
they have a really bad experience then
they're gonna tell all of their friends
that they had a bad experience with
canvas and none of their friends are
gonna have like try it and this is
exactly the opposite of what we want to
happen and the same is true when working
with medical professionals I have been
working with some a group of doctors at
Oregon Health and Sciences University
for a couple of years now and they're
highly skeptical of cannabis and I can't
come in and say like this is awesome
this will cure everything I have to be
incredibly familiar with the like
absolute cutting edge data and come in
armed with papers and be like okay you
don't trust this let's go over these
studies together because that's how
you're gonna change their mind so you
have to figure out like what are the
access points for the different groups
that you're trying to educate and do
that work because I think that the the
impetus is to be like this is amazing it
can cure all of these things and while
that it has helped a lot of people
different people with a lot of different
conditions it won't help everyone with
that condition so I think that's like
the biggest takeaway in this moment
you're talking about this these papers
and and maybe studies do you have a
point on your website or a way that we
can get in touch with you so that we can
make these papers available to the whole
collective yeah so there's the
conditions page on our website if you go
to the homepage I think it says CBD for
and each one of those conditions should
have a section of papers that are
related to the study of cannabis in that
particular condition
personally I also have a research
library that's a little bit more
extensive that should go on the website
one day but if you have questions I have
a little bit more in my personal store
so my email is Zoe at Project CBD org so
feel free to reach out if you have
specific questions also I just wanted to
say to encourage everybody you know here
we are we're hitting we're hitting that
that conversation of data so we have the
ability to start collecting data this is
something that we're going to continue
talking about how can we bigger our own
library by reaching out to collective
members and other community members and
nisha I would also like to make our
website have all those - the purifiers
website hi everyone
for those of you whom I haven't had the
pleasure of meeting my name is Nisha
Whitely and have the pleasure of working
with dr. Ethan Russo will be working
with Dale hunt as well
and be happy to send you a paper that
Ethan wrote with dr. Carolyn McCallum
from British Columbia which is the first
dosing article that has been published
in a peer-reviewed medical journal it is
a fantastic resource that would help all
of you in helping your community so I'll
get that to you if you guys want to send
that out to everyone this isn't gonna be
five minutes
I was asked asked to talk about things
to avoid in preparations and this really
a short conversation it's not a problem
with cannabis components in general
because there's almost nothing in there
that's dangerous at conventional doses
flatout statement I can defend I have to
think very hard
to come up with things that you should
avoid in the plant proper CBD as we've
heard about an incredibly versatile
compound 30 different mechanisms of
action and yet all of them are
beneficial it's hard to figure a
side-effect of CBD unless you're talking
about a pure preparation at phenomenal
doses there is nothing that CBD does
that won't be better with at least a
touch of THC and and again this is the
antithesis of the way drugs
pharmaceuticals are made normally the
process is oh we know the receptor we're
gonna computer design a molecule that
lodges there with the highest potency
and the highest affinity we'll spend a
few hundred million dollars and then
seven years out we'll find out that it
kills your liver kills your bone marrow
here we're dealing with something that's
thousands of years old and this had this
interchange with humanity for better or
for worse our bodies know how to handle
this medicine ah there is one component
a terpenoid in when i wrote about this
in 2001 withdrawing McPartland we listed
pilla joan as one of the agents one of
the terpenoids in cannabis it is
potentially toxic it can have an
abortifacient of fact that high doses it
is in pennyroyal and pennyroyal is
something to avoid him in pregnancy but
I have not seen that agent in any of the
analyses I've seen over the last 10
years it would be something to look out
for chances are it would be in such a
trace amount that it would have no
relevance so again this plant is very
safe but how we use it may not be I am
fond of saying outside of primary
treatment of cancer where big doses are
and necessary that for most medical
conditions 15 milligrams of THC is
usually enough to treat any condition in
conjunction with a whole plant medicine
30 at the outside beyond that you're
usually dealing with more side effects
than benefits someone who doesn't
respond at that level is unlikely to
gain a lot of benefit at a higher dose
on we have to take into account things
like tolerance and everything else but
in general that's a safe place to be
the problem really comes in in
extractions we heard mention of Rick
Simpson oil that's a term I like to
avoid because Rick Simpson is not a
professional he developed an extraction
technique calling using naphtha naphtha
actually isn't one thing it's a
petroleum distillate but there is no way
to safely purge this entirely from that
kind of extraction and I
I don't like butene either it's true
it's more efficient at getting some
things out but in the best of all
possible worlds where there's plenty of
base material we always need to be going
for quality rather than quantity and if
you it doesn't matter should not matter
that you're not getting every last
little molecule there you want the good
stuff in that regard the cleanest
extraction technique is supercritical
co2 extraction the problem there is that
tends to squander the important monitor
Pinoys so you end up with a concentrate
that's very rich in cannabinoids at the
expense of the terpenoids and I think
that this is a problem because of that
as a simple extraction I prefer an
oil-based extraction like we've heard
about coconut oil olive oil or a
particularly cold ethanol extraction
really will tend to do a better job in
getting material out
and then as we've heard yesterday
solvent less extraction some of the
old-style
techniques of making hash with Civic
technique a done on high-quality
material is possible to get a
concentration of like 62% THC
plus other stuff one doesn't need
ninety-five percent THC such as in dabs
that that is not a medical product that
is a product that's a product for going
extra galactic yeah but that's really
all I wanted to say again we're dealing
with very safe material and if it's
treated with respect and a little bit of
applied science good things will happen
[Applause]
in the industry and you've been talking
to all different members of the industry
and you know the amazing rainbow flag
that you're flying is getting access to
patients and and and helping people that
that are ill with with this medicine how
is it that we as a group can support
your mission or other people's missions
that are similar to yours well Kelly
so she mentioned that I wrote a book the
book has called chronic relief a guide
to cannabis for the terminally and
chronically ill and I'll create a
passcode when I get home next week and
if you guys want to send it out to
everyone here offer it at a discount
it's available on Amazon and the this is
really how I came to meet Ethan was
through the writing of that book and I
feel like a really understanding your
data is critical we want to be the
primary resources for information and it
important that we're giving accurate
science-based information of course
where there is an absence of that we
have to use what we've seen work in our
communities and with the people that we
support
so really the the goal with the website
which is my chronic relief com is to
educate people who are new to the topic
of cannabis and I think that when people
really understand why and how the
components of the cannabis plant work in
their bodies it becomes so much less
scary and you know we we've seen this
fantastic evolution in public sentiment
about cannabis since Sanjay Gupta did
his special about weed and now there's
CBD sold everywhere and so that's really
opened the conversation a much larger or
far more important conversation about
cannabis cannabis medicine how and why
does it work the fact that it's such a
safe versatile and effective component
when we're seeing this takeover of human
health from the pharmaceutical industry
and when you know people are consuming
large amounts of pharmaceuticals the
pharmaceuticals in and of themselves
cause a whole bunch of other problems
that oddly enough cannabis helps to
ameliorate and so what what I endeavor
to do with my passion project for which
I make zero money is just because it's
the right thing to do and this is
through social media on on my chronic
relieves social sites and the work
through the book and any public speaking
engagements is just to alleviate fear
and the way we do that is by empowering
people with information and helping
people
and their body and and how it works it's
unfortunate that in grade school and
through our education system we don't
have a better understanding of our
bodies and how they work
you know another challenge is the fact
that there might be
Ethan what is it something like 5% of
medical schools actually address the
endocannabinoid system in medical
education is that right and you know
when we have an interaction with a
physician and we know more about the
endocannabinoid system than they do or
how and why cannabinoids and turpentine
that a little scary and sad but it's
also an opportunity for us as people in
the cannabis industry to educate and so
I'll really kind of sum it up and the
fact that it's up to us to spread the
word about the fact that cannabis is a
safe versatile and effective medicine
and through constantly working to spread
just basic knowledge we don't have to
you know make people feel like they're
drinking from the fire hose of too much
information just a little bit of basic
actual fact base knowledge will empower
them to live better die better be better
and so I think that you know in the
grand sense of regenerative farming
that's something that we're all
endeavoring to do and in everything that
we're doing whether that's in our
personal life or a professional life and
now Erica winters and Wendy minty
speaking about charitable contributions
outreach with cannabis and nonprofit
groups and creating direct lines for
producers to donate to patients
completely derail that and add one more
health education resource that will
connect both bridges how many have heard
of nationally registered horticultural
therapists in America certified
horticultural therapist working towards
national registration this is a direct
line into the hospitals they're taking
this modality seriously everyone in this
room intuitively knows what
horticultural therapy is specifically
clinically this is a modality to achieve
a rainbow of therapeutic goals by using
nature based activities with every
population group on the planet hospital
administrators are listening to us right
now I have been approached by several
administrators in the Eugene area about
getting horticultural therapy programs
involved with cannabis patients however
in our code of ethics we cannot make
medical recommendations so I need the
doctors the endocannabinoid experts and
be a liaison between the patient and
we're moving in a direction where
insurance is on the table of discussion
so I think this might be a direct line
in thought if anybody's interested in
learning about a certification hit me up
over coffee it's not easy but it's super
doable with that
I am really excited to talk about
charity and outrage this is one of my
biggest passions and Wendy and I are
here on behalf of women leaders in
cannabis a 501 C 6 in Eugene Oregon so I
think we all intuitively know that
charity and giving and outreach is epic
and we should all do it but let's be
honest we have to fill the water tanks
and pay the bills and it's a wonderful
vision for next year so we want to talk
a little bit more about the true value
of outreach and I believe this is so in
line with our mission here at pure I
want to start by telling a story so in a
different chapter of my life I
skateboarded competitively and wrote
four tactics board shop in Eugene and we
were starting a petition to build a
skate park this is my first foray into
public policy and activism so we
collected signatures we met with the
city officials we built the damn thing
and it is a regional destination skate
park and we're very proud of it No thank
you thank you
but this naive little activist didn't
actually see what was also going on
behind the scenes so tactics is getting
press releases their facebook likes and
followers are going up they are
increasing local retail sales people are
posting their skateboards and their
tricks internationally they're getting
larger recognition and all of a sudden
they are one of the largest
international distributors for board
sports on the planet I love this model
do I believe that Matt and Bob genuinely
wanted that skatepark built for our
local skaters hell yeah and their
integrity and mission is what allowed
this project to be so successful and so
there are so many different avenues that
we could take when it comes to charity
and I understand deeply that this is a
goal for most of us and it's just a
matter of valuing it and understanding
there is a tremendous ROI to your
business with that I want to introduce
Wendy one of our
founding board members for women leaders
to talk a little bit more about how that
could fit into your marketing strategy
so something with charitable outreach it
comes down to our social responsibility
as businesses in this industry and and
and as any industry really we are here
we are doing good work we're doing
powerful things for ourselves and for
our community and on the other hand what
responsibilities do we have to our
community to our partners to our allies
to give back and to help support them in
the same ways that they ultimately
whether they intended to or not have
supported us to the point where we are
now to be able to do this to operate to
pay taxes and to do it legally without
fear of going to jail we're in this
position now we have the opportunity to
give back and we absolutely should be
based on core values and mission but
also because it does provide a beautiful
opportunity to get good ROI for our
companies and for our businesses and
that can be really valuable in the
greater conversation like Kelly's been
driving towards this whole conversation
is you know thinking about
internationally and thinking about
opening up new channels for later in the
future and it's something that's so
important we really need to dig deep and
get creative because the reality is is
we're still pop farmers and a lot of
people are scared to work with us but we
can overcome that and women leaders in
cannabis absolutely has our very first
charitable goal we wanted to put
together like food baskets for
Thanksgiving and we tried to partner
with food for Lane County and a couple
different other organizations and they
didn't want it they didn't want our
money they didn't want our food because
it came from the women leaders in
cannabis it's like what the fuck
we're here we have food we have money
like people are hungry what's the
problem well we can't say it came from
cannabis because we're a federally
funded organization exactly we offered
that take our name off of it here's a
basket of food if it shows up on your
doorstep are you gonna distribute it mmm
no that's a really hard conflict of
interest okay
we'll find somebody who will forget it
then
and we fought and we looked and we found
people and organizations like who the
autism rocks came to us like we'll take
your money we need help
great let's do it and so start digging
deep and getting creative and finding
these organizations that strategically
align with what you value in your own
ethics and work with them to support the
greater mission and it'll it'll come
about and I think that you know huge
change starts with one small step and it
might be a really rigorous obnoxious
frustrating step but once it starts you
keep going and it's really really
important this is all about mutualism
right so as a group it would be
fantastic to have later discussions to
define our charity scope do we just want
to work with patients year one and do
something that is manageable do we want
to work with established groups like
Hero grown who already have direct
distribution lines set up in place for
CBD so I'm really excited to get
together with anybody who wants to
discuss this further because this is
this is how we make the magic happen
together and I'm so excited to have this
platform to be able to reach everybody
who needs this medicine thank you so
much this is back here shoulder tapping
me and I appreciate it very much
one thing that Erica and I have been
really passionate about over the last
couple years through women leaders is
partnering with an organization called
beyond toxics they have been working so
hard to write some legislation and to
implement Oregon as a non toxic state
they work really heavily with the land
care acts about how to mitigate the use
of toxic pesticides in our city planning
and land care public land care and they
are making waves seriously seriously I
think that's a big part of this mission
this weekend is I think as a group we
really need to promote that kind of
stuff because really like the
origination of us creating this whole
thing was to save the world and to and
to be compassionate
they're farmers and save-the-world so
these types of missions that's where I
personally and us but that's where we
want to put all of our energy behind and
behind the medicine for the people
because really that you'll see us at
Emerald couple have two teepees and
everyone else will have all this you
know vinyl signs and crazy marketing and
stuff but it's just the roots that
really matters to us so this is the
coolest thing as the standards that are
set for care for cannabis are not set
anywhere else yeah and and their whole
thing is it is safer for kids to come
running through our cannabis farms than
it is for their kids to go run through
city parks and it's so true and so we
have a voice now to say that this is
possible organics regenerative practices
are possible in any avenue that we want
them to be and we just need to help
people understand that that's beautiful
and and we're bumping up against so many
hard things all over the place so I
think you know being able to find where
we can move around is just as a better
thing so we're gonna turn it over to Sky
and Sierra and they're gonna talk about
their mission with athletes and what
they're finding and they're touring the
world with athletes and I'm how our
group could maybe help you all hi my
name is sky my partner - Sierra hi and I
mountain-bike all around the world
pacifically downhill I go to New Zealand
and all over the place and find that
within the athlete's world and mountain
biking there's a lot of fun health
there's a lot of people kind of going to
races and have a healthy side to them
and have a good side but there's just a
lot of music communications and what is
actually good and just kind of what you
actually should be taking in with
a lot of health products which are
really unhealthy are in the athlete
market today and all of the nutrition
that put forward by professional
athletes is actually really unhealthy
and we're working towards getting
medicine that can actually help these
athletes in a way that's gonna make them
healthy and able to perform when they
have injuries that need to be competing
the next week rather than taking
something that might sustain them for
that week but they'll be down the next
so we're trying to get something that is
testing across the boards low enough
that athletes don't have to be worried
about coming up hot or having issues
because that's the biggest fear with
cannabis and athletes right now CBD is
something that is not really talked
about within the mountain biking
community it was actually just opened up
by the UCI which is a Federation that is
in France and basically runs all
mountain biking and any biking industry
of any sort they have made THC and CBD
and all these cannabinoids totally
illegal to use by any athletes and it
just makes it a little bit harder to be
able to go around and do your everyday
sport without having the support of the
plants around you even beyond the CBD
side we also want to open up all the
herbs that we have access to and all the
amazing medicinal compounds with those
and just open up a discussion with CBD
and natural resources with that the
earth has to offer us and just kind of
going back in time and going back
hundreds of centuries back to where our
roots have always been to create a
ultimate health because within the
mountain biking and within all these
industries there's a lot of energy
drinks and all that that really don't
give you that good of a feeling I mean
they might give you some energy but
let's be honest it's not a good way to
sustain your athletic abilities yeah
just trying to create a discussion of
health and career
an option and a place for people to come
to to be able to get all the information
that they need and all the products that
they need as well because when it comes
down to it people don't know what to
look for so I also want to say that
athletes always are inspiration to kids
and kids look up to athletes it forever
so it'd be really great if we can have
some health and wellness to help propel
those athletes so that our children who
are in regular school systems can be
seeing that and that's something I'd
really like to see we're working for it
[Applause]
so I think our last speaker for this
session is going to be Zoe again is
going to speak about the CBD new FDA
regulations and claims how to navigate
the market and keep your CBD products on
the market super easy topic to talk
about yeah cool cool I'm gonna start
this whole thing with I'm not a lawyer
so this is not legal advice so that
being said I have read all of the FDA
regulations I testified in front of the
FDA about CBD and cannabis regulation in
May we submitted 300 pages of comments
to the FDA about regulating CBD and
cannabis and then you know two weeks ago
they came out and they said it is
illegal to put CBD in food
you can't label anything any CBD product
as a supplement and they don't think
that it's safe for human or animal
consumption so yeah that's fun yeah so
so enforcement of that is gonna be an
issue I think that that's maybe in all
of our benefits cuz you know this
industry is massive and only going to
get bigger but I
I think it's anyone's guess as to what's
actually gonna happen in in the legal
side of things if the DA decides that
they're gonna go after everyone I mean
like they could are they probably not
I'm not sure I mean like we're in a
moment of deep uncertainty so the
question really is like what do we do
from here and I think the answer is like
as much as it sucks and all of us in
this room don't actually believe that it
will work is reach out to your Congress
people make sure that your legislators
are actually educated about cannabis I
mean like when I was talking to the pack
in Portland that some of my friends are
involved in and I heard what they were
like I can't afford to go to DC you
don't do that whole thing but I heard
what they were talking about when they
went to DC and it was only the banking
act is the only thing they were talking
about to legislators in DC and it's like
that's awesome super important we also
need to be talking about how to put
pressure on the FDA to regulate CBD and
cannabis in a way that makes sense so
one of the things that I did and
actually was talking to Eleanor the
other day which she should probably also
be involved in this conversation was
read all of not all of but a lot of data
and information about how Herbalife sins
are regulated globally and so currently
man how to do this in five minutes the
FDA regulates okay the FDA regulates
food and drugs and those are the two
categories that there are regulatory
structures for so drugs are
pharmaceutical drugs they have like the
whole pharmaceutical process every drug
has to go through clinical trials show
efficacy theoretically and food is its
own category there's all these sort of
safety and quality issues that come up
with food supplements are considered a
subcategory of food and the supplement
industry is deeply problematic in my
opinion the regulations governing
supplements are minimal and I think a
lot of people a lot of like corporate
players
in this scene would love to see cannabis
regulated as a supplement and
unfortunately I like don't agree with
that regulatory structure because I
don't think that they have the
infrastructure to test for purity and
potency and I think that that's like
those are my concerns like when you deal
with patients who need to make sure that
the product that they're taking is
actually the product and not only that
like that they aren't taking pesticides
or heavy metals which cannabis is super
great at like pulling from the soil you
need to actually have a testing
infrastructure which the supplement
industry doesn't formerly have through
the federal government although there
are third-party testing agency is for
the supplement industry so it's it's a
mess I came up with like a theoretical
regulatory structure for the regulation
of traditional herbal medicinal products
which would be another category of
regulation that would ensure purity and
potency like those are just the tests
there are a lot of differing opinions on
how to regulate CBD in cannabis but I
think like as far as you are concerned
trying to educate your regulators on
what it is and what it can do its safety
continuing continuing to provide data to
the people who can make decisions about
some of the things yes some of the
things the FDA has said which is like
it's not safe well okay we've got all
these studies showing that it is safe
here's this and then asking them to like
come out and regulate I mean I think
I've talked a little bit about this
which is like it's possible the FDA is
sort of sidestepping a little bit they
would really love to not have to deal
with this issue because it's a massive
industry and they don't have money and
it's like when I dug into how much what
their budget was to regulate the 32
billion dollar supplement industry last
year it was twenty three million dollars
so like where are they gonna get the
budget to regulate the cannabis industry
so I don't really have their solutions
yet but there's a lot of learning going
on and I think like it isn't
to be familiar with what's going on and
just please please please don't be
afraid of talking to your
representatives and congresspeople
and I know it's a pain in the butt and
it feels like you're not getting
anywhere and like maybe that's true
because we don't really live in a
democracy but like it still worth trying
because that's where we are we still
have the opportunity to do this right
and there's a lot of ways to do it wrong
so my feelings ignore the FDA I mean
they're they're all they did was just
say what they're they didn't change
anything with this statement that not at
all they basically said we're not going
to change and very briefly there are two
ways that you can be sure to run afoul
of the FDA one is to make a specific
disease claim that my preparation can
cure cancer whatever it is you will be
in trouble with them and the other is to
have a misrepresentation of the analysis
of your product if there is not the
amount that's it should be in there or
too much compared to what should be in
there and someone complains you'll be in
trouble
beyond that I don't think they have the
bandwidth to deal with this industry
right now and so it was exactly right
there sidestepping they they don't have
the time money or interest and so it was
a holding action at best but avoid those
two things and hopefully you stay out of
trouble
one of the most important things I
learned was coming into the industry I
was designed to me
and somebody explained the reason why
nobody has ever had at a balloon or
overdose from cannabis and I did I knew
that it was true that I didn't know why
we can can clean up the details of what
I tell you that this is basically true
the reason that people died from drug
overdose usually is because their brains
been shuts down and it makes them stop
baby that makes her heart stopped
beating their brain stopped functioning
and their brain stem is loaded with
opiate receptors or opiate receptors or
whatever they're called there are no
cannabinoid receptors in the brain stem
so no matter how much and nobody ever
has when somebody thinks maybe one
person died it's big news which proves
the point so if you're communicating
with your constituents to your
Congressman whatever Congress person
make sure that you have just enough
facts probably even though things don't
wait instead tell them this is a reason
why no one has ever ever overdosed which
is why the whole approach to regulating
this as a dangerous drug is messed up
from the start you want to clean
what Neil said was exactly right there
are scattered cannabinoid receptors in
the brain stem but not in the center's
that subserve respiration again so as he
said the mule receptor too much heroin
you stop breathing and you die because
of that
it's not because it's actually killing
any organ in the body but it's putting
your brain to sleep and you forget to
breathe and cannabis cannot do that it
just doesn't happen
so that wasn't a lot of cleaning up add
one thing to the list of no nose for the
FDA it is definitely unsubstantiated
medical claims on your packaging is
number one incorrect dosage on a package
but the other one is unsubstantiated
label claims based on ingredient content
that will hit you almost harder than if
you have the wrong amount of milligrams
of whatever it is taraxacum or calendula
like not having the appropriate species
on your label they will ding you for so
that's one thing everyone should start
to keep in mind as things become more
normalized and our products become you
know taken out of the dispensary proper
and maybe are sitting in an apothecary
or a normal drugstore if your label
claims if you say you have lavender in
there you better have lavender in there
and there better not be anything else in
there so those are exceptionally
important to the FDA and zoeng have a
very healthy disagreement about the
regulation of natural products they're
heavily regulated so the the landscape I
work in I consult with a lot of
individuals I am a third-party tester
for botanical identity because if you
don't have those label claims correct my
clients get sued and they get their
products pulled from shelves and it's
hundreds of thousands of dollars of
fixing that issue
and if you really want to say a breast
to the FDA issue one of the best
organizations I would encourage all of
you to at least look at them if not
become an active member is Appa is the
American Herbal Products Association
it's the largest trade association that
is an advocate for natural products
supplements and natural medicines and
they deal not only in the national scale
but the international scale and they're
a really great resource like if you want
digested commentary about what the FDA
is put out with you know what's
happening with the DEA with various
aspects of cannabis and CBD they're an
exceptional resource and they do amazing
advocacy they also have a cannabis
committee which I'm a member of which
everyone should be a part of its an open
committee your opinions are really
important because they really have
access to the government in a way that
most of our small organizations can
never have that kind of access so if
it's office American Herbal Products
Association yeah so they do a lot of
work and they do a lot of work with the
other plants right so when comfrey was
banned basically for use they did a lot
of work so they support us as herbalists
and as community healers and in ways
that are outside the normal work we do
within our own communities and so I
would really encourage you to check them
out one thing just really quickly with
the sky and Sierra didn't say was that
they created the de I'm pure athlete
collective which is new and it is coming
out and just the sky is a professional
mountain biker and yes we do work with a
lot of mountain bikers but it is open to
all
every sport