some of the challenges for growing
plants in space are basically trying to
make them grow in a way that's similar
to what we experienced them growing on
earth with gravity so if you're in space
you have no gravity which means it's not
necessarily the plants that are having
any kind of unusual response to the lack
of gravity it's all the other physical
parameters that the plants require to
grow that you have challenges that you
have to be for example water delivery so
if you don't have gravity water doesn't
stay in the pod it floats around or
water is has a it's a it's stratified
different in the media that the plants
are growing in so on earth where you
have gravity water is added to the top
of the pot it sinks down to the bottom
of the pot due to gravity in space it
doesn't so it it's equally distributed
throughout that media because the media
is holding on to the water the roots can
absorb that water out of the media and
so people some of the early experiments
in growing plants in space we're having
to overcome the challenges of water
delivery over watering the plants
because we're used to giving them a
certain amount of water on earth because
of that stratification of water in the
pot versus in space the water is equally
distributed throughout that media and
therefore you don't have to add as much
water so over watering plants is bad for
the plants and so that was that was one
of the challenges that had to be
overcome but overall the plants it
overcome with yes
by just simply managing watering
protocols water in control but plants
grow well in microgravity because they
orient themselves toward light and so if
you have a light source that's suitable
for growing those plants they orient
themselves toward the light and they
grow similarly to what you'd expect them
to see on earth they're growing towards
the light but interestingly enough roots
are not in the light so if roots are in
the media they don't have any clue or
any environmental clue to grow down so
roots will grow up and out of the soil
because they are sensing gravity as and
not light but at some point once they
start to get air pruned as they
yes they would okay yeah so once they
get out in the air and they're not in a
media a liquid or a liquid or a wet type
of media anymore they would yeah they
would not be happy in this the journey
to let's say a planet like Mars and then
growing plants on Mars would it all be
under lights or with the Sun like is the
Sun to radiation heavy on Mars to be
able to use that in addition to yeah so
like are we gonna have all LED lights on
Mars and that's the only light source
these plants they're gonna have
everything I have sunlight as well so
currently the the types of scenarios for
being on Mars or the moon is to have a
subterranean habitat and a subterranean
area to grow the plants and the reason
for that is the exposure to radiation we
those we are lucky that we have an ozone
layer and an atmosphere that protects us
from you know radiation from the Sun but
if you're on the Moon or Mars you don't
have that protection anymore and so that
that's a very hazardous environment both
for people and materials so if you have
a facility that is exposed to that type
of radiation you can start to have
material breakdown so the the current
types of models are to be subterranean
and have solar collectors that provide
the light and is and is then delivered
into the plant growth area as well as
the human habitat area and eliminating
those types are protecting from
protecting the plants and the people
from that type of radiation what do you
say solar collectors do you mean like
Solar tube type things that are taking
the sunlight letting it come in but
maybe having filters yes okay or
variations of that so it could be it
could be solar tubes it could be solar
light concentrators that have filters on
them that remove the harmful radiation
in that in the radiation band that
they're receiving so that you're only
bringing in the wavelengths of light
that the plants need and you're
eliminating the ones they don't so it'll
be a combination of filtered sunlight
and
Clemenza lighting yes because of the
well certain parts of the
extraterrestrial planets might not have
the same kind of photo periods that we
would experience on earth and so you
would want to be able to provide the
amount of light that the plants need to
grow to support the humans that are
going to be living in that environment
daily challenges you feel like you would
be going through as the guy responsible
for keeping the plants alive for the
population on Mars
I really cannot come up with a good
answer to that question we want to be
that yeah well your trip personally no
but but there but you're gonna have the
same if you're on an if you're on
another planet you're gonna have a lot
of there's a lot of things that you have
in your favor that's similar to earth
like you have gravity again so you're
able to have similar horticultural
protocols to growing plants that you're
using for example is your life-support
system that you'd have on earth but you
would also have to be very cognizant of
the various challenges environmental
challenges that you have under those
conditions as well we mentioned
radiation before so that's that's one of
those challenges things like oxygen and
creating sort of an environment for
plants and people to live in well you
would you would have a you'd have a
closed environment or semi closed
environment with which you would try to
retain as much of those life support
components as possible the oxygen the
carbon dioxide in the water and the
carbon you wouldn't want to lose any of
those things you would want to continue
to recycle and reuse those along the way
are those things things that could be
made by pulling out of the Mars
atmosphere like like is there maybe not
enough to breathe but is there excision
in the atmosphere that you can pull is
there
hydrogen is there yet the atmosphere on
Mars is very thin and so it's not
practical to think you could use that as
a resource but it's not to say it's not
impossible there are other aspects of
extraterrestrial habitations that could
be useful for example there is lunar or
Marcille that could
be used to grow plants and there are
there's research looking into using
those types of media suit to support
plant growth and so they've analyzed the
soil on Mars and they're yeah actually
has everything apply or although there's
lunar and Mars stimulants that have been
developed that they're using to do to do
plant testing to see if they're
compatible with that
you
[Music]