[Music]
foreign
okay perfect so I'm here with Scott wall
and Jenny garley hi from New Age Labs
you came in all the way from Michigan
you're in NorCal in the Salinas area but
you both just presented and I only
caught the end of yours and there are
specific topics that I want to talk
about but can you kind of give like a
recap of the key points you wanted
people to take away for your
presentation sure
um I just went over
Why Stop is op is important how
ever from tissue I broke down the
different components of esophonalysis uh
looked at especially Mobility Trace
elements cations anions the balances
synergism antagonism and then nitrogen
reduction breakdown so somebody can look
at a sap analysis and not just see a
whole bunch of bars but have an
understanding of each nutrient so they
can take it to the next level with God
so if you think of kind of tools in a
toolkit there's like soil samples
there's plant sap analysis there's
tissue analysis and in terms of
like I think a lot of people kind of
want to get a sense of that round trip
of I know it's in my soil I know how
successful my plants are and uptaking
whatever is in there there's enough of
everything
um can you kind of talk about
Eric come here you're going to tap in
for me you ready
so I just started asking the very first
question which was around Jenny's
presentation
oh he was a Clapper of yours I would
have Eric tap in yes yes tap it in
so what did what did you find what were
your takeaways
uh well I'm I'm definitely into
analyzing and lab testing and I find
that a lot of Harms in commercial
cannabis don't test anything for any
amount of whatever they're doing and so
um the explanation of how it's collected
and how the process that you guys use is
really I think informative and important
and I think more people
if they'd understand how easy sometimes
this process is and how valuable it is
they do it more but a lot of people turn
it into a headache and I find a lot of
farms are more pessimistic than they are
optimistics and so they look at ways
that something won't work before they
even try it and so I feel like as a
consultant that's one of the tougher
challenges is to get people to be
optimistic about new things and data and
stuff like that so I mean I think that
was a great aspect of your presentation
yeah absolutely I mean we you know
I mean we're talking about cannabis
today right but
the perfect example like in blueberries
I years ago I had a blueberry grower
come talk to me about the fact that they
were losing 225 thousand dollars a year
in soft fruit
so we put together a plan that would
have cost about fifteen thousand dollars
a year for sap analysis on 11 different
fields that would have been indicators
for them to improve their fruit quality
the response back from that grower was
well that's too expensive so he was
unwilling to pay fifteen thousand
dollars on a plan that would have helped
him remove a loss of a quarter of a
million dollars in Lost Revenue that's
insane and it's like an insurance policy
basically you're buying a fifteen
thousand dollar insurance policy
basically and yep exactly yeah it's
tough and I like to listen into your
presentation as well because you brought
up a couple of key factors and
um it wasn't necessarily on the data
side but uh what I resonated with was
the fact that a lot of things look good
on paper and and it doesn't do out
on the farm you get out there and
nothing works right workflow whatever it
is it's just not right and it looks
great on paper and that really is a
testament to the wrong people designing
and dealing with these facilities they
weren't farmers in the first place maybe
Real Estate Investors they can raise
money but putting together a harm is
really out of everybody's league and we
see it I think at the end yeah it bites
them in the ass a little bit well you
know the the thing was it you know
put the Legacy grow
you know away we we knew what we were
doing in Legacy but when we went to
legalize cannabis
there are a whole lot of people that
jumped into industry state by state
every time it phased in a whole new
group of people jumped into the industry
Builders HVAC people you name it and
they're it there's a lot of predatory
behaviors in all those Industries
and so you see grows you see amendments
you see HVAC you see irrigation
that
that might have been fine for the
industry that that person was associated
with
but and it may maybe it made sense on
paper and the investor or the the person
that had the money said
okay I'll buy that
it makes sense but it doesn't make sense
when in practicality 100 can you give a
green
HVAC like a traditional HVAC system with
chillers and Air Handlers going into a
greenhouse which typically isn't part of
greenhouse technology and traditional AG
you know there's wet walls there's you
know passive or natural ventilation and
that's pretty much it there's not HVAC
because tomatoes aren't worth that much
money they're they're a great crop but
they're not worth as much as cannabis
and so cannabis went into this area of
more is more you know like here at these
conferences and what we're all talking
about in some cases is less is more but
the industry started taking them more as
more approach and so with controlled
environment agriculture it was like well
I want more control so we're putting
more equipment in it but the equipment
suppliers never done the math on
something like that because there's no
calculations for HVAC with something
that has solar gain so we're seeing
equipment that's underpowered
relationships are broken because the
people that bought the stuff are pissed
at the people supplying it but the
people supplying it are like hey we've
never done that before so we have a
vicious cycle of everybody wanting to
help each other but they're doing it out
of a pretense of of maybe trying to you
know set new standards set new records
make a name for themselves or just make
a bunch of money real quick go in for
the kill and then come out of it going
oops we up or maybe that wasn't
such a good idea exactly and the problem
is every time we legalize in a new state
the the price per pound the price point
is huge so business plans are based on
these really big price point so
everything works you can you can afford
anything
and so you design these things then they
don't work the IPM is terrible now
you're getting powdery mildew occurring
every time you can't control the
humidity
the investors now the price point starts
going down because more and more people
are getting into it
you're not harvesting what you thought
you were going to harvest you're not
getting the price that you thought you
were going to get you're having to buy
more technology to treat for mediocre
cannabis really
and
now the business plan doesn't work and
the investors are getting pissed off now
they're firing management and it's a and
now you're getting this cycle that is
just it it feeds on itself it's like
cannibalism and those facilities
are I think are just doomed for failure
you know
um I think the the new states that are
coming on board need to really be
examining what's going on in the other
states and say okay look we know we're
going to get to a point where our price
point is going to be
eight hundred dollars a pound
make your business plan based on that
figure out what you're how you're going
to get return on investment based on
that
and and look at the failures in those
other states and plan accordingly don't
plan on
and if you're making if you're selling
at twenty five hundred dollars a pound
Great take that money and Bank it don't
go buy new Escalades and everything else
you know
Bank it because you're going to need it
someday get your Sops right and and
stick to it
um
don't blame everything on the guys that
are on the
rolls downhill right well don't
always blame the guy below because a lot
of the times the problems occur at the
top of the hill it's the manager it's
the guy that doesn't know a thing about
grow but he's the one who putting the
money in and they come in and they make
a lot of changes sometimes they don't
know a thing about what they're doing
well I think what happens too is
originally they start out like you said
and then they hire a bunch of people
that blew a lot of smoke up their ass
because they can talk a bunch of
cannabis talk and all that talk but
really don't have the experience maybe
the book book experienced and trained
really well and they can recite a lot of
you mean the major Growers yeah
we were talking about LinkedIn last
night and there was somebody in in the
comments and they said something about a
master grower and I said oh that's kind
of made a joke in the comments back I
was like Master grower LOL or whatever
and the dude was like well maybe the
terminology is different out there in
California but we grow the best pot here
in Colorado and you know by Master
Growers or whatever and I was like man
okay
um
enjoy the little bubble you live in but
nevertheless what ends up happening
though is upper management feels like
they have to take over and make all
these decisions and so a lot of times
what we're seeing also is that the
beginning of everything failed because
they didn't vet the people right and
they didn't know how in the first place
you know a lot of these people made
their money in real estate and other
businesses and they were like okay now
we're going to ship to cannabis and
everything really falls apart and it's
you know number one because they didn't
know how to vet people and then number
two they try to take control of the
situation because originally they are
the smarter people of the group and then
they compound it with making terrible
decisions right right based on what they
learned on Instagram or something well
and I think that's that's exactly it you
know we're in we're in an industry right
now that is
trying to produce a lot of cannabis
and it should be our goal is to produce
exceptional cannabis at the lowest at
the lowest cost per pound so that we
make a good margin
but it's exceptional and I think what
we're actually doing is producing a lot
of mediocre cannabis oh yeah and it's
not always at at a good margin no no and
I think in California I hate to say it
because this is where I'm from and I
love California Cannabis it's like you
know that's where my heart is but
unfortunately it's getting a little
boofier midsy out here because the price
of cannabis and the way that the
legalization has turned people have to
grow cheaper and cheaper which has
caused a big learning curve you know
switching the regenerative AG is a great
idea and living soil and all these
things but it does come with a little
bit of a learning curve people that
maybe were regenerative AG or maybe just
organic let's say not necessarily
regenerative and living soil but they
switch to cocoa and salts a little bit
of a learning curve Legacy Growers up
north that really always Grew From seed
never had a problem nobody wants those
strains it's based on a hype strain they
go and buy a bunch of clones nobody's
really grown clones before and
understand the sensitivity that for you
know as so there's a learning curve
there and so you know this last year was
the year of we can't anything up
everything's got to go perfectly and it
was actually the year of tons of
ups and so it was a really unfortunate
disastrous year for a lot of the
learning curve Farms I guess you could
say in some of those categories and in
other areas it was a great year because
we had such a long warm summer we didn't
have the early rain so a lot of The
Growers were able to get a great crop in
but like I said in between all that were
a bunch of learning curves and stumbling
blocks and so it's really great to have
this event again because some of the
other
conferences you know aren't happening
anymore what I find is that the trade
shows used to be centered around the
Growers back in the days max yield and
some of those things and now it's all
shifted towards the investment and upper
management and these kind of flashy
showy things like MJ bizcon and so to be
able to have this and you know speak to
the farmers and engage is really great
because you can only do that and January
and February also otherwise everybody's
busy yeah and nobody's really thirsting
for info because they're in the trenches
well and I think that's what we're you
know when when I'm talking with grows
and typically a lot of times when when
they ask us to come in
to start with sap analysis usually
they've got a problem to start with
nobody usually starts with sap analysis
when everything's going right sure we do
not get called
I'm just gonna throw this in right right
but you know the the thought is okay
we're gonna fix everything all at one
time and that's it's never that's never
a good science as a as a numbers nerd
that you've got to first convince them
look
I see what you've got
now I want you to make two lists make a
list of all the problems you you
perceive in your growth all right then
make a list of all your strains and list
them in priority if you fix this strain
first it would make the biggest
difference in your bottom line and down
to the to the lowest strain that you
give the the least about yep now
would take those two and we make a
matrix and we say okay we're going to
work on these two strains first and
these are the two issues we want to
tackle first
and we focus on changing one parameter
at a time yeah yeah that's science
that's good science yeah yeah and now we
can work on that and so you don't want
to be changing a whole lot of different
things at once the guy that wants to
change seed and HVAC and this and that
it's too much never figured out yeah can
you give it
anything to see kind of the effects oh
sure
um
irrigate yes very irrigation absolutely
I think irrigation is perfect if you're
if you have a automated irrigation
system depending on your dry vac okay if
you if you allow too much dry vac and
you're counting on good microbial growth
you drive back too much you're you're
allowing the microbes to die off
well you're defeating your point so if
you if you don't irrigate properly the
microbes die back but you're counting on
the microbes to facilitate uh phosphorus
mineralization in the in the rise of
Fear
well you could have all the phosphorus
you want available in that root Zone but
your uptake with sap indicates that you
have a deficiency and uptake so now that
one management
practice
is affecting the uptake that you want in
your finished product and
the fact that you have a deficiency in
the phosphorus uptake is opening up the
door for other problems like maybe the
plant's known to take up more chloride
and now you you create an imbalance you
didn't want the chloride but now the
chloride is so high that even if you fix
the irrigation problem there's so much
chloride in the in that one grow of 200
strain of 200 plants in that constraint
you've got to now fix the fact that
you've got so much chloride uptake so
you've created a problem that created
another problem that you if you even fix
it's a domino effect exactly with the
solution to the first problem you
basically more frequent small like
smaller waterings with more frequency
like what would be the solution to that
dryback period that's killing too much
it might be more frequent smaller
waterings which but
it would be inappropriate for me to ever
say this is the solution to that one
problem in general for all grows
there are 250 different grow operations
here everybody is doing it a little bit
differently and until
if somebody calls and says uh you look
we just did this sap analysis and I and
we and I'd say yeah you've got this
problem in this problem
and they say okay so what do I do I
don't know because I don't know your bro
I don't know what you're doing so until
I come and visit or we have a in-depth
conversation about what's your
management practices are and you have to
be a hundred percent honest with me
I can't give you any advice and I won't
I won't even try to give you advice to
say hey this is I think something that
we need to look at but we're only going
to work at one parameter at a time and
then then we'll do more and you're going
to give me speed honestly yeah yeah you
know that's that's where I get in
trouble yeah with complete honesty
because there are things that I don't
agree with in the Cannabis industry but
Bro Science says this is what you do
Association
okay
so yeah you see you're just gonna you're
just trying to get 50 of the P or 75 of
the people out there to hate me
this is come on so
so our industry as a whole
has come to the understanding that we
need to defoliate
and we defoliate hard particularly in in
controlled environmental agriculture so
in our indoor Grows Where basically our
HVAC systems cannot handle humidity
so the engineering is bad
it's not the plant that's bad it's not
the IPM that's bad it's the engineering
that's bad
we at three weeks and probably at 40 at
21 days and at 42 days we go in and we
we
call it training and we call it
defoliating and we pull all these leaves
off well
we would take out lateral branches
we're taking out
a
the the factories of the plant okay
those leaves are the only place that
that the plant can produce organic
molecules but the very thing that we're
trying to produce so sugars uh terpenes
THC
enzymatics proteins all these things can
produce in the leaves
there also are solar cells that collect
the energy that we're paying electricity
for
and so you know
we go in and we take them all out well
we spent money on energy and amendments
and everything to grow that leaf and
that leaf is holding mobile nutrients so
we strip it away we throw away money
we throw away the factories that are
going to produce make that plant
healthier and stronger and more terpes
and more THC more Bud more Bud swell
because it all has to come from the
factories
so I tell the Growers stop defoliating
not entirely just enough to maintain
good IPM
um
can you talk about your example of the
lower leaves that they only get 200 sure
yeah
but first I want to say what a mobile
nutrient is so when you're throwing away
those older leaves and Scott said
throwing away mobiles your mobile
nutrients is nkk magnesium and sulfur so
those if you're paying money to put
those in the leaves when you defoliate
you're also throwing them away so that's
immobile yeah calcium immobile right yes
where Calcium deficiency is seen at the
top of the leaf as where mobile nutrient
deficiencies are seen at the bottom of
the plant so you know
so many Growers when I go through and I
do a tour then I usually have like four
or five people and there's there's
Junior Growers and there's there's the
head cultivator and they say well
shouldn't I shouldn't I clean out these
leaves on the inside because it's
causing shadowing and so on and so forth
and and I've measured I've measured
light absorption in the inside and it's
only 200 you know Photon flux units in
the inside
and they're like no why well it's only
200 and up here at the top it's 800 or a
thousand I said yeah but if you take
that out that's 200 that you don't
capture ever
and it just goes to nothing you're
paying for it capture it that leaf is
gonna get that 200 and turn it into
something
um you know that's why we put the mylar
down
I mean an oak tree or you know a plant
growing out in the in a forest doesn't
just drop all the leaves on the inside
of its canopy it it keeps every leak so
long as it's got nutrients it keeps that
leaf because every little bit of UV
energy that it can collect goes towards
its production of sugars and metabolites
so as long as it's green don't start
pulling it up totally agree if it's and
then if it's starting to finesse and
it's at the bottom
and you if if it's there and you see
this in essence that's the language of
that plant telling you we're losing
we're stripping nutrients out of that
leaf you've got a deficiency problem if
you strip those leaves out before that
happens you're losing some some
communication with that plant so there's
there's no sense in it that's awesome I
love hearing all that stuff because yeah
more more it's so interesting because I
in My Bro Science head I always think
that that's a natural function of like
lower the feeds yellow and that's
natural but you're saying that it
doesn't always happen you know no it
doesn't a a a a healthy plant doesn't
have to get rid of lower leaves just
because they're older leaves it gets
right now because UV UV light light
particles don't behave the way we think
just because it's in Shadow doesn't mean
it's not getting light it just means
it's getting less UV but absorbing any
UV I mean when we talk about like the
Spectra on these lights they go from 300
to 800 you know that big broad Spectra
we want to collect as much of it as
possible it's bouncing around let's get
it you know let's pick up as much as
possible
um and you know people say well that
least caused taking more energy
is taking energy away from the top spot
no it's not that leaf already was grown
it's been produced it's collecting
energy it's doing something it's feeding
that bud if it's it when it starts dying
out the plants actually taking nutrients
away from it and taking it to the to the
butter to that new growth point then you
know that you don't need that leaf
anymore but you're also figuring out
that you've got some other issues going
on but we take all those we take all
that stuff away and at 42 days
when we're really in the home stretch
and we should be looking at nutrient
uptake we strip so many leaves away it's
almost impossible to figure out what our
nutrient uptake is yeah and and you're
you're cool with training oh yeah I
totally agree with training I think I
think there's some cool things I mean
I've seen cannabis bonsai trees and I
think I think they're fantastic I think
there's a ton of stuff we can do with
with training to open up light paths to
the center of a tree the question is can
we afford the labor to do it you know in
my laboratory
the the biggest cost in my facility is
labor 50 of my cost comes from labor
well when we're trying to struggle for
cost return on investment and cost or
price per pound
these guys you know facilities that have
8 10 people in a in a section working
two days a week pulling leaves off of
plants
um that to me looks like a labor saving
someplace let's minimize some of that
cost right there
um and if we if we've got a IPM issue
let's figure out what the real cause of
that is you know if it's if it's a
fungal issue if it's a yeast and mold
issue
figure out your vectors of how that's
getting into the facility you know we
build these fancy
super elaborate controlled environmental
agriculture facilities
you know we put on Scrubs we put on you
know if I go visit they make me put on
Tyvek right
and I go through an air booth and I put
on booties and I walk in and
I see Growers handling plants without
gloves on
and we talk about swabbing and we talk
about all these things and I'm like
you know you worry about protritis I
don't see anybody here with a face mask
on arthritis is is on your skin and so
on and so forth you want to get these
things out figure out what your vectors
are for these things that get into your
get in you know if you were a food
processing facility
as a food a food safety consultant I
want to see your food safety plans I
want I want you to know what your your
traffic patterns are
um if you're a CAA you've got a loading
dock because you're receiving materials
well sometimes that those materials need
to go into your grow facility do you
have two different pallet jacks one for
your Dock and one and a clean one that
only goes into your grow because if the
one from your dock that went on the
truck and trucks are dirty also goes
down the hallway to your in your grow
your flower roast you're just that's a
vector that that brings in pathogens
because that truck went to other farms
and that means that other Farms
pallet jack went on that truck
so you want to look for vectors for or
tritus and hop latent virus and
um
well the stripping is a huge hop late
and viroid you know spreader event
basically because you have all these
people in there stripping all these
leaves getting all this all over
yeah and they don't change their gloves
honestly I watch people I'll sit there
and audit some of these processes and
then
it's break time okay everybody's
touching the door handles everybody's
touching everything and a lot of the
workers it's amazing how they want to
save gloves or protect you know like
they're going to save the farm a couple
bucks by reusing the gloves or putting
them and so uh going from strain to
strain same pluckings a lot of what you
were saying also about having too many
strains in one room because they don't
all eat and drink the same and a lot of
the Farms try to claim that they're data
driven but they're not because they're
growing all the same strains they don't
know what eats and drinks differently
right they're not doing any of the
testing that you guys provide or any of
that kind of stuff the only data driven
I find is that they're monitoring their
dry back so they're not even doing that
right and so like to your point you know
the dry backs are this big
you know uh achievement to try to get to
which is a lack of moisture in the long
run so it's a lack of
Mobility for nutrients in a lot of ways
and so like you were saying for the
first steps of things I'm kind of in the
same boat so if the plants aren't
looking good let's make sure the
irrigation is right and they're hydrated
yep and then secondly then we can start
to look at okay if the hydration is
right and we don't see a change for the
better or things are still continuing we
move on to maybe the nutrients and
definitely sending things in for testing
but
again a lot of people will be
pessimistic and say the testing or not
know how to look at the testing because
of the closest lab that doesn't really
give you any kind of results that no
anybody knows how to decipher
um and so then that gets thrown out the
window and and it really gets tough and
the stripping of the plants is has
gotten crazy like I don't I don't know
if it's Instagram or what's caused
everybody to go to this crazy amount of
stripping but it's happened to be from
here to the East Coast with Farms that
you know will even say at times what we
have to do it or the plants will get key
in but I look at the plants and they're
covered in pm at Lake flower and I'm
like how do you how does that hold up
like how can that you know reasoning
stand hold water if your plants already
have PM so like stripping them down and
releasing of the solar panels is what I
call them the factories those solar
panels like they're gone and so once
they're gone it takes a week or two to
regenerate and to come back and so our
veg times turn into three to four weeks
rather than two
um and everybody who kind of wonders why
things are slow or why the diseases or
problems happen and and I'm just floored
at how many people plus and then when we
get into the nursery they're cutting off
all the money like the money is in the
branches and Bud sites and there is time
to cut that stuff off later if you go
into the nursery in veg and start
cleaning things up so to speak and
skirting and all this you've
cut away all kinds of money and if you
end up having the stretch go on you
yourself even more and there's plenty of
time to determine that in my opinion
sure cleaning some things up is is fine
and it's an okay thing to do but how
soon do you do it before you know you
have viable options and a lot of the
Growers are getting beat down by upper
management for hitting a certain grams
per square foot well are you going to
hit that number if you're in there
cleaning up all the time and
cutting things away and do you value
your job if it was me I wouldn't kill
any plants because of pests or pathogens
I wouldn't strip hardly off unless
I really knew that it was a something
that wasn't going to make anything yep
because you got to hit some numbers and
then if an upper management comes to you
later and you're hitting your numbers
and they're concerned about A to B ratio
that's another thing to look at but
right now everybody's concerned about
hitting these numbers and that's it so
if if that's what the case is then why
is the strip so important and you know
do we not realize the health of the
plant is compromised with the
cross-section of pathogen or viral
spread that goes on it's just like two
wrongs don't make it right well and I
think that that's
we have such a big information
Highway
and where the information comes from
if you're looking at a scientific paper
you always have to look at who paid for
the research right yeah well Instagram
and Linkedin and all these we never look
at
who's giving the message and why why is
that message coming from that person
who's behind the message but they're
popular well exactly well
IPM
when you pay for xeritol or whatever
there's a there's money behind all these
things I'm not I'm not here to bad-mouth
products but there's a reason why some
of these things get used more and more
and more because there's there's a
conversation behind using it to control
something but the fact is a truly
healthy plan a plant that's functioning
at photosynthetic levels that are really
maximized
it can protect itself from a lot of
stuff
and
instead of focusing on making truly for
healthy and plants that can protect
themselves we focus on
products that we have to buy to apply to
the plant
to save it from the fact that it's not
healthy and it's being predated on by a
fungus or a parasite or a thyroid or an
actual pest aphids or yeah thrips or
something along those lines you know
well and then in the grow right now
everybody's trying to avoid these
post-harvest aspergillus fails so
they're going in and spraying things at
Harvest to avoid what might happen later
based in the trim room or the why do
they typically spray well when he
brought up xeritol that's a popular one
to spray the day of harvest I've seen
people spray the day before up until the
day of harvest where they're harvesting
plants and they're dripping wet with
zero tall as they're hanging them on
carts to go out and to be honest with
you like we talk and you're mentioning
all this you know effort money and hard
work that goes into these plants and the
compromising that occurs and we all hear
about that through drying and curing you
know hey you over dried your weeds so
you lose a lot of the Terps you know
that was like a rookie up back in
the day but now we're into this level of
okay risk management says to do this
with this really oxidizing type of uh of
a product and it's not that I'm against
zero tall and the makers of it and the
product but the process and where we've
gotten to to spray it on the day of
harvest it rips the Terps right it's the
terp burglar it's like the biggest say
bye to your Terps before you even dry it
like it doesn't matter the Terps are
gone and a lot of people are trying to
go by this new Edge education of
terpenes are cooler than THC and all
this other stuff but at the same time
the degradation from the time that they
cut those plants by some of these
practices of risk management for
post-harvest fails or whatever it is has
really you know like I mean it's another
damaging factor to Quality cannabis well
you know it's like when in my talk where
I said you know an ounce of an ounce of
prevention is worth a pound of cure so
when we're talking about aspergillus or
whether we're talking about heavy metal
uptake
figure out what your what is that Vector
how is how is that
aspect that's negating the quality of
your cannabis getting into your product
it doesn't just it doesn't just
magically appear the the Cannabis itself
didn't
magically make that it had it had to get
transported into there there's a vector
there
figure out the vectors invest the time
in figuring out how these things get
there and then focus on trying to
prevent that rather than trying to
always treat the the the symptom or the
yeah the illness fix the fix the cause
well that's almost like the health
industry you know what I mean it's like
here's all these products to Band-Aid
your cannabis to a harvest otherwise you
know don't worry about it you know we
got something for you where right
something like what we're doing here and
what you guys are up to is to help
prevent that to see ahead and to create
a healthy system that can fight these
things off naturally so that we use less
of those products just quickly my last
question before I let you guys go is
around you had mentioned different Cults
of ours and kind of what you notice and
what they uptake at different stages of
the plant is
all right so can you touch on some of
that what you notice from the sure
so
with sap analysis
um in our databases and just the history
of what we've been doing
the the Cannabis industry gives us the
most unique look at the plant
nutrient uptake
and particularly
controlled environmental agriculture in
cannabis is the one that has has opened
the door and given us the biggest
Epiphany moments the AHA moments because
the Cannabis industry with CI cea
has tried to grow multiple strains in
the same flower room
with the same feed with the same
environment so we have a lot of
controlled parameters but multiple
strains so when we see this we can we
take a look and we say wait a minute
that Wedding Crasher
in the trop cookie and that Rose
under the same conditions with the same
feed are feeding totally different
they're taking up nutrients differently
so where this one is a heavy feeder crop
cookies a heavy heavy feeder it's taking
up a lot of phosphorus and look at early
on it takes up so much phosphorus that
it stretches it gets huge inner nose and
it'll be a six foot seven foot plant if
you don't hold back the Foss early
Wedding Crasher in that same room on
that same feed if you push it where the
chop cooking will take the 2-5 EC
Wedding Crasher will burn it cannot
handle that and it'll go way excessive
and it'll accumulate and burn
and then the rose it might be somewhere
in the middle but that controlled
environmental agriculture has given us
such a huge window into how varietal
differences appear and and then you can
take that same thing out to outdoor the
difficulty there being is that in a 40
acre field you might have a huge variety
of soil conditions across a Four Acre
field but you got to know that okay you
can't you can't feed it all the same
you've got to be aware that they're
going to feed differently across that
field and that's why everybody's so
screwed up a little bit I guess you
could say with trying to grow so many
cultivars in the same room to try to
keep the menu diverse to make the sales
people happy and all these other things
and so that's why I try to put it upon
these Farms to really try to figure that
out separate those things because what
we're trying to also create is the best
outcome like you can't create a great
outcome if you're doing all this
and especially not analyzing it and so
how do you create the best outcome well
obviously with the best healthiest moms
you know the same strain in the same
room so that you can feed it and and
irrigate it to the best of its potential
and you can't sit there and go oh well
aphids Love The Wedding Crasher but they
don't like the chop cookies yeah I mean
it's like hello well yeah one doesn't
take the nutrients is you know or isn't
as healthy as the other yeah and they're
they're feeding on the one that's the
weak sister yeah exactly stop analysis
can all and I I see this in crops I work
with all crops is that sap analysis can
show you which varieties you can grow
together which varieties yeah yeah you
can set up rooms with similar feeders
yeah yeah yeah same with other crops
um very similar so you're not doing 20
different feeding regimes which is
almost impossibly you can cut back on
work you can cut back on man hours yeah
yeah you need to grow similar varieties
together at least understand
the similarities I think that's so big
like it's bigger than most people really
realize and I think it's taken for
granted especially by the grows clearly
because that's all I see is too many in
one room it's like how can we calm that
down a little bit so that we can create
a better outcome like I mean God dang it
I don't know how it's it's glaring in my
eyes but they're the ones running the
show so well I think you know and that
can go all the way back to some of the
engineering and the design some of the
facilities were designed with flower
rooms that are so large
that you can't limit the number of
strains in that room because it's hard
there's nobody engineering yeah you
don't have enough moms the nurseries
don't hit that kind of numbers and so to
your point is that taking that data
aggregating it so that you can figure
out which ones go best together most
people just go oh this one harvests
around the same time as yep that one so
we put those together that's exactly it
if you if you can figure out which ones
feed similarly that's great but if this
one if this one ripens at 60 five days
and the other one ripens at at 75 days
now you're you're still stuck
because what happens is management says
look we got to find a we got you we're
either gonna find the medium medium yeah
and neither one of them is being
harvested at its perfect spot yeah so
we're instead of creating it instead of
harvesting exceptional cannabis we're
kind of making and you know we're making
that mediocre yeah yep 100 right on but
I think that's you know we we can take
this to another level and I'm not saying
you know I'm not saying use our sap data
I'm not saying use this product don't
use that product
refine your policy your products get
your program in place follow your Sops
use data there's no reason for us to be
cultivating in the dark it's the dark
that we're in the Dark Ages we shouldn't
be everywhere I go there's no reason to
be in the dark yeah yeah that's awesome
well thanks it's uh great being here at
the soil I've sentiment talking with you
guys and uh yeah
see you next time
[Music]
foreign