[Music]
I've experienced better yields and
production capabilities consistency with
pots in greenhouses versus beds run
couple acres of each for a couple years
see and that's the stress of the
environment of a pot but beds for me
being a soil producer and a soil guy
produces super soil called big roots big
roots is all tested a non GMO pesticide
free there's no contaminants tested for
heavy metals things that the industry
aren't even isn't even talking about yet
but for me a super soil is a product
that you can plant you can get your life
out of it you can you add your
beneficials and add more biologics to
the soil which actually eat up the
minerals you know digest any kind of
pumice stone that's in my mixes you know
all that stuff it's eating it's eating
and producing its own environment so
once you create in me this is my opinion
on beds versus pots in a greenhouse beds
once you start creating that living soil
out of a first-year soil and you have a
right medium to actually put down in in
you have to add less and less and you
create more of an beneficial environment
which produces a lot better plus I
really believe in the communication of a
plant I know that communications through
terpenes are benefi beneficials microbes
they communicate through terpenes
terpenes through pheromones right
through the sense same with the roots so
the roots are actually talking to each
other when you have one plant yeah when
you have one plant going and what in
roots are going past they can they might
not be able to find what they need in
that pot at that time but when their
roots are three feet away in a plants
you know
even that big but the roots are even
bigger than that plan they're searching
for their needs and they have a
free-flowing method that they can
produce their own environment and to get
the same results so when you're saying
and I agree with you we're all in this
together so I'm not a hundred experience
the difference
then what your experience which is cool
because we are different cats on the
same dream hammering it down the only
thing I don't like about beds in a
greenhouse or even with pots in a
greenhouse is in the wintertime on my
last run going from the late winter into
early spring I always like to bring pots
in and put pallets or something over the
top of the beds to keep that root zone
off the ground because when the soil
conditions drop below it's pulling that
that coldness the roots won't grow if
they're not in the right kind of
temperature naturally and that's where
rolling beds come through rolling tables
you eliminate walkways yeah and I just
find that your production per square
foot goes dramatically up with the pots
rolling beds and agree I totally agree
with you you know it's a it's a hard one
[Music]
so what this is what I've learned in the
last few years and I do a lot of in
Saudia we do greenhouse drones so we're
a couple we're a couple homies handling
business right in a greenhouse in
greenhouse environment what was I gonna
say oh so what I've learned instead of
doing less numbers in pots when even on
my indoor environment I do less or twice
the amount of numbers half the amount of
veg time and I flip like into my
greenhouses I put my plants in right and
I flip within 10 days immediately
flipped I produce smaller plants more
yields more consistency and my weights
my yields everything the time like
instead of doing three runs possibly
hard to do three runs in a greenhouse in
a season I can hammer out even easy for
because
my flipping time is now you know gone up
a lot like I'm using a lot less time to
produce more yields I don't deny the
microbe factor and here's where it there
is a moral it's more
maybe it's an ethical dilemma I'm not
100% sure I've always been an organic
guy and I've liked organics I have found
that the UI could get higher yields with
using the salt fertilizers and all this
and to me a plant doesn't really care
whether it's organic food or non-organic
food I got a different and so will what
where is that where is the difference
can you show that your animal test I
could show it in your terpene test and I
can show you that but enjoy being tested
I've done essential oils for a long time
for my whole life I teach at this school
in Santa Cruz de brillo college in
California and sit down anyways but I've
had access to this GCMs machine and I've
seen multiple years of data that
correlates an organic crop a
conventional crop and a hand-picked crop
and this is all not cannabis but
consistently throughout the years the
conventional farms have put out a more
diverse terpene profile than the organic
farms and mainly I think because the
deliverance of nutrients and as great as
the microbe web can be it's not always
giving the plant what it wants every
moment of
and when conventional you can do that
you're basically just giving them little
and and and the ethical dilemma
generally face would be is
denitrification in the soil etc etc you
know water pollution run offs but when
you can mitigate those situations with
runoff trays into recollecting and just
kind of I mean that is a responsible
part of the ethical punch but there's no
ethical backing in conventional farming
in my eyes it's just it's well just in
those to me where the dilemma lies if
you are producing something that gives
good run off clean runoff then you
should be runned off that's it but
generally there's low runoff you don't
necessarily need a high runoff you don't
but in conventional farming you're
utilizing if not double even more times
the amount of water on our drain to
waste
scenario I haven't necessarily found
that to be the 100 I need to get you
some big roots oil I really do and we're
just moments away from each other so I'm
gonna hook you up
and I want you to hi it's anyways I
think the data to me that I've what I've
seen yeah the college has been that the
conventional farms did actually put out
a better terpene profile yeah I'm not
saying I know but I would love to sit
down with you now that is hard for me
because I would like to say oh sure the
organic is better yeah you know I'm here
to say the organic is better the organic
is better I'm here saying that I'm not
yeah yeah I know he's not denied but I
I'm just playing the devil's advocate a
little bit because I what I have seen is
higher yields and and so now if I have
employees coming in every day and my
greenhouse is using a certain amount and
I'm running heaters and I'm doing all
this stuff employees are coming every
day and so there is a you know
sustainability kind of like what about
the living organism the beneficials that
are that are destroyed by conventional
farming 'sm let's just talk about a
plant welfare okay let's talk about
plant welfare one this is a beta test I
did on a hundred plant outdoor with
conventional and a hundred plant with my
organics this is a what a story I tell
all the time is I this was about ten
years ago nine years ago I did two
plants studies and and I always believed
organics and I was pushing it back then
you can probably verify though than
Santa Cruz not many people were pushing
any organic movement is Santa Cruz but
not many people back then were really
buying into it and I was ninety percent
sure I was on the right path then all of
a sudden I wanted to prove it to myself
because I'm a high drama store owner
your garden center I'm calling hydro I'm
a garden soil King garden center same
thing and on those two patches that
Krulak I grew conventional farming and
then organic farming at first going into
about July this conventional plants were
bigger they're about 20% bigger than my
organics and I started telling myself
maybe I'm fucking wrong maybe I missed
this boat maybe I'm selling me a ticket
that I can't buy into anymore what I
found out is that it started getting an
end of July into August and I'm having
root problems I'm having diseases root
I'm having plant diseases the winds are
coming these plants are falling over I'm
staking the hell out of it there's
spindle e same genetics as this one
these ones are steady the race steady
the race right harvest comes probably
lost you know good 10% of these plants
these plants are still running the gamut
running stone this finishes ape quality
this finished @cb at best
I got about we've figured out 17% more
yield on the organic than we ever did on
a conventional farming and the product
was sought after more Powder Mill do
everything and what I
I've come to realize is that your plant
needs its own biological system it needs
its own system to ward off and fight
diseases to pests
everything that's going on it and when
you eliminate that structure starting
with a healthy soil you eliminate the
plant putting off its own pheromones for
when certain bugs come an attack on the
out on the outdoor not so much into work
as a controlled environment you know and
you start you start messing with its own
and natural environment then all of a
sudden you run into more issues diseases
different problems coming on right and I
think you can also keep a plant happy in
many different ways yes it's a good
point you know love it's more like yeah
the organic and for long season you have
a bigger buffer because you're slowly
breaking down all these nutrients and
you're creating the life for all the
microbes and I almost think it's almost
more challenging you're mixing more
we're manipulating it instead of letting
it's biology biology manipulate it right
when a plant needs something that goes
to talk to the biology I need this what
it can't really the communication
between us and that plan on the
conventional is of different aspects you
really got to be on your game you do
yeah it's awesome man awesome give me a
hug
you
[Music]