okay gemma what are we looking at right
now a praying mantis
nice straight up
all right gemma bring the bug here give
me the top
all right come over here all right
we pulled a bug off the uh okay here
give it to me
give it to me i gotta get it get it
watch that's upside down
i know so watch here's the praying
mantis
oh damn
what if it doesn't need
hey the mantis just took it
isn't that awesome yeah is he eating it
he sure is
he's not like yummy and delicious
no i would not eat it you wouldn't
the mantis likes it look at that
it's now it's the domesticated mantis is
just going to expect us to hand feed it
every day
can you do it a little bit more yeah why
it can only eat one thing at a time
can we give it another one no baby look
at you you just want to
feed the mantis bugs huh okay so look at
that that is a good
it doesn't even care that we're here
isn't that cool
yeah like look how big that mantis is
and it's totally eating
this bug that wants to eat our plants
right
and do we like bugs that eat our plants
no not so much
we don't dislike them but not we like we
don't mind them when they're just a
couple of them
but when they bring all their friends to
the plant
but yeah that is