[Music]
today my senior talk there was a point
where you started to introduce pricing
as a new component to this data set what
what are the prospects of outlooks for
data in that space you're a chemist
you're back have you done anything with
financial time series regressions I have
not so financial time series regression
in a basic linear regression we say that
a conditioned variable is you know the
dependent variable is conditioned on the
independent variable and there's some
usually linear coefficient if you think
about how they would work with a
financial time series what you'd be
saying is that the price is equal to
some coefficient times time that means
the price would be a straight line going
some way up hopefully maybe down who
knows that's obviously not our prices
work in the real world a slightly more
complex model is called an auto
regressive model where what we say is
that the price at time T is conditioned
on the price at times t minus 1 times
some coefficient plus some random
distribution so it's linear over a short
time frames well what we'd say is that
it's a random walk that what's that
what's where the randomness is in the
rand is in the movement from yesterday's
price we're not there yet
we're only at a r1 we're not we're not
close to where we're going so at a r1
we say that the randomness is in the
price movement from one day to the next
and we say that those price movements
are drawn from a common shared
distribution but that's not really how
pricing works either because as we saw
in the financial crisis volatility is
not constant over time we have perience
periods of high volatility and we have
periods of low volatility and so we can
move from an
our model to what we call an arch model
which is an order aggressive conditional
heteroskedasticity model where we say
that the price movement at time X that
the Sigma at time at T rather let's go
away from access stick with time T that
the Sigma at time T is conditioned on
Sigma at time T minus 1 and we can even
become more sophisticated than that and
we can go to a generalized
autoregressive conditional
heteroscedasticity model where we say
that volatility is seasonal volatilities
periodically conditioned and so forth
that only gives us though a single price
it gives us a good male good estimate of
what a volatility is going to be in the
price risk for the near term but only
for a single price point but we can take
our GARCH model and we can lay it out in
a multivariate normal model and if we
lay out our guards from the multivariate
normal it becomes a model called a C
cubed GARCH where Sigma at each point is
related to the Sigma and the price
movements of the other prices in our
model well our Sigma instead of being a
single you know you know in a single
price model whether it's a R or GARCH
Sigma is a is one number it's a scalar
you go on to regress those then but
either in a multivariate model though
Sigma is a symmetric positive-definite
matrix because it has to relate the
covariance of every price to every other
price and that's the concept that I was
trying to introduce in short form today
which is that in connect we have
positions in connect that are related to
each other according to the economic
substitutability of two different
strains how close or distant two strains
are from each other is how good they are
as substitutes if you think about that
and if you think about how that should
relate to a pricing model there
substitutability is inversely
proportional or should be inversely
proportional to the covariance of the
price shocks which means that our
connect distances
natural relationship to the Sigma matrix
in that C cubed arch model and it
becomes possible at that point if you
tried to figure out the price is what I
was alluding to today if you try and
figure out the price of a strain
tomorrow when that strain hasn't traded
in five months because there are
thousands of strains they don't trade
that often if you tried to figure out
that price of that strain tomorrow when
it hasn't traded in five months and do
that directly you would have a very
rough time you're not gonna be able to
do that on the other hand if you have a
covariance matrix and you have
intervening prices in that intervening
five months for other prices and that
covariance matrix then you can have a
pretty well grounded estimate of what
the new price will be for this strain
that hasn't traded before or that hasn't
traded recently then these are wholesale
prices I don't worry about the retail
level we are a a company that operates
at the wholesale level right yeah and
what this lets us do is to predict not
an individual this is your likely price
tomorrow
it lets us predict a pretty narrow range
of probabilistic prices for not today
but for a week from today two weeks for
today a month from today and that lets
us help people to figure out what price
they can expect to obtain and help
people price their product on the market
right so you're talking about enabling
what's now a commodity and now giving
futures to that come on
you're a very insightful person born in
fact that that's exactly the direction
we're heading is to figure out to be
able to accurately estimate not just the
price but what's the price risk over the
next month two months six months how
much volatility is there in the market
and what's relativity is going to be
associated with the strain with the
price of this strain and so forth
that's how other commodities are priced
and we would like to be able to start
doing that as cannabis moves into an
ordinary commodity that is to say a
commodity that's readily available
that's efficiently priced where buyers
can get a reliable stream of Commerce
that's the kind of risk assessment that
you need to be able to do interesting
could you as a chemist could you take a
similar model and apply it to statements
about the potency of cannabis is
cannabis becoming more potent over time
or less potent or is it stagnating out
could you apply it to questions like are
we seeing more what we refer to as
indicas versus sativas more uppers or
downers could we get a sense of well
indicas and sativas indicas and sativas
are chemically indistinguishable we see
no significant differentiation between
indicas and sativas there's a little bit
of attendances what's down there's a
little bit of a tendency for sativas to
have more to pennilyn but that's it I
don't know that there are uppers and
downers distinctions that I can define
chemically is the amount of THC growing
yes there is if you're selling cannabis
as flour there are people who walk into
the dispensary and what they're going to
pick is what has the most THC in it give
me the stuff that's the strongest give
me the most THC for my THC dollar and so
producers are marketing to that and I
have to tell you I think from the
consumers perspective I think they're
making a terrible mistake
if you have cannabis that has more than
you know 20% 25% THC in it there's a
limit to how high you can get and
there's certainly a limit to how high
you want to get and
it's hard for most people myself
included but really anybody that we've
talked to any whenever we've done
research into this people are much
happier with a cannabis that's 10% THC
and 10% CBD than they are with a
cannabis that's 35% th say you're going
to get frankly too high but nevertheless
that's what producers are moving towards
and the other place where producers are
moving towards very high THC amounts is
in production for extraction
there's certainly demand for very high
THC very high CBD in a very high
cannabinoid content for sale to
extractors consumers would probably be
happier if they focus less on getting as
much THC as they can and more on getting
a balance of other psychoactive
chemicals and they're in their cannabis
well thank you Amos thank you very much
[Music]