[Music]
I would like to welcome Baron nurata
over there from Marley natural Baron
introduce yourself and tell us what's
your title there um my name is Baron
NADA and I am the marketing director at
Marley natural get it real close to your
mouth and talk a little louder marketing
director at Marley natural
[Applause]
hi I'm Dave the founder CEO of
clay9 cultivator
cultivator hi I'm Morgan soal director
of compliance and Regulatory Affairs at
medmen you guys can hang out to that so
I we purposely chose uh this particular
group so that we could talk a little bit
about 2018 which is when we're looking
at hopefully licensing or starting to
take applications for licensing so I
have a representative from a brand a
cultivation and a retail and a
dispensary and I think it's important
that we all take a look at what is going
on what I want to
know is what are you guys talking about
at your quote Monday morning meeting
around whatever kind of conference room
table you might possibly have in your
environment we want to know a little bit
of an Insight of what what's going on we
have a a quasi regulated system right
now we have a law that's partially in
place we have medical regulations that
are going to come down and start taking
effect in 2018 regul recreational
marijuana that's going to start taking
effect in 2018 which probably will be
late 2018 so I don't want anybody to get
the idea that it's going to be January
anymore because it will not um and
knowing that these are knobs to be
twisted still and to figure out how this
is going this is what I want to discuss
with you guys okay so we're coming from
that perspective so um let's start
with
Dave um you've been a cultivator for
about 20 years maybe even more than 20
years at this point right um the
1996 all right so prop to 15 right how
convenient very safe answer awesome so
you you got so let's let's talk about um
testing
right because that's a big part of being
a cultivator is being able to properly
test all of your product what what do
you see now and then when you're going
forward and you're looking a year and a
half to two years in advance what kind
of things are going through your mind
and what are you guys talking about um I
think the biggest thing is clean room
technology for indoor cultivation um the
one you know benefit I think we have is
we went out of state in
2012 um and we've been cultivating in a
regulated space space in Arizona now
we're cultivating in Las Vegas and you
know so we're already kind of subject to
the state testing requirements and
having facilities in multiple States
really allows us to have two
Laboratories where we could do lots of
testing on just different procedures to
dial in our protocols so I think a lot
of what we've been doing is kind of
developing cultivation IP so that we
could you know understand how to pass
the State Testing kind of the
Technologies we need so
our product could be safe so that's what
one of the main things we've been doing
is developing the the IP to uh to
compete in a regulated market and how do
you how do you do that when you're
looking at different states with
multiple sets of laws right so I think
the the way the way that I look at it
and the way we're kind of looking at it
as a company is what's the strictest
requirements on the books and let's
shoot for that right so we look at
Oregon and say okay basically you can't
use any pesticides you can't use any
fungicides you pretty much have to grow
in a clean room environment so how do we
how do we survive in that market if we
could survive in that market we could
survive in any Market uh and so kind of
that's the philosophy we're taking got
it and and and baron let's just talk
about that as well
so um as a brand you guys have uh you're
constantly having to pay attention to
the current regulations everything from
from you know licensing which we'll talk
about in a minute but and to packaging
as well what kinds of meetings and kinds
of thoughts and talks are you guys
having at that conference room table
right
now
so with regulations changing um
consistently um we're actually talking
about the right Partners so looking for
um the right sources and cultivators we
don't grow our own cannabis um our goal
with our company is to support
entrepreneurs and cultivators and
Growers so is our Focus we never wanted
to grow our own um our own product uh
Marley natural is about continuing Bob's
Legacy um and if if you guys don't know
so the Marley family um approached
Privateer Holdings about two years ago
to develop a cannabis brand because they
wanted to continue his legacy and his
message Bob was an advocate for cannabis
for 50 years um so what we're talking
about is finding the the right partners
and long-term partners and we are
actually you were talking about
restrictions we are our compliance team
is very strict um we
don't um our Partnerships are very tight
so it's all about creating tight
Partnerships knowing who your partners
are and relying on them for long-term
growth both for yourself and for their
businesses and have you guys increased
your level of compliancy let's say over
the last year in response to regulations
and laws do you feel like there's been a
big shift and is there another shift
coming we've always taken the slow
approach grow Slow Grow right do it for
the long term so we've we've been you
know anticipating regulations and just
really planning to do everything really
slow so we're in California right now
we're in Oregon as you said Oregon is
really tough um and we're planning to
launch in Washington as well and you
know the partners The Growers we work
with work with they're all natural
they're pesticide free they're chemical
free so it's really important to know
exactly who your partners are your
Growers are and continue that
relationship and and let me just touch
on testing because we talked about it
how does that affect you looking at all
the the you know nebulousness in the
testing world right now right um so we
you know we find great Partners all the
time and we test products and if they
don't pass the test we can't do anything
with it we will not put it into the
market um it'll be a loss for us you
know we stand by our word and our
product and that's all anyone can do
that's in this industry so if there's
any um anything I can recommend to
everyone here is just be true to your
product and make sure you're doing it
right there's too much to risk we're all
all here to advocate for a great cause
and this is just the beginning so don't
don't cut any Corners that's great
advice let's definitely that one
deserves a hand Morgan let's pass the
mic over to Morgan so Morgan you're with
medmen medmen for those of you who don't
know is actually a corporate company and
that has several different dispensaries
you can tell us a little bit more about
that under the umbrella but really you
are mostly dispensaries would you say
that's correct for this talk yes for
this talk
absolutely so dispensaries are all about
compliance at this point let's talk
about that what's happening at your
Monday morning meetings and you know I
joke about that but what are you guys
talking about as to how you've been
operating and then how you're going to
have to change your operations going
forward I would assume sure so first I
just want to say thank you so much to
Jackie and women grow for having me here
it's really exciting medman is a manag a
cannabis management uh company and we
have facilities throughout the country
and we're also an investment firm our
Flagship dispensaries in West Hollywood
and one of the big things that we're
doing and preparing for 2018 is thinking
about
documentation what kinds of standard
operating procedures can we have that
give us a full picture of what our
operations look like everything from
welcoming uh new members into our
Collective what does documentation look
like how do we train our new employees
even thinking about emergency
preparation fires all kinds of things
because in our experience for the other
states where we've applied for licenses
the applications often ask for a full
packet of Sops so we want to make sure
we have those another thing we do is
create compliance packets we have a
dispensary in the city of Los Angeles so
I literally took proposition D went
through every single compliance measure
in there put it into an Excel
spreadsheet sheet and made sure I had
documentation to back up every single
thing whether it was getting our
business tax registration certificate on
time checking uh physician
recommendations to make sure that those
are all correct for our members or
having the right hours just making sure
we have this full packet so when the
state releases its application and its
regulations we could present that you're
ready to go I think that's a really good
advice for everybody in this room too um
we get asked these questions a lot and
if there's anything you could do for
yourself right now as a business if you
just don't know what's your next step
listen to what Morgan said which is do
everything possible to get every piece
of documentation you might possibly need
together now so that when 2018 comes
around and they are ready you literally
can just hopefully Go and show up in
line and make it a lot easier so uh and
you know understanding what those what
those documents are is challenging but
if you can start thinking like that I
think that's going to be good you
mentioned something about training and
there a lot of we talk about this a lot
butt tender
training um would you say that in your
retail operations that you feel good
about your the bud tender training
because and I think I want to bring this
up to all of you guys because we're now
getting into a place where with
recreational there's going to be a lot
of people coming that don't know as much
information as let's say patients out
there that have been maybe at this for a
while and know the questions to ask Bud
tenders need to be well educated
what do you guys do about that and are
you going to set up any kind of training
for them going forward that they don't
have now we absolutely have trainings in
place we have a system that we use to
train all of them in our standard
operating procedures and it actually
provides them a lot of quizzes that they
then have to take and we assess whether
or not they complete those but another
thing that I recommend for businesses is
to have someone dedicated to compliance
if that's possible it doesn't need to be
their full-time job you could have a
Communications person or a public
relations person and on top of that they
do compliance but having the buck stop
with one person in particular can be
super helpful so around the November 8th
election I wrote a bunch of memos for
our Bud tenders so they could feel very
informed when patients walked in about
how to talk to them about the upcoming
election that's really good let's pass
the mic to Dave there so Dave you don't
really deal directly with Bud tenders
yeah not too often but with the stores
with retail you do right so looking at
what might possibly be the distribution
models coming down how will that affect
your business and as oppos like looking
at how you do things now and how you
might do things going forward to get
your product into the stores or into the
hands of Distributors what are you guys
talking about in that area that's a
great question I think you know what
we're doing is a lot of data collection
um like I said earlier one of the one of
the benefits that we have that we went
out of state and we're attached to
retail locations out of state and so
we're able to kind of see how our
breeding so we do a lot of breeding for
specific strains for the retail market
and so we could kind of see the trends
in the retail market for specific
genetics for extraction and we bring
that information back to kind of inform
us on how we're going to proceed on the
cultivation side so it's really I think
having the retail data and using the
retail data to inform kind of the uh
protocols on on the cultivation side do
you feel instead of just kind of blindly
cultivating right now but speaking of
retail data do you feel like you're able
to get that data yes you feel good about
that we feel really good about it okay
because that's important too is making
sure if you're getting data that it's
quality data it yes yes so yeah in in
Phoenix we have a dispensary extraction
and cultivation and they're all
connected under one license so we we
have a lot of retail data that's great
now are you going to try to do something
similar here yeah of
course uh actually on the on the retail
side that's probably what what we're not
going to focus on we're looking for
Partnerships you know um with with
investors or uh people on the retail
side we know our specialty our you know
our talent is in cultivation and so
that's what we're focusing that's great
pass that to Baron Baron um as we're
talking about compliance how much time
you guys spend do you think dealing you
know here's Morgan saying you should
have somebody dedicated to compliance
you know there's been a there's been
changes that sometimes feel
daily you know how do you keep up with
that as as a brand especially when you
have packaging so you're generating lots
of product and you're also having to
manufacture this packaging on top of it
and then the regulations change um we're
fortunate enough to have um a couple of
people dedicated just to
compliance and I run everything by them
um so I do I do marketing one other
thing I wanted to say about butt tenders
butt tenders are king and queen of your
business um you need to bow down to your
butt tenders it is so you we can't
advertise well minimal advertising
minimal marketing the bud Tender Is your
spokesperson they sell your product
they're your Advocate take care of your
bud tender love your bud tender respect
your bud tender be best friends with
your bud tender if there are any bud
tenders here I bow down to you we love
you we want to do more with you um so we
love butt tenders um compliance we have
a dedicated team we're very fortunate
that is something very important to us
we don't take it lightly um we we invest
a lot of time and energy in everything
we do and we and everything we say goes
through compliance all of our packaging
you know we're we're working in a
business that's still federally illegal
that's it's it's scary you know um
anyone can get shut down at any time and
with our new Administration we just have
to be careful with everything we
do definitely uh let let's go back to
Bud tenders because I think it's an
interesting topic we don't really talk
about that often um but some of us here
spend time talking about it and one of
the things that seems to be a a a Talk
Amongst Regulators is maybe creating
some kind of certification for Bud
tenders what do you guys think about
that and let's take a quick poll in the
room how many people in here think Bud
tenders should have a
certification that's pretty much
everybody okay what do you guys think
about
that um I I agree I think it's it's a
process I think all bud bud tenders
should go through a training process you
know they're recommending um you know
medicine to to people so there
definitely needs to be a training
process and there's a trust you know so
when I go into a dispensary I'll go go
to a bud tender and ask them you know
let them know what I'm looking for and I
and I trust them so I think it's very
important and what we do from a Brand's
perspective is we go in there and we try
to educate them about our products and
what our products do and hopefully other
brands and you know companies do the
same
that's great you have a thought on that
bud tender certification yeah I think
it's a good idea um you know there's
always you know I think on the
cultivation side uh the cultivators take
the you know the the plant very
seriously and we spent many years
developing different strains and
studying tpine profiles and different
techniques and um a lot of times that
doesn't carry over to the other side
there's a lot of name game happening and
you know you'll develop something and
the the name will switch when it goes
across to the retail side so I think
it's a great idea I think you know the
more the bud tender knows about tpin and
cannabinoids and um potential
interactions and negative and positive
effects that's much better for the
retail user so I'm all for it great
Morgan I don't have a particular stance
on it but we are operating in New York
and it's one of the most highly
regulated medical marijuana programs in
the country and they actually require
pharmacists to be on staff and on site
at all times which is a pretty
interesting thing I would say as we're
waiting for the regulations to come down
to look at other states and see how
those regulations are written so you can
anticipate what potentially could
come hang on to the mic there so
um how will the new laws affect like
what SKS you guys put in your stores you
have X amount of SKS right now and I'm
assuming you kind of have a finite
amount of shelf space until you can
expand so do you feel like the new laws
are going to change how you guys look at
which products you're putting in your
stores again going back to testing
testing results and things like that and
just sort of overall compliance right
what happens when you come up when
somebody presents a product to you that
you guys aren't on board with sure I
don't think we fully know the answer
right now but we do know that the
state's going to require C toale
tracking so tracking it from the origin
all the way through the dispensary and
it being uh purchased by a patient uh
and we developed our own software called
my medmen that allows us to do that kind
of robust tracking so I would just
recommend for people to think about your
existing point of sale software can it
eventually adapt to whatever the state
is going to require um and just be
mindful of what those potential
regulations could look
like let's let's talk a little bit about
licensing because I think pretty much
everybody in the room is in one way
shape or form going to be trying to go
for a license and Dave if you don't mind
jumping in on this
um in California yeah do you feel like
you're going to take a wide approach and
try to apply for multiple licenses and
see what you get are you also part two
is are you going to apply for medical
licenses and recreational licenses you
know even though we don't know if those
things can sit side by side just yet
what's sort of a strategy that you're
thinking about
I think because we don't know it's a
shotgun approach it's just like let's go
for all of it and whatever works you
know uh when we when all the you know
pieces fall then that's what we'll we'll
make a decision at that point but I
think you know for licensing it's just
going after opportunities that are
available if there's an Avail available
opportunity for a license we're going to
go after it I mean and until we know
what the state's going to do we we don't
want to wait for them so we're just
going out after opportunities on the
licensing side and and baron what about
Marley Marley natural um are you guys
going to also do the same thing are you
going to go for multiple licenses do you
think I mean I know that's not exactly
your role in the company but I'm sure
you've been talking about it and medical
versus recreational how does that factor
in that isn't my specialty but what I do
know is we are going very slow with
everything we're we're we're watching
watching we're trying to work out all
the Kinks that um come up with any
cannabis business and really just kind
of um specialize in what we do work with
our partners and and see where that
grows and again like grow slow we're not
trying to be this you know big company
too fast it's like it's about the
Partnerships we have right now and
growing slow and having growth are you
guys in multiple States we're in
California in Oregon and we are
launching in Washington this spring okay
and so potentially plans for other
states down the line yes hopefully
hopefully but it's again it's I mean
with with everything that's going on in
this country right now it's slow it's
slow for sure so Morgan let's pass this
over to Morgan
um we talked a little bit about this
before what kinds of questions are you
getting from the customers in your
stores and how are you guys answering
those because I'm I'm sure many of you
in the room know that just because prop
64 passed doesn't mean you can actually
sell marijuana at this point to a 21y
old it is not yet licensed so that
particular piece of the law is not legal
yet until those licenses are issued but
unfortunately there are many operations
around the state that have just decided
to start selling recreational marijuana
and the problem is is that the customers
don't necessarily know any different
they just are kind of going with it and
following what the what the shop is
saying how are you dealing with that I
think one of the most common questions
we get is do I need to renew my
physician recommendation especially as
I'm already a member of the collective
and our answer is always yes we only
have a license to operate a medical
marijuana Collective so we will continue
to be fulfilling that and requiring all
of our patients to have their updated
physician recommendation valid ENT
identification and be a resident of
California and that's going to hold you
until licenses are issued right so we're
looking at again sometime in maybe late
2018 that they'll start to take
applications and hopefully get some so
just to be clear in this you know for
this room everybody still needs their
medical wreck so whether it's a pot
Lounge that someone's having you need
your medical wreck if whether it's any
dispensary anything you're doing that
scab is involved you still need that
wreck so and that's going to definitely
hold for a good year and a half maybe
two years years so you know that's a
question that we get asked a lot what
about you what are your customers say to
you you have a different kind of
customer um are they in the know most of
the people who you deal with yeah I
think so yeah most of the people we deal
with um just because we've been
operating for quite some time so
everyone that we deal with for the most
part has been in the industry for many
years so they yeah they're in the know
and the only question we really get is
when are you going to have more
product which is a good good you know
good problem to have at this point so I
mean it's just you know the issue is
like keeping up I think with the demand
of of uh the market exploding and are
you we know you're you know looking your
in in other states are you going to
continue to try to expand that business
to be able to help meet this this the uh
need oh yeah yeah I mean I think
California is our Focus for sure um even
though we went out of state you know uh
California is really you know we know
it's the place to be we is where we
started it's where we're from so this is
where we want to be that's great so
Baron are you guys um one of the things
you and I have talked about is uh your
we'll call it giving back giving back to
the community um what are some of the
things you're doing now and looking down
the road in into 2018 is that going to
change what what are you doing now yeah
so um we created a um social impact
initiative called rise up before we even
even launched or sold a product um in in
California and that is because we feel
responsible to um to this community to
to the Cannabis industry and to give
back to people that have been harmed by
cannabis prohibition so first and
foremost we gave back to Jamaica um
Bob's Homeland and the family's Homeland
and we helped fund um entrepreneurial
programs uh sustainable farming programs
and then um in in the US we're
partnering with the minority cannabis
Business Association and um defy
Ventures and our goal is each New Market
that we launch in we give back to that
market and the long-term goal is to
continue um our advocacy work and help
create entrepreneurial programs for
people that want to get into the
industry and to help create an even
playing field in the industry because um
you know there there's so many stories
there have been there are so many people
that have been harmed by cannabis
prohibition so we feel in our hearts
that we need to help those people so in
Oregon we we did an expungement program
we helped expunge 25 um records and men
and women and we paid for it we got the
lawyers for it I mean it's it's the the
least we can do and you know that it's
just the beginning it's really that's
it's my passion actually it's it's what
I want to do it's why I um joined the
industry I actually worked for the
Marley family before um getting into
Marley cannabis uh Marley natural I was
working for one of their other companies
and I I joined the I was fascinated by
the Cannabis industry I I felt like I
wanted to be a part of um a community
that is changing the world and we
actually are we um in my lifetime time
we'll see the end of prohibition and
that's something I never thought I'd be
able to say so I feel very grateful to
be this in this industry and I feel like
all I want to do is give
back definitely definitely what about
you do you have any programs that you
you know do kind of a giving back
program yeah I mean you know the the
thing about cultivation is um you just
kind of by Nature have to employ lots of
people with criminal
records so I think we've been giving
back for many years on that
side but um you know we we we uh out of
state you know we've definitely employed
veterans um we we have a lot of old
hydroponic equipment that we've been
building up over 20 years and we're you
know uh creating a program to give it to
dispensaries and collectives to donate
to patients so they could start their
own grows um but those are the main two
things we're looking at right now hire
we hire veterans like I said we've been
employing people with records for many
years and you know uh we're giving back
equipment uh and teaching people how to
grow I'm also actually in Nevada I got
to go back uh to Vegas tomorrow and I'm
going to be creating an education
program to help people with felony
records um so they can present it to the
judge to produce their records so that's
another thing I think that's very
beneficial that's wonderful and one not
on that uh for those who don't know in
prop 64 in California uh it is now the
law that um if you have a prior
marijuana offense that you will not be
discriminated against when applying for
a license and that you'll have every
same opportunity to do that so even if
it was just a small offense um or a big
one and you were incarcerated for a
felony you are now able to apply for
license that's another one that's going
to get fought but in the law that is
what it says so that's good you you were
ahead of the game oh
[Laughter]
[Music]
by by
Nature uh so um I want to bring up a
topic that um everybody seems to want to
know about and that's CBDs and uh THC so
um knowing that these regulations and
laws are still very nebulous are you
guys making any distinctions between CBD
products THC products um as you're
carrying them in your store and thinking
about stocking them on your shelves or
are you just kind of winging
it we do have a variety of products
whether it's just CBD products or a
mixture or THC I think it's largely
dependent upon uh what we see from our
patient base and what they tend to want
and that's what we continue to stock so
that goes back to our software that we
have and our point of sale system and
being able to review all of that um and
just in terms of compliance and thinking
about the future in regards to that one
thing that's really important for us is
to craft our policy strategy and to
think about our priorities so for us
like one super important thing is making
sure that the state while they are going
to require seed toale tracking uh
software that we are allowed to still
have our own that could then roll up to
the states uh so just think about what
your policy priorities are and then how
you can use your voice whether it's
through your city council or joining
existing Trade Organization to get those
important things across I think that's a
really good point um you know uh getting
involved with your city councils we've
talked about that a lot are you guys
active as well the other two of you in
in any kind of city councils or just
getting out in front of people and that
are regulating um we hire we hire people
to help us with that we're focused on
cultivation but on the licensing side
yeah we hire um law firms like Frontier
law they're uh doing a lot of hard work
out
there but yeah so you know like I said
we focus on cultivation but we we kind
of contract out for those
services and baron what about you guys I
I'm personally not in front of them but
um we have the right team members that
are definitely what about the CBD THC
discussion do you guys have both we do
you do we do and do you ever make any
distinctions between that or you know I
just because the the laws and everything
are just so questionable right now and
with the DEA doing what they just did
with CBDs you know it's just a topic of
discussion there's no actual answers yet
but I'm just kind of curious if those
conversations are happening oh sorry
what was that just about being able to
safely carry CBD products we kind of
know what's going on with CHC but CBD
it's somewhat weirdly you know
unanswered I'm I'm not that person that
the person that would know that um I
heavily rely on our team and our compli
team that would you know investigate
that further for us okay all right all
right so the final thing I'm going to
talk to you guys about um and then I'm
going to take uh we'll open it up to the
audience for some questions is uh
banking so it's a problem for everybody
we know this but what conversations are
you having right now and how are you
dealing with Banking and looking forward
what are you anticipating so that same
question goes to all of you whoever's
the mic and go first um so banking is
not my specialty but I can tell you you
know
um we shouldn't try to rush this
industry it's about doing it right for
everyone and the more time it takes you
know we need to get involved we need to
voice our opinion we need to let people
know exactly what we're looking for um
and what kind of benefits we want um as
members of of this industry so you know
it's not it's not a rush game it's let's
let's take our time with it and and do
it
right uh Bank of
[Applause]
mattress banking is a huge priority for
us and also thinking about federally 28
and the tax code and all of that I for
what we decided is to join as many
organizations as we can to make our
dollars and also our voices stronger so
in the city of Los Angeles we chose to
be a part of ucba but there's a ton of
other Traders associations that you can
be a part of um and at the federal level
we've become members of ncia which is
also pursuing the banking issue at the
federal level okay um so if I just want
to go across real quick and and if you
could give the small business
owner something to think about something
to chew on from your perspective because
you guys are already in business so a
lot of people in this room are not yet
in business or are just starting and
they want to be in business what advice
and what thoughts and suggestions do you
have for that small business owner from
where you
sit I think largely documentation is
super important and also research look
at how other states are handling this
and see what could be transferable to
you what makes sense uh do the robust
regulations in other states deter you or
are they actually something that you can
handle and take on and then pursue that
further yeah no I mean it's partially
true the banker mattress thing but I
mean uh I I think in in in our situation
we kind of default to our CPA and we say
this is what we've done you know you
make us you know
compliant
um what I'd like to say is this isn't
easy at all um so you should all be
proud to be in it or to be smart enough
to think about getting in it um I want
to say fight the fight um it's worth it
and it's there's a bigger picture at
hand and we all have a chance to to get
into this and do it right so don't give
up
that's great thank you guys so much all
of you so we're going to take some
questions Cass uh there's there's one
okay that's fine too uh you mentioned
the ncia handling banking at a federal
level what other
organizations are involved that we can
be associated with sure so I would say
look at the marijuana policy project
they're doing an amazing job across the
country locally the LA cannabis task
force Southern California Coalition
minority Alliance those are all amazing
organizations also ccia which is
California Cannabis industry Association
so NCI is the national and then ccia is
the California one as well as a drug
policy Alliance who's very involved in
the prop 64 side so there's a lot of uh
different different places but those are
some really good ones next oh she's over
there right now yes I have a question um
for
Morgan so we're in um we have our
lo50 tax bill coming up on February 18
28th because of prop 64 it's sort of
changed the rules it looks like this uh
city taxes taxation without
representation curious what you guys are
doing with that at medman pay it so for
the business tax registration
certificate specifically we're just
following what the office of Finance is
saying and we're going to submit our
payments whatever
based on however they Define it I know
that the Board of Equalization has taken
particular stances on uh prop 64 and
whether or not you have to charge sales
tax for medical marijuana so I would
just suggest looking at their website
we're largely going off of what those
agencies are telling us to do are you
doing the 6% and the
9% I'm not part of the finance team so I
don't specifically know but um I would
just defer to either your legal counsel
your CPA or you could even reach out
directly to those agencies to see what
they
recommend hi I have a question for Dave
if you're growing in Las Vegas and
Arizona how do you transport it like
across state lines no we don't they're
all individual entities so anything we
grow in Arizona stays in Arizona
anything we grow in Nevada stays in
Nevada so there's no yeah no Crossing of
state lines not yet okay you know in
five years but right now it's all each
each uh cultivation is isolated within
the state and why can't we cross state
lines federally it's a federal offense
okay yeah make sure everybody
understands that do not cross state
lines whatever you do yeah okay next
question so I agree that bud tenders are
King and Queens too because every time I
go into dispensary they're just so
knowledgeable as it relates to training
can you make a recommendation
um Oaker versus an
online um training organization because
as a business owner I feel like I want
to know everything there is a note
too um I'm not familiar with those
schools but I would rely on your
partners so your sourcing Partners your
Growers your vendors your Brands to come
in and educate um your staff on on their
product that's key it's the duty of your
partners to do that so there are there's
Oaker Dam that's one example there's CCI
anybody in here in the room know any
others that we can just shout out any
sort of good cannabis training program
say that again green green flower media
exactly that's another one anybody else
420 Learning Tree 420 Learning Tree so
there's a couple of different places
that you can uh go and learn about this
um but as far as ual butt tender
certification programs I don't know if
they really actually exist yet it's
something that's being discussed right
now with
Regulators hey my question is for Dave
and baron who do you guys use to test
your flower and
why um I use two Labs
exceler um up in I think it's in Union
City and the workshop Jeff raber those
are the two Labs I use here in
California here in California yeah
and in the other you know other states
it's a little bit hit or miss so but I
would say in California those two labs
are very very legitimate um and they
give you very you know very scientific
results that are reliable you know and
on the cultivation end because we do a
lot of breeding we're not really looking
for the lab that give us the highest
results we're looking for labs that give
us real accurate data and so if you're
looking for accurate data I would
recommend those two Labs the workshop
and exceler and I think Workshop is is
about to reopen in uh the next couple of
weeks um they've been kind of out of
commission for for a minute but
definitely I would recommend the
workshop in
exceler and work is spelled w
RC I I defer to
DAV okay we have a question up here I
know we do oh okay that's fine here then
there um yes it's I don't think it's a
question but um I I just came back from
Amsterdam we in prom and but I live here
um they were selling CBD liquid in in
bottles uh at the CBS Store and it's
considered uh you know easy over the
counter to get and it's considered a
food item and they said it's it's easy
to transport even so I don't know what
you maybe it is a question what do you
think of that
penel I I think the DEA just came down
with a ruling that makes CBD schedule
one so there I think I think you know I
mean I'm not 100% sure but I have lots
of friends that have companies that were
doing CBD extraction so they were
importing a lot of CBD from Europe um
especially Germany because the source is
very clean uh but I think because of the
DEA ruling I don't think you could
export it or import CBD anymore but I'm
not a lawyer so maybe you could ask
someone else but that's what I've
heard yeah give the M knows a little
about that yeah actually you can import
it still okay um okay as long as it's
from the the stocks of the hemp plant oh
okay I didn't know that okay so it has
to be certified as that Europe CBD is
excellent because you can get it over
the counter the United States we have
not the schedule it's always been
scheduled as a schedule one CBD has but
we finally the DEA finally gave it a
number that's the difference and the
reason they gave it a number one of the
reasons is is to make it a
pharmaceutical so connect the dots there
and that's what they're doing so they're
not enforcing it and a couple lawyers a
couple big law firms hob and law is one
of them has actually filed paperwork
against the DEA so we'll see where that
goes okay just cleared up thank you
H uh we have a question over here in the
corner hi my question is for Dave so uh
with some of the larger cultivators that
I converse with depending on how the
state rolls out licensing and everyone
talks about the quick Crunch and the
shortage of product everyone else is
talking about what happens a year later
and the collapse of the Commodities
market and the general prediction on the
optimistic side I hear is 800 a pound
and on the not so optimistic side 400 a
pound I'm wondering what your thinking
and your feelings are well I you know I
think it's inevitable that there's going
to be a price collapse I I don't think
that low you know just because I think
there's a high enough demand for like a
higher end flower and just the cost of
production makes it impossible to
survive there was some data recently
published by medical marijuana Business
Daily um and I you know I I'd like to
think that Colorado is probably one of
the most saturated markets in America
and they have something like 1,500
regulated commercial cultivators and
their average price dropped to about
1,500 so at 1,500 with a very very
efficient commercial cultivation you
could still be profitable so I I I think
if they're still hitting that number on
average and that includes outdoor indoor
is still I think well above 1500 for
really high end so you just have to make
sure that you're doing something unique
you're doing something Boutique and I
think you could still survive in this
market for several years many years
maybe 5 10
years I might be incorrect but on your
website is says you have indoor
production to 7 cents a gram no that's
not I wish that that would just be our
that's the cost of our n of our
fertilizer just our fertilizer but the
total cost is way above that yeah the
labor and the electricity and the yeah
the rent but yeah that that's just the
nutrient
cost all right we got time for one or
two more questions and then we're going
to move on what you
got
uh thank you so much for being here so
for a lot of us that are new to the
industry um do you recommend going in
with a partner or someone who's been in
the industry already or do you think
that it's doable for us to come in as
newcomers and learn the industry and
maybe become a small business
owner
um I'm all about Partners but you have
to know who your partner is um I'm all
about being independent as well um and
being a small business owner I I believe
you can do it um it it really depends on
who your partners are you you really
never know you have to vet
everyone agreed yeah I mean um it's hard
to say because I'm very you know
exclusive industry side so uh in my
experience it's definitely good to at
least pick the brain of someone who's
been in the industry because it it it's
it's a completely different industry
than anything else so I think you at
least want some perspective I don't know
if you necessarily to partner up with
someone in the industry but at least you
know do due diligence and and and kind
of talk to as many people as you can in
the industry to get some
perspective on the re retail side I
would just say be careful about where
you are entering like for West Hollywood
for example they've already given out
the four licenses that they're going to
be giving for dispensaries for Los
Angeles it's a pretty iffy situation
right now with uh measure M M M M that's
coming on there's going to be two
measures on the ballot guys there's
measure M and measure n n though is on
the ballot that's the ucba one and
that's not to be voted on but made the
ballot and it's going to be there so we
have to get that straight m is the one
that people are really looking at n is
the one that we're at least not voting
for so to enter Los Angeles is also kind
of iffy because it's unclear what the
city council is going to determine for
the number of dispensaries that they're
going to allow so just be mindful about
what the existing regulations
are okay so with that I am going to say
thank you to all three of these
wonderful wonderful people up here thank
you guys so much this is really really
informative really really helpful uh for
everybody to understand and uh I'm
assuming these three will be floating
around here so you have more
[Music]
questions