[Music]
California unlike any place in the world
is woven from a diverse fabric of that
dynamic terroir its rolling hills and
foggy coastlines which sit atop unique
deposits of rich and bountiful soil
create a cultivation environment unlike
anywhere else in the world which I'm
sure we're all aware as a licensed
distributor based in San Francisco
Philly Green believes in the celebration
of these extraordinary Appalachians they
strive to be an active voice in the
articulation of these incredible stories
through community events and their
online marketplace they believe that
more than they can more than educate the
market about these vivid cultivation
environments the more loyal their
consumer base will grow people who
consume cannabis want to feel a
connection to the land and these
individuals on our panel today are at
the forefront of forging those bonds so
huge thanks for philly green and for all
the panelists I want to pass it off to
Janine Coleman thank you it's great to
be here thanks everyone
my name is Janine Coleman I'm the
director of the Mendocino Appalachians
project and I'd like to introduce my
esteemed panelists to my left here is
the one and only Frenchy Canole then we
have Dan prominence the CEO and founder
of rebel groan welcome Hezekiah Allen
the chair of emerald grun and Dale hunt
founder of plant and planet law firm
welcome all I'd like to give thanks to
camp Navarro which is situated in Rancho
Navarro and Rancher Navarro is a Kanna
cultural area of historic importance to
our community here in Mendocino County
it is a large subdivision it's a rural
residential area that's zoned for
agriculture and there's smaller parcels
and so they're more affordable and so
historically over the decades it's been
a community that really has given the
young people the next generation and
small families their their start
to be able to get their foot in the door
to the local economy of Mendocino County
and so you know really want to give a
shout out to this decades-long historic
area that we're enjoying this event in
and really acknowledged the importance
of these incubator area
to the economic development of rural
producing areas like Mendocino County
thank you want to give a special thanks
to Meadowlands they have been really
really supportive of getting our local
community out here and getting the
members of our trade associations
present and really want to thank you
guys you've been awesome this is a
beautiful event thank you so much so
we're gonna do a series of introductions
and then we have a couple of discussion
topics then we'll open it up for Q&amp;A at
the end I want to talk a little bit
about Geographic indication systems and
offer an overview for the for the panel
so Geographic indication systems are a
category of intellectual property rights
they collectively belong to the region
that's tied to producing and special
practices and the product of the region
an appellation of origin is a special
kind of geographic indication that's got
standards associated with it that really
codify and protect the practices the
heritage and the special genetics of the
region and in California we've got a few
tools now in state law we've got county
of origin which is a general geographic
indication it's tied to our counties and
then in 2017 the industry lobbied and
really advocated to get appellation of
origin in California statute with the
very special associated standards
practices and cultivars tied to it and
so right now we've got those two tools
in in law and the California Department
of food and egg will be taking petitions
for appellation of origin in 2021 and
right now they're working to develop
their regulations to support the program
so we're excited to see this moving
forward the Mendocino little hand yeah
shout out to Cal cannabis for working on
cannabis appellations they're putting a
lot of resources to it and I think
that's a really significant thing for us
at this time it's going to be a really
important tool for us moving forward so
the Mendocino Appalachians project is
part of a coalition of regional trade
that are working together to realize
this tremendous opportunity for
standards-based legally recognized
nationally and internationally
recognized appellation of origin
protections and we're doing this from
the basis of rural economic development
and really thinking about sustainability
when it comes to our rural economic
development because this is happening
fast there's a tsunami upon us and it's
very important that as we build policy
in a market that we think about rural
economic development and doing doing so
in a way that's sustainable so that's a
little bit about what I'm working on and
the overall topic that we're going to be
addressing around genetic resources and
I'm gonna go ahead and pass this on
so the panelists can introduce
themselves and tell us a little bit
about what y'all are working on the
first time I out the world tell well
here in in California was with Tim Blake
and Leo's turn from aficionado and
because I'm France and it's part of my
culture it resonated really strong and I
started to study it because I spa as
much as it's part of my culture I didn't
really know very much about it for a
scene in Europe every agricultural
projects that as a certain biggest
achieve aspect is evaluated see here's
the origin of the place and the world
literally the world country of France
it's based on Jew stoned out of
Appalachia and origin and appellation
d'origine of quality that give the
maximum protection for summer and
protection internationally and bring
your the name of that little farm in the
middle of nowhere to a world to the
world view and every stone downs that
are made are dedicated solely to create
that quality and get greater than that
so the world Appalachian the region its
internationally protected you have to
follow set
then stand out to the later that have
been given from by France so you have
the choice here in California
all you do like the American wine and
you create your own classification for
cannabis and you have to make it so good
that the rest of the world when they
legalize they want to follow your song
down and your regulation and your
classification because it's it like they
did for the for the wine oh you follow
the the appellation d'origine stand out
the wine and just he didn't do it
because they needed to create their wine
and Eustace they needed to have no
limitation so that they could create the
amazing wine that you have today you
don't have that problem you have so much
diversity so much quality so much
microclimate that you need literally to
define it and and classify it because
it's solely age so you need basically
zhuzh limitation to to understand what
you have my world war heat all that time
was how can we prove that the reader can
I be stay well actually and during my
study in there is a French government
websites that tell you everything you
need to know about appellation delusion
and control your lotteries in English
and they made me realize that actually
even Bordeaux was recognized as a
terroir because the wine coming from
Bordeaux well recognized worldwide for
their quality so you don't have to prove
that you have a cannabis taehwa the
world over know that you're going the
best quality now you need to define the
terroir and defining the terroir goes
beyond defining a region if you go the
so-so quality cultiva in Bordeaux it
not get an Appalachian Division if you
go the Gators quality of cultiva but in
the wrong part of Bordeaux it's not
considered an Appalachian the reason
it's not everywhere in Bordeaux that is
terroir
it's certain parts that are terroir so
the the our problems are labels that you
have it's to define all those amazing
tell ones that you have and then it's
like every agricultural product it's
like it's like wine except that in a
wine and you see they have twenty
surgical Chiva you have thousand of them
and it makes seems more complicated but
it makes you so much richer in the
amount of step and what you can bring on
the table and on top of that every one
of your farm when you work with living
soul and you really use the world
beneficial life force of you of where
you go is gonna make your body different
and the neighbor then you can go even
deeper you are recognized for that
uniqueness of yes that specific genetics
that is poor gone on your farm and
that's that the name of the game is like
I've lived in many producing country
what you have here it's amazing and you
don't know how much how much you are
worth basically hey everyone yeah so
first of all you know I really
appreciate being invited to speak on
this panel it's kind of an honor I've
done some public speaking but none this
is kind of like the white collar
cannabis event and so you know I'm kind
of coming in and representing people
work with the plants the growing
community small craft farmers from the
Emerald triangle and people who are
really dedicating their their lives to
breeding work a little slow recovering
this morning but so let's talk about and
touch on some of the things that Frenchy
was talking about which is what is the
purpose in the origin of these
Appalachians and in
where they came from is really the small
craft farmer so in Romania and France in
certain regions where they were
producing a wine or a varietal of grape
that was famous and was starting to make
their names famous and then all the
sudden larger producers started saying I
want to get in on that I want to produce
that Pinot Noir I want to produce what
this little microclimate in Romania is
doing I want to produce champagne and
those small communities that were not
rich wealthy farmers they were small
family-run businesses said how can we
possibly compete against these massive
scale operations that can just demolish
us in in terms of efficiency and cost of
production and so you know this goes
back what he probably knows more of the
history but 100 150 years they worked
with their governments to establish
themselves and say look we started this
we are the originators of this the
process of how we grow these grapes and
what's in our unique atmosphere and
microclimate and our soils this is
champagne you can't get anything like
this you can replicate it but it'll
never be the same and that has to have
some intrinsic value of being an
originator and putting in decades and
decades of work so in California
Northern California especially I grew up
on the East Coast and I was an indoor
grower and you know I loved smoking
outdoor weed because of the unique
terpenes but you know there's there's
really no comparison when I came out my
first season in Humboldt
I was still iffy I'm like yeah this is
amazing but I kind of wish we had some
lights you know to show you kind of what
I can do after that first season my life
was changed I was completely blown away
about what the environment can actually
do the intensity of the Sun the the
balances and the coastal versus inland
micro climates the elevation and it was
really life changing just seeing how
incredible and how diverse cannabis can
be at all these spectrums because of
these unique areas and then over the
years as I started traveling and doing
consulting work or meeting different
farms I've been able to see genetics
similar and unique grown in all these
different areas so Humboldt County alone
is the size of a lot of small states
so just in southern Humboldt alone you
know the east or west side of the 101
represents a dozen or so little
microclimate some of them are more
coastal some of them are closer to the
redwoods and
just above a temperate rainforest some
of them go way too far out and they're
dry but you can see and taste the
difference in the flavors and terpenes
and resin production between all those
different regions and same with
Mendocino and I think that I have a
pretty good palate I smoke a lot and
I've seen herb produce and so there's
unique things to say about what are some
of the textures that resonate to me that
are similar whenever I see herb from
Bell Springs versus island mountain
versus Layton Villas comp Shi versus
burnt ranch and the deal is it's it's
really something unique and in
California right now everybody is
competing over this market share which
is eventually going to be really big for
California but the reality is that
California cannabis has something really
amazing to offer the entire world that's
that's the value California originates
culture you know besides you know San
Francisco and tech but we have Southern
California where I've only ventured to a
few times there's 20 million consumers
down there and those types of people
they need education about this so what's
happening is a lot of people want to get
in and they want to make money because
they think that cannabis is going to be
a business where they can just get in
and make money but there's folks who
preserved the way by taking a lot of
substantial risk and devotion and
determination for years and appellations
of origin is a way to potentially
protect and preserve the way of life for
those folks what's happening is there's
massive scale commercial production in
Southern California huge and there's
some really nice micro climates there's
green belts in Santa Barbara where they
grow certain varietals of wine so I
think that the balance for Appalachians
in Northern California is really
establishing not just the microclimates
and the difference in between what
varietal grows best in what area are
what farm grows him and for what reasons
but also the stories behind those
regions because just like in champagne
you know I have an associate of mine who
has an artisanal wine imports business
so two months ago he was in Champagne
met with small farmers and was able to
tour these facilities where they've been
passed down for multiple generations and
these are not wealthy people they live
in small houses they work their own you
know they they work their own grapes and
then their village it's like a church a
little store and then a community
processing facility where they have
these cooperate
models so these champagne producers they
all share time about you know they can
all make their grapes and/or their wine
in different processes and store them
but the only way that they could ever
survive is by you know communally kind
of sharing that whole operation and
those are folks they've never had that
champagne ever distributed more than 30
miles from where it was grown you know
so a friend of mine his company goes and
meets those farmers and brings it over
to the US
that's what California's model needs to
be for the future because I know that in
my neighborhood the paloverde we have
some very very special sacred energy
from like the Native Americans to the
early homesteaders to the cannabis
that's grown and I picture people in
Tokyo buying a quarter ounce of that
stuff and ten years from now going you
can't get this anywhere else and when
you hear the story behind it and who
produced it and why it's it's the most
sacred thing in cannabis so that's why I
think something like this is it's really
important because you know what matters
are the producers and the consumers
everything in between is a part of the
process but the producers are the
creators and the consumers are the ones
ingesting this and they're the ones who
need the education and to know about the
importance of all these things so that's
just a little bit man I was really
excited to participate in this and I
wish that we had a lot more than just
one hour and then the genetic side of it
is another huge huge thing because you
know who wear your genetics coming from
what what is in them how did they get to
be what they are and again that is one
of the greatest stories of cannabis
because you know it originally started
with some landrace varietals somewhere
that had been growing maybe for
thousands and thousands of years and
over millennia of you know nomadic
tribes traveling and bringing seeds to
you know the modernization of cannabis
and all the the you know hybridization
it's it's it's kind of like over the
last 70 years there's never been an
opportunity to understand any of that to
do medical research it's been too
illegal the people who were paving the
way with breeding back in the 70s 80s
90s they had such restrictive laws and
law enforcement that they couldn't
document most of their work so now
modern-day cannabis breeders are up
against massive challenges in terms of
the preservation of these genetics and
how do you apply science and weave in
and out so
it's really intense times for the
cannabis industry exciting intense I
mean it's it's really you know if you
look at the end of prohibition of
alcohol you know it didn't just settle
right away to the point where there's
five or six conglomerates that bought up
all the companies I mean there were tens
if not hundreds of thousands of people
making their living through some type of
bootlegging being involved in alcohol
that transition took decades to settle
into you know an industry so this is a
really amazing historical time for
cannabis and especially for Northern
California we have something really
special to offer to the world and I
think it's really important that we find
a way to represent that properly you
know and present it well so that it can
have the impact that it needs to so that
our industry doesn't die out and go to a
bunch of greedy corporations and massive
scale commodity producers who really
only care about money at the end of the
day so that's good morning everybody my
name is Hezekiah Allen it's good to see
you all I know Jeanine did a great job
but Thank You meadowlands Thank You
meadow forget us all together again
out here been working on this project
called emerald grown I'm sure a handful
of you are familiar with emerald grown
started it back in late 2014 our first
meeting properly turned into a group
therapy session where a bunch of friends
and neighbors were admitting to each
other they were growers for the first
time ever there were a fair amount of
Tears a lot of laughter and at the end
of the day I think we were stronger for
it at the time we were you know sort of
just dusting off our I was born and
reborn at home raised off the grid in
southern Humboldt my grandparents
started growing in Pennsylvania in the
60s yada ya been a grower all my life
and so we were really just starting to
sort of pick our heads up and realize
what life off the hill was going to look
like acknowledging the future was coming
and that it was time to be a part of it
um you know if we're not a part of it
we're not gonna be a part of it I think
simply put so evolved from there into
realizing that a lot of what we wanted
to do was still illegal
you know Salatin has that book
everything I want to do is illegal
something to that
fact it still is and it definitely still
was in 2014
you know Frenchy and Dan mentioned the
cooperative models of the old world in
the wine industry we couldn't form coops
we were actually you know weren't
allowed agricultural coops are common in
California but we couldn't form them and
so there were a handful of things we
identified coming out of those series of
meetings that became the advocacy
platform that we advanced in the Capitol
over the last few years Appalachians
being one of those four pillars
regulation is agriculture sustainability
sort of that the basic core tenants that
we decided make our community what it is
I'm pretty pleased to say that we
checked off all of those boxes on our
policy goals that's not to say that the
regulations are something that I
celebrate as being finished good or even
bearable at this point it is to say that
when I don't know if any of you have you
know Luke Bruner used to be around at a
lot of these meetings the first meeting
that Luke and I we were not invited to
the meeting with senator Korea we
elbowed our way in and they said this is
a closed meeting you have to leave and I
said no we read the law this is the
capital we're allowed to be here this is
the people's government that meeting was
proposing the Board of Pharmacy would
issue 30 licenses statewide mandatory
vertical integration so while it's not
great just think of how far we've come
from that was July of 2014 that was
about five years ago so to be here
talking about this topic and talking
about what we can do together the bottom
line what we've been discovering at
least what I've been discovering through
this process of catharsis is that we we
genuinely are stronger together and
being able to work together is is
probably the most important thing we can
do you know so hence emerald grown it is
a Federation of cooperatives cannabis
cooperative associations are capped at
four acres each we are aggregating
several of those co-ops through this
model you know locally owned facilities
haven't announced this publicly yet but
we do know I own three acres of
commercial property just north of Layton
Ville where the first long Valley Center
will be built out and then
badda County we have a facility out
there that we're working on build-out
sort of to serve as those first hubs
[Applause]
it's a lot of fun it's a lot of work I
applaud all of you licensees that have
made it through this on the first wave
let me tell you what and you know how
this all ties into our conversation
today obviously marketing is a huge part
of our future going forward so we've
organized our marketing strategy into
five pillars you know we're going to
have a very strong house brand and
emerald grown will be on products at
every price point on every shelf in
about three years I think is what will
ramp up - we'll see but one of the one
of the the the brand pillars that we
have is the regional brands and this is
an adventurous playful marketing effort
it is a welcoming hand taking you on the
adventure of your lifetime into the
middle of nowhere in California these
most beautiful beaches where you can
find the solitude these most bustling of
urban areas where you can find the
culture we need to be a guide we need to
welcome and invite people into this
experience but we need to do it in a way
that's open and inclusive because the
beautiful thing about Appalachians to me
and about the their shared assets
I am unabashedly a socialist it's no
surprise that these programs largely
developed in socialist countries where
quality of life matters the idea of
taking something from France there's so
many policies in France that would be so
unpalatable in in the US economic system
but the more that we can cross pollinate
between our market driven system and the
common good that is more common in
European social democracies the better
humanity is going to be in my opinion
and so this idea of thanks yeah right
yeah humanity go us we don't totally
suck yet sorry I swear like 30 years
until civilization goes away if we don't
do better so let's just keep that in the
back of our minds while we're building
our cannabis industry that we're not
just building our cannabis industry I
think that we're building a beacon of
hope for the broader world if we do it
right
and so you know the the these are shared
assets that's the common point nobody
owns Mendocino nobody owns bell Springs
these are all of ours we've built them
together and it is our responsibility
and it is incumbent on us to manage them
together and to share the benefits of
those things equitably you know right
now unfortunately we're doing this panel
at the same time as equity to me this
conversation is about equity how do we
manage shared resources is about
fairness and equity and to try to
privatize those things to try to make
them mine is unacceptable and it's a
moral travesty tragedy that we all need
to call bullshit on and we all need to
be better than that so I know I know
that that we didn't come here
necessarily on this Saturday Sunday
Sunday weekend in the woods to like hold
our feet to the fire but it is how it is
in my life
feet to the fire we need to manage these
assets together we need to do better and
be better and I am excited to be a part
of that with all of you
[Applause]
i'm dale hunt i was i just want to start
by saying i was excited to be on this
panel before i heard all this and it's
just an honor to be on this panel with
everybody here
I started as a botanist I somebody told
me in college that I couldn't consider
myself educated unless I'd had a biology
class and botany fit in my schedule so I
took botany and after three sessions it
was so fascinating to me I changed my
major and I I never looked back I had no
good reason to take botany but I loved
it so much I that was my major so and
then I stuck around for a master's
degree in plant genetics just because I
didn't have anything better to do and
then I I went to UC San Diego to do a
PhD in molecular and cell biology which
I did also in plants and by then I knew
I didn't want to be a professor so I
went to Berkeley for law school and
became a patent attorney
and even that was a long-ass time ago so
23 years ago I started working as an
attorney in a law firm and one of our
clients was a Central Valley fruit
company that made great varieties of
stone fruits and and grapevines table
grapes and I had the opportunity to help
them protect their their genetics all
around the world and not just protect
but commercialize
so I in addition to that I did a bunch
of other kinds of patents but I didn't
know that I was preparing myself to work
in the cannabis industry but I was so my
mission now really I the way I see it is
the difference and I've worked with a
lot of other plant genetics companies
but the difference between all of those
companies and every other every other
company I know that works with plant
breeders and this industry is that in
every one of those companies the plant
breeders are employees they're either
the founders of the companies in which
case they're doing great or their
employees and they sign their
assignments of their patent rights and
they have fine jobs but their employees
and in this in this industry they are
III in many cases they're successful
entrepreneurs already but otherwise they
are they're the rebels they're the
outlaws they're the survivors but I
think they need to be the rock stars and
they are going to be the absolute rock
stars of this industry you know who they
are you know who you are
and super creative this is the most this
is the plant with the greatest genetic
potential of any we already know that
and but there's one other thing about
about this plant that is this is this is
not unique to this plant but it's it's
unusual at least that the the patent
system I don't want to bore the hell out
of you but I do have to tell you this
that's why I'm here the patent system
for plants is kind of divided between
it's divided three ways it's divided
between plants that you
bigot asexually and and and you know the
plants that you clone or plants that you
propagate with seeds and obviously as
you know with cannabis you go both ways
right and so that that makes it
complicated even know what how to
protect what you're what you're what
you're doing or which which kind of IP
to get so I was on the phone yesterday
with a friend of mine who was speaking
at a at a cannabis event a patent
attorney is speaking at a cannabis event
in DC and she said just gave me this
short rundown on I need to sound like I
know what I'm talking about I said we'll
just read the blog I posted last week
and she said I don't have time I said
it's five minutes at most she said just
just give me just explain it to me
quickly I said okay well first thing you
need to know is they might make their
money by selling clones or they might
make for their money by selling seeds or
they might just sell harvested material
they might make an extract and she said
what and and the kind of IP they get
totally depends on what they're making
their money oh okay
and then I said anyway we had this whole
conversation and she decided it was way
too complicated and she's just gonna
send everybody to me you know that's
great but one other story I want to tell
you I I have you know if you're an
attorney you work in an office a lot one
of my favorite things I ever did was to
get out of the office and come up here
and meet with one of my clients who's a
plant breeder he has a farm up in late
and vil way up in the hills and he sent
me back to San Diego with a bunch of
samples and two of my favorite people
that I work with are experts at tasting
cannabis and so I brought them back some
stuff from here and it didn't look like
the stuff they usually get I think
because the stuff they usually get isn't
grown outdoors in Mendocino County and
they looked at it kind of they said oh
this doesn't look like what we usually
get and then they started to roll it and
say this is super sticky and then they
smoked it and they said this is the best
stuff we've ever had
yeah yeah and then the next time I went
on a road trip they came with me this is
just this is special this is being here
as special working with people who who
grow the plant is special I just I
really do feel like it's an honor to be
part of this industry and I'm just glad
to be here with you so let's go thank
you I really want to take the
conversation specifically into genetic
resources I think from an appellations
perspective it's really kind of the
heart and soul of the designation
because it's really the plant in the
product where the place the practices
the the cultural knowledge behind how
the plant is produced and loved and
nurtured into a product really expresses
through the cultivar and cannabis is
such a responsive plant it responds so
personally to our endocannabinoid system
to the environment that we're
cultivating in and our practices I think
it's really kind of the heart and soul
of how we differentiate ourselves and
and how these appellation of origin
designations will come into bearing
fruit for us and there's a number of
threats to our biodiversity real quick
I'd like to see a show hands for the
breeders in the house there's a lot of
people here thank you so much for all
your work
we wouldn't be here without you
really so we're facing you know first of
all it's an annual plant right and so
the the risk to losing our cultivar
lines is already high right from the
start as an annual and then we're facing
regional bands where before we had the
capacity to cultivate under you know
previous our previous you know
regulatory regime we've got hemp coming
forward and that you know does pose a
risk to our cultivars as we transition
rapidly and to have cultivars
you know there's a number of things
facing really like threatening our
genetic resources and so I think it's
important to really contextualize this
is as like the first priority when we're
working to really establish our
appellation of origin protections and
really build the tools that we need to
meaningful meaningfully protect our
cultivars moving forward and you know to
look at the international context
because appellation of origin is an
international protection there's a
number of ways that the world bodies
have frames avenues of protection for
our work right so you look at the World
Health Organization and there's
international policy tools around rights
of access to traditional medicine this
is a traditional medicine right that
we've been really nurturing over the
decades and I think it's really
important to remember that there's
traditional knowledge embedded in the
work that we're doing traditional
cultural perspectives and expressions
and these are the things that we're
protecting last year there was a pretty
amazing piece of policy that was
approved by the UN it's the declaration
on the rights of peasants and other
working people in rural areas and their
specific language in there to protect
our genetic resources and recognition
about how that's a bedrock of rural
economies and agrarian economies and so
I want to put those thoughts forward and
understand that we're creating an
appellation of origin system not for
wine but for a traditional medicine and
so there's a unique perspective and set
of considerations that we need to put
into this work as we frame these
protections not just for the producers
and the consumers but for the patients
right because how we produce our
medicine and what genetics where we're
working with and how those express in
the diverse expression of cannabinoids
and terpenoids defore front of how we're
building our appellation of origin
system so really wanted to put some some
love out for the history of medical
cannabis advocacy and how we've all
gotten here over the decades and really
give thanks to that aspect of the plant
as a as a healing healing plant
so with genetic preservation it's uh
it's it's all about the details so for
instance with Platt plant patenting what
you would do is you would characterize
these genetics the big question that we
need to figure out is what genetics grow
well in specific regions and for what
purposes and that's the thing there's
there's no research into that you know
there's neighborhoods where someone may
have been developing a varietal for you
know a decade two decades three decades
but we don't have the research to know
what variety is going to perform better
in this coastal environment versus this
inland climate and for what reasons now
we have the farmers are the ones who
have that data so really man this whole
conversation we should leave politics
out of it because this is all about
representing the farmers the farmers are
the ones who have this information
they're the ones who have this
experience you know most farmers were
afraid to write down notes you couldn't
keep data records of your yields you
know I remember being at a poker game
where someone was talking about all the
records that they have from their
harvest and trimming records and they
got laughed out of the room because
these guys are like dude you're gonna if
they raid your house you're gonna get
indicted and they're gonna have all this
information on all these genetics
records so we used to have notebooks and
you know have them buried in the woods
with all the the trimming records data
collection analysis on on breeding and
phenotype characterization we would bury
that in the woods and literally have to
hike 15 minutes anytime we wanted to see
a note on a phenotype the next time
we're making a breeding selection round
so the thing is it's a big discussion of
how do we know what varieties are gonna
grow best in what regions and it's kind
of like this is brand-new we need to
bring farmers together and compare notes
first this area verse this area and you
know there's gonna be some science
that's gonna need to be applied to it
which is a very difficult thing for
growers to start to get into that notion
of applying science to their their
intuition which has come from their
instinct and intuitive experience and
relationship with the plants so it's a
whole new spectrum but I think the first
part of it is starting to characterize
these genetics beyond like oh is it into
Costa Teva or a hybrid or gross like
this we need to get into what are the
textures to the flavor profiles and the
details of the cannabinoid
and the terpenes and how do those
cannabinoids and terpenoids for for what
reasons and and beyond that just
characteristic you know the the vigor
the structure is it symmetrical is it
elongated is there you know a redness to
the stem all that needs to be it's like
the next step of cannabis genetics it's
it's intense and it's interesting
because you know cannabis growers
sometimes are you know people who keep
to themselves and are way out in the
hills starting to interact with
attorneys you know people who have that
experience I mean that's the next step
it's coming together the problem is when
you take people from outside of cannabis
you always need to question their
intentions why are they doing this and
what do they want out of this and you
know everybody wants to support their
families and make a living and there is
going to be people who come in from
outside industries with the intentions
of I want to help these people preserve
their work I want to help them do it
right but we also need to be careful for
people who are coming into it for the
wrong reasons so yeah can we talk about
trust issues we need to talk about trust
right because we got some serious that
there are some serious trust problems in
right I mean the thought before we go
into protecting genetic you have a pool
of genetics that is unique and amazing
the problem that that pool of genetic
are in the oils and you're going
whatever they're going down south which
you shouldn't do so you're going son
gone genetic wedding cake and all the
stuff that everybody else and his
brother is going and you're competing
with the same genetic with some with
indoor it's not the solution because you
have much better so if you could go back
and take what you have in your cupboard
and then took all those data of the old
good old days and bring back the
genetics that created everything that we
actually smoking today and that is
weaker than their parents and
grandparents and great-grandparents you
you have
seeing that is unique and it's not
really a loom because you don't let you
see it spend the winter in the inner
ground that's you need that you need
that full cycle of the genetic if you
really want your plan to become heirloom
and become the place where it it did ago
you need to understand the value of the
genetic because like Gen inside
so first things basically that they
didn't you in an inner in a wine
industry when they created all those
appellation it's a classification of
quality so that jelly when there is no
standout of quality which is the best of
the best going in specific region in
specific farm then everything else that
come into play in your own region have
to be able to keep Zeus down down
everything that is not Zeus Tonda have
nothing to do in your territory so that
the source of everything is you I'm so
dependent on you it's silly I'm like a
winemaker and I shouldn't even have my
name on the packaging the name on my
packaging the ashes made it's yours when
I was traveling in producing country
nobody can really much that I made the
US but they were asking me which Valley
wish amulet which altitude and this is
long race you have so much more value
because beyond the farmer actually tell
Wow it's long it's a climate it's a
genetic but it's more than the thermal
it's a community around the farmer
actually the farmer is the part of the
osmosis but that community around that
farmer is super important for for the
quality literally of the product so it's
like you really have to to realize how
valuable you are and how valuable
everything you have is
and bring it back on the market because
that's what makes you different from
anywhere in the world and I've been to
quite a few producing country yeah and
before me before diving into trust
issues I want to take a minute to you
know Frenchy is probably the one of the
more if not the most travel the Heche a
scene that I know I've been to a handful
of these countries to also in my
wanderings and and it's absolutely true
you know the the diversity here the
biodiversity the culture genetics I
agree is step one for the the fact that
there are so many external threats to
our genetics we have to start by
protecting what is most threatened but I
don't think by any means that genetic
stands apart from the other elements of
what makes good cannabis good I think
microclimate climate is very important I
think culture standards the way that the
communities are structured the way that
we share information the way that we
treat ideas wisdom and experience as
things that can raise everybody as
opposed to something to privatize and
take and so again it goes back to some
of those fundamental questions of how we
structure social institutions and how we
structure our businesses you know when
we start to talk about the commercial
aspect of it speaking specifically to
genetics and I don't mean to be terribly
doom and gloom but climate is changing
my you know my family's varietal of
afghani that we've localized to our tiny
little sliver of the natal mid metal
honey dew dry creek upper east branch of
the dry creek if we get really technical
about it
that afghani is not growing the same in
that watershed as it was when I was 10
you know that that's been our family
farm family ranch what ever since I was
seven it doesn't grow the same there
anymore and yeah we're 30 generations
deep into it but the climate is changing
around us and so there's this impulse
that I have to preserve protect and hold
and I'm finding myself very often
needing to focus on the mantra of adapt
evolve and flow as well and they they
they it's nice that it takes
so comfortably to our culture but I find
sometimes that articulating these things
really helps me realize them and bring
them into shared space and so we do need
to be attentive to the changing
conditions around us I know you know
just not to bring too much politics in
it I know cdfw and the water board are
kicking our asses to some degree but
it's for a reason and our culture and
our processes need to be adaptable
enough to continue to persist I am
incredibly thankful that cannabis is so
diverse that it expresses itself so many
different ways sometimes it's
frustrating that it expresses itself so
many different ways really wanted the
HOS ones to be you know that that
particular expression and they weren't
and that can be a drag etc but we have
this very very very dynamic core of
genetic material core of experience of
narrative and culture and being able to
both hold on to that and preserve it and
keep it safe and steward it be the
guardians of it like we've always been
while also acknowledging that the world
is changing around us both regulatorily
commercially but also just fundamentally
climatologically changing
it's a tricky tricky intersection to be
in but this is the community to be in
that crossroads and and let's let's keep
at it and I didn't mean to derail from
the Tres conversation I think it's
really critical I just wanted to mention
those few key points oh I'm glad you did
I'm glad you did and I don't want to
have this turn into a conversation about
trust instead of the topic but I think
it ties into the topic because I think
protecting genetics there is a need to
reassess trust I'll tell you one of the
first in-person client meetings I had
with a with a nursery the the person I
was meeting with told me that he was
evaluating whether to protect any of his
any of his cultivars any of his genetics
and he said that he had one that was
pretty valuable that he liked a lot and
he gave some clones to somebody on kind
of a handshake agreement that this guy
would pay him per clone
and he never saw any money he figured
that the clothes that that particular
strangest never went anywhere I'm using
strain in the vernacular sense we can
use cultivar I'm not as as obsessed with
that as some people are and I'm actually
going to update my blog about that but
he said that a year later he saw that
very cultivar in a catalog his buddy's
catalog so he called his friend and said
hey we had a deal and his friend said
you know I got I got employees I got
bills to pay you know how things are
sorry
done that was the end of the
conversation they didn't have a written
agreement he didn't have any IP
protection and he thought he knew who he
could trust but he he was he made a
mistake things change we all know you
know we're not here to rehash Philo's
but we know that you think you know who
you can trust and then and then things
change you if you grew up in the some of
my favorite breeders the ones that grew
up breeding the plant in the 70s and 80s
and you absolutely knew you couldn't
trust the government so the last thing
you want to do is trust the government
to seek intellectual property protection
but guess what that's that's who grants
intellectual property protection so it's
time to just kind of reassess I'm not
even I'm not even going to tell you who
to trust I'm just saying reassess your
trust
think about who to trust and then I
think that's a really great point sorry
I just wanted to speak to that really
quickly I don't think it's as much about
trust as it is about you know what are
our methodologies in place what are our
filters right what are our resources so
that we have the education and the
understanding you know behind what the
tools are that we can protect and how to
negotiate our contracts and I want to
give a shout out to the trade
associations because they're really here
to serve you as an industry and
aggregate resources and bring that
education and that knowledge base to
pour your efforts in protecting your IP
developing your Appalachians and also
navigating contracting
I mean who of us you know has so much
experience with contract law you know
prior to five years ago right so there's
a whole cultural transition in place and
really looking to our local associations
as the bedrock to navigate in negotiate
policy contracts resources research you
know and looking really doing our due
diligence as individuals and as
communities and through our associations
to really vet you know what the tools
are in the filters through which we're
pursuing our research and our data
aggregation and our ownership and so you
know to that point I think is a really
important thing to keep in mind as a
resource and really support you know
your community through your trade
associations right so so that's good
there's a lot of good knowledge here I
respectfully agree with half of that I
disagree with the other half and and I
just wanted to say that Hezekiah point
on climate change is a really important
factor because I've only been in
California for ten years eleven seasons
that I've seen fall harvests of and I've
seen drastic changes in the way that
varieties perform you know and every
season is different if you have a hot
September two years ago it was 95 plus
degrees in my neighborhood for 21 days
in September so we have a delayed
ripening you know it's so the plants
think that it's the middle of the summer
again so that's that's a real challenge
to to consider in terms of the the local
trade organizations look when someone
starts devoting their time to something
there's a purpose it's either a selfless
purpose of giving back or they want
something out of it it can be both and
so the thing is I think for those trade
organizations who want both like
Hezekiah grew up in southern Humboldt so
I'm trying to preserve the community in
southern Humboldt where I'm still a
transplant you know it's like I finally
own my own place it's my dream but I
still consider myself an outsider
because there's people who sacrificed
way longer than I have so with these
trade associations there needs to be
more inclusion of the farmers because
how many of the farmers actually have
the information and how many of the
people in the trade association know all
the information but anyway just go into
the fun part and talking about plants
and genetics and preservation because I
thought it would be a lot more fun to
talk about weed and growing weed on this
panel then then you know all the the
politics and trade is
so genetic preservation for the future
in terms of the breeding or threat you
know preservation of genetics it's
really it's really two forms one is
through seed production and selection
and breeding programs which is that's
what I spend a lot of my time
daydreaming of since I was a little kid
and you know really liked to get into
and love to speak about and the other is
through clone propagation and
preservation however when you look at
what's happening with the clones like
when you mentioned wedding cake it's
like something becomes a popular variety
the market gets hot everybody gets it it
gets really oversaturated people don't
take good care of their mothers you know
and so there's always like the next
greatest thing so I think it's really
special when you find the varietals that
have been like you said your family's
been working genetics for 30 years the
people who started bringing you know
different Afghan ease into these regions
when people just used to grow sativas
that would come in their bag seed that
was shipped over by the Megaton from
South America and Colombia and it never
finished in time but in terms of clonal
propagation we now face all these new
challenges with with pests and pathogens
and disease if you compare it to other
industries
I think the banana industry is a really
good comparison where there's like
10,000 varietals of bananas but we only
use three of them because most of them
don't store well they have to be shipped
and transported across all these
countries and what happened I believe it
was in the 80s or 90s I'm no expert I
may be completely miss speaking but
basically a plant virus and pathogen
wiped out a ton of the commercial
produced banana varieties so what
Americans were eating as bananas in the
50s is not what we eat as bananas
because that species pretty much doesn't
exist anymore it it basically got taken
out by a pathogen so for the clones that
we have from the time that I showed up
all these pests you know powder mildew
Russert mites root a FIDs and now you
know unidentified plant pathogens and
viruses are now present in our
environment which is also due to global
warming so before I came here I had only
seen powdery mildew once most of my
neighbors had never seen powdery mildew
I I heard when they first started seeing
it they thought they were crystals on
the weed you know and if you look
there's a there's a University study out
of out of Mendocino from like 2011-2012
that each year the spore count for
Powder Mill
is dramatically increasing every single
year in the environment so farmers have
to be smarter about how to prevent that
and combat that by using you know
organic microbiology and living soils
but the paths and pathogens are really
the biggest risk because just you know
let me think of how to phrase this so
basically all these clones that we grow
they stay in people's mother rooms
people go through different treatments
even with some of the best organic
practices you can't you can't prevent
against certain bacterias and so it's
really important for us to start working
with science and thinking about micro
propagation which is essentially tissue
culture where we can bank these genetics
what can happen with technologies people
can clean the genetics for instance I
love Sour Diesel I've been growing it
since 2002 like back in the East Coast
and it's an old clone it's been around
since the 90s oh gee cush is from the
early 90s any grower in here who's grown
in sfv clone it's not fun or easy to
grow because it's been passed around you
don't know where it came from and
imagine what's gotten into it in terms
of pathogen disease and viruses with
tissue culture propagation you can take
that sfe clone it can be completely
wiped clean remove all the bacteria
essentially disinfecting it and then
when you get those back in tissue
cultures whether it's a mother or clones
for propagation for for your cultivation
it's clean it's like growing a seat for
the very first time ever so so it's
basically going to be through seed
production and proper preservation of
breeding practices in terms of keeping
things preserved but also maintaining
the diversity that's in the genetics
which is a very long conversation and
then in terms of clones starting to work
with micro propagation applications so
even if they're not going to be grown
out you don't need to keep all these
mothers around and we can start every
year producing you know tissue culture
mothers that start out with a clean
slate there's someone in northern
Humboldt that's been doing a lot of
research on these pathogens and he
showed me these graphs from field
research starting in 2009 through the
present time and he started with a few
areas where he would you know test the
tissue samples and basically you find
these stunted you know clones that
basically take two or three weeks to get
to get healthy to the point where you
can actually grow them effectively and
really talented growers find themselves
out growing this virus out growing this
pathogen by applying
you know good beneficial microbiology
and good sustainable organic soils and
practices like that but it's still there
when you get a clone from somebody back
I don't know man like nine out of nine
point nine nine nine out of ten times
the clone has issues and so this guy's
research has actually shown that he's
discovered a virus and you can see on a
graph we're starting in 2010 you know he
found it on a few samples in 2011 he
found more and then each year by 2012
2013 it was in every single sample of
tissue that he took from clones of
cannabis plants from all around the
Emerald triangle between my area Island
mountain all over Mendocino and Trinity
so in terms of preservation I do think
we need to we need to go to some greater
minds from the scientific community and
work collaboratively so that we don't
lose clone genetics because anybody
who's a grower or breeder in here has
probably lost something special to them
that you'll never get back like a last
of the mohicans variety and it's really
important for the future to be able to
preserve that so I saw it be more fun to
talk about weed and growing 100% thank
you well we're we're kind of getting
towards the end and I wanted to go ahead
and open it up to the audience if you
have questions shoot
but then opened up the conversation with
my father-in-law can you repeat the
question on so your question was legally
what's the first step of protecting all
those seeds you know that's a great
question and I'm gonna start with this a
lot of people wonder if what they have
is unique enough to protect and the the
easiest answer is every single every
single seed you ever plant is unique
enough to protect just and that might
sound crazy but you know no matter how
many children my parents had unless
they're twins we're all different we're
all unique enough to be different right
to be protected well the question is are
we worth protecting right and so the
real question is if you have something
that if you have a seat if you have a
plant that you've grown up
is it worth commercializing does it and
not just is it going to be worth
commercializing for more than a few
seasons if it's gonna be worth
seasons then you want to protect it and
then the question is are you likely to
make your money selling clones selling
seeds or just selling harvested material
if you're gonna sell flour and you're
never ever gonna need to sell plants so
never sell any kind of propagating
material you could if you were positive
that no genetic material would ever slip
out of your control you wouldn't even
need intellectual property protection of
course nobody's ever positive that's
going to happen but if you're if you're
never selling clones or seeds the best
thing to do the
easiest cheapest thing to do is get a
plant patent that's like a copyright on
a plant it's it's really not that hard
to get you don't have to have DNA you
don't have to have a whole lot to get
started you need a couple photos of the
plant you need a name that isn't your
trademark name what's the cost on that
to get started it cost
I don't yeah that's that's so it's
likely not worth the cost currently what
what I would recommend that you guys do
if it's important as a family heirloom
grow it out and do an open pollination
and make the next generation of seeds
but do the whole thing all the males all
the females call out the weaker ones
that way you have it and as your family
continues to grow it and if it's special
to you and you keep it preserved over
time the the need and value to protect
IP will come that'll happen if you prove
it in market but if it's just sacred for
your family open pollinated preserve it
store those seeds properly do it before
it's too late and you can't get them to
germinate maybe take some clone
selections and we've all lost stuff due
to human error you know it's like man if
you want something right do it yourself
but but that's what I would say keep it
within your family reproduce those seeds
so you have the next generation open
pollinate you know call out any of the
weaker plants and then if it proves
value in the market at some point when
people are starting to come for you to
find it
then talk to some lawyers then look into
protecting the IP it's it's too early to
do that and I completely agree you don't
want to spend money on IP until you know
that you've got something valuable the
only thing is if you're losing control
of if you're losing control of the
genetics that's when you it may already
be too late just just be careful about
that part can you own I have the next
question because it's he late how can
you patent a plant that she's on
schedule one
they didn't can get the last part out
can you patent a plant that is on
schedule one ah this is great the US
Patent and Trademark Office is not
concerned at all about legality or even
safety they leave that to other agencies
they've been granting patents on illegal
and unsafe things that
throughout their entire history so great
news with plant patents it's kind of
like bleep patents is like this all
right here's the real deal like if
you're a grower it's like who can own a
plant you know it's like that's how I
feel about you know all of this stuff
it's like what is your entitlement to
owning this like when I first owned land
I never thought that I would so I was
like man I own this land and then I went
to and I stood there and I go I don't
own this land you can't own a light you
can't own land
you know it's my job to steward preserve
it but just like like the Native
Americans and in you know cultures
throughout civilization it's like if
it's part of nature can we really own it
and then as you start to create and
adapt things that are more unique to you
that you've put effort into then you
start getting there but I just think
with Platt you know with patenting stuff
I mean it's like I said all of this is a
new intense discussion you know but I
think it's too early for cannabis and
unless it's really proving an
application and market and there's a
risk of it being infringed on I'm gonna
respectfully just point out that people
you don't own land because that land is
gonna be there long after you're gone
but people do build fences around their
land they stop people from building
roads across their land they stop people
from moving on to their land that's
exactly what a patent is a boundary
around what you've created so that
you're free to do what you want to do
with what you've created and you can you
can allow people to come onto your land
and to even live on it to have parties
on it whatever but if you don't exert
control over your land it's not your
land anymore by the same token if you
create some great variety you're free to
do what you want with it
but as soon as you utterly lose control
of that it's not really yours to decide
anymore and if you get a patent and I'm
not absolutely there most things that
are ever created are not worth patenting
but if you ever have something that
really is worth patenting and you don't
patent it you will lose your opportunity
to be the one that controls its destiny
is fate so that's like not putting a
fence around your land I'm gonna thread
a middle line here if I
while you're in the middle I think we
need to prevent other people from
patenting your stepfather I think
happens to be the source of my family's
afghani from from several decades ago
coincidentally not two we grew up very
close to one another and so I think we
need to stop somebody else from saying
no this is mine you can't have it we
need a way I mean and I'm obviously a
broken record I'm really good at getting
into obsessive obsessive grooves and my
obsessive groove currently is
cooperative cooperative ownership we I
agree we can't no nature it's a silly
concept it's part of why things are so
screwy in the world today we need to do
a better job of asserting our
responsibility to these varieties
varietals and our guardianship of them
actually owning it is very costly and
agree entirely with both of them that
like it's too soon we don't know but to
start establishing benchmarks and lines
in the sand around these shared assets
around these things that these
courageous heroes brought to us from you
know these land rate like this is a very
real community asset and and figuring
out where to set the balance between the
individual and the community and you
know to sort of Frenchie's opening
comments it's not just the farmer it's
the community around the farmer and that
to me is why I'm a broker so what he
said I think was really really valuable
information is the main purpose of why
people should protect us who's gonna
steal it from you and who's gonna take
it from you and you're really correct on
that because so you know the guy who
didn't show up today and all the
controversy with that I was really
hoping he was going to show up I was
gonna be very respectful but I was gonna
really drop some some knowledge for sure
and so the deal is the roots of that go
very deep this didn't just happen with
this Philo's thing in the last six
months or in the last year that
organization in that entity started in
2009 2010 they had Robert Clark and Sam
the skunkman
went on to these online forums of
cultivators and started asking to
collect people's genetic specimens of
landrace local varietals even in seed
form that they thought couldn't
germinate they still wanted that for
what they
calling a worldwide classification
program and this is all documented you
can find it all online so Philo's was
involved in all of this back in the day
and then my question was who's paying
for this because this is some really
forward-thinking technology so who's
who's putting up the money for that and
if you really start diving I mean I
don't care that much but if you really
look into it there's ties between
executives at GW Pharmaceuticals to that
whole structure of entities at that time
that was really ahead of everyone being
like look let's just get as much genetic
information as we can into our pockets
so that we can hopefully be the ones to
start adapting biopharmaceutical
products because that's the the whole
thing when you think about the forward
future of the industry we are gonna
learn certain cannabinoids and
terpenoids
might cure diseases they might have
incredible medical applications that can
better humanity but it's going to be
biopharmaceutical geoengineering that's
those are the companies who have the
applications the ability to do that and
so it's just it's a very mixed thing
about I feel the emotions but in terms
of people who want our genetics all of
the biggest agricultural companies in
the entire world Bayer SCI genta
Monsanto Cargill every one of them you
know when people talk about Omar Abreu
Philip Morris is buying up land people
talked about that 20 years ago and they
were probably doing it it's not a
conspiracy they're smart
forward-thinking massive conglomerates
that can crawl control the whole world
you know on some conspiracy stuff so
that is what we do need to protect
ourselves from and it's like those
people are coming into this industry
they're doing it they've been doing it
they've been doing it for over a decade
they were smart and they stayed real
silent now some of it is bubbling up but
who knows where they've been in
investing and figuring out and then the
thing is can growers like us can we do
all that stuff without joining them
because it's like you don't want to join
them if you can't beat them do you have
to join them we don't know yet but it
that's that's the conversation in terms
of protecting our genetics which was
really smart it's like it's too early
for us to go there we don't have the
funds but we need to make sure that
someone else doesn't steal your family's
life's work because there's people
already trying to do things like that
thank you I appreciate it okay so let's
take another question from the audience
and let's go with Frank the only way to
really please paraphrase the question
for the video folks um is there a way to
collectively or broken record
cooperatively owned a seed and genetics
Bank is like if silo I put all the data
they had taken from everything that was
given to you available for the public
then it's okay to share but everybody
has access to it then it's really
worthwhile because like like a they can
say it's and usage way that plot is way
beyond possessing it while you need to
protect your yourself so dealing with an
OTT that puts it available to the public
it's a big deal I take it personally
because Robert clouds that I respect a
lot asked me to ask you to give sample
Sam's or skunk man sent me GM personally
to ask you Mowgli ask me to ask you
personally and I love you to death and I
need you like nobody else but I cannot
give I cannot touch to that level it's
like I cannot give my world and take
something from you that I know it is so
precious and give it to an OTT when I'm
not sure that those data are available
for everybody but yes there absolutely
is it wasn't a planted question I swear
but it might as well have been our dear
colleague Casey isn't here he had a
wedding to go to but you know one of the
first things that Casey did back in 2014
with Emerald grown we're a mutual
benefit meaning all of our assets can
only be used for the common benefit of
all of the memory members was start a
seed bank and
free open swap and exchange seedbank it
has been a tough time for growers the
last couple years we've been about as
spread thin as we can be
I think we're turning the corner on that
and I think we're moving into a new era
where we will have the capacity to
formalize some of these institutions
looking forward to talking to the
colleague here about how those types of
cooperative ownership structures might
help serve us but but making sure that
our community protects our common assets
from the oncoming threats is I think the
bottom line and your question is spot-on
yes there is a way to structure that yes
there is a way to do that I think it's
really important that it's possible to
collectivise individual IP assets and
put them into a pool that can be
asserted as a defense if anybody gets
taken on by big AG that the collective
could kind of form a counterbalance and
I think that's an important yeah I think
that's a really excellent point and you
know to your point around trade
associations I think you know just like
any partnership right if you're working
with a company you're working with an
institution you're working with trade
associations
it's about standards right standards of
how we do business standards of what our
agreements are and I think it's up to
all of us to do our due diligence and
really follow the money you know where
is the money coming from how are we
evaluating this data moving forward and
and how is that piece coming back to the
community and so I think that is
everyone's individual job to really do
that due diligence and really look at
you know who we're partnering with and
really what are what are the tools were
working with and where's the balance of
how we're exchanging resources in that
context so we're about 20 minutes over
time and so we're down is we're down to
keep going no one's telling us to get
out of here so let's go ahead and with
one more question
[Music]
[Applause]
they know everything
what are they gonna do with that data
all these things
he's got pushing up there okay yeah but
it's also important in your real health
I think we need the looking of
participatory plant breeding programs
there's a lot of data on this there's a
lot of information out there look it up
kitv's or awesome we need the farmers
association the farmers to get together
with the Appalachian groups we need
those cultivars that you've got to get
in and protected in the appellations of
origin as our cultivars as historical
representations of what we're trying to
prevent even if we can't get it into the
patent system and even if that's not
necessarily the greatest value added or
you know money proposition we need to
figure out multiple strategies that
start with farmers working with local
breeders collecting all that data and
using our local trade associations and
like all this we need to get over
differences like there's all sorts of
camps going back decades in the cannabis
world we fight incessantly and we got to
get over that shit because sales article
was incredible
[Applause]
[Music]
I agree yeah she was man it's a lot of
it's a lot of question but she was
saying you know how can we develop those
processes of getting the communities and
the farms together with some of the some
of the organizations or companies that
actually have the resources or assets to
help collect all this data and use it
responsibly to benefit everyone in the
right ways with positive intentions and
I think it's already happening this
discussion is a part of this your
organization which is done really
amazing work and come up into my
neighborhood and gotten people to show
up at the firehouse who like would never
even consider showing up at a meeting
like that so it's it's about dialogue
reaching out to each other and
connecting and that's the thing about
weed is like weed culture used to be
like you had to be down now everybody
thinks they're in it and they're not you
know so it's a it's definitely about a
dialogue the folks who have the
resources and the assets need to reach
out to the communities or the leaders of
those communities you know and and
that's it man it's a dialogue a
discussion and starting more meetings in
organizations because that's one of my
missions there's so much crazy cool sea
genetics that I you know haven't even
seen people produce in five or six years
and all these people that have these
collections and I want to see those come
back into the light I want people to see
the amazing terpenes that they've never
experienced so so you're right that has
to happen I think it already is and it's
just encouraging people to collaborate
and and you know and be selfless in
terms of like let's just have more
conversations like this so there's two
really firm strategies and two things we
need to be absolutely mindful of in my
opinion first and foremost the reason
the appellation law notes varietal is
because the intention is to document
catalog and snapshot where we are now in
the public record that is a public asset
you can't undo that document and library
except sort of maybe Elinor it might
correct me which okay so first and
foremost public if it is a public
institution it is for the public benefit
secondly ownership and control how the
company is structured a private company
can and will liquidate assets if you the
farmers don't own the
Bini in part it's probably not going to
have your interests in heart at the end
of the day and so obviously the farmers
don't have the capital structuring
partnerships very very carefully between
farmer and financier is a way to move
forward but if the bottom line communal
farmer ownership doesn't exist it's
probably not a good strategy so public
ownership farmer ownership cooperative
shared ownership are very important
strategies and structures to to really
like trust at the end of the day back it
up and and then you want eco nation
because when what you give us
extractor everybody in the industry what
we receive we owe it to you if you don't
receive credit for what you give us it
doesn't work you need to be able to
create a market where the credit is
given back to the origin of the product
and must extract oil if you do a red pen
and yeah you want to do big number but
when you buy your biomass in Salinas or
when you buy your biomass in mandu or
ambled
it's not quite the same it's not quite
the same biomass and because you have a
world recognition you have to walk this
you so won't know that you go the best
you you need to be aware of that when
you sell your product already you sell
it to chip but on top of it they don't
give you credit for the quality that
they recognize for is that you need at
least to ask for your name on the
packaging you don't care if it of a pen
you don't care if it's a chocolate you
don't care whatever it comes from your
farm and that name on the packaging is
actually promotion and marketing
worldwide power for all those companies
that feed on you so it's like it's you
need to protect yourself but you
to be aware of the value of what you
protect and there is no deal that not
get doesn't give you credit back because
you use a center of that new and just
Helia being born the breeder and the
grower need to become the brand I really
believe that nourishing the lawn and the
climate we coexist with them and can
create something that is different and
better than other it's all the origin we
are just visitor but when you when you
buy your great cheese great wine any
great agricultural product in that place
because that's that's amazing value of
it that world living soul and being in
osmosis well what you live that's what
he make quality that you cannot
duplicate
and
so just real quick practices that's it's
in the statute we have another panel
coming up in two minutes so we're gonna
have to wrap this I really thank
everyone for spending your time to have
the conversation let's give a big round
thank you hey
anyway lastly I did bring some seeds to
give to some folks I didn't bring enough
for everybody but I have some sot some
seeds from my collection I'll just leave
them here if anybody wants some free
seeds as a gift for showing up