[Music]
welcome to our pro athletes and cannabis
panel this is also for anybody that's an
athlete whether you're 80 years old and
you go for a walk in the evening like if
you're a runner you like to swim
whatever anybody can use cannabis with
in athletics so we're quite lucky to
have these high end professional
athletes up here with us but at the end
of the day this this information
translates to everybody in the room so I
always like to analogize that we've got
these top pros but I'll be the average
Joe up here and all of you can listen
from my perspective as well and I also
really call this panel marijuana
rebranded it's really I think since the
year 2000 when y2k the world didn't end
everybody kind of started to doubt their
certain things and people collectively I
think woke up conscious wise in America
to the fact we were being lied to about
cannabis that's when the culture shift
really to me 2000 happened and now 18
years later it's a beautiful place to
see where we are today
the true rebrand really marijuana was a
drug it was bad for you bad people used
it it made you lazy made you stupid and
even the word itself marijuana just I'm
sure most of us know the connotations
behind the word we're not positive so
now cannabis is a medicine and cannabis
is used for wellness and to help people
and to fix seizures and enlightened
people use cannabis so on that note on
the light of enlightenment I'm going to
start off by letting our panelists
starting with Al here introduce
themselves instead of me doing that and
just I guess the way I'd love for you to
introduce yourself is tell us who you
are and then tell us really ultimately
the most important part why you're here
today
well how're you doing my name is al
harrington former NBA player i played 17
years professional basketball from ARS
new jersey now reside here in los
angeles
I live on vacation I love it here but
you know what I'm doing here today
obviously is just to continue to raise
awareness about the unbelievable
benefits of cannabis and you know quick
on my story you know I told you I grew
up in Jersey so you know the war on
drugs was really real you know where I
grew up I had seen people getting locked
up or I was always taught to believe
that cannabis or marijuana at the time
or reefer as I was you know happy we
should talk about it where I'm from was
a gateway drug
so you know throughout my whole life you
know and especially you know me going
you know to the NBA out of high school I
was always afraid of cannabis and when I
got in the NBA that was the first time
that I saw actually like you know
top-notch players actually using
cannabis but at the time I still didn't
understand it so that makes sense to me
and I look down on our teammates that
use cannabis but in 2011 my grandmother
had come to see me play when I was
playing for the Denver Nuggets and you
know Denver is obviously one of the
first markets to you know have medical
program and she suffered from glaucoma
and you know glaucoma was always the
first you know thing that cannabis was
you know they actually healed was I you
know was it was something that I said
it's a hill so I was able to convince
her to try cannabis and it was hard
because you know she was the main person
growing up telling us that you know we
was a was a gateway drug and um when I
was able to get her to try it and I
checked on our hour and a half later and
uh when I went downstairs she was
downstairs reading her Bible and you
know when I asked her how she was doing
she said I'm healed she that's the first
time I've been able to read my Bible in
over three and a half years and for me
that correlation was just crazy that you
know from someone like her and I always
say like it my grandmother is not going
to heaven we're all going to hell and
you know for the first thing that she
would do would actually go down and read
her Bible
you know she spoke volumes to me and at
that point I started to educate myself
the end of that season I actually had a
knee surgery and got a staph infection
and I was in the hospital for you know
ten days I have you know four surgeries
in a week and at some point I thought I
was gonna die but uh when I was sitting
in there you know obviously I'm taking
all this pain medication and this lady
that I had knew in Colorado came to see
me and she introduced me to CBD and she
gave me all these topical she gave me
tinctures capsules
and you know ever since that day I
haven't taken a hat spring
I haven't taken an advil I haven't taken
any pharmaceutical drugs to manage my
pain away from the game and uh you know
pretty much that's my story and that's
why I'm here though our story is great
and gems and everybody's up here and I
think the reason I'm in cannabis is
because ask a lot I ask a lot of
questions and do a lot of listening and
if you do that you can hear countless
stories of lives this changes my name is
Matt Nordgren
I run a fund called Arcadian we do a lot
of investing in the industry I've been
doing that for years have been very
successful at it also was a former
athlete some were probably in between
Joe and out Jim and al I was a backup
quarterback my whole career so a little
bit of an average Joe that was around a
lot of high level athletes and so you
know didn't have to use a lot of it for
pain but was around a lot of guys that
did for the for a long time and and
really saw a lot of benefit that it did
give a lot of athletes I used it as well
in my own personal story my grandmother
had Alzheimer's were able to help her
quality of life at the end of her life
had a couple of cousins with cancer was
able to increase their life have quality
of their life at the end of their life
all three have passed and so not just
hearing other people's stories but you
end up experiencing some of your own and
I think these are the types of things
that make this industry work so we got
into it it has been one heck of an
economic benefit that's for sure but it
feels really good being an industry that
you can do good business and feel good
about the business that you're doing
every day
[Applause]
hello oh there we go
hi uh hi everyone my name is Eliza
Maroney I am the co-founder of Lucky box
club a cannabis subscription service
here in California yes we actually do
deliver actual products to your doorstep
and I'm also known as the cannabis yogi
so I've launched a brand that infuses
yoga classes with cannabis in various
different ways every attendee receives a
lucky box one of our boxes and they get
to learn about new brands and products
in the process before during and after
their classes it gives people a really
warm intimate space to experiment with
new products and to learn about the
different ways of using cannabis and CBD
as well we have CBD only boxes and I am
in this because I just like everyone
else I think in this room have been
profoundly moved by this amazing
incredible plant in many different ways
so my history does stem back to being a
cultivator and going from cultivation
into retail and really understanding the
entire plant process and I'm really
proud of that I am not a professional
athlete I'm the only one on this stage
right now but I do have a lot of insight
in how cannabis can enhance performance
and it can also help people to heal
after post-workout and and and games I
would imagine so thank you here focused
on this industry um I play for the 49ers
that's who drafted mean the kind of my
introduction to the industry firsthand
nurse and then then uh Seahawks in the
center the Redskins so we I mean we got
a company started a couple years ago
initially my dad and a couple partners
so now we're transferring which we're
translating I'm tripping right now so no
we're switching over from agro to of
manufacturing facility so that's where
our primary focus is right now and
the reason I'm really big on marijuana
is just not just me it's my family we as
a whole we believe that gonna benefits
of it not just physically but for like
your mental well-being and with my
history on footballs mean I played
linebacker and free safety at Florida
State and then in the league so I've had
plenty injuries dislocated shoulders
broken bones concussions disc issues
arthritis so I've had pretty much just
about anything you can imagine so my
thing is like the benefits of the just a
plan itself them wanting to restrict us
from being able using prescribed as
opiates that's a big contradiction in my
opinion and that's what I'm kind of
getting to more so now is the advocacy
for that and then the Wellness and the
THC and the CBD as well so that's why
I'm here I'm no Gary Vee but I
occasionally swear just as with just a
warning and I wanted to say it must feel
fucking good to be able to come out of
the closet of cannabis and not have the
NFL breathing down your neck
that was huge because personally for my
experience I was God I was actually in
the drug program so I got put in there
for two years and I put in there well I
failed the test and then I was placed in
there so that comes along with I was
tested twice a week every week so of up
to eight times a month it would come
6:00 in the morning 3:00 in the
afternoon Saturday mornings ask you
where you are you got to give him a log
of your travel so my actually had family
members and friends that I've actually
been on probation they had less
restrictions and I did but just being in
that process and seeing other guys go
through that process and then just that
you actually kind of really realized how
much cannabis does help you in terms of
your injury and then de-stress and like
dealing with the stress of being a pro
athlete the family demands and all that
stuff and then when you have that taken
from you when it's somebody when you're
somebody actually relies on that you
don't even realize you rely on it but it
does really help you then you kind of
see like the negative outcome or then
sometimes you'll be in certain
situations or we wouldn't even have been
in that when if you were allowed to
still be able to use cannabis I've seen
different guys get into situations when
they mature program where they start
doing things they wouldn't never
normally do and they were just like
completely different people in honestly
I think that with the NFL program they
kind of do more detriment than they do
good when they restrict us and then
trying to tell you what to do and this
is how you need to act and you got to
follow these rules and you can't act
like everybody else even
you're no person but you gotta act this
certain way I mean while some of the
guys that have give writing the checks
they do some of the wildest stuff you
can imagine no you guys ever watch
ballers before I live in mind you said
it this was pretty awesome
well no I agree with you two men and
really that makes a poignant port point
when you are caught using cannabis
you're almost then put over a threshold
to have to take opiates for pain because
you can't use a natural remedy there's a
friend of mine named Marvin Washington
that played as well and and I think he's
in the process of filing some form of
lawsuit you know against the NFL for for
forced addiction when they don't give
you a solution and yeah it really does
sadly pushes you guys when you can when
you have no other option you know pills
are the only thing to do when you're
playing that hard and being hurt so
cheers to you and congrats prone on
retirement okay
so quickly I'll go over what I do in the
Athletics in cannabis field very quickly
I put on an athletic tour around the
country
somewhat like Tough Mudder or Spartan
Race called the 420 games we compete we
do yoga 4.20 mile runs Jiu Jitsu big al
coach to three-on-three basketball
tournament here in Venice last March and
so we go out and we do the opposite of
what people think when they hear
cannabis we go bein be active we bring
our families our kids and we don't smoke
at the events and we talk about stuff
like this at the events things like
cannabis is an alternative to opiates I
have an edible line called cannibal can
a fleet and it's an edible product it's
a spray for before you workout for focus
and it's a post recovery serum and then
lastly I tried very hard last year to
open the world's first cannabis gym with
Ricky Williams it was called power plant
fitness it's a venture on the Shelf that
we hope to eventually bring into
fruition where the trainer's understand
how to use cannabis and help you you
know figure out if it is or it isn't for
you and and that's an important point I
want to touch on I don't think cannabis
on well actually I'm going to back up
there are are really two ways athletes
use cannabis you can really delineate it
in two very defined manners and one most
people understand his recovery CBD you
know you hurt you smoke you feel better
and we're gonna go into that for sure
today on the opiate side of things but
I've always enjoyed it for focus
I've always liked to smoke before I go
into the gym before I swim before I ski
before I surf and it gives me something
you know that's a focus that I don't
normally have it really translates
across my life with a DD like when I was
in college I smoked to write my term
papers and I just needed it almost for a
focus you know ie a medicine versus to
get high so there's really two ways
focus athletes can use it for training
or during athletics or they can use it
for recovery so I wanted to kind of
actually like Matt for example
did you ever use cannabis during your
career when you were training or during
a game yeah Jim both the categories you
just mentioned used it for and so did a
lot of the guys I don't know I mean in
our sport I would imagine the numbers
have got to be 60% of the players
probably York higher maybe NBA it's
probably what like 95.9 yeah I mean it's
you know either way it's a significant
amount of people that benefit from using
this for both of those areas I did and
and I saw a lot of guys do it Jim anyone
else want to chime in on focus the at
the aspect of using cannabis to get the
what I call I of the tiger me in
particular I like to use it to focus for
me it's like it takes away the
nervousness and the butterflies so it
just kind of makes me feel like you do
go out there every day in practice
there's another day nothing out of the
ordinary just makes everything normal
easy what I like to liken it to is to
everything in life there's something
called flow state and whether you're an
athlete whether you're a musician
whether you're an artist having sex
anything when you're just your mind goes
away and your body just becomes one with
your mind that's called flow State
that's why artists have always been kind
of let you know let to be that sect that
used cannabis and psychedelics and even
the surf community
and whatnot so flow state is something
again I like to translate this beyond
just athletics and why cannabis really
it's a good for athletes and fitness but
it correlates across our whole life to
allow us to enjoy things like athletics
it makes the things you love it allows
you to love them a little bit more and
appreciate them a little bit more so so
on the focus side of things
I think we kind of covered it I think
you know al you've mentioned before you
don't like to use cannabis before you
train and again I want to hear from Al
because I don't think everybody should
use cannabis and it's important to hear
from someone who maybe it doesn't affect
in the best way before they get in the
gym yeah for me so I'm an indica smoker
so I like to smoke the heavy stuff so
I'd go sit down and chill out so that's
the reason why for me like you know
obviously for me to consume right before
trying to do anything especially
athletics is probably not the right
thing now most people say well chew
straw sativas so I've tried the tea bus
and then sativas make my heart race so I
was in a lose-lose so that's why I
actually choose not to you know consume
before but um you know I don't knock it
I've actually started to be able to kind
of control it now you know because I use
so much you know I've been using this a
lot so like now I actually can smoke
indicas and actually get stuff done I
have four kids so I have to medicate
before I deal with them so uh so I've
changed I've changed a little bit jump
but you like that another point on that
Jimmy and the interesting thing is just
being able to figure out what works for
you because it's the amount of products
that are coming to the market now you
can sort of experiment and do just what
Al did and no one person is alike I mean
our chemical makeup is so different our
systems work so different that it's just
important to continue to figure out what
works for you and what environment yeah
you know that's something I wanted to
touch on and and I think al if indicas
you know are more sleepy and heavy to
you that's a great way that you know
yourself you know what you want in your
medicine and you know when to use it and
to me the one thing I'd like to try and
debunk to as much as I can we've got dr.
sue Sisley here in the front
today hey dr. sue let's give sue a hand
I might even ask you a question right
now
but you know there's a long myth in my
opinion that indica means one thing in
sativa means the other meaning that
indicas had heavy and it makes you
sleepy and a sativa is an energizing
cannabis you know result and what Matt
just said is truthfully to me what's
most important everybody especially I'm
saying this because we're talking about
fitness and cannabis knowing what works
for you is way more important than hey
bro do you have an indica or sativa so
it's like understanding your body type
and then how cannabis works but you know
from a science standpoint the the myth
has really been shown that indica does
not necessarily mean one thing and
sativa doesn't and the easiest way to
understand that is two people can smoke
the same plant and they feel completely
opposite so it's really about knowing
yourself especially within athletics in
terms of what type of cannabis you use
and when I'm in on this one because it's
something I love talking about but it's
really interesting to see that it's
really not indica sativa anymore and now
that we're learning so much about
terpenes and different cannabinoids and
even how our endocannabinoid receptor
system works I mean there's so much
research that has not happened yet right
because it has been federally illegal so
this is something that we're just now
touching the surface and it's really
important to understand that there are
different ways to also apply cannabis to
your workout I mean it sounds like you
should be using topicals like topicals
are amazing and people don't give it
enough credit there are so many ways for
your body to benefit from cannabis as
well as tinctures understanding CBD
versus CBN and how you can use blends
and creating your own blend there it
really goes deep and I don't want to go
off on a tangent but just pointing out
that there's so much more than just
smoking or vaping nowadays and and its
really a blessing that we have all of
these options even patches I've been
saying lately you know well yeah and
what I take from you dialing it dialing
it right into this is that you really
have a lot of options to choose exactly
what
type of medicine to get you where you
want to be and so again I just think
it's starting slow is important and let
in this room I just a show of hands I'm
interested who likes to use cannabis
before they go for a run or they do
something athletic so it's about half
and half very interesting all right well
so cannabis has also been proven to be a
neuro protectant and that's something I
kind of want to touch on and delve into
the CBD side of things you know we've
got big x pro athletes that played
football here and then we've got a yogi
and we've got al who played basketball
where you get banged around pretty darn
good and so we all use CBD in different
ways in a recovery facet but Matt do you
want to talk a little bit about CBD as a
neuro protectant and how like a football
player uses CBD both you know prior to
injury as well as post traumatic injury
yeah that would be I'd love to talk
about that in particular as my father
was a pro football player and as was I
you know i grew up around all of these
players from the 60s and 70s so i get to
see it at 50 60 70 years old the
repercussions and these guys are in
tremendous amounts of pain almost none
of them aren't in some kind of pain and
head trauma is a lot of it maybe we
ought to give dr. sue more money so she
can figure some of these things out but
you know we to see my generation now see
the past generations downfall and you've
seen the movies I mean it's it's a
really important topic for us all think
about CBD is a great way to do it a non
psychoactive molecule you can derive it
from hemp or cannabis and with Mitch
McConnell's efforts we're about to have
him legal federally thank God we think
very soon so it's going to be tough for
the NFL to not recognize that in other
sports but I think that there's a lot of
different types of CVD as she talked
about you kind of have to figure out
which one's good for you there's some
great brands we can suggest I think as a
neuro
protector you know we would I'd see guys
using it literally ten minutes before
game time and it's because CVD doesn't
take away from their ability to use
their minds as much as THC might so I've
seen that but I've also seen Jim a lot
of guys using it on mondays get day
after games to do more of the
rehabilitation efforts and and I think
rather than being pumped full of all
these medicines that they would prefer
to give you which I know you can talk
about and dr. sue and Mike James who's
got some great stories out there can
tell you about and I've get playing
football I get tammany these minor
concussions you get I mean every time
you get hit you just assume like you
shake it off but there are little
concussions and we've all had the real
ones I mean they knock it lights out so
a real thing and so if CVD can be
helpful in these efforts it's it's
something we all need to consider I
think CVD is really important when it
comes to the neuro stuff because I'm
Mike is a good friend of mine we
actually trained do rehab down the same
place in Miami so I've seen firsthand
like him recovering from the concussions
in having to wear the glasses not had a
couple concussions myself and I've had
any questions I know weren't documented
but I've know I've had like I definitely
had over ten so sometimes every now and
then I'll get like little headaches in
the front in front of my head when I
notice when I take my cell lingual CBD
and things like that that the pressure
go away or like anything anxiety and
stuff like they had things that from the
just remark it's Rama in contact it
helps it helps with the relief of that
laughs and I hear there from a lot of
guys now so that's more and more people
they're kind of reaching out trying to
find out more and more about CBD and see
how they can get their hands on it now
to treat their symptoms al you know you
have you're quite the entrepreneur and
I've admired your your rise in the
industry with your brands and viola and
and everything else so when we talk
about CBD something I think as an
athlete and again translating across the
board but especially for recovery
there's something called whole plant
medicine and you can take CBD CBD has
become a buzzword in the general public
and half the time like quite honestly
it's like when you buy organic food I
wonder like is this really organic or do
they just put that on the box so it's
really important like with all of your
food and life food is medicine it's how
I'm going to end this today know where
your medicine comes from just because
something says CBD doesn't mean
good for you and it doesn't even mean
they're CBD in it so know where you're
getting your medicine and people like Al
who are doing it the right way tested
whole plant medicine is an option where
people you know you don't have to take
THC but when you ratio it was THC and
whether it's an eighteen to one to CBD
and it's a very low amount of THC using
the whole plant versus an extract can be
much times it's called the entourage
effect and it's a lot more beneficial
sometimes medicinally to have that
combination of the whole plant do you
want to talk a little bit about you know
excuse me whole plant medicine yeah so
um you know so like you said you know
for me obviously you know we first
started I had to go through the
education process and you know my I had
needs so I first need surgery I had I
think was in 2001 and from 2001 to 2009
I used to take anti-inflammatories like
celebrex Advil every day like I was
taking one in the morning one at night
the weather was during the season or you
know or in the summertime when I was
actually training to get ready for the
season and we all know like you know the
potential side effects you know and I
and I looked at him I knew what they
were but you know like a lot of us on
this panel you know especially athletes
you know this is a way to make a living
so you kind of got to put your body in
those positions or those predicaments
and kind of just have to see what
happens because you're providing for
your family and stuff like that but once
like I introduced the cannabis and I
realized I had an all-natural you know
option you know it's spun me for a loop
because I was just like how can how can
these professional teams say they have
our best interests at heart
but they don't want to give us something
that you know that we could take that is
without all the you know potential side
effects of you know I always laugh about
when we look at these commercials of
these new drugs that come online and
it's just like you know people skipping
you know to a sunset and everything is
just so happy and then at the end is
like side effects instant death internal
bleeding eyeballs falling out
and you think about what cannabis we
have none of that you know and you know
for me like I said you know started with
my grandmother then me and now I was
like my whole family like literally my
whole family consumes my I just went
through about a breast cancer went
through chemo you know I gave up Rick
Simpson oil that you know one of my
friends produced for her she actually
gained weight you know throughout the
process
my grandmother's Church you know
obviously you know she's 80 some years
old and all her friends are 80 something
years old so they get knee replacements
and hip replacements and she's always
calling me out what can what can they
take so now my grandma was actually the
biggest drug deal in our church that's
what she's transitioned to but she's
also the most popular exactly but yeah
but you know ever since I've learned
this you know my daughter you know
literally I just last week so I put my
daughter on a CBD regiment you know she
has ADHD and you know watching her
personality swings and different things
like that and being a you know we're
giving her drug that I fully don't even
understand and you know when I really
think about it the this the course that
was setting her on is that she will be
taking pills for the rest of her life
so I got to stop that and I'm gonna try
to stop it through this plan and we're
gonna see what cannabis does we're gonna
start like she said we're gonna start
messing with blends and different things
like that and we're gonna try to heal
her or naturally it'll work
get away I have ADHD so when I was in
college I was diagnosed my head coach
actually suggested I would tested for it
and that was one of my ways and medical
one of my reasons for Medicaid was my a
DD it would help you focus and study my
plays because if I didn't if I didn't
smoke there was no way I could like sit
still and they actually sit there and
study I'll go play the game go out and
then that was big that was big for my
EDD and I was a medication in the league
I was on ritalin so I was dehydrated my
heart rate would go about during
practice I'd be sweating so much like I
would my hands would be clamming I'd
have to drink Pedialyte they had all the
head on centers and I had to take their
I'll take 30 milligrams twice a day in
that how it works though right if you
take your kid into the doctor and
bouncing around too much Oh a DD you
need to get a matter all you take your
kidneys not bouncing around oh my gosh
she's depressed we're gonna need to put
them on some antidepressants yeah it is
it's sad I I really hate that I'm trying
to naturally teach my family an Eastern
philosophy of medicine versus a Western
and they all drugs aren't bad this is
I've talked so much bad stuff about the
pharmaceutical industry I want to say
one thing we're lucky to live in a place
where technology surgery and and even
medicine pharmaceutically can keep us
alive longer and help us but it's so
goddamn overused that's the problem that
cannabis can accept there's a place for
opiates you know when you're hurt and
you're really really really hurt there's
a place for it but really you can use
cannabis to really accentuate and as a
complement to those type of
pharmaceuticals when you have to take
them thereby reducing the amount of
pharmaceuticals that you have to take as
well so interesting I that's a cool
story about your daughter I'm looking
into my daughter's just like me with
ADHD and we're trying to figure out ways
to to get her to calm down as well let
you know what I figure out yeah please
do so you know this isn't a new thing I
like to always point out like we when I
started the 420 games a few years ago it
was like this big Wow we've never seen
anything like this
fleets and marijuana oh my gosh but it
it wasn't it's like a secret fraternity
that we all were in for all these
decades you know especially these guys
like they all knew that they inside the
locker room that they used weed but they
couldn't talk about it and I couldn't
talk about it cuz I was an executive and
you know people could get blacked out at
our Christmas parties but God forbid I
lit a joint I would be an outcast so
it's a it's and so I looked back as I
started to do this because I was a
closeted cannabis user since I played
soccer in high school and I was the
starting pitcher and my baseball team
and and all that and I looked and you
know pumping iron Lou Ferrigno and
Arnold Schwarzenegger in the early 70s
they were smoking weed at the gym when
they were competing for mr. universe the
most prestigious bodybuilding contest in
the world you know we've got Phelps
Hussein the fastest in land and water
ever those were both known cannabis
users I'm a man right here Big Al and
the entire NBA
that's why fifty dollahs you know the
NBA represents the most heavy cannabis
using professional sports league and
they're the most incredible athletes
that I like to watch more than any of
them so it's just seasons was it for you
17 that's a lot of seasons later god I
wasn't getting concussions thank God no
303 still well on that note I want to
ask you know starting with Alan then we
can go down the line or whoever wants to
pop in but to me like a question as a
proponent for the pro athletes is how do
we get the professional athletes the
owners of these businesses and these
teams to allow cannabis to be used and I
think we all kind of have seen CBD as
our gateway my my statement and my
unfortunate reality is that it's only
going to be money and we need to with
data prove that cannabis can actually be
better medicine with people like Sue and
her research to show that this will
actually get you on the field and keep
you playing longer and they're not going
to really do it just because it makes
somebody feel better so what do you guys
think you know how are we going to get
this legalized to use cannabis in the
NFL and beyond
well I think the first thing you said is
true it's gonna take money testing sue
you know what I'm saying to continue to
you know break down these barriers but
what I think you know like just say MBA
guys right it's gonna take one of the
top guys to come out and say he used you
know if I'm NFL I always say like if Tom
Brady did it but from the NBA you know I
personally think it's gonna happen
sooner than later too because the league
has changed a lot in the way I say let's
call the run labret but I got somebody
close to LeBron that's thinking about
doing it but um you know these guys are
in a different stage in their life so
like when I was coming up just to say
like you know there wasn't as much
endorsement money and different things
like that but if there was you know he
was tied to McDonald's and four million
dollars and I was a lot of money but now
these guys are making 40 million dollars
just from me a contract and then they
have all these endorsement deals and
stuff like that so I personally think
that now they make so much money that
they don't care no more they like I'm
gonna be exactly who I am now I don't
have to hide Who I am and I personally
think that you know there will be an NBA
player that will make this statement
within I would say like the next two
years and then I think that'll just
continue to push the conversation
forward and we're sorry got to continue
to break down barriers and then we need
people like us who are retired at least
to speak our truths and like you said
come out the weed closet or the green
closet and as we continue to do that we
just keep raising awareness and we'll
just keep breaking down barriers that is
great to hear well I think you're right
I mean what a great world we live in now
that everybody has a voice right I mean
you're seeing this across the board
people can be exactly who they are and
not be so worried about it anymore which
is really the ultimate I don't even know
how to say it but the ultimate
responsibility that the cannabis
industry has is to build an industry the
right way from the beginning female
empowerment sustainability
environmentally conscious I mean we get
to do all this versus every other
industry that's trying to reverse
engineer themselves right now so by
speaking up doing things right as we
build this it's not only our
responsibility but it's
it's sort of a luxury and it's great to
hear that you think there's some big
people about to say some things and I
think across the board some big actors
are about to do that some NFL guys I
mean I think we're gonna continue to see
the chips fall as long as we could good
research back from dr. sue well my
perspective is is very much in line with
yours I would say that initially we need
education we need to educate people the
same way that you had to educate your
grandmother and show her that this isn't
something to be afraid of it's our job
as the cannabis community to come
together and really take the time to go
to your families and to explain to your
kids what this is explain to your
parents what this is explain to your
grandparents what this is and how it
affects your life and then when the time
comes and when the athletes are ready
it's your guys's job to endorse the
right brands that are doing the right
thing in this industry because there are
so many bad actors but there are lots of
us with the right heart that really want
to get clean products into your family's
hands I think with the NFL to take a
little longer though because with them
it's more so like to image the league
and the brand just how you kind of see
it is with the stands from national
anthem as far as like on a lower level
like the coaches themselves there's are
this coaches I've had personally they're
just like if you guys are gonna do it go
ahead like we know if you need it you
need it like we're aware of they're like
we got our tests our annual tests once a
year so it's either in a spring or some
training camp and if you feel that
that's when you're in a program so if
once you pass that test you're good for
the year so they're pretty much they
know whether they're fully aware is just
they don't want to be so blatant that
for it to damage the brand it's all
about the brand so once it gets like to
like a cobra level a house in Canada
like with canopy with that level where
the same guys that like Jerry Jones had
soil and money in the oil he can put
into marijuana then they'll be all for
it cuz remember the end of the day those
guys the owners they're businessmen so
the business is side of it it's really
opening their eyes because a good friend
of mine is actually a big corporate
owner and he's friends with a couple
owners the NFL and they're kind of
opening their eyes to their business
opportunities over the actually put some
money into the stocks in Canada and
things like that so the kind of they're
coming around but
I think then if the MBA is is always
ahead of the NFL in terms of player in
terms of how they treat the players and
what they had a little player to express
themselves and they actually say and did
the players have baseball hockey don't
even care do they they'll just follow it
follow you guys lead so I want to know
if you're tested once a year and you
know you get the call you know you're
clean you go get tested how high do you
get right after that when you leave the
testing facility it depends on how long
you had to wait so if you had like in
the spring to say it's April June so you
stopped in like March so you have like
I'll usually give myself I would cut it
short because I like had my system down
I'd like all right my buddy fast here up
like I need this mayonnaise I get I got
drink two gallons of water a day do my
regular workouts I'll be good in 10 days
so like I would cut it closer to most
guys but a lot of people would do like
30 they were stopped in but I remember
like after that everybody had their
chest and everybody with that goat the
everybody would go link up together and
everybody just have a good big session
yeah all the tests came maybe like a
whole thing they do about second a lot
of time so like a little bit of DBS
sometimes we'd be like oh they do
something everybody think is corny
because most of the most times the guys
I don't smoke is hola me but most part
so good like in the spring the first
test like everybody would get mad
they're all wide chest no alignment
first they you know they don't smoke
anyway so I was like yes they do about
say group and things like that it kind
of brings everybody gets split everybody
gets done it's bringing in a training
camp kickers own kickers yeah so yeah
you get those get them out the wing
thank you ceremony for that I would have
a have a bowl loaded and just be ready
to rock after that test now interesting
stuff and so you know I think it is
something important to say again like
you know all these guys have lived these
lifes and and it had to wait until now
so I work I want to quickly mention an
organization Sue's on the board I was
part of it Matt's part of it you're
gonna be part of it soon I hope if
you'll honor us
it's called athletes for care we work
with retired athletes not only just to
help them understand cannabis but
to help understand how to assimilate
back into life after you know beyond
beyond the glory kind of thing so when
the lights go off and you're not a
professional athlete anymore it's not
the most easy thing in the world
financially in a lot of other ways and
so beyond just teaching them cannabis is
an alternative to-- Piet's we've got
mentors and then people who are just out
of the league and you know one of the
big things and pillars of that
organization and again it's not just
cannabis but I want to mention that one
of the pillars is cannabis to keep them
level and keep them healthy and it's a
great organization you should check out
so as we end here kind of as we wrap
this into kind of Q&amp;A to me what I've
seen happen is a movement of a few guys
doing this and then starting to talk and
then a few more X guys talk in and then
gain 420 games and other people starting
things there's there's a social movement
out there and it's there's thousands and
thousands of people that define
themselves as athletes that use cannabis
can of athletes or whatever you want to
call it in there that's what your
product line is built for from what I
can see how and so it's just it's I'm
very very thankful to these guys so I
want before we wrap this up and go into
a Q&amp;A let's give them a huge round of
applause for being branded they're the
frontlines of this movement it's these
guys that are gonna help us legalize it
really is these guys that are gonna help
move it across the line so you know from
here I guess why don't we jump into a
little bit of a Q&amp;A you got a mic all
right
this questions for Jim you mentioned the
power plant fitness center what's the
state the current state of on-site
consumption in the regulations now and
what do you think that would be possible
that you will be able to open a gym that
you can consume on-site I mean legally
it's possible now I mean there's ways to
do it and it call it a cigar room style
where it's separated and ventilated so I
mean we were legally able to potentially
do what we did we were unable to open
the gym due to some regulatory stuff
outside of that
the inability to really have a pretty
large capital raise that it was right
when Trump and sessions kind of came
into office which kind of killed our
raise from some more traditional VCS
that we're gonna get into the game but
you know legally it's there's a lot of
things you got to jump through but
there's ways to do it now if you wanted
to do that so I mean if you want to open
a cannabis gym give me a call and you
still trying to do it I'm awesome
smoking ice hockey rink I love that so
this questions for Nick so you mentioned
that during training camp and before and
over the summer you stay clean unless
you're tested did you notice that
recovery time from being hit or having
some of the concussion-like symptoms was
more or less after using cannabis and
CBD see I didn't have too much head
trauma so as far as offseason when I had
to actually stop smoking I felt more of
the effects with my training like as far
as my recovery and my rest that's when I
felt like me I personally I like smoke
on my way to working out like I was
smoking like right before I get there
and that's kind of gets me am i right
mental state like I actually feel like I
breathe the better when I do I know it
sounds weird like when I don't smoke I
feel like I can't breathe I had a
question given the fact that the
professional organizations are not
accepting abuse how do a fleet current
athletes get educated on you know the
the various effects of cannabis and what
it can do for them is it more just like
athletes sharing their personal stories
in the locker room or how how did you
out of each of you start your your
journey into you know researching the
effects and what it might do for you I
guess kind of once I actually got into
the program I looked into it more deeply
as far as like once they started making
me like listen to them explain all the
chemicals and stuff like that then I
kind of understood like how would
actually like helped me when I looked at
it from the scientific perspective but
like
I mean that's a hard one right there
actually it's kind of I mean I'm not I'm
not an athlete but I can still tag in on
on how I learned which is I mean
probably by doing the wrong things
sometimes like smoking too much and then
coming back from that I mean I'm sure
that it has to be something that a lot
of people still do there wasn't the
wealth of information available that
there is like now and that there has
been in the last two or three years
honestly I mean the market has changed
so much and and the conversation has
really shifted but I mean to start at
least myself I mean I remember smoking
my first my first bowl and and I was
like okay this is interesting and then
somebody would give me a different you
know some purple and I was like oh this
is way this is not what I just smoked
last week and and that's it's trial and
error and then hopefully learning from
your mistakes and also sharing the
information with your friends in general
education is probably one of the biggest
issues in the industry anywhere and not
just for consumers on the street even
major politicians don't know it is going
on so I think in general that
information is is critical and we've
invested in some companies recently
there's a WebMD of cannabis we think is
really good so I think there's more
information tools to come but just
understanding what is happening is
probably the most important answer we
can give you I mean for example we
invested a lot of insurance companies I
don't know does anyone have life
insurance here okay has anyone tried to
get life insurance while you're smoking
cannabis and get tested for it right I
mean it used to be life insurance you
would get denied if they found cannabis
in your system and in every other way
you were healthy right which is absurd
now they time they penalize you
basically somewhere between if you're a
tobacco user or an extreme alcohol user
but they'll give it to you and you think
about these insurance companies the
resources they have and to not
educated enough to know that you're
telling me I can't get insurance because
if I don't even consume alcohol or
tobacco and/or opioids but I use a
natural plata product to sleep or my
pain that you're gonna penalize me on my
life insurers to take care of my family
I mean there's things that are just
crazy they're getting better they're
starting to get smarter but it's an
institutional thing as far as she said
as far as the trial in there I think
that's definitely a big one as far as
myself I kind of learned that edibles
are another good way I like to kind of
medicate before physical activity like
playing the game because I know it would
last longer so I could be the Edible for
the game it would last me the whole game
or if I just smoked the blood it would
only kind of last me kind of like
through the first quarter and then you
kind of learn from the older guys to
like when you're first coming in you
like kind of art like how do I do this
like how do I like make sure I can like
get out before the game and like I don't
get caught in like I can make sure I get
my stuff with me so you kind of learn
from other guys they teach you how to go
about it and as far as they actually
learning what the plant does to you like
now it's just get to the point now where
more guys are open to it so like now
it's like I've always been known to the
younger guys under me in college and
guys are played with like I was already
smoker so guys that didn't smoke or
didn't smoke as much they're looking to
hearing more the medical benefits they
want to know more so they want to talk
to somebody else that actually does it I
get more people coming to be
face-to-face specially training in Miami
where I train at and with my trainer
Bommarito and my doctors I go to that do
like the stem cell therapy and the pro
lobe and the nutrient Ivy's so it's kind
of everybody else all at the same time
is trying to gain interest in and so at
the same time athletes are learning
about it more than medical professionals
that look into not the traditional
methods of healing like the surgeries
and the injections were more the
homeopathic they're kind of helping us
educate as well too because they're
learning at the same time I guess this
question is more for Eliza it's it's
really cool to hear your guys
experiences on on the professional field
but you know I don't I'm not an NFL
player I don't know if you could tell so
I was hoping to hear a little bit more
about how you suggest we incorporate
cannabis into you know like normal
people fitness totally yeah I mean well
so we did ask the question who
zooms cannabis before workout can can I
just see a show of hands who uses it
after ok a little bit more than the
before so that's awesome so there are
three ways to like use cannabis right so
you can consume it you can inhale it or
you can apply it so topicals in other
words so the first thing is just
educating people about those three
different modes of application and
understanding how they can be used it
really depends on the activity there are
certain activities that I personally
wouldn't recommend using cannabis
beforehand because of just you know
sometimes things are dangerous so
certain people when they're lifting
superly no weights and stuff I wouldn't
recommend high THC because your muscles
do get a little bit more relaxed and
somebody I've got somebody laughing over
here because obviously he's done it once
or twice but so that's one one thing to
be aware of but once again educating
yourself and learning about these
products starting with micro doses this
is something that I teach in my class is
all of the time micro dosing which means
that you're using less than a medicinal
dose so start with 2 to 3 to 5
milligrams and then work your way up
from there really give your body and
yourself a chance to understand how your
body interacts with this medicine and
and also just understanding that you
want to find the least amount necessary
to get the desired effect which is
something we don't really see very often
in the pharmaceutical industry it's like
they're like we want to make sure we
eradicate that so we're gonna give you
three times the normal dose to make sure
that you don't need to come back no no
no we want to start with once again the
least amount necessary for that desired
effect you want to allow yourself to to
find space and to really find that time
to focus with the ouka classes weed is
awesome before a good yoga practice or
meditation even and really getting into
your body because when people are on
their Maps in my classes it's called
bendin blaze so people they think they
need to get blazed and when I say no I
want you to get lifted I don't want you
to get high there's a big difference
between high and lifted and I want you
to find that in-between space where you
feel enlightened
and as opposed to feeling stoned and
like you need to lie down so there's a
few different ways to apply it I don't
know if I answered your question but I
think it's important to talk about it
and for anybody who's interested in
applying cannabis to their practice or
day-to-day activity please find me later
I'd love to talk to you about what
you're doing and how we can enhance it
and and and also solve any issues that
you may have in your day to day I like
lifted week I call it activated it's
kind of our term for it so as we close
up there's there's something I kind of
like to close up on and I like to bring
cannabis into a bigger picture and a
bigger discussion and not just talk
about it is like to get high cannabis is
part of our lifes whether you're an
athlete or not to be well and to be
happy I started this off by saying you
know marijuana used to be a drug and it
was bad but really it's it's a medicine
cannabis is a medicine that makes us
better people and we should look at not
only cannabis cannabis is a plant
everything we put in our body so food is
medicine and America looks at medicine
as what I think of as a drug which is a
white pill and medicine and a pill or
excuse me drugs or a pill that's trying
to fix something that was bad decisions
made over a lot of years and I think
that you know if we can use cannabis in
a lifestyle of wellness eating right
thinking about what we put into our body
what kind of cannabis we use when we use
it how we use it I just want everybody
to think about mindful cannabis use
especially as an athlete because if
you're gonna use cannabis and you're
gonna go out and you're gonna go surf in
a big wave or do whatever you want to be
on your game you don't want to get hurt
and same thing in life so be mindful
with your cannabis use find out what
works for you it's not the same for
everybody
god bless you all let's give these guys
a big round of applause
[Applause]
[Music]