[Music]
see your grower yeah okay
so I'm actually really curious about
your thoughts what what are your
thoughts on proprietary genetics and
patenting things like cannabis cultivars
well I don't know very well how you go
about patenting a plant and naturally
the variance that we see in our crops
and even in fairly stable crops the the
speed in which we go through these
different varieties and and subsets of
these varieties that I don't I don't see
the viability of patenting a plant and
what what do they mean when they say
patent to plant talking about patenting
a name patenting a strain a chemo type
what where where do you draw the line so
it's a good question and I can spend a
lot of time answering it I guess and I
will in a second but I think before I
get to like all the technical stuff I'm
curious as to your thoughts around
really because but there's really like a
higher level question on the table which
is like do you want like do you feel
like the things that you grow and that
you cultivate and more specifically that
you like that you breathe like let's say
do you breed something oh my god this is
like my very favorite this is like
Reynolds dream you know I mean it was my
Reynolds dream string and it's perfect
is that something that you would want to
get intellectual property protection for
is it something that
you know because you think it's new or
is it something that you want to just be
out and free and open and that kind of
thing
like what what are your if I definitely
think the latter I think of what uh what
I've been able to do because of the open
source nature of all the varieties that
I've grown that I've never had to
purchase intellectual property I've
never had maybe add there was a steep
entrance free fee at some point to get a
certain type of genetics but in general
it was it's historically been open
source we've given and and traded and
been fairly loose with our genetics and
that's how we've kind of proliferated it
and that's how we've gotten to where we
are and I see with people that are
coming in that they have great business
plans but they don't have a cultural
understanding they're not seeing the
what's happened in the last 40 or 45
years in the you know the undergrowth in
forests and in basements and closets
with people fearing the government while
they pushed forward with this hybrid I
say the hybridization of this plant and
how we've come to a place with this
standard higher potency than we've seen
in the past potentially better taste and
we've done that out of a love for the
plant some of it higher yields and and
things of the nature of typically gone
with prohibition though there were
things that needed to be done for the
sake of prohibition but other than that
the majority of it was done for the love
of the plant and when we have people
coming in that want to monetize every
single aspect of it it's disheartening
and as far as what I want to protect not
much from people that share a similar
viewpoint but
from people that want to take my work
for free essentially and then turn
around and monetize it it's a hard pill
to swallow and I completely agree with
you like I should admit that I'm like
relatively new still to like the
cannabis industry I've been using
cannabis for 20 years and you know so
sure I'm well familiar and it seems like
I think that what's been the saddest
thing for me in the year of running open
cannabis project has been seeing this
influx of people that just like give no
about the community and about the
culture and the other thing that makes
me really sad and I don't this is maybe
more true in Oregon than it where you
base Humboldt you're on a humble okay
okay all right so then this will
probably hit close to home like it
really bums like I'm a rule follower
like I like fought like I like you know
dotting my eyes and crossing my T's and
making sure my is all lined up and
it really bums me out that because of
the way the like right but because of
the way that like the legislation and
all the regulations have rolled out
there are a lot of people who have
started to go jump through a bunch of
extra hoops because they believe in
legalization and they believe in like
getting this plant out there and they're
getting screwed financially you know
like that's something that like really
like gets my goat in a major way I'm
right there I'm very deep into this
process I spent a lot of money and I
mean forget invest investors or
investment capital I've never had a
credit card in my life I've done
everything from the the first flower to
the next to making it all work and when
you see 10 20 million dollar angel
investments come in to these companies
they can they can do things they can
make moves that your average person
can't totally and that's actually part
of my big issues with patents and - so
to get back to sort of your technical
question around like how do you even go
about patenting a patent you know like
you I mean
the the long and the short of it is you
need to prove you need to prove that you
invented something like just generally
speaking for kind of any invention of
which like new plants fall under it and
by the way I should always say like I'm
not a lawyer this is not legal advice
you know always if you have legal
questions you should always consult your
lawyer sure working in your jurisdiction
of choice you know whatever but you know
there needs to be an invention and like
proof of a mentorship and that invention
needs to be new enough and unique enough
and if it is then with the help of legal
counsel you can file for a patent and
get a patent and I think that what's
been and really ultimately there haven't
been very many patents have been issued
on plants like the vast majority of
patents that are out there are on like
like cannabinoids and uses and on
formulations and processing methods and
some of them are really crazy like one
of the lawyers who we work with
Dale hunt just put out this thing called
MJ patents weekly dot-com and it shows
like all of the cannabis patents that
are being issued and all the
applications that are published in the
US and in Canada and internationally and
like the that people are patenting
it's crazy you know like but when it
come and that's like a whole other
tangent that we all should be looking at
and paying attention to because it has a
similar documentation problem as
cannabis but for patenting a plant like
you basically needs to like follow the
same rules of any other invention and I
think what's really problematic
especially for there's a family of
utility patents that have been issued on
plants with at least 3% CBD and a
certain terpene profile and it's not
just like this one cultivar it's like
any plant that fits this definition any
product made with us any new plants that
are bred with it and you know I have a
major problem with
patents in part because you know they
were issued at a time where there was
very little documentation about the
plants and of course there's very little
documentation about the plants because
it's still federally illegal you know
naming and so and the way that you get
that is you have to have money you have
to have capital and like farmers don't
have it
you wanna mean by and large you know and
like if we wanted to fight back against
that we'd have to like work together and
come up with like some crazy awesome
legal strategy which you know I'm
interested in talking to people about
but yeah anyway so that's kind of the
deal with a lot of the patents that are
out there so what was your initial
starting point or the catalyst for this
open cannabis project even working on so
the project was actually started in 2015
by mouth Lee Holmes if I was bioscience
okay yeah
and Jeremy plum and I was brought on
just about just over a year ago to help
basically to make open cannabis project
its own nonprofit in part because the I
think that like FiOS was getting some
flack from people about asking them for
data and they're like wait a second
you're Jetix lab like we'd want to share
data with you and they're like oh wait
it's nonprofit wait it should be
separate from us and so they hired me
initially to separate it
I believe in open information and I
believe in open data and I believe that
we should have transparency in this
space in particular because you know
both both patent law and intellectual
property law and intellectual property
law around plants which are different by
country and you know like have different
governing bodies and all kinds of things
like that is one area of knowledge that
has been that is for the most part
pretty opaque to people you know didn't
mean it takes a lot of digging to really
get in there and I think for cannabis
because of the underground nature of it
it's also something that's been
completely like you know opaque to a lot
of people and so there's this
opportunity
like bringing information into the fold
and if nothing else helps to bring
clarity around like what is out there
and then for people to give people the
option to ask the questions like okay I
really want to develop something that is
new and unique like what is really new
and unique here and I mean like it's
anyway I think it's really fascinating I
think when we look at these these
multi-generational hybrids of hybrids
where do we start drawing the line when
you are simply crossing and you the the
breeder may be doing their due diligence
as far as producing a stable genetic
line but still they they took two
varieties and cross them together and
typically at this point in the game
those two varieties were a cross of two
other varieties and so on and so on and
we go back to what people call land race
trains are really what inbred lines
because they were cultivated in these
regions of the world it's not wild
product and at what point if people stop
getting credit is it like whoever cares
to get the credit gets the credit and
that's really interesting because that's
like a place where like plant biology
and open source like kind of diverged
right because in like open source
software and open and open source like
anything which really falls more under
typically really comes out of like
copyright law you know like there's an
automatic authorship like if you like
you know like make a postcard like you
know like you get to have copyright over
that postcard right sure so and like if
you want to open source it then you can
say like okay anybody can use this with
attribution as long as you know they say
like hey Reynold make this make this
postcard like you can use it for free
and you can't do that with plants like
you know what I mean like you can't like
have like so I don't know where they
tilt draw the line you know naming and I
feel like there's not really a great
answer to that question because the
lines have been blurred so many times to
me it seems like you know maybe
you shouldn't be able to patent these
plants but at the same time the law says
something different and so that's where
things get really tricky right and and I
think it goes down to for a lot of
people that I know that that do their
own breeding at whatever level they do
it for the most part it's not financial
in terms of what they want its
recognition that they they did something
that is popular now and I think a lot of
those same people it's it's more the
issue they take of somebody else making
money off of this work that they take
they take issue with and how much of
that comes down to the actual variety or
the cross involved how much of it comes
down to the naming of that product and I
mean I think that there's other there's
other businesses that we can look to
that that deal with this the difference
between the product itself and the name
that's put on it
Oh totally yeah and so we're we're these
and what I think a lot of people coming
from the outside world
think of must be nicknames because we
know some of the names are these flowers
that those are the actual name of that
variety and there isn't something you
know more scientific there's no Latin
version of it to go back to and
subsequently how tied is that name to
that variety and how truly unique is
that variety and could the majority of
consumers of the product tell the
difference between that variety with
that name and a very similar parental
cross right that goes under a different
moniker totally and then what about like
growing so what about growing like the
same like a clone of the same variety
but
two different farms under two different
methods new what I mean is that the same
variety or is it something new now
because it's chemical outputs are
different because they've been grown
differently absolutely I mean I think
even taking it further to to outdoor
versus indoor something like that that I
see greater differences in the same
clone grown under different
environmental conditions and maybe the
same basic type of growing indoor
greenhouse outdoor but in different
environments with the different
nutritional inputs then I do often
between two different varieties that are
similar but are produced in the same
environmental factor and great and I
think that's interesting I think it's
really interesting too and part of what
I think is really interesting about that
is that the way that patents work and
even plant variety protection work is in
the u.s. specifically internationally
it's a whole different ballgame that I'm
only beginning to really wrap my head
around but we don't really take growing
method into account like that's kind of
like brushed aside as a trade secret but
for cannabis that's like part of the
magic and I wonder like one of the
things I think about all the time is
like could we as a community create like
an alternative an alternative
intellectual property system that was
really based on that also had legal
teeth right because we can come up with
all kinds of but if like like the
USPTO and the feds don't look at it that
it's kind of like we were kind of
wasting our time so but what if we had a
system that was similar to you know like
Appalachians or something like that I
know that the Mendocino Appalachians
project is working on this and I cannot
wait to talk to them about it but like
what if we had a system that was really
like okay there is the the cultivator
and the cultivation method right like
the farm
the environment plus like the genetic
variety whatever equals the output and
that output and like that whole process
is taken into account as an intellectual
property thing absolutely right but then
like would that be up I mean I don't
feel like because the community is so
like based on open source like it
doesn't feel like a patent doesn't think
it seemed like the right thing and a
plant variety protection isn't the right
thing so like I don't know I don't know
what the right answer is I don't know
what that thing is but it's something I
probably think about I see that and when
I look at some of my methodology and
some of the the the modifications I've
made over the years to make my product
superior at least to what I've done in
the past I'm not sure at what point
whether I really came up with that where
I got it from and to try and claim that
that's mine
it's a little bit of a stretch but I can
fairly safely say the way that I've
compiled these pieces of information
does make it to some degree mine and
I've not come across anyone that does it
exactly like I do just like any other
farmer that I come across we all follow
some basic with similar paths but
because we do have these different
approaches we come out with different
flowers in the end and like something I
kind of like to throw out to people is
that it's an easy plant to grow and it's
a difficult plant to grow well and the
difference I grow other things besides
cannabis and I've yet to see a terrible
amount of difference between zucchinis
that I grow from one season to the next
or sieved versus a start in different
locations that I've grown it or whatever
you want to throw in it seems to carry
more similarity and with this plant I
see such great differences with fairly
my new
weeks 2:02 a recipe totally and from
what I understand and I'm also not a
botanist like it seems like the the
heterozygous nature and then the
hybridization of cannabis is part of why
it is so like you know there's a stable
seed lines are possible you know I mean
it's not like you can't make a stable
seed line but most of them are buried
within their seat line sure that's
correct I mean and I think most of these
words that would be thrown thrown around
are very subjective right and stable is
one that we throw around and what is
stable really what is stable mean to the
grower or what a stable mean to the
breeder and I think there's two big big
points that I bring up as far as
stability one is how similar is one seed
to another when they grow up to be a
plant and the almost at this point the
more important thing is what is its
tendency towards turning hermaphrodite
that's become a huge thing and that's a
lot of what the word stability is being
thrown around these days when we talk
about stability we ask it does it have a
propensity to be a hermaphrodite and so
those are kind of like two very
different things but we're using a word
like stability so then you could see how
you going down the line it becomes a
little bit confusing when somebody says
is this stable I never thought that I
would spend have any desire to like go
and look at the word stable in terms of
like legal documentation but now I
really am wondering I'm like okay like
like what is and I think I've actually
seen this written I can't remember what
it is but it would be interesting to
compare like the definitions of stable
like you're talking about with like the
definitions of stable that the that the
plant variety protection office uses you
know anything they're talking about
stability there's so many words like
this and at least in in my in my world
in the cannabis world that have you know
kind of been maybe not hijacked but
certainly taken by the cannabis
community and
sometimes used correctly or aptly and
other times misappropriated I was
talking with with the geneticist and a
biologist a couple of weeks ago and we
got onto the topic of genetic drift and
he said is that what is genetic drift
well if you were to talk to a biologist
they're gonna have one viewpoint on what
genetic drift means and then if you talk
to the majority of the cannabis
community and what they have co-opted
that word or that phrase to mean it's
gonna be two different things in the
growers cannabis growers world genetic
drift seems to predominantly apply to
people talking about their mother stock
and seeing that over time they take
clones off of this same mother stock and
they have a typically a degradation but
at least a shift that the plants aren't
coming out the same as they did in the
past and I was asking him is is that
possible and he said that he didn't see
how that would be possible especially in
the timeframe that most people are
talking about two years three years four
years and that the reality would have
way more to do with my hypothesis to him
was the reality would have more to do
with the the mismanagement and not
properly taking care of that mother
stock and it getting sick and maybe it
rebounding but that it never been the
same and the important part of it was
him being so shocked by the way that we
use the word genetic drift because he
said that's not accurate and so I see
this over and over again in these words
in the way that we communicate here in
the community that that doesn't always
line up I mean that has to do so much
with the underground nature and not
being able to like have access to decent
research for so long right and to like
really participate in it along those
lines like there's this like whole
debate around like
it's not really don't really feel like
it's a baby like the strong feelings
around like they used the word strain
versus the use of the word like cultivar
or every team of our yeah yeah exactly
and so like and I and I like you know as
somebody who likes to be technically
correct of course I mean I want to use
like cultivar whenever possible all
because like that's technically correct
and also I feel like there's like some
validity to the vernacular that has come
through the cannabis industry that kind
of like needs to be addressed like I
don't like I think it feels shitty for
me to be like no I'm sorry you can't use
the word strain anymore hi I'm new and I
know science so you know like what's the
bet like how do you address that and
what do you think is the best way for us
to address that as a community I I'm not
a fan of people correcting correcting
other people but at the same time that a
certain base level understanding of what
we're talking about is important so when
people go into a conversation that
they're able to convey themselves well
enough that the other person understands
and I I find myself kind of going back
and forth between the two different
worlds and I don't know so I picked up
from somebody I forget where and they
were like strain is in reference to
bacteria and before that I had never
cared and after that I was kind of like
oh that kind of put a distaste in my
mouth so I find that kind of funny what
companies in the industry are looking
towards open source as as the way
forward versus people that are looking
towards more proprietary nature to their
business and patenting
the various varieties with regards to
genetics yes that's a really good
question I actually don't know that many
companies that are like openly on board
with open-source but that's actually
something that we're hoping hoping to do
at open campus cannabis project next
year is to create a program that gets
people kind of like on board is like a
membership to be like we're about open
science and open data they have like
some similar things in the psychedelic
community that I think would be really
good fits for our community in terms of
the people who either have patents or
seeking patents there is one in the
United States there is one man named I
think it's Steven Covey and he has a
plant patent which is actually a very
narrow patent on a cannabis plant called
ecuadorian sativa that apparently
produces something like 45% limonene by
weight there is there is a patent family
issued to a company called the biotech
institute LLC and those are some of the
broader utility patents that i mentioned
earlier they have a narrow version of
their patent family that also just got
recently accepted in canada and biotech
institute LLC is associated with nei Pro
and I believe fight X but biotech
Institute is the name on the patent and
then the most recent thing I heard is
that there is apparently stem holdings
is looking to get a utility patent on
genetics for cannabis plants that do
something with treatment of epilepsy so
that's as far as I know
at least in the United States elsewhere
there was so much more research to be
done
[Music]