[Music]
So another example of the pains that we
face um beyond banking, beyond taxes
would be we recently were sued under
California law under um Proposition 65.
So this is something that no one ever
told us about. Uh, no lawyers ever
really warned us about it, but
basically Proposition 65, it says under
California law that cannabis is one of
the chemicals that causes cancer. And
you've seen these signs before at
restaurants that say Proposition 65, we
may have chemicals that cause cancer.
And so, I guess dispensaries were
supposed to post a sign, and no one
really knew this, that says cannabis may
cause cancer. Now, that's crazy to us
because obviously people are coming in
here to help uh get rid of their
cancers. And what happened was there was
an individual lawyer who um went to
maybe about 20 dispensaries in the state
of California. And basically to put
together a lawsuit to sue the
dispensaries and he sued all of us and
said they came to the collective, we
don't have a Proposition 65 signed,
therefore they're suing us. about eight
of us got together with one lawyer and
formed a group and defended it as a
group. And I remember that after about
um 6 months or so into the deal, our
lawyers called us. We got all got on the
phone and they said, "Hey, they're
willing to settle now. You guys, you did
violate the law, so we're going to have
to pay this. We're going to have to pay
their attorney fees, but I think, you
know, we think we got a really good
deal. Um, but you're going to have to
post like several signs all over the
store. And my immediate reaction was,
well, I don't want to post a bunch of
signs all over the store that says
cannabis causes cancer. What are we
supposed to do? We'll just do that. And
he said, well, you know, they're really
pushing to have all these notices and if
we try to fight this more, we're going
to have to pay the attorney fees and
we're still going to lose, but maybe
they'll do it. And I felt like, well, I
represent patients. I'm the president of
a nonprofit. They spend their money
here. They have faith in us. And I think
for the patients, my worst fear would be
that someone knows a a cannabis patient,
they come home with some product, say an
elderly, I was thinking like an elderly
person that gets cancer or something
like that, and they look at the package
and they say, "Well, I'm not going to
try this because it says right on the
package that it causes cancer." And then
they could not try it. They could die.
and that's just unfortunate. So, we
actually we fought the system. Um, we
did have to pay more money, but at the
end of the day, we made it for everyone
in the industry in California to post uh
a small amount of signage. So, we have
to have one when you walk into the
showroom, you need to have one visible
and then either on your receipt or um on
the point of sale system itself. So, we
put ours on our receipt and and then we
put one sign in the showroom, but they
actually wanted like it was going to be
like four or five signs and
And we and we said no. And and now our
thing would be we got to change this
law. You know, it's it's but with all
the fights we have on our hands, you
know, we'll see when we get to it. But
like we need to come together as an
industry and and change this ridiculous
law that says cannabis causes cancer.
Oh, I didn't get to how much we had to
pay. You said 25,000. Well, it was it
was
um it was it was like 16 or 17,000 and
then it was 8,000. Then we had to pay
our lawyer. So, it was like over 20
grand. So, the crazy thing is that this
attorney that sued us, he didn't even
have to prove that it causes cancer.
Unfortunately, and I'm not that well
verssed on this, but unfortunately
sometime in the past, the state of
California actually used a study that I
was told was by uh Donald Tashkin, MD,
who is a big cannabis doctor at UCLA and
he's been in the industry and I heard
that they he had an early study that
said cannabis causes cancer and that's
what they could cause cancer and that's
what they used for Prop 65 law. But
since then he's overturned that study
and said that that's not true.
What is the evidence that marijuana
smoking, habitual marijuana smoking can
lead to lung cancer? With respect to the
development of lung cancer, uh we uh
found no evidence of any increased risk
of lung cancer uh occurrence in
association with marijuana smoking
alone. The marijuana smokers if anything
had a reduced risk for developing lung
cancer. Not a significantly reduced risk
but reduced less than a onefold. So that
means reduced. THC actually has an
anti-tumoral effect.
And uh these are studies that were done
both in experimental animals and in cell
culture systems and for different kinds
of cancer for lung cancer, breast
cancer, thyroid cancer, prostate cancer,
glomomas, brain cancer that the
development and growth or the growth
actually of the tumor is is suppressed
by THC and metastases are also
suppressed. The average smoker of
marijuana whom we recruited smoked three
joints a day for about 15 years. And so
what did we find
uh for any category of cannabis use
including heavy use? Heavy use we define
as more than 10 joint years but we
looked at 20 joint years and three joint
years. For every category of marijuana
use the ratio was less than one meaning
reduced risk. It wasn't significantly
reduced but it was reduced.
And so that's what we need to get in
front of the the legislators and change
this law. But it's it's kind of far from
our minds with all the other stuff we
have to deal with. We've already
settled.
[Music]