how do you protect your IP and and I
think that's the pieces that you hold it
right now in for them Philo's doesn't
take your living material what they're
doing is they take a material that's in
sap form basically cellular level they
can't take it and utilize it any form
other than map it on a galaxy what I did
with the galaxy is I mapped a tremendous
number of cultivars because I was
worried about losing the ability to run
them if someone had a broad spectrum
patent so these broad utility patents
are pretty fucking big and they allow
them to gather up many varieties so I
said listen if I can predate your work
in a marked form you can't fuck me so I
did all this work and a lot of it was to
that a lot of the farmers were afraid of
this tech but I said my mom's a
scientist so I'm like no no no this shit
isn't this isn't they're going to steal
it they're gonna use your data but
they're not gonna take your material and
what it does it starts to allow us to
repeat pieces I use the galaxy to prove
varietals so when I build a new bed
before we release a piece I say just
send it in for mapping so we make sure
that the stuff that we're sending did
you get it from the right mom because
this shit doesn't look the same map it
and I map it it lets me come back but it
sets precedent so it says that you're
the first person to put this up on a
galaxy it states a genetic mark and then
what you can do is you're working with
laboratories like no these are micro
alarm then you would work on a contract
with them with all like all laboratories
where it's secure and so you take that
piece you don't have to put in
propagation you could work with them
directly and never have me touch it see
I don't have to touch your product to go
work with my other end of the company
and so what it does it allows you to
scrub protect and then hold in vitro if
you wanted in vitro hold but though most
of it is the mapping of that genetic
material allows you to say what you're
working because people once it gets out
in the world that less one it someone's
gonna s want it but s1 never comes back
as the same source material and then
that's what we're doing it's trying to
build these pieces so we can set up
these legal contracts that say this is
the material we work with and as long as
it gives you a head start on the market
you run and typically s ones don't come
off the same because you're you're
having to go through the Janek selection
process no
there there there has been no its
quality so the Biggers down s1 is where
I take I take a plant and I self it into
itself and so if I wanted to do self
incorrectly I could take a plant of a
dissimilar genomic form and I could FEM
it and go into it so I'm going female to
female but because I'm not going keV -
keV I'm going have the Ken I'm not
having that vigor decrease as soon as I
start to Umbria much my overall vigour
levels decline dramatically that's the
same problem with the Royals so every
now and then you'll have a huge pop up
that comes off incredible but most of
the time you get some really freaky
anomalies that you need to get rid of
and so most of the stuff you're looking
at in genex today is someone got to
cutting someone's self tit they said
look I have all these other cuts this is
my unique cut but it's never the same as
the parental the p1 and so the marking
situation allows you to begin it because
none of us can patent this necessarily
because you can't just patent a plant
you've to patent a line and to patent a
line you have to have a 25%
reproducibility that's at a genetic
level 25% that's what though you can you
should be able to increase all of these
processes but 25% in normal agriculture
is patentable and so in normal
agriculture nothing to do with cannabis
just regular AG that's considered to
where you are genetically stable so
we're 25% of them are identical and I
mean identical right now you you're
similar and most of this poly high
because you guys sift you pop it out and
you're like I did a thousand I got 900
different looking plants and I got two
or three that looked the same right
that's poly hybrid ISM too many parental
lines coming into one one swirl and so I
think like for you guys
what you do is you take these varieties
you have and if you're gonna put
together your own micro problem Atari
and get your own cryo scientists then
just follow the advice where you're
gonna take it meristem cleanse it so
that you have no viral contamination on
it that you because it's a lot of these
lines have them you just don't see it
scrub it up so that it never comes out
on you hold it in cryo hold it in a bio
form someplace
Celso you have a triple redundancy I
wanted in cryo I wanted in vitro I
wanted it in biologics so that way I
have it in three different locations
three different forms of hold now you
start to be able to have the ability
where if any one of those operations
fails something happens catastrophe
occurs for us I used to say raid because
I lost rivers and other banks to raids
through all the hot operations good I've
been doing this a long time so for all
the years we were in the in the in the
markets prior armed robberies and raids
knocked out multiple libraries of shit
that I can never replace I can never
replace any of that stock and so for me
when people tell me hey we can hold it
in this form I'm like I want it held in
three different forms at three different
locations by three different people and
I need three that I trust and now we're
talking the hard part the three that you
trust if you guys can do your own
banking then you don't have to worry
about it but you start to use the galaxy
to mark to map your situation to say
look this is my specific piece and then
you can license it and then you could
always go prove that if someone utilized
that you can do a cease-and-desist on
that product because you have control
and I learned that from Michael buffer
so Michael buffer the guy that does
let's get ready to rumble do you know
how much that's worth half a billion
dollars that that little phrase is a
half a billion dollar empire and the
reason why it's a half a billion dollars
is because he puts lawyers on your ass
if you use it any context if he doesn't
license it he goes at you aggressively
and so I realized from him that his
methodology is it's very easy to use it
but he finds out you're using it he's
going at you a cease-and-desist just
like hit man glass got nailed for the
Starbucks so lo and behold an 800
thousand dollar fine later they're not
doing Starbucks anymore you'd have the
ability to do the same situation and
then for us what we're working with is
some individuals have some of the other
large indoor facilities that we talked
to that I know say hey would you be able
to do my own genetics and then hold them
in in vitro and then release them back
to us through micro because you can give
it to us cheaper than we can produce in
ourselves with the new facility and I
said totally because we just signed the
same contracts and and then it puts me
in a position
of getting watching language on tape
I'll get ripped