[Music]
Thank You Ariel okay so I want to do
something first that's gonna be a little
weird but that's cool cuz we're gonna
get a little bit weird so can everybody
stand up please everyone it's the end of
the day we're all a little sleepy you're
probably over caffeinated at this point
so if you could just put down whatever
is in your hands and don't worry about
self being self-conscious and we're all
just going to shake a little
okay so sorry all the way up hands up if
you need shake your head keep going keep
going and then one more audible exhale
awesome okay now we're ready to talk
about mushrooms have a seat
I have a heckler already what Bruce okay
okay thank you so much to the organizers
to Ariel to everyone what a beautiful
day right can I get a round of applause
for this amazing day yeah I'm so honored
to be a part of this thank you so much
all of you okay here we are we're gonna
talk about psilocybin um that's not the
well that's okay
those aren't the slides that we had up
but that's okay so we know based on
evidence that psychedelic mushrooms have
been used by humans since before
recorded history
and throughout throughout human history
in the 1950s there was some scientific
research and some development that was
started by some some noted folks Hoffman
among them as we know in the 1970s the
war on drugs the war on intellectual
freedom on freedom in general was
started with the Controlled Substances
Act and it pretty much sorted all
meaningful research on psychedelics
psilocybin in particular and and really
any any advances were stopped at that
time fortunately today we are seeing a
revitalization of interest and research
in the use of psilocybin and that's what
we're gonna focus on today because of
the time that we have and the panel that
we've assembled for you there are a
couple things that have have led to that
the FDA has approved psilocybin again as
a breakthrough therapy so it has allowed
research studies at Johns Hopkins Johns
Hopkins UCLA and NYU that are studying
the therapeutic impacts of psilocybin on
depression anxiety end of life and
addiction treatments coupled with that
we now have a policy reform
movement that is underway Denver in May
legalized or decriminalized psilocybin
yeah really cool really amazing I don't
know why I Denver is always ahead of us
maybe it's because they're a mile high
so they just are closer I don't know
but good for them and we now have other
decriminalization measures that will be
on your ballots coming to a ballot near
you one in an Oakland and several other
cities and then decriminalize California
which we'll hear a little bit more about
because a couple of our art bar folks
here are heavily involved in that
campaign so today we wanted to have a
high-level discussion about psilocybin
hopefully you will learn something you
may know a lot about it already but
hopefully you will learn something or
you will take away something that just
makes you more curious about the plant
about the policy reform about their
research about the mycology some sort of
strain of knowledge or curiosity that
you take away from this so that's the
point for today of course we have an
hour so we can only kind of scratch the
surface we've spent a whole day talking
about cannabis and could probably do it
for several more same as absolutely true
of psilocybin so to help me whet your
curiosity I have these three lovely
people here to my laps and I'd like to
introduce them so to my left is Madison
Margolin Madison is an LA and New York
based journalist on the cannabis and
psychedelics beat she has been published
in Rolling Stone Playboy lots of amazing
publications and she has started double
blind which is a journal yes
oh good I'm so glad to know that so many
of you are familiar with it I was blown
away by it when I read it it's it's
beautifully beautifully done her partner
Shelby Hartman is up here in the front
that these two amazing young women have
started what is really a groundbreaking
journal so if you haven't seen it out in
the hallway go go pick it up and take a
look at that so Madison is here to help
us along this conversation and next to
Madison is will Goss will is a trained
he was educated in plant genetics and
mycology
he is a mycologist a forager a
researcher and he is currently the
mycology director for decriminalised
California which is the ballot
initiative that will be god-willing
coming to you should they gather gather
enough signatures and I'm sure they need
volunteers
yeah and then on the end is dr. Michelle
Ross dr. Ross is a neuroscientist a
therapist you know just an advocate and
a researcher both for psilocybin and for
other psychedelic and implant based
therapies she is the research director
for decriminalize California and the
founder of infused health which is an
online platform that helps people heal
through magical plants and compounds so
thank you so much for letting me
introduce them to you okay so when we we
hear about research around psilocybin in
particular being helpful for folks
healing from depression anxiety dealing
with end-of-life major illnesses what is
it that's happening in the brain that
makes that the case okay so we spent the
whole day talking about cannabis
research cannabis manufacturing
cultivation etc we're gonna switch gears
a little bit here with psilocybin now
just like THC psilocybin is psychoactive
so he actually changes our perception of
things it can rewire our brain there's
so many interesting things about it that
makes sense that we're talking about it
in the same place as we're talking about
cannabis but it all comes down to the
default mode Network and so the default
mode network is really our state of
consciousness our state of being it
really controls what we think about
ourselves what we think about others how
we think about our past how we think
about our future
it really is us what's interesting about
the default mode network is that that
basically it's not active when we're
consumed with thinking about tasks or
doing things or we're in a flows
we're like really enjoying ourselves we
sort of have turned our ego off and
we're in the present moment but when
we're not really active when we're just
sitting around or daydreaming when we're
thinking about our jobs or whatever that
is that's when the default mode network
is on and first started different brain
diseases there's actually either too
much activity of this default mode
network or there's too little activity
now really what is this default mode
network it's a bunch of brain regions
that are interconnected that are
communicating so different parts of your
cortex that front part of your brain
that does all the thinking if there's
too much activity there like you have in
depression you can actually have too
much activity there and so when you
think about okay I'm thinking that I'm
worthless or I'm thinking too much about
bad things that happen you're just
overthinking ruminating that's too much
activity in those brain regions and
that's pathological anxiety you can also
have similar things you can also have
different brain conditions when there's
not enough activity for example autism
there's actual evidence that shows that
in autism you have too little
functioning of the default mode Network
and that may be e underlines why there
are issues with connecting with other
people and also understanding emotions
and yourself so this default mode
network is super important so too little
activity too much activity is not good
you want balance you want that right
amount so that we understand ourselves
in our relationship in the world and to
our past behaviors and future behaviors
so that we can think and feel
comfortable with ourselves now why are
we talking about psychedelics in this
default mode Network well we actually
know some things turn on and turn off
this default mode Network now we know
that cannabis THC can actually turn off
the default mode Network we know LSD can
we also know psilocybin that active
molecule that's in magic mushrooms can
turn off the default mode Network and so
if you're trying to help treat
depression or anxiety what you're
looking for is to be able to shut off
that hyperactive Network
and maybe switch off those negative
thoughts about yourself or stop thinking
about those traumatic experiences and
psilocybin is actually tool that is been
proven in clinical trials to turn off
this network and provide healing so if
you do a brain scan you can see these
different areas and say okay there's
less activity there and you might be
able to correlate it with people feeling
better so when we talk about psilocybin
mushrooms being so effective for mental
health there really is nothing out there
like it that can really change these
negative patterns these negative brain
patterns and help people heal excellent
thank you could you say a little bit dr.
ross about serotonin and micro dosing
and why is it that psilocybin as a
compound
mimics serotonin sure so it's really
interesting that actually psilocybin is
actually broken down into a compound
called salicin and it's sillas and I'm
sorry and it's actually very similar
serotonin and so we have this natural
fungi based compound that fits in with
our serotonin receptors actually
activates a subtype called serotonin
it's a 5-ht to a subtype and it's
responsible almost all psychedelics
stimulate the same receptor and so the
serotonin system it's not the same as
the endocannabinoids system so we're not
talking about cannabinoid receptors cb1
cb2 we're talking about these serotonin
receptors now serotonin and regulates
everything from how much we eat how much
we have sex how we sleep how we wake how
we think and feel the serotonin system
is what's responsible we think for any
depressants working so it's really an
important function of our body so if
psilocybin containing mushrooms contain
these compounds that can stimulate the
serotonin system again that's why it's
so important for mental health
now I actually did a lot of research on
both mushrooms and on a process called
neurogenesis and neurogenesis is the
birth of new brain cells
your brain it doesn't just happen when
you are you know a child a baby it
actually occurs throughout life in an
area called the hippocampus which is
your learning and memory center so we
know that certain compounds can actually
boost this neurogenesis our brain cell
development and it can actually help
rewire or your brain for healing for
healthy thought processes and sort of
help again use some of those pathways
that are more positive rather than those
negative pathways that lead to
depression that lead to trauma
you know reliving trauma and things like
that so we know that psilocybin like all
the other serotonin drugs actually
stimulates neurogenesis so again if
we're looking at these compounds it's
very similar to any any substance any
psychedelic that is stimulating your
serotonin system is going to boost brain
cell growth it's going to rewire some of
our synaptic branches and again heal our
brain so it's a fantastic tool to really
reset our brain and set us up for
healing thank you yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
so I want to segue from that to talking
about you know the science of the brain
to more the experience a bit and so I
want to ask Madison to talk about what
she has learned about some scientific
research around the concept of mysticism
of having a mystical experience
scientists are now starting to actually
quantify that there are I think seven
factors and I want Madison to talk about
her research around that and she's
interviewed some of the researchers who
are have an ongoing study at Johns
Hopkins right yeah okay so we'll wait
you know just we're out a cannabis
conference mainly and you would think
from cannabis policy there's only two
ways to consume a plant there's adult
use or recreational and medical and I
think that leaves out the concept of
mysticism and spirituality as something
that is also a benefit to the consumer
so just to to lay it out there is
something called the quote unquote
mystical experience that science has
defined and it's been found that the
stronger your mystical experience so the
more criteria that you kind of check off
during your psychedelic trip or you know
clinical session there's a correlation
between that and the extent to which
you're healing from addiction depression
and of life anxiety and cancer patients
and so on so to begin
it's not like scientists just discovered
that psychedelics can be mystical right
for thousands of years before this
humanity has had a religious sacred
relationship with psilocybin mushrooms
and really scientists began to pick up
on that around the 50s and 60s
so in 1962 there was something called
the Good Friday experiment that Walter
pinky did under the supervision of
Timothy Leary and the Harvard psilocybin
project and nine out of ten so they
recruited about twenty divinity students
from Boston University and nine out of
ten reported that they had experienced
spiritual highs with psilocybin so that
was in thousand 1962 then currently at
Johns Hopkins wrote roland griffiths
who's the head researcher there is
recruiting religious leaders from all
different faiths rabbis Imams priests
Buddhists Rohe's etc to do psilocybin
and basically the reason that religious
leaders are so important to this is that
these are people who are already who are
quote unquote already familiar with the
idea of a mystical experience and our
familiar talk having that conversation
and taught using that rhetoric
so the actual tenets of the mystical
experience are internal unity so
basically this pure awareness within
yourself external unity which is kind of
feeling connected and oneness with all
other things transcendence of time and
space and ineffability or paradoxic
allottee meaning that it's hard to put
the experience into words or that you
would need to kind of use contradictory
descriptions to really just to say what
that felt like
a sense of sacredness and an intuitive
knowledge of ultimate reality so just
sort of you know if you've ever done
psilocybin you maybe have come to a
feeling of okay everything is okay and
this is how it is and everything is
right with the world a no-no etic
quality which speaks to that also sort
of feeling of ultimate reality ultimate
reality and then a seven is a deeply
felt positive mood and if you have
basically you're having a quote-unquote
mystical experience of about 60 to 70
of this criteria are experienced by the
user and so yeah so basically the main
thing here is that I see psychedelics is
sort of the intersection of science
the law and spirituality or God so a lot
of the the mechanism of action that
people are not the mechanism not not the
mechanism of action but the way that
people are experiencing psychedelics and
psychedelic assisted psychotherapy is
forcing scientists now to grapple with
the concept of mystical experience and
that's going in to the published
research and ultimately seeing now that
we're going through these fda-approved
studies I think psilocybin studies are
in Phase two if I'm not mistaken and
there are three phases the concept of
someone of a patient having a mystical
experience with God or whatever you want
to call it is going to pave the way for
a psilocybin to become a legal
psychedelic assisted psychotherapy tool
and I think that's just fascinating so
thank you Madison
[Music]
okay so speaking of God let's talk about
nature will how what is the lifecycle of
mushroom how do we get mushrooms from
from nature actually questions so first
of all we have to understand that
mushrooms are in a different Kingdom
than plants and they're actually more
closely related to humans they are
heterotrophs we are heterotrophs we get
our nutrition from out there in the
environment and not sunlight and so you
can imagine and try to imagine a tiny
spore anywhere from four to twenty
microns in length and that spore
germinates or opens up and just like the
radical or first root of seed you have
the initial growth from the spore and
that's called hyphae and once you see
like a visible mass of hyphae that's
what you call mycelium and high-bay is
where all the action occurs in terms of
the metabolism until the fungus is
turned on and ready to undergo its
sexual reproductive cycle some fungi
produce mushrooms not all of them do
that so you start with a spore some
plants have spores like ferns these like
prehistoric really old evolved plants
have similar modes of growth and life
cycles but for for the mushrooms that
we're talking about you know they're
spreading by spores and growing into
their environment through extracellular
digestion they're releasing enzymes into
the environment as well as metabolites
acids bases basically they're trying to
create a suitable environment for their
sometimes they are parasitic in nature
sometimes they are symbiotic in the form
of helping out plant roots so we're here
at a cannabis conference you maybe some
of you are growers and you've used
fertilizers and compost that have been
inoculated with mycorrhizae fungi that
are supposed to help those plant roots
do a slightly better job of mining the
soil for nutrients and so fungi grow in
all sorts of different substrates or
foods they can grow you know in wood
makes them very special that they can
break down laitanan the scylla a lot of
the psilocybin mushroom containing
mushrooms which there are over 200
species a lot of them are associated
with dung and growing out of cow patties
for instance you've probably heard that
you know people go picking in ranchers
lands and maybe get scared off with a
shotgun or something but people think
that the psilocybin and psilocin and
these psychoactive components are
actually an evolutionary trait by the
mushroom to ward off insects insects are
very common in like as a pest in the
mushroom growing industry like fungus
fungal gnats a real big problem flat
different types of flies and so there
have been studies that shown that
insects that have been fed psychedelic
mushrooms essentially or like maybe
synthetic psilocybin actually have a
reduced appetite and so those
psychoactive components are a pest at
orient or like an anti orb every
compound and then I'll just add that
this is this trait or this gene complex
that's responsible for producing these
psychoactive components of
psilocybin tolson they've they've shown
up in all these unrelated mushroom
species mentioned 200 but these
mushrooms are not actually very closely
related and so there was a paper
released a couple years ago that gets
into the perhaps the origin of the
extreme number of times that this popped
up in in uncommon mushrooms so the idea
is positive that perhaps bacteria are
doing horizontal gene transfer fungi
have also been shown to be able to move
these genes so when when the - connect
through a process called hasmig me and
karaoke you know they're sharing genetic
material and so you find that this trait
has been transferred over to many
different mushrooms because it's
evolutionary evolutionarily advantageous
to improve their fitness and I find that
simply remarkable that hereditary you
know like the genes response that are I
passed down from one generation to
generation are not the only means to
which these these properties are are
cast on are transferred in the
environment and dr. Roston I were
talking about epigenetics more on the
the human side of it maybe we could get
a little bit into that later and how
some of these these medicinal properties
have such a long lasting effects and I
just wanted to have Madison I think
didn't they talk to those patients like
like 20 years ago or excepting goblin
didn't follow up yes when a
yeah so Rick Doblin followed up with oh
sorry about that okay right sorry so
basically Rick Doblin followed up with
with some of the people who were it
during the Good Friday experiment and he
did find some sort of methodological
holes in in the experiment that
double-blind nature of it wasn't as
foolproof as double-blind studies are
supposed to be and just to explain what
double-blind is is neither the subject
nor the researcher knows what they're
taking so in that experiment this
placebo was an act of placebo there was
still a little bit of an effect so it
wouldn't be totally obvious because they
were all sort of in the same environment
but he had found some holes in it but
the bottom line is is that and döblin
wrote this is that the drug and
drug-induced mysticism is not inferior
to other types of mysticism so the idea
being that you can have a very
legitimate mystical spiritual religious
experience from psilocybin and again now
researchers at Johns Hopkins and NYU
have been going on to kind of pick up
where the Good Friday experiment left
and goblins follow-up which was in 1987
left off and that's an ongoing study now
but yeah and another researcher Charles
Grove who's at UCLA has talked about the
concept of applied mysticism and I think
what mushrooms are forcing scientists to
do is to look at the shamanic history
and sacred and spiritual uses of
psilocybin long before science really or
Western scientists at our universities
here quote/unquote discovered them and
it's realizing that and we write about
this in double-blind as the differ
which is synthetic psilocybin experience
and actually taking the real mushrooms
which come with other probably you can
explain what else is in the real
mushrooms versus less synthetic isolate
of psilocybin but there's a lot that's
lost in synthesis and in the experience
of sitting in a room with blindfolds and
two therapists a man and a woman for six
hours or however long your experiences
versus doing it in a ceremonial
environment with a medicine person or a
shaman or whatever you want to call it
with songs and in with basically the
cultural technology that humanity has
used for centuries that goes along with
psilocybin and I wanted to jump in there
and talk about why it's so important to
decriminalize psilocybin mushrooms right
we've heard about the Mapp studies right
eventually after these the clinical
trial process goes through they've shown
advocacy for using psilocybin to treat
anxiety in addiction all sorts of
different things that it will be
approved as a pharmaceutical drug that a
doctor will have to prescribe well if we
look at the history of cannabis for
example THC was approved in 1985 as
Marinol CBD was just approved as a
pharmaceutical drug as epidemics for
epilepsy now is cannabis legal nope it's
still illegal federally so legalizing
just an isolated chemical or active
ingredient in these plant based
substances did not actually the legality
of the the whole plant okay so it's
really important for us to look at
decriminalizing the mushroom itself
because again we want people to be able
to access a mushroom we want to be able
to access something that you can grow
safely at home and consume and there are
benefits to using these substances at
home and also there's benefits to using
magic mushrooms or psilocybin mushrooms
at different doses at dosages so we
talked a little bit about
whole experiences no that's sort of a
macro dose so very large joes that's
intended to have lucid genic properties
you can also use psilocybin mushrooms at
micro doses so these are doses a little
bit under half a gram that might not
really produce any type of hallucination
or any psycho activity you just might
feel maybe a little bit more focused a
little bit more clear a little bit more
creative for somebody who's in pain with
fibromyalgia for example like myself you
might micro dose to actually distract
you a little bit from them pain so
there's a whole bunch of different
reasons why somebody would micro dose
and you're not going to get that miss
school experience but you're still going
to get benefits and there's even
clinical research suggesting improving
some of those benefits that it's not
just placebo that you can take small
amounts of psilocybin mushrooms and
actually benefit from it you can also
take those macro doses and there's other
purposes and set in setting that is
going to actually help you get those
benefits out of mushrooms so very much
like THC where you can do micro dosing
where you're not high but you're still
getting anxiety relief or a little bit
of pain relief or you can take those big
doses and feel great or even have a
mystical experience it's very similar
and I just wanted to touch on that that
there's many different ways to use
psilocybin mushrooms and it's going to
be different than just taking say a
psilocybin pill great Thank You Michele
but actually segues to a question I
wanted to ask you all about leading to
legalization but if there was something
else you wanted to add well before we do
that go ahead are so afraid of this
mystical experience that they're
actually prescribing alongside these
legal ketamine treatments a drug that
will deactivate or prevent the mystical
experience and to me you're kind of
robbing people of this healing
experience and I'm
a big proponent of the kind of whole
plant or a whole mushroom medicine and
that it's important sometimes to go
through some of that like anxiety or
like nausea associated that you might be
have associated with trips on on
mushrooms because that's your body
telling you to get rid of something and
and I think that's equally as important
as the euphoria and the kind of be the
feel-good parts of yeah thank you so
much so so before I do that actually
I'll ask I'll ask this question because
it leads it it piggyback stuff what you
all were just speaking about so we heard
about the entourage effect in cannabis
today in quite a bit is there well I
guess do we have any research about
whether whole mushroom versus a
synthetic psilocybin whether there's a
difference and are there other compounds
besides Sullivan that are active in in
the the psychedelic component of a
mushroom sure yes so it's a really good
question because this is a good kind of
parallel between cannabis although I I
would say in my limited and
understanding that it's much more
complex with with cannabis but yeah so
we talked about psilocybin it breaks
down our D phosphorylates into solo sin
and then there's a breakdown of that
into bassist Dean bassist in and then
there's a breakdown of that in tune or
bassist in and I think there's many more
compounds that were still very like
novice and still having really
researched and that's part of why we
want to decriminalize mushrooms so we
can actually like fully carry out this
research but most of the time folks are
are looking at the compare the ratio
between psilocybin and psilocin and most
of the times people are cultivating or
talking about q Benzies which are one of
like the lesser active mushrooms
it's like third out of out of these like
200 but I think we've still got like
to learn also the mycelium of of these
fungi can also have active components
meaning that the mycelium and not just
the mushroom have psilocybin and
psilocin and it has a different
structure in its and its you know it's a
different morphology so I you could
reason to think that it has a different
metabolism in your body as well great
thank you
how exciting is that by the way I just
wanted stress like how many strains of
cannabis are like thinking about all the
different cultivars like over 200
mushrooms that contain psilocybin we may
find out that some are great for PTSD
for example some are great for pain like
we are just scratching the surface on
what we know and what we could learn so
we for those of you who don't know
psilocybin is a Schedule one drug
so just same as cannabis no accepted use
by the by the federal government so
still Schedule one and in California we
are one of a handful of states that
actually make it a crime to possess the
spores of a psychedelic mushroom Idaho
and Georgia there we go we're in great
company there so that leads to my next
question okay so I I came to learn when
I was getting ready for this talk that
there is a bit of a debate among learned
learned people in this area about
weather policy reform should give way to
scientific research and we should wait I
think there's definitely some hold over
from Timothy Leary in the 70s there's
definitely a there was a feeling in the
scientific community that that really
set things back in a major way whether
you believe that or not or whether
that's factually accurate but it is the
case that that folks do kind of have
this there's a little bit of a debate
about whether we should not legalize
should not decriminalize so that we can
let science scientists do their work and
then we'll come to it later once we have
more information as opposed to folks who
say no we need to decriminalize because
one is just about fundamental free
but second that really it supports the
kind of research that we actually need
to do and maybe that leads to the idea
of whole mushroom as opposed to just a
synthetic or a or an isolate of a
certain compound and how it might also
how legalization might relate to the
actual experience that that folks would
have when they are on it so whoever
wants to take it first what do you what
say you about legalization versus policy
reform you know yeah you know as a
scientist it's sort of funny I never
really thought I would get involved in
drug policy or a forum we're supposed to
get you know not play in politics
especially when the government is the
one funding or not funding your research
right
it took me actually leaving academia to
and actually founding my own nonprofit
and working with groups like drug policy
Alliance to actually have the voice to
make change and so when we talk about
scientists not being you shouldn't be
getting involved in drug reform well the
fact that these substances are federally
illegal actually does hamper research
for example if you have patients that
with anxiety depression for example that
might benefit from consuming psilocybin
mushrooms but are scared of getting them
because they're illegal right they're
scared of losing their children losing
their job getting drug tested whatever
it is they're not gonna participate even
in an observational study right even if
it's just an app that's saying hey tell
us what kind of mushroom you took how
much you did it what you did how it felt
like maybe record your trip not everyone
is gonna be open to doing that and so
it's really hard for us to collect data
when it is still a Schedule one drug and
there are state and federal penalties
associated with it we saw this in states
where cannabis was illegal you know if
you were fearful about going to jail if
you reported your use you weren't gonna
fill out that app you weren't gonna
participate in that research study you
are really scared and I think that
legalization will help improve our
ability to do some of the research again
we're gonna have to go in baby steps
right California first states first and
then hopefully federal level will change
at some point but it will help
stigmatize the use and also distinct
eyes the research around it and I think
that research is a really big part of
decriminalized California we want to
learn how it's helping people we want to
learn if it's safe or not safe for
certain groups what the research shows
us right now is that it's pretty safe we
want to be able to practice harm
reduction rather than saying wait we
need more research there's a radio over
30 clinical trials on clinical trial gov
on psilocybin you can see all the
different studies out there it's been
researched it can be researched more but
we cannot accept things like you know
our government saying there's not enough
research on cannabis that's why it's
still Schedule one you know how many
more studies would do we need it's sort
of this limiting fear-based
approach to you know drug reform policy
rather than saying hey you know we have
better ins Dyne we have people dying
from depression right through suicide 25
percent of people with depression are
treatment resistant that means no
pharmaceutical or other treatment is
going to dent their depression are we
gonna wait for them to commit suicide
are we going to allow them compassionate
access to a again a fungus that grows
from the ground that could be beneficial
for their depression you know as a
scientist to me I hope and there's other
scientists here that you feel compelled
to go with your heart to change laws to
participate in this research and again
moral obligation to change really bad
drug laws in this state and in this
country
I thought you might say that okay will
you want to go next
sure yeah that was amazing fully yeah I
agree with everything you're saying I
actually started off as a Poli Sci major
in college I'm so glad I didn't but I'm
also so glad I am sitting up here with
these professionals talking about drug
reform one thing that I just want to
vibe off of from this conference
thinking about the talk about the
Mississippi like dirt weed you know what
I think of and there's this controversy
right now happening with this
organization called compass and there's
this real fear that they are creating
this monopoly on synthetic psilocybin
and so by keeping it illegal you're able
to consolidate that power and money into
a small group of people when we're
talking about something that has been
used traditionally throughout the world
I would add this is a global you know a
phenomenon by like you know in tradition
for thousands of years and and at the
end of the day for all the therapeutic
medicinal and spiritual at benefits and
bandages I'm of the mind I think as with
many people in this room that it's it's
a problem with the government telling us
what we can and can't do with our bodies
and I have a big problem with that
and think that should change immediately
[Applause]
[Music]
as a journalist I'm not really supposed
to take an official opinion on this as a
human being I don't think anyone should
be in jail for a plant or a fungus and
so automatically I believe in
decriminalization and to your point I
mean one thing is that the FDA approved
trials that's gonna pharmaceutical eyes
these substances in a synthetic format
which would mean legally then taking a
whole mushroom doesn't mean the same
thing as taking a synthetic pill or
capsule of psilocybin and that's just
false so one thing that I'm worried
about and I wrote about this also in
double-blind is what can the
up-and-coming psychedelic industry learn
from cannabis one thing is compass again
does pose a serious concern about a
monopoly on pharmaceutical eyes
psilocybin and also whether it's compass
or some other company the idea I mean
there are still gonna be questions of
accessibility access affordability
whether this will be covered by
insurance and stuff like that which will
make it so that most people are not most
people but a certain class of people are
able to access psychedelic assisted
psychotherapy and everyone else is still
gonna have to risk their legal freedoms
to get the same benefits or not even the
same benefits one thing I also want to
note is that there's a lot of enthusiasm
around this and a lot of the benefits
that people are getting from psychedelic
psychedelic assisted psychotherapy is
happening specifically in that context
of psychedelic assisted psychotherapy
not necessarily like out with your
friends or at a party or whatever
sometimes you are going to have an
amazing transformative experience in an
unregulated or on clinical setting but
the results that we're seeing are only
specifically in those clinical settings
so in order to whether or not you know
the majority of these psychedelics
whether it's MDMA or psilocybin and so
forth are available through the
pharmaceutical eyes model or through
decriminalization I think that's
something that right now psychedelic
industry people and advic
it's an act activists and scientists are
gonna have to ask themselves as we go
forward and vote for decriminalize
California and everything else awesome
thank you okay so we have we have just a
few minutes left so I want to do a
little bit of a lightning round I have a
couple questions I want to ask each of
the each of the folks up here Madison
will start with you since we've started
down at the other end so can you share
what a book or a study or an article or
a song or a poem or a finding or
something that you would like to share
that will spark curiosity
yeah so I one thing is that when we talk
about psychedelics we talk about the
Wellness of the individual and the
Wellness of the collective and the good
and I or the good of kind of everybody
at large and so I think that a
psychedelics have the power not just to
transform a person but then to transform
the way they vote or the way that they
are a political citizen and wherever
they are and wherever they're living so
there's one study that Natalie Ginsburg
from Maps the multidisciplinary
Association for psychedelic studies is
doing which is looking at ayahuasca in
conflict resolution between Israelis and
Palestinians yeah so I I think that
whether or not not everyone in a
conflict zone is going to have access to
psychedelics but I think as we start to
apply psychedelic principles and ethos
to the way that we approach policies and
politics and the way you vote that's
really gonna transform the current
paradigm thank you well yeah I'm
inspired by the work of Paul Stamets
he wrote yeah a couple fans in the
audience
yeah he wrote the sillas psilocybin
mushrooms of the world I believe in the
90s oh yeah
so Stamets but psilocybin mushrooms of
the world one study I mean there's
there's starting to be so many studies
where you mentor like 30 years or
something on psilocybin just something
personally I have a brother with he's on
the autism spectrum
and they're looking at anxiety you know
reducing social anxiety in people with
with with autism I'm like I would never
have thought like my brother should be a
micro dosing well like yeah maybe you
should you know so it's challenging like
even my kind of narrower view of
psychedelics which I think as a society
we're all going to be doing or all we
are doing right now I really believe in
the power of psilocybin mushrooms to
heal the world we're sort of in a bad
place right now right there are two
studies in particular that show the
power of magic mushrooms to heal some of
our social ills one is the fact that
taking psilocybin mushrooms not in a
clinical setting not as a psilocybin
capsule just any point it could haven't
been in a concert you went to right just
consuming psilocybin mushrooms at least
once in your life reduces your risk of
overdosing on opioids so you're going to
make some better choices in life somehow
it's happening I can't tell you the
mechanism for that but you have a lower
risk secondly we talked about domestic
violence in this country and also trauma
that women have to endure every day you
know we talked about the me to movement
like things like that there's a lot of
stuff women go through and if we could
reduce domestic violence we were to
reduce trauma being handed down from
generation to generation there is a
study that shows consuming psilocybin
mushrooms reduces domestic violence and
reduces violence in general
so again healing the world through less
violence more love what more can we ask
this mushroom for right
[Applause]
okay last question rather than take
questions because everybody wants a
drink and some food and you can come ask
these folks questions afterwards I'm
gonna have each of them give you a
question to take away okay so we didn't
we didn't actually ask how many people
even consumed psilocybin mushrooms here
either at macro doses or micro doses but
what I want you to do is take if you are
new to this learn about this tell
somebody about this and I want to
recommend a website that has great
information on psychedelics in general
and their benefits risk implication for
legalizing etc it's called drugs over
dinner org hosted dinner party let's
talk about psilocybin maybe your mom has
done it you know like let's normalize
the conversation about psilocybin
mushrooms in the same way that we did
with cannabis and you might find that
more people are open to it than you
thought I mean we are pretty much in Los
Angeles but not in other cities around
the world let's start the conversation
please spark that conversation okay yeah
I've had a lot of thoughts about this
and just purely as a as a mycologist
thinking about how my ecology has a role
in the work that you do whether that's
if you're a grower if it's a pest that's
a problem like powdery mildew or the
mycorrhizae that are helping your plants
roots or in remediation of the soil I I
think we all need to open our minds to
all the uses of my ecology in our lives
psychedelic non psychedelic and just
bring bringing forth this conversation
excellent Thank You Madison so you're
I'm gonna guess a lot of you are in the
cannabis space ask yourself how you feel
about the regulations and the way the
cannabis industry looks right now and
then
ask yourself if that's what you want for
psilocybin great question great question
okay
[Applause]
okay thank you all so much thank the
three of you just amazing I want to
leave you with one thought this is my
little personal touch here I just want
to read a short poem to you that speaks
to my experience with with psilocybin
it's bile all dead who was a 14th
century Kashmiri saint and and poet I
was passionate filled with longing I
searched far and wide but the day that
the truthful one found me I was at home
enjoy your evening
[Applause]