a presentation that is gonna be kind of
like the road to Prohibition and then
the path to legalization so I'll tell
you a little bit about myself because we
want this to you kind of like an open
discussion so I'm gonna disclose a few
things about myself I went to Stanford
Law School after college and you would
think that Stanford Law School would be
a pretty conservative law school
experience for most law students it was
but for me it was very different there
were these housing cooperatives at
Stanford and one of them was named the
enchanted broccoli forest where my chief
dealer lived and so I was exposed to the
psychedelic undergraduate and graduate
culture at Stanford going there for law
school there was a literary society
called Alpha Delta Phi the Alpha delt
and they had an initiation which
consisted of going to the hills of
Stanford where the dish this is like a
radar dish was located on a full moon
and taking LSD and having an initiation
ceremony and when I was at Stanford the
DEA was on to Stanford students
synthesizing LSD so they would carefully
control all the precursors no precursors
to get the Stanford all strictly
controlled so Stanford students would
not be deterred by this they just
invented new ways to synthesize
precursors and once they had their
precursor they would synthesize LSD and
when I was in law school you know in the
spirit of like openness and disclosing
my own psychedelic experiences I had the
good fortune of having access to some of
the purest LSD at the time on earth and
it was all manufactured right on campus
by Stanford students
many who avidly experimented with pure
LSD
I also took other psychedelics mushrooms
ecstasy it was legal back then it hadn't
yet been scheduled and I can tell you
that is an intentional use of
psychedelics really enriched my life and
was positive for me I can also tell you
that I experimented with william blake's
this maxim the path of excess leads to
the palace of wisdom and I also learned
you know through overindulgence that the
perils of straying too far with
psychedelics so now we're going to talk
about the etymology of the term
psychedelic I'm glad Peter asked me to
do this presentation because I really
didn't know where the word came from
it's a word that was coined by dr.
Humphrey Osmond
he was a British born psychiatrist who
emigrated to Canada and he was a
pioneering psychiatrist who did some of
the very first research with mescaline
and LSD
he also took peyote with members of the
Native American church and said it was
not madness but a mystical experience so
this is somebody who's not well-known to
many people in psychedelic world at
least not to me and it's somebody who is
very interesting and serves as an
inspiration for you know future
endeavors if you're like a psychiatrist
we're gonna hear from a psychiatrist who
is what I would consider maybe a
modern-day Humphry Osmond dr. Cole
Martin today so psychedelics how are
they defined you know according to the
Oxford English Dictionary it's basically
a drug which produces an alteration of
the mind and apparent expansion of
consciousness often accompanied by
hallucinations and you know remember
that reality as a consensual
hallucination in 1953 dr. Humphrey
Osment was in correspondence with Aldous
Huxley and Humphry Osmond came out to
the LA region for a conference at which
point he administered 400 milligrams of
mescaline to Aldous hooks
how does Huxley had his mind blown wide
open by this experience and he wrote
about the the whole mind opening
experience in the doors of perception
which was a seminal work extremely
influential he described staring at a
bunch of flowers and said I was seeing
what Adam had seen on the morning of his
creation the miracle moment by moment of
naked existence and I think you know if
you have read Naked Lunch
I think Naked Lunch is also describing
that you know looking at that in the
moment so um William Blake also wrote
about the doors of perception and this
influenced the title of the Huxley book
and William Blake who was tremendously
influential you know the doors here in
Venice the doors were influenced by
William Blake that was the name of the
band the doors if the doors of
perception were cleansed everything
would appear to humans as it is infinite
for humans that closed themselves up
till they see all things through narrow
chinks of their cavern and so
psychedelics were a way to expand
awareness Huxley suggested a new word
for narrow thym to describe substances
like masculine which expanded awareness
and this is made from the Greek terms
that indicate reveal and spirit he wrote
a little poem to say to make this
trivial world sublime take half a gram
of venero theim and Osman countered with
a better one in my opinion to fathom
hell or soar angelic just take a pinch
of psychedelic and that comes from
psyche for mind and Della's for manifest
and it's basically mind manifesting so
now the path to psychedelic prohibition
is kind of interesting and it involves
Timothy Leary in 1969 the US Supreme
Court issued a landmark
opinion in Larry versus the United
States Timothy Leary was being
prosecuted for violating the fair the
federal marijuana Tax Act which required
him to file for a tax stamp he didn't
file for a tax stamp and he said I can't
because it's illegal under Texas law I
would be incriminating myself and I this
would violate the Fifth Amendment the US
Supreme Court and this was the warrant
court agreed with them unanimously
giving that it was illegal in Texas to
possess marijuana then Timothy Leary
would be incriminating himself if he
complied with the registration
requirements of the marihuana Tax Act
and the US Supreme Court invalidated the
marihuana Tax Act vacated the
convictions around the same time it was
you know the summer love was you know
1968 just right before then there was
like a conservative backlash and so
Congress replaced the marihuana Tax Act
which was no longer enforceable because
it violated the Fifth Amendment with the
comprehensive drug abuse prevention and
Control Act which was signed into law by
President Richard Nixon title two of
this Act was the Controlled Substances
Act so this is the birth of psychedelic
prohibition the Controlled Substances
Act of 1970 for the most part you know
that they isolated psychedelics had been
prohibited before that but this was kind
of like a widespread unitary statutory
prohibition and it classified substances
into one of five schedules Schedule one
has a high potential for abuse no
accepted medical use and a high
potential for addiction such that the
drug is not safe for to use even under
medical supervision schedule two high
potential for abuse yes sometimes
accepted medical use with severe
restrictions and abuse can cause severe
addiction schedule 3 medium potential
for abuse
yes accepted medical use it can cause
severe mental addiction scheduled for
low potential for abuse yes accepted
medical you
schedule five the lowest potential for
abuse and it may lead to a mild mental
or physical addiction so schedule 1
controlled substances you know one of
them which I don't think is physically
addictive cannabis you know was placed
into Schedule one it's a mild
psychedelic so was DMT so was I Bo gain
they're just like adding everything they
could think of into its Schedule one so
was LSD so it's MDMA and mescaline which
is the psychoactive constituent of
peyote and San Pedro cactus as well as
peyote itself which is sacred to maybe
many Native American tribes as well as
psilocybin and psilocin which are the
psychoactive components of psilocybin
mushrooms and here we have a picture of
cubensis but there are literally dozens
of mushrooms that are it's like
psychological psychoactive then this is
the Controlled Substances Act you know
the schedule one they basically try to
add every single hallucinogenic
substance they could think of to
schedule one with really no supporting
research because a lot of these
substances they don't have a high
potential for abuse for the simple
reason that it bad trips happen and
after a bad trip people don't want to go
back there something about the
Controlled Substances Act is Howcast
casks and arbitrary it is so for example
cocaine cocaine base which is crack PCP
and fentanyl are scheduled to meaning
even though they have a high potential
for abuse yes there's an accepted
medical use with severe restrictions
although the abusing the drug can cause
severe physical and mental addiction now
marijuana is Schedule one with no
accepted medical use makes no sense at
all that's an old Saab we'll move on to
you know you know marijuana is never a
hundred percent THC marijuana is like
some percentage of THC and then some CBD
and
you know a lot of terpenes and a lot of
other cannabinoids
well sure Navin all which is a hundred
percent THC that's just a Schedule three
controlled substance that's known as
marinol and then dronabinol in oral
liquid form that you can drink and get
super duper high that's a schedule two
controlled substance even though that's
a hundred percent THC so this just shows
how kefka ask this whole classification
of the schedules of our now we're gonna
move on to kind of like the federal
mandatory minimums you know it's part of
like this ridiculous prohibition that
we're living under this is the current
state of the law right now and so
there's a US Supreme Court case that
discussed the mandatory minimums for LSD
and you know very briefly you know this
is the Chapman versus United States case
and I want to say the name of the guy
who you know it's was sentenced to a
mandatory minimum Richard Chapman and he
was selling a Bible ten sheets of a
thousand doses of blotter paper
containing LSD and according to the US
Supreme Court the weight of the LSD
alone was 50 milligrams or 0.050 grams
and the weight of the LSD with the
blotter was 5.7 grams the US Supreme
Court held that the statute requires the
weight of the carrier medium to be
included when determining the
appropriate sentence for trafficking in
LSD and this construction is neither a
violation of due process nor
unconstitutionally vague and that
basically meant that based on the weight
of the blotter paper somebody was giving
a mandatory minimum sentence and if
you're curious what the mandatory
minimums are for LSD and it's the only
psychedelic that is subject to the
mandatory minimums it's right here so a
mixture counting blotter paper of one to
nine grams is a five-year mandatory
minimum for the first offense and a
10-year mandatory minimum for the second
offense
and curiously in the Chapman case the US
Supreme Court said this is just because
the LSD is impregnated into the blotter
paper and cannot be separated if it was
in a bottle liquid LSD then you would
not count the weight of the bottle so
that that's a practical tip from the US
Supreme Court don't put it in blotter
keep it in a bottle liquid LSD so they
don't use the weight of the carrier
medium against you if the amount is 10
grams or more first time
clean record 10 year mandatory minimum
second offense 20-year mandatory minimum
and two or more priors basically
three-strikes-you're-out
life imprisonment and we still have
prisoners in federal court serving time
for LSD even though like people are
engaging in schedule one distribution of
marijuana and and overlooking the
classification of marijuana a Schedule
one you know it's with when it comes to
enforcement of LSD I think it's still
happening we've seen reduced enforcement
I can tell you the good news is I
haven't really seen an LSD cases case in
years
there's doesn't seem to be much interest
in there now we're gonna discuss
cannabis legalization in California and
what lessons can be learned from
California for thinking about how to
legalize psychedelics in the future so
in California I was the first state of
the nation that really kicked off this
worldwide cannabis legalization movement
with proposition 215 which legalized
medical use and cultivation with a
physician's recommendation or approval
in 2004 the Legislature passed Senate
bill 420 which established the
collective and cooperative defense and
at that point the caregiver defense
became increasingly rare because it was
far more difficult to establish that one
was a caregiver and then just to show
that one was a member of a collective in
2010 in response to proposition 19 which
would have legalized marijuana
the legislature at the behest of
Governor Schwarzenegger we reduce the
penalties for marijuana from you know a
misdemeanor to an infraction and it
didn't really reduce the penalty the
penalty was already $100 fine no jail
time what it did is it took away the
right to a jury trial and my very first
case was marijuana jury trial
you know possession Alessa and announced
in van nuys
it took a whole week you know it was a
hung jury the prosecutor was furious so
we didn't plead guilty and you know that
I could tell you like it's it was better
having possession be a misdemeanor than
an infraction just because you got a
jury trial in 2015 the legislature just
really got sick of collectives and
cooperatives it basically said this is a
Wild West it's out of control it makes
no sense and they wanted to tame the
wild tiger of medical cannabis so they
passed the medical marijuana regulation
Safety Act which established a
regulatory framework for medical
cannabis and also set up a sunset clause
for collectives basically an expiration
date 2016 we have prop 64 which was an
adult youth regulatory framework with
partial decriminalization so before prop
64 cultivation of a single plant was a
felony and with a medical defense but
still a felony often prosecuted in court
with the medical defense and often ended
up resolving as a misdemeanor after prop
60 for most cultivation became a
misdemeanor there's you know a million
plants now it's a misdemeanor if the
person is over 21 and so law enforcement
lost their enthusiasm for prosecuting
cannabis cases while it's still illegal
and now there's like a regulatory
framework so in 2017 the legislature
said we don't want to have a separate
framework for medical and a separate set
of regulations for adult we're gonna
unify both frameworks and
this resulted in the medicinal and adult
used cannabis regulation and Safety Act
2018 we had the state issuing licenses
for commercial cannabis activity
regulatory rulemaking began and now we
have a new set of regulations and
remember in January 9 2019 the
collective and cooperative defense will
expire and we can anticipate there's
going to be an increase in enforcement
but the way cannabis was legalized in
California it was not legalized there
was a partial reduction in the penalties
and then this onerous highly regulated
system that is akin to the way that
plutonium is regulated it's over
regulated and why am i bringing this up
these are lessons that need to be
learned when we think about legalizing
psychedelics maybe not repeat not use
the same model for cannabis so now we're
gonna discuss the California initiative
process because the way that cannabis
legalization was kicked off worldwide
was not by changing the federal law the
federal representatives are not
responsive to the will of the people it
was through voter initiatives the first
one was prop 215 in 1996 and the second
one was prop 64 in 2016 because the
legislature wouldn't do it they did not
have the political will and I feel it's
the same thing when it comes to
psychedelics and other controlled
substances there is not the will for
politicians who are constantly thinking
about re-election and maybe this is
something where the citizens need to
take the initiative so the initiative
process in California to get an
initiative on the ballot you need 5% of
the people who voted for governor and at
the very last election which was
November 6 we had 7 million two hundred
and thirteen thousand four hundred
sixty-four people so you really need
three hundred and sixty thousand you
know plus or minus signatures to get on
the ballot how do you draft the language
of the initiative well the California
government code has something very handy
it requires the Legislative Council to
cooperate with proponents of an
initiative in preparing then they should
have when requested in writing to do so
by 25 or more electors electors just
means registered voters proposing the
measure and so basically 25 people would
get together they would draft the
language for the initiative and then you
can go to the Legislative Council and
they will help you come up with the
language to effectuate the aims of the
initiative I found this incredibly
helpful when I was writing marijuana
legalization initiatives in 2016 2010
2012 but you know I heard many none of
which got on the ballot but had they
gotten on the ballot we would have seen
like more radical legalization than what
we have now and then this is to prevent
people from coming in with what if the
UFOs land initiative and would you
please write an initiative for you know
the government when the UFOs land it has
to be something where the Legislative
Council thinks there's reasonable
probability that the measure will be
submitted to the voters of the state
under the laws relating to the
submission of initiatives so basically
you got to have a decent shot at getting
those signatures for them to help you
they're not gonna be just writing
hypothetical initiatives or you know
like the unconstitutional initiative the
guy who wanted to shoot gay people there
the Legislative Council will not get
involved in their drafting the language
language of the initiative you know I'm
working with the Legislative Council as
I have there is a person who would be in
charge of you know I guess look helping
people if there was an initiative and
that's Jacob Henninger and he has
advised many initiative drafters and he
is somebody who I can tell you is
receptive to the idea of criminal
justice reform and he would be happy and
honored to start working on a
psychedelic reform initiative and so an
idea that I'm proposing is the idea of
California cognitive Liberty initiative
and this is based on a term that was
coined by Richard Glenn Barr and his
partner neural ethicist dr. rice
intention and their founders of the
nonprofit Center for cognitive liberty
and ethics and so taking about with a
really cool idea which I'd like to share
it's the idea of cognitive Liberty which
is the right of each individual to think
independently and autonomously to use
the full power of his or her mind and to
engage in multiple modes of thought and
this means the right to use controlled
substances to explore human
consciousness this also means the right
to be autonomous and not have you know
the artificial drugging of people for
psychiatric reasons as and you know so I
think this is like an initiative though
it's an idea that whose time has come
and I asked dr. or I asked Richard clamp
are well you come in here and will you
talk about this and he's like no I kind
of moved on to other things you know but
you can go ahead and talk about it and
so I would like you to look kind of like
if you can get a chance please spread on
the you know this idea of cognitive
liberty and just start researching it
it's a great idea it's kind of
libertarian you know the idea is that
nobody should tell you what to think and
that these psychedelic substances give
you the ability to have completely
different thoughts that you could not
have otherwise and it's your right as a
human being who wants to engage in your
exploration of your own consciousness to
be allowed to use these substances in
the privacy of your own space as long as
you hurt nobody it's I think it's it's a
very appealing idea and I want to spread
that idea and this brings us back to dr.
Humphry Osmond who thought that
psychedelics could help humanity you
know he said I believe that psychedelics
provide a chance perhaps only a slender
one for homo Faber that's like the human
who builds the cunning ruthless
foolhardy pleasure greedy tool maker
to merge into that other creature whose
presence we so rashly presumed Homo
sapiens the wise the understanding the
compassionate in whose fourfold vision
art politics science and religion are
one so that's
[Music]