[Music]
well first of all nice bullet I gotta
mention that right off the bat
thank ya we were talking about different
psychedelics yesterday and guys do me a
favor to introduce yourselves yeah oh
sure yeah I'm Thane Evans and I'm Bryan
Jungers awesome
and we were talking about you live in
southwest area and grow San Pedro's
yourself and I yeah in the backyard
under the mesquite trees got a lot of
Peruvian cacti and that region you know
there's there's peyote that grows but
it's really rare and it grows really
slow and you know peyote contains mescal
and just like the san pedro does san
pedro is a lot more amenable to
cultivation as it grows very quickly you
can water every day and it's fantastic
yeah and I think Peruvian torches seem
to be more available generally speaking
and different horticultural centers
where you can pick up such unique plants
there's a place called companion plants
in Athens Ohio where I'm located and
yeah they have different things like
that
Peruvian torch is great because it's
consistently higher alkaloid content to
exam page was vary a lot and tend to be
a lower concentration but San Pedro is
more common
they're everywhere in the you often just
find them growing in people's yards or
you know in the parking lot at the bank
so do you create a garden have you build
a garden to grow them or what's the
growing environment that you've created
yeah I have raised beds and can you talk
a little bit about that sure yeah
so amended amended beds with a little
structure over the top so you can throw
some plastic over it during the winter
keep them warmer and happier
and then take it off in the summer when
it's hot I mean Tucson gets pretty hot
in the summer and you don't want to have
it you know under under plastic for the
summer but no I mean I've grown them
just in pots too or you know bring them
indoors I used to live at 9,000 feet in
Colorado and had San Pedro up there and
you know you'd have to we didn't bring
him inside during the winter because it
was just too cold so is there a special
soil or what are you growing now well
the cacti really like calcium so you
want to have plenty of calcium in your
soil but other than that you actually
can't put too much nutrients in they'll
burn really quickly so like even I used
to make compost tea and I put it on all
my other plants all the plants love the
compost tea but you put it on the cacti
and the character I would actually start
to get these little scabs on them and so
you have to like back it way off and
like dilute the hell out of it to
actually make it something that cacti
would like so like you got to be careful
with nutrients you can water even water
them every single day as long as your
soil drains well they'll just grow and
grow and grow don't grow like a foot a
year or more depending on the size of
the cacti yeah you were saying you've
been through different methods of
consumption just raw and now often dry
out and put in capsule form yeah have
you ever seen a Christian raschi's Book
Encyclopedia of psychoactive plants yes
yeah that's what got me into this of
course I was in grad school at UC Davis
and I was wandering through the library
and I found his book and I pulled it out
on my what is this you know I'm like 20
to 23 years old and I start flipping
through it and I'm like I found San
Pedro and they're like wow that's
growing in the garden at the co-op's
where I live I'm like I had no idea this
was psychoactive and you know Christian
in his book he's got all these you know
recommendations on how people use it
like
historically and like the folk use of
these plants but also his own personal
context he's used it and you know so one
of the things he said was he would dry
and take capsules and gave
recommendations on dose of dosage so I
started trying that but I also will brew
brews with friends and we'll go out and
go on journeys in the nature and that's
a lot of fun so do you cut pieces of the
plan off or do you harvest the whole
cactus or how does that work oh yeah
always just cut cut pieces well cut cut
lengths of it and depending on what so
if you're going to like brew it you can
cut it cut a section chop it up into
little slices and brew it for six or
eight hours or whatever I'm gonna dry it
i'll you know define it cut it into tiny
little pieces to put a dehydrator for a
few days and dry it till it's like
crispy and then powder it in a like a
coffee grinder and then put it in oil
capsules and so with the brew then would
you add alcohol or anything to help with
an extraction sort of lime juice
okay this is incredible so so how how
powerful is this like how do you how do
you dos yeah so it's not I I find some
Peter to be really gentle as far as
psychedelics go it's really an emotional
experience and so if you take like one
gram of powder dry powder it just has
like some sort of tonic effects like
it's a slightly notice perceptional
change if you're sensitive
but like it's it's more just like kind
of therapeutic cleansing if you take
four grams
you'll should notice like an emotional
response and heightened energy like it's
it's got you know mescaline is actually
a lot like MDMA it's actually got this
energy energizing sort of interesting
yeah sounds like more like an empath
agent type experience yeah very much so
and like six grams is much more
heightened more even like party and
dance and at 10 grams or 12 grams you're
talking full-on psychedelic experience
usually for most people so but it is
conducive to micro to it 12 sort of
micro extent and that's that's typically
how I use it and you know unless I've
got other intentions to be popular these
days my so so just so I understand the
plants the the cactus will remain there
if the entire plant isn't cut down so
you're just constantly it continues to
grow and you just harvest from it so so
so an individual doesn't need to
continuously plant new plants no it's I
mean it's a great plant to work with
because you cut it and it will it'll dry
and scab will the cut or the cut part
will continue to grow you'll have
usually like two or more will grow out
of that same spot and if it falls over
it will usually start to grow again I've
had cuttings sitting in my garage for
six months or longer and I take them out
and they're growing new growths like
they're still alive and they're still
trying to put out
like you can't stop these things they've
got so much life in them so if someone
wanted to grow some of these what would
they do how would they go about doing
that did you do you you go grow from a
cutting from yeah you would you go out
and find it wild and it would you do
hard-to-find while you might find it
growing and like I said like landscaping
that you sent landscaping all the time
you go to Home Depot or any nursery they
usually have them but even if you just
took a cutting from someone the only
thing you really need to make sure to do
is let it scab over before you try to
plant it so wait let me get this
straight
Home Depot is selling psychedelic cacti
I mean I'm sure some people working in
taking all the ones that don't look so
good after a while it's getting a huge
collection and starting them up you
don't want to put it directly in the
ground if you've just cut it fresh
because they can rock the bottom can rot
and it won't root well
so usually you let it sit for a few days
in scab and be totally you know scabbed
and dry and then you can put it in and
then it'll start to put roots right out
so to have it refocus its energy after
it's healed itself back are there other
people that you know of that are into
this particular plant I mean is this
like it's becoming a lot more popular in
recent years
you ever watch Hamilton's pharmacopoeia
I'm assuming here you like Hamilton is a
big fan like he went in the last episode
I've seen of that show he went down to
Peru and studied under a shaman who's
the San Pedro shaman and the guy asked
him just like so are you religious he's
like well I'm kind of an atheist but if
I had a religion it would be in this
campus so so you had mentioned altitude
and obviously Peru is like you know
pretty much up and down so does altitude
have an effect on how this cactus grows
or flower producers or
question I actually really don't know I
mean it would have been nice if I had
known more about it when I was living at
9,000 feet and compared to live down
lower but I just know it if where I live
in Tucson if I leave them out in the
direct Sun like full Sun they get
unhappy to start to yellow because it's
just too intense so they really like to
be under the mesquite and they love
especially when it's hot it allowed to
be watered every day and they'll just
grow grow so they they they love water
yeah because if in brew it rains a lot
where they grow but it's a cactus but
it's a cactus yeah which is confusing
for a lot of people they're like you
know you don't want to overwater cactus
but that's not a problem with San Pedro
as long as the roots drain drain well if
the roots get soggy then they will mold
and and get mushy so what are you guys
seeing overall just in general in terms
of the psychedelics movement like you
know because it's really happening right
well I mean it's fantastic Oakland
you know extending the language to
entheogen is at large which is in Santa
Cruz yeah so kind of taking you know
again Denver's lead on legalization here
transforming it and expanding it is
fantastic ayahuasca ceremonies obviously
becoming more popular in the States
yeah it's very interesting and like you
said micro dosing of course is now you
know on the rise as far as trying to
understand the therapeutic potential
there
of course consciousness potential is
just pretty much off the charts I mean
are you guys who believe that you know
done right it could make for a better
world
oh yeah there's no question right I
definitely believe that and I mean I
believe the only reason it's illegal is
because it pose so much of a threat to
the oppressing classes and you know now
that it's coming back around and we have
that opportunity to have it done right
and use properly and and get the
benefits from it what about commercial
pretend like commercial like on the
market you know is that gonna happen
I've heard rumors about yeah
yes there's a company silo that has
first nasal-spray actually suicide so
it's more of a micro dose administration
so I think you know if you've had enough
micro doses you could probably get out
of Colorado or more I forget where
they're based out of the yeah relatively
new company the research I believe was
done in Jamaica where apparently there's
a extremely wide variety of psychedelic
mushroom species and so some research is
going on there now it's pretty pretty
incredible so but so you're dabbling
this for your own purposes and friends
and stuff like that do you have any
plans to expand your garden and you know
to grow other types
yeah I mean I would I've grown my
shrooms before neither problem with
mushroom growing for me was it was very
interesting and fascinating at first in
these very sterile environments right
like oh just the ability to do it and
then once you've done it then you have
to keep doing it over and over
everything has to be so sterile because
you don't want to be get contamination
right and I didn't like having to
sterilize the shit
my the grow environment constantly and
if I could grow outdoors like again
Hamilton's pharmacopoeia one of the
episodes he's he's down in in South
America and he goes and finds this guy
growing mushrooms and actually he's in
Oaxaca and he's there growing mushrooms
on sugar cane scraps and the mushrooms
are insane like they're growing so well
and it's like so they need do they need
also a moist environment like a lot of
so put particular environments like yeah
like outside I I don't really I mean
could they grow wild don't they these
over a while and it's you know different
varieties obviously want different
environments or grow in partnership with
different types of trees right so they
want to be like companion growing along
with the root systems of these different
trees so it's it can be really hard to
actually cultivate certain types of
mushrooms sure morels come to mind
yeah symbiotic relationship that's
imperative to their growth that's why
they're you know very hard to grow
commercially psychedelic side there's
very difficult to replicate so it would
only make sense to do it because if
there's a cost associated with that
there's the effort you know the time and
you'll all the yields are are not
massive right no and so that's what most
people focus on like the cubensis right
because the yields are good and it's
consistent it's rate well it sounds like
your cactus has nice yields - yes the
cactus is very it's very favorable and
it's just not really known or really
widely applied
outside of Peru quick question in terms
of dosing so that five grams 10 grams 12
grams range is that dried then yeah
dried count that's that's a lot yeah
that's pretty incredible when you
consider you know five grams of cubensis
is the big boy dose you know terence
mckenna's notion of that being in a
full-ride if you will so that's you know
double that so that's just kind of
interested you know wonder if back to
the environment and like genetic
expression maybe of the cacti if it
varies in its in Peru and if the
altitude actually plays into the level
of you know psychedelic compounds that
are produced mescaline that's produced I
do so is that is that the active
ingredient in this plant masculine
masculine most famous there are other
alkaloids as well that are present but
you know like I said like that the
masculine content in San Pedro is much
lower than in peyote it's lower than in
Peruvian torch so if you were going to
do the same thing as improving torch you
probably use half the dosage so San
Pedro is relatively you know low
concentrations but so with that with
that with that well how many grams worth
five grams of dried what would you do
make a tea I you know it may be a little
brew as well you don't have to can you
make cookies can you make
you know use it baking sonic I could
have dishes dishes savory yeah because I
mean you can brew it for hours and hours
and hours and makes me think too if
there's other alkaloids that you know we
aren't really even aware of yet that
creates sort of the synergy or entourage
as with cannabis cannabinoids and
turkeys and flavonoids and if there's
maybe something going on there that sort
of influences more of the empathic genic
experience versus psychedelic experience
with I would imagine yeah I mean I think
it's virtually unstudied and and like we
were talking about like which things
affect you know your alkaloid content we
really have no idea at this point
because there's all these different
studies that have been done since like
the 50s and assays and they all come up
with different results even from the
same stand of plants interesting
different results so they have no idea
that that you know that implies that
there are meant there's a lot at work
here all different variables that could
be elevation it could be any number of
factors if the results are different I
mean how could it be otherwise that's
really interesting which sort of also
implies there's like more potential you
know within this plant you know once
it's understood how do you know about
the mescaline content then and those
different Out Boy's with somewhere some
studies done some studies have been done
you know there are some that are in the
Christian Ross book there is trout's
notes are you aware
remember it's like stories from trout
there's a guy named trout who's done a
lot of work around San Pedro more than
just about anybody in like the in the
lay field and so he's published a lot
under it synonym or what yeah just a
false name yeah what does the plant look
like what is yeah oh it's a colander
cactus it grows up very phallic tall
green sometimes very very big usually
one name will grow from one main stalk
and you'll usually get a few coming out
of the base or sometimes just one
they'll grow next to each other but and
what color is it
it's it's a fairly bright green bright
green yeah is it flower
yeah these beautiful white trumpeting
flowers when it does flower and do they
have any use the flowers I don't know
they tend to wilt and die very quickly
they're gorgeous they smell wonderful
but I have no idea they're useful for so
they so that this plant contains
terpenes as well with the flower dude
you know though I don't know
zhenia fragrance yeah yeah most plants
yeah interesting you pick witness
compounds where is this happening in
Arizona I'm based in Tucson in Tucson
yeah okay
yeah and Tucson has a community a fairly
significant community of folks that are
in this space you know we're like the
epicenter of where the the bufo alvarius
toads the Colorado River toad that has
the five amino DMT and poison sacs yeah
that's that's where they're indigenous
to yeah so interesting I wonder if
there's other plants with similar you
know capabilities that we don't know
about growing out in the desert there's
a ton of suspicion around the acacia
--is in DMT content right so a lot of
occasions have been found to have DMT
and there are all these acacia trees
that have not been studied or profiled
yet and so I haven't haven't dug into
the science of it too much well thanks
you guys anything you want to add about
those stages just a couple more things
yeah hilarious grass is another you know
opportunity cool yeah likewise haven't
really done anything with it but fun to
grow and speaking of Mao lies which we
were talking about yesterday maybe just
a brief note on
what people could seek out to
potentially expand and extend a
psychedelic experience through sure yeah
and I'm actually growing a Bannister
offices cap I as well yeah likewise
the secretary yeah I mean it's a
tropical plant it really likes just to
be under like an understory growing up
on other on trees at the plants so it's
a little it's out I have it outdoor it
hates the winter as soon as it starts to
get cold it dies back but I've had it
for I think it's like ten years old at
this point so how big is it how many
leaves are on oh I could show you some
pictures it's gotten it got really big
this year it was finding out like taking
over the whole whole area if it had
stayed warm I wouldn't just kept going
it was super happy and it was the
compost tea that I was using on that one
it just loved it so because I was using
bat guano and the back one oh just was
exactly what it wanted and it just went
crazy but yeah I mean vanna stream is
great other mm eyes like we were talking
about passiflora the passionflower it to
be a little careful with that but it
works really well toxic in high doses
yeah it's the same way nutmeg is very
similar like toxic and high doses but
it's a very effective Mao I you know
when use properly
what's an MAOI monoamine oxidase
inhibitor essentially it inhibits
enzymes in your stomach so that you were
able able to process and then bring to
your brain other psychoactive
without them breaking down along the way
and so yeah expanding and extending your
experience essentially yeah it's very
it's economizing to really reduce how
much you take those in conjunction with
other with your with your psychedelic is
that how that works
yeah yep and and so does it make desert
does it increase the intensity or just
prolong your experience or it really
depends what you're taking and also this
is I just want to say this is a very
sensitive area because right absolutely
there's some there's some dangerous
aspects to combining meos with just like
it's sort of like don't do this at home
unless you know what you're doing
yeah no you definitely need to know what
you're doing if you're playing with ma
rice because they because they inhibit
your your digestive tract people there's
they call it toxic cheese syndrome or
like there's certain ferments wines
cheese's that can actually kill you if
you are if you're have a high dose of
maoi and you consume these foods so and
there's contraindications so often like
if you are on an MAOI there's lots of
other drugs they tell you not to take
we're not using so very good side yes
yeah more of a you know just a
conversation about potential right
anyone you know interested in this
subject obviously you know a lot of
research is is required before
experimentation and so it's not really
advocating necessarily the use but the
conversation is very intriguing
obviously and the notion that Oakland
Santa Cruz now have again expanded that
language kind of back to where we
started here to include in theo jhin's
at large is is the notion that you know
society is interested in exploring these
compounds and trying to determine their
therapeutic potential and how they can
really help shape the world that we live
in
contribute to what touching out you
mentioned earlier seems to be sort of a
spiritual battle in a way and so that's
really what the conversation is about I
think at large just to be clear light
disclaimer
we've disclaimed we're just talking here
but but but but the insider talk you
know is a value in P and and it's not
like people aren't using these in doing
these that's why the conversation is
important right yeah actually what a lot
of it comes down to for me and people
should have the opportunity to do what
they want within their their own skull
but but we but it's providing
information you know so that people
don't go out there you know without the
proper knowledge that they need
not everybody is necessarily as careful
so you know really speak away yeah it's
the psychedelic reticence of sorts
happening and we're and that means we're
coming out of the Dark Ages so there's
lots of misinformation and just total
absence of information that for a minute
because what do you think are the
largest bullet points or misinformation
like that people in general or that you
know for a fact might misunderstand
about you you know this this area I mean
one of my big one for me is the
psychedelic determinism that this drug
does this thing to this person always
right that like I took this drug so
therefore I must do XY and Z almost like
you have no choice or no control over
over yourself yeah think of reefer
madness and how cannabis is a gateway
drug to heroin addiction which is you
know what the narrative was
mid-1900s exactly it's very complicated
and that's part of the other words
you're saying you're not in control of
this experience the the product or
whatever it is is controlling you and
that's not I think it's a product of the
fear-mongering honestly you know there's
all these scare stories that have been
out there you know every drug scare
story PCP and I mean you can name so
many crocodile from from Russia it's
always as if like this drug it's just
controlling this person and making them
do crazy things right and and often you
know people that do really crazy things
on drugs we're in a fairly fragile or
maybe a really bad spot before the drugs
were introduced to the situation so I
mean yeah there's a lot of things at
play and so it's it's kind of it's very
naive it's like drug naivete it should
just be like the idea of the
predetermine ISM with psychedelics is
that as especially problematic but but
is that especially acute with
psychedelics this idea that that I'm not
in control of my ultimate experience is
that is that the pet peeve I think I
think it's very common yeah because it
is a very intense experience and and
there's this ego death experience part
piece of it and yeah and sometimes you
aren't you aren't in control but you did
make a choice and you just have to like
set setting dose are very very important
with psychedelics right so knowing where
you are who you with what your
intentions are what your initial mindset
was before you went into it as
anecdotally I said last night of years
ago not not not willfully of my own
accord but I ended up tripping with my
mother and maintained and everything was
fine and and then in fact you you you
can control your experience and and and
and that's just a fact but you might
need to you know be experienced a little
bit
yeah and you your willpower is very
strong
yeah maybe we'll do a part two sound
thanks you guys