[Music]
and she's a policy and advocacy director
for the multidisciplinary Association
for psychedelic studies maps and that
she's psyched passionate about
psychedelic therapy because it works by
addressing the root causes you know
something that really interests me about
her work is her focus on
intergenerational trauma as well as
using psychedelics for something I never
thought possible community conflict
resolution and restorative justice
something that we had started to kind of
discuss a bit earlier is when kind of
the progression of cannabis to
psychedelics and and that is something
that comes you know we're already seeing
state-level initiatives right now coming
around psilocybin but kind of wondering
where that conversation sits among the
broader conversation for drug
decriminalization for all substances and
and what it looks like when we're
picking out individual substances versus
holding it kind of in this broader
broader context this is something I'm
really thinking a lot about because we
actually saw some polling that there's
much more support for full drug
decriminalization than taking out
individual substances and though
cannabis has played such an amazing
groundwork and created a pathway for
other things to move forward some people
fear that we are you know picking out
that this is a good drug and that there
are bad drugs and what that really means
and so that's something I think it's
really important for us to hold when of
course psychedelics have so much promise
and I guess we can speak a bit more
about that as well but yeah I guess so
I'm curious with how you think that kind
of fits in
to this broader space well I've
experienced exactly what you're talking
about like doing criminal defense which
I did for I now you know turn 20 years
as a lawyer and I remember like
prosecutors just like demonizing math
you know and like math users are evil
meth as evil we're okay with some
substances but meth absolutely not and
when I saw that demonization I thought
like you know we don't want to be like
taking sides and saying like some trucks
are the soft trucks and they're okay and
meth and cocaine and whatever other
substances LSD are bad and they're hard
drugs and it's not a nuanced approach
you know Toni Sarah my mentor says there
are no bad drugs you know that there's
sometimes bad times to use certain drugs
but yes every drug can help you explore
your own human potential and something
that I kind of forgot to mention is that
in fact the more dangerous that a drug
has the potential to be I believe the
more important it is that that drug is
legal and we people have access to
information that they can make sure
they're using it in the most safe way
possible so it might seem like kind of
counterintuitive at first that's
something more dangerous we'd actually
need to be regulated more but that's
something that I hold and that's
something I think sometimes we can lose
track of because as you so beautifully
laid out our whole system of scheduling
is just complete bullshit excuse my
French you know not based on any kind of
research not based on anything that
makes sense so I think yeah it's we we
got caught up in that and something like
cannabis that is so incredibly unsafe in
so many ways and you know it's non fatal
of course seems like extra ridiculous to
be in that space
I guess they refuse to bring up around
cognitive liberty I find really
interesting and also is something that
comes up a lot and so I guess you know
to back up on the director of policy at
maps so I'm lucky to travel the world to
go to different conferences be meeting
with people that work on drug policy and
and psychedelic policy reform
and kind of thinking about it from all
different angles so cognitive liberty is
definitely a strain that is very present
and makes a lot of sense in the context
of of psychedelic advocacy but I guess
kind of centering that in and what we
are just speaking about it's also
interesting to think that some people
you know who are as you also went out or
currently you know in prison and cages
around and around their substance use
feel you know that also cognitive
Liberty though it's something they a
hundred percent you know believed so
deeply and it's kind of like beyond they
you know someone sitting in a cage is
like sure of cognitive liberties great
but you know my physical Liberty like
getting in this in this space and when
there's so many fewer people arrested
for psychedelics than for other
substances like how that kind of comes
into play yeah although I don't we'll
share one there's kind of a tangent that
is really exciting I just learned
recently that apparently LSD is finding
some more ground and use in the prison
system because it's I guess easier to to
access and it's really providing a lot
of people it's a lot of healing which I
thought was just really interesting oh
it's easier to introduce into the
prisons because how compounds not in a
legal right now there is no you know
legal use of LSD that I'm aware of
that's in the research setting yeah and
can you tell us about LSD research like
sure yeah so right now there's actually
not a ton of LSD research going on
there's a ton of psilocybin research and
MDMA research going on but there has
been LSD research in the past maps
conducted a study using LSD therapy to
work with people who have anxiety
associated with the end of like a
terminal illness I mean you saw really
great results with that there are also
some kind of companies starting to
develop LSD for creativity right now
kind of not really a super public about
it and I'm trying to think but I guess
the majority of OSD itself for LSD
analogs I think I've heard of both
actually and just like with psilocybin
where it is suicide in itself and not
the analog that's being developed both
by a nonprofit called
you sono and also for our company called
compass it's also developing psilocybin
now to treat depression and then Maps is
is is developing mdma-assisted
psychotherapy to treat PTSD and all
three groups that I just named about FDA
approval to continue doing this research
Maps
expects by 2021 will have MDMA therapy
approved to treat PTSD which is really
really exciting and we have some people
working on our studies here who can
speak of it about that later
and P tell us about the FDA approval
process you know how onerous is it you
know do they make it easy for research
sure so the FDA process there's a
process of drug development that you
have to take anything through in order
to make a substance into a medicine so
it is onerous but it is also quite just
like here are the steps and that those
were the frameworks that map you know
Maps was founded over 30 years ago when
MDMA was first made illegal based on
ridiculous research that was actually
not MDMA research so we have kind of
taken this path and the FDA is actually
quite insulated from politics because
they're really protecting this ability
to innovate on substance research
however it's really expensive to conduct
there's a phase 1 phase 2 and phase 3
trials and you have to complete phase 3
to have full approval but it costs a lot
of money and so our whole system right
now is created so that you know you have
big pharmaceutical companies or the only
ones able to
research in order to make something into
a medicine maps is a non-profit and
we've started a benefit corporation but
when we were a non-profit we were able
to afford to do this MDMA research
because we basically there's so much
MDMA research sponsored by the
government to try to demonstrate the
harms of MDMA but in fact they failed so
that's like the safety and efficacy data
we've also used that for our cannabis
research so we basically like Aikido
that into like saving us millions of
dollars worth of research and were able
to fundraise to do Phase two and also of
Phase three and in Phase three we have
started a benefit corporation because
post-approval and MDMA is for sale we
can't function as a non-profit but as a
benefit corporation it's really
essential to us that you know the social
benefit is our priority and not profit
maximization because we've seen how that
impacts other pharmaceutical companies
and our healthcare industry and that's
something I'm really proud of with maps
were one of the very first benefit
corporations that our pharmaceutical
companies which is like mind-boggling
like if anything to me should be a B
Corp it would be a pharma company but um
so we're right now just working on
developing like a standards of ethics to
be evaluating a beautful company so if
anyone's interested in that I mean can
you talk about like the funding for
psychedelic research has it shifted now
that cannabis legalization has happened
in many funders minds do you see people
getting more and more open like kind of
coming from the cannabis world or you
know picking up a Michael Pollan book
and being inspired I would say that also
the fact that now the compass for
example is one company that is taking
investors to developing psilocybin that
also pulls away some donors you know
we're trying to do it in a different
context and some people might rather
prefer to invest than donate some people
do both so
I would say if anything were just it's
continuing to grow a lot of the
cryptocurrency community has been really
supportive you had like multiple
anonymous million dollar Bitcoin
donations which was really incredible so
yeah I think just the more and more
people are learning about these things
the more supporters we are having we are
finding are there any legislative
efforts you know to start reforming the
psychedelic prohibition there are there
are ones that I'm really encouraged by
or actually initially I mean I'm all for
referendums and state initiatives but
actually legislators in a number of
states have introduced bills around
ibogaine research iboga is a West
African route bark that's used in the
blue tea tradition and as a really
powerful spiritual guide and medicine
and it the extract ibogaine and iboga
are very effective in stopping opiate
withdrawals and the psychedelic piece is
very healing for people struggling with
substance use and the physiological
component of really blocking your opiate
withdrawals makes it like extra and
powerful there's also research being
done and then in iboga for parkinson's
it's a really powerful medicine but
because of the opiate crisis right now
there's a lot of interest so there are a
few states where we've had state
legislators including Republican state
legislators introduced ibogaine research
bills we're talking to people in
California who are really interested
again I actually have a Republican from
Iowa state legislature like reaching out
I have a call tomorrow so it's like
there definitely is interest I think
right now what's going to be most
feasible around that will be research
focused initiatives and I also you know
I decided I'm all for those legalization
regulation and decriminalization but in
terms of psychedelics I think that's
going to make most
in that broader context and so you think
just choosing to repeal psychedelic
prohibition foresight psychedelics alone
it's not going to be as effective as a
broader strategy yeah I think that both
it won't be as effective because there
won't be as much support but also
because it won't be targeting the like
to me you know the greatest harms of all
drug prohibition are you know those
being incarcerated those and and I just
think that I mean it's not and I also
want to take a step back I am pausing
because even when you say psychedelic
prohibition you know as you saw in the
schedules it's not like they're like
here the psychedelics right like which
what's the sake of that like even MDMA
you know many people around and the
secretary conferences will tell me I'll
be a is not a psychedelic and you know
to Maps it is it means mind manifesting
but the point is that these things are
you know there isn't they're perfectly
defined categories they're already
psychedelics like ketamine that are not
schedule one right and so this process
is already starting and to happen and I
certainly like support anything moving
through the scheduling system I
personally is work getting completely
rid of the scheduling system the country
I just that doesn't even make sense so
that's another frustrating part to keep
working and within this system that's
not really serving but yeah I guess to
me when there are you know groups like
psychedelic societies that are really
excited around you know psilocybin state
initiatives I think that it would be
really awesome to focus on ways to make
psychedelic access safer right now like
things like MDMA use for example as much
there's the most common psychedelic
besides you know not including cannabis
but MDMA is often adulterated with many
other substances and people don't have
access and outside of US and Europe
there are many countries that actually
have drunken government-sponsored drug
checking the u.s. does not quite have
that yet but we are working towards that
and actually it says can you tell us
more about that government sponsored
drug testing drug testing to tell you
what's in your powders or
in your liquid or whatever it is so like
in Barcelona I literally went to a
center that the government sponsors you
can drop off some substances and they'll
they'll give it back they'll send mail
it back to people in the US they were
showing me but then like in other
countries they actually have them set up
at festivals so you can go drop off a
pill and then they'll put a report so
there'll be all these pills that are at
the festival so you can even go by and
check like if you happen to have that
same thing you can check it and it's
been really successful and reducing you
know people find out there's other stuff
in there substances they're less likely
to use it and that kind of actually
helps me to kind of connect to what I
keep saying about psychedelics being
connected to everything in the US now
the for the first time drug checking is
being decriminalized because it's used
for in the opiate crisis it's used to
check opiates for if they're
contaminated with fentanyl which is a
much stronger opiate that's killing with
so many people so there's been this big
move around decriminalizing drug testing
for opiates and because of that then
that makes them decriminalize for MDMA
and for everything right so like that's
like a just one example of ways that
we're actually much more connected to
all of this and then we like to think is
there any a chance of progress on the
federal front what does that look like
well I mean federally is what we're you
know taking through this medical route
so yes you know 2020 one will have MDMA
as medicine so to me that's pretty
exciting I do think that we can be
pretty optimistic about cannabis on a
federal level too but you know then
again that has its own set of
complications but I would say that you
know eventually we can have hope in the
longer term I wouldn't be expecting like
full although you know as I say that
again like I could see a context for
maybe for drugs are decriminalized in
the not-so-distant future I certainly
hope so I so it really does look like
MDMA will will it be rescheduled or D
scheduled what will happen after that so
when a substance is as a medical value
then it's moved to the schedule like two
or three um but what they've done with
other subs
like this is like very well could just
say well for this medical use it's
scheduled to but MDMA any other context
is scheduled one so that's something
that's complicated because usually drugs
going through the system are patent new
molecules that a pharmaceutical company
can patent and then make a lot you know
probably like they have more financial
incentive in that space so that there
are always new substances but with it
something like MDMA or cannabis that's
this widely used substance it's not
clear like for you know with for the
other substances they've actually taken
like they've had their can be to
schedule they can be in to schedules
unfortunately so I've got to get rid of
the whole system well and that happens
with cannabis like you know canvas
itself as scheduled want or Navin all
the schedule 3 that other thing I forgot
what it's called the syndrome is
scheduled to and so it's all over the
place and I guess it remains to be seen
now the history of the scheduling of
MDMA I think was the medical community
thought initially that if it was gonna
be scheduled at all it should be
scheduled for you know there was a kind
of like a consensus actually that my
boss and founder and director of maps
Rick Doblin he when MGM a was first made
illegal which was actually in the early
80s and after some of these other
substances he gathered a group of like
faith leaders therapists doctors to kind
of protest and and they're DEA like was
moving to schedule it they forced them
to have a hearing and so they're DEA
administrative law judge had this
two-year hearing on MDMA and whether it
deserved to be in schedule 1 the judge
decided did not and a moved to schedule
it to another schedule and then the head
of the DEA rejected their own judge's
ruling and it was like nope it's
Schedule one and this was in the 80s you
know and the height of drug war hysteria
with Reagan so it was really like I mean
the MDMA especially was just really not
based in anything it was it had been
used in therapy in the 70s and a lot of
couples therapy and for phobias and then
early 80s a group and it was legal at
this point and it was called Adam and
then a group decided to rename it
ecstasy and sell it to a Dallas like
nightclub scene and so that quickly
helped it skyrocket and then emits the
war on drugs you know what is this new
drug everyone's using and then
immediately move to schedule it and the
crazy thing is this actions in the u.s.
like for MDMA and all other substances
really reverberate throughout the world
we've exported this war on drugs
everywhere so at the UN the same thing
happened a little year later with MDMA
and they moved to schedule it just based
on faulty Rhian research with MDA and
rats like it literally wasn't even MDMA
research they were citing so it's pretty
crazy
[Music]