[Music]
my name is dr. Cole marcha I went to
medical school in Chicago and I did a
residency at UCLA VA program did a lot
of work with people with PTSD II knew
about maps from actually a really long
time ago and sort of caught back up with
them when I was in medical school and
sort of been sort of making my big life
choices based on trying to align my
direction of my ship with the direction
of maps of ship and we collide and so I
graduated from residency 2015 I've been
in private practice doing actually
primarily ketamine for depression and
the opportunity to be involved in the
maps MDMA for PTSD research has been
sort of the dream since 2010 I've been
actively pursuing and trying to get a
site here in Los Angeles and my goal is
for to get as many people involved and
to make Los Angeles specifically like a
an epicenter for the psychedelic
movement and medicine and and anywhere
else
let's see how I'll do a quick little
recap like you did so I used to be an
oceanographer for nine years I worked in
marine science and environmental work
and about five or six years ago I had
some pretty big experiences with some of
the things that we've been talking about
here and really shifted my perspective
and and got me interested in advocacy
and educational work around psychedelics
and drug policy so I started a
psychedelic society called the aware
project rethinking psychedelics and we
have been running monthly events for the
last three years here in Los Angeles we
also have a sister organization called
the inner space integration which is a
integration support program for people
who have had big psychedelic experiences
and need help coming and organizing
their thoughts around what what kind of
came up for them during their experience
so we have monthly integration circles
all around the city for that and through
my work with the aware project I got
unconnected to coal and and maps and we
did a couple of fundraisers for for maps
and and then I got invited to come be
the study coordinator for the clinical
trial of mdma-assisted therapy for the
treatment of PTSD so I'm thrilled to be
part of the team and we just opened
enrollment for our phase 3 clinical
trials last week so we've finally opened
phase 3 it's very exciting it's huge and
I'm also getting a switching careers and
getting a Masters in Social Work now
just like Natalie to become a therapist
and eventually get on the team so I am
on the team but be a therapist so
waiting for me to come graduates and
phase 3 does that way you know what like
the significance of phase 3 as opposed
to phase 7 or
jealously feaces yeah so in psychiatry
in particular phase 1 2 3 phase 1 this
is FDA research specifically how a drug
goes from an idea to on the market phase
one is that you first have to
demonstrate that the drug is safe so
it's given to healthy volunteers that's
where a lot of that the research was
done sort of for us for people
interested in researching MDMA and and
cannabis because there was so much money
spent exploring the dangers that a lot
of that data was already there so then
phase 2 is the first time you apply your
actual theory like we think it's going
to be helpful for this particular
condition and we're going to you know
take people with this condition and who
typically run out of other options and
give them this potential you know
potential new treatments so usually it's
double-blind placebo-controlled and it's
the first time you get you get to see
whether you're this idea holds any water
there were a handful of phase 2 trials
actually done all sponsored by maps for
for mdma-assisted psychotherapy for PTSD
and then phase 3 is when you try to show
that that wasn't just like a lucky
occurrence in one place or something
unique to in this case like South
Carolina where the first study was done
but it's something you can expand that
you also part of phase 3 is having a
plan in place to actually provide all of
that drug to the market should it come
to market because we don't want to you
know go through all this trouble and
then nobody will manufacture MDMA and
everybody's waiting around so so that's
where we're at we're in the very last
step like phase 3 is we are showing that
it can be done not just in one place the
results were amazing in the face to data
and then yeah so phase three is I think
we have 14 locations 12 or 14 locations
and Los Angeles is one and and yeah
we're gonna see I think like 200 people
in total we're gonna do actually two
phase three studies but essentially if
we can reproduce data even close to what
we did with Phase two
like it's gonna be an available drug
it's like it's right at the finish line
and following up on what you said
congratulations but following up on what
you said that you know somebody's got to
build it you said there's already an
infrastructure in place for the
production of MDMA can you tell us more
about that
[Music]
there there's a contract between maps
and a particular drug manufacturer I'm
not sure the name yeah and and it has to
be made by something called good
manufacturing practices so the place
manufacturing the drug if it's gonna be
available to a broad market it has to
meet all of these standards of the FDA
so up until phase three because you
don't know if it's really gonna work out
or not it's not as important but for
Phase three you have to have a
manufacturer it has to be made in the
same way it's going to be made and has
to be manufactured in a place that's up
to FDA standards so that was actually a
big a big adventure and I'll jump in and
just say a little bit more about phase
three which was that it's kind of unique
in in maps applying to do phase three
because they went to the FDA and they
said okay we want to do one study with
around 200 people to show efficacy for
this drug and the FDA was like we've
never seen
a phase three trial that just has one
study and with so few people but because
the effect size meaning you know most
drugs you know that's a you it's a very
small effect size in terms of seeing if
it makes a difference or not and so they
have to have a very large number of
people thousands of people typically to
see if that is that is a significant
effect size but because our effect size
is so big we need such a smaller amount
of number of people I mean for the Phase
two clinical trials it's between seven
between 60 to 80 percent of people after
three rounds of mdma-assisted
psychotherapy did not show any where did
not qualify for PTSD afterwards after
three sessions so that's huge and so so
the anyway Maps went back to the FDA and
said okay well we're not gonna do one
study then we're gonna do two studies
but with 100 each so it's basically the
same number of people but they made it
into two studies and they're like okay
we'll prove that so it's a little funny
that so there's a specific protocol that
we go through that we take all of our
participants through and there's a
several screening criteria that everyone
has to meet and for them to be safe to
be able to enter into the trial and they
take lots of different kinds of tests
and so then they have three integration
or three preparation meetings with a CO
therapy team so each participant is
paired up with two a male and female
Kothari's not your typical individual
therapy but you are actually working
with a pair yeah yeah that's a change we
can have female female through
I'll have to talk about that so so the
participants go through three
preparation sessions and then which is
about an hour and a half
sessions and then one month apart they
have an all-day MDMA experience with
their therapy team and these are spaced
one month apart with three integration
sessions between them
so in all they're getting three
preparation and in DMA then 3
integration then it might have even a
300 and then the whole protocol takes
about four months screening time can
vary a little bit but it's a you know
it's a very efficient therapy yeah yeah
it's and it's a big time investment I
think it's important to communicate that
it's a therapy model the the MDMA
certainly is a powerful part of the of
the whole picture but it's the therapy
model is you know it's the reason for
all of those visits it's the the MDMA
sort of supercharges the therapy in a
way there's there's a trusting and a
bonding between the the therapists and
the participants I I'm guessing that
that's what happens that is just much
much harder to achieve in without that
particular aide and for people who are
talking about the worst thing that's
ever happened to them it takes a lot of
trust and a lot of bonding and a lot of
trust primarily and one of the things
that then makes this so effective is
that is that a therapy because in the
integration work that I do through inner
space integration we see that people
that have experimented either
recreational with these things or maybe
done underground therapy that they're
not
getting you know either any integration
any preparation or not enough and people
either are just not prepared for what
can come up for them and so having it in
this context creates such a level of
safety especially with people that have
severe trauma really makes this very
effective I wanted to ask you to
elaborate on the preparation and the
integration and what does it look like
if you're a patient you know what does
it feel like the preparation the
preparation integration visits are going
to look very similar but obviously at
different points in the process and it's
the room the our particular study room
is it doesn't look like a hospital room
it's it's cozy it's inviting the
therapists pairs usually address pretty
casual like this and and the first three
sessions are getting to know each other
building rapport building a relationship
talking about boundaries and talking
about talking about at at some point
talking about the trauma itself and then
the integration can be and those are
about 90-minute visits after the MDMA
sessions the integration can can really
vary as far as what comes up it can be
about what came up in the medicine
session itself it can be about what's
continuing to unfold in the days
afterward or in attempts to like apply
insights into their real life or yeah it
can really be all over the place and the
the therapy model is very non directive
or or participant directed its we're not
telling people what to do or what's the
right way to think about what happened
to them in fact that would be the exact
opposite of what we're supposed to
it's not we're not interpreting for them
or or or steering it in any particular
direction a lot of times what comes up
for people is not what they expected to
come up a lot of times what what what it
may be a very healing experience to have
isn't what they thought it was going to
be when they went in and so it's just
supporting what's the therapists are
trying to support what's happening
naturally for the for the participant
and whatever way that requires and can
you tell us about like the all-day
therapy session with the medicine what
is the dosage you know what is it like
for participants like I'm you know my
experience is limited to I guess like
the night club ecstasy contacts with
people rolling nobody's rolling at these
things are they I'm not sure what the
typical like night club dose is supposed
to be but I'd guess around a hundred
milligrams or something
[Music]
so somebody pays like twenty bucks for a
pillow at a party so to answer the
question yeah so when they first come in
there's just general orientation to the
room and review of what's gonna happen
and they take 120 milligrams and the in
the study that we most recently did and
a potential booster of 60 milligrams
after 90 minutes or 90 minutes to two
hours we check in with them and there's
a potential booster of 50% more has been
consistent through all of the studies
but it's varied from a hundred to start
with a 50 booster
there were some dose finding studies
specifically but yeah that's pretty much
that's the default default is that
people take the bonus and yeah there's I
think we've had a participant that
didn't take it at one time most of the
time they do dr. Marta was describing
you know it's really not directed by the
therapist but so therapists often invite
the participant to go inside and put on
a blindfold and listen to music and
that's often how this process starts and
sometimes the you know the session is
like four to six hours long and
sometimes hours of that session people
are just like listening to music lying
down with the blindfold on and it's
really I've had the privilege of
watching videos of people like dr. Marta
doing the therapy and it's amazing to
watch people literally their body like
they'll be lying they're like moving
their body is releasing stuff crying
laughing like you know sometimes they'll
sit up all of a sudden and take it off
and want to start speaking and there's
just really such varied ways that
they're processing and then after that
is over you know spending the night at
the sleeping over is a really nice piece
of a way to like close it out because I
know when I people always say to me you
know after doing MDMA I have the worst
down the next day I feel terrible all
this stuff and in our studies we really
haven't seen that happen and I do
suspect when people are telling that to
me they're also like drinking and
partying all night and then go back to
work on Monday so there's some other
things in play but I do think in our
studies when people have a really
nourishing dinner spend the night in the
space have another session in the
morning with the therapist it's like
kind of closes it out and and and can
creates a container that I don't know if
you guys have seen it but I certainly
don't hear of people having those like
down after MDMA experiences and our
studies well you know can also I mean
it's maybe a little hard to tell if
they're having a Down or not because
they
they're going through in a really
emotional process right so even if you
know the even if there wasn't it down
from the MDMA it'd be kind of hard to
tell if you know because they're
processing you know examined in the
moment in their lives so yeah yeah it's
hard work I mean it's not easy to do and
I applaud the people that have the
courage to do it and they really are
yeah addressing the worst thing that's
ever happened to them in a very like
face-to-face kind of way so it's very
common for there to be a lot of ups and
downs especially after the first
experience the first of the three or
actually the first where there's a big
confrontation of of the trauma sometimes
I've seen I've watched a lot of videos
too and as part of our training
sometimes the first session people are a
little more reluctant to open up still
it takes again a lot of trust and a lot
of safety a feeling of safety but yeah
like it's hard to judge whether that
that day after thing is is something
that we're actually seeing clinically
because there are so many things that
could explain any state after any
session and it really is a continuingly
unfolding process like it's not once
they're engaged in the treatment they
need a lot of support both when they're
at their visits and when they're not at
their visits because again they're
confronting something that by definition
I mean it's like part of the description
of PTSD as a syndrome that it's
something they avoid dealing with so
yeah
it can be kind of erratic I guess that
so I'm I guess I have like so many
questions this is very fascinating for
me you know have you thought about doing
like longer-term studies have you
considered that and for the first there
there's been efforts to get longer-term
data as far as you know how the how the
effects good or bad maintain and I
believe the first study that was done
there was a follow-up a long-term
follow-up and it varied based on when
people had entered the study but for the
most part you know the the changes are
sustained like a lot long after I think
the average duration or the average time
period after the last session in the
particular study I'm thinking of was
like two and a half years was the
average amount of time some people like
eight years since there they stopped
their sessions and the majority of
people I don't remember the exact
numbers but the majority of people
having maintained the benefits of they
have as you were saying before it's like
this process and framework so because of
that the results are often better
further out from the study both like not
a meet immediately after people also
don't call five for PTSD but then months
later their PTSD score decreases and
then the long-term follow-up study that
dr. Martha is referring to also board
that out which is just like unheard of
and other kinds of psychiatric
intervention so yeah in a way what we're
doing you know in in how different this
is from typical pharmaceuticals is that
instead of masking symptoms we're really
getting to the core of what people what
people are feeling in the pain that
they're feeling in the suffering and so
and addressing that directly so and you
know you're also kind of teaching people
how to heal themselves and so I think
that might be kind of what's
contributing to
the sustained and an even in long-term
improve continued improvement because
you've started to teach people how to
address what all the feelings that have
come that they've been kind of
suppressing or and allowing them to
teach them how to bring them up in a
healthy way and to be able to process
them in a manageable way I think self
healing I want to bring this concept of
inner healing intelligence or inner
healer which is something that the Maps
framework speaks about a lot and
introduces to the people who are working
with to kind of have that concept of
like listening to your inner healer and
what that means for you to lead the
healing process yourself and not to come
from somewhere external good point so
set in setting are very important for
the psychedelic experience and I I'm
thinking back to my experiences with
ecstasy back in law school it's like we
would always take vitamin C because I
don't know if it was actually the real
deal but they're supposed to heighten
the experience and maybe like you know
reduce the crash effect do you do
anything like that to prepare people for
the experience we don't have anything
specific you know we want people to take
care of themselves prior to coming in
and we have refreshments and snacks
available on hand general like self-care
items but we don't have any particular
regimens I think for a number of reasons
but in in the context of a study like
this you don't want to add any possible
sort of introduced variables yeah
exactly variables that story thank you
you don't want to add any additional
variables that somebody could point to
and say oh well you know maybe it's the
vitamin C that it makes everybody better
you know so we want to control as much
as possible we try to take people off of
all of their
they're psychiatric medications and
there are a couple you know things on
hand in case of emergencies but but yeah
we we don't have any particular regimens
we recommend before or after and just to
step back a little bit for people who
don't know what sentence setting is it
was a phrase that was coined in the 60s
as these things were coming into a
public forefront and the idea is that
your set is your mindset so whatever
you're kind of coming in with whether
it's trauma or how your day was that's
what you're bringing into this space and
then setting is your context that you're
doing the experience and so psychedelics
seem to kind of make you a little bit
more permeable to whatever it was kind
of going on underneath in your internal
system but also what's going on and
externally and so the ideas that we're
trying to at least in the studies make
sure that we're helping support people
in both that from that psychological
perspective but also creating a
comfortable and safe container for them
to experience whatever they're
experiencing and Maps has another
program called the zendo project which
Cole and I have any volunteer to where
have all been volunteers for the zendo
project which is a psychedelic
opportunity and you can't do is the
psychedelic harm reduction nonprofit
that no okay like having you here here
for my back checking and they provide
services at festivals for people that
have had a big experience or in in midst
of a big experience and they create a
safe container for people to calm down a
little bit get some nourishment to get
stay warm whatever it is and so they
have volunteers that are medical
professionals mental health
professionals and just anyone
volunteering that can help support
people in these spaces so that we're
making sure that these people are
getting help and then that they don't
necessarily have to go to the Med tent
or get picked up by the
just because they're tripping too hard
but and their friends bail yeah and then
you're creating more traumatic
experiences and and you know and so many
so many things that I've experienced
sitting doing the zener project and also
hurt so many more experiences that
having that container with a person that
can compassionately listen to you really
can change a very challenging experience
into something that they find actually
that it was very in in sight and
influential so it's a really great
project so I highly recommend checking
it out and a lot of psychedelic it's a
great place to learn you know legal
contacts and people and and kind of
learn I would highly recommend it it's a
really awesome experience anybody
interested and that's that kind of if
you're if you're oriented that way
towards trying to help people in crisis
like that it's a really great way to do
it and meet really awesome people it's a
it's a peer support service there's you
know access to medical if things you
know we're more difficult or complicated
but but yeah it's it's a peer support
service and and I think it changes a lot
of people's lives really a lot of people
who end up in there instead of being
arrested like PTSD study you know and a
lot of them a lot of people who have
come in as guests of the zendo have come
back as volunteers there is a really
cool
so I just want to prep everybody out
here we want to make this a little bit
participatory so if anybody has any
questions or comments or in we got the
backward can you guys come maybe up to
help therapists connect more with their
patients I was wondering if you can
speak to that and if there's any studies
coming up that kind of integrates the
therapist into the experience as well
[Music]
was actually developed by Merck a
pharmaceutical company in 1912 and it
was developed to be like a blood nothing
to do with therapy and then it kind of
really cool again then introduced like
kind of it's still unclear to me how he
like knew that kind of might be helpful
to therapists but then I think that's
maybe what you're thinking of that it
was first introduced in like among
therapists it wasn't first like a party
drug was first given literally by this
chemist to therapists across the country
saying why don't you try this with your
clients and that's how it kind of spread
yeah it didn't go through the process
we're going through now and it wasn't
illegal yet so it was just sort of like
Shogun was respected brilliant person
who had doctor friends and so I can
imagine that it could have been used in
that way and but and actually a lot of
the therapists that that received MDMA
and used it in those early days I think
primarily did couples therapy and that's
a lot of that has sort of seeped into
the way that we are trained now like the
I believe that male-female therapy team
came from a model that was for married
couples from the MDMA because they
advised a lot of like a lot of the
therapy model and the technique a lot of
those psychiatrists helped to sort of
develop the process that we're using now
because they're still around and we're
pretty bummed on that tool got taken
away from them I like the premise of the
question and I wish therapists were
allowed to use MDMA with their patients
I think that they might be able to bond
even more quickly well and I'll say one
more thing is then maps did make a way
for therapists to experience what MDMA
is like so that they can have a greater
level of understanding of what their
patients are going through so they have
a study going on right now and their
plans to be more studies where the
therapists get taken through sort of an
abbreviated version of the of the
protocol that that our participants are
going through so where they're the
participant they're the participant and
that they get to do the MDMA with to
therapy their therapy giving healthy
volunteers MDMA just so they can
understand how to be yeah it's a very
different model more safety data and so
I was gonna ask about the zendo project
that you guys are just talking about
I've actually signed up online to be to
be notified I guess when those volunteer
opportunities I don't see a lot of stuff
come through there and I have seen the
downloadable training manual but I
wasn't sure if there was face-to-face
training locally or if there was kind of
a more immediate way to get involved I
don't think that there are local
trainings but there
there is someone in Chicago there that's
a really great question and they
basically have been responding to people
like you you know wanting to have more
access to the training so they've
actually done one I think in Portland
one in Chicago and they're going to be
developing more but you're based in LA
yeah I think also you know they're there
they work and like burning man after all
actually no longer at Africa burn you
know because they supported the groups
there so they're trying to kind of go to
more training actually unless outreach
so hopefully you should could do an LA
training the home bases that I believe
they're gonna continue to do sort of in
perpetuity at least right now are
lightning in a bottle and vision and
Burning Man so thank you so much yeah
would be a good way locally to dip your
toes in okay great thank you know
coordinator based in LA well accordin
well connected a couple yes several Z
and do project org hey guys thank you so
much for everything you're doing for us
so thank you Omar thanks okay I've got a
question for you on the criteria of
research facilities and I'll put it in a
hypothetical scenario like let's say you
have a retreat center right I'm not
gonna say like esslyn or maybe some of
our Northern California farms that are
transitioning from cannabis farms into
you know retreats and spaces where you
know we're sort of like licensing
certain things can we register to work
with maps and or other research
organizations to do set setting guided
meditations and long-term retreats and
PTSD
you know healing like not just for weeks
but for months residency things of that
nature I mean it would that be a viable
business model for us to sort of strive
for in the future or do you see that I
hope so
that's the dream for a lot of people
myself included is that we would have
places like that but yeah we're still in
the getting it legalized part or at
least the the treatment part but you
know once it once it is an available
treatment then yeah you can you could be
able to create a specialized retreat
place that it almost be like short-term
living because it you know several
months long but I think it would be
great for people to be immersed and have
other healthy activities to fill their
day with because yeah it's hard to
especially people who are coming out of
just traumatic environments you know an
eight-hour session sounds like a long
time of therapy but you know the other
hundred some-odd hours of the week
they're you know listening to gun shots
and trying to make it safely to the bus
or whatever the research is kind of as
we're kind of set for Phase three
research spaces but before we have full
approval we're actually we're actually
expecting approval for something called
expanded access so technically if if you
were to get a team together of people
that would have to be trained that go
through the MDMA therapy training and
have a Schedule one license and have the
appropriate team but if you collected a
team and had a space as soon as 2019 we
could have expanded access MDMA therapy
happening there so it's actually we're
really really close but right now maps
can't you know we've invested in
developing our different feet like Phase
three research sites but we're not going
to be sponsoring this expanded access
it's kind of like an add-on before
approval basically we are a grant like
this comes because there's such a huge
potential for treatment that they're
like want people to have access you know
as soon as possible and so there's that
caveat that could allow you if you
gathered your team together where would
we learn about this
say you can also email and we can like
will sent we can send you all thank you
and if I could add like right now
ketamine is a Schedule three control
substance and there's ketamine therapy
and actually you conduct some ketamine
therapy for depression can you tell us a
little bit more about that and I was
always curious like you know I associate
ketamine with a k-hole and falling down
the K hole and you know is that a
paradoxical effect of ketamine it's a
it's a potential effect of ketamine for
sure but yeah in the in the doses that
are that have been shown to be helpful
there's been a lot of studies with
ketamine for depression it's not
something that's likely to get go
through the phase 3 process because I
think even something like MDMA for PTSD
where we're it's all donor funded and
it's like a shoestring budget it's still
in the tens of millions of dollars so
ketamine not having any like reason to
invest tens of millions of dollars
there's nobody who is going to unless
anybody in here has like forty million
dollars I'll do it's just me for you but
yeah it's like forty million dollars or
something like that to run a phase three
study all the way through so I figure I
was going with that but you don't need
right because it's already scheduled
through exactly so so the the studies
that have been done there's plenty of
evidence that it's effective at a dose
that also can provide what they call a
dissociative or psychotic effect in
studies but it's most people have had
the experience and they're familiar with
psychedelics would describe it as a
psychedelic experience and those of us
trained in working with psychedelic
States and the potential healing its I
see it as like a sort of wasted
opportunity not to just set up a
treatment plan where we administer the
medicine that's been shown to be safe
and effective and also add some
psychotherapy that's been shown to be
safe and effective
and psychedelic experience which
psilocybin and MDMA are starting to show
may be safe and effective too so we see
very very difficult cases in my clinic
we have as good or better outcomes than
the research that's done without those
considerations in mind and I think that
that's one of the reasons why how's it
going guys I just had a quick question
so I've heard a lot of talk about MDMA
LSD psilocybin I really haven't heard a
lot of talk or I guess maybe research
maybe I'm wrong about DMT and what's
crazy to me is that it's the most of
like crazy of the psychedelics and it's
naturally occurring in the brain do you
guys have any insight on that or like
research or anything that you have to
stay on that well yeah I mean DMT I mean
besides the research that Rick Strassman
has done I mean it's it's hard to to
know what the the therapeutic value is
but it's it's it's a little bit hard to
contain whereas with something like
psilocybin where it's milder and you've
got a longer working time whereas in
supposed to you know the DMT experiences
that people may have in recreationally
you know it was a five minute inhaled
experience and you're thrown to another
dimension
and then you come back and it's like
okay what what just happened you know
and so I think it's gonna but also DMT
is also in the ayahuasca brew which is
shown to show lots of effects and
beneficial effects for various mental
health conditions so there are there is
considerable amount of research
happening socially in in places where
ayahuasca is legal so when using it in
that context there is some not it more
retrospective and sort of survey
research around the effects are in the
benefits of five mio DMT some research
with quite a bit of studies coming out
of that came out of Crossroads treatment
center in Mexico that was working with
that medicine and has shown several
different things about that
it's just both of them
it's a it's very hard to fit those into
a medical model because it's it's
blasting into an another space and to be
able to can create as medical eyes that
is very hard there are people that are
maybe not so much with DMT in the in the
it's pure form
but five amino there are people that are
interested in in trying to figure out
either moving that through some sort of
religious freedom movement or through a
medical context there is a group out of
Boulder Colorado called medicinal
mindfulness and they're working with
Rick Strassman to do some really
interesting research with extended state
DMT but it's more for exploration in a
way than it is for like medical usage so
that's really the only way that you can
research these substances if it's
medical so even if it's like it's
naturally occurring in the brain and we
just want to figure out what the hell it
is they're doing like neuro imaging
studies with DMT at Imperial College in
London so they're actually doing a
really cool study seeing what what part
of your brain lights up when you see
entities or something what that could
mean
so as Ashley it was saying like because
there isn't a therapeutic context that
we've created except the ayahuasca which
I really appreciate you saying and I
think we can't ignore that the way
indigenous cultures have used this DMT
medicine is in ayahuasca that's how
these appears great so at you know DMT
but it is being examined like
academically in neuroimaging and other
contexts just not in like maps is very
focused on therapeutic research so it's
just so stigmatized you know there's
very little research money out there
even for something that like the study
that we're doing there's there's there's
you're not gonna get research money from
the government to do research on
schedule on substances so that's going
to be one of the really interesting
things that happens when we get MDMA
rescheduled that's going to open up all
of this federal funding to be able to do
more research on MDMA and then we won't
have to be asking people for money
may research and doing it through a
non-profit model so then we're gonna see
this explosion of research around you
know the first ones that are coming
through the system is MDMA and
psilocybin so I'm we you know our
collective hope is that through that
just rescheduling it will open up so
much more money to do so much more
research and then that will open
people's interests and minds about these
things to be able to open up more
research in the future not necessarily
medical research but just to figure out
what the hell it is it's just big
mattias I think to conference in New
York called tearing em initiative an
Imperial College of London okay thank
you guys thank you I appreciate it hi
you guys folks talked a little bit about
stage 3 trial and needing to line up a
partner to manufacture the MDMA and also
the shortness of how you know a few
therapy sessions can can have a big
impact has it been an impediment to
finding a manufacturing partner someone
that's not looking to like make another
prozac or something I take for the rest
of your life and can you speak on that
gossip or anything but I know that it
makes sense that you know a small order
would go a long way and so there were
delays in getting the medicine that we
needed to do the phase 3 studies and I
don't think it was like a conspiracy or
anything it was just math on the side of
people who make their living doing math
and it was like that there I think there
are higher priority things for sure
means that it was really not like the
amount the quantity we're asking for it
was so small that they first feel like
industrial yeah first agreed to do it
with us because they're really
interested and then something shift I
mean
it wasn't as you said it wasn't because
of the MDMA and we haven't actually had
we have far more difficulty doing
research with marijuana than with MDMA
based on where we can like with cannabis
we can only get it from the University
of Mississippi grown by the National
Institute on Drug Abuse so it's like a
government space but with MDMA we can
contract with any like they're a pharma
company that's a creating the chemicals
not the kind that's necessarily
developing those chemicals they're kind
of two kinds of fart when you say
pharmaceutical companies but that we
haven't I had issues with that thank you
I guess I thank you for being here and
sharing all this information I have a
question where like the the studies that
you're participating in are there
considerations to like the endogenous
parts of the human body like so the
variance between someone who has like a
really clean digestive system enteric
nervous system liver all these things
that are going to be part of the the
endogenous activity right so they're
considerations too like the individual
the difference between administering
that dose to someone and like how much
dopamine and serotonin they kick out and
then post use are they looking at
cortisol levels and then like how do how
do you adjust that kind of stuff I guess
that's what I really can and then the
delivery system does that change is it
always orally administered are there any
variants in any of these substances like
is there a sinus spray with MDMA would
that change metabolism with that change
that individualized dopamine serotonin
and then potential kick back of cortisol
in the post side I know that was like a
lot yeah you know the there's there's an
invitation out to kind of academia to
throw a Don Studies on this is like in
my experience in academic research this
kind of study is sort of like a
mothership study that people can get
grants for ten thousand twenty thousand
to like like we have an ad on
study happening with ours where we're
gonna do epigenetic we're going to look
at some epigenetic data getting some
like DNA swabs from people or you know
with swabs are spit you know very easy
to add on so there's been invitation and
that's that's pretty standard in
academic research I think in the earlier
studies there probably wasn't as much to
that cool like secondary data basically
being collected because everybody was
hesitant to just touch it at all but now
there there is there's a there's a a
pile of secondary data that's just like
still waiting to be you know to be
searched through I don't know it to the
level of exact detail but there have
been cortisol levels looked at oxytocin
levels looked at vasopressin
lots of different hormones that people
have different theories about and and we
always collect as much like demographic
data as we possibly can so yeah there's
a goldmine of data to look at it's just
the focus has been on the of our
research in particular has been on you
know does it work we don't we're not as
concerned in our specific study designs
with why it works it's showing that it
does cuz that's what's most important
and that it's safe and then we can
figure all the rest out as we go then I
guess just real quick for MDMA and
ketamine oh is it just orally
administrator are there any other
delivery systems that you guys know
about for MDMA I believe orally is all
that's been utilized so far for ketamine
it's been studied in a lot of different
routes of administration majority of the
larger studies used intravenous
primarily because the first studies had
to have anesthesia all over see all
Studies on human subjects they required
anesthesiologists to administer the
ketamine because they had more
experience with it because it come
from anesthesiology so it was delivered
IV sort of historically but then lots of
different routes of administration have
been looked at and as far as safety goes
it seems like or Alize has the least
amount of side effect dental Assad
profile and then you work with it in
term usk you'll early yeah I primarily
work with it intramuscularly because it
is delivered quickly there's not as much
monitoring it's not as invasive as IV
but and it has the second most amount of
data but orally intranasally yeah I
think there's even some cases of
suppositories thank you so much so I
guess there's a complement to the like
scientific and research ways of getting
MDMA or psilocybin to be rescheduled or
at least I'm being me at least in the
United States it would it be a
compromise or a complement to the
research if there was something like a
normal for psychedelics that was
advocating on behalf of consumers like
trying to push forth like
decriminalization policies on local
levels whether like the municipality or
state law or that kind of thing like is
it yeah I guess is that it would that be
a good or bad for them have been overall
normal like an orm oh yeah to advocate
for consumers who are taking it outside
the research context I think you know
overall definitely would be a helpful
thing to have more people engaged and
learning and advocating and not have
these substances be criminalized or for
anyone to you know we
not having access to them and the Cephas
is possible so like I've definitely not
against something like that happening
but I was kind of speaking about was how
I would think that the priority for me
strategically would lie with those
activists and groups connecting more
broadly with with people working to end
the war on drugs and not just take out
psychedelics but to say how can we as
psychedelic advocates like help support
people who are trying to legalize
opiates because you know these
substances that are so stigmatized no
one is gonna want to talk about and
instead of when they are speaking about
it they have to focus on reducing the
harms of things like it's so dangerous
we need to make this legal but how can
psychedelic advocates be like well
actually there are so many substances
that are really know for the betterment
of well people that are safe that are
kind of fill out this spectrum so that's
or like my strategic priorities would
lie but I know that it's certainly like
having more support and awareness and
just like there's so many people so
excited about it so I feel like there's
something missing by not like taking
advantage of everyone being like we want
to legalize psychedelics and move this
forward so I think it would be cool for
that group to really think about how to
organize this community of people that
really want to make change and like to
think what are the biggest pain points
right now and what to focus on and right
now for those of you who don't know
there are a network of psychedelic
societies across the u.s. I know Murray
says audience is healthy does a lot of
coordination and working with a lot of
them so they're like groups that are
kind of built in there's kind of like
normal equivalent that our chapters
literally over 90 around the whole world
and they would probably be built in
they're the ones reaching out and
starting these psilocybin initiatives so
they're kind of already are those
frameworks so I would like connect in
with that the drug policy Alliance is a
really great organization because
they're really fighting for the
decriminalization of all drugs so yeah
they're awesome and I would like to
offer I guess a concurring perspective
you know I think it's good to have
change on all levels at all times it's
not a cereal
it's a parallel thing and so it would be
good for there to be activists pushing
actively to repeal psychedelic
prohibition in addition to repealing all
prohibition but you know it's not gonna
happen if people aren't pushing for it
and it needs to be part of the
conversation so if you want to take the
lead on that then you will be my hero my
question is very similar to the last
question actually so I guess I'll just
go a little further with that because I
was just wondering since there has been
a lot of information about a lot of
psychedelics for a long time like LSD
for example it's people saying that it's
not harmful like Timothy Leary and in
the way the US government like made this
guy into a criminal there's still a lot
of of the other side of people trying to
make them illegal and pushing for that
and is that a big hurdle or do you feel
that psychedelics will be more legal
soon how do you guys feel about this
situation and currently I think that's a
good question and something that I think
is part of the maps strategy from you
know over 30 years was how do we use
this like scientific research to kind of
prevent anyone from saying this is crazy
and dismissing Timothy Leary and you
know there was tons of research before
but it wasn't in the FDA framework that
it is now so it's getting a lot harder
and even in the five years I've worked
at maps I've seen a lot less resistance
and also Maps is we work a lot with
veterans and PTSD and I feel like that's
also a particularly a population that
when they're speaking about their
experience it's really hard for people
to just you know dismiss what they're
saying and and we're having people like
Michael Pollan and all these kind of
more mainstream and sources talking
about you know not we're in LA how many
more TV shows now do you see ayahuasca
mentioned an MGM a therapy session or
whatever it is so I think that's really
shifting it
and right now I my like great I think
the people that are don't want
psychedelics to be medicine and be legal
are probably those who are making
pharmaceuticals that got to take every
single day for the rest of your life and
something's coming along that could
totally change that and those are
already the groups trying to prevent
cannabis from moving forward so I think
it's more along those lines even though
of course people still have you know
don't not everyone knows about this new
psychedelic Renaissance so there's
probably a lot of that left over but I'm
not I'm not seeing it like in DC then so
many Republican legislators I meet with
know all about the MDMA for PTSD
research so yeah just my my feeling of
it and made just be my opinion nothing
more is that the whatever the source was
of all of that fear and you know fear
tactics of it like the whoever was
benefiting from that initial like Nixon
you know like the the source of that
paranoia and fear is kind of aged out
and and there are a lot of consequences
that are leading to bigger problems like
with you know prison overpopulation and
stuff there are a lot of like sensible
things now that I think can relate to
most people I don't I haven't at this
point felt any like true conspiratorial
hand somewhere just more like laziness
of like not you know it takes a lot of
work to like pass a law to unpassed one
takes like ten more ten times more
energy it's like ridiculous
bureaucracies are crazy
I think psychedelics are becoming
increasingly more accepted in society
and especially with the advent of micro
dosing they're going to become
infinitely more accepted especially with
all the boomers who are now nearing
retirement and they're looking for a way
to spruce up their retirement and
brighten their day I think and also with
minimal enforcement of the LSD
prohibition by the DEA I think we're
gonna see widespread use of micro dosing
and
even more acceptance you can only bear
the truth for so long my questions about
legalization as well I'm a person who
used to be like super anti drug war and
thought all drugs should be legalized
but then you hear anecdotes I was
talking to a woman who's rural town
because of the opioid epidemic this is
her citation it's like people you know
steal everything like you can't have a
store with like lawn furniture out front
because it gets taken and obviously it's
like tough to be an addict like that and
there's like social consequences how
would you respond to comments about you
know widespread drug legalization you
know affording more opportunity for
people to get addicted in like really
bad ways and then the social impacts
that come from that
I didn't maybe speak enough about that
and actually in countries like Portugal
was one country that decriminalize drugs
when they were experiencing a really bad
opiate crisis and actually what they
found it might sound counterintuitive
but actually decriminalizing substances
doesn't increase use it actually
decreases use and also decreases rates
of contracting different illnesses
decreases rates of overdoses and the
theory is basically that instead of
people having to like shoot up on a
street or in a bathroom and overdose
alone and have a dirty needle and and
not know what's in there substances when
they can go and feel safe to seek
treatment or seek any kind of support
even if it's not to stop using even if
it's to go to a safe injection space
where you can have a clean needle you
could have a nurse there and you could
have access to resources maybe you need
help getting a job you're not ready to
stop using yet but you want help with
one thing or another
and there the research really abundant
it makes abundantly clear that that is
the way to actually decrease use and to
make use more safe and in all the
countries that their opiates remain
illegal and have more punitive laws
they're actually higher rates of
overdoses and dangerous interactions so
yeah I guess I would look at both there
Portugal the Czech Republic has been
decriminalized Spain like countries that
have that going on and how their opiate
context says is different than ours and
it's it's we're kind of shifting its
instead of treating drug use as a
criminal justice issue it's treating as
a health issue so when you you've
distinct eyes dit people that do
actually want help can get help and
you're going to be giving them to you
know a social worker rather than a
prison guard right yeah that's exactly
right and I would just add that it is
important you know not to overlook the
you know they're not harmless a lot of
them are extremely dangerous
I think drugs in general are just like
any other tool that we have discovered
as a species you know we can use this
mic stand as a mic stand or we could use
it to bludgeon somebody with depending
on our intention with it right like so
drugs have effects I think I couldn't
agree more
that's exactly right that this this is a
health care these are health care issues
like addiction the health consequences
psychosis induced by sight psychedelics
psychosis induced by cocaine math those
are all medical issues let the medical
community work with it support the
medical community in dealing with it
treat addicts as patients I think when
you make it a criminal justice thing you
just add one more of those bad
consequences now they're disenfranchised
citizens now they can't vote now they
can't get jobs
it's like much faster to steal and you
know do all those bad things when you
have no prospects - you know I've been
told you're you're a fuckup when you
look at some of the work by cab or Ma
Tei who
looks at addiction and what the root
causes of addiction are you see it's
often trauma and so if people can get
help with their trauma then and you can
give them better coping skills then
maybe they don't need to use drugs to
cope so it's not we like to it's a lot
easier for us to vilify the drug but
it's really not like the drug is the way
of treating the trauma
I think our stigmatizing a substance
kind of makes it more appealing it
becomes a forbidden fruit you know want
to see substances are no longer
forbidden once they're seen for what
they are something that is usually
harmful to the user then they don't have
that appeal of you know doing something
that is out long thank you that's really
awesome information thank you
in terms of micro dosing like I wanted
you guys to maybe address it from like
the everyday life of sort of like I
don't know like professionals and like
or people it's just everyday the
everyday person right but also like
micro dosing in terms of like LSD versus
MDMA and like how those two there are
very different drugs but you know I mean
we can't encourage people to do illegal
substances so you know but there are
good resources online there's a website
called the third wave that helps people
be safe in their use from I would say a
little bit more of a harm reduction
perspective so I think there would be a
great resource for for learning more
about that I'm not as familiar with it I
think James Fadiman who has been around
for a long time and did a pretty serious
dissection
of the topic though James Fadiman be
somebody to look for I think you
recently published a book and a lot of
like the I started hearing about a whole
lot more after after that book came out
so encourage people micro dosing to fill
out a survey and that's what he talks a
lot about but I'm curious you mentioned
MDMA micro dosing and I'm curious like
from you guys if you've heard of that
good speaking of you know negative you
know that it's not all fun and games the
MDMA there's a there's a effect called
chronic tolerance that some people are
potentially everyone would get after
enough doses of MDMA where it no longer
works so microdose you know regularly I
think would just expedite that and if
it's a tool that would be really
beneficial and helpful and a you know
down the line after a traumatic event I
mean life's full of traumas and nobody
can be guaranteed not to have one it'd
be good to have that tool still in their
toolbox and it's not oh go ahead it's
it's it's also I mean MDMA is a little
bit different than some of the other
psychedelics it doesn't I mean a LSD and
psilocybin have shown to have kind of
neurological benefits or creativity
benefits words when we did our dosed
responsive studies in further maps they
were showing that actually lower doses
of MDMA they were still not microdose
but actually made people more anxious
and had they had worse outcomes at lower
doses of MDMA because what you're doing
is MDMA is it's a it's a it's related to
amphetamines so you're getting all the
jittery fetta mean a part of the the
MDMA without getting the the serotonin
and dopamine and oxytocin flood with it
so you're not getting the
benefits you're just getting the the
anxiety part and the the health their
MDMA is not a good one to do very often
because it does tax your system it's
it's not like the other ones a bias plug
maps though is been carrying the torch
like they have been around for thirty
years earlier there was a the comment
about you know DMT you know that though
when I was hearing was some frustration
that we will only study things if
there's may be a medical benefit because
of maps we don't we even only have that
like no one was funding this stuff yeah
maps like raised the money by donations
from rooms like this with awesome people
and the effort of more and and a
snowballing process of funding and
research and we're right at the finish
line there are lots of groups and
organizations out there but maps really
deserves I think that recognition and
credit and we're just trying to get past
the finish line here you know because
once we reschedule then we're gonna get
so much more ability to get research
money and then all of these studies that
people are interested in we can start
doing them because there's gonna be
money so it's like focusing all the
money on to get this across this finish
line and then it's gonna really open up
right like I can't I couldn't try to get
a a grant for a federal loan which is
where the majority of research comes
from unless you are a drug company or
being funded by a drug company to do
their research the National Institute of
Mental Health and the National Institute
of drug abuse combined I think is over
almost three billion dollars in funding
this study is thirty to forty million
something last fall park estimate I
heard like that kind of that kind of
grant you know is not very hard to get
for something something this
groundbreaking like the
if the there would be plenty of funding
but but you can't propose a study of
something that's directly against the
policy of you know the neighboring
department or sometimes the same
Department in the government agency so
once it's rescheduled those proposals
can be taken seriously and yeah I mean
then the Renaissance will really begin
yeah I don't know if this is a question
that might be better for like after the
panel or something I could do online but
I work at a place it's actually called
the psychedelic healing Shack and it's
in Detroit Michigan and I was just
wondering if there were any like
chapters or representatives of maps in
Michigan or in Detroit because we would
love to like have an event or like you
did a discussion at our venue there's
mine manifest Midwest but that's coin in
Detroit not in Detroit yeah you should
start your own psychedelic Society talk
to Marissa where do you see the or is
there a relationship between the work
that you're doing current currently and
the unregulated guided psychedelic I
don't know what what exactly that you
know to call to call that right now that
is
yeah you know I think that's what like
Michael Pollan was speaking to a lot in
his book and I mean I see that right now
is like oh man would I love my parents
to have some sort of guided experience
to help them transition in an
appropriate way but it makes me a little
bit nervous just you know look up
someone out of the you know blue or even
on a recommendation because it's you
know dealing with 65 and 67 year olds is
maybe different than I would experiment
on myself or surely the 20 year old
version of myself would have done feel
that people that are doing this work
like bravely at risk of incarceration
are really important to what we're doing
and you know it started you know before
I was illegal in the 70s there were
these therapists and these frameworks
and then when it got made illegal a lot
of these therapists kept working in
different contexts and they've kind of
maintained this protocol and modality
and way of doing therapy and you know
we're very careful and art you know our
work is all very separate because we
have to be used to do this FDA research
but we're definitely I'm really grateful
to work at maps because we're not one to
be like we're nothing like that you know
we're like really appreciate the work
that they're doing and right now we
can't give access to people the way we
want to and so if people can get
something that's gonna literally save
their life or make their ease their
transition like we're you know I think
that's wonderful and there's also a lot
happening legally outside of the US so
that's something really worth
investigating and then there's like
ketamine that's legal in the US so
there's really lots of levels but you
know I know I recently moved to LA and
there's definitely lots of communities
around here and I think that's really
for me like that's really important
because that's part of what's giving
people access and experience and
learning about how these laws are messed
up and also mcc's perience Healing
changes that hopefully are going to
impact our whole world and and I think
that we have to just I guess are focused
I'll just end with this as talking about
reducing harms right so we're know this
stuff is happening whether or not we
like it so we really believe in making
sure people have as much and for
as possible to do it as safely as
possible so like maps puts all of our
protocols are for how we do our study is
online we make everything really
available so that people can learn and
read up and do these things with
intention because it does really matter
how you do it but you know we don't
think we can control everything and I
wouldn't I would add that they it's it's
a it's a tricky time right now because
this is getting more attention there are
many more people jumping into this field
with maybe not the best training or the
best container or and when you the
people that are working in the
underground don't have supervision they
don't have people that they're figuring
out if they're doing their best work so
a peer review you know it's it's a
tricky you know a space and so yeah it's
it's you know it is the Wild West so
I'll do a little bit of a shameless plug
but we've been talking about this at the
aware project a lot and we recently put
together a multi-part guide that we're
helping people make good choices when
they start if they go down that road and
are looking for someone to work with in
the underground because from a harm
reduction approach we need to make sure
that people are asking the right
questions of themselves making sure
they're asking the right questions to
the people they may be sitting with and
also making sure that those people are
asking you the right questions so that
they're they're not giving you anything
that that could harm you so we have a
really extensive guide on our on our
site so I recommend checking that out
yeah and then the integration our
integration program Maps has its own
integration program where they've have
people from all over the the world of
the u.s. that
that offer psychedelic integration
support but it's not underground therapy
it's just integration Innerspace
integration and we also do the same to
help people prepare for an experience
and then also integration afterwards so
you can get really good advice from
people there on how to kind of figure
out how to navigate those kinds of
questions but obviously not to help you
find them because some people might take
psychedelics on their own and then come
to this therapist that can help them
kind of integrate and make sense of it
or some people might have had a bad
signal experience and need a therapist
that understands but it's just a list
that Maps has on our website of
therapists throughout the country in the
world that are kind of familiar with
these states and experiences so they can
like support you through that I guess
I'll also say because I definitely was
forgot about the caution which is really
important okay we're all up here there's
also unfortunately a lot of instances of
sexual assault and like ayahuasca
communities and it's like where people
who you know call themselves shamans or
sleeping with people in ceremony and
telling them are the employees and that
can be deeply traumatic especially when
people are healing their sexual traumas
and there's just so there is a lot but
it's you know things are illegal and
unregulated then there's a lot of
dangerous we had someone in the
underground ayahuasca community recently
arrested and put in jail for sexual
assault during an ayahuasca ceremony so
it happens up here too yeah there's
there's so many
yes it's an underground movement and
it's a critical time and yet there's
hundreds of Facebook groups that are all
being monitored by the government there
of every practitioner of this
underground working it's signal or
telegram or hidden messengers there's
really no place safe to find out how to
access a therapist yet there's a hundred
million people doing different forms of
MDMA without any guidance and who did
not understand the difference between
ceremonial medicinal and recreational it
seems to me that
can start to transform the way people
think about MDMA or Molly or ecstasy on
mass that is possible we can bring this
revolution transformation faster so
what's possible from a communication
medium to allow this information to
propagate and to find the right
practitioner and to make it safe for
people to jump in the water and truly
start healing I mean until we have a
legal process I mean until is legalized
I mean there's not going to be a wait
for people to do that safely for the
practitioner I mean so I mean there are
people that put themselves out there
quite boldly in what they do and I think
a little too recklessly but you know
that the practitioners need to be
responsible too because if they're not
watching their practice that could
really jeopardize what we're trying to
do in the above-ground work so I mean if
people want this to become a medicine we
need to support the legalization
movements because this is and and to
realize that this is a slow this is a
slow I mean we're getting to a point
where we're getting some faster turning
points but you know this is a long game
and and and so I mean I don't know how I
mean the best we can do right now is
help people find harm you know teach
them about harm reduction from a legal
you know from above-ground way but
underground communities and and people
that are participating in those kinds of
communities need to watch out for one
another and when they do bring people
into their communities to do it in a
responsible way so that there's sort of
a buddy system and and that you're and
that you're supporting people in their
integration process so you know they're
the and they're more and more the
underground communities are connecting
more and more so that they can watch out
for their own
yeah so there's there's a lot of good
recommendations for those and and more
the more people get connected especially
you know people through a net
psychedelic societies just talking about
to each other about you know smart ways
of going about these things I think is
helping a lot you know like these
problems also come up in the
above-ground world you know there are
people who violate their role in
relationships and but the difference is
that there is a system for qualifying
those people there's a system for
reprimanding those people taking away
that right to play that role anymore so
yeah I mean if the underground can
create a similar sort of board
certification process or in my opinion
we we bring these modalities into the
system that has those kinds of checks
and balances and reporting systems and
that's how we reach the most people
because a lot of people aren't doing a
lot of people who need this help don't
live in Venice California you know they
live in like an Idaho and the Midwest
and wouldn't think about going to
somebody underground you know would be
able to find some ayahuasca circles are
spreading out everywhere don't discount
the Midwest all right any last words
because we got to wrap it up I would add
that these underground practitioners
need to self-regulate because we're in
an era of very tolerant enforcement and
they don't want to bring down the heat
on everybody and ruin it for everybody
and so if you're an underground
practitioner and you see somebody who is
in that same space and it's not being
ethical and it's not following the best
you know practices I think it's
incumbent upon you
as a matter of enlightened self-interest
to set our person aside and to you know
really encourage best practices so that
you can self-regulate as opposed to
being regulated from without agree and
on that can we all thank our speakers
for that marathon session psychedelics
pathway to legalization
[Music]