eka Aloha Aloha Mahalo good evening
everyone welcome I hope you've had a
wonderful evening it's kind of a capper
to the weekend right now and it's been
so many amazing faces so many beautiful
experiences it's nice to link up in
person and we're really excited to bring
to you regenerative hemp tonight and
talk to you about how hemp can save the
world not only through medicine but
through intentional cultivation and we
have three wonderful people up here that
are going to share their experience and
their intentions on their farm and
beyond yeah go ahead Dave Sullivan well
thanks for sticking around guys and
listen to his talk and thanks Josh and
Kelly for inviting us to be on this
panel
my name is Dave Sullivan and thank you
guys for sticking around my name is Dave
Sullivan I own sweet leaf organic farm
which is a certified organic farm along
with the plant which is a recreational
marijuana farm we're located in outside
of Eugene Oregon in the farming
community of Junction City and we manage
about a hundred acres of ground that
includes forests woodlands riparian
zones wetlands and a heck of a lot of
class one farm soil we generally have
about twenty to thirty acres in
production annually and we employ 18
people year-round including five
families and over the years we've
developed a style of farming that
incorporates cannabis into its long term
fertility programs soil building program
and crop rotation program and we've had
a lot of success having that be one of
our key crops intermingled amongst our
other fruit and vegetable crops thanks
I wanted echo I wanted to echo my thanks
for everyone who stuck around oh it's
been a long weekend and it's nice to see
everybody here my name is Matt Davenport
I'm the founder and CEO of arlo systems
I also own a company called cliffside
hemp Supply were supply chain management
logistics company that supports domestic
and international markets at this point
I'm a permaculture designer I've spent
my time and career applying permaculture
designed to cannabis cultivation my
passions really just evolved into
working how I can to scale endure and
full Sun operations really so my work in
the hemp I was a certified hemp farmer
in 2016-2017 out of Colorado and ran
that farm for a year went to scale we
had to pull out of the drought back I
think is 2017 2018 we had a really bad
drought in Colorado and I was yeah it
just caused a lot of farmers to pull out
some not to be very successful as a
result of that so finding a problem out
of that solution I built that supply
chain management company I referred to
and we've been just working with farmers
to help them solve problems in the
movement of their hem one way or another
from biomass flower post or find goods
seeds and really helping educate farmers
who are both you know conventional
farmers shifting crops conventional
farmers just looking at shift organic
and then working with organic farmers
looking to shift beyond to regenerative
agricultural practices so thanks again
for being here hey everybody I'm Daniel
Richardson co-owner and CEO of Lane
Creek em company
we're in Jackson County Oregon and we
got a 40 acre spread down there and
we're growing an acre of hemp in like a
two acre cultivation zone growing it in
Hyuga berms and you
a very intensive perennial eyes system
no store-bought nutrients whatsoever
we're managing you know like nine cows a
bunch of sheep a bunch of a bunch of
livestock and rotating them around and
just trying to work work with the land
and create nutrient basis in that way
and yeah it's been a really really
exciting project and just getting into
the into the roots of of the land and
and what you know what land Stewart can
really do on a piece of property with
the right ingredients with great Sun
great water great soil and animals and
humans like how that symbiotic
relationship happens and yeah just
trying to do our best in this tumultuous
hemp scape which has been a really
really interesting project and super
excited to see where it goes but yeah
just trying to you know lead by example
and just ensure that we're building top
soil and that we're keeping fish happy
and we're keeping wildlife happy and
we're just trying not to grow fence
defense and understanding that you know
then the network of fertility is so you
know it kind of circles around us as the
land steward as the human but you know
you have to you know this whole
regenerative model is different for
everybody and you know it's just like
it's this mindset of you know you have
to compromise some profit and you have
to compromise some of your needs to you
know to to allow your land to thrive and
just trying to create you know nucleuses
of of fertility and you know linking
them up and you know that's where you
know systemic fertility really comes
from so we're just trying to you know
like I didn't grow up doing this I was a
heavy civil construction background and
got into the farming world
so now I'm going down this path and it's
just it's a it's a great canvas to work
with for the first time probably in over
two hundred years North America seeing a
huge increase of young farmers young
farmers are very interested in buying
land they want to know how to farm it in
a way that's responsible because hemp
and cannabis has got their attention and
this is really exciting and I believe
that we have this wonderful opportunity
to give you know to hire and and and
give alternatives and be more creative
two big AG and while this plant is an
incredible regenerator it is a
remediated can feed the world it can
give fiber to us and give us medicine
there is still as this hemp industry
ramped up there is a lot of people doing
it's still big AG style and there's some
real problems and I wanted to talk a bit
about those and and go through and you
all tell me about the solutions that you
have for them and one that we're seeing
is thousands of acres underneath plastic
mulching is what they call it which is
basically planting the plants and
putting layers of plastic over thousands
of acres and that's not going to
regenerate the land or the waterways at
all it's a horrible environmental
disaster so it's our responsibility as
regenerative hemp farmer's to change
that reality and get the education out
so I'd love to hear from you all about
some really good solutions to that well
that'd be that being said for us I feel
like a lot of people in this room that
probably have experience or have
dedicated their lives to ganja what it
was like for me you know as a teenager
and learning how to grow crops and
learning how to
we'd looking to like people that were
older for us to have success we were
told you couldn't get chunky killer
yields of sticky buds without using
bottle synthetic nutrients or once you
have spider mites the only way you're
gonna get rid of him was avid or
FloorMate or whatever other toxic
bullshit
was being pushed on people so that being
said not one to to go down that road we
would have our pen and paper and
listening to our elders who were able to
pull off killer ganja without using any
of those inputs so I'm seeing the same
thing happening in with plastic right
now where people are being told that the
plants won't size up in time or you
won't be able to manage weeds or water
retention whatever the reason is and I
can tell you from experience and with
lots of crops over the years that the
Willamette Valley is not an ideal
climate to grow cannabis you have to you
have to be on it and there's a lot of
nuances that that are the difference
between make and break and you do not
need plastic mulch to go killer high
quality cannabis hemp CBD any of it so
we have found a really good alternative
I'll just kind of nuts-and-bolts our
style we I think that to start off in
any industry especially farming
especially cannabis starting small is
key learn your plants learn your crew
learn your land get it all work together
there's no rush
anytime I jump ahead and try to grow two
acres at onions versus one I get
tennis-ball onions instead of softball
sized onions it's the same exact thing
for cannabis that being said I think one
person with a strong back and a strong
will with a green thumb
can manage about an acre is the
threshold hands-on especially when it
comes to weeds which while on the topic
of plastic mulch we're a bit bigger than
that we did about twelve and a half
acres of high CBD this year in one two
quarter acre to half acre two-acre plot
Saul kind of scattered around our
chessboard overall
our properties and just nuts and bolts
how we got it done some of it was direct
seeded some of it was transplanted then
after the first round of weeds come up
when the plants are established we come
through with hoes wheel hoes hand weeds
secondary first of us we're slightly
mechanized so the old-school tractors
like the allis-chalmers G's and the farm
all cups these things were built to last
forever and then multiple functions but
will come down and literally drive on
our tractor and knock down the weeds in
row with basket leaders we come by a
second time with the finger weeders
which will smother the in row weeds and
then our crew just comes through pans
and hoes like the ground troops knocking
back with the with the tractors couldn't
knock down then if we could we can time
and right and and and timely cultivation
is key in any farming operation the
second round we can get away with no
hand weeding and just have our finger
leaders just smother the in row weeds
and then we follow that up with a
combination of cover crops
ideally grass a rye grass or an annual
grass and we we're really digging a New
Zealand white clover for ganja in
particular the reason I like the white
clover is that it grows really short so
it doesn't kind of choke your understory
canopy and also it is more drought
tolerant so we water it in overhead and
once it's established it can take foot
traffic
so in our Isles we can walk all over it
and it won't we won't smother it and it
can take less irrigation and it'll still
thrive
then we find if you can get that clover
not turned until the following like late
spring early summer when after its
flowered the amount of nitrogen boost
you get from flowered New Zealand clover
is choked you can't even believe how
much it builds up your soil so those are
all alternatives not only are we
creating an environment for beneficial
insects and habitat and choking out all
the competing weed species but we're
also creating a natural living mulch
that's an alternative to plastic mulch
and in my
my experience I think gives you a much
superior end product and we're building
soil exactly and and one more thought
the grass come combined with the clover
the reason for that clover is a lot
slower to germinate and a lot of times
your next round of weeds will just choke
it out where your grasses can kind of
come up immediately and choke out all
the invasive weed species that were
already there and all your broadleaf
grasses grasses and weeds and then after
that's established you mow that back and
your clover comes through and then by
this time of year all you see is fields
of clover thank you
thank you Matt appreciate that so I
think to to address the plastic mulch
thing you know we really just have to
ask ourselves what problems are farmers
having with you know the approach to
setting up farms and and most of the
time what I found you know I work
directly with and oversee probably about
13 14 farms all over the country and a
lot of them are art and and this is by
nature of just the the demand for the
market hopping into the season in the
spring they're they're seeing the
dollars they're seeing the green rush
they're seeing the need to just get to
heart get to market gets market get
plants in the ground and they're they're
ultimately missing the boat on the
reality that to go towards for example
an organic no-till methodology which is
a great solution for you know broad
scale hemp cultivation that's on
relatively flat land they're they're
missing the boat on planting those cover
crops in the fall so really one of the
best advices that I have the people that
are looking to get into farming or
looking to really get into this large
scale organic no-till thing with with
regeneration as as sort of the long
long-term end goal it's really to start
your design work you know June August
September of the year before work with
with land where you're able to
to have fallow fields where you're able
to to leave places for plants to
continuously occupy the ground because
you know at the end of the day the the
big take away with cover crops is that
you really want to treat them is is with
as much love as you do you know the the
crops that generate your your your sort
of primary source of income again if we
look through the lens of permaculture
and you know different sustainable and
regenerative methodologies simply you
know sourcing your livelihood off of one
plant one stream of revenue and on a you
know sort of financial monoculture begs
the question of you know whether that's
holistic in and of itself so assuming
you know we have the ability to do the
right kind of design work the foresight
to be able to start designing the year
before you know the concept and and it's
going to vary from region to region but
the the general concept is you're
planting a hairy vetch awry somewhere
depending on your zone from is as early
as end of Aqaba end of august to
generally you know no later than October
15th you're planting a type of cover
crops that are that are really going to
grow up over winter and then you know in
the fall or in the spring you're going
to use certain implements that are
designed that have been designed by the
Rodale Institute and if anybody really
wants to go deep into organic no-tell it
suggests you really studying the the
work that the Rodale Institute has put
out there they have free designs for
what are called roller crimpers which
are the basis for how to actually create
long-term mulch for these organic
no-till systems which again technically
speaking they're not no-till right so
most no-till farmers are doing single
passes at the beginning of the year you
know and then they're doing another pass
to harvest at the at the end of the year
so as you as you sort of look at the
season on the cycle you're planting your
cover crops in the fall you're buying or
you're buying or you're making what's
called a roller crimper which
you know is there is the idea of taking
you know a rye grasses and with this
really a big metal cylindrical tool
excuse me a cylindrical tool with what
they call a chevron pattern you're able
to actually roll this this thing
typically you put it on the front of the
tractor and this is in the spring so
again I'm trying to keep the cycle going
but you plant it in the fall in the
spring you plan on rolling and crimping
your crop so you put this roller crimper
on the front of the tractor and then on
the usually you have to do two passes
usually you'll plant four generally
speaking a winter rye and then a hairy
vetch the first pass the the Rye will go
down and then generally speaking
sometimes the hairy vetch will pop back
up say if they do another pass with the
roller crimper and on the back of the
tractor is where your you're planting
implements are planted so the idea is
that the roller crimper rolls the the
res whats called residue to the ground
and then on the back of the tractor
they're basically disc cutters that
split the residue spread it apart spread
it apart just enough for you to be able
to get a cutting or seed start in there
and then behind the tractor on that same
implement you're running behind and
planting accordingly so I think the
that's one solution for broad scale
agriculture you're able to certainly
reduce your passes and when it comes
down to it if you have the ability to do
the foresight and design should
eliminate at scale plastic mulch also
the big takeaway for organic no-till is
most of it isn't necessarily organic so
you got to make sure that you're
following a biological pathway to it a
lot of organic no-till farmers are still
spraying or organic or no-till farms or
spring glyphosate sd4 and all sorts of
chemicals herbicides on there thank you
that's awesome
and Daniel can you maybe add maybe
weight kind of
foods you might be able to plant within
your you know a part of your system yeah
absolutely you know in any fertile
environment there's going to be a lot of
growth and in you know in our like firm
no-till environment we're you know come
grass season it's just unbelievable what
happens in those Hyuga berms I mean we
got chest-deep grass by 420 and you know
trying to to deal with all that and like
you know you're you're looking at this
you know this gardenscape that you're
approaching to plant your your annual
into and it is just fully thick with
with annual grasses and perennials but
that's a great thing you know you just
have to manage those properly and so we
do a lot of like just stepping on the
grass and just like getting what was
that word you use the well the residue
the residue thank you that's I didn't
know that one yeah making the residue
and you know so you're prioritizing you
know you're pulling up annuals and
you're chopping dropping all of your
perennials to just create space for for
your annual but we have a ton of
potatoes and onions and garlic in our
system because everything's got to eat
we have a lot of rodents we have a lot
of you know moles and voles and all of
these things and everything everything
needs to eat so we found that potatoes
in with with the hemp has been a
lifesaver they come up and they create
this this great canopy loving potato
what's that
we love potatoes oh my god they're just
delicious too
it's like they're everywhere it's like
Lou I'll take some of that onions
everywhere so it it's a it's a fabulous
way to to just you know think about it
you know mulch for us is is
yeah his is grass and is material that's
grown ideally right right in place we do
import a lot of rice straw and wood
chips we run a lot of wood chips and
just to squelch those springtime grasses
to like create space to plug your your
annuals in and as the summer extends
then you know those annuals are I'm
sorry those those grasses you know
become less prevalent but and in the
spring you know you got a you've got to
do your due diligence to get those to
get those grasses down I love it and
you're able to use fungi and garden
giant says to eat those grasses and that
creates a filter so all the water that's
coming over the ground is filtered
through that system and so you're a
positive impact on the environment David
you have a something you want to add to
that yeah our approach unlike a
production foods farm is we initially in
cannabis days or medical days we would
are you first year we would do cannabis
in a greenhouse and follow up the second
year and one thing that about cannabis
versus a lot of other crops it's it's a
really it's a heavier feeding crop so
it's kind of once it gets rolling as
most of you guys know what kind of gets
that feed me Seymour vibe you can throw
everything at and it's gonna love it up
that being said whether your whatever
your agricultural practices are if
you're building your own fertility and
having your own animals for manure and
doing green manures and composting or
you're bringing in amendments and inputs
ideally regionally if not locally for
ganja and cannabis and hemp it's all the
same plan obviously we're really
throwing everything we have at it so
then year three and year four where we
initially had those things planting
other food crops we finally get really
high yields really bountiful crops that
are super healthy with zero additional
inputs so it's a rich you know Kelly
talking about a lot of young folks just
getting into farming
for the first time and cannabis bringing
them in the farm it's a really good
first year crop and as most people know
here you know the whole philosophy
behind crop rotations is the different
different families of crops have
different disease pressures different
pest pressures and uptake different
nutrients from the soil so the mono
cropping system where as far as you can
see having a crop growing year after
year the same crop an inch eventually
those depletions are going to lead to
imbalances and that's where the heavy
artillery of fungicides and fumigants
and insecticides come into play but
smaller scale so as much diversity as
you can and just having this giant
chessboard where you're playing a shell
game with the pests and diseases
cannabis is a really good first-year
crop to segue into other food production
and we've had a lot of success with it
that was kind of my lord to get into
hemp to begin with and seeing that we
could have kind of bigger tracts for
bigger other tracks down the road and
kind of have bigger squares on our
chessboard if you will and also one
thing I wanted to add is that with
plastic mulching we're really looking at
mono culturing like you all we're
talking about in poly culture is
incredibly important right now as we're
looking at the hemp aphid anybody who's
growing hemp or anybody who's growing
cannabis is starting if you if you
haven't had this pest in your garden you
will it's coming for you it's here it's
here to stay it's incredibly healthy and
and our cannabis populations are feeding
them we need to be very vigilant and
taking care of them and one way that we
can do that and it really is the only
way to do that is through polyculture is
inviting in massive amounts of predators
to take care of those aphids they're
really delicious they're soft they're
sweet they taste like cannabis if
they're sucking our cannabis plants
they're super nutria t'v and there's a
massive amount of predator bugs that
live on all of our pollinator plants
that love to eat them up so and I wanted
to move right into a big question about
hemp right now and regenerative hemp
which seems to be the really hot topic
is scaling you know there's this
conversation
no you can only scale this many acres
and be regenerate over you can only
scale this many acres or what do you all
feel about what's scalable in your eyes
for regenerative hemp I would say you
know ultimately if you can have
everything coming off your farm I mean
that would be the ideal situation where
a portion of your farm was wild a
portion of your farm made hay a portion
of your farm had weeds and grew
you know nutrients for any teas you
might need or different mulches or maybe
it's flowers for the pollinators and in
my perfect scaled world the farm is part
of an intact environment where there's
trees around there's birds flying
through you know there's flowers
happening and in that the hemp is
thriving and it's filtering the soil and
I think that can be done you know to put
a number on it who knows you know 10 to
20 acres or anything I there are some
really good examples out there of you
know seven hundred and thousand acre
plots where they're you know doing
roller crimping stuff and and I think
that can be really beneficial I think I
think anyone is trying to who's enabling
the environment to thrive while they're
creating medicine you know that's gonna
be beneficial but I think in large-scale
production we should probably do rows of
flowers through it you know we should
figure out ways to do like one row of
hemp and maybe berries through you know
or some you know just alternate your
crops throughout the thing because that
diversity really is gonna help you with
the hemp aphids so that's what I'm
thinking at the moment well for me I
feel like it has a lot to do with your
your location you know for example the
amount of tomatoes you can grow in in
Quebec is not going to be the same
amount that you can grow in Southern
California the eastern shelf of Colorado
this
is a lot more appropriate for scale but
I also think that you know the economy
of scale has everything to do with your
experience and the crew that you're
working with so you know if you have a
dream team crew of experienced people
that working together for a long time
and you're appropriately
you know small-scale mechanized I think
the sky can kind of be the limit as long
as you're saying principals don't get
compromised
the larger you get in size and I think
one really good thing that kind of tying
the the what is regenerative when it
comes to scale and what you were saying
about the the planning ahead and the
season ahead I think a good mantra for
any business and especially in farming
especially in cannabis farming one thing
that I like to think of is the the seven
P's if you haven't heard of this the
seven P's is prior the proper planning
and preparation prevent piss-poor
performance so if you can have your
seven P's in line with your principles I
am of the opinion that the sky's the
limit because really in shifting the
paradigm for a utopia with a lot of
little micro farms every they're over
there and then the people that have the
biggest impact that are that are taking
the most acreage up you know even if
it's a watered-down USDA version of
organic first of what we think is
organic these big players that's that
many less millions of barrels of shit
that they're putting in our environment
waterways every year so the balance of
us finding new solutions without
alienating the bigger growers is is part
of the work we have to do they might be
yeah I think that that's a great point I
was just speaking to a colleague and
just to convert our our ability to
convert farmers from heavily chemical
glyphosate ridden parcels to you know
more conscious cultivation simply by
shifting one crop in their in their
lives you'd be surprised at how quickly
a corn farm Oh will will grow will shift
their crops grow
without pesticides simply because you
know they're seeing the market value of
this crop so I think the conversion rate
is super-important I mean we're talking
two hundred and eighty five thousand
acres that were licensed this year up
from seventy eight thousand last year
you know and so when we start talking
about regeneration we need to start
really talking about carbon
sequestration and the lack thereof in
the way that we're farming this
reductionist style cannabinoid paradigm
which is not the way our forefathers and
and and our ancestors thought about that
you know when we're talking about
asexual propagation feminization however
it's done I think no matter what we're
we're playing God in a certain way and
when we start to create these single
lines of revenue that alone
I think begs the question of of really
how can we get to the endpoints that are
on both and that are on both sides of me
here I think regeneration is a process I
think we have so many lifetimes of work
to do that if we ever get satisfied or
comfortable with how regenerative we are
I think we're fucked and I think the
reality is that we need to keep pushing
the edge keep pushing ourselves forward
and modeling people like this to to look
to examples and solutions scale is the
name of the game right now we can't keep
up with the the good intentions and and
the conscious farming we can't keep up
with the scale at which people are
tilling I mean I'm talking 13 passes a
year imagine 13 path plus right I mean
unconventional farms it's it's to a
point where the to keep it simple I
think we just have to you know ask
ourselves how much carbon are we were
really sequestering period and then go
from there start reverse engineering it
but perennial eyes systems true
industrial hemp for fiber food fuel oil
you know that's that's I think what's
gonna really push everyone to a more
regenerative twenty-five thousand uses
for this plant which is not what we're
doing right now so no well said none
scales of a really tricky one it depends
on your end goal and
you know like they've said your location
super important I watched a balloon
absolutely deflate around us in Southern
Oregon it was it was hard to watch
[Music]
you know scale is a super tricky one
if you know if the sky is the limit that
that's great but you know you know we
need to really step back and like
understand what our needs are from this
plant and utilize its potential but you
know it has so much great potential hemp
has this unbelievable ability to and you
know if we're gonna grow it in the
Emerald triangle and we're gonna service
you know a huge portion of the world
then it could be really intensive on on
our watersheds in our topsoil and if
we're if we're if we're growing an
annual on plastic mulch and we're not
remineralizing the soil in a proper
manner it's gonna be bad you know so we
have to we have to really think about
what we're doing here and you know the
beautiful thing about like Kelly said
you know all these young people are not
necessarily young but just we have a new
seed we have a new ability to to take a
great we have a great opportunity in
front of us and it's like where are we
gonna go with it like literally where
are we going with it we have a chance to
be very cognizant of our impacts or we
could just be profit mongers and just
keep planting way more than we have any
idea what we're gonna do with it and you
know that's not necessarily that's what
happened but there was portions of that
that happened and people really got
humbled this year and I hope that we all
just can be transparent with each other
and communicate and be honest with what
our scale really needs to be it's it's
important if if you don't have anywhere
to put it probably shouldn't grow it so
I mean it's just it's it's kind of
common-sense stuff but it's very
exciting to get into it it's very
exciting to get into it it's a it's a
great opportunity but like and just
because you're neighbors running mulch
doesn't mean you have to
so let's communicate and and let's just
be honest with you know you know what
what we need from this plant and it's
it's definitely a balance and we're
teetering so we need to we need to be
careful yeah and I think it's really
interesting that you know we don't have
an idea of what successful scaling is
because anything in our recent history
has not shown successful scale you know
big agriculture the way that it is right
now is not successfully scaling anything
the food is beginning depleted our
waterways you know all the things that
we know about and the other thing that I
was thinking is that as far as scaling
goes I really like the idea of many
farmers big land you know one farmer you
know 15 25 acres and a whole lot of
collective people working together and
and this is a model that I think could
really keep intact integrative systems
that are you know more diverse with
nature on the next question that I
wanted to ask you well we really don't
have a lot of time and this is such a
hot topic that I feel like it actually
could be another hour to two hours which
is seed feminization and now hemp has
forced us to look at you know when we
talk about scale feminizing seeds and
there's people feel a lot of different
ways about it so I thought I wanted to
bring it up to you all we don't have
much time and maybe we could give some
food for thought or even ask a question
if we don't have answers to this what I
know about it is that silver Theo
sulfate is one of the common compounds
used to make feminized seeds and it is a
talk
a compound and if overused can get into
the waterways and and I think that in
our farming what we do with the pure
certification and all the farms that we
work with is we just don't want to
support through our actions any use of
any harmful compounds and so if that's
gonna be a harmful compound we don't
want to use it
feminization really isn't a regenerative
practice because it's feminized you know
it's not something you can breed with to
move forward so that part right there
you know genetically may not be the best
thing but efficiency wise you know in a
field setting I think feminization can
make a lot of sense it is a way of
stabilizing genetics for medicine which
is ultimately going out to the
betterment of people and that's really
important to us with the Dragonfly
arthritis and pure certification we had
an amazing gathering at the heartwood
sanctuary this last weekend
and we are working on putting together
some guidelines on what we think is
regenerative for hemp and feminized seed
as part of it and one of the things we
talked about was if we did use feminized
seed on our land that maybe we still
kept a portion of our land for regular
seed breeding and that regular seed
breeding and having you know the ability
to breed is really really isn't you know
important for our future and with the
laws changing which is a whole other
hour and another subject with you know
what how do we even plan for hemp in the
future when we don't know what the
government's gonna do in another six
months that's kind of ridiculous and and
also there's a ratio of CBD and THC that
went with these new laws changes
everything but um seeds is really
important to consider and just we've
come up you know with the concept of the
seven we didn't come up with the concept
but we resonate with the concept of
seven generations so you know if you're
gonna use feminized seeds you should
maybe offset at some some other way well
I think see breeding in general is a hot
topic because on the ganja scene if it
doesn't fill up the whole room when you
crack the jar and test over 25 percent
you toss it
so we're quickly becoming like the Amish
with our whole gene pool
so it's gonna be a slippery slope with
in the hip game as well but at the same
time we're hemp's in its infant stage
and any farmer or any business you know
getting on the board and just even the
very basics of making ends meet and
being able to continue to do what you're
doing
as your systems improve then you then
it's every farmer or every person's
responsibility to keep paring it down
and keep getting better at it with less
inputs so I think it's too early the
jury's still out on the feminized
hempseed game and I think that as this
as the industry evolves and breeding
evolves because cannabis and al-khansa
cannabis hemp it's all in its infant
stage as far as stable F ones across the
board so as it unfolds we'll learn but I
think it's too early to say you can do
this and you can't do that because it's
it's hard enough to just get out on the
field as it is right now I think I think
that make that's a great point quick
flash back I mean feminized seeds in
general in the hemp industry are a
relatively new thing and I think the the
reality is we've seen it as as one of
the unique tools to scale and I think if
we start looking at the way for personal
heroes of mine such as Mark shepherd
Eric tones Myer Darren Daugherty I think
if we ask them if feminized seeds are
good beef could fit into regenerative
agriculture I mean I venture to say they
probably would just start laughing and
so I think in general is feminization
something that we find in nature I can't
exactly point to a place you know in
terms of ethylene blockers that are used
to achieve feminization they're about
eleven known ethylene blockers the one
that Josh was talking about at the MSDS
is 24,000 milliliters per liter for it
to be quote-unquote toxic to invite
so I think the levels to which people
are applying these these compounds to me
a second whether they're using them or
not using feminization as sort of a
leverage point to regeneration or you
know if they're able to do things
without feminization so for me if I can
grow crops without that kind of
technology that's my preference I think
for farmers that you know have a desire
a need and ability to scale it's been
it's been really the solution for
acreage 10 20 40 acres and above so I
hope to see feminization become a safer
process but I think anything anything to
keep CRISPR tech sir tech any any of
these genetic editing and genetic
modifying technologies out of these gene
pools is to me first and foremost I
think that's it's a big deal so thank
you a great point yeah there's something
systemically uncomfortable for me about
the fact that I save seed from every
other thing on my farm but every year we
we have to buy new hemp seed so but it's
just the climate that we're in and you
know where it's brand-new we're all
moving forward and we have great
momentum in an awesome direction so at
this point there's something
uncomfortable about that portion of it
for me but I know that we have so many
good minds and so many good hearts
putting energy in in really good
directions that I'm confident that
there's a future for us growing hemp
it's I'm trying to make it like
one-sixth of what I think about and I'm
trying to diversify my farm and
diversify my my financial landscape
because it could just go like that and
then all of a sudden it's it's no longer
not necessarily viable but just hard to
prioritize so
I'm excited that we're all pooling
together and we just we need to continue
to unify and and and use our resources
and and just keep moving in the right
direction thank you and I would add
ultimately you know using male and
female regular seeds is is the ultimate
goal and there are field test kits that
farmers can get and it does make sense
you to start you know all your male and
female you know regular seeds and then
sex test all of them and do and then in
that you can do a mega phyno hunt and
and really in hemp has shown us CBD is
the talk right now but CBG has been
grown this year and maybe it's CBD V
next year and THC V that the hemp has
the ability to harbor cannabinoids and
then that you know brings on the subject
of hemp as industrial hemp or hemp as
cannabinoid him and that's a further
discussion another our discussion but
you know cannabinoid hemp is what we're
really interested in because of the
medicinal qualities in it but we really
also need to really promote an embrace
fiber hemp and seed hemp and hemp seed
as a food is a phenomenal thing and
being able to create hempcrete and
plastics and even biofuels from hemp is
something that is extremely important to
us and i really have an issue with
clear-cutting and logging in the
mindless devastation of the forest when
we can grow hemp for fiber to replace
cellulose on the market i
I want to go crazy over certain things
you know and that's one of them so I you
know let's let's figure out ways to have
hemp farming work together you know I
don't think that fiber and an industrial
hemp needs to be grown maybe in the same
place as that medicinal hemp has grown
and as a community maybe we can create
maps for that so is there any questions
in the audience that we had I know we
don't have time
is there any other quick questions
anyone had really quickly elevation
resulting without us use subsurface trip
what do you guys know of that use can
you repeat the subsurface drip systems
for him which would help believe you
yeah I'm relatively familiar and it
doesn't work I mean yeah I got a friend
in Greeley Colorado that did 68 on 68
acres I think there were seven zones all
sub irrigation using net afem it's a
company that you know so I mean the
logic that the technology if you can
afford the 3500 bucks an acre whatever
it is to set it up I mean he's seen
incredible success with it allows for
the plant to achieve really the same
successes you know the ideas that they
bury large pipes of sub irrigated piping
under the ground and then the plants can
go down fetch the water through
capillary action it will rise but it
mitigates the weed pressure in a way
because there isn't top-down watering so
for example one of the big problems for
with with pivots is that you're watering
your weeds just as much as you're
watering your your hemp right so if
you're working with sub-irrigation
you're not giving the competitive
advantage that weeds might have if they
were you know if they had access to the
abundant amount of water that said it's
a very mechanized farm certified organic
three people harvest 68 acres so it's
not exactly your model for regeneration
or necessarily that paradigm but yeah
and one of the one other thing of the as
far as on no plastic film
to understand that there's still a lot
of fossil fuel input for cultivation of
an acre and the continued tractor work
it's needed and additional people so the
energetic the energy embedded needs to
be looked at as well not just just you
know we can do away with a lot of stuff
irrigation if we are properly doing
mulching and we're properly doing cover
crops we can really and even even
tractor work all of that can be really
mitigated by you know using more natural
systems and you know we we're gonna have
to wrap it up I really thank you all for
coming out today this is an incredibly
important topic we've barely even
scratched a surface on a multitude of
issues that need to be discussed in hemp
and like Josh was saying earlier this is
cannabis this is you know an important
plant that's here to save the planet
it's here to save communities and I
think that the more that we have these
community discussions and the more that
we work together as communities is the
more that we can bring up the evolution
of this plant and the evolution of our
own species as humans on the planet
thank you all so much for being here
today
[Applause]
thanks guys