[Music]
thanks everyone for being here and
meadowlands for giving us this
opportunity to talk about regenerative
cannabis we have not sitting in order
Jessie who created the regenerative
cannabis farm award with Dan Marr over
here as well as Jacob and Carla from
flower days farm in Trinity County
forest and Patricia from Sun roots farm
in Mendocino County and Josh from moon
gazer farm in Mendocino County so these
all of these amazing farmers can tell
you guys all about regenerative farming
but before we start that I just want to
let everyone know that the reason I'm
here is because I spent years trying to
find the dankest weed that I could smoke
and that search led me to these farmers
and their weed really is the dankest and
when I found out that they grow in a way
that is actually good for the soil and
their watersheds and the bees and the
whole ecosystem I was amazed and
inspired and it's basically the only
thing giving me hope for the future
right now but even if I didn't care
about the environment or my carbon
footprint or the survival of humanity I
would still want to smoke their weed
because the flavors and the effects are
of a spectacular quality and from my
point of view as a pot snob who cares a
lot about quality I believe that the key
to that spectacular dankness is in the
relationships between the farmer and the
plant and the soil so I think so Jesse
should tell us about the regenerative
cannabis farm award on how it recognizes
those connections well traditionally in
like cannabis cups we're celebrating the
flowers we're really excited about
what's the dankest and and I'd and I
agree I think that the dankest practices
lead to the dankest flowers that it is
it's a relationship with the soil with
the land with community the art that you
put into the flower biodiversity healthy
environment that that comes forth that
makes the flower art it makes it
something that
you want to ingest but like how do we
talk about that and so with the Emerald
cup and the cultivation classic we
created this award called the
regenerative cannabis farm award that
recognizes these practices and we
created an application process where we
can have farms tell us about them hear
their story we have a lot of different
specific things that we ask about so we
can know about watershed we can know
about soil practices closed-loop systems
community work and then we get to set up
site visits and go and meet them and
recently this last year's we've been
doing documentaries with with Claire of
la Oso films who's filming right now and
man they've been coming out so beautiful
they connect the audience with the
practices because you can see the
animals you can see the soil you can see
the connection with the land and it's
like that's the cannabis I want to smoke
that's growing from this beautiful soil
in Pali culture so it's been this
amazing journey of the last few years
and one of the coolest parts is you get
to meet really amazing friends along the
way and you get to learn a lot and then
you get to feature the best farms and
then now this conversation is out there
about the practices how is cannabis
grown how can we do it better for our
environment how can we do it better for
our watersheds and our communities and
and also grow the best cannabis and
reduce our costs at the same time and
come together as a community of sharing
information so we have some amazing
farmers here that have that represent
the last two years three years oh yeah
that's true yeah sorry three years yeah
yeah the original here two guys are here
too so the very first year all three
years are represented so that's amazing
um the very first year we had dragonfly
Earth Medicine GreenSource gardens and
moon gazer farms and it's it's been
amazing to see how how you know putting
having them come up on state you know
take that award having people connect
with that and seeing the journey of
that's come from there and the
information as Josh and
have been doing amazing work
consistently building their land every
year there's improvement there's more
closed-loop systems there's and with so
much food and polyculture and now
there's twins two little baby boy twins
but it's yeah it's it's amazing place of
life and amazing cannabis and genetics
and it's it's a it's a place of art and
and I really appreciate how much that
you've taken on connecting with the
community being at events like this to
continue talking about these practices
and you know it's like we all have these
abilities to do these things we can
build soil we can build polyculture and
we can grow better cannabis as we do it
and the more we talk about it the more
we empower each other the more we show
each other practices there's not like
one way to do something the best it's
each different environment and each
different you find what works for you
and it's it's a it's a collaborative
effort but yeah let's let's hear a
little bit about what's going on your
farm thank you
I'm Josh from moon gazer farms yeah I
mean it's been a it's been a wild
journey since 2016 I mean we we had just
actually landed at this property so we
had just started building our Google
culture beds then and just seeing how
much life is coming through in these
beds and and and all the worms and and
activity I mean we have just you know
the worms are now just kind of going
even into like the forest and they're
helping to even just break down like
things in the woods like even faster and
stuff - I mean you've create a sanctuary
on your land that is you know is is a
haven for for up for life you know and
and bees and and we're able to do that
as small cannabis farmers and if we are
able to do it then why shouldn't we do
it it's kind of how I feel and and you
know if I and as and as a cannabis
consumer myself
I prefer why wouldn't I prefer to have
well I prefer to have something that's
grown in the soil in this full Sun of
course sangra Sun grown in general is
better than even an even endure of
course but for me personally I would
like to see it in the full Sun this is
where we talk about full spectrum if
we're talking about the highest quality
product I want it to be planted in the
spring and I want to be harvested in
this in the in the fall and we have and
it's and it's going through the entire
cycles of nature you know and when we're
talking about like the moon cycles and
the cosmic cycles this is this is part
of just a natural rhythm right now it's
spring everything's green outside and
yeah so that's kind of how we're how
we're approaching approaching it and
we're just blessed that we're able to
grow from seed we don't have the
pressure of having to do a lot of Konoe
I understand people have to grow from
clones that come from who knows where
and you need to have a consistent
product for the market I get that but
you know we've been able to figure it
out to be able to grow from seed you
know continue to breed on our land
continue to create strong genetics that
are meant for our land and of course
bring in you have to bring in genetics
too sometimes from people so it's nice
to have this regenerative network of
people because you don't you don't wanna
I don't like to imbrie too much to so
that's what's beautiful about this
connection that we have with other
farmers and stuff too that we're able to
I got some velvet goo actually growing
right now from sun roots that I'm pretty
stoked about and and and some cherry
lime dog from Jessie that's going real
strong I gotta get some of that rose
lemonade from you guys too but yeah yeah
but yeah so that's kind of where I stand
and it's so beautiful to have this just
the support of the regenerative movement
so that we can really grow in the intim
in my opinion like the most ideal
fashion possible
we still don't make a hundred percent
all of our own potting soil but we're
working towards that
maybe you guys could talk about it well
I just want to mention that I've spent a
lot of time in moon geezers few goals
and its really you can if you've if
you've been to a pot farm you really
have not experienced anything like what
it feels like to walk around moon
geysers garden even from you guys have
been building up your soil over the
years and it just keeps getting better
and better but even from the first year
even when you were still building them
there already was just bursting with
this like vibrant energetic life force
that like just feels so different than
than what you would normally think of as
a farm and watching it grow is really
awesome and watching it just like keep
exponentially amplifying and building on
itself and watching the goat herd keep
getting bigger is really a delight and
these and Josh's Josh and his wife
Sandra who's not here have been super
awesome about inviting people to come
and see what they're doing and like feel
that feeling and then take that home
with them to their farm and I think it's
been really beautiful what you've been
doing to build community and like
holding up that example for everyone so
thanks for that and I was hoping that
some that actually no flower days that
flower days would talk to us about their
farm and specifically what I think is
really having also gotten to visit your
farm what really stands out is how you
guys are very dedicated to keeping
things small because you're very focused
on these little details that might get
lost otherwise and it like the way that
you're approaching it from this boutique
standpoint I was hoping you could tell
us about that and how that translates
for you well part of our effort to stay
small is also the limitations of the
land we work with so a goal on our farm
is to try and explore what what we can
how we can cycle nutrients through the
land and so we are keeping animals and
the land is also feeding them it's also
growing food to feed us and so through
that we're able to generate enough
fertility for what we're working on and
that's a really
special thing it's basically since in
1925 farm farmers were recognizing that
soil and nutritional quality of food and
medicine were deteriorating and so this
has been a problem for a long time and
so since 1925 it's degraded even further
and so what work we need to do is
recreate natural cycles of animals
consuming you know like the coarse
fibers that grow on the land not
imported foods and recirculating that
through our farms so that we can rebuild
this high nutritional quality and really
that nutritional quality is what's going
to give you the quality that you're
going to enjoy and take and taste and
your food in your in your cannabis and
so I mean that's something for all
agriculture to start striving for we
don't really have time to start doing
anything else and keep getting this
fertilizer from Indonesia and this thing
from there and these cow bones are from
industrial slaughter offices but we call
it organic like that that's not progress
you know and so we're talking about
climate change and we have these goals
that we're trying to meet and so what is
what is the answer to that and like so
for me I took that really personally
like I was living in the city and I felt
like dude my life is this is not you
know like this is not a solution that
I'm being a part of you know
participating in this huge consumptive
society and so how do we figure out how
to to fix that and and so we went on a
quest for that and we've discovered that
the cannabis we were producing was
really high quality and so it's our goal
to produce cannabis that goes out and
inspires people to keep to maybe make a
change in their life and
so that's kind of where we're coming
from with staying really small-batch on
our land and we hope that as we build
our fertility you know the batches will
grow but we are we put ourselves in a
box so that we could try to think
outside of the box yeah I mean I think
in a lot of ways we just really made a
lot of changes in our lives because of
our initially because of our personal
health and cannabis is very integral to
our own healing and our both physical
and metaphysical and spiritual healing I
would say and in our kind of quest to
discover what living a sustainable life
really means in today's world and how
how we could actually be part of the
solution we through cannabis the plant
led us to to Trinity County and to this
homesteading community in hi and palm
which is kind of outside of Hayfork
so you get to Hayfork and then you still
have to go like 45 more minutes down a
windy road and it's on the South Fork of
the Trinity River and it's this just
epic little valley and there's a lot of
beautiful epic little looks out here and
it's the mountains are steep around us
and it's like canvas just loves to grow
there we have a long outdoor growing
season and we can grow all our stuff
like josh is talking about doing it
through the whole full season in the
cycle of nature and once you start
really integrating yourself into nature
you start seeing like like Kate ins
Caitlin's talking about how lovely it is
to see the goat herd and life exploding
everywhere and it's springtime and you
really witnessed that right now and when
you start to see that you realize that
ok well we know that it makes our food
better we know it makes my canvas better
we see in the science
everything nutritionally all of the
terpenes the whole profile everything
we're looking at doesn't matter if
you're talking about food or or cannabis
you you see everything testing higher
better just more nuance coming out in
the flavor especially but in the
nutrition in the quality and so for us
being small batch or a three acre
property and we initially bought a place
that needed some work but from a
permaculture perspective as far as a
property that you could really work on
the soil work on the design of the land
as a whole and figure out how to turn
the farm into a real integrated living
organism and if you can let the
biological systems really thrive and
build the systems that provide sanctuary
then suddenly you see that life is
exploding and that you don't have to
deal with the problems because they're
being dealt with already like you don't
have to spray for a pest or you don't
see a pest infestation because you have
an actually complete ecosystem that is
dealing with itself you have health and
you have health in a in another way
because you have this joy and you see
you start to see life really working in
a progressive way where it's actually
getting better things are getting better
and it happens quickly remediation
happens quickly regeneration happens
really quickly cells rebuild themselves
really quickly in the human body the
human gut becomes healthy really quickly
but you have to do the things to make
the right environment and then you see
the results in the quality and for us
it's about the art and it's about the
plant and that's never going to change
and so we can only put so much energy in
and on three acres you can do what you
can do on three acres but we're not
planting three acres of can
we live on that three acres our animals
live from that three acres and we grow
all our food on that three acres we grow
all our animals food on that three acres
we're getting there you know we we have
things we source sometimes locally and
that's the other really integral part of
it is that it's a larger ecosystem that
you're a part of you're one part you're
a living biological system your farm is
and then it's part of another localized
ecosystem and we need to work in our
localized communities for resources
because they're abundant and if we use
our surpluses that we have on a small
scale to supply each other like hey Fork
you know needs to grow a lot more hay
because we need a lot more local organic
straw mulch it's actually frustrating to
try and source things sometimes which is
why we went to the point of realizing
like we need to be self-reliant enough
to not have to import anything and so
that's what we're striving for
ultimately and what that does for the
quality too is it builds your terroir it
actually makes your specific
characteristics of your soil in your
land and the place where you live come
out and there's a story behind each
place and you know we really understand
that to a pretty sophisticated level in
wine but as far as cannabis we still
have a lot of education and people need
to actually experience it to know it and
understand it and that's part of what
terroir means it's you know the place
and the characteristics of that place
that give the product that's being
cultivated there whether it be wine or
cheese or cannabis I mean there's
Appalachians that were just talking
earlier about Appalachians for chamomile
and there's an amazing terpene and
chamomile which we found in some of our
strains were really prevalent and it's
it's part of what makes it calming it's
part of why it makes the highest
amazing I mean there's so much nuance to
it that's the art behind it and that's
why it's so fun to be a farmer and what
we really need more of actually is
scientists to come out to the farm and
help us continue to collect collect data
because it's a lot to manage and that's
something we could really you know use
some collaboration with people doing
that kind of work
suggestions I just got a weather station
and they're not that expensive and it
constantly just updates data but it's
just a great tool to be able to put
right near gardening your cultivation
location and get the radiation the
temperature the humidity you can get
them with soil probes to get temperature
you could set up game cams and like
really like pay attention to everything
and the rhythms of the plants with the
environment but it's cool just to have
it you can look on your phone at any
time and see yeah that's awesome so
there's those close loops the looking at
the farm as a whole we had a really good
example this trip up to Oregon and our
winners this year Lane Creek Kemp they
do full Google cultures they have
animals on-site lots of different like
llamas and sheeps and goats and pigs
they grow about 27 acres I think of a
straw that's feed for the animals and so
they've actually fully closed that loop
and it's kind of interesting just like
looking at this land and seeing the way
water moves and energy moves and the way
they've done like small things that are
gonna like lead to really big thriving
changes and just with how energy flow is
how water flows and putting the things
in the right place for a system to build
itself and then building diverse
polyculture both in the soil diversity
and in the plants that you're growing
and when you're doing that you're
bringing up all this all this ability to
process nutrition when you have a
diverse biology in the soil it's able to
you eat whatever is there and make it
available for the plants and then all
these different plants are able to bring
all
these different minerals and nutrition
up and they bring it to the surface and
then that's mulching back in and it's
just constantly building soil when
you're part of that process you're part
of sequestering carbon to create
something that that leads to nutrition
and it's a system that just thrives and
thrives and thrives and you're able to
make an economic product at the same
time something that has value that let
you know that people get jobs based off
of that feed family and you're literally
improving the environment like how
amazing is that there's very little
thing few things in the world like a
business that actually don't have you
know dramatic negative effects on the
environment and regenerative agriculture
is one of those things that that do and
most of Agriculture is horribly
destructive and so the more we support
small farmers that build soil that build
polyculture that reach out to community
that provide really good products that's
what we need to do as a society so
support these farmers up here thank you
for coming to things like this and
believing in this I was just gonna say
real quick in the regenerative cannabis
calendar I just saw for this month the
the stropharia opposed there were there
was a lot of info about it that I hadn't
known about how it benefits the bees
even so with those Kings for for your
mushroom you're benefiting the bees
you're growing food you're sequestering
carbon and that's that's a really that's
a fine tenet of regenerative canvas so
he's referring to - mushrooms wood
eating mushrooms like yeah oh yeah once
Jessi starts talking about closing loop
well I think everything that we're
saying about systems and all these
things integrating really speaks to what
for me is the real differentiator
between these farmers and most farmers
is this attitude of like instead of like
you're the master farmer and you're
looking down at your farm and everything
is like your responsibility and if
there's a pest problem you have to solve
it it's seeing there's this incredibly
powerful larger force and it's like
working within that and creating that
environment
and that's necessary to let these forces
do what they need to do is just a much
more powerful and an effective approach
I think and that's what really makes all
of the any whether it's cannabis or
produce stand out when it comes out of
these kinds of Gardens
so I think some roots should tell us
about how they do that to make
especially really beautiful enormous
crazy colored cool-looking plants in
particular but also just really
nutritious and good for the soil and all
that stuff - thank you you guys are all
amazing and everyone here for being here
thank you so much for taking the time to
care it matters it matters to care
everything that we do makes a difference
I'm Patricia and speaking on kind of
what you were saying Caitlin about not
looking down on your farm as if it's
you're the master gardener because
there's no hierarchy in the garden there
is something I always want to speak on
when we talk about regenerative
agriculture is that yeah letting go of
control in the garden and letting go of
control in a way that helps you to open
your your eyes and your perspective to
what you may not see when you have all
these ideas and all these structures in
front of you and when you let go in the
garden you're listening more and that's
my biggest thing on regeneration is that
we're here not as controllers but as
servants to this earth really I see
myself is this like okay mom on earth
like I will do this I will continue
working hard and and for my community
and for everything that I stand for it's
not easy work it's intensive labor
intensive you know mentally physically
spiritually you're in it all the time
and it's a commitment and you know we're
human so we're it's wonderful to make
mistakes because we learn and grow from
them but yeah regeneration in the garden
again and just in our lives where we're
all need to do our part and then power
you
hether and support these kind of small
farms and support the lifestyle of of
helping one another out because not only
are we regenerating our land and working
our soils and building and building
every part of the year we're building up
soil because the work is not really ever
done so you continue doing things and as
you build up in that you build up in
other parts of yourself where you can be
better for the world and be better for
the environment because right now we
need all these earth stewards to come
forward like you're all-powerful each
one of us has so much power to really
make a difference in this world and yeah
we're all these little small farmers in
these mountain areas way out there but
wherever you are you make a difference
so with your little Gardens you know
plant what you can and even if it's in a
container and a patio in the city that's
fine
do do our part and I'll let forests talk
about big plants because this man is
like I always praise them up but just
yeah I walked into his farm five years
ago and it's changed a lot since then we
have a lot more flowers and the
everything is building and building
we're basically building compost piles
for every single plot of land we have
ten by tens where we just keep adding
the manure adding the straw adding
mushroom mycelium woodchips adding
plants chop and drop that is definitely
a big creation of the larger plants and
also the genetics that that we're
working with our local and I'll let for
us get into it more but thank you all
for listening thank you and so diversity
is one of our main things that we try to
focus on having as many types of plants
and as we can around the the ganja and
giving space and the vision to seeing
how you know if you're gonna grow a big
plant you need to like
invision at the end you know giving it
enough space so it has that potential to
get to where you want it to go and just
keep building the soil up layer by layer
and having those natural you know
systems to help you on the way
so maybe get some context for when you
say big plants what that means in case
people haven't seen your plants
last year the look the largest one was
like 20 pounds they 60 yeah 16 feet 20
pounds dried yeah
no way I call bullshit but I saw these
players painted like they're beautiful
that one was grown on like a compost
pile of old we'd like stems and stalks
but like I mean the majority of them
were 10 plus you know these these are
all strains that I've been breeding
myself you know on the farm for years so
no not 20 feet high
not quite that big how wide probably
like 12 feet wide by you know 13 14 feet
tall you know if you go to regenerative
cannabis farming org there's videos that
you can link to that walk you walk
through these monster pants it's it's
all it's all about how many bud sets the
the density of the the colas and how
happy they are you know if you're giving
them the right nutrients and an adequate
amount of water you know we we have drip
systems that go you know once around the
base and then around you know the big
part of you know the mass amount of the
soil that we have and so like they pull
out water when they need it and you know
have as much nutrients as they need also
so available so you know throughout
their course of growing
oh all I have to do is go out there with
a hose and like do a hand water to like
feed them extra food you know I don't
have to add anything else everything
else everything that they need is in the
soil already so we walk us through the
soil building and composting process
well that's like a yearly process like
in the fall we we prep the beds by
laying more more straw and covering any
bare spots and then in this in this and
then we throw out cover crops too so you
know during the winter there's cover
crops that are growing and then in the
springtime you know we cut the cover
crops and add bring in more more manure
locally-sourced and our own you know we
have alpacas so they're really good
adding nutrients they have a high
phosphorous it's phosphorous we're in
public
California Mendocino so two hours inland
from here but I just wanna say about the
apakah
because they have communal dung piles
and they are really hygienic and they
are light on the earth they don't eat as
much they don't drink as much and
they're less harmful in ways that
livestock can be so that's one of our
you we don't milk them just some we the
little koreas the baby alpacas we let
them have all the milk and I think you
can though the camel lid milk is
apparently very delicious but we haven't
tried it so in the springtime then we
bring we pretty much make a pile of
manure right in each plot where we're
gonna put one plant so each plant gets a
pile of manure and then what was I gonna
say
no-till so if anything we have these
meadow Forks metal creatures they're
great broad Forks
so if you want to loosen up your soil
you have a you have those to do a little
bit of mixing if you need to other than
that you know that's pretty much it just
pruning the plant up when when like
three or four times during the grow
cycle
caging them really well because right
where we have we have lots of strong
wind and they'll blow your plants right
down if you don't have them fence post
in you know we have tea posts on each
corner and then a cage going up you know
two feet high off the ground so we can
actually you know support the plant well
and then we'll have to like do a third
cage at the end right before that you
know they're they're done you know in
august-september we're third caging it
so it's a big process but you're totally
worth oh yeah we start our seeds in
February second week in February second
third week in February so you know
having that whole process of you know
from springtime all the way till fall so
these plants are sucking in all this
energy from the the cosmos and the
ground all that nutrients and you know
just making a real medicine for the
people you know and that's what it's
about you know we're all we're all
growing medicine so and that's the most
important thing keeping the cannabis
sacred so that's how we feel thank you
thanks so much I was hoping that we
could maybe get a little bit more into
kind of explaining what's going on in
the soil that you guys are creating
because for me as I was like visiting
farms like these guys and really
starting to understand what makes them
so special that was like a big light
bulb moment for me was like oh living
soil that's really what it comes to it's
like no-till living soil going to a farm
and having having Jesse say look at look
at this look at my soil look at these
worms look at these spiders and he's
like oh my god my worms
so I think you know we could talk about
like how you build your soil and that's
really valuable information for people
that are gonna do it but just for anyone
that's gonna consume cannabis or buy
cannabis or sell it like what is live
like what makes living soil different
than you know what a bagged soil with
maybe you know you can put nutrients in
it but what makes that no-till living
soil special and different than then
other than dirt it's connected to
everything and it has like as far as
like building it like there's no like
this is a way to build soil or make some
super soil it's like working with your
environment what makes sense you know
like certainly cover cropping and
mulching working with animals and
building biodynamic compost and
integrating that back in Google cultures
burying wood creating dynamic spaces
with organic matter that's like tons of
different types of foods for very
diverse microbes and continuingly
building on that diversity and adding
more organic matter and as you do that
you just draw more and more life and you
know it's not just about like we talked
about the the bacteria and the fungi but
I when you're seeing a lot of the larger
bugs you know the centipedes and little
soil mites and all kinds of fun things
worms and like there's all this nutrient
cycling that's happening you're like you
just think about how much energy is
happening to constantly have these more
and more critters that are like moving
around eating and pooping and and
they're just building more and more soil
and they're all just doing their own
thing you'd like feeding themselves but
they're all improving everything you
know as they do their thing you know
they all have their specialized way and
you know I kind of see that as part of
this regenerative movement is like
paying attention to like you know all
those bugs are building soil and they're
doing their own thing you know like how
we can all kind of connect like that and
and put carbon in the ground and build
living soil and grow good things out of
that you know the same with with
mutualistic relationships of any kind
with plan
with with soil biology you know cannabis
roots there cannabis is a mutualistic
organism that's how it like evolve zits
very smart so it knows how to give other
organisms what it wants and so the main
process that's happening on the the
roots is is this exudate exchange where
the roots of the plant are they have all
of this energy from the Sun that they
can turn into carbohydrates and they can
feed different bacteria in the soil they
can feed different fungi those fungi
have the enzymes that can then break
down other minerals in the soil the
plant can uptake that and it becomes
this cycle where the soil biology
thrives the plant thrives all the energy
is coming from the Sun the carbon gets
stored in the ground and it's a system
that continually builds and builds and
builds and what's left behind is soil so
like yeah those are the processes to
mimic and that's what plants have
evolved to have their best health with
just like us eating a healthy diet like
eating a fibrous market you can eat
around food a plant growing from insect
poop and fungi and in and well developed
in aerated because like worms are moving
through and because the fungi clumps
things together we have aggregated soil
that allows the right amount of air that
allows the right amount of organisms to
have an environment to all thrive and it
just continues and continues and that's
going to give birth or give rise to the
best you know how off the best in the
plant and then the best cannabis and
terpene production at the end so that's
why if you buy soil and then throw it
away at the end of the season that is
incorrect and should not be your
approach you're the soil you know it
just just be this thing that you're like
constantly like improving and adding to
and and it's like it's the most valuable
thing you have you know and if we all
like think about that like that's where
everything of value comes from that we
grow all of our nutrition that's what
keeps us healthy like and if every
person you know like their space like
thinks about that soil and say a sacred
and something like they can make thrive
more and more every year
you're sequestering carbon and you're
bringing health to the world
what is it oh so easy ya know all kinds
of things you know compaction bare soil
the Sun beating down having water go
over correctly spraying anything doing
any kind of salt nutrients pH going off
there's all kinds of things that you
know you make it like a change and the
biology is very specific especially
different bacterias for a very specific
environment so the pH gets thrown off
salt balance gets there you have a total
die out of a certain thing and then that
throws a whole cycle off so like you
have to be really careful of not
allowing any kind of collapse in your
soil biology that using things like that
you know keeping it protected don't over
compact don't leave things bare don't
every you know don't use salt nutrients
don't use pesticides thank you for
explaining that to us so when I started
smoking cannabis that came out of this
kind of soil and realized how different
it was then the cannabis that I might
have previously been smoking it pretty
quickly made me realize that I only
wanted to eat food that was coming out
of living soil also because the
difference is so dramatic and then that
kind of means you have to start growing
your own food and building your own soil
if you want that but I think a big part
of all of your Gardens is like that is
the same soil is providing your food
that you eat like you're not gonna spray
pesticide on your cannabis cuz you are
dedicated to what you're doing and you
know that's wrong but also like that's
your food that you're eating is coming
from right right there so I was hoping
maybe anyone who wants to speak to it
all you could talk about just what it's
like to have that kind of connection
like it's not just like this is my job
this is my cash crop it's like this is
my life this is my food this is
everything and that's I think a really
magical relationship that not very many
people nowadays have gotten to see your
experience and it really like it really
colors like your whole existence I think
when you are doing that and eating
eating the food that's coming out of
those kuegel beds or those those beds so
does anyone talk about their food that
they grow
I'll start because I think the change we
made in our lives basically saved my
life from a health perspective I think I
don't know where I would be if I hadn't
started seeking the answers to like what
am i eating and and insource I mean the
city sourcing your food is it took it
would take me all week and I had certain
farmers at the farmers market and I knew
exactly how they grew their food and
they nourished me and kept me alive but
I think it's really important that you
know ultimately the solutions are
solutions to a lot of things and if
we're only focused on profits for the
sake of profits and we're not taking
into account the people or the planet
and their health like for real like the
quality of the life then what are we
really gaining and for how long is that
even sustainable and we don't have the
time to waste anymore to be playing that
game and I'm not interested in playing
it I'm not interested in buying anything
or consuming anything that does doesn't
take these things into account and so
for me it was like a big life choice in
a lot of ways that led me to be a canvas
farmer in a remote valley in Northern
California where I'm growing all my own
food but to know what it tastes like to
go to a high-end pomme potluck there's
like the saying that like once you've
been to a high-end pomme potluck you're
like ruined forever because you could go
to like the best restaurant in Paris or
wherever and you're just gonna be like
yeah it's pretty good or you could
appreciate the chef or if you go to a
place that's really farm-to-table like
for real and you can really appreciate
it but there's nothing
like homegrown so like one thing is if
you can grow it in your backyard I hope
you will and the other is that it's Luke
it is lucrative to support sustainable
business that's based on health and
well-being of everybody involved and
that's mutually beneficial and it's
really important that we start thinking
that way because if we don't where are
we going and how does that how does
anybody really win otherwise and it's
just like we were just like there's no
more time to waste we're just gonna like
die like well I'm dying I can feel
myself dying I'm like not even that old
this is fucked up you know so like what
are we gonna do about it and oh look at
these mycelium in the woods they like
found their way indigenous
microorganisms to this crazy plastic
that some cartel left here and they're
like eating it and turning it into soil
and like if you just build it they will
come so like like seeing the
microbiology on are just three acres and
what it could do to our ecosystems I
mean we can reverse climate change if we
practice regenerative agriculture it's
very simple I don't even know what the
original question was I'm sorry I think
going back to the no-till growing our
food in this system is is very
unconventional in terms of agriculture
having the this this constant supply of
luscious you know lomi amazing living
soil for for your food I mean we're
going through this right now my you know
my wife just had two babies and there's
a whole there is this you know in terms
of milk production and lactation all
this kind of stuff I mean there is a
real nutrient like food sort of science
to all that you know I mean we're
harvesting like stinging nettles out of
our garden and these are all things that
are growing in like a no-till
nutrient-dense
style and and it's real and you can
really feel it and and it goes on I
spoke about worms in the beginning but
it you know there's all kinds of life
there's all different kinds of earthworm
castings are wonderful but then you have
the insect frass from the pill bugs and
I mean it goes even all the way to
hummingbird poop I mean there's probably
some special compound in that and we're
a track and we're attracting them with
with certain flowers that we grow next
to our plants you know so it's just
creating creating good life is where
it's at I wanted to tap in and just say
to like to be real also with not all of
us have access to being on a farm and up
in the mountains like you live in the
city you live in the city and that's
perfectly fine and fine I think it's
important to find your strengths and
where you are you know like our strength
is growing food but that's not
everybody's lifestyle so you go out and
you support the people who support you
back and in turn you know where you guys
have a mutually benefiting relationship
and also diversifying with different
foods and medicine I think it's so
important to talk about not many people
talk about this in cannabis I feel like
you know herbal medicine there's all
these other herbs and sacred flowers and
food is medicine and everything that's
growing is basically medicinal all
around us and when we can combine the
intake of cannabis with different herbs
that were either growing or sourcing
from someone that we know who's growing
them I grow them if anyone is ever
interested in herbs because I I believe
that we have to blend up the different
medicinal values of each plant so you're
not only receiving anti-inflammatory and
adaptogenic properties from one plant
but you're receiving it from multiple
different sources so that your medicine
is actually now enhanced and more
diversified and it's all about that it
always comes down to that how we can
diversify everything around us our
culture's our come
Unity's and ourselves internally it's
it's I think it's an important balance
to have thank you so much for bringing
up the importance of diversity and I
think that really comes through across
like the soil the companion planting
growing around food all of it it's
really like diversity is a huge part of
every regenerative farm I think and when
I see like a big monoculture now it
makes me just really sad and it looks
dead to me because it's like the
diversity of all the different plants
and one hukill bed or in one space and
then the diversity of all the different
types of life that are going on in the
soil I think all of that comes together
in this amazing symphony and I thought
it would be nice to hear you mentioned
that um Patricia you mentioned that you
didn't always have so much things
besides cannabis growing in the cannabis
garden and now you guys have more
flowers and more all different kinds of
things and I was wondering if you have
noticed changes you know changes in the
space changes in the cannabis after
increasing more different types of life
absolutely one of the parcels that were
honest actually was planted 20 years
prior with by a woman who created a
Wildlife Sanctuary so we had one half of
the property that's like amazing
thriving plum trees fruit trees
everything that nature and all these
birds and bats want and then on our side
of the property when we move there
it was a long progress because most of
it was just cattle ranching you know our
areas AG land so a lot of ranchers
around there and it's all flat all the
trees have been kind of in the valley
what was it used to be a swamp more
grassland and then it all got fenced off
so what we had to do was sheet mulch and
sheet mulching is beautiful because you
can start with like a graph a piece of
like land of gravel where nothing's
growing at all and you just start adding
the layers of soil and two years later
or even months late months later I mean
three months later you can see the
difference in the soil you can put your
hand in and it's soft and it's it's
workable but years later and I'm talking
about now I mean the amount of flowers
and
and thriving native plants and trees the
birds are crazy like people who stay
over our house they're like oh my god
why are these birds so happy in the
morning like 5 a.m. they're going off
and you can't sleep anymore but but
unless you're used to like me and you
can sleep through it
but yeah it's just you're creating like
a paradise an ecosystem that is
literally paradise like if you can
imagine the most beautiful place that
you would want to go to I'm sure it has
flowers and gardens and edibles and
fruit that you can just pick off trees
that drips on you and it's divine that's
what we're striving for is just making
this paradise and I we keep spreading it
wider and wider and wider and that's
what we do with each other - hopefully
it's amazing with the herbs and
medicinal plants is just growing them
with cannabis you you improve your past
situation like big time having yarrow
having basil oregano Lavin all these
different herbs that are really easy to
grow that just kind of take off on their
own that you want to have in your garden
anyway chamomile and love it's like
they're bringing in all these different
insects that keep the the whole system
in balance and I almost never see out of
control you know out of balance pest
issues in gardens with a huge amount of
polyculture so last year we had a Fadel
they showed up and all of a sudden they
were like all over in certain parts of
the garden and it was Connie unnerving
for a minute and then you know what do
you do you know no we're not gonna spray
chemicals on them so we did a little
research she found out that spraying
milk on them helps so we started doing
that and then you know the beneficial
bugs these little sipper flies the
Hoover flies they started laying their
larva on on the plants and I was like
what the heck what are these little
larvae is on here now I have all sorts
of bugs it's like it's like a haven for
all you know all these types of new bugs
that I add it's like whoa so he's like
why'd you make us plant all these
flowers here ruining it but then then we
find out that that they're you know
they're going around eating these aphids
and I'm like taking the aphids and
putting them in front of the little
larva and watching them devour them and
then I see the aphid population
diminishing off for certain plants you
know like Oh some of them almost like
you know a hundred percent and so it's
pretty amazing to see like this actually
working and you know the garden just
taking care of itself
you know so having that diversity is
very crucial and you know just having
fruit trees around and you know being
able to pick your fruit with you you
know as you smell your buds and you know
it's it's all it's just you having like
a Garden of Eden around you you know
it's just that's all I think what we all
want so I think that gives a really
different like seeing that seeing those
systems work and seeing how quickly they
can work and how the garden can sort of
take care of itself when it has the
appropriate amount of diversity it seems
to make make you guys all a lot more
calm than a lot of people who are
managing a garden like I've been in Josh
takes patience developing that patience
and that calm really it comes in or
anything you do did not panicking but
also you start to learn you know these
plants and the animals and the insects
they're not just like working for us
they're beings of their own independent
nature that deserve our love and respect
and we can't get along well without them
and so if we keep farming in ways that
hurt these creatures
we're in big trouble yeah let's get
along with the creatures I've been in
I've been in moon gazer scarred a lot of
times and seen because like I said you
guys always have just different people
coming through and checking out the
garden and so I always see we're always
walking through the garden and someone's
coming through and they're like Oh Josh
I just found something here there's you
out of bugs here there's some stuff
growing here and every time he's so
chill they're like oh look out and these
are you know experienced farmers not
just random people that are like oh my
god a bug like they're experts they know
what they're talking about they're like
oh oh you got something to worry about
here and every single time you just let
it roll right you're like oh something
will come along and eat that like just
so chill and your weed is amazing and it
does not get all eaten by bugs so it
seems like it's working so just not
stress out about that there's definitely
an element of trusting in nature that
that it'll it'll it'll work out and and
observing well yeah biological
intelligence is amazing and I mean it's
very nuanced and so you have to know
what you're looking at for sure and
sometimes you have to constantly be
doing research and we need to be really
connected in our communities because you
know just an in agriculture like new
things come in as like it's actually the
because of hemp blowing up that we saw
these new aphids for the first time on
cannabis the their hemp aphids that
crossed over so anyway there's always
going to be something new to deal with
and it's always changing and but but
biological intelligence is very nuanced
and it's it's something that you don't
want to be ever fighting against and
actually if you just really constantly
observe and really work with its own
balance balance it doesn't mean you're
always perfectly on a straight line in
the middle like this that's not how it
works
balance is fluid and biological
intelligence allows for a natural course
of
to walk that line in a way that's
actually fluid and that's that's what
life means and that and so when you're
creating as the farmer that creation
that's what life is about its creative
and so ultimately we are the innovators
we are the ones that are that come
before the science the science is that
is what we're doing but then the numbers
just our ways we can measure and
demonstrate and prove what we are
discovering and so the discovery and the
creation that's what life is doing and
the biological intelligence there's more
more and more and more and more to it
the more to it that you uncover and the
more that you learn and so that's what's
exciting about our job but the other
thing is we need to really need to build
space where we can be working in this
way in agriculture and that it is
possible to create both abundance
well-being health for the planet and the
people and have lucrative sustainable
system so I think that's really
important that our industry be guiding
this because we've been doing this work
there's research in Korea there's like
um hundred years of research from
Germany and other places and we're one
of the places in the United States and
this part of kind of the Western
Hemisphere that you know in cannabis
that we've been doing this because our
way of life kind of plant all of it
leads to us asking these questions and
so as an industry how can we really
support the fact that we are in a lot of
ways the innovators and and part of the
people that are doing some really
creative work around what can happen
positively in agriculture and with this
plant so I hope we'll all kind of
continue to really think about
regardless like Patricia said of where
you live how we can support those
systems in our regions because they're
really important to the sustainability
of our of our cities and of our future
in general so say and socially also
promoting diversity as a form of
resilience when people come out to our
farm and we have you know last year we
had about that we had at one point like
20 visitors at one time came from CDFA
because they're coming up with their you
know with their ways of looking at
things and and there was a couple
farmers there too and one farmer said
they go aren't you are you worried about
you know pests coming over or you know
and and it's it doesn't really become an
issue when you have the balanced
ecosystem and and resilient resilient
nature making sort of farm that we can
create want to say I want to smoke the
flowers that come from the farms where
they're paying attention to which plant
had hummingbird poop on it and which you
know and just noticing the aphids and
that there'd be you know that the hover
fly started eating I'm like that kind of
nuance like in connection with your
landscape and your flowers there's no
way to replicate that it's something
that's really special it's something
that's art and then something that we
should really do everything to support
agreed well I think there's probably a
lot of things that you guys could share
that are valuable because you're always
learning and discovering new things so I
don't if there's anything that that we
haven't touched on that feels important
to to share and then we can have
questions after that anything we missed
I'd like to encourage everyone to go to
the website regenerative cannabis
farming org you can learn about these
farms there's cool photo galleries and
movies and a lot of information about
practices and resource links does
anybody have any questions
regenerative cannabis farming dot-org
the regenerative farming is is that
stand alone on its own or who is that
sponsored by where does that stem from
yeah it's it's a project that I anmar
it's just a way of evaluating farms
based on their ecological and community
standards and something that we just do
independently for both the Emerald cup
and the cultivation classic for
rewarding farms based on okay cool yeah
that was my question awesome it's
independent yeah I typed permaculture
and bio vortex it's very grassroots I
just had a question as a like city
dweller I have a small garden and I was
just wondering how it even gets started
and introducing like beneficial bugs to
my crops and where I would get that and
like how to get smaller just build
compost and build a bunch of flood and
create a bunch of flowers create habitat
for them to come and they'll come so
plant flowers you know move some la
sticks logs around or get some woodchips
and there's a lot of availability of
resources in urban areas to do
interesting permaculture projects look
up Google culture beds too and do a mini
hula culture you might have fun with
that in the yard it's always fun to to
look at native plants in your area
because that attracts the native
pollinators and bees and bugs that you
like right well yeah if you can do some
research look for a native plant nursery
in your area and there'll be a awesome
resource to let you know how to you know
give a habitat for the bugs that are
best for that particular area
hey um so I work in a nursery and a lot
of the people that I interact with have
indoor grows that try to be very sterile
and use a lot of really unsustainable
practices and I feel like everyone knows
they can't last forever but I'm curious
what you guys think a path toward being
more sustainable indoors could look like
hmm
will sustain as far as pest control I
think like a lot of people have pretty
good luck just doing common things like
mineral oils and sulfur and and then and
then introducing biological controls
like the bugs that might eat the next
one but that's a very control this is
such a different world the indoor
environment because it's like the
opposite of what we're doing you know
we're tracting as much life as possible
and you're trying to kind of control it
indoors but biological controls do work
well and and living soil works super
well indoors and you don't have to
replace it and it gets better and better
there's a lot of really good examples of
people doing like 30 cycles and it just
improves every time I always pictured
like the most ideal indoor situation
would be like with solar panels and you
had some animals may be grazing outside
and you could use that like material to
compost your beds and stuff like that
and do like a no-till indoor style and
like if you check out check out green
life productions over in Nevada they
have some cool indoor techniques that
they use there's lots of micro
mycological life and stuff like that in
there and it says there's a way to do
anything and there are also quite a few
plant based pesticide products on the
market that could be alternatives
there's definitely I know one called
SNS 209 which hat is basically a
rosemary extract it's a pet and it's
like generally recognized as safe food
grade product that is a is a pesticide
you water in made out of rosemary and
that's it so there are definitely
options for for consumers to support you
know regenerative regrown products if
you choose not to make it yourself
like we do and I think some of that is
definitely worth supporting
I think it's cool to see in places where
Endor is the only legal option people
exploring companion planting and no-till
living soil in an indoor environment but
I think that the best way to improve an
indoor grow is to take the roof off and
then take the walls off and then take
the floor away we have to remember that
the reason we grow indoors is not
because it's superior or more clean it's
because helicopters used to fly over and
you could get you could get away with it
you know that's the only reason we grow
indoors why would you ever eat it tomato
grown indoors are you kidding me like
who eats tomatoes grown indoors and
prefers tomatoes like and to grow your
own medicine in your house not everyone
has a farm and for fighting yourself
medicine it definitely makes sense but
to commercially be be using this much
energy I think I I don't know I heard
some outrageous statistics about how
much fossil fuels go into an indoor
pound that's just like the equivalent
I'm a server of a server center yeah
it's like it's pretty terrible so we
need to fix that there's we don't really
there's no excuses anymore
at least not for us because we have the
environment to do it and we we need we
should be celebrating that and and doing
that because we can now and there aren't
I mean they're actually that's not true
they're still helicopters flying over
but that's a longer story and not not
with this panel is about anyway so I had
a friend who grew pretty traditionally
you know whatever worked kind of style
and you know he was pretty good at it
and he definitely knows cannabis well
but he was doing a nursery and he's all
he's been all excited like calling me
the last like several months it's like
constantly like oh my god I'm doing so
much less work I'm like because he's
gone told the organic and he's just done
natural predators for his nursery and
like there's no spray it's just like I
don't have to hire anyone up to do
anything the plants are happier than
I've ever seen and you know he's doing
your amounts of kind of classic you know
hype strains and stuff like that - and
keeping them clean just with you know
organic and biological control simple
it's cool to see that next question yes
so thank you I'm gonna start off by
saying that I'm vegan and I'm very
regenerative so these questions might
come a little bit more of a reality
check for for me anyway 80% of the
cannabis that's consumed is grown
indoors and so the 20% which is where
the beautiful also gets pricing that's
much lower and often much better quality
so I think there's got to be a way to
bridge that gap and be become more plant
centric for sure
and you don't need an example of that
with the regards to different kinds of
comparing you know additives that you
might do whether it's chemicals salts
whatever because you can look right
around you and see this beautiful that
really doesn't have Monsanto here
doesn't have you know a peak number xxx
it does it on its own it's been doing it
for years right I think the issue is how
do we the Sun is extremely important as
we all know the UV factor so no matter
whether you put it on a greenhouse or
you do it indoors
the issue is you're not getting UV and
UV is so significantly important for
pest control as well as compound
development and outside we can get so
much more compound so much more medicine
it's all medicine whether you're getting
high on it or not it's medicine so my
question is I see a lot of camaraderie I
certainly do and that's one of the
reasons I came because I want to be
centered in there it's the kind of souls
that are here but where's the
collaboration in fighting off that 80%
grow and fighting from a quality
perspective from a land race perspective
being able to buy the true medicines
that are
available to us not just in cannabis in
psychedelics and and em but grown in a
way not only that you are servant
to mother nature but that you produce
the best highest quality because they
will find you so my question is what
strains or what plants what are the
plans of the group here to differentiate
yourself in the marketplace with a
quality product that no matter what
other people make they know you your
farm for that how how is it that you're
gonna do this against this huge machine
that's going to be branding and they're
gonna do everything else they're gonna
poison it and I do this often and I'm
sorry for this I'm getting on a soapbox
I figure that everything that's not done
the way you do it is poison cannabis
truely's poison cannabis in this way we
extract it with bioaccumulates in our
body along with the chemicals that you
use to grow it which also is in the
plant so the question is how do we
collaborate in a way to be able to
change that balance a little bit because
we all know in our heart the cannabis
growing out there in living soil
outdoors is going to produce the best
medicine and high so how would you guys
go about doing that well that is the
point of the regenerative cannabis farm
award I got at the heart like that's the
concept it's like the getting this out
there at that thermal cup you have 4,000
people on stage looking up and we are
showing the movies connecting the farms
with the animals the soil the poly
culture the community work and they see
it and and then you know connecting them
with the flowers after that - and we had
a really cool flower testing - and you
did these amazing reviews certified dank
did amazing reviews of all the different
flowers so each different farm put in
like two different samples and they were
they were all got these really fun
elaborate wine type reviews that we're
actually quite on point because I'm very
familiar with a lot of problems like wow
that's really
really good very specific it almost be
funny if you read one of those but the
more that we like kind of have that the
practices be the subject and the more we
communicate also with dispensaries there
certain dispensaries like soulful that
really do push forward these practices
they have the you know come meet the
farmers and so then the consumers get to
connect with you know see pictures talk
to the farmers know the practices and
it's you know it starts off slow you
know a few years ago it was just like
there's no concept you know as far as
the general public on these things and I
think it's grown more and more every
year and we just have to just constantly
be beating that down in beating that in
everyone's head talking to the
dispensaries just letting everyone
demanding it as a consumer but the more
people come in contact and learn about
these things there's only one direction
nobody's all the sudden like now I'm
gonna go back to that you know chemi
endure because that was working for me
like this region thing that there's only
one direction I've never seen anyone
like who really gets to like know the
quality of living soil sun-grown like
amazing genetics of course to go with it
too but like once you've experienced
that you know there's not really
backwards so I think it's a constant
slope and it's all of us constantly
talking to each other about supporting
each other and and bringing each other
up it has to be mutualistic so much
business it's like you know cutting the
other person down and why you're the
best and it's not like that in this
movement it's why you know it's like
supporting everyone's practices and
because there's there's stuff to be
learned from everyone and and
celebrating the differences in the
diversity and how that makes us stronger
just as a group just constantly putting
out the education and and hopefully the
public supporting that it definitely
feels like a David and Goliath situation
and it's like oh man there's so much
endure everyone like they think okay
something costs more to produce
therefore it's been we're expensive
therefore it must be better and that's
really frustrating to to see that
attitude be so prevalent but at the same
time watching this movement grow and
it's really been pretty rapid and
amazing
it's it's really true that basically all
you have to do is just like smoke at
once and you'll make an effort to look
for it in the future and so the more
people that just know that this exists
and get a chance to try it the more it
will become available because the demand
just it yet like Jesse's that you don't
go in the opposite direction once you go
this way yeah I think the quality is
what's really gonna help us prevail
because you know one thing that I've
noticed and and as I've become a farmer
and when I drink wine I noticed this too
is that people who use the same things
all their stuff tastes the same and so
how do you differentiate yourself in the
market when you're using the same recipe
as six thousand other people or more and
so when you are bringing out a unique
quality of your place that doesn't taste
like anybody else's place you know
whether you're trying to get a lower
price and produce more and and you know
process it in a in a more you know quick
manner or you're trying to do a smaller
batch that you're trying to really you
know train those plants and and produce
a quote product that's equal to what
people expect of a top shelf indoor
that's you know finely manicured and in
taken care of you know basically that
quality quality is going to
differentiate you because your land is
different from everybody else's land and
whether you advertise your practices or
not that quality is gonna help you
distinguish yourself and so we as a
society and as an industry need to focus
on quality above and be off absolutely
and and diversity so not just like
growing tons of the same diet different
same clones you know like seeds they all
have different phenotypes so each
phenotype is special so
each plant is you know should be held to
its full you know beaut being you know
it's it's one seed it's it's not like
any other it's like a snowflake you know
so it has all different properties and
having diversity like that it could be a
way we keeping in a niche market yeah
exactly it's it's about the niche market
which I mean as as an industry as a
retail market space as as a regulatory
policy there's as far as you know all of
these things as far as like the the
ability of the small farmer or small
business to operate as a regular small
business we have no direct retail access
there's you have to be pretty clean
degraded there's all these different
things that don't make sense that we're
doing in our industry that aren't even
standard in all other industries and the
markups and the way the who has to take
what cut out of where and and none of it
makes any sense it's like we've been
talking all weekend about how crazy this
is that we were all doing this but but
at the same time they're you know the
people who want the good weed and you
know it and back in the day you know we
would get that amazing bag and you it
would just come to you magically because
you didn't have control over what you
would get necessarily maybe you knew a
guy or your friend's cousin or whatever
if you were lucky but but you know like
you got this mate magic bag of weed and
it was incredible and you were like whoa
and one day we actually met the people
that grew our weed and it changed our
lives forever and just I mean like with
wine we we have a level of
sophistication with the consumer now
where you can have that niche market
really thrive and it's going to take
time and we don't even have our
Appalachians set at this point like it's
it's gonna be difficult and we're at the
beginning of a long road of development
as far as that and as far as consumer
education as far as all of these things
but there is a very very strong
desire from all demographics of
consumers realistically for things that
are natural that are pure that are
healthy that are actually legitimately
clean and that are going to enhance
their health because I think the latest
statistic I heard was like one in two
people in the u.s. now have cancer it's
one in two so it's it's again it just
goes back to how all those things are
connected but there there's a there's a
bridge that we still have to build and
then get across and we're at the
beginning of that right now
and the that that's just real reality
but we live really sustainably on our
farms so we're gonna be alright you were
no write it out you know for however
long and whatever is gonna happen after
that like I'd rather be on my farm than
anywhere if the shit hits the fan you
know but but we want to help help it
thrive and we we want to help them move
along as quickly as possible in consumer
advocacy and awareness or consumer
awareness and just how we get the
knowledge out there is really what this
movement is about and what regenerative
canvas farming org is about and why the
Emerald cup made it such a priority to
create an award specifically for how the
farms are practicing and and really
centering around why that makes what we
do up here in Northern California so
special and why ours that creates a
uniqueness to our story that is
definitely marketable and the challenge
is yeah there's you know a lot of
capital going into all kinds of things
right now and it's gonna be a shit show
for a while so it's really about like
finding the other people on the other
side that are all part of this that that
care because definitely people all over
the place really care Forest forest was
mentioning oh really
the diversity
Forrest was mentioning the diversity or
the uniqueness and the potential of that
flower and you know like this jar what's
in it is its high art and it can only
exist this year in this wet you know
like it's it's very unique that genetic
expression in that environment from that
has the love of the cultivator in it as
well as a diverse living system around
it that it gave to existence to then
change your consciousness like I don't
we're talking about things that change
our consciousness like let's like let's
care about the process that went into
creating this like this is incredibly
special art to me that I love I love
cannabis I think we're out of time but
these guys are all incredibly generous
if you find them and ask some questions
I'm sure they'll talk to you for a long
time and tell you a lot of valuable
information but since we're out of time
can we just can you since we're not on
Instagram right now maybe everyone could
say where people can buy your flowers if
they're available anywhere does anyone
can anyone find anyone's flowers in a
store and buy them if they want to
they're all at soulful right every one
of these farms is soulful yeah I think
we're all all of us are at soulful in
Sebastopol and we want to thank those
guys for doing a lot of the work to find
the people really doing the work proper
wellness for us in Eureka and the kohung
in in Oakland which is a micro business
that has been very fair trade with us
and so we want to thank them for for
their support as well so I also want to
thank I saw her out here earlier Amber
Center who's just starting up her
business leisure life doing pre-rolls
she's a small these are the kind of
people we want to support
are small not big time invested and
we're learnt we're all learning about
this to just smaller investors and
companies that care and make a
difference and make a difference in
their communities as well not just on
the bigger level and out of state and
that chemistry is doing really great
work with the vape cartridges and
working with really fine boutique
regenerated farms and they do like whole
plant whole plant extract so it's really
wonderful thanks everyone
Smoak regenerative wheat
[Applause]