[Applause]
[Music]
welcome to functional art where we look
at glass and hash have a closer look
today I'm with Zach from resin heads how
you doing buddy
great how's it going it's going and then
today you brought us a uh who makes this
piece right craft right crafted glass
he's based out of Medford Orion where'd
you find this piece act
I got it directly from him no ice had a
show or no I went to his house and got
to choose from his current stock at the
time it's pretty awesome well can't wait
to hit it you also a hash maker right
yes sir
resin hits resin heads resin hits we
make ice water hash and rosin this is
summing of rosin yes sir that one's GMO
garlic cookies it's not funky offensive
smell to it beautiful resin we heard you
recently took second place at the ego
clash for cold water extraction yes sir
what was the strings it was a mix of
papaya and banana OG 90 micron mix that
sounds very nice do you happen to have
any with you yes yes would you pop it
open whoo and take them that's not rosin
that is not roses bubble a creative
bubble hash straight heads 90 micron
that is gorgeous and so you say this is
a full metal cold water extraction yes
just ice and water no solvents no
solvents and it will melt like an oil
yes it'll melt like water how would you
describe that flavor almost like a
fermenting bananas I don't really know
how else to describe it has almost got a
almost a rotting fruit smell to it and
then the banana just comes through with
like a creamy sweetness almost and what
got you into making bubble hash opposed
to solvent was how I solve them hash I
had a bunch of roommates that lived in a
min to see no County growing up and
their family grew weed and every harvest
time a little bit after four actually
around now Christmas time right this is
hash season they'd always come home and
bring some hat and it was my favorite
thing to throw on bowls and smoke I just
really enjoyed it and so did you watch a
lot of trim when you started there buds
yes started out with trim basically I'm
a grower get our stuff trimmed freeze it
we used to make BHO
didn't really like the way that was
going the taste or just the potential
hazards that involve are involved with
me canned vho so I personally just
really wanted to get into bubble hash
and to clean our product yeah clean
product just ice water agitation no
solvents no chemicals that tastes
exceptionally good you get that real
banana OG on the front end and a lot of
the papaya coming on the back yeah
there's like a tropical smoothie got
lucky with that mix I will say that and
so that's a the second best hash in
California right now guys
and you got a trophy for that right yes
sir yes I did I'll show that to you in a
sec you can heat me up um that yeah and
who made the trophy
JD maple s'en I hope I'm saying that
correct he's been making trophy all he's
been doing glass for quite some time he
has made trophies for the Emerald cup I
believe he did the trophies last year
for the ego clash he's definitely a
pretty coveted artist when it comes to
the scene and it's got a three-hole Bowl
yeah the old style of threw bubble hash
you need a three whole bowl ball it up
stick it in there and you use a glass
rod with the rounded kind of marble end
you heat that up and you just kind of
like hold it over press it in and kind
of dab away if you guys with good bubble
hash it's essentially oil and we tried
to hit it with a pipe it'll just turn to
oil and yep
thin membrane and just kind of melts
away to almost nothing and ru hand
stirring or using machines or a paint
stirrer I use machines and bubble
machines I don't really have time to
hand stir it takes takes some time and
obviously you get a great product with
using machines yeah you know I mean I
think you get just as good as a product
as you do with the hand stirring it just
maybe takes a little bit more time to
clean up here and there but it allows
you time while the machines are spinning
to do the other things you need well
like cleaning sanitizing prep work for
pulling the bags and getting everything
ready so that's kind of my reasoning
behind it I can't just justify standing
there for hours using an oar and hand
stirring hand
can't time is money exactly especially
when you grow your own material
you really got all the time in the world
and you got to spend a lot of it
processing and cleaning I'm just gonna
the term glorified janitor has been
tossed around yes 100%
I have to try some of this GMO because
it smells I don't know how you describe
that smell but it's very unique it's
very offensive off-putting almost that's
funky
real interesting flavor on this one I
don't even know how to describe it it's
just like a garlic and burnt rubber
maybe it's kind of offensive but it
reminds me of like the old school cat
piss almost there
you know something where you smell you
like oh that smells disgusting but I
need to smoke it yeah that's that's the
weird thing about weed definitely some
offensive flavors that you smell and
you're something you I want to smoke
that interesting
this second place trophy is that's a
beautiful piece of work with the
trichomes all up at all yeah that's a
nice marble you've worked a few more
twig wags fumed marble right there on
the front a really great job like I did
a really great job on those trophies I
love it man I grew up in Sonoma County
we have a lot of glass artists here a
lot of smoke shops growing up
I've always loved going in and just
looking at the glass even when I didn't
smoke even before when I was a kid and
younger you know before it was a lot
that you had to be 18 to go in you could
just kind of walk in and look at the
stuff and it's kind of hypnotizing all
the girls love them I'm always loved it
just the craftsmanship that is put into
it the pride they put it into it the
hours they put into hours they've
learned how exact mold their craft and
to make these beautiful pieces I mean it
takes definitely a lot of time and
dedication so it's cool to like smoke
your art out of someone else's art kinda
because it takes almost as much time to
really mess the glass community and the
hash community a very close-knit because
they're both forms of art and they're
always pushing each other they push each
other and they work with each other yeah
because they rely on each other exactly
yes they do well thank you for coming by
and showing us these amazing glass
pieces and this award-winning hash oh
yeah thank you so much for having me
hopefully I get to a smoke some more of
your product here in the near future
white pasty I'm sure you and you know
congratulations on the second place and
the ego clash that's a big one thank you
so much and next you'll take it for the
first I'm sure shooting I'm gonna find
some new flavors possibly make some new
flavors and really kind of just push it
well buddy thank you so much
Cheers
[Music]
[Applause]