[Music]
we're in a time where brands are talking
about like we're positioning ourselves
for the future and to me what that means
is brands have raised a ton of money and
are going after market share and kind of
thinking in the long term but the short
term that's not a very profitable
strategy and it has consequences to you
know smaller brands that haven't raised
a ton of money and so I kind of wanted
to take a snapshot in time you know
September 2019 kind of what are the
dynamics between brands and retailers
and what are you seeing from your
specific vantage point in the industry
so we have a retailer we have a SoCal
dominant brand but NorCal not so
dominant we have a small scrappy NorCal
craft Sun grown cannabis brand we have a
small scrappy SoCal distributor so kind
of I wanted to just start by each of you
kind of talking about what you're seeing
in that relationship between the limited
retail shelf space and the thousands of
brands fighting for that shelf space so
Mike Bosse from VCC brands why don't you
kick it off thank you my name is Mike
I'm with the fetish cookie company we
are a legacy brand we are based out of
Southern California
been in business for about the past
eleven years and we're facing tough
times just like everybody else since
regulation and there's many different
facets of what's going on right now and
I think a few of them could point
fingers towards hey retailers are making
it tough on us regulations making it
tough on us
everything that's happening with
industry is a rocking motion right now
and I think the people who are going to
persevere through this are the people
who are really here and passionate about
what they're doing right new folks
coming into the industry who might not
necessarily have a story but might see
the green of money might not last right
and I think it really comes down to
passion an Eric Pearson retail operator
I would dovetail the area and Sonoma
with I couldn't agree more and I think
it waits to patients right now there's
there's a mad dash with a lot of capital
to make a lot of money and to build a
brand that's gonna be sticky with
consumers and to do that when
everybody's doing that you have to burn
a lot of cash and that's that's only
sustainable for a certain amount of time
I think there's too much uncertainty in
the industry as it relates to
regulations expansion is not as easy as
it is with technology I think I use this
analogy a lot of the times the investors
in Canada and the early investors in
cannabis sort of equated this new
industry with the dot-com or technology
that came along and they kind of thought
well this is something that's explosive
and and therefore we should invest
because the returns are going to be huge
and then they realized that dokay you
have to get a permit to build a green
house and you have to grow the cannabis
in the crown of cannabis the first crop
doesn't do so well then oh shoot the
jars are here from China and and we have
to get you to track mitt oh the
retailers don't have a license and and
so it takes a whole lot longer then
investors wanted it wanted it too and so
you have this
massive amount of cash coming in to this
economy and here in California is it's
that's the state to take and everybody's
competing for that shelf space so you're
selling your company if you're if you're
running that race and you're trying to
be the biggest and the best right now
you're giving up a major part of your
company and the more you give away the
less interested you are and continue to
run that company so having a love and a
passion for what you're doing and
spending the amount of time that it's
taken to get this far
eleven years I've been as cookie company
has been here and if we were just
chatting about it and I've been up in
here since 98 so taking a step back you
know looking and realizing that this is
just a moment in time and things will
money will be lost and investors will go
away and things will settle down and
those who have brands that are authentic
and teams that are in it for the long
run they'll they'll come out winners
patients we've been cultivating for
about ten years in Sonoma County we
launched our tincture brand Fiddler's
greens about four years ago we've taken
a little bit different approach from a
lot of the brands who had an idea and
when raised a ton of money and expected
to just have tons of funds coming in we
actually have been focused on building
infrastructure and relationships and got
the first cultivation permit in Sonoma
County and
we have manufacturing in distro and have
just finished with our upgrades to our
facility and so now we're really looking
to launch as the industry is going I
think we've been fortunate because we
started small as prop 64 went into play
and so we're actually growing as the
licensed stores are growing so we're
just we're ready to take off as soon as
they start issuing some damn retail
licenses so cow distribution wrapping a
bunch of brands real quick I'm just out
of curiosity so I know like who's in the
house how many people here are
cultivators and manufacturers
distributors retailers how many people
yeah thank you labs I'm just kind of
curious I guess we have a little bit of
everyone here and for those of us that
have been around for more than a year um
I mean we all have different
perspectives but you go through a lot
you know we have the joke of cannabis
years like dog years and we all know
what that means
um yeah I think it's like a really
interesting time it's nuts it's chaotic
it changes constantly I have learned
that I don't know what's gonna happen
next I mean I've seen the tables turn
time and time again I've seen the people
on top fall to the bottom I've seen like
you know the the crowning of you know
who's on top of the hill change and I
think that it's all up for grabs
Wow there's there's actually a lot and I
try to refrain from like really talking
about other brands too much especially
when it's like who was on top and now
they're not that's not you know I'd
rather big someone up but I would say
that it's extremely competitive and I
think that there's a number of ways to
compete and I like this panel it's cool
because I think we're all like kind of
the scrappers as you almost introduced
us as
and I think that those people have an
advantage like I you know there's an
advantage to everything if you if you
have huge capital there's great
advantages to that right like you have a
problem throw money at it you can no
potentially overcome it and there's a
lot of people that can't compete with
that
but what those brands can't compete with
is the ground-up approach which I've
always been a fan of and I think the
people that are kind of grassroots that
have a true passion for this that have
paid some dues that have kind of worked
and paved their own way forward we have
a great advantage because we went
through it we know things firsthand and
we actually know things we're not just
speculating from you know Instagram blog
posts that we've read and whatnot and I
think that those people that have a lot
of money but are coming from outside are
often and we see this again left and
right but we see these people like
leaking money like crazy and if they're
backed enough then maybe they can
sustain and pull through but um yeah I
mean it's there's a number of ways to
compete I think you need to have the
full package to be honest I think you
need first and foremost we look at
people who's running the company who's
behind it you know you have to have good
products need a story I think and I
think one of the hardest parts and I'm
in distribution so I'm biased but I
think that the sales and distribution
may be the hardest piece of it all for
the people out there on the ground level
like pounding the pavement knocking on
doors and and the thing is is getting
into the shops is relatively easy I mean
it's it not it's the relative to the
rest of the journey right it's extremely
difficult everyone's laughing because if
you've ever tried to get into a cannabis
store it's extremely fucking difficult
but that's the easy part the more
difficult part is building that brand
and and self through and seeing those
reorders and then if you're a
distributor like we are I talk from that
perspective we kind of are extremely
selective with the brands that we are
align ourselves with and we represent
them like they're our own and I think
that's a mostly that's mostly a weakness
from
distributors from the feedback that I
hear I think that most distributors are
not out there repping your brand's if
you're a brand owner the way you would
write and and I think so that's that's
our strategy our strategy is to kind of
keep a relatively small menu of brands
that were passionate about so going back
to what was said before and just really
reppin it like it's our own and we put
our heart into it when we try to make
good decisions and we work with good
people and that you know that has helped
us survive this long and we'll see what
happens next well so getting back to the
fact that you're all kind of small and
food strapped in for me a concrete
example like in LA I went to visit a
bunch of dispensaries a couple weekends
ago and I went into urbe down on Pico
and basically they have a lot of shop in
shop where it's almost like you know
going into the Bloomingdale's perfume
and beauty section where each brand has
you know they're renting space they're
paying their own employees to show up so
when I went in there you know then I
left and I looked at their Yelp reviews
and kind of the common commentary was I
this is from consumers I went into this
dispensary and I wanted a pre-roll and I
walked down and everybody's trying to
sell me something that's not it because
it's basically all these brands so if
I'm a vape pen brand I don't care about
pre-roll as I care about vape pens and
I'm gonna try to sell you my products
and when I find out that you don't have
an interest in the vape pen you want a
pre-roll I lose complete the consumer
like the people writing the Yelp reviews
are like they just lost total interest
in me or they were still trying to push
the thing I told them I'm not interested
in like because that's what they're
trying to sell so from an end consumer
standpoint kind of some of the models
that are emerging are like they're
turning people off and and then how do
you compete against that those brands
that can afford
to hire a full-time employee to go into
multiple la shots multiple bay area
shops wherever you can't do that yeah we
definitely can't do that I mean our our
core product is teachers and topicals
which is I think like one or two percent
of the total sales we've only we've
actually because most of our patients
are our customers our medical patients
we haven't had a lot of pressure from
retailers about buying shelf space but
the handful of people that have reached
out to us they've wanted more in shelves
for shelf space than they do in revenue
for us each month and obviously that's
not a sustainable business model but
companies that are well financed are
actually doing that oh absolutely
you know we none of you will name names
you're at least acknowledging that this
is happening oh yeah absolutely this is
definitely happening and I mean we are
seeing the exact same thing as you guys
it's it's not a sustainable option it's
not a sustainable way of doing business
you know
venez cookie company has been in
business for the past 11 years off of
our own dime just recently we've gained
some investors which is fabulous but the
shelving space right we're being asked
for $2,000 a month and when it comes to
edibles the average ticket is $2,000 a
month right so why am I going to give a
retailer $2,000 a month when I'm not
going to be able to sell them that much
it just doesn't make good business sense
for us yeah no we're in the same boat
and I'm we're pushing back on those
folks and we're like we'll go across the
street and we'll deal with the
dispensary that wants to support local
brands that wants to support legacy
operators and we're going to send all of
our customers without shop but so
between the three of you what percentage
of shops that you're trying to get into
are like if you pay us a little bit of
money it's a pretty it also done I would
say it's training up and it depends on
the territory
different territories or some are more
likely to do that it's it's almost like
cultural so depending on the territory I
think you see a little bit more of that
in the valley interestingly enough um
and I would say it's it's still I don't
know I would say it's 20 percent under
20% of shops maybe but it's it's not
very few I mean there's a lot of them
charging for sale shelf space and some
of them like urbe you know just to get
back to that um no no I mean yeah I look
I'm not I did we said we do business
with herba right and we've done business
with her before a long time we've never
paid for a shelf space now we're not
gonna have the same presence there as
other brands so but but that's a store
that will allow if they believe in your
product they'll care you so you're gonna
have to out hustle everyone and that's
kind of the theme that we kind of live
by is just out hustle everyone to make
things happen so to give like a current
example are our main brand right now is
tikkun olam which is a very medicinal
brand it's an Israeli brand so a pretty
technical brand as far as like cannabis
brands go it's probably the most
technical and so we dedicate a lot of
time to train the staff and and stoke
them and that's part of what we do for
all of our brands is like make personal
connections with everyone get them to
understand whatever it is the brand
story is in this case there's a lot of
information that we can educate them
with but sometimes it's just a lifestyle
and it's like a vibe and but if you can
translate that vibe and you can really
touch you know those those staff the bud
tenders and whatnot and stoke them out
you know it helps when you have some
schwag or whatever but those are all
ways to play the game without playing
paying for shelf the shelving space in
certain stores other stores yeah some of
them charge of the serious ticket to 3
grand
sometimes more just to play just to get
in the store and sometimes it doesn't
make sense and for us the strategy 95%
of the time is we don't pay for shelf
space um some of the has
to do with us or our brand more often
than us but yeah we try to add value and
try to you know just present the value
of the brand and why it's a value to
them and their customers and if they
don't see that then we don't have a
problem keeping and moving and like you
said work with whoever's next door and
and pump it through there and yeah how
about things like trade samples and you
know introducing your brand's all the
but I mean things you could do a couple
years ago where you're introducing the
brand to all the bud tenders and giving
them samples and letting them appreciate
what you do which is a little more
costly now we're still trying to do that
I think it's very important for folks
that are representing our brand to have
used it to understand it our
distribution model is also very
education based and so before a
dispensary gets our gets the first
delivery from us we have one of our
account managers come in and do a
budtender training they talk to them
about a said it cannabinoids they talked
to them about what CBD is good for what
THC is good for so that it's not just a
conversation of oh yeah I've got this
you know dab that's ninety-nine percent
THC because that's not our customer our
customer is sick you know sick children
you know parents who have kids with
epilepsy it's grandparents you have
arthritis and things like that and so
the education side of it's super
important to us being on shelf space and
having educated by tenders who represent
us then in a way that communicates our
message and what we're trying to do I
think getting samples out into buyers
hands is extremely important and we've
transitioned from outside crews bringing
in samples to manifesting and drivers
delivering those samples and I think
it's going to evolve even more into
here's our non-activated product give
this non-activated product to try it
tastes just like darn activated product
right especially when it comes to
edibles is and not for joints
right it doesn't it doesn't work for
everyone for flowers and extract that
doesn't work for edibles that were it
works perfectly if you're pushing a
brand getting that brand to engage with
the staff whether it's the buyer or the
bud tenders anyone you can get with
that's critical it's critical it's
critical that you engage with on that
they can try the product because there's
so much more likely to sell it if
they've tried it it's worth every penny
I personally am a huge fan of investing
in the store I you know shelf space I
don't think has the best return on
investment but I think investing in the
store in terms of samples of hooking
them up with swag of your time and
effort the training the demos and just
stopping by being there in person I
again coming from a district I think the
brands are better at representing
themselves in doing the the work that I
think like it takes to get through to
stores and actually promote their brand
than most distributors and that's just
going by most of what I hear you guys
maybe have had other experiences but um
spending time in person in those stores
whether it's with a sample or a piece of
schwag or it's just your time you just I
mean people appreciate people also
connect with people and if you take the
time to hear someone out and and you're
not just there to kind of like some kind
of quickie and then how thing then
you're gonna build a relationship
they're gonna like you they're gonna get
to know the brand and they're gonna be
more likely to support the brand so I
can't agree with you more I think it's
it's all about a partnership and that's
what I preach to everyone at the fenders
cookie company it's a partnership we
need to start a partnership right and
what is selling to somebody without
being partners to them when you walk
into a store and they say the only way
that you can get on our shelves is by
you paying us two thousand dollars this
month and every month after this that's
not a partnership that is a shakedown
you know that's my opinion yes
I agree Eric retailer as a retailer you
know as a retailer the bond between the
retailer and the consumer is very
important and to what all you said is
when you walk in and what you initially
initially started with Peter is when you
walk in and you've given up your
retailer to brands just representing
themselves where shelf space is sold so
we were walking in looking for a joint
and you're going passivate you know
cartridge and you're and you're losing
that connection with a customer I don't
think that's a long-term strategy for a
retailer I think you're gonna see brands
come and go through there so having that
as a retailer you know it this
dispensaries are very interesting
because this is not normal retail right
you know we go to pharmacies like this
but we also just go to pharmacies which
are closest to our homes you know and we
everything else we buy is through online
or a very sort of what I call I guess a
horizontal approach to retail to where
you just you go to the closest place
that you can shop and you buy things but
with dispensaries it's similar you you
you go to the closest dispenser you can
get to that but you develop a
relationship with with that organization
and it's I lost my train of thought so
fit
but I think the important the important
thing is when you're selling your store
to someone else in order to make those
sales then you're losing that connection
with with the customer so yeah and I
think this is I don't know if I am
around enough in the Bay Area but I know
we don't sell shelf space I don't think
we sell at our five stores and I hear
about it up to $20,000 per month for
some of these brands in Southern
California
and you know you don't you don't connect
and the customers that we have
we're vertical so we're a little bit
different than the average retailer that
says I've got a prime location you know
I know I'm going to have these customers
coming in so as what we do is we sell
our own products right and we have that
relationship with the customer and
honestly we'll have the big brands
because people will come in and say I
want being chocolate or all when Kia or
whatever it is and we'll take them over
to our brands we'll say yeah we have
those but we also grow our flowers over
here we make these products ourselves
and we want you to buy these that's our
approach traditional retail markup is I
sell you something for a ten and you
sell it out the door for twenty and it
seems like in the cannabis industry
sometimes you're it's being sold out at
the door for 30 so what are you all seen
like as brands what do you sell
something into a retailer what are you
seeing them mark it up by BPI where I'm
coming from is consumers and patients or
the like unrepresented group here from a
price point they're not happy and
obviously some of its taxes but some of
it is like I'm trying to understand why
sometimes stuffs marked up more than
traditional retail so I'm not sure what
you guys do and I would say that 65 70
percent of our customers do a 3x markup
on edibles and a 3x our markup on
edibles is really tough to them
consumers and not only is it tough to
them consumers but in my opinion the
retailer's aren't going to see that
volume of sales from those and from
those end consumers because of that 3x
markup and I would agree with you that
the end consumers are looking for less
expensive products that's why we can see
them going to the
illicit market right now and if maybe
you can help in lameness I'm not sure
what you guys do but generally speaking
over the retail market why is it that we
are finding that there is a 3x markup
right now I think it's location you know
back to whatever is the most convenient
store to go to a lot of folks will just
go to the most convenient store I think
on average most of our stuff is 2x we're
in a market that's fairly competitive in
San Francisco and probably very
competitive we have a lot of delivery
companies E's and their partners you
know have a lot of larger companies I
have a lot more capital to burn to gain
market share if in theory I think if
folks are charging 3 X's because they
can get it you know they're in a limited
market they've got the foot traffic but
if you're in a competitive market you
know you can't do that well I hope Erik
out hit a little bit here I think part
of it too has also been with the
segmentation of the industry a few
during prop 215 days retailers were able
to package they were able to do some
things and take some cogs write-offs on
their taxes and with the way the
industry set up now retailers are almost
paying like taxes on their gross sales
they don't get to take those cogs
write-offs anymore and III think that
has a lot to do with it and also the
fact that just trying to justify
competing with the black market so we've
created the situation where we've priced
ourselves out of being competitive so
now we have to charge more to justify
being here and it just it's created a
vicious cycle the only business partner
any of us have making money right now is
the state of California I think they're
losing too when you're dealing with
brands what I mean what are some of your
frustrations
I guess well I don't deal with them
directly when you're
it's that guy over there right so when
that guy bitches to you what is what is
he bitching about I can't say I get not
a lot really does he does he complain
about friends complaining about that you
I know I've because it's consistent
everywhere it's constant unreliability
right it's people saying they're gonna
do things they don't do them they're
unavailable you hit them up you don't
get hit back right away you get orders
for stuff you didn't pay for you didn't
order what else there's 1,300
manufacturers and 700 retailers that
might be part of the problem they're
wearing 10 hats instead of two or three
half most of them are maybe underpaid
yeah they're overwhelmed with so many
people like just trying to get their
attention and man there's so many things
how right am I how many buyers do we
have in the house savvy other what
metrics a VI metric I think they're all
being forced to be I think if I'm not
mistaken like most retailers either just
did or in the middle of or are are
imminently having to you know apply like
get in on the metric so I think right so
all right so down the line what kind of
metric nightmares
are you having at night well we've
strategically stayed away from metric we
don't we have our provisional for for a
while
we don't legally need to be on metric
we're grateful to just let it like buy
something we have some time and and
we're gonna hopefully let metric and the
rest of the fucking industry get their
shit together because it's a shit show
like trying to deal with metric we hear
the nightmares left and right and they
call in and metric doesn't even know
what's going on they don't know how to
do things you're bringing up I mean this
is what we're hearing from retail
and other brands and stuff so for now
we're our strategy is to stay away from
metric so as a distributor you have that
luxury for now because I don't think
we're now let's have that like for this
part and I'm not gonna lie yeah I think
buyers are having two challenges one now
right now well first is 1,300
manufacturers knocking at their door
right that that's that's one of the
major problems is that they're
overwhelmed with the amount of brands
that are coming knocking at the door and
and who did they buy from right and
who's going to perform the best and I
think the second most major challenge
that's happening currently with buyers
are metric and metric is being put on to
these buyers to be able to operate on
and so this is a learning curve for the
buyers that they now have metric that
they have to deal with and I think that
there is gonna come a time and I really
hope not but I think there's gonna come
a time where buyers are gonna say are
you on they already have asked me are
you on metric and the answer is yes
right and if the answer is no they're
gonna say I don't know if I really want
to work with you right now right it's
here it's here what's happening
understand be nice yeah I'm not gonna
lie I come from the software industry
I'm actually pretty excited about metric
it's been pretty painless for us to
implement does your husband thank you
enough my husband track
[Laughter]
all right so Eric you you you have a Bay
Area shop and you have a were in Santa
Rosa you have a shop how far away from
here yeah we do all kinds of stuff
that's why I don't have the answers to
these things so we're yeah we're
vertical so we have we have a we farm
and Glenallen and we manufacture in
Santa Rosa and we have stores three
stores in San Francisco one in Santa
Rosa one and one in Sebastopol okay so
Sebastopol so talk about the economic
decision making there are a lot of local
brands mm-hm and so I guess my question
is in your local retail operation are
you proactively featuring local brands
and have-nots what are kind of the
business decisions you're going through
to decide that it's just not feasible
yeah most most brands we feature are
from Northern California so I'd say
local unfortunately Sonoma there's not a
whole lot of brands because of the
regulatory kind of difficulties within
the county you have one city next few
champions do you carry her brand no
Shawn do we carry Pilar's not yet what
why not have you been pitched by them
why I don't know I I mean I I do like
I'm I do a lot of stuff but but retail
is not my focus okay I probably should
that's Shawn up here talking about
retail be partially your question what
was the first part well it's basically
like what are the economic airy the
amazing craft sun-grown
regenerative hugo culture or local well
yeah okay so well smart first honestly
we will we will sell everything that we
produce and manufacture first that that
is ultimately our objective that's as
the reach as a vertical retailer I think
I think the further south you go the
more larger brands that are coming and
going I don't see that the revolving
door up north and we've been around for
a long time
and a lot of the brands that we have on
this shelf continue and have been around
for a while and I I'm not experiencing
the disruption I think that a lot of
retailers in Southern California are I
think we have a lot of consistency with
her brands from from Northern California
answer the question do you have
something to say back to that what Shh
where's our buyer I'm honestly I'm gonna
give Eric a pass on this one too because
Northern California markets tough
because San Francisco Sonoma County are
a short drive from the triangle and this
is the belly of the beast us being in
the industry ten years we're a new brand
in Northern California and we spend a
little time banging our heads trying to
get into some local shops and we were
competing with people that have been
there for five or ten years before us
and been consistent so our strategy
after being in our head for a couple of
months was we're going south and we're
taking Northern California to Southern
California and we've been crushing LA
we've been crushing the desert we've
been crushing San Diego and you know I I
hope that that that the tables turn
because I think we're one of the few
survivors I think you know there's a
handful of legacy brands that are still
standing and I'm proud to say we're one
of them and it's a bunch of badass
people that are in this room right now
that bleed for this company every day
and you know I hope that we start
getting that recognition in our local
market but I understand how we got where
we are I just I would love to see a
change so Eric what's your what's his
name these guys Shawn you better run my
sharks are here all right so just
quickly wrapping it up if each of just
down the line of each of you can talk
about a a regulation that is a pain
point for you and companies like you and
which regulatory agency is responsible
for that and what your better regulatory
policy
is towards that specific piece of
regulation I think the biggest thing
that's holding back this entire industry
right now is two things I can't answer
with one I think it's two things I think
it's the over taxation of excise tax and
I think it is local ordinances who are
not allowing more dispensaries to be put
into their areas right there's 700
licensed retailers some odd licensed
retailers in the state of California
that's just plain and simple not enough
and there needs to be it can't be one
approach of oh well let's just bring the
tax down or oh let's just add more
retailers it needs to be multifaceted
and I think it is reduce that tax add
more retailers free the cookie I would
agree with I'll just add some other
challenges I know Northern California
faces and in here in Sonoma County as it
relates to cultivators I think what's a
real problem it's really going to
destroy what our industry is if hasn't
destroyed a lot of it and that is the
environmental regulations around
cannabis and the way cannabis has been
treated differently than agriculture I
think you know four years ago we thought
Humboldt was going to in Mendocino was
going to own that the cultivation for
the state and and it's not you know I
don't see heading that way I see the
cultivation heading down into the valley
to large large industrial greenhouse
facilities that's where as most of us
going to end up and I think that's an
unfortunate thing an unfortunate
situation or result of the way we've
regulated we've approached cannabis as a
nuclear factory instead of a plant that
it is and we're seeing a lot of you know
every grower I know is north of
California north of San Francisco is
back to the black market it's
fascinating how it affects you know the
prices and the black market versus that
the legal market but I think that's the
that's one of the regulations that's
caused the most amount of
and destruction to the industry that we
that we had and the people that created
it I would agree with everything both of
these gentlemen said one of the other
things it's really crippling us right
now is that my salespeople cannot carry
samples and drop them off after they
have a great appointment with a buyer it
takes two three four days to place an
order manifest a product package it up
ship it and get it to a purchaser and by
then they've seen 30 40 50 a hundred
other purchasers and they don't remember
why the hell they got this box product I
think that's one of the biggest things
we need to be able to solve is having
salespeople account managers hand a
product to a buyer say here try this
hand it to your staff I'll talk to you
next week yeah I I agree with everything
I was said if there's something to add I
think writing off of cost of goods sold
is probably gonna help with some of us
operate and in the regulation the actual
enforcement of regulations is one thing
that I don't think I heard directly
address but yeah more licensed
storefronts lower the taxes actually
enforce the regulations on the people
who are not abiding and and give those
people a path people that have been
doing this for 10 20 30 years give him a
fucking permit
do you bring up a really good point
there's there's what I believe that an
article came out saying there's 2,100
illicit stores in the state of
California so it's just a way mostly in
Southern California but the problem is
is some of these guys are bad players
and they shouldn't be in our industry
but I think the majority of them need
help and need a path and don't have the
money or the cash flow necessary to be
able to become legal and I think it's
very important to help them out any
peanut gallery comments the woman in the
back row
haha oh well I mean we're heading to a
metrics inevitable right we're just
holding on until we absolutely have to
and we see it in our very near future
it's just I mean we're gonna be bringing
our metrics sooner than later it's just
a luxury that we have at this moment and
yeah we we we haven't had a single
retailer turn us down but 100 percent
that conversation is coming up and we
see it right there it's not like we're
gonna try to avoid metric it's
inevitable right and we're not maybe we
don't even know all that when you have
to be scared of I mean it's just for us
it's like it's an inconvenience that we
could potentially postpone just a little
bit longer and and hopefully in that
time a few things I mean one thing that
I think we've all learned is like the
people that are kind of innovators and
or or doing things first are paying a
huge cost to do it you know what I mean
and that's not just financially and then
you occasionally I mean in really the
pioneers or the people who built this
industry who are not me these are people
that have been here you know for a
decade or three or more the work that
those people did that paved the road
that we get to travel down I mean what a
luxury we have right and so you know and
I am grateful to those people and I want
to express my gratitude to those people
but those people don't get you know they
don't really get like the any benefit
from what they did they did the hard
work and so I'm just not quick to be
like oh yeah let's be the first ones
there I mean it would be cool and I
think there's advantages to it um but
there's also disadvantages and in my
experience in this industry is is like
play like on the fringe of what you can
get away with without crossing the line
liking you know don't you don't risk
your whole business or license up but
like the people who win are playing some
sort of a gray area and most of them are
playing a much greater than what we're
doing but that's that's the real
ecology of of you know all's anybody
disagree with that statement I do I
absolutely do there for us there's no
gray area anymore and it's completely
black and white to us because but you
disagree that a lot of companies are
planning ray areas oh no I think a lot
of companies are planning the best that
are following the letter of the law or P
being penalized for sure so just last
question as to you Fiddler's high tide
and you socal entering NorCal all right
do you see any nuance differences
between dealing with SoCal retailers and
NorCal retailers or like obviously there
are more than two markets it's two it's
two different animals the NorCal market
is completely different than the
Southern California market you brought
up the fact that like the bay area is
the Beast of the belly and in fact
really is it's definitely been one of
the hardest markets for us to penetrate
and we have been around for a long time
right and we have a large Southern
California following and perhaps maybe
that large Southern California following
and perhaps that Southern California
home base puts us at a disadvantage when
we're talking to Northern California
buyers and that that's what I see all
right well thank you all very much and
thank you to the whiskey tip for having
us and we're gonna have some music
outside then there's karaoke inside
[Applause]