the co founder CEO president of alt
Indus Holdings that is an IP company
that actually holds the IP for Dixie
California along with Iran all ty based
in Monterey California Salinas Valley
you know we started looking at this
about two years ago really hardcore
about a year ago we got into this to
create a brand an edible brand on the
market that can be trusted that was
about transparency low-dose
single-serving and and really have a
product that everybody knew when you had
this product that you'd have the same
experience time after time we met Dixie
kind of in the research as we were
looking at all tie and how we are
launching our own brand trip and Chuck
and I met in in Las Vegas actually with
a business partner of mine had met trip
before introduced us and we just hit it
off we were so like-minded in the way
that we want to look to continue to
elevate this industry and to continue to
bring legitimacy and transparency and
safety to this industry and so that's
kind of where the conversation started
with Dixie probably about six nine
months after we started down the road
with all Thai and we ended up launching
both brands at the same time both Dixie
and all tie and it was a great synergy
Dixie's been in the industry for five
years they've gone through a lot of the
ups and downs the different regulations
and in Colorado they have the ability to
have science on property and in their
science department is unbelievable to
where we were able to benefit from that
we're in California we can't really get
into the extraction process and some of
that science where we had that
experience with them and then my
business partner Mark Ainsworth two
heads because you're not we're not
allowed to correct extraction is still
an issue here in California and so
having the plant materials legal having
the oil is legal the process of making
it from plant material into the oil is
still considered illegal here in
California now with 266 that's changing
and they'll actually be
an area there that's written into the
bill that that highlights extraction and
perm and you can actually get a permit
for either in volatile or volatile
extraction processes but so that's
really kind of where where the things
came through mark Ainsworth use my other
business partner works for he had his
own manufacturing facility where he
produced for Whole Foods nationally for
the last eight years he was a pastry
chef for ritz-carlton for eight years so
we understood understood food science
and quality and shelf life and that's
where you know really got us excited
about coming into this industry also is
that a lot of the the products out there
were people that were in the cannabis
industry that maybe didn't have any
experience in in actual food
manufacturing and understanding food
science and shelf life and safety
mechanisms to where you know we had all
of that and we use cannabis as an
ingredient in our products so oil is the
cannabis oil is just another ingredient
so we look to create a product that
could stand up on Whole Foods or in any
gourmet shop on its own and then look to
infuse the oil to make sure that we have
the medicine for the people here in
California there's no reason medicine
needs to taste bad you know we we looked
at really going into the low dose of 10
milligrams and 25 milligrams are the
only two serving sizes that we have our
belief is that that's where the where
the market is going to go he wants to
take a 500 milligram cookie and break it
into 10 pieces and have guessed work of
how much am i having what is you know
last time I you know I had a good
experience this time I gonna have a bad
experience what how much medication am I
really getting all of our stuff is
triple tested so when we tell you it's
ten milligrams or 25 milligrams it's
really 10 milligrams or 25 milligrams of
active THC and so we feel that's really
the future on a lot of things as as you
look at California Colorado and their
regulations it's all now it has to be 10
milligrams serving size maximum of 100
milligrams proportion or per container
you know it really leads to making sure
with the safety aspect and as people get
into it to understand you know when you
talk to a lot of people these days they
talk about how edibles they're excited
they like it but they're still unsure on
how to actually
medicate with edibles what is the
appropriate dose how am i how do I know
and there's really a lack of education
out there on some of this and that's
what we're really trying to push is the
education level that consistency level
that people can really understand and
and know what to expect every single day
every single time they have it as we
looked into licensing a product here
into California like Dixie you know it
was it was one of those opportunities to
as we jumped into this market to have
somebody that had a lot more experience
than us and knowledge into things and
and to be able to benefit from that so
when we started talking with Chuck and
trip on the licensing things and being
able to feel comfortable sharing
information we're going you know latest
like you guys are starting your own
edible company anything else we're going
to share our recipes and our process and
the science behind it and we quickly you
know we worked through a lot of that
stuff because we had the experience in
food science and manufacturing which
week we could also lend to Dixie and
really help elevate each other's brands
where they're really strong we were a
little weaker where they were a little
weaker worse we were we had we had some
more expertise and so we're very big i
come from the restaurant industry where
restaurants the camaraderie between
chefs and restaurant tours we constantly
help each other out we loaned the
neighbor restaurant a bottle of vodka if
they run out or you know i just ran out
of sugar you run next door to your
neighbor restaurant and they loan it to
you you know there's not a lot of that
camaraderie in this business and we're
really starting to see that to where
like-minded individuals like-minded
brands can can really help each other
there's plenty of room on the shelves
for multiple brands that that are all
doing it in the right way so that we can
bring transparency and we can bring
safety and we can bring expectations
into this industry the industry with in
terms of camaraderie has as definitely
some room to grow and as we can all get
together and share trade secrets and
different things on how we do things
it's going to be great for the industry
and that's where i think that there's a
lot of like-minded people that are
starting to see that and come together
and say there's plenty of shelf space
there for the best in class
that that will help elevate this
industry that will help move the the
movement will help with legislation and
be part of it versus fight the system
and that's that's a big part of what we
want to do we are very open we have a
15,000 square foot manufacturing
facility in Salinas we have we have a
license business license actually States
cannabis infused products we've invited
we've had congressmen senators police
chiefs FBI all walk our facility torrid
other competition we've opened our doors
to everybody else to say listen it's an
open book let's let's get together and
make sure that we're all doing this in
the right manner so that we can elevate
this business and we can stand on this
on the steps of Congress or the Senate
and say listen we pay our taxes we're in
childproof packaging we do everything to
be a legitimate business and to continue
to give patients you know the medication
they need or in other states like
Colorado and stuff adults that are over
21 years of age an alternative to a way
to unwind at the end of a day's work or
to relax or to medicate in a way that
they see fit licensing in the cannabis
industry is always a very interesting
you know a pathway because there's so
many things that the federal government
still doesn't recognize contracts really
in the cannabis industry so you really
have the rights as was going to stand up
in court if you're going to do if it
ever came to that so it's really about
doing business deals with people that
you trust and like and you know I always
joke life's too short to be in business
people you don't enjoy being in business
with or working with and so that was one
of the great things with Dixie and all
thi is that we have the same mindset the
same goals long term with elevating this
industry you know but it's interesting
because we want to share ideas and share
product but you can't go across state
lines because they're federally
regulated and so you have to be able to
come up with systems where you know our
packaging comes from Colorado for Dixie
but we manufacture everything in
California so we buy all local
ingredients from California all
accustomed to their recipes and in touch
with that all of the cannabis and the
oil comes from Monterey County in santa
cruz county all the test results are
here in California so it's really
looking at how you build out markets and
being able to trust your brand because
as we all know your brand is everything
and to be able to sit down with
individuals and say listen here's my
baby that I've nurtured for five years
and we've created this amazing thing and
you know in the area of Dixie where
they've spent five years and built this
brand in Colorado that's so recognized
and to be able to turn that over you
know to us here in California know that
we will we'll treat that brand just as
they will in Colorado and to make sure
that the safety and the aspects and all
the manufacturing and science and
everything they put into their bars and
their products that will maintain that
quality standards you know it's great
with the licensing deal too and the
relationship that we have with Dixie as
we look at the markets the difference
between Colorado and California ologies
they are very vast you know California
has had a cannabis movement for over 20
years Colorado you know as much as they
passed us with their recreational or
adult use hace California was way ahead
of them and obviously the culture you
know with the growers everything that we
have here in California so we spend a
lot of time with Dixie whether we're in
Colorado where they come here and our
facility as we start to tweak recipes to
make sure you know there's no humidity
in Colorado or very little compared to
California and so recipes have to be
tweaked for that also making things at
7,000 feet elevation vs sea level all of
these things are taken into effect as we
build out recipes and product lines here
in California again you have a lot of
areas where people have been utilizing
the product for a long period of time
they're looking for higher dose so we've
taken things like the toasted rooster
that was 84 milligrams in Colorado and
it's 180 milligrams here now again it's
it's scored for 15 milligrams per square
I think when anybody looks at doing a
licensing deal with another company is
really do your research look at the
brand understand if you're your core
concepts your core values are aligned
and also do you like the individuals
that you're doing business with because
hopefully it's going to be a long-term
deal I would always stay away from
short-term things putting your toe in
the water
you don't want to go out and build some
of these brand put bring everything into
a bunch of entries and then walk away
from that in the year so always looking
for long-term relationships and do your
research really dive into things
understand what is the what is the the
consumers feeling about this brand what
is the industry's feeling about this
brand and to make sure that when you
when you go into a partnership like this
you're bringing the right brand the
right values the right package and
product to fill a void in your market in
the edible market you're going to see a
lot of growth over the next few years as
you've seen in the last year I mean the
the markets I think quadrupled in the
edibles when you talk to Steve DeAngelo
and harborside edibles used to make up
this tiny little portion of the
Harborside in a corner two years ago and
now it has primetime space right in the
middle as they're seeing consumers
continuing to move towards that if they
especially here in California where
smoking people are so sensitive to
smoking for smoking flower edible seems
like it's it's it's not this illegal
thing right it's hate popping a piece of
milk chocolate or a bonbon doesn't feel
illegal but it gives me the medication
it gives me the relaxation that the
feeling that I'm looking for in a way
that I am NOT you know publicly out
there smoking or
and you know any other ways you're
looking to ingest the the product I
think it's you know beverages are
definitely an area Dixie elixir in
Colorado I mean it's more than fifty
percent of their revenues is their lick
sirs and their sodas it's definitely a
popular area to go again for people who
don't drink and to be able to go out and
and be able to be social with people
these days and be able to have their
their soda their medicine their thing
that's equal to a glass of wine or a
beer and have a Dixie one which is you
know 10 milligrams it's pretty much
equivalent to a glass of wine or a mixed
cocktail and be able to be social like
that in the in that marketplace so I
think you're going to see continued more
low dose items more regulation where you
actually know what's in the product
everything's tested versus being Saran
wrapped with a sticker on it or
something like that to where regulations
going you know regulations and good
things in different areas to keep people
safe so tamper-proof packaging it's
definitely going to be a big area that
you're going to see things moving down
and again low doses people start to
experiment back into this industry and
understanding what their comfort level
is and to be able to be social and just
be able to take the edge off as we've
jumped into this industry it's been
interesting it's been a year in the
works we've actually had product on the
shelves now for only eight weeks both
all tie and Dixie and we continue to
grow the team we have 10 sales reps
throughout California that that build
out everything and visit all the
dispensaries we have a manufacturing
team right now of about 15 people that
work you know monday through friday our
plants 15,000 square feet it's all
automated so we have the ability to
really ramp up and and look towards that
ramp of you know november 2016 when most
of us here think that california will go
adult use that will go into effect most
likely in january of 18 but really
ramping up for that and so as we see
that will need to really build the
manufacturing side out and make sure
that we can handle
the the new influx of people that are
very interested in the industry and
looking to try a different alternative
when it comes to you know social being
social