all right we're on like day ten of
lockdown
I haven't taken a shower today or
yesterday or brush my teeth yet today
and it's afternoon but to keep me happy
and not going stir-crazy some companies
have been sending me some products to
review so we have actually said this is
the very first pipe I ever smoked out of
when I was about I don't know nine or
ten years old the prototype Richard
Jorgensen sent us down so thank you
Richard very much I'm excited to play
with this which I haven't smoked out of
in a long time and then also back in
those days be Patti the one hitter was
big and riot sent me not one so here's
the would one but two values this is the
more advanced one but anyway what I
wanted to focus on today was the dry
herb vaporizer from riot so let's turn
this thing on it's called the verb okay
there we go
all right I don't know what did it maybe
it's the fours we're gonna be smoking
Josh D gave me some OG Kush so we will
what's this gonna light up to 190 202
and it's fast I get you ready let's be
quick okay
so this thing still heating out
for huh my let's put the top on for haha
for 20 very funny
probably hotter than I'd want to go but
let's start there that's tasty a little
hot and it comes with this poker that
there's the poker okay it works
ergonomic lightweight it's small not too
small not too big easy to use let me
just bring it down let's go down to
about like three it's kind of like 380
so different terpenes boil off a
different or in cannabinoids at
different temperatures
a little nicer so what you could do is
probably start down at like 320 and work
your way up with each hit so you're
hitting different terpenes along the way
and cannabinoids I like it
super easy it's literally the first time
I ever hit this so anyway we'll come
back and we'll go through the dugouts
batty dugout proto plate
we also have a cantor guard roller from
Purple Rose so we will make a can of
guard we need some fresh needs very cute
turning off alright anyway we'll make
some Kanna gars we'll have some fun boys
and girls anyway we'll be back they
saved