[Music]
you know one of the things that I'm
always curious is really around the
market size right particularly around
delivery I think we've got a pretty good
handle on at least what we believe the
size of the market for our storefront is
but you know but what do you think the
the size of the you know greater
Sacramento area
you know delivery market is I know so
I'm not the only reason I jumped into
Oakland was because that was the easiest
place to get licensing but I'm a lot
more familiar with the Sacramento market
I think on weed maps horrible topic to
bring up and home weed masturbate on
weed Maps beginning of the year there
was about 140 150 delivery services and
they were all thriving and operating in
an equilibrium but now we're legal ones
they were definitely not legal but they
were they were thriving operating but
now we have in the city of Sacramento I
think 70 applicants right correct we
have seven of the applications for non
storefront delivery right now so I think
that it would be reasonable to say that
we can we can sustain another 70 to get
back to that level of equilibrium at
about 140 to 150 operators and have fair
market share for each each operator do
you think it's is how large is is the
size of the of the retail delivery
market relative to storefronts do you
think is it is it 25% is it half I've
heard numbers all the way from half down
to a very specific 12% man anybody that
has a very specific percent like that is
really watching their analytics but I
would say I would say it's about half
the market just because every every
delivery driver can only complete so
many deliveries in a day versus a
storefront can take in an unlimited
amount of foot traffic so they have they
have that advantage there so it's you
know just just in my experience and I
I actually had a dispensary in LA as
well previously to have him that's why I
moved into delivery was because the
market was so saturated down here and I
would say it's a roughly 50% the
business that you're able to conduct
with the storefront compared to delivery
Sacramento has been on the forefront of
the industry as a whole since January 1
they've really tried to push the
envelope and make make a lot happen
beforehand and be one of the cities that
was out in front of the problem to be a
pioneer for for other cities to use as
an example Joe would be a lot more
familiar with with the trials and
tribulations that have come with that
cuz I know there's been a lot of
victories but then he also comes to
blame when things don't go right so ii
was definitely not berkeley you know and
i I love I love Berkeley I love the Bay
Area but Sacramento is you know always
been much more you know moderate and all
of its politics relative to the coastal
cities I mean we are a Central Valley
City I think were we what we have been
is just is very pragmatic and realistic
about cannabis I think the council and
mayor showed early leadership on a
complicated subject and at that moment
at least politically when they really
acknowledged that you know what we have
cannabis in their community the last 30
years of prohibitions and enforcement on
and the war on drugs did nothing to
remove cannabis from our community and
so let's try something different and you
know the people were collecting
signatures and they were gonna they were
gonna put this bowel initiative on the
on the ballot and you know and we saw
that coming and and we had conversations
with like okay we think this thing is
going to qualify for the bout and if it
gets on we're pretty sure this time
around it's gonna pass and so we took
steps early on to proactively develop a
regulatory framework that wasn't wasn't
easy
there are a lot of internal battles
around you know what do we need to do in
order to prepare for that and you know
where does this you know where does this
permitting Authority need to you know
even live within the city and there are
still you know small battles every day
around you know how do we how do we do
this and how do we do this better so
after the district six cap was
implemented do you see that rolling out
across all the other districts do you
see that impeding us in the city of
Sacramento as operators reaching that
150 target market where we once we're at
I don't were worried where I actually
see this potentially going is and and
someone might have my head for this but
look as I think as we gain more
experiences I think we can have more
informed conversations around what is a
rational reasonable policy and maybe the
two and a half million square foot cap
that we have currently in Council
District six
stays forever maybe after some of those
come online and a lot of it is
distribution that maybe shouldn't be
applied towards that cap maybe we should
have that conversation about pulling out
distribution and you know maybe there's
a conversation we had around lifting
that cap around you know after we have
some more data on what those impacts
potentially are you know one of the
things that we well we have a cap we
don't have we don't have to now familiar
square feet of applications yeah and so
there's still some property speculation
I guess within that part of the market
and so I think it's going to take a
little bit of time to figure out but I
think as we get more data we'll have
more informed conversations policy is
released
it's gonna be never-ending I mean this
is pretty much the you know attorney
full Employment Act so you know I think
like everything else Candice related
it's gonna be an evolution I was
surprised to hear that from Lori earlier
to talking about the regulations
everybody was under the assumption this
was it after these final edits and she
said this is gonna be an evolving
process over the next coming years this
may very well not be it so I can I can
imagine on the city level it's gonna be
the same as well
absolutely you know the the realities is
that this industry is going to continue
to innovate much quicker than anyone can
regulate and so industry is going to get
out in front of regulation you know call
it a loophole whatever you want to call
it but they're going to innovate to meet
customer and consumer demands and
regulation by nature is going to be you
know behind that innovation and so we're
gonna have to continuously adopt what we
do and how we do it if we're ever gonna
I think help this help the consumer
transition into that legal space as well
as helping the cannabis businesses
himself trans transition into that legal
space do you think on-site consumption
is on the menu for the city of
Sacramento coming soon I don't know
about soon I think we're gonna have that
conversation beginning early next year
we're going to start it at the policy
committee and in the city it's you know
we'll see where it goes I think this is
anti consumption is is going to be
really where each community is going to
have to really kind of dig deep and and
and make some you know big choices
around around what that looks like
in their community
I think between the on-site consumption
that's possible with dispensaries and
now these special events that can take
place outside of County Fairgrounds
on-site consumption is going to look
very different in again probably in a
short period of time in different cities
San Francisco has an absolute need to
have a very robust conversation around
on-site consumption in places other than
other than you know this handful of
dispensaries they have so many people
that come to that city every day that
stay in hotels and Airbnb s
and some percentage of those folks smoke
cannabis and so in addition to the
population there that smokes cannabis
I've heard that some people smoke
cannabis in San Francisco you know so
they're gonna have to have that
conversation you know do they do they
allow a lot of these events to take
place in you know Golden Gate Park I
think the other piece that's interesting
as it relates to on-site consumption is
you know is there a conversation we had
around designated consumption areas so
it's not that consumption can only take
place at a dispensary but it's the
proverbial yoga studio I get an email
week from a yoga studio hey can we smoke
before class you know is the answer but
you know is there a way where that could
be done you know safely and respectfully
to the community around it you know and
then cities you know that are you know
very dense can have those conversations
like okay we've got a thousand people a
day smoking cannabis in this park
do we want to acknowledge that that's
happening you know and and put some kind
of you know framework around it around
how we would like it to happen you know
otherwise you're looking at you know
really just rules that you're not
enforcing and I don't
that does anybody any good at speaking
to temporary events so in the interim
while the city wraps its mind around the
discussion of on-site consumption is
there a possibility for temporary events
to occur in Sacramento 4 and an
allowable on-site consumption for those
temporary events or is that something
the city is going to hold off on until
on-site consumption is completely ironed
out as a whole no we're gonna i'm very
intentionally trying to bifurcate those
those two issues i think that they are
well related though can the conversation
on on-site consumption is incredibly
more complicated and political so we're
gonna be moving forward with an
ordinance to allow what would
essentially allow the city manager to
approve special events that would take
place at a County fairground and then
and then I think if the early part of
next year will address the the new state
bill that would potentially allow us to
have special events at places outside of
outside of the County fairground
it's for local governments and for local
elected it's just a lot I mean I feel
like I bring an item agenda item before
them every week and and and and they get
a little you know tight they get a
little tired of talking about cannabis
you know they have other things to do
they're trying to you know run entire
cities and be responsive to the totality
of a community's needs and not just this
one particular thing you know over time
it will die down over time it's gonna be
a little bit more normal but you know
we're gonna we've been taking a steady
incremental approach to this and we're
gonna I think kind of keep plugging away
at it until it's until it's done
something I've seen come up in a couple
of different cities and I know from
somebody else that I work with is the
tiered tax measure so if somebody like
myself who's looking to vertically
integrate and
city of Sacramento every every
operational standpoint is effectively
taxed at the 5% so it'd be manufacturing
distribution cultivation and then
delivery retail that would collect the
four percent or 5 percent attack of
being an effective twenty percent tax
measure on top of excise tax and the
other taxes is that something that the
city can consider I know that the city
is already trying to are talking about
micro business licensing is there a way
to consolidate those to be a single
business tax or is a we are we are
absolutely looking at that like I think
everything cannabis related it's been a
lot we've tried to get it right the
first time and you quickly realize that
you know maybe if you're lucky got it
mostly right we've begun the
conversation around our current tax
structure and how to not just remain
competitive within the region compared
to other cities but you know primarily
the goal is ensuring that businesses are
successful because that's the only way
the illicit market goes away we need
successful legal cannabis businesses
that consumers can access so we'll be
having that conversation I expect that
to probably start becoming more
more public in the next couple of months
you
[Music]