Nik I wanted to have you do a SAP
analysis just like monologue
you know we're essentially just looking
at what's ending up inside of the plant
we're looking at what the mineral
nutrient you know micro metal comp
composition of cytosol and cytoplasm
inside of the plant actually is which
gives us another window into what's
going on as we try to balance our
microbes and as we balance our minerals
in the soil what's ending up in the
plant and so with the leaf extract
analysis is actually with the lab that I
use which is apical here in Oregon they
you know they're looking at old and new
leaves so what is concentrating in the
old leaves and what is making what
nutrients are making their way to the
new leaves and sort of you know what's
what's going into that along with that
what are the surpluses of nutrients in
the plant is their storage of calcium in
an old leaf that can make its way to a
new leaf is there an excess of chloride
that's locked up in the old leaf and not
actually making its way efficiently to
the new leaf so you know if you have you
know a thousand parts-per-million of
chloride in an old leaf and the new leaf
has only taken maybe a hundred and
eighty of that that plant is telling you
that it is trying to shed chloride
because there's too much of it in that
so really it's just giving us another
window into what's going on with plant
nutrition which ties in to plant health
that ties in to what's going on with the
protein what's going to be going on with
flowering as we move through that cycle
you know as we are talking about
cannabis on a cannabis show here and you
know what the susceptibility to pests
and disease is really going to be and
it's it's taught me some interesting
things I've worked mostly I've worked in
soil that is
less than ideal in terms of the mineral
profile and so I see a lot of high
sodium in cannabis and that's a whole
other story why that happens but it's
common and I expected to see very very
high sodium inside of the plant as a
result because you know it's a single
charge and it's not very tightly bonded
and so I moves around readily you know
you can flush it out I would think what
they can't plant would just take it up
very efficiently but that's not what I
see
it doesn't actually end up inside the
plant and most places in most cases in
talks at toxic levels and I think it's
the biology that's actually doing that
that or the plant is actually what they
would call sodium exclusive and so it
actually takes up the chloride side of
the sodium chloride instead of the
sodium if it is sodium exclusive that is
a very energy expensive process so just
because it's not ending up in the plant
doesn't mean that it isn't sucking
energy and you know nutrition and
enzymes and everything else from the
plant in it to enable for the plant to
enable itself to actually exclude that
sodium so along with being able to see
what the profile is in the plant you
know we can also make some of these
other correlations with what cannabis
actually prefers for example you know K
gets up in there no problem I don't find
myself having to to really supplement
with K at all as long as there's a
decent amount in the soil because it
moves so readily the lab that I work
with is the numbers that we see there
are a lot higher than what you're going
to see on a normal tissue test because
they're able to extract the SAP the
cytosol and the cytoplasm from the leaf
without crushing and extracting any of
the vascular tissue in that leaf I don't
know exactly what this process is what
the leaf looks the same after they pull
the fluid out of it and so you see parts
per million up into you know with K
sometimes
seven eight thousand I've seen 12
thousand in a plant that was looking
fine you know we we also learn about you
know what certain strains are actually
you know taking up and concentrating
inside of their SAP versus other strains
so it's just it's another dimension it
really is and the reason we're so
interested in this is because you know
we want to know you know what nutrient
cycling looks like from the plants
perspective but secondly we don't want
to be spraying integrated pest
management
you know pesticides insecticides these
kinds of things
we want to tackle the nutrition we want
to get to the root of the cause we want
to treat you know even if you do call it
a band-aid to apply a full year
application of a targeted mineral that's
been identified as deficient through
testing that's what we do because it's a
lot better than being on a program where
you're just constantly on you know
you're on a spray routine where it's
three different insecticides you know
every two weeks or whatever regardless
of if they are organic or not and then
the other thing is you know what are
those sprays doing to the you know the
mineral composition inside of the plant
and that's been interesting too so
there's been plenty of cases where we've
been doing that kind of testing and
there have been sprays occurring and
that is essentially clouding some of the
results so you know we go back to the
ingredients and look and see what's
actually making up that spray and what
are some of the inactive ingredients and
that spray and then we can make some
further conclusions about maybe why
we're seeing what we're seeing but being
able to see the difference between the
old and the new leaf lets us be ahead of
deficiencies by you know maybe a week
maybe two it's really hard to say but
you know it's been valuable for us we've
learned a lot from it for sure and we'll
continue to use it into the future to
make some targeted applications to try
to bolster plant nutrition instead of
falling back on
insecticides fungicides those kinds of
things even if they are again yeah how
much have you done on like have you done
much of that on indoor SAP analysis on
indoor I have yeah and cuz sometimes
it's like those systems are driven a
little harder with the lights and
everything and yeah yeah it's it's
interesting you know I've really seen
things all over the map I've seen indoor
gardens with functioning biology that
have parts per million of soluble salts
of where 2,000 parts per million you
know which is not something that you
would expect to see with a you know a
fairly well-functioning
food web right so this is why we look at
all this data right we're trying to
learn about this stuff and manage it as
best we can we're trying to avoid you
know the kill it mentality we're trying
to make it healthier instead of killing
off whatever it is that's attacking that
plant because that's not the real issue
the real issue is there's some kind of a
deficiency with the physiology of that
plant and usually you know how does it
deal with nutrition and obviously the
biology or you know microbes or what are
enzymatically catalyzing that nutrition
and the root zone to be up taken by the
plant
yeah but I think when you get into
genetics and all that kind of stuff
whether it's a a wild genetic or a newer
hybrid regardless of what the crop is
you're gonna see differences there as
well in terms of how the plant can fend
for itself in a biological soil you know
what what kinds of transport protein
says that plant actually been bred to
produce you know is it going to be able
to pull that calcium in in the way that
it needs to and so of course there are
new anomalies that have come about from
using SAP analysis but we invite them
you know but that's that's what we're
all about we're you know we're trying to
find answers we're trying to identify
the root cause of a lot of these
physiological issues that we see
regardless of what the profits
yeah not have to reach for that
pesticide yeah I appreciate how
seriously Nick is taking a
sustainability you know part of
maintaining the regenerative movement is
having farms that are a shining example
of financial success and you know having
their products move in the market and so
I'm not saying that the only way to
ensure success is by doing a lot of data
points but you know I feel that that's
one of the things that the organic
sector really needs more of
we need more measurement of something to
guide these farmers to know when it's
going wrong you know one of the really
heavy aspects of our job is we get
people that call us at the end of the
road you know we get a lot of last
chance you know farmer on the suicide
watch type phone calls and so we're
really in in tune to you know some of
the problems with popular trends and and
and the inability to measure those in an
effective way that leads to a successful
outcome you know and and you know it's
tough sometimes it's it's tough it's
tough when some of the loudest voices
are constantly speaking against
scientific quantification of the process
which can ensure your success and I just
like what I would like to see more
organic farms adopt reasonable levels of
quantification of their process at least
in the beginning to help you determine
where you're going and where you're at
and possibly what some roadblocks might
be ahead you know it seems like any
organic farmer that's done this more
than several years has a story of one
year where everything went terrible and
you know the more we do mineral analysis
the more we do biological analysis the
easier it is to see those indicators
coming so that we can redirect around a
major obstacle that will take another
farm out because the number of
hydroponic farms is still increasing
everyday the number of people that
believe Rock will is still the strategy
for cannabis is still the way they're
getting funding you know and one of the
ways that organic commercial facilities
can maintain
their funding is by meeting meeting the
business world with a reasonable level
of quantification to show why you do
things we see a lot of farms don't get
supported or don't get chosen because
the cultivators don't appropriately
quantify how you're going to protect the
investment or how you're gonna protect
this operation in general whether it's
mom-and-pop investment or you get some
long or whatever you might be partnering
with some big business I don't know but
nonetheless some quantification of the
process needs to be done in order to
have a different level of validity in
the market you know they're just there
just needs to be a little bit more
accountability of process in my opinion
the small farmers don't get a little bit
more data-driven in some cases in order
to work smarter not harder than
understanding the aspect of all these
bugs and things you know yeah spraying
the pesticides is what agriculture wants
to do but also understanding the
nutrition of the plant and so that it
can resist these bugs all together and
going back to you know everybody looking
at strain-specific they're these certain
strains or you know turf profiles
attract more bugs but it's a lot of
times what we're seeing as the plants
take up nutrients and and and process
things differently by different strain
which in turn we're growing all these
same or different strains in one
greenhouse or one grow room or one field
trying to operate it all the same same
drip feeding food we're definitely gonna
see inconsistencies and outbreaks and
certain things that are consistent with
you know plant health basically I agree
with yes God Nick I the the
quantification is huge and it gives you
even if it's not the whole answer it
gives you points on the board where you
like you all of a sudden you kind of
brush up against it you're like oh right
this is going on and it helps give a
fuller picture of the laws of nature how
we're partnering with nature and Nick
I'm wondering are you gonna
produce a PDF or some sort of
publication on your findings with with
all your the sap analysis and then one
more one more thing before you because
because well maybe we'll all like twist
your arm on that one by that I think
what you're doing with a the connection
of the the analysis of the microbial
population in conjunction with the
nutrient analysis in the SAP is so vital
so much of the kind of agricultural data
we have you know on nutrient uptake on
what nutrients you need based on soil
nutrient deficiencies was created in
these scenarios where they would never
actually looked at in the ten farms they
did which farm had microbial life
present which was totally torched dirt
and that that lack of accounting for the
variable I think has really hurt our
understanding of how nutrients are taken
up and so I think looking at you know
mere merit marrying the the SAP analysis
with the microbial life profile in the
soil that they're growing then I think
is vital for us to actually understand
the the ways plant take up plants take
up nutrient and the deficiencies they
show up going forward because it's we
don't live in a vacuum I think so too
and I've proposed this idea to others
you know including Elaine just as
another again tool but also just like
piece of data to look at all these
things right it didn't you know it's
sort of fell on deaf ears at that time
but that doesn't mean that it won't come
around with respect to publishing
something I probably need to get a
little more serious about the importance
of that right now even doing this kind
of thing yeah I don't do much of this at
all I'm mostly you know working with
farmers trying to solve their problems
not right now but you
usually on site with farmers and that's
that's where I want to be for sure but I
do see that there is a need for this
kind of data and I would encourage
everybody to check out there's some
different labs across the nation - not
all of them will take samples from
Canada from cannabis apical AG here in
Oregon we'll take some samples but he
won't take them through the mail so
that's that's been really tough because
people can't send it in from other
states they basically got to drop it off
in person so I you know I do I try to
take in some of those samples as a
courier for some of those clients of
mine that are having bigger problems for
sure and try to prioritize that kind of
thing but even if we call it half right
exactly I've sorted I've tried to cross
that he said no on hemp - I don't know I
don't know this this may change sooner
than later and it's not that he's anti
or anything like that he's just
concerned about taking that stuff
through the mail because I don't think
that yeah he's just trying to play it
safe that's all but we certainly see
correlations to the things that we read
in the academic publications with
respect to pests and disease and the
profiles inside of the plant whether it
be a deficiency malnutrition if you will
or an excess of something like nitrate
which is I think just a really common
one that everybody points to those are
the situations in which we see pests and
disease pop up you know we've been able
to deal with a lot of different pests
just from a biological standpoint well
you know you guys talked about cannabis
aphid recently on one of these episodes
and that's a new one that everybody's
dealing with and it's it's a it's a
beast for sure it rates a reproduction
for that thing are pretty wild but you
know I feel like we're we've really got
a handle on that one
specifically through a couple of
different modes
but you know this has helped immensely
with looking at the composition of
what's inside of the plant and trying to
respond to that with by you know not
applying anything that's already in
excess or in surplus but trying to get
some of what's deficient into that plant
and in some cases like what the chloride
that I brought up we're learning stuff
about you know carbon in the plant which
I talked about having by a lot biology
in the soil and not hindering the uptake
is some of the sodium but having carbon
in the plant seems to mitigate some of
the uptake and regulation of the uptake
of chloride if you that's a really
common law okay
sodium not so much but the chloride side
of that molecule that comes in the table
salt if you will that one makes it up in
there know the problem yeah it's just
we're learning a lot there's a lot left
to learn for sure I don't think that I
have big enough datasets right now to
really put forth a PDF but we will we
will eventually and you know we're
starting to work into some other crops
now with this happen
SAP analysis or leaf extract analysis
and so I'm excited for what we're gonna
find with respect to wine grapes which
is something we're going to be moving
into here in the next couple of weeks
and through this season you know what
kind of a benefit can we have for that
type of the crop so David is really the
person who runs the owns and runs a flag
that could really elucidate more of
what's going on behind the scenes and
these findings that he's sort of
gathered over five years so it's finally
been long enough that you know he's got
some pretty significant data sets and I
would say he's going to be the one
that's going to be putting forth you
know PDFs or maybe something in preprint
maybe he'll work with a PhD on something
in that and they'll get something into
the archive for sure but we're just
starting to talk about
trying to work the microbial data into
that as well because I think it's
important you know we need to paint as
big a picture as we can and you know
he's done some work with a lien in the
past and so he's on board for sure but
he's a small business as well just like
me and he's always flying by the seat of
his pants
so getting publications that out there
that kind of thing to mean these kinds
of appearances I mean who knows maybe he
would even be interested in being on the
show and just talking more about you
know what he's learned in the course of
five years with working with this stuff
you can check out some of the videos of
his on YouTube his apical AG channel and
I think that really helps put things
into perspective when I first started
working with him he didn't really have
general levels for cannabis but now he
does which has been really nice so I can
kind of see an instance originally what
it was was we were basically looking at
the concentrations of any given mineral
or nutrient the gradient if you will
between the old and the new leaf and you
know if something was three hundred
percent in the old leaf than it was in
the new leaf like I mentioned before I
mean that's a toxicity the plant doesn't
want that but it's there you know it's
being uptake in any way and it's causing
some major problems so he yeah he's
really the guy to sort of to talk to
about you know what he's learned and
he's taught me a whole bunch with
respect to how to acknowledge or to
respond you know what are the action
items that come from seeing that
something is deficient and in a surplus
or actually at levels that are toxic for
the plant so that has sent me down a
whole other rabbit hole if you will of
trying to learn plant physiology from
the standpoint of you know what's going
on inside of the plant and what are
these mechanisms inside of the plant you
know what are the transport proteins
what are the different organs what's you
know what level of diffusion or active
transport is involved with this one and
okay yeah going back to what Eric said
is going to be variation from crop to
crop and from strain to strain if you
will from you know between genetics in
terms of what the nutrient use
efficiency is going to be or this strain
or that crop verse another one so I
think it's a great tool it's inexpensive
you know if you're in Oregon or growing
something other than cannabis send David
a sample and just start to look over
that and see what you can learn about
your own crop because those targeted
applications are really what it's all
about that's what we're trying to do we
don't want to apply anything that's you
know that we don't need to be applying
we just want to sort of fill in the gaps
and again it's a band-aid for sure and
with cannabis it's been a very valuable
tool because of what we talked about
before being in these very unnatural
environments where we don't have a
season of rest a season to gather energy
in the soil in some cases like in these
greenhouse settings it's just go go go
you know clients that are twenty thirty
rounds in on soil and that you know
three four crops a year that's that can
be a challenge but you know we slowly
gather this data and look at all these
points and we respond and we go with
what works and we go with what moves the
needle in terms of the data in the
direction that we're trying to go and
that's been immensely helpful where you
know I've cannabis clients as well that
are right in native soil and it's more
like clockwork in terms of this
regenerative process that we're all
talking about we can inoculate in the
fall we can get some of those minerals
down in the fall we use cover crop we
inoculate that cover crop scene with the
microbes we want to proliferate in that
soil over the you know fall and winter
and early spring and barely have to use
inputs whatsoever and you know grow a
great cannabis crop right in native soil
I think the appellations of origin thing
that we were talking about via email the
other day a little bit that's going to
proliferate you know the number of
operations that are willing to plant
cannabis in the native soil which is
what they should be doing if they can't
as for sure this stuff goes a little
more by the book when you when you're
working with nature and it's a little
bit more complex when you're in an
indoor setting or four-season greenhouse
setting and I don't even sit clients to
Eric because you know he's really the
guy to talk to in terms of what the
environment and what the the appliances
and the levels of this and that and the
atmosphere really need to look like and
how do you smooth out this seasonal
shift you know I think he talks about
the summer in the winter mode in
greenhouses and most people aren't they
aren't ready for it when winter hits and
then you know you see a drastic drop in
production and new problems arise and
all kinds of stuff like that
and so you know it's more complex and we
need all kinds of people on that experts
to really help on that front you know if
we're going to continue to do this thing
you're out