I want to get the Cliff Notes version
for all of us who missed your
presentation okay what did you want a
clue study here so what was the title of
your presentation a scientifically
driven solutions enhance canvas
production and I say with confidence and
precision and what I think about how I
structured this was kind of holistically
conceiving the whole grow operation the
whole grow environment in terms of an
ecological ecosystem you know and in
nature which was my training and I
didn't think I'd ever do anything
besides natural ecology as a microbial
ecologist learning about plant my
interactions and I did a lot of climate
change studies where we look at the
environment you know this is traditional
ecosystem sciences well I love taking
that concept and putting it into the
grow room and I tell everybody you know
there's only one thing you have to
control in precision agriculture and
it's everything you know it starts with
plant genetics it starts us off with
plant genetics and then I give the
simple 11 parameters for success you
know and the very last one I talked
about the very bottom is soil microbes
you have energy and you have temperature
and you have airflow and you have
humidity and you have co2 any up oxygen
in the rites of sphere below ground and
hydrology and in room temperature and
nutrients and then and then there's
microbes and the fascinating thing about
is treating that as an interaction of
ecology and you better understand what
all of them doing if you tweak anything
you're gonna have to change everything
else
it affects yeah
and I so this you're gonna appreciate
this you know the typical phenotype
formula P equals genetics plus
environment plus the interaction of
genetics times environments closest
standard error variability over time I
present that my talks in terms of
precision at precision agriculture
because it's basically the same thing
you start with genetics and then the e
is everything else everything including
nutrient inputs and you have to dial in
all those things so this is huge bucket
and then dialing in that interaction
right and making sure those right
genetics are right for your environment
because not all genetics were meant to
grow up here I talked about that so
because there's the photosynthetic
equation too that comes into yeah and so
conceptually the the growers that are
newer or like ah it's beautiful and kind
of daunting because you're like oh I
have all this stuff but once you know
the picture you know the buckets that
you can start working on and then I kind
of transition that to talk about the
importance of microbes playing that very
very small part in that ecosystem which
is a huge part and I talked about some
of the challenges in nature and nutrient
use efficiency Xand how you can actually
maximize the success of plants and I
kind of talked about how you know as a
matter of fact no plant in nature exists
without plant microbe interactions why
is that you know they support the
success of life when I talk about the
human microbiome how we know now
microbes support all our health the same
thing for plants and every other life
and so you put microbes in the concept
of that bigger picture of cultivation
and then you understand how we can start
formulating microbes with precision and
confidence so growers can use these in
precision agriculture settings so you
know what they do we're talking about
targeted function we're talking about
ethics C we're talking about things like
shell flap also all these things but if
you can do that and then you can show
the results not only from a scientific
point of view from a microbial
ecologists point of view if I started
like realizing my purpose and impact of
bringing nature and natural processes to
agriculture but we're doing it
sustainably not only because of the
nature of bringing nature to agriculture
but because we're doing it profitably
and you can't do a lot of things with
success in the market unless you bring
profit to your end-user but if you can
align profit with sustainability you
really have a true sustainable
technology and so that's kind of the the
big picture of the talk and we go into a
lot of details about end data and you
know our publications and so it's about
fitting that one soil microbial piece
into the puzzle that's probably of
everything else in that in that
ecosystem is not necessarily well
understood it's more and more inner-city
to talk about the living soil concepts I
just went up to the lift show in Canada
and you know who doesn't have a million
square feet up there now I mean
literally almost every girl I went to
it's a ridiculous and some of those
facilities are turning the whole million
into a living soil grow I'm like what
that's awesome I can't believe it and
that's changing really yeah change very
very quickly and you're an organic
grower you understand that until you
understand it's not like plugging
synthetics in it's a little bit of a
process in a learning curve and you can
reap the benefits and rewards on the
back end if you can go through that
learning stage right yeah and get to
know yeah what you're working with and
yeah how to put it all together like you
were saying and all the little factors I
feel like everyone assumes oh yeah it's
just oil microbes they just put it in
there it's like well what does each one
of those microbes do specifically in
your soil biosphere what other microbes
or bacteria is that interacting with
it's causing this to happen and it gets
very intricate it's in it and it's
harder to measure because they're
they're microscopic and so you're
looking for responses when you're adding
and so you really have to have
confidence with manufacturers and make
sure they've done their diligence and
you still have to be diligent to do
diligence as a grower but I put it in
concepts of things that you can measure
like think about if you turn your grow
room temperature down 10 degrees or up
10 degrees your plants respond to that
absolutely or if you change your lights
you know does that change everything
from a low intensity to line to a high
intensity yes or what if what if you
double the co2 in a room what happens
you have to change everything else well
the the microbial component is the same
thing there's a little more finesse and
microbes don't help with any of those
macro environmental conditions you have
to get that right but it allows younger
growers to fix a lot of problems if
there's some nutrient lock out and
really add that component which isn't as
measurable except for on the back and we
see significant increases in quality and
yield you can maximize what I think the
phenotypic potential of plant because
you're maximizing the overall plant's
potential to be healthy
through those right and healthy
rhizosphere interactions and nutrient
uptake and then we've also talked to
many growers who are completely maxed
out they've dialed in the room perfectly
and there's that one missing component
and also it's that catalyst just to up
it to the next level and they're not
seeing the same Delta or increase in
yield as the newer growers but they're
getting that extra 5% that they never
thought they could achieve they're
getting that little bit extra yeah yeah
and that that top 5% is a hugely
difficult percent to get because they're
really pushing the plant and being
precision and so I love thinking about
using nature and natural processes and
microbes in general with precision
that's a new concept yeah to bring them
together to create something that is far
superior than
anything you can trade before then yeah
yeah so I geek out on you can tell me
yeah
microbes rule the world yeah it's
absolutely true you ever done any
research or has anybody on like light
and microbes because I think I'm like
sunlight and then indoor lights and then
I also think of life effects the plan
which exudes you know - it sends a
sugars to attract the right microbes but
then also certain microbes react - right
so so I don't think about that latter
part as much as I think about that first
part and you think about the response
you can't measure anything directly and
it's very challenging because you're
dealing with microscopic life but if you
can improve the energy and the resources
you're gonna improve the photosynthate
and if you improve that food source
increase of food source squirted into
the rhizosphere priming basically sugars
you're gonna maximize or improve and
increase the microbial diversity -
microbial activity and so you have to
measure that over a period of time it's
I wrote some papers early on was it was
called I called it BPM I for the study
it was called visualizing plant microbe
interactions where I had four different
grasses and an invasive grass cheatgrass
and I did an infield experiment in a
greenhouse experiment and over time we
would look at how different grasses this
is an example in the same environment
the same climate might differentially
influence the rhizosphere microbiome and
the hypothesis was that maybe cheatgrass
which is an invasive grass that's taken
over the u.s. it was planted naturally
because it was a fast growing grass it
turns out like every other biological
transplant that it wasn't that great of
an idea cuz it's too aggressive it dies
quick you know the story but I thought
maybe
cheatgrass as a hypothesis is even more
successful because they can nurture a
specific rhizosphere microbiome to
enhance nutrient cycling to make them
more competitive so that was the basis
of that study and it turns out the study
supported that published in soil biology
and biochemistry and that's an example
where we just started thinking about the
plant by itself from these different
cultivars or species being able to
influence that and it's very difficult
to measure that because you have to
measure it over time and it takes a lot
of finesse a lot of methodology and
we're equipped to do that but it takes a
lot of destructive harvesting also so it
takes a real experimental design to get
to that resolution and a lot of its
quality and so the questions I actually
initiate tons of hypotheses and the
research isn't very well established yet
on those exact mechanisms just like any
other ecology system you we should do
plant microbe interactions in a whole
series of global climate change
experiments we would have rain out and
we would have extra rain and we have a
heating patch in co2 in this space study
in Wyoming it was awesome super geeked
out a lot of money went into that trial
and then do you have to measure all
these variables separately and put them
together in modeling and then modeling
is slowing this together and there's a
level of error and so there's such a
huge road ahead of us and really
understanding how those interactions and
that's the biggest challenge alone
network and network analysis is a new
tool that comes up to allow us to
understand more real time what those
responses that you're talking about
Peter are but tying those together is a
very challenging thing for scientists
right now
you guys have an R&amp;D capability what in
the past let's say four years are some
of the things you've researched and what
or the results so that's a great
question and here's what we're here is
where it distinguishes at some point
fundamental research program and Applied
Research Program and we had to bridge
the gap and it's a very painful thing to
do for any scientist you know you want
to ask questions from the very beginning
and follow it through all the way and
you're never going to get to the end of
what really matters you make these
assumptions that oh I saw this little
mechanism early on implanting and then
you make this bold statement in academia
and so that of course is going to lead
to increase plant health quality and
yield but you're not measuring often
plant health quality and yield and we
realized at the very end when you talk
to farmers and farmers want to see plant
health quality and yield data that if
you're gonna turn your science program
into an applied science program you
better provide that data for the farmer
and you do that by completely flipping
your train of thought and you you take a
leap of faith that what you're doing is
is interacting with the plant the way
you think you know it is from your
expertise and years of study that you
measure plant health quality and yield
and then you start reverse engineering
what those mechanisms are and you
measure a couple along the way but the
details are very involved and it takes a
lot of time and a ton of resources and
so we pour focus on early on and now on
our early research programs the needle
that moves the influencer hurdle for
farmers if we have a rooting agent for
an example or a microbe that we think is
going to interstate rooting there's a
lot of mechanisms into that but what I
want to know for sure is this rooting
increase and you know I can measure
mechanisms and a thousand different
samples and never get to that but if you
measure a thousand samples for increased
root growth and then you find that
increased root growth and then you
okay what's happening here and you start
making hypothesis there and measuring
certain things in the next study and you
know we've just had this huge R&amp;D team
for the last 18 months and we're talking
year's five-year study your disregard
spider webbing off and all these new
directions and it's like well this is
happening over here and this is going on
at the same time right here we should
probably both look at both of these
laughs and then it takes that then the
fundamental aspects of the science kick
in and yeah and then then as a
co-founder of a company unfortunately be
like wait a minute we have our metric
for success we can't understand all the
mechanisms right now we have a company
we have a scientific company and we're
measuring repeatable and results we have
to do that and we have to measure and it
makes my policy to make sure we know
some modes of action but to know the
complete sequence of interactions and
and chemical synthesis or chemical
interactions and signaling that make
that happen it's not economically
feasible at the company private company
level and that's what you do all day
long in academia you never get to that
end game but you geek out on the details
yeah yeah all what he was saying tied
right back into how effectively the
nutrients can make their way into the
plant and how effectively you know the
environment is allowing for
photosynthesis to take place between
chlorophyll and a and B production and
yeah carbohydrates and all that there's
a hundred parameters you have to measure
to get it to get a chance and a snapshot
of what's going on and you got to
remember if you collect data at day five
of a plant growth in day ten and day 15
in day 20 you know you have one snapshot
at one time of the day and then things
happen on a daily cycle not a weekly
cycle and so there's all these
assumptions you have to make even when
you're collecting the psychological data
at that level
yeah so another random questions if you
took a gallon of super-happy microbes
and put half in a living soil
environment
you put into like synthetic fertilizer
what what's going on with
are those ones just totally unhappy so I
would say a general statement absolutely
and they'll tell you why because they
haven't evolved in that environment you
know if you take microbes directly from
soil we could do this tomorrow I can go
show you how to grow microbes and we'll
grow a bunch of them from whatever
source you want I'm an expert of growing
microbes and we take them directly from
soil and we grow them pretty quickly
that first growing event
you're gonna lose over 50% of the
microbes that exist in that soil because
you put them in an environment they
haven't been able to evolve into and you
have to ease them into any new
environment and so you've knocked out
50% this general you know I haven't
counted but I've experienced this before
and so you're only capturing the readily
culturable microbes that will grow in
two or three day period not that grow
over a 10 day period or not that can't
grow well or just got over competed so
you automatically biased that and then
you separate those it will grow them up
and we put half in a living soil
environment and half in a salt high salt
environment what you're gonna have is a
living soil environment that more
naturally mimics a soil condition though
they're from and so in general
hypothetically this is hypothesis most
of those microbes are much more those
microbes will survive in that soil
because that's an environment that
mimics their environment that they
evolved into initially the other half
they just got put in a very
environmentally stressful environment
and you're going to knock out probably
90% of them that's one of the findings
that we found when we are culturing
microbes and talking to farmers before
we started our R&amp;D back in the
university when I heard from a farmer
that he loved the idea of using
precision microbes like we were
hypothesis in creating and that the only
way that he was going to use them
because he couldn't make a special trip
over his field to apply to the field too
much fuel too much cost he couldn't
change a thing so he was going to take
any microbe that I gave him and dump it
in a hot fertilizer
and spread it at the same time I had an
aha moment I thought whoa
I don't think microbes can do that and
the truth is most of them can't so you
have to understand and that's why I love
what we've done with mammoth pee we
understood that going into the R&amp;D not
after the fact and we understood that we
need to evolve microbes to be able to
withstand that environment or weed them
out through selection before we took
them to market because then they
wouldn't be a viable product and so if
that if that kind of told the story most
microbes can't survive any transplant
some can and very very few can bridge
that gap
yeah
I think what
okay fun yeah thank you