[Music]
we are here doing the dragonfly earth
medicine uh panel these are breeders i
kind of announced earlier but i'll kind
of go over it again we've got jesse
biovortex he's also a producer of a
movie that's coming out called tending
the garden
um he's also an incredible breeder he's
been working things he does a lot of
breeding on the coast so if you are
looking for that mold resistant stuff
this is the man he's been doing some
amazing stuff i've been working with his
genetics for years and i can't talk
highly enough about them
uh we've got forest from sun roots
covelo you know
we all know kovalev
big plants big plants if you guys want
big plants these are the people that
work on that so yeah but you have to
grow
with water
i think it does help all right
and then we got zelig from spring
you gotta creek out what he does i mean
the man obviously works really really
hard and and uh you know much respect to
just the the tenacity and the pursuit of
of farming and challenging mountain
hillsides and stuff and working with it
so
yeah and then daniel from heart rock
mountain
[Applause]
you know daniel's
daniel's the family guy that you want to
bring your kids to hang out with because
and and so he's a true breeder
um he he's good at making kids and he's
good at making seeds and he makes a lot
of them so
you know people that want the autoflower
or some cbd this guy's got kind of the
range
look look into it and then we got
moongazer we got josh over here
uh you know
i met joshua a long time ago at this
point which is kind of a trip because it
doesn't it's just like time has gotten
weird but
um
it's been really cool watching somebody
like you guys came to our farm
way back in the day before you had a
farm and before you started yours
and so you know i got to kind of watch
that process unfold via instagram mostly
but also i've been able to visit that
farm and it's been just magical they've
got twins you know uh we all
you know
the whole kid thing changes your world
so um
but yeah so yeah that's who's up here um
i do have a piece of paper and i was
trying to be somewhat organized
i like to look like i am
[Music]
but basically what i'm going to do is
just kind of bring up some topics in
relation to breeding and genetics and
let these people uh kind of share with
you their thoughts on what i'm asking so
um
prepare
uh damn pure so i just got a shout out
to josh and kelly you know they really
have spearheaded a large
uh network of community that has really
you know
they're really doing good stuff like
they're up in canada kind of stuck there
uh
and and
and that's so good you know because they
get to really work on their space and
um but they bring bring a lot of
inspiration and so this is the damn pure
panel and we're all a part of that
family and
um we've all been sharing genetics and
working with genetics uh for for some
time now so
thank uh thanks uh everybody who put
this on you know tamara and joey um
making this kind of thing happen
to me this is like
this is like the true future of all this
it's like going back in time you know
it's like let's make this happen like it
once did again
regardless
and i feel like it's a timeless act so
you know we gather we share seeds we
work we we get to be around the people
who have put a lot of time and energy
into their seeds and and and that needs
to keep happening in our in our planet
in order for us to really fully awaken
into
uh this next coming age uh which is an
age of golden light and
you know that age of gold and light and
consciousness is real so
you know i just want people to
i've been trying to give people as many
people some of that weed that i i grew
just a smoke during
the time while we're all listening so we
can receive that energy
um
and so let's get let's get into it uh
i'm gonna i'm gonna let each one of the
breeders here just kind of talk about
themselves a little bit um
and i want you to just kind of introduce
yourself
but
i want
i want to know
your relationship to the breeding and to
genetics
and and what inspires you
and what has inspired you in in that
realm
um and where it kind of started and and
i know it can get long-winded so let's
just keep track of time but just try to
pick out some nuggets of things that
have really helped guide you further
into the process
so let's start maybe
on one end and work down the line just
for easy sake
so jesse
what's the inspiration
come up or do you move in the microphone
let's do that oh wow
[Laughter]
stand and deliver
can we hear it for nick that was
freaking amazing like
it's a real shit
mix a little stand-up comedy and like
brought everyone in and all of the seeds
and those seeds will do a lot of stuff
it makes me think of the original uh
living soil symposium and the seeds that
went out there
and like seeing that stuff today still
in all the different ways that
it's been worked on so
i don't know i think it's real beautiful
the
sharing of seeds in the way that we
it brings us together and we get to like
exchange
a relation around a relationship with
nature observing a plant
and i think um
from the moment i first like
found cannabis seeds and weed like i was
immediately fascinated immediately grew
them brought them out in the woods
fascinated about the plant in every way
and then that fast made me fascinate
about nature in every way and science
and art and
mutualistic relationships all the ways
that those work and how those actually
can apply to everything
in
nature but also everything in our own
constructs in that's the way we should
be working for economy and for the way
that we interact in business and friends
and events like this i think are an
amazing example of that potential so
yeah hear it let's hear it for this
event thank you guys
really special
because this is what it was and it's you
know it feels good the weather blessed
us
um yeah it just
this is the type of exchange this is the
type of thing we've been hungry for in
very much the last two years for sure
but honestly before those two years it
already kind of got fucked and we didn't
even have shit like this before kovid so
i don't know it's a it's definitely a
very cathartic feeling to just be here
and um experience all this with you and
celebrate the plants and friendship and
community um
i started a project called biovortex
a while ago um
around the idea of
influencing cannabis industry in a more
environmentally thoughtful direction
and mutualism in general in the way that
we interact with each other and the
breeding has been part of that but so
has the
um social media as the photography the
art projects the movie projects that
we're doing now all kinds of different
aspects and then the talks and events
the regenerative cannabis farm award at
the emerald cup and being able to have
an award ceremony also talk about the
practices and the farms and getting to
know the farms in that level and being
able to do the rage lounge and do all
the different talks that got to connect
cannabis community to the practices that
mattered and that also built this kind
of amazing family like everyone
you know right here just very special
people and we've got to like grow each
other's genetics visit each other's
gardens
sharing each other's families and
food and and watch each other's children
grow up and
it's yeah
special stuff you know um
and yeah i'll
let it go to the next person but i'm
very thankful for this moment and all of
you
[Applause]
hey i'm forrest from sunrood's farm up
in kovalev and uh everything what jesse
just said like bring this all together
really feels like the right thing to do
right now
you know it's like we need this more
than ever to be able to come and just
show each other
what we're doing what we still love to
do and
it just feels like a good thing to be
doing
um
like
i started growing when i was in a young
age and i always was drawn to you know
the color and the weed and like the
connection to farming and
you know just being out in the garden
and it's really been like a journey
through life just doing what i love and
like sharing
each step and
you know
just keep you know expanding like the
awareness of
of uh you know good conscious gardening
and bringing the skills to the table to
show people
and
i like to grow big plants obviously you
guys have probably heard
we do a lot of our own genetics
we've done our own genetics uh for a
long time my family has been
breeding
my brother uh
crossed the jagu and we've just been
kind of
going off
you know
the goo line really
and uh
you know bringing this and that into it
and it's really been a
pretty awesome
thing to be doing and it feels good so
thank you for being let us letting us be
up here and uh showing you what what we
do best at
[Applause]
yo what's up everybody
nice to see you all
i'm zelig spring creek farm
um sonoma county casadero
we've been uh doing uh no-till light
depth for you know 18 19 20 years for or
so
before we knew what we were really doing
so uh you know it's really nice to uh
you know be here with everybody and
you know experience you know this seed
swap and
you know i'm just really thankful to you
know know you all and and just
you know just smoke weed i just smoked a
bunch of hash so i'm fucking big
but yeah no this is what we all really
need you know for you know we all know
what's going on in the industry and
you know it is what it is the plant is
kind of uh in control of this whole
paradigm you know
it's not about money or anything it's
really just about the plant
you know and and so
it's there's a lot going on and you know
i i think that
as long as we you know obviously it's
bringing us together as much as
you know i think we can all say that
maybe we feel a little bit detached you
know honestly because i know i do
um
i am right here with everybody you know
but at the same time i feel i don't know
if it was just me but i feel like
there's this detachment going on and so
by all of us coming together
it's really crucial you know especially
right now because i know we're all
feeling it i know i'm feeling it i know
everybody else is feeling it so just
really thankful that we're all showing
up for each other
um you know
you know just like you're all about like
my favorite people in the world right
here you know i just love you all
and just uh been doing my thing up on
the hill y'all probably see me doing
what i do and you know i just do what i
do
make no claims
i come from no educational background
i'm just a practical guy who you know
just listens to the plants and do what
i'm told they just tell me what to do i
just do what they want me to do that's
all i need to know it doesn't matter if
it doesn't matter what what you think
and that's kind of the whole
part of my whole methodology is just the
trust you know
um just trusting the plan trusting the
process
you know kind of like an onion you're
just peeling back the layers the more
you peel back the layers the more you
trust it and the more
the more is revealed over time so i
think that's just the
you know because like there's a lot of
you know there's like the the bro
science that people like the science
world it's like oh if you don't test
stuff you're a bro science you know like
you know what i mean nick like if you
don't test something you're you're
automatically you know like you don't
know what's going on like you don't need
to know because if you're following the
methodolo methodology of nature
nature's taking care of everything
because nature is the most intelligent
system on earth so we don't really need
to know you know i think it's good to
know so you have that relationship with
your soil but once you get that base of
your understanding and relationship with
your soil then you know
you can kind of just go from there and
you know i don't know it's just
i don't know just something i've been
thinking about a lot you know just it's
just like this you know within the
industry how you know people are if you
know just the different sides of the
coin of the science side to you know
like me and nick or just like on our own
little world you know
and like you know a bunch of other you
know farmers we just kind of like do our
thing and listen to the plants do what
we're told
you know but you know then there's the
the side of the coin where you have to
test everything and it's all like that
and you know i think it's and ultimately
everybody's just looking for that
balance you know
so i think it's just what we're looking
for everybody's looking for balance
whatever it is whatever you're trying to
do i think we're just all looking for
the same thing which is balanced so
i don't know yeah i've been doing my
breeding project which is just like i'm
just breeding for like this head change
that i
am experiencing
um which was this uh dog shit seeds
bag seed that i started uh just kind of
a long story i won't get into it all
but yeah i've just been kind of which
turned out to be i was breeding for a
high cbga and didn't know it
until i started testing
and then went back and
went through all of my previous tests
and i found they were all high in cbga
and so i've realized that's what i was
breeding for so that's kind of like my
breeding project is like a high cbga
breeding project
which is the precursor to all
cannabinoids so you know it's kind of
significant
um
so that's something that's cool that
i've been working on but
yeah just super thankful to be here um
yeah
i don't know oh yeah just love y'all
give thanks
[Applause]
okay um i'm daniel with a heart rock
mountain farm uh prideline seeds and i
think kind of what like jessie was
saying uh cannabis was my gateway plant
um it was the first plant i grew
uh and my older brother isn't here to
confirm anymore but he had like house
plants in like middle school but he
could have been growing weed then too
probably but
yeah i started out growing cannabis and
now i have you know cactuses in my
greenhouse you know i'm like taking
cuttings from people's houses of their
house plants and i'm obsessed with
plants
and uh
so i'm thankful for that and for this
community and
um i'm second generation
uh cannabis breeder third if you count
my nana who's who grew and oldapanga for
a long time i even went down to help her
harvest once in high school she's like
can you help me out and make sure i'll
come down and it'll be a fun trip to l.a
that she had like a plant after a second
story window like okay i see why yeah
[Laughter]
uh you know my one of my favorite
stories from my dad he was saving
backseat for like a decade you know
before he popped his first seeds in 76
and it was like you know mexican south
american
they acclimated that to the hills in
northern california
and then some indica came in from
afghanistan that grew that they crossed
those together groomed for decades and
then i came on to the scene my older
brother a lot younger i think he was
like 10 or 11 helping my dad in the
garden and he looked at me and said you
know you need to go to school i got one
kid growing and weight do something else
with your life and now i'm running the
family farm and he's pretty happy
he wanted me to be more than just an
outlaw which i get and now i'm more than
just an outlaw i run a commercial
cannabis farm and licensed nursery
yes
and then uh we just you know we just
we we've always made seeds and like
um
i've talked with nick and like zelic was
saying like we learned the heart first
we were plant whisperers first and now
we're like okay what does failule mean i
better look that up from webster's okay
like you know so we're learning the
science
um where we need to
and it's it's fun and we're all very
passionate about what we do and
it's great to be up here with these guys
hey i'm josh from moongazer farms
just gotta give a huge
love and gratitude to joey and tamara
this is amazing
you guys are amazing
uh this is like how things used to be
and i'm getting a lot of good feeling
from how that all was and thank you all
for coming um but basically pretty much
uh
my wife sandra and i uh we have a couple
kids twins and we're just trying to make
it as illegal
as a you know wreck farm
back when we met nick and jesse and
everyone things were starting to get
legal we kind of jumped into it and
uh
people were telling us to grow clones
and have everything be all uniform and
everything and we just always wanted to
stick with the seeds and
do our breeding and it's uh
finally gotten you know it's gotten us
to a point now where it's like you just
gotta have like triple a
herb right now and it's gotta you know
it's like
it's gotta be good
and and growing from seeds you know
we're able to achieve that even though
we have different phenotypes
and you know things don't have to be
like super duper uniform all the time
um so it's you know yeah so you know
seeds like just for so many reasons i
mean i mean even our own kids like
they're you know we
they're different phenotypes but people
think they're identical people think
they're identical all the time
but we see their subtle differences and
we love their subtle differences
and so that's sort of how i approach the
cannabis
and how a lot of us here approach the
um
and and and it's just kind of been
if you want a truly sun-grown product uh
which we do that's what we like to smoke
uh it's sort of
planted in the spring
on the when the moon is a specific when
the moon is in a certain uh phase and
we harvest it in the fall um when the
moon's in a certain phase
and uh you know when you're growing from
clones clones are wonderful and they've
been crucial for this plant of course
uh in its evolution but at this point
for us when we're when we're out in the
light and we're doing it out we're doing
it this way
um you know that's
that's how we want to smoke that's what
we want to provide for people and so
that's how we're doing it is just from
seed planted in the spring harvested in
the fall and
of course planted among lots of other
beautiful plants so we don't have to
spray anything
and that's what we do
[Applause]
hello hello okay i think this just got a
loose uh thing so we got to be careful
when we're holding it but i just rather
sit down and kind of not do the whole
thing
in that way um
and then i'll just pass this around but
i'm just gonna kind of bring up some
topics
back on okay we're back on
all right uh
so
i want to i want to get into some um
just kind of i want to dig into some
breeding a little bit uh i'm pretty
passionate about it you know my
evolution with breeding seeds has
evolved rapidly in
and i haven't been doing it as long as
everybody uh
but i've been committed to it uh very
pretty seriously and
been paying really close attention to a
whole bunch of different lines and and
working lines but
my question is uh
out of all the seeds
that you like to grow
and if we can think of seeds in
different categories such as
f1
ibl
poly hybrid
specific traits within genetics that you
might like
uh
but what type of seeds are your
preference for growing
for you
not
not for
what the market wants because if we're
all all breeders have to do a certain
amount of work uh for the market but
also then there's a certain amount of
soul work that goes on in breeding and
so i want to pull some of the soul out
of you guys
and just like
hear what your favorite types of seeds
to pop right now are and interpret that
the way you will if it's from your own
stock if it's just whatever but
if anybody wants to volunteer to take
that one on first let's go down the line
go down the line again it's nice and
easy with the mic
i guess
what i most want to grow is what i find
interesting and
that's a little bit rough um
yeah it's what
what i get to learn from what
things that i find interesting that's
that's what i want to keep sprouting the
things that i have
in my head what i want to see
what i want to see other people
grow and what i want to see come from
that it's all like very interesting
like possibilities that go out and you
know what what else will come from this
seed um
if you turn your body a little bit you
won't forget the there will be a meet up
block your back
the speaker's right here so that
actually works better
um
so to be able to
see the outcome
of something on a farm too in different
locations also really interests me
and
doing that around hash is really
interesting to be able to see
how hash comes out how that yields and
to see that on different farms and
different plants isolated and then the
idea of reading with them
but
some of the like really
joyful things are growing like true
primordial varieties and land races and
seeing
all the lessons that they like kind of
have
in there and really observing the plant
in those forms
the lab um from
the razon indian land rice seed exchange
he had got these low lab valley
uh seeds which is like 7 000 feet up in
cashmere and in an area growing in the
trees and in the hills where
it didn't have any other
cross-pollination there's no light
pollution so it's not really affected by
human encroachment and it actually is a
primordial variety that's just been
growing in the trees and it was really
interesting to see
all the things that were already there
and this thing this plant that's been
growing in the same way for thousands of
years in the same location without other
things messing with it and it was very
they were yeah very adaptive very smart
they're kind of like
the wolves of
a cannabis plant and the fact that
they're like just adapted to survive in
this place and not domesticated when we
start to do domestication process like
instant
morphology changes happen so like if
you're picking your favorite plant and
smelling those flowers and then or
seeing how well it hashes or something
those seeds are the ones that are
actually inside
the the flower and just hidden in that
brax a little closer to the the actual
stem and inside and so
those ones they don't like fly out that
easy and they get bigger and instantly
you start domesticating the seeds get
plumper and bigger these seeds are
incredibly small and very thin and ready
to like fly out so like
when breeding with it like i had to be
really careful to like put a bag around
it before cutting it because the seeds
would all just start flying you know and
that's like a scattering too the wind
would come by and they would actually go
pretty far it was just like ready to
shoot out and it's like oh yeah you know
like
the only reason why they'd stay in is
because that was like an interaction
with humans and like picking the thing
that you so those are the ones that keep
getting passed on it's like the one in
your favorite flower if you're actually
choosing that kind of selected
process it's just kind of interesting to
think about
all the lessons something old show us
the adaptive aspect of it too as far as
being able to watch it and interact with
the sun in its environment or them i
don't want to say it it's not like the
right word when referring to a plant but
um
you know they i was growing both male
and females and we should have better
words i guess but they were they were
tracking the sun so perfectly before it
rose you know like and i actually did
night vision
uh uh time lapse photos of them to watch
this dance that they do each day and
they would just like set up so good like
just stretching like straight yoga ready
for the sun and got every bit of that
perfect like light
in the beginning and then would kind of
track and then at night they would fall
down so far
just completely
like hold everything in and go through
this whole
breath um
and yeah it was just interesting like
how fast they grew and how
small and slow they grew at first too
all the seeds were um
they're just so small and they take so
long to germinate and and are are
difficult to germinate and i was
thinking about well that makes a ton of
sense because if all of a sudden they're
scattering and then the snow comes down
or like it rains right before the winter
every plant that germinates just dies
seven thousand feet up or so and so they
have to really be smart enough to know
hey are these conditions really right
you know like okay yeah it's wet maybe
it's warm enough but is it warm enough
for enough period of time for us to
really
be like
okay cool let's crack we're gonna we're
gonna have a successful season and not
immediately die by like some big storm
and uh yeah then they seem to like show
that too they're very careful there's
like okay is this it and they they they
crack so slowly the germination and just
that root radical is just so small and
coming out the tiniest little sprouts
but then they grow really really fast um
and take take advantage of whatever they
have and that might be um but if they
don't have much they'll conserve too so
they they can kind of they're very
adaptive in figuring that kind of stuff
out
but
um yeah the things that are are
fascinating are interesting that connect
to something old and get me thinking and
whether that's for making something that
makes a farmer more successful in what
they're doing you know i like
mold resistance i like having stuff that
flowers at certain times certain terpene
profiles certain hash yielding just
profiles in the flowers and look all the
things and like figuring out what works
for someone and that's a constant puzzle
and fascination too so
the things that are interesting
[Applause]
that's so
i want to thank jesse because he
shared his genetics with me and
um have just made
new genetics now that are like
substantially
better mold resistance and
you know
crystal content
um because he has a lot of hash strains
um so i bred that with a lot of my
different velvet perps crosses
um so now they're like
they seem super charged but uh
i started growing like little plants in
the bushes like guerrilla status you
know
i'm sure a lot of people have done that
before but uh
i was always uh fascinated with like
you know throwing pollen on i would have
to like
walk two miles and i had a couple little
male plants in a in a little creek a
little spring bed you know and i would
take the pollen and throw it on my best
my you know one of the best plants
and you know just to see the diversity
of what comes out of
you know just throwing a little bit of
pollen on
and uh seeing you know the different
phenotypes that come out it's just it's
kind of like a pandora's box you never
know what you're gonna get so that
really like you know
got me into breeding you know
so about 10 years ago i really started
to do it each year
making my own seeds and then growing
them and then selecting the best ones
you know that i liked and throwing more
pollen on them
um
and
it's
you know it's just like a
it's a good thing to do
you know
yeah
it really it makes me happy
[Laughter]
and uh you know
yeah keep on doing it yeah uh
now it's like that
everything's changed into you know like
you have to have the best stuff to even
just get it on the market to maybe sell
it for a decent price possibly i don't
know not anymore
maybe hopefully in the future you know
but uh you know
we can just keep crossing our varieties
together
and who knows what we'll come up with
so
i'm going to jump in because i'm right
here in line i just want to share what
i'm working on as well or what is
exciting right now
um
but when i think of breeding seeds i
mean that's the piece that
i'm most excited about which is funny
because that doesn't mix as well as a
commercial production farmer which i
have to rely on
but
i love
breeding so much that i just do it and
my favorite thing lately has been doing
as many inbred lines as i can as many
populations of those inbred lines as i
can in small rows within a greenhouse
high population counts and making
selections within those inbred lines and
furthering each inbred line but also
they're all there set up stacked on one
another to make real f ones if all of
the lines that you're putting in your
breeding hoop are inbred so you're
making more ibl's and you're making more
f1 stock and f1 stock is what you want
to have if you're growing production
which i have to do and i have to depend
on that so i've had to go through that
testing process but the truth is there
aren't really real f1s out there right
now because we're all still so immature
in our breeding uh you know
there are some you know deeper f we're
getting further but really uh standard
in breeding for isolating traits and
characteristics is like more than ten
generations so you know when that's the
case we just have to be realistic but i
just say keep going down the lines keep
inbreeding but also keep crossing those
inbred lines to make those f1s and
explore that because the hybrid vigor is
definitely something to understand when
you're growing for production
so
the breeding is the most exciting thing
for me and i just go kind of a little
overboard with
uh inbred line collections but
what what nick just said
yeah what he just said
basically well said
[Laughter]
but yeah um
there's a bunch of things in there like
what you're saying how it's it's hard to
do that in in a commercial space that
you're trying to run for production and
that's what i've been doing for years is
breeding and doing production so running
a research facility and a production
facility in one space which is really
crazy
because you there's a lot of room for
i mean there's no room for error you
know uh so you really have to be like
extra on your shit
you cannot slack for one second because
you just you're working with a lot of
different lines so
plus it's just you know uh
yeah it's just hard to really you know
pop enough seeds and and have the square
footage to make those selections so i'm
kind of
actually kind of phased out of
um doing my breeding projects for right
now and just holding on to my seed stock
just because
it's it's i'm trying to just stay you
know we you know shit's kind of falling
apart right so i'm just trying to stay
in my lane and that's that's okay you
know so i'm not trying to do too much
which is you know it's okay you know
i've been so yeah i was running these uh
inbred lines i've been running this
these dogs i'm calling it the dog pound
which uh you know from my uh dog uh my
my dog originally was like dog shit bag
seed and then um this um uh super silver
haze uh male
um so you know we just started running a
bunch of lines off of that dog shit so i
really like the dog shit terps
i just literally i just love it
i don't a lot it was a hard sell because
of the name you know obviously
so you know but
so that's you know so then that that's
how kind of the dog star came up once it
went into the super silver you know we
we called it dog star you know which was
you know um like like serious a you know
the origins of cannabis um that whole
story i'm not gonna get into all that
but you know that's kind of like you
know paying homage to
to the origins of cannabis and that
whole thing and the fact that you know
kind of you know
that we ended up finding uh the high
cbga
which is the precursor to all
cannabinoids
you know that was pretty appropriate for
you know calling it dog star i felt you
know to you know because it was it was
something special like you know over
three percent um cbga
at full term like like full term harp
you know full term
three months later testing it it's over
three percent three four percent cbj
which was
you know which is one of the first uh
cannabinoids that you know deteriorates
you know and and so or it's really hard
to get high you know to isolate the cbga
apparently which i didn't know at the
time so you know once we found that out
um we just started uh working with that
a little more intentionally you know and
that was kind of like that was that head
change that i was chasing kind of like a
cbd you know we all know what that's
like you know but the cbga
it's kind of it's similar but it's got
like that different head change but it's
similar
you know and and it's really hard to put
your finger on you know what i mean
because
you know it just is so
um that's you know so that was really
exciting for me because that's what i
was doing and that's kind of like my
story so that was really exciting as far
as what i would like to work with i'd
like to work with everyone else's stuff
but
i i don't quite have like the space to
to pop everybody's in label at all and
and and you know but i would love to so
i really you know and if somebody's
gonna give me something to work with i
kind of need like a hundred of any one
you know
you know seed to just to pop because
like 10 is just like what am i doing
with that you know i'm like
where what i i don't have you know i'm
going to start looking for other you
know headset you know just you know i'm
trying to you know on a commercial
facility you have to have more of a
direction so
but we just don't have the my county
whatever so we're just uh we're just
staying in our lane for right now um you
know which is cool
so anyway that's been uh it's been good
but you know i'll get back into uh
messing with uh popping a bunch of seeds
and looking for different lines and you
know i'll get back into that in a minute
now but
for right now i've just been trying to
like you know
um hold the line
you know just survive for a minute but
um yeah yeah i just like to i would love
to work with like everyone's stuff
really
but yeah kind of like what nick is
saying it's just like that's what i've
been run you know just
doing that for a long time and
so yeah i just uh yeah we're it's
working out just gotta listen to the
plan you know we were just we were just
you know we weren't we didn't have any
like you know education-ness or guidance
we were just literally just like you
know like we do everything just
listening
just being guided by the plant and
it's amazing how far that can get you
you know it's amazing that's really just
what it is our ancestors did that that's
just how it is you know
it's really effective it got us all this
far look at all the amazing genetics and
lines and green breeding you know that's
that's happened throughout you know like
a long many many years so
yeah it's just uh it's really good that
we're all here swapping seeds and
you know i think it's awesome it's
really cool how everybody's like let not
holding on to shit anymore like it used
to be like this like whole lockdown you
know
and that's kind of also why i just was
like doing my own thing you know just
because we were just doing our own thing
we weren't like messing with anyone
else's stuff really
so yeah it's just been now so it's
really nice that to have all this
variety because that's you know that's
just like that's what life is about
variety
all right cool
um i'll keep this short uh what nick
said
um yeah i'm just working lines is
definitely what i'm into too and um
you know you kind of
you kind of see what you're want to look
for in your your first generation and
then you get to see what you're working
with in your second generation and
you know so
and it is like i'm sure everyone up here
will agree like it's about getting lucky
too you know it's like sometimes
you just
but then if you have like the population
to do the sifs like if you start enough
seeds
of uh you know f1 f2 f3 you're gonna
find one that looks just like her mother
and that's the one you made the seeds on
you know that's the one you want to
stabilize and sometimes you get lucky
and find her and you know 40 seeds or
less you know sometimes you don't you
gotta look again the next generation or
there's been a lot of times where i make
a generation of seeds get the pot i'm
like although i'm not gonna make it this
year this isn't you know i didn't find
what i was looking for but
you know
it's fun and you're gonna lose things
and you're gonna find things and it is
uh beautiful working with this plant
this plant's spirit you know the the
you know cannabis is
i mean everything's consciousness right
you know our light or vibrate whatever
you could look at on the molecular level
and something like cannabis or the
cactus or some other plants that
interact with our consciousness they
have a higher concentration of that and
we get to co-create with that and we get
to find whatever you know
you any one of us could take a line and
go a different direction with it when we
put our heart into it and that's a
beautiful thing too and it is beautiful
to share uh those genetics with
everybody and and
and to not worry like worry about
getting it out there because you're
gonna do something beautiful with it and
we might go somewhere else with it and
then we get something back from somebody
or lose something and
yeah that co-creation with this plant
and uh and yeah we really need that
right now
uh as a planet and the people what
cannabis can do from like oil production
to medicine and just with consciousness
in general
you know and and i'm also very excited
that uh psychedelics are going to be
legal soon hopefully in the next
like our lifetime across the united
states
um
yeah i mean
if you listen you know
she calls to you she talks to you and
and then you get to put your input in
too and it's a fun relationship as a
breeder that you develop with your
plants in your lines and then your
fringe lines like you know like you know
we're all doing like amazing work or you
know or getting lucky
[Applause]
yeah i mean
with regard to what we like to grow
uh basically when we first started out
um
you know definitely just these seeds i
had been seeking out
i was basically looking for seeds that
had been
grown living soil and on the full sun
that were resistant and of course that
tasted really good and things like that
i mean since then we've probably
ever on this panel we've got a little
bit of genetics from we have some from
amanda's garden and joey and tamara we
got some seeds from so
we just love to mix it up we love to
smoke and so we like to try lots of
different things and
from day to day or you know our taste or
our palette might change but we
definitely will go for commercial
uh as well so
um
but we're not too fixated on having them
all be purple you know if if you end up
having a little bit of mixed phenotypes
but they all have a certain smell uh
we're super
into like some you know uniformity in
that sense um
but hash also we're definitely been
reading for and thankful to jesse for
getting us some of the nana breath and
the other banana og crosses
they've been super nice for us
yeah bananas coffees uh
just lots of different
guavas watermelons blueberries
just kind of mixing it all up it's
always been fun
[Applause]
so
um
i'm into hash as well now by the way
uh and so that's another part that i'm
super excited in the
i like i'm seriously mostly focused on
hash line seeds for
growing because i really just like
well
truth is is when the resin
is stored i can have something for years
that's really like it was and the flower
you know it's bulky and big and
i don't know but
so there's this beauty and hash that
i've really been tuning into um so from
a genetic standpoint that's definitely
been something i
i have felt but i think you know things
have been rolling for quite a while
how's everybody feeling do we want to
keep rolling down this path or should we
kind of take a break and walk around and
what do you guys think it's it's way
past the time i can't i don't know when
we started i don't know where we're at
um
keep going
cool um
yeah let's do another round we got it we
don't rarely are we all in this kind of
scenario together so
um
let's see we have
so
when i
when i talk to people about
what are you going to get from a seed
standpoint
um you know i like to have some
categories of like steering people in
the right direction to kind of most help
them in their path towards what they're
trying to do so it's like
trying to uh
create a whole bunch of stuff
and so there's all these names that
people use in our cannabis genetics and
and and i just kind of want to address
them a little bit and be like
there's a lot of loose
meaning to a lot of the language uh when
it comes to
f1 f2
um there's a lot of uh you know
it's it's not super dialed within within
cannabis breeding or it hasn't been as
much but um i think it's important for
us to explore it and to understand it
more
and to understand like what agriculture
normally does in in the breeding sense
and so
i was talking about inbred lines and and
you know
the value of breeding within inbred
lines to create hybrids that really have
a lot of vigor and all that but i want
to talk a little bit about
uh the benefits and the and the the
value of poly hybrids as well because
you know there's a lot of uh there's a
lot of poly hybrids around and a lot
less of the more strict line work has
been being done and you know there's a
lot to learn when you get on that path
of strict line work um and and when you
peter out or or just understanding that
inbred lines do kind of slowly become a
less of a productive thing but it should
be being more honed and as you narrow
that further your population should
start to become increasing so you might
bottleneck some things a couple
generations to try and steer it in the
direction you want but at that after
that point when you've honed something
that you've got and most of them are
showing that you want to open the
population's backup because you don't
want to keep taking one single parent
and one single male and only doing that
you want to make start to increase the
genetic diversity amongst your
bottleneck genetics already so inbred
line work is more than just continually
filial generationally crossing but you
also want to think about some
population expansions as you getting
into a
lesser or more inbred degraded state
which are actually really good for
breeding and people shouldn't get scared
of an inbred line that doesn't produce
and grow like a hybrid does but you
don't get them for that you don't get
them for production you get those inbred
lines because you want to work with them
from a breeding standpoint because they
create a super vigorous f1 uh
hybrid offspring but let's i want to go
down the line and just let people
address poly hybrids and how poly
hybrids and working with poly hybrids
what that's like for you
so here we go
man
is it working
man that was excellent information i
hope everyone was actually paying
attention to that um
yeah there's a lot to
think about with that so um i really
appreciate nick's constant work to go
down
you know like
multiple multiple generations like
getting to f6 seven eight
um in different varieties and when you
get to that point it's a certain level
of line breeding that breeds over very
true as far as
genetics go and and the hybrids that
come out of that are really amazing
you know when we first met we there was
these um it was with ryan from humble
seeds and the glazed cherry and he gave
you those i gave you the black dog and
you took them to like multiple
generations and then put them together
and
those hybrids were so
even and so much bigger like you could
just see that multiple generation
bigger and it's like you know that's how
a lot of breeding's done in agriculture
for vegetables and everything you take
stuff to pretty far generation fa f9 and
then you put them together to make an f1
that is a true vigorous hybrid and
there's actually strangely enough a
certain uniformity in and what happens
from
that crossing of varieties when they're
there to that point of line breeding but
he also just gave really a really good
information
around not getting bottlenecked
genetically so as you you know you start
off early you're making very
solid selections for exactly what you
want it to be you're building that
cannon of the flavor the like
the resistance the structure all the
factors that you're thinking about and
building that but then you want to make
sure that you're using multiple males
and then if you're putting that on to
multiple females and this is from
sibling generation
that you then get to really choose from
those females but you know that they've
been pollinated with multiple males and
so then
as you've already done some work towards
that
um
selecting what you want and
stabilization of that variety you make
sure not to bottleneck it and then you
can work that for for longer so that's
it's really like opening that potential
to not
get too far down that line and what
happens is actually smaller and smaller
plants a little
less bigger and but but more and more
smaller seeds yeah yeah and and but more
and more
um
similar too though you know and so it's
an incredibly useful thing but f1s are
amazing too so
anyway poly hybrids that's actually what
the question's about or
what we're supposed to be talking about
and i fucking love poly hybrids i love
the work of of going down multiple
generations i also love back crossing
work too which is going back to a
generation
the original generation that what you
like the most of something and it's a
way of like kind of stacking the
genetics onto each other and you can get
to a higher percentage of the same
genetic in that next generation really
quickly so that's something i like to do
and then i like to combine that with
then doing
uh sibling cr uh generations from that
and so making the
vc1 f2 or f5 or something in the black
dog case and then it becomes a very much
just that genetic it's the and very
useful for breeding because it it's it's
similar to that wine breeding of getting
to a f8 or something
but
during that time with poly hybrids you
get to like
do all kinds of things i i only line
breed like a couple things you know each
year you choose a few things that you're
going to work pretty good
and then but then you have the potential
to do whatever you want so i don't
really want to limit that and so it's
pretty exciting to be like oh my god
this would be amazing with that and just
it's all these probability like wave
fields of potential and goodness that
you're like
looking at and wanting to see happen
and uh yeah it's just a super fun
selection process it's a it's a freedom
it's a jazz it's a
art like that you get to just kind of
immerse yourself in the moment and
figure out like
man this should go here on this and i
just can't wait and you're so excited
about it like as soon as it happens and
it's like oh my god i'm going to crack
these next year and i want to make sure
my friends grow these and then you get
to see it on other farms and places and
that's
so exciting to see something
new and all kinds of amazing things come
out of poly hybrids and it can be very
you know different too so i like to
really label the polyhybrids because
there can be certain aspects that
that
come from the line breeding so they can
actually kind of be some relatively
stable sometimes and then other
combinations will be all over the place
and it depends on those combinations
going in and so i'd like to kind of like
be able to let people know a bit and
guide like on what you know you might be
experiencing with something you know
there's
three very select kind of things that
come out of it or there's a certain
uniformity or it's just all over the
place but um
yeah i just i just love the the
selection process and and
um really respect the the length of time
to put each year into making a selection
on that next generation like to grow out
several plants and to then continue on
that's a very useful thing and um you
know nick with the seeds that he's
brought today
a lot of people have some really useful
breeding tools in their hand because now
you actually have a lion bread thing
that you could put with another one to
make
true hi you know
f1 hybrids that are going to have that
vigor uniformity that we expect in all
agriculture
[Music]
[Applause]
so yeah keeping the uh the diversity in
the stock is important like uh my dad
always
said keeping more than just one one of
the males around
at least keep keep a couple of them to
breed on you know keeping the the
diversity in the stock
um
that you never know what you're gonna
get out of those seeds then like there
might be one in there that's just like
b1
louder
um poly hybrids i
i like uh i i breed
i bred the velvet perps down
like five or six generations so it's
pretty stable and then um definitely
bringing them back on other varieties
and
you know it it just uh shows the
diversity of you know what we're working
with
and uh
it's just really special and
i'm
happy to do it so
poly hybrids i say
are the best
for people hunting clonal stock
[Laughter]
yeah
um yeah what no but seriously what nick
said yeah like uh for clone stock yeah
that's kind of
yeah because i've yeah this just depends
on the direction you want to go right
you know who your clients are what your
market is so i mean a lot of this really
is depends on who who your clients are
and where where your market is so it's
kind of like
but yeah as far as poly hybrids um
yeah like if you're which is kind of
good because you you have your poly
hybrid you have you make a an amazing
selection and then you clo you're
working that line there and
which you're gonna get some really nice
diversity and then you can just kind of
work with that because
you know
there's a lot of ways to
you know i don't know it just depends on
i really feel like it depends on like
what you're trying to do a lot of the
times you know that just makes off that
just
makes you know
whatever you know you go in that
direction so
you know for me that's kind of like the
poly hybrid thing is cool because i make
a selection and and run that in my
greenhouse and uh in like a high yield
in you know
uh see a green style and that kind of
works
um then i get to get what i'm looking
for but but lately i mean i've just been
kind of running with you know whatever
different
hype clones and you know bullshit just
because like the market all right
hey everybody um
finn
is looking for
tucker
[Music]
gonna find you okay so
he's not leaving without you but we're
gonna stay really close to this area if
anybody knows tucker what's tucker's
last name
johnson tucker johnson from last name
from where
thank you very much gave you a good
little time
[Applause]
[Music]
everybody
[Applause]
which you know with the price of inputs
you know it seems like everyone's going
to be hitting that route you know
i'm about to go get a truckload of
mistletoe i'm excited for the high
phosphorus
um
yeah it's fun working the lines and i
like to grow for like production for
like a commercial farm like an f3 the f6
and i've seen some f3s that are really
stable and i've seen some f4s that
aren't um but stable stable enough to
blend and you know moongazers here
they're you know
they're doing some smaller batches stuff
which is also kind of like uh it could
be a niche market trend anyway like i
know like smaller batches are easy to
work with and and we're going to see
what that's like when we're going some
true f1s in a few years you know they're
going to see that's going to be fun you
know i have the velvet coffee i'm going
to be starting which is
you know not you know but two stable
lines um bread in together i'm excited
for that and
i also bring a lot of autoflowers and
back cross it uh into that with the
photo periods and just for getting the
here you go what nick
said i'm just gonna just repeat what
jesse said i fucking love how they hyped
up
testing testing
i just absolutely love polly hybrids too
yeah i guess yeah i didn't know about
cloning but i just love to find them and
breed them and then just kind of do the
whole cycle again we keep our males
pretty close
like just far enough and downwind so
i love each every of each of our 600
plants to
have like one seed in it so if i find
some pheno that i didn't breed i can
just i'll plant that and if it's a male
i'll use it if it's a female i'll
definitely seed it up
that's it
sweet yeah
i like if you're looking for hash
if you're looking for the best hash
varieties you gotta go find the poly
hybrids and look at the back stock the
lineage in there and all the stuff
should be from other
hash varieties too so
so yeah yay for poly hybrids uh we
should never like look down on that yay
for inbred lines we love them yay for
the back crosses we could get into that
and i have a whole my own kind of way of
back crossing but
um back to generation even next
generation but anyway
um thanks thanks for listening you guys
we're going to wrap it up thanks for
coming out everybody
stem peer panel
[Applause]
you know we're hanging out come talk
uh
there's a lot to talk about
feel the light
[Applause]
what nick said
[Music]
you