[Music]
we got all kinds of stuff we're doing a
collaboration actually that's cold
Adam and I have the demo out
collaboration and that's going through
seeds here now in the very future
basically we have all the probably start
off with explaining who we are
yeah let's do that
obviously everybody knows right but
let's start with you first yeah so my
name is James loud I've been breeding
for over ten years I've been with
working with the plant for over 25 years
I started a company called loud seeds in
the Netherlands and in Spain in 2013 I'm
writing a book on breeding and currently
I'm reading everything regs films auto
flower genetics and I'm working on a
whole bunch of different projects
stabilizing genetics for the longest
time I was bringing a lot of F ones like
everybody because the demand and now I'm
kind of gearing towards AG product that
can be sold to big AG and so my name is
Adam Dunn and I've been growing since
around 93 sort of seriously and that was
in Amsterdam I've you know I started to
seek company back when I when it was
more of a because I wanted to bring
American genetics to Europe that was
kind of my goal at the time because I
felt it was a little stagnant and you
know lo and behold here we are 25 years
later and it's like the Europeans are
looking towards America again because of
the you know I feel like the heart and
soul of cannabis is sort of here here in
California here in America where I live
in Colorado there's no spots all over
the states but the the passion has
always been here so I've kind of
followed that like again like when I
went to Amsterdam I was 19 years old
didn't realize I was gonna be working
for sensi seeds which I did for about
three years and then start my own seed
company and it was all based on just
seeing that the all the customers were
and also here I am an American living in
Amsterdam and every guy who walks
through the door is a you know living in
some small town and got some seats from
Neville a few years ago and now they
came back and Neville is nowhere to be
found and we filled the void you know
and so it's kind of like those special
times make it easy now to kind of you
know interject into the into the
industry as far as it's all cycles you
know if you're a grower you realize that
you know five years ago you know people
had a different taste and right now the
gaps are getting kind of tighter and
tighter because less people know what's
going on so it's good to be onstage and
hanging out with these guys and that
James back in Amsterdam when he came
over there he was also like another wave
because it's like every few years a new
wave of American Burton Grover's goes
over there and they all have the same
sort of thing where they see it because
it's like a sea of genetics over there
and you kind of get lost in the shuffle
so we're here to kind of clear that up
cool I'm James bean I'm CEO of sea cheer
now calm I ran what I believed to be the
largest banks in those states if not
that world I work with 52 breeders I'm a
breeder hunter if you will one thing
about working with all these different
breeders is all wood all the breeders
that work with all work with a different
male as far as I'm concerned that's the
only way to really separate who's doing
work who's not doing work for instance
if you bred with an MK ULTRA across it
with the coast out cookie
I really can't represent that like you
didn't do any work here you took
somebody else's cookie who will say st.
George st. George did the cookie I
believe 60 miles is cooking it took them
kale check cross to put them together
and they you know mkay cookies I don't
want to represent that you know this
guy's not getting paid off of it
why won't I represent the guy who did
the thing through the first place a lot
of the old-timers and so I have to do a
lot of sleuthing if you will to figure
out the history of things and make sure
the stories all collide and they surely
all make sense but it's been my thing
and I've worked with 52 All American
breeders right now so we happy about
that yeah just just to add on breeding
with males you know I feel like the
second you sell seeds sold lots of
different varieties over the years and
the second use of those seeds if you
have males and they're I'm totally happy
with people using my males but I feel
like there's integrity involved if
you're gonna use them to start a seed
line that's different than if you're
using them to create other strains if
you know it's again is this sort of like
it comes down to you can do whatever you
want with it but the minute you start
making money it starts to become a
little bit tense because it's very much
like music I always try to put it out
like that like like look we we create
something that's a sort of a vibe and
it's a thing but it's actually a you
know it's work behind it so like if you
I give you some seed if I sell you seed
yes you own it to a point but I feel
like when you start to make seeds from
those seeds and sell those see
self-preservation of not trying to
either have to either just work with the
person and get their kind of blessing
you don't have to but it feels like it
gives a better vibe to the whole
situation and you know and it'd be great
if they kicked down but that doesn't
ever happen I'm like I could be living
off bubblegum for the rest of my life
just on the amount of people that have
used it in crosses but I've never seen a
dime you know I talked to bog about it
at one point and he didn't even know
where it came from and I was kind of
like well you do realize that the guy
that you got it from got it from me and
that still doesn't you know you know it
wasn't that long ago it was a couple
years ago and he had no clue but it's
you know at the end of the day I think
if you work with other people's stuff
it's nice to have some arrangement
whether it be verbal you know we're just
doing a collab like we're doing with the
done loud series is he selected a sage
and sour male around three out of five
hundred right
yes dead water 50 males 50 there's 50
males that I selected from over from the
Tony sees the tunnel seeds I had 50
males and then I went in and I took
males that represented like oh gee cush
that were more shorter I took something
that were more on that Hayes side and
then there was one that was really
sourish when his stem Robin so I figured
using that cuz breeding F ones the more
variety you have the more diversity you
have the more options you'll have to
select from you know from the progeny
mm-hmm
yeah and something that was about your
as you told me yeah I harvested the
seeds over a year ago and they're just
you've been tested they're about to go
online here shortly
right and so it was one of those like
yeah sure you know that's the whole
point of putting out regular seeds
because III saw the market change and
you know it really threw the idea for
feminized seeds in Halle which works you
know totally started their Dutch passion
seed company was kind of the first guy
who really put it out commercially and I
don't know just somehow right out of the
gate I just didn't like it like I was
really against the idea of sort of
pigeon holing your work or kind of like
giving it a dead end it felt like
because if everybody starts to work with
only feminized and this is also you know
in a place where everything's about
money and all and right everybody's just
money money money and the Dutch are
notoriously lazy and the Spanish are
notoriously lazy growers none of them
want to do selection they just want it
to work right they don't want to they
don't like F ones they don't like things
that are have any kind of variables but
in a way like I feel like when you buy
seeds
whether it's f1 and a lot of times f1 is
where all the magics happening anyway so
you're actually doing better than
letting a guy screw it all up and get it
to like f3 and have terrible selections
and just somehow miss the mark and now
you're the victim of their terrible
selection you know what I mean where as
with f1 it's like you have to if it's a
true f1 which is almost impossible these
days because whether or not you know it
most stuff is interrelated in some way
shape or form and
closer to videos think a lot of times
where you're like oh actually those are
cousins laser cousins and so what do you
think is gonna happen is you're gonna
end up you know you always have shiny
examples in the trailer park right but
it doesn't mean that that the genetics
are strong right so it's like one of
those situations where you're gonna have
one or two pop up wow this is beautiful
but if you're looking for stability
that's when you really want to run down
the line and get it 2 F 2 F 3 F 4 and
the thing is the problem is we don't
actually want that you know or an
industry that wants that because once
you're in agriculture they don't want to
have any variables right they want it to
be exactly the same
yeah but the biggest problem that we're
running into like stabilizing stuff to
an f7 and that's where you take it back
cross it with an inbred line to 7
generations where you can stabilize it
is a heterosis the black of vigor so you
have this lack of vigor now you either
need to breed parallel lines and cross
those together or you need to back cross
it to the original f1 and that thing is
is with that you want to breed when
you're breeding that inbred line you
want to breathe stuff that's very
similar so you have less Fino typical
variation when you make that back cross
but again like I think a lot of us you
know unless you are growing on a scale
and that with a price point that's so
important and you can't have any
variables if you want to grow that way
yeah sure but for the average guy and
especially for what you're gonna get
when you get a selection of seeds that
still have that hybrid vigor based on
the fact that there's still some there's
there's like an actual you know
hopefully they're not too interrelated
but at the same time even with that you
can sometimes get you know shining
examples coming out and really I think a
lot of times now it's separating
yourself from all their other guys and
people finally got to the point where
you know they've seen these clone onlys
that have been around for 20 plus years
sometimes they're more trouble than
they're worth you know that man because
of the other day maybe they have viruses
or problems and and or they're just you
know been worked way too hard so it's
like sometimes nice when you see a whole
tray of new fresh genetics and then
that's like literally again where the
magic is happening and then it comes
strictly down to the selection and
that's where people can either make or
break
yeah yeah yeah yeah welcome to the gun
show
well you know and it's really
interesting because I see a lot of work
being done by a lot of breeders out
there and I I don't see a lot of novel
genetics coming out I think one of the
things that's kind of sticking this up
right now is people are buying based on
THC levels and dispensaries especially
on the rec market because they go
industries are buying on sea levels yeah
so the first thing they do is they go in
and they're gonna buy the highest THC
and well you know I understand that but
that we've smoked a lot of different
cultivars different strains that are 14%
like Sour Diesel that'll knock your
knock your socks off compared to some of
those that tested 30% well yeah and it's
really down to like I mean how many
times have you gone to some place and
had got some really shitty looking weed
that you were like this is definitely
not gonna get me high and then somehow
you're like in your hotel room all
fucking cool oh dude I don't know then
we got that high and I've been smoking
all this candy and all these all their
strains but you're just so used to that
you know what I mean like in just
tickling those other spots it doesn't
maybe last very long after the second
drug or like I don't know how that did
it but it fucking it got a super big do
those green eye crack and that could be
like a nine percent or it's you know
super low even lower but it's just
because it's the right Pro you know can
cannabinoid profile at that point for
you yeah and changeably methyl is good
it's funny because some of the shittiest
looking weed back in the day was the
best we had cat piss that was one of my
all-time favorite strains still is and
I've been seeing it in 20 years the real
cat piss and you know we've been I've
been talking to people I talked to JJ
when we're at lunch a couple weeks ago
and he was saying it's probably from an
a5 lineage well I was told originally
was nl5 Hayes cross but that really
doesn't make sense with that but that
strain was lost 20 years ago at the big
gunfight in California with AJ's and
nerves well you know yeah that's gonna
say like the the victim of your own
success was probably the biggest problem
back in the day is at all like
everyone's always like looking you know
where's that old skunk and where is that
old skunk and it's like the reality is
it's because those old skunk smelled
like fucking skunk
they got people arrested and you know
they're walking to their local shop and
they're stink like a skunk and they tell
the cop and the cop would you know
follow over to their house whatever all
those people got caught and that's why
like there was a point in time where you
know people would come to Holland didn't
ask you like do you have anything that
doesn't have any smell to it you know it
may be like you know there's things that
don't have a lot of smell but that's
usually an indicator of good weed right
but it's also the fact that that's the
reason why a lot of people find lost
those and then the cactus had that
lingering fucking 1/10 of a gram would
make your whole house smell yeah the
premotor filter days yeah well that was
like from the early 90s maybe 93 to 2001
and it smelled they had this strong
ammonia smell with skunk and it was like
that's it was after that dry no it was
after it dried and it like some of those
like the a5 haze has that it's that
really it's accurate almost it's like it
burns your nose and then with a skunk
along with it it would just like
literally a tenth of a gram if you had
it in your shirt pocket
you'd be looking for the bud like for
four hours and that's it's been gone for
a long time but a lot of those old
school smells I mean I think they've
evolved but I haven't seen a handful of
them in many years I think the other
funny thing too is that we're like back
in the day everybody was drying in these
like dank little nasty spots and growing
and drying in the same room all the time
because that's all they had and it was
like the only place that ventilation was
the grow room so you just dried it in
the grill room and they'd still have the
pots in the corner and the things kind
of breathe there's some decomposing
going on and it would all end up in the
bud too because you know how it was he'd
be like kind of smells like a basement
and I think that was the thing about
that particular we did it never really
dried very good it wasn't a very easy
drying like thing it was very leafy
right and very but but it had that very
heavy oil coat on it so like you know
the oil air but which is not dry
particularly it was greasy yeah and so I
think a lot of those strains I mean it's
funny because the ones that are the most
difficult
back in the day at that moment they were
kind of difficult to grow and not very
great yielding and the only reason you
kept it around this because of that
particular function and you know that's
a lot to do with I think the success and
failure of a lot of strains because
people now or so not only is the THC but
you know as a grower when you have to
grow a plant that's needs support by 15
Stakes or it just grows like a soldier
you know theoretically doing way better
if you grow and that's why strains like
yeah like blue dream become popular
because it's like yeah believe it you
could pretty much shit in the reservoir
and then you'll yield at least two
pounds I hate sort of lesson well I
think the the success of blue gem is
based on the fact that it's stored
really well compared to other we'd like
there's a lot of strains that are great
when you first harvest them and though
if you're lucky enough to be that guy
who's that you know got it within a
certain time frame it's still got that
pop to it but then after a little while
it dies off and blue dreams the opposite
where if you store that shit and sit on
her for a year or two years and pop it
out it's like that actually still smells
pretty good like it always gets better
yeah it's better exactly so age is
really well I mean so that that was that
was a bonus yeah like so limonene I
believe limonene makes the weed
deteriorated definitely like shortens
the time well this is a story that I was
told by somebody in this room so maybe
he can confirm if it's true but back in
the day when they would put rubber bands
around bags of haze it would eat through
the rubber band is that true mysterious
man in the back yeah mon-sol so the fact
that it would eat through rubber bands
kind of tells you that it's got a
different sort of reaction than other
sort of because he could put that same
rubber band around some other plan and
nothing would happen to it so there's
something going on there yeah and no no
around a bag of weed so it's just like
like literally through everything man it
was just like it's like enter the tops
of the seals of the things right on the
tops of the mason jars and stuff they
would get sore to eat up so you can
imagine that there's some
a reaction without anything happening
going on there and that means shits
working on your brain probably
something's going down by day I digress
yeah so as far as like we can definitely
talk about Europe and how they kind of
homogenized all the strains and and also
oh yeah anything was evil people
invented cheese no I mean the thing is
it was really like it goes in cannabis
has these waves and like things don't
change for say six or seven years
sometimes in these little waves and then
all of a sudden there's a massive change
and and it's usually based on just
exposure from wherever like and so
Holland had that thing where you know
those those people that brought genetics
there in the beginning you know blew
people's minds because they were trying
to grow a bunch literally of like bird
seed and shit they were not they were
not doing their selection you know and
all of a sudden it took the outsiders to
come there wake him up you know and and
the problem is a day they also had a
business running right they had a
business model that they're trying to
keep going that was totally illegal yet
illegal but whatever and so at the end
of the day now the people here figure
out that that's actually really hard
when you have customers coming in every
single day demanding the same quality
we'd like which as you know as a grower
it's really hard to deliver year-round
and stuff and so I think that they were
the first ones to take that model and
try to work with it and so from a
breeders point of view I feel like they
did a great job of keeping it alive for
everybody sure on a creative side they
just didn't quite have that creative
thing go and they were didn't care about
weed that's the problem all the people I
cared about weed there were Americans
they were when they were breeding for
different things
breeding in Europe I feel like the the
traits they were breeding for was vigor
and yield course and smell and not
really smell because look what happened
with OG kitchen over there so Oh G cush
which amazing came from California the
second at hip how to get there
we should probably have well you want to
come out to clear that up so yeah so og
cush I feel like the seeds I I bought
seeds of OG Kush in probably 2009
waiting my seeds of could yeah well no
that was his og cush times white widow
and maybe that crossed OG Kush or
something but it definitely wasn't a
very good representation of OG Kush it
was garbage - no it was feminized and I
realized the issues like all the wrong
thing you went for like literally like
wrong everything yeah give me that
feminized
og cush something from Europe that
really you know I must have been oh yeah
the amount of I'm not going on and that
is terrible yeah I did ninety-eight
percent chance it wasn't I'd say it was
just white widow probably I would guess
to me yes right and so there's a there's
a white widow male that people use over
there for sure that's been out and used
like no other
all the big seed companies used it back
in the day for their feminizing but that
kind of goes into what James was talking
about earlier about giving credit to
where credit to do I think a lot of the
in and I'm totally guilty of this I
released the AJ's Sour Diesel pack a
long time ago but it wasn't a J's Sour
Diesel as AJ sour diesel crossed with
white widow we were working with some
guys over there and then they put that
back on the the AJ Sour Diesel cut that
I had and so we called AJ Sour Diesel
but like moving forward I feel like we
were doing the wrong thing back then and
we didn't really know it I saw Kim 23
the other day I was like what the hell
is m23 so I mean it's it's getting to
that point now where people have already
forgotten like it's been the thing about
the ho G in Europe was you know like
when it first arrived there of course
people who smoked a lot of weed like
we're like well this is good but why all
the people over there they don't even
like really strong weed like if you give
it's too strong nobody wants it like
what like this is the exact opposite of
reason why we're growing
but you know that was part of the thing
was figuring out the packaging of this
product and which was now kind of like
like they kind of like as long as the
buds were a certain weight and size hey
it was good you know I mean they don't
want to think about it too much they
wanted to really put it on the scale
lesson on a brick you come in there with
a big giant giant bud it was like no
this is not happening you know who
looking crazy of course
and so everything had to be toned down
that was the first thing you learn as an
American grower over there was like
probably should tone it down a little
bit yeah that's just a hard place to
grow in that's got to be like one of the
worst places well from readers point of
view though the one thing that I did
find interesting was that a lot of the
seeds that like that we would grow there
if you imagine where they're growing
right it's like dank and nasty and it's
not like California or something like
that right then so then you get those
seeds and somebody magically like flies
home with them wherever they took them
and then unbelievable right like those
plants just fucking loved life whereas
when you grow in a beautiful climate and
then those seeds end up going back to
like Holland or somewhere shooting like
that I bet that they're not so happy you
know what I mean like they're not
they're not as a Stoke to like when they
come out they're like what yeah but I
came from California I want to go home
and so you know there's memories with
and and epigenetics with everything and
in like when you grow you know for the
right reasons and you see the plan at
the right time and everything comes all
the things are working you almost like
as you're handing those seeds to
somebody you just know like guaranteed
like those are those are gonna be so
good you know because yeah it was all
good whereas if you have a situation
where yeah they were in a room and then
the lights went out cuz the power went
out for three days and then the plants
kind of suffered a little bit and the
seeds still came through it's not like
you're gonna not sell any of them but at
the same time you do know that there was
a little stress involved on that
particular run and it is again it's it's
epigenetics it's like something where we
we as breeders try to put something into
it and that the problem with Holland was
a lot of those guys it was all fat it
was it was without even them that none
of them cared you know they smoked
shaggy's in tobacco from
you're like but you grow weed all day
long no I smoked a pack girls guys
didn't breed right half of them they
just buy seeds from other people you
know I feel like that was the biggest
thing over there yeah and you know sad
but it's you don't part of the things
every time you see a mislabeled seed
sold or cloned going out with the wrong
name on it you know it's just like
causing just endless problems down the
road like so many people are gonna say
oh I've smoked this and it was either
shitty or it was great and it could be
the opposite the way or no credit is
given where it should be done and yeah
so from a growers point for from a
breeders point of view I kind of feel
like if you're in the perfect places
sometimes not the perfect place you know
so that was the one thing they had going
for them is it anything that came out of
their seem to thrive I just allegedly
thank you also thank you allegedly thank
you
[Laughter]
it's all right here yeah yeah I mean I
consult thank you very much but yeah I
cancel for a lot of people when I travel
a lot so there's always good food I used
to be a chef as well so I graduated the
cordon bleu top of my class a long time
ago yeah thank you no thank you very
much appreciate you know it's great to
be able to get people if you know if
people come out of their comfort zone to
come to a thing like this I got a little
little a little bit of heart and
dedication to the work that we're doing
and that's also part of this industry is
kind of a lot of camaraderie between
people which is also nice and like we
like our collab yeah customers Jameson
it's big too you know I think a lot of
people are losing that they just
expected customers and it's one of the
things we're big on is ancas customer
service if you have a situation with the
back you know you email us you tell us
what happened I'm going to send you a
free back no questions asked I mean I
can ask you how you germinate of them
but my way is not always the right way
your yeah just because I do it one way
doesn't mean you do it that way and the
way we works you're not supposed to
germinate in many ways don't get him wet
or dirty so if you have a situation with
them with things to do is just replace
that back and then you're happy to go
again and then I have happy customers
like that so I appreciate you coming out
and and Shanti's cuz I think everybody
should definitely grow but definitely
grow from a seed that's it's a big
difference between buying a clone and
taking home putting in some dirt they're
like oh how I got a clone in order
taking a little seedling and actually
watching a pop and enjoying it and then
has a tapper that's the potential it
could be they're all gonna be different
you know it's a lot
awesome brings its seeds look under your
seat everybody and that's also the cool
part like as you see like giving away
like you know from such a small thing
compared to like clothes you're kind of
working with other people's selection
right so like dude you're not gonna be
able chances of you growing a better
version of the guy who gave you the
clones is pretty slim you might be a
better grower and you might get a
fraction of a bit better but when you go
from see there's like a rolling dice
every time so like you might just hit
that you just might nail it right where
you just like a hole man not only is it
bigger faster or tasty or whatever all
the things you're looking for
and in the best part is like a lot of
things it's like I used to always joke
that you know the best thing about the
cannabis industry is the fact that
there's so much testing involved and
work involved and trying to figure it
out right so like that was never never
felt like work sitting and doing a fee
no hun and having all these different
strains to kind of know these different
cultivars at the same time and narrowing
it down to one and you know tell me
where the breeders don't even have the
best cuts anymore half the guys that are
selling their seeds the seeds here now
half the time the the best phenotype is
probably out with the consumer I've
actually been at the booth or someone
come up with that and to me I think
that's the true representation of a good
breeder he's trying to improve the line
you should come back with something
better than he has if you don't you
should be disappointed if you don't have
a keeper if you don't get something
better than yes I think that's a good
representation of that is I like
breeders when they bring me seeds or
everyone to bring me gear that I love
flower with it too and so that lets me
know that they grew an out they tested
on it passed all their checks dollar all
their boxes and they're comfortable with
it and so I think that's really big when
you guys go for for buying and selecting
genes is make sure whoever you're behind
from testing them out you know look for
pictures make sure they give you data
make sure they give you info because
they if a real breeder did it or if they
to do it for one they'll have the mail
service it's a lot of things right there
a lot of things were accident so we
don't have the mail they didn't do it
there's a lot of guys like JJ doesn't
keep his mails you know I mean there's
some people everybody kind of has their
own style too I see other funny thing
about breeding it's like we're all doing
the same thing but we have kind of our
own style it's a look like it's like
making hash same sort of thing we're all
kind of trying to do the same thing but
somehow somebody does it better than the
other guy and it's just because they
have better patients or their timing or
their their their temperature sort of
knowledge of being on point is a little
bit on you know better they don't know
usually it's a lazy factor you don't I
mean it's one of those anything that's
hard to do like making a lazy he doesn't
keep his own doesn't keep males it just
kind of moves on keeps on moving on
which you know is good if you're if you
keep your if you really are good at sort
of seeing what's coming up around the
corner but I do try to keep males as
long as I can that's kind of one of
those if I can you know yeah what's so
difficult keeping me let me for you
I mean I've lost most of my males but
now I have a handful that I'm keeping it
a nursery and now with the rec market
we're able to kind of move forward with
keeping things alive a lot longer tissue
culture I think is gonna be a good
solution currently I don't think it's
ideal but I think it's not promoting
Klan stir - yeah it's not practical yet
I mean it's great for for personal in
keeping it like for your in house sort
of being able to clean things up that's
kind of where right now
yeah and just meristem propagation well
now that we can recognize like a V roads
and viruses and all these things that we
can actually clean up and then put
through tissue culture get a new start
of that plant that is clean and healthy
I mean there's there's so many old
plants that need to go through tissue
culture yeah it's I think that's that's
only way that people on large-scale
production are gonna be able to do it
anyways just because they need to have
clean fresh healthy claims and a start
and be able to look back and put a date
on it you know because you could just
imagine how many facilities got ruined
without you know by taking in that again
that's the problem with clones in
general is yours
there's pathogen problems you know
there's viroids and there's hundred
mildew and if you have any kind of
medium going with it it's all that - you
know like how did Europe get better
powdery mildew oh no I definitely
brought that now is that 100% verified I
never seen it before and I was super
proud because I had OG and and sour D
and I was all stoked and had my friends
from Minnesota come into town and the
first time they said is uh dude you got
pm and I'm like what like what are you
talking about it I literally did not
even see it and it was just at that
stage where it was just coming in enough
that if you once you see it you can't
unsee it now all of a sudden you're like
oh my god is everywhere like it's and it
wasn't bad but it was just coming on and
so you know they're from Minnesota
they're they're used to seeing that
they're like no problem get some time
exude it's got to get to get to work on
it but if I didn't have them come
through I would have just completely
wiped out my things but that's because I
brought those cuts from here literally
from Cali and straight to Amsterdam and
just like yep there you go all those
cuts I gave you so I got what did you
use because there was no eagle to pony
over there I used to I went for sulfur
uh early on just but it was also burners
yeah and the burners were kind of a
bitch because they they get everywhere
like and now I realize I would never use
burners I'd only use micronized sulfur
because that way you can apply it
directly to where you want to apply it
and not just like I'm going to nuke the
entire facility because we can never get
it out like that stuff is like fire
because you like you feel like you're in
a firecracker factory like okay this is
not good no it's not good and it's
because it's micronized or because it's
been the burners it's going up and
getting like so for me my problem was I
was using a lot of light members at the
time
and it was so slick that it made my
wheels on the light members just spin
and I wouldn't that's not come in the
room and be like god damn sulfur burners
so I stopped using them for that but
then I realized later like man I just
didn't like the way that it was applied
but it worked I mean it definitely got
rid of it but there's a there's a
product called
micro Thyle dispersant it has two S's on
it it's a it's amazing it's micronized I
used to use the brown bags of micronized
sulfur and then put a wetting agent this
has it all in there and it's like $50
for fifty pounds you can buy it I you
can order it for you typing in Google it
shows up and it's perfect in every way
it's good for us it might it's good for
powdery mildew if you have to use it if
you have to use a sulfur product and I
believe it's all recertified yeah it's
amazing when you because that because of
the bad taste of my mouth literally from
from the burners I just never really got
it was like no sulfur did it not gonna
do it and then about a year ago somebody
again same problem someone gave me some
phones and then I was like all you
mother fuckers I can't get into this go
like yeah the nuke oh my so I hit him
with I was like this I got to do him
this time I got to do it I don't want to
just go straight to try to use something
chemical because it's like you gotta you
gotta it's the only way to do proper
organic is to start organic you know I
mean I've done work it all the way
through cuz it's pretty much you know
it's in there so use sulfur and I was
amazed I was like wow this soap does
this work better than all the other
things I've been using so and she well
we used to think powdery mildew was
systemic at least I did and then I
learned that you can have Grove powdery
mildew it's not systemic so yeah it's
way well it's just one of those things
where it latches it gets into the plant
technically so it feels like it's
systemic but it's not it's it's not
permanent I mean it can be it can be
beat but yeah I think I think just it's
a lot easier when you're growing plants
that don't get powdery mildew it's just
like hey look this plan doesn't get
powdery mildews like if I could just
grow that like if that's possible and
you can somehow you know get rid of that
sour D or that cut that you actually are
just so
attached to that always gets it you know
which is always a problem there's
certain plants that just do pushes
pushes are really susceptible typically
the power to mildew just in Europe it
was HP 13 that was the worst right that
plant came around and just anybody who
got that cut especially a lot of the
Dutch growers didn't recognize what it
was and they were all proud when they
handed it to you and you're like whoa
what's all that they're like what do you
mean it's all trichomes or something I'm
like no that is powder fuckin mildew and
then they've won see once they figured
it out yeah it was like you know dude I
thought everything I have because what
it's exactly what all my plants look
like back home so yeah it's definitely
like that particular cut was a nightmare
and soma sold a lot of that a lot of
people that was just around for a short
amount of time long enough to really
infect a lot of people's gardens so but
that wasn't me technically it's somebody
else right but that wouldn't seem to be
inherent and that there's an old plant
from New York in Hawaii and all that
that plant which is another one of those
weird think about strains is that you'll
notice that there's a lot of drama based
around a lot of these strains and it's
like there's certain ones like HP 13
because especially because it was a
Hawaii New York kind of thing drama like
unbelievable amounts people a lot of
groups broke up over it fights
infighting Sour Diesel he got his name
from being a causing people to become
sour from you know not lack of getting
access you know I mean so there was just
like and you know obviously og has its
own history and it wasn't necessarily as
brutal as some of the other ones but
I've seen other strains causing all
sorts of drama and it's because I think
it's just because well back in the day
it was power struggle more or less and
now it's the same powers forever let's
just in a in a legal way you know yeah
which is worse of course way worse is
way different you know the white market
in the black market way different
traditional market traditional
traditional
yes the traditional market yeah and you
know used to be more honor code let's
say or something like that and now it's
we worked on handshakes back in the day
it was it was handshakes we didn't sign
papers it was like you work with people
to eat trust you get burned occasionally
and you grow and you learn who you can
work with and you work with those people
and then the shitheads you get rid of
now it's like you gotta sign papers and
well yeah there's a lot of names lots of
contracts there's a lot of lunches now
it's what you get you get a lot of lot
of lunches everybody getting a fuck
little lunches a couple dinners usually
at that point they've done the brain
drain enough to like there's somebody in
the back just the sketchpad and and
that's the thing about this industry's
like it's very much
you know saturated in many ways but in a
weird way reinventing itself all the
time too so I think if you can kind of
stay slightly ahead of the curve and or
just sort of figure out your your
position within this industry you can be
comfortable but at the same time it
sucks to try to be on that front end of
what's going on because things are until
it goes federally legal there's no point
of even investing a ton of money and
trying to put all your energy into it
you know you're gonna get your ass
handed to you the minute it goes into
that zone so you kind of almost want to
either had you've already been doing it
you know and I mean taking that risk
early on because now the the to get
involved it is kind of a bit much
and on a breeding point of view he's
nice because it's a hub can be like a
hobby style side thing you could you
could go full steam but again you're
gonna see it's gonna get less and less
interesting the higher up you go up the
ladder because yeah wow your hands are
tied once again because you're now
limited to these particular strains that
may have already been put through the
system and now it's like well how am I
gonna do anything with that because it
has nothing to do with what I'm doing so
well then even trademarks so we had the
trademark for loud for the longest time
me and my partners with loud seeds and
it got to a point where it just wouldn't
be enforceable everyone wanted a loud
Kevin we were the first we're the first
there was no other loud
for us but then like 2014 people started
hearing there's a lot of farms and in
Kansas now and Oklahoma not Kansas but
like and there's there's another loud
company in Seattle but there's probably
a hundred different loud companies now
so it gets to a point because it's not
federally illegal to where how do you
enforce it and how much money do you
really want to spend enforcing something
like a trademark yeah it's it's
unenforceable at this point like anybody
who goes down that sort of rapid hole is
either well funded and they don't care
about losing money because that's about
the only people that you could really do
it or or they just don't quite get to
how the system works because once you
get there's no way to take it to the
next level because the next level is
gonna laugh at you and say well it's not
legal so what I'm gonna do so you can
only do it at a state level which
doesn't make it nationwide anyway how
can you be you can't be nationwide if
you're doing it at a state level right
so there's you kind of get yeah you're
stuck yeah if you look at like runts
Gorilla Glue skittles these names these
guys have had uphill battles because of
their names it was a dumb idea I think
that I think the fact that people can't
think outside the box and put something
at least sort of original like I mean
it's like if it's not Lucasfilm or
Disney or Nestle or you know one of
these big curtains like who really
thinks that they're gonna be able to
take that anywhere federally once it
gets to the federal level they gonna get
Tom they're gonna get creamed because
there's gonna be like 50 lawyers
laughing at you like you really put all
your money and just use naming
everything after Star Wars like come on
it's like a little more original that's
and that's the problem is that the
cannabis industry is kind of like always
worked off of like we get it we all love
puns and we all love to ripoff logos and
we all think it's funny when you come up
with something that looks like something
but you really got to think like okay if
I'm gonna put too much energy into this
I might get my ass handed to me just
like a hit man with his debauchee nose
you know it's like you you you copied it
a little too close I mean it was a pipe
that was not a you know
copyright infringement in any way shape
or form except for the fact that it was
called the dabba Chino and it looked
like their thing so Starbucks you know
they won so it's just a matter of time
before those people get caught up I
think when they you know put too much
energy into that kind of stuff so I
think with trademarks either gotta be
dedicated because we've trademarked as
many strains as I could a lot of stuff I
couldn't trademark like it couldn't
trademark bubblegum but then somehow
Simon from seriously it's gotten too
rigid I was like wait how did you do
that they told me I wouldn't have that
because it was too general but there's
you know but they did give me MKULTRA
which which I thought was funny so I'm
like oh so I got the trademark for
MKULTRA is that here over I got that
here that's later you know and so it's
like I'm like oh so I can get government
experiments and trademark their names
but I can't trademark the word bubblegum
for seeds but I think it's well we call
it is like surrounding the the wagon
right now so basically you just cover
your ass and trademark everything around
the product and when you legally can do
the product when you're in a state like
California you do it but it costs a
fuckload of money dude like we've spent
tens if not hundreds of thousands over
the last 15 years on just trademarks
that we never ever ever ever used in any
way shape trademarks and website names
except having that little TM and knowing
it's real you know it has something
behind it but it's rough right yeah
you're all over this stuff it's on bitch
and you've got 52 growers who are all
like have no clue half of them or what
they're even doing when it comes to
business right everything imagine you
can't tell them that though nobody I
know cuz I'm one of them I'm one of them
I know exactly I'm like like how he's
doing this
oh no well we're doing
and that is a part of the industry is
like we got to make it up as we go along
because yeah when it comes to seasonal
pleasures well see it's always weird cuz
seeds are like one of those things where
it's either the most benign thing
because you can't get high from it right
did you just City think you have a
thousand pounds of seeds in the room and
we couldn't get high from it we found
some weed that was mixed in between it
but when you grow that thousand pounds
you could take up the whole the whole
town you could get the whole town you
know you can get those everybody high
for miles you know so it's like the most
dangerous thing in the world in one way
to them and it's the most benign because
if you get the right guy he's just like
yeah yeah yeah nobody you know explained
there's not well more than 0.3 percent
THC in an entire bag of some seeds so
we're kind of in a weird zone where it's
theoretically we should be able to sell
those things in every 7/11 and
everywhere in town because they they are
just like any other CBD product out
there they're 0.3 they're like they
follow all those things but we haven't
quite got there yet so and when's that
coming
I don't know that the farm bill passed
the 2018 fungo pass which stated
anything below point zero three percent
THC was considered Hamptons was to be
removed from the control show Substances
Act which legally made seeds legal it
can only have there's you take ten seeds
you take hundred seed you take 10,000
seats squish them all up you're not
gonna get a 0.3% THC it's just not gonna
happen
there's no cannabinoid to the embryo of
a seed whatsoever and so it's really
hard you have to explain your case to
like the mastercard visa and tell them
why they're different when I shut you
down did they actually listen to you
that there was lawyers yeah but yeah so
we're in this weird zone where it's like
you know theoretically we should be able
to you know conduct business like
anybody else and sell our stuff to
anybody but we have to be you know
that's why I mean I only have he's my
only distributor because of that I kind
of I don't trust the having it because I
feel like we're still are kind of like
overstepping still by the fact that
we're crossing state lines things
getting weird like the whole seed game
is definitely one of those things where
it's it's it's kind of like the Wild
West still out there you know and it is
but it's also the best part of the
industry because of the fact that is
changing and evolving and getting you
know genetic spread out throughout the
world
yeah people you know that was one of my
mottos of our company was always drop
seeds not bombs because we felt like
every time somebody bought a pack of
seeds they were going to their
neighborhood and just like you know like
there's some pretty sure DNA trademark
that they're ten years behind I do my
friends that's fine but and and so me
used it too for a long time so I'm going
to go out there and what I always said
drive seed bomb so I was like are you
kidding good shirts posters come on but
but I mean we don't really care we want
more people to use the motto because the
idea is it's real you know I mean like
when when you see neighborhoods change
because somebody grew some fireweed it's
like especially back in the day now of
course it's kind of people are spoiled
as usual oh there was times when people
would come to the shop in Amsterdam
and tell me how like by buying a pack of
Chocolate Chunk seeds or whatever they
bought at that time it went back to
their placing screwed up really well
everything changed you know what I mean
like now all of a sudden people are like
finally knew what good we was you know
and that's the good feeling as a grower
cuz that's like with clones you don't
get that because there's no trap you
know very a little bit yeah you might
want to you might go here to there and
but it's always like it's weird just
like a clones make people weird very
important there's a lot of hoarding
going on and a lot of sneakers that goes
to the cat suit Bluebird cat because
were familiar with that I can't see
Bluebird online you know as a genetics
out but he bought the he bought the
bubble cutter cut and I do in 2001 when
it had a little too much money and not
more money than he had cents they bought
the cow for five to five hundred bucks
after you got it yeah so you guys have
all treated greatly compliant we did I
called him said you can't give away cats
you can't sell clones
he's like hey that wasn't that wasn't
part of the fucking deal and so for
about four years online if you emailed
him he'd send you a cut only that you
only covered it being you have to give
away five cuts and so if you were
anybody and you mailed him you know you
that clone and that's how Bubba got out
everywhere and that's a if you can
imagine like you're in Illinois you're
on the forum sheet you know this guy
emails you the bubble cat you know like
the king of your fucking block like
you've got the fire I stay on the block
everybody loves you they're blowing up
your phone and the guard tubes cigar
tubes you pack a cigar and then you'd
cut the top off get some tobacco mosaic
virus with it here you go yeah have that
have that along with your cut no problem
yeah you you would get the you know
there's small plugs not the standard
rock Wilke of slugs with the small so I
always felt like I was similar I would
do opposite I would cut fresh and I
would stick a whole bunch into like one
piece of rock wool and then wrap that in
plastic and then put that into a poster
tube and then wedge it in there so that
you could flip it over either way and
then that would go through no problem
and and the thing is if you do them when
they're fresh and you don't have any
roots there's no stress right because
when your plant has roots and you bounce
it all around and you take it gets cold
and hot and all that there's there's
again that's the same problem that we
were saying earlier were you kind of
like yeah you kind of it's like you drop
the baby it's like you drop the baby you
know what I mean you're like it's gonna
be fine honey don't worry
and then like third grade you're all I
think it dropped a pretty heart you know
that was a problem and with the can with
these plants you you know you see that
quicker because you'll see one plant
you'll track one plant through and
you'll realize like oh that's the one
that I fuck the root ball up on or
whatever and you will see that that
plant does not succeed as well as the
other ones because it had trauma at that
time so I feel like when you take the
cuts fresh it's like ER thing it's like
you're as long as you get it within a
certain time frame and in the beginning
this is pre 9/11 but I used to we put a
little LED light on the top of the tube
and thinking like oh it's gonna keep the
photo period but then later on I
realized these elbows
the matter and then nowadays you can get
clone tubes you can get the whole clone
box and stuff Isis I still feel like to
send it with roots is unless you're
gonna do it yourself like if you're
gonna transport it in a cooler and bring
it to your friend's house and all that
is cool but the thing you put into a
mailbox that guy just goes ok thanks and
throws it behind him you know that
things on a rough ride so I had I had
clones shipped to my friend's mom's
house back in the day and he forgot to
pick him up and it was 2 weeks later I'm
like so do you have those are they are
they growing and he's like oh I forgot
to get him and sound like fuck they're
probably dead so he went over and got
him and they were still alive they were
just fine and they were in the dark for
two weeks that's crazy so well then you
want roots at that point you want roots
but I've had I've had I've had clones
arrive that like didn't go on a direct
shipment I got stuck for three or four
days and then it's just like
thanks for the box of frog dehydrated or
just basically spinach that's defrosted
I was like wow that didn't work out so
well but I think it's funny because
people think it's so crazy
moving cuts around like that but you
know back in the day it was just like
you got to do what you got to do and it
made a huge difference when they did
when it's such a good feeling when you
get a clone from a thousands of miles
away and get it's a root and you're like
alright you know now it's fucking on
because and plus when it starts fresh
there and it's got no snow to stress
he's like it's all on you at that point
yeah James yeah you stop talking so much
yeah oh man that's all he wanted that's
all he wanted was the breeder drum I
hate to see this oh good you got some
alpha females is it alpha females alpha
her oh my god so tell us what happened
okay so I got the insane I got a banana
hammock the crescendo the some other
cross he gave me as a freebie all of em
I couldn't I just couldn't get it to go
so I was wondering what you guys thought
of it his thumb crosses have you grown
any of them out and so when I said they
didn't go what do you mean like they
either did I didn't germinate or to like
where they showed a little bit out of
this it was like dampening off it just
yeah like showed itself either died but
the ones that I did get to go they were
fired and I've been following him for a
minute
hermaphroditic she's you said taught
yeah so the insane half of them harmed
the other two I kept and I braided I hit
them with a male but like I understand
that's just how fuckin shit goes it's
like you're breeding these crazy-ass
things it I know plants will show their
substrates but they shouldn't show that
know one thing that I think breeders
aren't doing right now and this is
something that I've been doing the last
a year especially especially with all
the feminized work is stress testing you
want to stress this a shit out of the
plants you're breeding with because if
you stress test them then when you breed
with them you're less likely because
those I was talking to rob Clark and
Mojave don't even know I don't know who
they are so we're talking about manisha
species dioecious so Manisha's plants
basically are the plants that
hermaphrodite they have both male and
female organs on them and how do you
feel about that as his feminized lung
like are you seeing that a lot it's not
just him it's a lot of people and I feel
like I you know I I haven't seen it
personally I can't comment on that but I
just feel like a lot of readers aren't
properly stress testing their plants if
they're trying to breed stuff that does
and have hermaphrodite rates I mean the
biggest problem is that a lot of people
you know you can stand behind
feminization and all you want but the
reality is that these plants are just so
fucking sneaky they're not gonna wait
around for you not listening to rules
put it that way when you're like it's
impossible it's like no it is not we've
seen it happen the thing is especially
when we're now talking about millions
and millions and millions of seeds at a
time that are actually getting grown
because before there wasn't that many
places that you could get to see
somebody put down four million seeds you
know I mean but now it's happening
because that's because the hemp crops so
people are seeing four million seeds and
they're going like okay well 275
thousand of those four million are
autoflowering and the other 275 thousand
are doing this and then you know so
there these are real like true numbers
that are coming out that are like okay
now we're gonna get some real data and
yeah I'm not trying to like bash on the
guy like no I mean he has great stuff
but just from the comas problem is that
he's so cocky that like I don't think
he'll gain he will probably replace as
she replaced everything I had plus okay
so here so beef with that I'm just
saying like with all this feminized
stuff and especially with the hemp
that's coming online yeah all the organ
hemp company oh that's like so the hemp
industry they're some of the companies I
feel like that's a scaling issue that
we're seeing with hemp right now it's
cuz what happened is we need all these
hemp seeds cuz everybody's come online
to grow hemp and so everyone's growing
all those hemp seed outdoors and we're
getting cross-pollination
but when these companies first started
they had like intersexual traits of like
Oh point zero two percent which is like
one in 5,000 male or hermaphrodite but
this the fact is that if you're growing
seeds outdoors you're more than likely
gonna get cross pollinated by other
stuff right
whether it's regs from you know THC or
whether it's other hemp you're gonna get
that cross-pollination and I feel like
the government is gonna start regulating
its and make people either grow in
greenhouses that are basically with wet
walls that prevent cross-pollination or
indoors and you can't even sell seeds to
Germany right now like
hemp seeds unless you have phytosanitary
certification and I believe you need a
cgmp certification okay well that's the
most anal place in the world of course
of course they're gonna make you
effective they want legend rockwool yeah
I'm not gonna let you come through easy
yeah and it's but it's cool to see that
because we're figuring out quickly also
that as far as the hemp game goes that
the window for all the CBD guys is
closing a real fast you know I mean like
there gonna be some sore people this
year when they realize that what they
you know thought was gonna be 30 million
dollars worth of something is gonna be
worth three hundred thousand or
something and if they if they can get it
even to process you know I mean that's
that's the issue that we're running into
a lot of bottom oh this is so much hot
so much I imagine what imagine like he
was saying with a cross-pollination
imagine what's gonna happen in both
directions right like there's gonna be a
whole bunch of shitty weed being grown
cuz people are gonna be like oh I got
this fire well when they're growing in
making seeds from seed rather than using
clones so like if you really want to do
breeding I feel like it's more ideal to
use a clone for your receiver and then
you know it's like with your donor as
well selecting that donor that you know
that's tried-and-true when you're making
your seeds but a lot of people aren't
even testing their seeds they're just
selling bulk seed you know at a dollar
apiece they're selling a hundred
thousand two hundred thousand a million
seeds to some of these companies and
they're not even testing oh we saw stuff
that was 13% zero for all the zero
percent CBDs that's general I think
we're fucked
yeah you have nothing to harvest at all
there you know well and we haven't
figured out cannabis whether it's hemp
or whether it's marijuana we haven't
figured out like the tomato industry is
gonna wanna I mean it's all cannabis
it's all cannabis but you don't karen
oncidi i can't believe it yeah it's all
cannabis right and that's all you know
we've can like we have waved in their
face so hard with this smokeable hemp
right now like to the point where it's
like like I know I'm not smoking smoking
but all shitload of people are out there
and it's weird because like we the whole
point of us getting it legal is to say
hey it's not only we're gonna smoke it
or anything but Austin was like that's
all our doing what's marijuana so easy
so it's just high cannabinoid low THC
cannabis you know I mean that's this
pretty much and that's why the people
that are growing good are getting you
know 300 bucks a pound let's say four
four they're smokable him but that
market is gonna drop soon too because
we're so I can't wait to see all the
smokeable have this super fire though
that's coming out for sure
oh it's there's not as it's there's
technically but it's not there no one's
been producing it and large greenhouses
are not that I'm sliding though not in
quantity is there gonna be a drought 2.0
no no not like what again somewhere
where shit went up to like 20 something
honey problem is like the problem is
that everybody saw that happening and
our our reactions are so slow they're
quick and yet slow at the same time cuz
for stoners right so our reactions are
like we're all thinking the same thing
but no one's really getting up to do it
yet and then all of a sudden it's like
one day no one shows up and they're all
out doing it and then they all come back
online and it's like oh shit now we're
all getting that we're all cashing in at
the same time and what we thought was
all you know so that those markets I
feel like we're you know the problem
there's always going to be a shortage of
good weeds right there's always a
shortage of good week but there's gonna
be way too much weed way too much
you know the black markets really
changed - because metrics aren't in
place in California so we have all these
license companies that who knows where
it's coming from it could be coming from
those license companies and cuz the
black markets died that those guys have
been humbled and in Sonoma and in
Mendocino this is guys and even down
here those guys got hit hard this year
but there's still a lot of black market
pot out there so I have no idea no idea
it's cut the moon it's a it's
interesting how like I saw it maybe
about five years ago maybe even longer
maybe seven years ago somebody in New
York was telling me about like $1500
packs of Sour Diesel right and it was
all from from from out here somewhere
and it was like that's it it's over you
know it's over if it's the same price on
both coasts see that I mean like what is
there to be said anymore and that was
you know like I said seven years ago or
something like that so the saturation
points are getting like Oregon's a good
example if you go to Oregon and see what
like they have six years worth of weed
and storage six years and it's all just
rotting and you know I really like it
it's nothing nothing's getting better
I mean it's oh yeah it's gonna be the
state of CDN for sure and and and just
the fact that like that's one that's
because they could they can grow pretty
pretty good there you know it's it's
like NorCal has become Southern Oregon
really when it comes to the the way even
the way the weather is moving like it's
all kind of moving up this sweet spots
are all up there and they just can grow
too good you know so and I think once it
goes national then Central California
will control the market as they do with
all the other agriculture too so yeah
yeah once interstate sales go online
that's gonna be big-time game-changer
for Oregon well they're the one I mean
they actually pushed and for ya to be
able to sell out of state which since
its usual thot it's pretty awesome if
they can if they can pull that off then
that's really like the beginning of the
end of the whole thing I mean that's
when it starts to crumble because it'll
just set precedents for other states to
follow now
organ stops for doings are switching
over to hemp licenses because in places
are cheaper you don't have to deal with
all the headache and all the bullshit in
all the hoops so we're just paying 500
bucks couldn't have license and
switching over I was there a few weeks
ago and it was it was pretty amazing to
drag and to drive to the one farm that I
had to go to I just passed probably 15
or 20 farms and didn't see a single
person out and it was kind of like eerie
because it was like wow there's a lot of
harvesting to be done here and a lot of
work and I don't see a single person out
there doing any proof like no one's kind
of felt like they were ready for it and
this is no this is a few weeks ago so
it's Peru before the that kind of snap
came through but and we had it in
Colorado we had one day like we had just
like all of a sudden out of nowhere we
had one day that dropped down to the low
of 20 and the high of 38 and snow and
then the day before was 70 degrees and
the day after or was 87 degrees the day
before in 78 degrees the day after so
just this weird like one day snap but
there's a lot of hemp farmers losing
money of cost they scale too big they
don't know what they're doing
I mean I heard about some farmers in
oiled committing suicide I don't know if
you guys heard about that no no it was
that real I don't know but it seemed
Wade you know a lesson for everybody you
know that even if it's not real it seems
very orchestrated it was one of those
stories where you're like okay maybe it
seems very yeah I mean you lose a bunch
of someone's money like that I don't
know no you picked the right stocks yeah
you definitely picked the right plant
for hanging yourself that's that's what
she was if you wouldn't deal with your
own with your own hard-earned I mean I
paid money to the GoFundMe page so
there's really kidding
no I saw that story and I was a little
bit like skeptical because it was almost
like it was one of those deals where
you're like I was standing in line and
the girl turn around you read the whole
thing and then you realize this is just
a trolli thing like what
so what else what's up
what grinds your gears