[Music]
you know we're talking about more than
coveted the top shelf right now and
obviously thousands of different
cultivars and strains and sub strains
and cross threads and back breads and
all the rest of it how do you determine
like how do you know I mean we know some
trendy ones like Gorilla Glue blew up
and you know bubba 97 and and blue
skittles we were just talking about or
even some of the more modern pushes but
is there a way for you to kind of get
feedback from the open market to go hey
maybe i should do something that's a bit
of maybe a retro Acapulco gold crossed
with Northern Lights yeah you know
there's a company called seed junkie but
there are seed junkies out there there
is a whole phenomena of people that are
paying attention to the breeders that
are coming out with the new stuff and
we're you know we're seeing trends you
knows oh geez for a long time then it
was everything with cookies and now like
purple punch came on the market now I'm
seeing all these things that are crossed
with purple punch so I think it's just
always gonna be an evolving thing and
then how do you make how do you know
that's going to hit or gonna become a is
I think it boils down a the quality of
the genetics and then you know B is
marketing and market outreach you know
get get someone that's well-known to
hype it up and you know really cover
that or win a cup with that strain but
that's that's kind of another artistry
and beauty and growing cannabis is that
the sky's the limit and yeah you know
really it's just getting into breeding
on my farms and trying to do some
selections and I mean that is all that's
a lot of work it doesn't take much space
it's really high volume production and
low square footage or small square
footage so it's attractive in that
regard and it's always attractive to
make something new and exciting so I
think once we get all our operations in
place that that's going to be the next
fun thing is to focus on breeding and
work with other breeders that are
and then using their their material
someone like Kevin is like super into
that Kevin Joe dream I love it eating
that stuff you know it's it almost takes
over the passion from growing the plan
agree to just being the breeding factor
and you know that hunt and seeing what
males are gonna be that you're gonna
select and teaming them up with the
females and you know just creating that
cross and there's widget with wizardry
artistry and a little bit of luck I'd
say so Mike so you never know you get
something you see I mean we can bring
the lab into the equation yeah but I'm a
little bit of a seed hunter and I'm
looking for someone's like I'm looking
and I've I've heard it exists in
Amsterdam that someone has a true pure
Acapulco gold that's some sort of cross
bred or back red but I agree with you
it's an art one concern I have is you
know something great comes along but
we're so busy trying to constantly
innovate and change it and unfortunately
in the state's it's kind of a race to
the top right a lot of us that are
purists are little bummed that it's this
whole THC race - oh I've got it renoble
that's a 36% a 38% it's overkill my
concern is if everyone's racing to the
next thing what about some of those
coveted strains we low loved and grew up
with right like an like a true Northern
Lights you know which I know Joey has I
know he's got it but it's like are we
gonna miss out on some of those coveted
- you know so yeah it really bothers me
that people pay so much attention to
hybrid sativa indica like whatever or
potency levels it's like I person would
never judge any cannabis that I want to
consume or check it out sent by the
percentage or whether it's a hybrid or
sativa I mean when it's growing it's
very obvious for most growers to tell
that has some sativa qualities and I
like sativas but everything pretty much
at this point unless you're getting into
some tree landrace stores everything's a
hybrid sativa domineer hybrid or indica
dominant it's also it's all canvas
and that's exactly it's interesting we
even look at something that's like a
skittles which is always look it doesn't
have much bag appeal yeah usually tests
around 14% but it tastes so good I think
it's a Blue Diamond man oh hey it's a
blue side of the
I agree it's such a well-rounded and
Jodi gets into and I think it's the next
phase it's more of the turkey and say
what I I love Mersin I'm eliminating
like there's certain Terps I know that I
love more so but it's funny you mention
that because you nights back at the
Cannabis with Ricardo Baca they did a
whole documentary he is saying called
rolling papers and the producer every
opportunity he had he had asked is he's
like are you high right now you know in
asking someone if they're high right now
in this industry is very similar to
asking someone are you indica or sativa
I laugh when someone asked that because
yeah if I had to choose I'm an indigent
indica dominant guy I'm a nighttime
medical I'm an advocate on the medicinal
side my ailments more so I deal with in
the evenings at night but it's funny
when people are like indica sativa or
hybrid it's like really pretty much
every I would venture to guess I don't
which room I'd say 80% plus out there
are hybrids right yeah on the shelves
easy I mean it's just crazy to think
that someone has a pure sativa pure
indica I guess your point landrace I'm
that's only if you can find something
that's truly out of Afghan or truly out
of you know South Africa truly out of
row I mean it's just hard right yeah
[Music]