[Music]
can you kind of talk about your
greenhouse and what sets it apart like
why people find it why you find it
interesting and how you got there yeah
so I had quite a bit of experience in
indoor farming and for quite a few years
and it's kind of came from that world
and then actually transitioned into a
lot of vegetable a lot of vegetable
farming
[Music]
[Applause]
nixtamalization nixtamalization
[Music]
okay so you're doing vegetables yes so
I'm so no outdoor you know so we 13
years ago we got our farm that is more
farmland and in Eugene and so I started
going market veggies and a little bit
wholesale and did that for quite a few
years while kinda transitioning the
indoor cannabis getting more into deep
organic practices indoors and using you
know getting into plant based fertility
and so getting away from all the animal
animal products getting away from the
back Lanos and phloem eels and the blood
meals and using more plant-based
fertilizers what was each one of those
animal based things doing like what were
you using back 104 and then what was a
substitute that works so in in your
quick cycle of kind of more than you
know indoor continuous production you
you only have the two months you know
really a flower and trying to get the
soil or Gantt in and or you know drill
organic soil try to get that to release
the nutrients to have those nutrients
soluble to the plant get chelated that's
that's a tough thing unless you have a
lot of microbes so conventional farming
uses a lot soluble foods that are
already broken down and so you know from
the chemically derived where it's in
sulfate form ready to go into the plant
or to the sub there's some people make
organic bottled foods that are animal
products that they basically isolate you
know but basically they're trying to
make them soluble so it goes right into
the plant and just so you really get
that boom so you get that that nice
growth you know quickly and that's in
that in that two months so replacing
basically those heavy duty foods that
were quick-acting with with plant
ferments that was really a big thing
plant and fruit for mints so basically
fermenting plant material which which
pretty much comes all from our farm so
we're just gathering and even a lot of
weeds a lot of things that have deep
roots even like thistles that you think
a hard
really bad weed they are bringing up all
these minerals from the subsoil and
they're making basically a fertilizer
that's beyond a lot of these other
fertilizers even if you're using like an
alfalfa Muller sling if that field that
the alfalfa meal fertilizer came from
was devoid of minerals you know you're
not getting as many minerals whereas if
you're using weeds that are you know
nutrient accumulators you're really
getting all these weeds the reason
they're sending that taproot in down to
the ground is to bring out minerals and
regenerate the soil so so using plant
ferments and fruit ferments to really
supplement that that extra boost and
then this plant material and kelp meal
rocked us seeds and really so yet seeds
really replace a lot of
so you know people use a lot of seed
meals so seed meals are really plants
basically have plants everything plant
needs you know so you have this balanced
form of nutrition it's just getting that
to go uptake into the plant in the
amount of time you want and if you have
a really living soil it's it's a lot
easier but starting out when I did
transition from the indoor it was trying
to get these containers to have that
have the fertility to make those really
like indoor quality buds you know really
have that full quality in that amount of
time and and so transitioning to a more
like ferments and and ways of
solubilizing those those nutrients out
of the out of the organic matter so is
that what the fermentation process does
so all the microbes that are in the soil
that are in our gut that are in a cows
gut so you know animals are all the same
type of microbes like the probiotics we
take or the same probiotics that they
sell you for your soil and the same that
are in a cow's gut and the cow is
basically having this fermentation
process happening in their stomach when
you're making a ferment you're taking
all the stuff that the cow would eat or
the horse would eat and you're
fermenting it in water and those same
microbes are breaking everything down
and basically killing those nutrients
making em chelating is just making those
molecules smaller and smaller so that
they're I basically be I've taken by the
plants and microbes are chelating
they're just breaking down to a smaller
smaller particle and so that all happens
in your ferment and instead of like when
you're using animal manure you're
getting with animal didn't use the
animals using the calcium-magnesium a
lot of the micronutrients and getting
the macronutrients and so I mean you can
use it's useful of it but but it's a lot
of times it's over fertilizes a lot of
people in this intercept for years it's
been over fertilizing especially without
soil testing so we're really in the soil
testing now as well to know what's there
to make sure that we're not missing
anything and to make sure we have it all
our basis you know basic covered and and
and not overdoing anything because the
balance of the soil is really important
if you overdo macronutrients especially
the micronutrients get locked out and so
and that's really the micronutrients
were really the plant really depends on
him to make the secondary metabolites
which are all the terpenes the
cannabinoids the flavonoids
yeah and the the the seed meal is
literally taking the seeds from plants
that are native to your area
ideally ring we're using a lot of
actually foods he's like flax amaranth
Chia
buckwheat and then the cover crop seeds
too but a lot of those like the flax and
Chia they're really oily really super
nutritious you know for us they're like
they're super nutrient dense foods so I
like to use those where I toss them in
there some of them get broken down and
eaten by the worms some of them sprout
into cover crops which are cycle of what
we're doing now is a lot of planting top
dress that cover crops come up and then
we mulch them in really about three
weeks like three weeks like also letting
them sprout and then mulching them back
in so so currently fast forward is where
we are with the greenhouse is we've
brought that I brought that indoor that
that that was one service all this
thinking was when you were indoor and
you wanted to do kind of like a living
soil indoor transitioning over yeah and
it was still doing big containers and
you knows but before the the current
pull regulated you know in the medical
days but once wreck happened and we
built our farm we wanted to really build
it out with what we feel is like the
best of both worlds which is to get the
quality that you need the indoor
environment and to get that really good
taste and what we really want is that
deep organic soil culture and so our
greenhouse has beds that go down into
the native soil but are raised up two
feet out of it and it with our custom
mix and and so that custom blends a
really nutrient dense like
nutrient dense we do use a little bit of
fish bone meal to build our soils
initially and I really like it
I find it adds to everything and like
just like the fish used to swim up from
the ocean they'd swim up the rivers and
bring all their nutrients back that fish
bone from the ocean has a lot of
minerals and there's a lot of really
things that I feel brings in but that's
that's the only animal products we're
using besides that we're you know
building all that with different
plant meals quel rocked us seeds bran
and then even so that's where with the
seeds using high quality seeds I find
you know it's a step up from using like
like a like a cottonseed meal or
something which a lot of people are
using grandchildren they take out all
the oils from that con seed meal where
when you're using just the whole seeds
you're getting all the oils and
everything and but then even with your
plants when you're using plants to
fertilize if you're using herbs that
have terpenes in them already
all these elements that made those
molecules are in there and you're then
translating into your soil and you're
just packing more of the elements you
want that are gonna translate into what
you really want so so I try to use like
as many herbs and really fragrant you
know for exactly done any testing where
it's like this plant is high in this
terpene and I'm going to take I'm gonna
test a cultivar that I grew but or I
introduce that and the Steve after I
introduced it as more of that talk about
it I have not yet and I totally someone
had thought to told me that you know you
should use plants that are high in the
same turfy into like Bert and I mean I'm
sure it would be a benefit all our
practices our numbers have gone
completer fiends cannabinoids everything
so we've seen a general you know really
pretty amazing
just woodsy and the community analytics
showing it so yeah but I haven't gotten
that yeah um so we're operating right
now 2000 we were 5000 and we lost three
thousand square feet in a snowstorm last
year so we like I mean serious fart like
we're all of a sudden two feet of snow
and it was like really freaked row area
and just three thousand square but
greenhouses and so it was a pretty big
it's pretty big lost it and we're
rebuilding right now so we'll we back up
to 5,000 our license is five thousand of
lighted greenhouse space and then we can
do up to a half acre outside but we are
doing 10,000 square feet outside
and then all these inputs you're growing
on the same farm oh yeah we're going we
have the veggie we have about 20 acres
total and and so we're growing a lot of
the inputs we do bring in some seeds and
you know a few little things like the
kelp and the rock dust so we're bringing
a little bits of things but really with
them so our current situation with the
greenhouse and the beds the fertility is
there we do soil tests and I mean it's
basically everything's there we're
adding like little bits of things that
are a little low and then really what we
really weren't beds I mean when you pull
it apart they're just wool worms what
we're doing is really just feeding that
top of the soil letting the worms have a
lot at their healthy environment and
some stuff to eat to really just break
down what's in the soil more and make it
available because all that stuff's in
the soil but it needs to be made
available to the plants and so really
that's what we're focusing on now is
really just these top dresses that have
the seeds popping up and just make that
worm activity happen to really just make
that stuff that's in the soil available
and then just giving a little bit I
still give a little bit of some plant
permits and permits at certain times
it's a lot of it's green natural farming
stuff and a lot of them are just to
stimulate certain different like
flowering with the fruit ferment and
then we use like a water soluble calcium
that we make out of eggshells and
vinegar and we do that in transition
when we when we transplant and in
transitions times and then sprouted CTS
I do which is another technique where
sprouts have a lot of enzymes in them
and so I'll use a corn sprouted CT going
into flour for the first two weeks about
once a week and that has a cytokine in
it which is the shoot more Mon and so it
makes your you know buds just stack
really in that first two weeks and then
after that we'll go to barley seed
sprout and barley has a lot of
phosphatase because in the in the spring
it has to be 60 65 degrees really for
the soil to for the plants uptake
prosperous but barley is usually growing
before then and it's it's colder so they
make their own phosphatase enzyme to
help themselves uptake in that cold
temperatures so we're basically
sprouting that barley and then making a
tea of it and taking that phosphatase
and that phosphatase helps our plants
absorb phosphorus which is what makes
buds you know what makes them the nice
buds and so really that's what we're
kind of using some techniques to make
our our indoor quality where we're in
the indoor market you know and
getting up in the price for it able to
kind of grow a little bit less in a
little more focused way and kind of
really and there's a really big demand
for it so that's the the balance we
really we are using some resources that
are more than a lot of the I mean the
weight way more than a lot of Sun
growing especially and stuff but but are
a lot most of our fertility resources
are coming from our land
you know our beds go down into the
native soil it really is this deep
organic culture we have the Sun involved
you know in the greenhouse but we also
do have the lights and the climate
control supplementing light you have
supplemental lighting like double-ended
yeah we don't have a LED led the price
which is so restrictive and prohibitive
that it's as hard it's a hard one to
judge and also they don't give any heat
which we actually when we use the lights
is in the winter and we like the heat
and so in the summer we don't really
hardly usually in summer it's and
amazingly where you don't use the light
and you can we're getting an indoor
quality product for you know almost like
two of the seasons and then for like two
of the harvests we're using more lights
and and you know depending some days or
more sunnier we've got a meter that
turns lights on and off so you know as
efficient as we can be dialed and we
have sensors and meters for everything
that that that only turns it on if it
needs it and but you know if we are
using some resources to basically get
the quality products are our people
using climate batteries
like what are some concepts you're using
to kind of manage the heat like at a
summer
that's hot so yeah the summer gets hot
and also the other problem is that it's
dry and so the dryness the leaves get
impacted by that you want to keep the
vapor pressure deficit up when it gets
hotter you want to keep the humidity
higher and that basically keeps the the
leaves healthy and the sand and the
transpiration happening correctly if it
gets it gets too hot and dry the plants
close up their stomata
and they're not functioning correctly
and if it gets too wet and cold the
plants open up and they just try to
water just comes out of them and then
water sits on the leaves and it gets
moldy
so really the vapor pressure deficit is
hot and dry and so we have like a wet
wall where the air comes through through
water and we're in our veg we actually
have an earth battery where we kick all
the air from we excavated underneath it
when we were building it yeah yeah we
kick the air in and we take air from we
basically ran pipes next to each other
and one comes from in the greenhouse and
the other ones bring outside air pass
that warm air and bring it in so the air
is tempered when it comes in it's a
little bit warmer that one so we in our
air we have a really high water table
and so for that one we only went about
three feet and so we've been the water
and so it's a it's kind of new there's
some people doing a different greenhouse
companies doing it we were kind of going
off over there and it is almost new in
itself so we didn't have it definitely
works but I think ideally it would be
nice to go deeper to get you know the
more constant temperature but definitely
the air coming in is tempered and some
of that heat gets translated into the
ground and so that'd be acts like a
birth battery so we did that for our veg
for our big greenhouse and actually our
new greenhouse we're trying to figure
out some way of bringing in air from
we're thinking like an undergrad like
where it's some kind of trench so that
air just gonna be coming from there
because really that's what we need to do
is we need to take that that coolness
from the ground and the heat we don't
get too hot
I guess California but we definitely do
have days when it's 90 and really the
biggest part is in the end of flower
that's when the quality gets rude if
it's hot at the end of flower
makes it you know the first month you
know you can have nice hot you can human
make it humid and just really get them
to rage but it really is that end of
flower that that that'll ruin the
quality so and then also the end of
flower just the humidity thing is really
the dehumidifiers so that when the
lights do go off they can just get rid
of that initial load and it really it's
a pretty crucial part to is getting rid
that humidity so I think thatthat to it
people are coming like definitely the
the technology is really advancing for
all this stuff too and the engineering
where I think that it's gonna come leaps
and bounds you know the efficiencies and
there's like cirrus greenhouses which
are like in Colorado serious
they're super efficient really
interesting if you want to look up and
it's just it's going that way where cuz
you can make an indoor product in a way
more efficient sustainable way and get a
premium for it you know we're really
it's it's translating the the cost of
goods translating to what we're getting
and the demand really makes the business
part of it really easy like we're not
you know there's no if it's taking out
that part of the struggle of the sales
and everything you know so it's well
what's the specific differentiator of
those greenhouses what are they call
them so as far as the OCR SCE re s so so
the there's the company yeah and the
whole back of it is a insulated panels
so the whole back and it's almost like a
it's like a warehouse almost that that
has one side that's that's your
greenhouse and it's acrylic so that it
gets more UV but then they're doing the
earth batteries so it's like a full
closed system and it's just really built
with efficiency of making a closed
system kind of go closest and efficiency
built in it instead of like ultra
greenhouse where it's just air coming in
one side going out the other that's
really the traditional greenhouse is
just bring area and bend it out and
where this one is like a closed more and
and the blue the back you don't lose as
much heat out of the back and
yeah the way it's built just for
efficiency really so but very pricey
what once one like when you get back
what's kind of one of the first like
experiments you're gonna like something
you're going to be playing with whether
it's in the greenhouse infrastructure
the soil the compost tea we're getting a
lot more into wood chips and really
using them so you know peat moss is
usually or if you're just potting
material peat moss is that fluff and
it's really what the people use coconut
as well but it's not as good and really
that soil component you can replace with
wood chips that are fungally like broken
down but usually takes about like two to
three years and can work on getting that
to happen a little sooner with
inoculating with fungus and really is
pulling branches from the problem yeah
we have a lot we have a little woodlot
and so a lot of alder that needs to be
thinned out anyway and it's to thin it
out to make the firs grow a little
better and you know they definitely
there's a real room to take them out
so using that and just turning that into
into soil basically for our our potting
because our beds are there they're you
know note so we just leave the bed we're
just planting in them but but all our
starts in our vegetative we we need soil
and so we have been getting a soil mix
that we have a custom blend but I kinda
wanna get away from bringing in that
outside you know a little bit of peat
moss really does work amazingly but but
what I've been seeing for most
experimentation and hearing from some
other antidotal is that it really can
replace the wood chips can replace the
moss fumbly broken-down wood chips and
so yeah that'll be a big part other
experiments we're getting a lot more
perennial plantings around the farm just
creating that long-term if it's hard not
to just get caught up in the day-to-day
just grow in the weed but just kind of
that whole system's thing so really just
bring in the more permaculture and we do
a lot because most of the the ferments
we use a lot of in our own art base all
our own plants and herbs but you also do
IPM integrated like pest management
sprays and stuff with herbal teas and so
we do like a heavy herbal tea
of different things but Jerusalem
artichoke is one thing but then thyme
and oregano and mints and you can roll
around on the property and we will make
a heavy T of that and then we make a
wetting agent which is a castile soap
and we use that as our as our pesto as
our pesto when you and when dear yes
yeah the JWA so it's all jude and
methods that we're basically bleeding
from we used some korean natural farming
sunja dams and biodynamic really just
taking whatever we can glean from these
different methods for you know where we
need to fill in those and the whole shit
is a Jedi JD a.m. so it's basically
addressing what was the issue that kind
of KNF doesn't quite address that it's a
big scale it's more for like so Master
Choa we started KNF you saw that all the
old farmers were using like using their
kimchi juice and using these ferments to
help their food production as well as
making permits of all their crop waste
and using that as fertilizer because
Korea was Island so they're not bringing
in stuff you know a lot of agriculture
like 50 years based on ramen your
fertilizer being an input you know
usually a waste material input that they
put into in the fertilizer for something
else Korea they didn't have that so they
really had to like close the loop and
and then the ferments as well we're just
part of the agriculture and and you know
feeding the soil those microbes could
break all the nutrients down which is
the same thing for us the probiotic with
the microbes are like our probiotics
they're what's breaking down our
nutrients and being unavailable there
was breaking down the nutrients in the
soil making them available and so so the
more of those microbes the more you can
you know inoculate with that the more
breakdown you're getting and so a lot of
those is for like small-scale and really
the crea natural farming I think to for
like quality giving that little boost to
make that that
what conventional agriculture does to
make it that marketable fruit you know
marketable really nice fruit it's like
hard to get without giving it all that's
a little boost and so I think that very
natural farming is really that extra to
give that market a bold that net really
nice and then but it uses different
sugars and some outside materials to
make experiments which a lot of them are
stable though so they're easy but but
they do have a cost involved where's
your damn so master Joe's son learned
from Master Joe and then went to
university went to chemistry and biology
and everything and then farmed for
fifteen years so this would be like
Bruce Lee
- if man like he learned from some guy
and then he's like let me yeah and then
also with a lot more of a science like
he's been like testing and he does you
know nutrient tests on all these things
so a little more of a science background
you know it's definitely like KNF 2.0 it
will it's but it's scaled more for not
his whole thing is that organic farmers
and this is like food farmers can
survive it could thrive if they don't
have to buy all their inputs if you're
buying inputs and if you're like
fertilizer and pesticides and everything
that are organic but still you're buying
them and you're bringing them in there's
you're you're losing your you know
you're spending too much money you're
basically costs are too high so his
thing is we would make everything with
with inexpensive you know organic inputs
you're basically going to be making
money and or inputs that work and so so
he came up with all these different math
it's a lot of them just ferments or ways
to ferment and examples that that and a
lot of it's just your your crop waste if
you're growing strawberries you take all
your strawberry waste and you firm in it
and the next year you use it on your
crop but he also has a microbe solution
that uses mashed potatoes and forests
like the leaf mold I go to like nice
healthy forests and where it's like
fungal and stuff you take that leaf mold
and then nice place in the field and
take that and take all those that's your
like your microbial inoculation and use
the potatoes mashed potatoes and sea
salt and you make a you take the starch
out of the potatoes and the sea salt
into the water and then add that microbe
inoculation and it sits for about three
days it starts to bubble and
just like this the roots of the plants
are feeding microbes so what's happening
in what's happening in so in the soil
naturally that plants are
photosynthesizing right and forty
percent up to forty percent sometimes
like you could say that more or less of
the sugars are going down into the soil
and feeding the microbes so that's the
natural process the natural process if
the microbes get fed by the root
exudates that come out of the plant and
and so basically when I make the microbe
solution you're using that potato which
is a root to feed as the sugar the
microbes and the sea salts the minerals
and you're basically growing those
microbes and proliferating them and then
we're feeding that to the soil and so
that's our microbial inoculation that's
another JDAM method the herbal solution
he has a sulfur spray that is uh pretty
amazing so I think pajetta management
was one of its more for like a
commercial agriculture kind of see where
green natural farming seems like it's
more for really the high quality it's
really that's what makes like quality
it's always little extras like super for
the heddes and to dance more like the
utility that's what I find it's like the
yeah it's for the crop that Korean
natural farming really helps the quality
and and the jus damn really helps with
the the bulk stuff that you can just do
for a lot cheaper and so in a nutshell
yes quickly one cultivar that you're
growing that maybe doesn't have market
appeal but that you love so it's an
interesting one that we have a turbine
chocolate that not the most bag appeal
and it's by 16 percent THC and but it
really it gets like three to four plus
percent torque means and it's amazing
terpene and and we actually we entered
in the cultivation classic up in Oregon
and it didn't really have too much inner
I didn't think it would win at all and
it actually took first place against all
the indoor which showed it was I mean
it's super high chirpy really nice
smoking really lively strain that
basically won against all these I mean
really
new thing you know all these new
designer and like an all indoor but it
kind of really shows yeah we've seen a
lot that some of these really they have
strains that aren't heavy-duty that
don't seem as much just when the smoke
comes out it's really it's what's in
that smoke and what's in that final so
now really that's an interesting one
I'd say though we are we're selecting
for marketability so most of the things
I mean we're we're definitely it's a
hard day yeah it's a little bit hard
we're definitely have to so much fear
towards what the market wants which is a
strong you know but we really when we
phenotype it's all for what it smokes
like we want to oily residence smoke you
know we'll we'll basically it could grow
great I could look creating smell great
but how does it actually translate into
smoking and we found through our
phenotyping that some yes some strains
it could be the same ten seeds and a few
of them will smoke amazing and be oily
or maybe one of them and and some of
them and you know majority of them will
just be like leafy and just not not have
a nice smoke to them and even if they
look beautiful they and over it's pretty
amazing it's it's kind of a some strange
definitely so that's what we're really
in the flower market I find that's our
niche I find that that's gonna be the
niche because only so many people want
to grow a good flower only if twenty
people know how to grow a good flower
want to put the love and energy into it
it's a very hands-on thing and and so I
feel there's always gonna be that market
it's gonna be that fine wine and you
flower-like solvent let's hash I feel
like we have we do make some and our
well our outdoor production it goes to
extraction which some of it's been co2
now some good solvent list but uh that's
mostly we don't really have enough and
waste or leftover like trim material to
make too much product just cos art we
have small batches we do so much small
batches of different flavors and so yeah
that's our can essentials that's our
brand right there yeah I it's so my
whole journey to came over a lot I had a
lot of I love digestive problems and I
was really into the food I guess I got
into veganism early and it was real odd
because the animal thing but if you're
my veganism I got really unhealthy
because I wasn't eating right and I a
lot of digestive problems and and fast
for tied to grow some weed it didn't
really grow I was like I need to take
botany I dropped out of high school I
saw at the Community College was botany
a win and I took botany and and just
learned all about how actually
everything works that you know how our
our DNA is actually putting the other
proteins to build everything and and you
need those raw materials to make all
that happen and and just translating
that into like the plant I was like oh
I'm not feeding these plans for the
plants are drying and then I realized
well I'm not feeding myself enough and
really like growing cannabis has shown
me with growing them and seeing how you
can make them super healthy you can take
a plant that's totally sick and bring it
back by feeding it and even out in the
field to vegetables and I really like to
you know it's really taught me about
feeding myself and being healthy and
that's what I kind of like to get out to
I like to have a platform of the herb
where it's like you like wow that herbs
amazing and say well it's grown with all
these things all these nutrients
nutrient-dense things that translates
into it and this is how the soil works
and everything works and this is the
same as our bodies our bodies have the
same kind of system little microbiome
going on in us and we need all these
base materials you can take us through
how impressed they are with the flap
that's what I feel it's I mean I could
all day long be like I got kale I got
kale but people most people don't care
about the flower I can get in front
equation I love going to like
dispensaries and talking about tenders
and everything because I I have a little
bit of a plateau
a minute of their time because I have
their attention and that's what I like
follow the flower exactly and then I can
really like download stuff that they're
really like Wow
and then able to you know you could put
out even more because there is we do
have the you know they're talking to
people and they're sharing information
so we have this kind of a really cool
information sharing community thing
happening with the cannabis that's
really and it's a lot of conscious it's
mostly people that are a little bit more
trying to think a little different and
conscious which is kind of what we need
you know what I mean hopefully we need
to get the people that aren't thinking
to get on our train tube but I really
feel it is this this this movement and
and seeing it in my you know short
lifetime and experience with it is from
20 years ago it being completely you
know illegal and and not really it was
all over but now it's just so normalized
that everybody and what I mean like my
mom smoked and we my grant but you know
it's like the kids grandma everybody
it's like you know it's such a and it's
not stigmatize it's it's so really yeah
it's pretty amazing to see that it
there's no reason it shouldn't have been
anyway but I don't know it's just kind
of amazing to see what really is and I
think we should definitely use it as a
platform to spread more better things
you know not just again of it so that
that's my whole thing that's how I pull
it all for a full circle