we're all working independently no one
person controls this industry as much as
they think they do and we're all small
participants that combined we make up a
big tool and it's just trying to figure
out how do you share technology and how
do you use what you use and how do we
make money off each other's stuff
because if you had a varietal that had a
demand and I was allowed to license it
through my nursery then I could provide
it to cultivators that could then
subsequently sell it which is what I'm
doing with with Vernon screw where we
know that the lemonade line is there
everything coming out of Martin Martin
has the 11 acre campus over in Oakland
so that massive facility that was the
old Naval Base the Safeway warehouses
that's that's all Martin stuff so you
met Martin Lee sitting there and and you
know and a lot of it is what we found
when we went into it was virally
contaminate virally contaminated so when
we did the first so the first project we
worked with on this was through Martin
as the R&amp;D because he said listen let me
work with the product cuz I can push it
through my facilities then I can move it
on the end zone but I'm having problems
with it so we go through and they say
well this is all virally contaminated
which a lot of this stuff come in from
there is virally contaminated and then
so they scrub it and then so then Martin
runs side by side trials to be able to
say what are we looking at and the
difference between the two cultivars is
night day yeah you'd be banging because
it's got an ultra loud signature and
it's got a built in branding yeah yeah
yeah it's a lemon pine salt and and it
and unlike a lot of the mono tear up
lemons it holds it all the way through a
joint so it doesn't flare off so it has
a sesqui combination the sesquiterpene
combination Terps that don't flare up on
the heat more Multi bonds that's what
gives you the enjoyment after the first
hit
so people that small bongs of apes they
have a different situation than those
that actually burn it because the heat
is burning off that that complexity as
you go forward to what you're left with
is only heavily multi bond terpenes at
the end of it and the lemonade holds it
through the piece I'm just I'm just like
just like the perk I always wondered you
know when I was we were
moving perfectly crazy I was there pre /
when / nobody wanted hurt nobody wanted
black little pounds next thing you know
nobody wants anything but black little
pounds and so purple comes out and
actually wipes out most of the genetic
diversity in a lot of the California
because if you weren't moving / if you
weren't moving weed but what made / trip
was that there was that blunt revolution
that was occurring so the blunt was
coming out in full form and perf had a
high sesquiterpene combination that
allowed you to hold a flavor all to the
end and at that time cannabis was still
being flipped through the windows of
cars more than through storefronts and
when you looked at the baggie it had a
distinctive orange carrot looking hair
with a heavy purple tone but it was a
bright light royal purple it wasn't the
typical heavy purp of like a purple cush
even though it's related to purple cush
genealogically so purple cush is the all
these perps come through purple cush as
a progenitor because we can track it
genetically you can see the link on the
DNA line but it had a radically
different quality of mouth appeal and so
lo and behold it's recognizable in a bag
it holds in a blunt and it's great
kool-aid and at the time most of the
ghettos the way that stuff was pushing
heavy and I'm from the hood on East
Coast and so great kool-aid is what we
all drank you didn't have multi flavor
kool-aid
and so lo and behold grape is popular
holds in a blunt recognizable in a deal
all of a sudden you have this magic
little trifecta of things that come
together to create a billion-dollar
variety and it's trying to put together
those same kind of combinations and so
now you have you know the the og but OGE
isn't gonna go anywhere because OG has
an incredible aside of branding it has
an exceptionally high impact because a
mere Cena is the anesthetic and it also
has an exceptional complexity within the
line where as you go through it people
are happy with it if you get a good
quality o gene you consume it pretty
much you really don't have a high
ceiling to it every time you smoke it
you get a very similar effect than
you're happy as well this one of the OGS
it's really not a diluted watered-down
and even and even though the the the old
oh geez the originals were running
around seventeen eighteen percent when
you scope them with me and Josh were
talking in in Carpinteria and I said he
came to the lecture I gave in
Carpinteria about genetic mapping so
two months ago month enough yes so we
went to that oh it was you yeah yeah yes
got aggressive
yeah and study granola yeah and so and
so and then you had then you had Steve
Cantwell from the the no-till right yeah
and so they asked me to come in to kind
of tie the package together and then to
say look this is where you're gonna go
with all these technologies and so you
come in with your supplemental
greenhouses and then you come in with
the no-till situation where you're
getting biological because really the
cost of production is low once you're
able to get this biological circle
completed and Cantwell's doing killer in
Vegas with his no-till operations
because he's not losing any of the
product and having to blow it and then
you got Scottie granola doing your
predicated of testing to say listen when
I see microbe levels here
I know problems are about to be present
there and so even though and he's one of
the laning I'm just like you know
disciples and Elaine says you can't use
science to predict but you kind of can
and so even though it's true scientists
won't do that because scientists did
study not prediction you can make some
pretty good goddamn predictions based
off of the science yeah it lets you
allow it and we'll and I like it because
it creates the warning situations and
you got you got and Scott sharp and he's
a intelligent guy who is involved most
definitely with cultivators and a lot of
these people coming in aren't involved
in cannabis production cannabis cannabis
sourcing the aloe vera part is what are
you guys using it for we're using it and
we are using aloe vera in terms of
wetting agents yeah yeah wetting agents
yep but the yeah the but the effect is
phenomenal because what we know is that
really numeira have I was messing around
with gene from me and gene from
Mendocino right so me and Gina buddies
and so he lets me access his cherry line
but it says it is but I have the line
males to but I mean the the cherry that
he uses in the lime and he says hey
listen here's the seed stock just don't
let it out because it's it's it is my
shit so it'll it'll sense
somebody right into my lines and so I
said sweet so I'll work with it I'll use
it as progeny to stock for breeding so I
pull out a cutting of it that it's just
this cherry is one could humanly hope
for it comes out of like eleven and a
half twelve percent but I found that
it's perfect for people that let's go we
enjoy I like I like something a little
more power to it but in terms of the
quality the fact it's just resonates but
it lets me use it for my girlfriend and
for my buddies that can't smoke high
potency devastating cannabis because
they're able to get the effect they want
and not get blasted off the top of his
shoes and I get it because the flavor
profile is fantastic and so I was
talking to Josh we met at carbonaria and
we were talking about and I didn't who
he wasn't we first met so we just meet
each other we're talking about numerix
and we started talking about old oh geez
and I didn't know who he was at the time
and I said all my old oh geez that I got
from an NGO from you know like late 90s
they're all coming in around you know 17
18 points that's what he said he goes
yeah he goes he said my stuff is coming
in never over 20 he said I've never hit
over 20 with my foundation stock and
then I have and then I have I and so
well you we can we can we can tweak it
because we can drive our humidity levels
far down and I can get a higher trichome
density and I can also dry the plant
Warren and depending on what lab I use I
can make these numbers but if I'm
looking at it free period of time and I
see the graph I say whoa that's a panga
cup that I picked up from Mandal and
then that we called the SME cut those
two lemon lime that the two bookends of
what he thought oh gee word that he got
probably out of you guys at that time
yes yes Douglas sister Linda Banga no
but it works killer for hybridization
for outdoor because it has a it has a
faster trigger yeah yeah yeah yep yep
yeah it's a faster trigger outside so we
use it in breeding projects to upgrade
what we want is what we call fuel
designations but with a faster of
trigger time because if I can get the oh
if I can get the og to come in around
that first week of October versus the
third week of October I'm killing it cuz
I got two weeks to process and get
into the market and so he and I were
chatting about and he goes yeah so he
gave me some of the stuff that he had
grown he goes hey this is all stuff for
my my original stuff and he goes and I
never get over 20 with this one and so
we started talking about all this all
the swings because now we're looking at
oh jeans that are in thirty twos but
that's all self then selected out but
that's where you start to see such a
huge propensity for p.m. problems
pathogenic issues by relations totally
no no because it's it's it's a
foundation line yeah you keep any kind
of any kind of it yet and that's what ya
know it's that it doesn't make it
profitable for you and if you make any
mistakes at all I'm doing I'm doing this
old reservation skunk project so I've
been collecting skunk from around the
world that's from the early eighties me
too you know the chunks and I want to
see the range in tones and they all got
wiped out because there was no chaco
filtration so I used to run these hot
operations using ozone technology I used
to get from hospitals so I went into the
hospital said how do you guys clean up
your shit and they said they use ozone
so there was a company in Texas saunas
here that was a commercial ozone company
and I would bring in the ozone tech and
I would blow all my ducts and vents as I
vented her modernes houses yeah because
if you let it if you let the ozone in
the room if you'd wipe out all the
plants yeah yeah yeah you haven't gave
it your everything possible yeah yeah
kill the grass though yeah one look
awesome yeah and so and so we we end up
wiping out these skunk situations and
then and there's a smoke around I'm
getting bored right I mean I'm smoking
everything on the fucking planet I'm
getting bored and I said you know what I
wanted something from the past that had
been selected as smoke for generations
from people from other countries and
then put together these of these
varietals and I said well how do I
access it so I started going into crews
over in Europe that the stock
had left northern Northern California in
the 80s and went over to Europe for
holding and then I was able to mine it
back so they would ship it back to me
from Europe and then I started doing
some recovery work for people that had
old stock that they had kept forever and
they were having pathogenic issues and
they couldn't get it and they said
listen we we don't want to give it up
but we're gonna lose the varietal if we
give it to you would you clean it and
then you can play with it and so it
started letting me get into these skunks
so I go set up to do a whole breeding
project and I get ready to do all my
work