[Music]
are you still planning to cultivate are
you just going to let it go fallow for a
year actually I'm gonna go probably take
it all out I brought a permaculture guy
in from Layton from the permaculture
conference I was involved in so he flew
in yesterday and took a look at my
property and we're gonna start getting
ready to play a radish all over the
benches because everything regressed in
form although because I did the initial
work a couple years ago so the whole
thing is all grass in so you're gonna
grow radishes hey Madison but I can
bring out the soil then that I can mulch
it in and what it will do is it'll let
me start building soil because see the
thing is that if you follow Colorado
Oregon Washington model the first year
first year and a half and two of legal
everybody got paid really well because
there was this shortage of product that
could move into the system through
regulated people with California because
California made the deal with law
enforcement to allow each kind of need
to have its own control over the market
in that County 65% of California is a
desert and so where you have storefronts
they're concentrated and in places like
Humboldt where you're gonna have a
couple in barbourville red way that you
go to arcana for - they're not for tuna
but Rio down then you go into Arcadia
Rica area would they be like you know 10
there - by the time you're done you can
have like 40 dispensaries inaudible
county total like watch how many they're
gonna really build it up in 3 or 4 in
Rio down you're going to have there's a
new one open and the nice one - there's
a nice dispensary in red way I just
drove by can't wait to go inside it's
gorgeous it's called the Country Club
and good looking spot so I'd love to go
in there and check it out but you got
one there I think they're gonna pop one
here there'll be one up the road there's
mine then they'll be down the road so by
the time you're done how many will there
be if they'll be maybe 10 and arcade at
10 in Eureka that'll be 20 just within
that little distance McKinley Phil we'll
have a couple so you're gonna have in
Humboldt County with 120,000 people so
say 37 over-exaggerating 40 said we have
30 toll
how many that means very 4,000 people
you have a dispensary that doesn't work
in a rural area it just doesn't and so
you have places like Humboldt that are
popping up stores everywhere but there's
no population here if we had a million
200,000 it'd be incredible for the store
owners but the store owners about to
take a real beating because they're
gonna compete with each other to the
death over who's gonna be able to get
the cheapest pot and then you get to a
point where it gets down to a 1 percent
margin like Walmart then you got
companies that like the one that just
popped up in Arcata
where they're doing delivery only where
it's basically the Costco a weed because
what you do is you pay them a membership
fee and the membership fee to them
allows them to just deliver it to you
direct so you can get away from the
nasty stores because they overcharge you
much 400% unlike would have been put in
florid four hundred more times on the
price it's not really true in every one
has a cost of production and so when you
when you create a system where you don't
allow the whole state to have
storefronts and you have these huge
deserts and you favor areas that can
produce massive quantities of cannabis
before that you allowed the industry to
kind of stabilize my movies it was
supposed to be a five-year delay but
anything over an acre
well that anything over an acre you
would still don't have anything over an
acre each each you could have multiple
acres but you can't have a 40 acre grow
you can have 40 contiguous acres where
they touch but it's not one plot of 40
its zoning if it's it's it's semantics
but the bottom line is let's get around
that issue so what you have is you have
mega producers producing and they're
burning investment dollars so most of
these big companies aren't making any
money at all they're losing money and
they that's the strategy and we've been
saying this for years that's a no
legardie model when I took a look at
this years ago I said look let's there'd
be no Legarda model you're gonna have a
few big companies come in and price war
everybody out of existence and then as
soon as everybody's going they'll raise
the price as to what works for them
that's the oil companies so you have two
or three major refineries - three major
producers everybody else buys gas for
them
price is the same everywhere you go
regionally same thing here with cannabis
and so for us you know that the only way
we can survive in a way we'd be talking
about this is to do digital
survivability where if you're in
Michigan and you're in the cherry areas
get together with all your other farmers
if you're in southern Humboldt you're in
this for this record valley this is the
center strip through the ill River if
you're over in palo verde that's a
different appellation if you're in you
know southern Mendocino hotter drier if
you're in Trinity all those places have
unique characteristics and they're
pretty clustered each one of those
groups those gardener's those farmers
have to work together in some capacity
and form their own alliances so that
what you can do is you can share IP you
can share assistance and labor and you
can get yourself to more efficient model
the dream of us all being owner
operators and running our own little
farm and be able to make money and have
a brand a brand means people know who
you are doesn't mean you have a hat and
a t-shirt and these people recognize you
and how do they recognize you and what
you're going to drive it every store in
the state you're going to go drive it
they move the pound last month so you
each each place moves a pilot a month so
you've got you know 12 stores move 12
pounds you group hours in homes yeah and
yet the two work together the
co-operative model as California has it
right now is is somewhat cumbersome I
mean there's a four acre limit in terms
of exactly you have to be only ten
thousand square feet or lower as an
individual farm and then collectively
you can't be over four acres so you're
still put at you know it's still a
cumbersome process and an additional
cost to go through to become a
cooperative it lets you be about 16
people because you got if you can only
have four acres and it's 44,000 square
that gives you about 16 people per group
so if you just choose the 16 people you
grew up up with but the additional time
of working together is 16 individual
owner-operators isn't it what you have
to put your choice yeah Donegal porn you
can do it on your own show me how
gonna do this on your own show me sure
that there's the model of like flow
Coty's coming in as the largest
distributor amount or in California
currently and they they're sort of
looking at the Sunkist model where all
the orange farmers are branded under
Sunkist orange juice you buy orange
juice it's it's a Sunkist but it comes
from different orange farmers but are
the orange farmers getting the profit or
is Sunkist the company getting the the
arty of the profit that's a question
when it comes to some a model like Flo
but even no matter how you look at it
though AG is that the farmer always gets
screwed in Ag it's just it's what it is
and so you that's why you have to have
multiple permits you can't just be a
farmer the dream to be a farmer is a
dream but the reality is you're in the
lowest price point of the entire supply
chain so Flo Ken has got a choke hold on
the sun-grown because they're basically
beating everybody by price so if you
want if you get flow counter products
through the distributor they're lower
than other sun-grown models it makes it
difficult for other distributors to
compete with them because not every
distributor can afford to lose a million
and a half a month so so Flo can is
bleeding a million and a half a month at
least from documents that got released
into the public now they don't they
don't they won't publicly address that
but documents got released and somebody
brought it up and then said hey look
it's it looks like you're losing a
million and a half a month and so if
you're losing a million and a half a
month then how exactly is anyone
supposed to compete with you at that
level so if your model and I understand
this because basically like I said
earlier that that is the model of new
business is its price war it's can you
get enough investment so that you can
bleed everybody out long enough to
outlast them and so the thing is that
yeah you can flick Hannah's grab enough
farmers and putting them to work but are
they are those farmer and I don't know
I'm not involved with looking but I
don't seem to see people jumping up and
down I mean with the lead that they are
either so I would assume
that they're not getting paid very well
because if your company is losing money
the idea that they're paying you a lot
of money to lose money doesn't make any
sense to me it's more a strategy of
let's get the bottom line as low as
possible and then let's dump and then
that way we can get market share and
then hopefully market share converts
into value of business and then that's
an acquisition model I don't see because
it mean with the price for the farmer I
mean ultimately go up it could possibly
go up in time but I look at Oregon as
the for individuals that have
recognition like Washington only couple
farms are really making good money you
know what's that fat panned up there I
was doing really well because they put
that pan to do drop the price in half so
when they came into the industry the
first thing they did was cut it from 60
to 30 instantly when price war grabbed
huge market share use that to drive
their infrastructure in advancements so
they can operate at that level but if
you're not able to operate at that level
where you can drop your price by half
press wore it out grab share and then
use the share to build so you can still
live at that margin how are you going to
do it see the problem with the small
farmers in our regions is that they had
to go through the same amount of
infrastructure development as anybody
that was a big mean in that if you had a
ward across and effects for your for
your you know 1,500 square foot heritage
farm I got 25 plants you still have to
go spend 50 grand to get that culvert
fix just as if you had an acre so there
was no easement that's the political
thing here is that what made it easy for
you to do this no you didn't and you
didn't make it easy at all it's as
difficult as it could be and it's as
expensive as it could be so the smaller
farmers are going to get buried alive
that's where that that's been here
twenty five hundred five thousand you
know now you're talking forty farmers
form a collective because it's still
it's a it's for a core cap
and to me the only way that any bus any
bits are gonna do this is to work that
method I mean for me what I did for as
many years as I've been doing this is
I've been put in plants into people's
hands he couldn't get your hands on I
mean if it was red hot in the market I
had my hands on and I moved it into the
public right away and I didn't hold it
back for myself so only I could have it
I didn't look into the the grower world
so that this way we're always constantly
fresh and training so are you suggesting
for farmers to that are getting together
in forming cooperatives they're working
on that but they're growing similar
cultivars so that they have a larger
product two of the stalker or that's
only they're focusing on just a few
cultivars instead of a large variety
what is your advice my advice on that
would be if you have enough people you
have to realize that first you got to
figure out what's over produced so you
take a clear look at the market and you
say anything under 20% and numbers don't
mean a damn thing to me in terms of how
I smoke it but I'm being crystal clear
as a dispensary owner that stuff doesn't
have some numbers on it the market still
doesn't really care and it has no
extraction value so if you're not going
to have a certain amount of cannabinoids
present you can't blow the material you
so you can't have your tops move into
the world and all your lowers go because
if the numbers aren't prime the market
doesn't want to buy it so the market is
still numerically driven the numbers
alone the product won't move you have to
take a look at the nurseries that are
selling product is right now it's a
freak show track of traces of their play
they've got rid of they got rid of track
and trace here the SIP the system and
how what got whacked out metric hasn't
really kicked in fully because nobody's
really an Ewald yet but the nurseries
that are throughout the state
most of them selves are is similar
products whatever was hot and trendy in
their mind and so a lot of the farmers
were run in and get those the big
operations running and get those well
that's going to be a nice oversupply
come November
so these large monster operations starts
view and I mean they're they're dropping
some of these operations are good for
250,000 pounds a year so some of these
guys are dropping 12 to 20,000 pounds of
drop you don't want to be in that
wherever those varietals are that are in
those production models you don't want
to be in you need to be in something
that is a little differentiated so that
it's not fitting into that same mega
category because then you're going to
have to work off of efficiency they're
gonna get you on efficiency so you need
to go into things that are trendy in the
terms of what people desire that they
like fruits and Earth's that means like
in some kind of cherry pie lay it on top
of a cookie which is almost all these
new modern varieties that are
blisteringly hot or they're a sherbet
tied into something or it's an OG woven
into a fruit or it's it's the gorilla
glue because of the because of the
numbers and and the quantity is woven
into some kind of fruit little
differentiations so that you're not just
running the base varietal and if you can
get enough of the small farmers that can
produce at a similar production
methodology and are in similar
situations then what you have is enough
of that product to actually satisfy your
distributors where the distributors can
say hey listen we don't really don't
want to buy six pounds off you because
they're not filling niche dispensaries
what they would much rather have is
there is six hundred pounds of it
available so they can at least move the
supply chain and get it moved I think
that the major issue with this whole
problem for us is holding the product
once you've harvested it it does not
move through the chain quickly so what
you have to look at is first where do we
get differentiation where do we find
something that doesn't fit that doesn't
fit into the bigger picture but it's
desirable and then make sure the numbers
are hot if you got over three five on
the terms you got over twenty on the
numbers your your number looks good on a
shelf because those numbers drive
until the market the consumer realizes
that numbers don't really mean a lot
except an efficiency for extraction
we're kind of stuck with it and you have
to be Allah understand that if you go to
some of these big distributors some of
these big processors they have buildings
full of weed that are brown that is
sitting there because they can't move it
at the pace so you need to make sure
that your product is not overly
monoterpene dominant because the mono
turf is grateful fresh frozen where we
can freeze it we can extract it but how
much of that is moving and that's cheap
now too and so how much how much how
many people are really consuming fresh
frozen pen pens killing it but that's
distillate in Terps combined the fresh
frozen model is for people who like to
smoke pho and it's not as many people as
it was the you just don't see it every
when I go to events I don't see the
torches everywhere anymore now like I
used to so that market was never massive
it was just hot so everybody's gonna
shoehorn it into a tiny market you kind
of screwed so if you're gonna go into
that market you have to be model turf
driven but if you're going to go into
something that's going to sit for
five-and-a-half months before it moves
it has to have a couple of
characteristics that are important tasks
that an incredible density of flour so
that each time it gets handled in this
process it doesn't break apart into
pieces and it has to have a really good
deep rich sesquiterpene base so that it
holds flavor when it's consumed cuz most
of the stuff you see is damaged if
you're going to get into pre-rolls cuz
freerolls are hot
you better be crystal clear about who's
moving them in and what rate of speed
and that way you'd be able to determine
how much of your product do you convert
to pre-roll and move versus how much do
you hold back and then when it's
appropriate because as soon as I grind
that I oxidize it like diminish it and I
hold it and it diminishes and by the
time it
to somebody it's a c-minus and it was an
A and from somebody who knows a
tremendous number of farmers and then
sells the product the difference in what
they grew and what I sold is so
different there's no word for it and
it's not the farmers fault the farmers
are looking like shit because of this
they're all looking like they can't grow
the outdoor guys don't know what they're
doing it indoors better if it's not it's
the indoor models or predator primarily
people that are much more funded you
could afford to spend a couple million
minimum to build an indoor model you
typically have other investment groups
around you tied into supply chain
management which means your product
moves quicker and more expeditiously
so indoor I'm looking at two months old
outdoor I'm looking at seven months old
so why is that because of the fun of the
fact that they don't have the money so
their funding doesn't allow them to have
enough licenses to speed this up and to
control the quality so if you look at
wine a state a state means all processes
controlled in-house and so in a state
model is always considered better why
and then sending it to a subcontractor
to process even though the
subcontractors going to do the same
process the idea is that you're
controlling the variables of quality
more definitively and so that's the
thing that I see with cannabis is that
until we have an ability to get product
held correctly in stasis so we don't
have deterioration of the product
holding it in in some black plastic
totes in a garage waiting to get
processed is not what I would call the
right method but what do you do you have
to have an extremely expensive
sophisticated system to hold so then
when we will pass it on to other bigger
entities and they'll do it they don't
have the facilities either and have a
temperature and humidity of control
whatever the level needed and for the
varieties because not every variety
wants the same control so the bottom
line is you happen to be very specific
and we're not would be very general and
what it's doing is it's just destroying
the perception of value of these
products so the customer becomes
dissatisfied with some
and they become satisfied with some
sun-grown parts that move through but a
lot of it is they keep going lower and
lower pricing and what it does is it
takes a lot of these small craft people
that produces some exquisite probiotic
ly grown you know regenerative ly grown
cannabis skin is that's environmentally
friendly people put a lifetime effort to
get that good they're producing
world-class pop but the consumer market
doesn't care because they figure hey for
half the price I can get something
pretty close they're going to do it and
I think that that's such an issue with
us right now that it makes these
conversations just you know what do you
do and I tell people hey if you're
asking my opinion on what I'm doing I
was gonna go crude and then I started
laying out the numbers the other day and
I realized I would be better to lose 15
grand than to lose a hundred grand and
that's maybe make it back so what I get
to do is I get to run my farm on here
and not get paid myself that doesn't
make any sense
and so I think that the long game is
especially places like Humble County
more than most places is that the brand
value of Humboldt is strong outside of
California not in California as much as
California the big markets SF in LA and
and those groups are caught up with
their own hype scene and so Humboldt
doesn't have because the each Beach
region is competing for who's the top of
the food chain well they don't want to
buy our product there neither does LA in
the same way small groups do the
education has to happen and the pricing
has to be correct but the farmers that
are growing here have to be able to
survive long enough to do it and they
also have to be able to realize like in
their initial conversation we had about
genetics the stuff that you have might
not be yours by the time you put it out
because utility patents from these you
know the Baucus group he's gotta go
around it like 17 18 peppers right now
utility patents before patents on you no
wonder one no mare scene they own that
it almost seems like a strategy that
you're suggesting is to pull back from
the farming if you can and focus your
energy
you know like let your hold your permit
and do all the hoops and the fees to
keep the permit alive but you can all
you can also file that you're not
growing and so you don't have to pay the
tax on the cultivation and then put your
energy into preparing for when the
markets open up both in the States and
eventually globally building that
business so you have the structure of
your business solid so you have what
your marketing and branding is going to
be what your relationships are going to
be what your message is stand out
globally really because we're looking at
the possibility of global trade in the
next 10 years and definitely state to
state trade we're already there's
already talked about trade between
California and Oregon and how would that
affect the market Wow because they have
such oversupply in Oregon so it's the
same same situation it's just that you
know how do you financially handle this
and so for me I mean I would back to
work
you know it's insulting so I mean I'm
traveling all over the place to make
money and it's sure the hell not what I
wanted to do but I I have made the plan
based off of
the other states that went legal i
followed how they operated and i said
hey there's a beautiful window that when
legality opens up there's this
incredible opportunity to capitalize pay
back your investment on the farm break
yourself even so now the farms not a
liability it's an asset most of these
farms of liabilities right now really
because most people didn't get their
there they haven't ducked the whole
secret key component done they haven't
done all the environmental so that you
have like two minutes benefit whoa it
makes everything else cheap the permit
is not expensive it is the work to get
the permit that's expensive and that was
something that I thought I'd be able to
recover and kalyn nobody can get a
business loan like every other business
no and we never expected that I never
expect a business loan so I never
expected any miracle to occur but I
expected California to follow the other
states in the same way when each state
had the same exact first year of
legalization all farmers got paid so the
first year in Oregon first year in
Colorado first year in Washington
farmers made money after that prices
went down and then we went into this
overproduction the situation California
complete opposite which blew my mind and
I was wrong like I I built my farm and
aggressively went at it so that I could
recover the costs in the first year and
I just basically wiped out my capital so
what it did is it put me into a
situation where I realized all right
well where we are now because none of
this plan seemed that this doesn't make
sense and it's it's the largest cannabis
economy in the world probably is
California and we're probably the the
most inept in what we're doing and
regulatory regular like that's already
why it's you know and it's it's just
unbelievable and the kind of shopping
but we had this advanced watching
Colorado do it watching Washington do it
you know there was this possibility that
we were going to be the first because
that proposition fail prop 19 and then
so it seemed like you know people were
like oh well maybe this is a black
because we'll get to see the mistakes
made and yet Colorado and Washington as
Bessie as they bed and Oregon have
seemed to be better than California I
mean California is just the biggest shit
show well that's because we're so much a
bigger tennis
what is that's bigger it's much so much
bigger we making it with a years ago
make it count for making Colorado Oregon
and Washington look deliver and we are
and it just is so everything we do is
different because we're so powerful and
big as you know you have 40 million
people and there's money here so the the
way that you created the deserts
throughout the state just created a
disaster for sales and they didn't
people didn't really understand that the
society isn't so caught up on parody or
they wouldn't have fast food you
wouldn't have such an incredible obesity
and and lack of health in the country
because a lot of that's coming from the
food source what you're eating you're
being poisoned well if people can I mean
I think there's a hope that people are
waking up to that and there are a lot
there you know or less organic food is a
huge market you know it is why do people
do there is a huge market in the Bay
Area and there's people that will only
eat organic food but we're talking about
less compared to the regular market so
huge compared to what regular so organic
is how big a ratio compared to regular
going at local supermarket tell me how
big the organic aisle is tell me how big
the supermarket is there's a it's a
substantial niche yeah it's a niche
though yes it's a niche and who is in
that niche if it was in any of these
rural regions it was pot growers fuel in
it and I said this B is I believe a
cannabis organic cannabis production
drove organic food production
simultaneously because the people who
were growing wheat organically were like
hey we want to buy organic food it
became a market they could afford it but
right now I noticed that the liquor
store is selling a lot more pizza than
normal and cuz I'm there because it's
cheaper you can afford it it talented
you don't you know what's in it
versus a lot of the restaurants and
restaurants in town have you know a
largely organic food it's oh it's more
expensive double-double and so the thing
is can you afford it and does it do do
the people who buy organic produce smoke
a lot of pot who buys pot that's this is
a magnetic question that men is trying
to get you know sophisticated stoners
that's an oxymoron it is because stoners
historically of blue-collar workers
they're people who work hard and they
use cannabis because it allows them to
have very little side effects the next
day it lets them relax it lets them have
some kind of a theory or move you know
moment after work lets their body well
but wealthy don't smoke a lot of pot
they never have they like cocaine and
champagne and opiates and that's not
what we're making and that's not what
we're selling and so the blue-collar
individual in America is the one who
buys the predominant amount of cannabis
if you want to see places that move a
lot of weed they're not in Beverly Hills
they're in Compton Compton dispensary
moves more weed than Beverly Hills
dispensary never the hills are doing a
lot higher price point but they're
definitely not moving the same quantity
a week coming out of those shops in
Compton because the the people that are
living in in those type of situations
the lower priced cannabis works I'm from
I'm from blue-collar New England so I
grew up in a blue-collar reality I think
on it wasn't raised and when wealthy
Humboldt County where there was money
bubbling out of the ground like wells so
what you have here is this really odd
it's not accurate it's a reflection of
an in in an accuracy that people that
are regular have money this is regular
people who had money no longer to any of
the grower communities have money go to
any grower community in the California
and ask them are you doing well
financially
tell me anyone raise their hand and say
yeah I'm doing great I'm making money
like my business is thriving
very very few cultivators some
distributors are doing well some
extractors are doing well couple stores
are probably doing well process
and all that kind of stuff secondary
outside of cultivation the cultivators
show me anybody that's doing well and in
those regions and this is a change in
the last five years
obviously out last couple years in its
nationwide I mean I go around the US and
I see it across the u.s. that you're
seeing changes in global economy you're
seeing it in all the type of businesses
that your amount of money that you make
in any job is decreased versus
management so management and radically
change in what they make workers rather
than changing what they have
that's disposable income that directly
reflects it the chief markets are going
to become the ones the only way that a
we've survived as our little regions is
that we have us wide sales and we have
global sales and all we need is really
us at first because if you go to
anywhere from the Midwest down in the
southern region up they don't have the
ability to cultivate year-round like we
do and they most definitely have a
horrific time through the summer when
you would normally cultivate go to
Florida try to grow in ninety nine
ninety percent ninety degrees ninety
percent humidity tell me what you're
going to produce out there so you have
to go into it and so once you start
running these indoor operations your
cost of production skyrockets once
California and Oregon starts releasing
cannabis across the u.s. you think I
think these companies are going to
actually be able to compete price-wise
and so as a cannabis consumer when you
go to the store do you typically buy
Wagyu beef do you know you don't buy
forty bucks an ounce meat no as I say
you're a meat-eater but if you do you
typically buy what you can afford
very few people buy that they have to
advertise it to very wealthy or they
advertise it as a special occasion like
a graduation like a high-end bottle of
alcohol like you don't you may not drink
400 I love scotch but when you son
graduated you drank the bottle of scotch
so once every four years when it kid
graduates you buy one you got married
you got one
but mostly you're drinking Johnnie
Walker red and you know 20 bucks well
they wouldn't be selling so much of it
and so the problem of cannabis pricing
is that in order for people to pay
higher prices they have to understand
why they're paying and they have to have
enough exposure and with the new clients
that are coming in the new new customers
regular pot wipes them out so they get
high selling anything so they think a
little it's like alcohol when you were
12 and you first had your first beer you
didn't you're really a discerning Micro
beer connoisseur at that moment I only
like stouts you didn't know a damn
difference and so that's the problem is
that people that are coming in don't
have any experience with really quality
and it takes a minute to start to be
able to say well I got you the
aftertaste was radically different the
quality the high was better and man the
lucidity was better just better drug
cannabis it's a better experience
cannabis well that takes a minute to get
that education and when people are
buying products most people are very
cautious about price very few people
just close their eyes and say I buy what
I want they look at the price tag and
that's the reality and so the problem
with it is trying to get it into some
level that works for the farmer
[Music]