I think we were talking about growing
terpene and resin rich cultivars is what
you were talking about right it's
growing and selecting yeah so how to
select was where I was going with that
so I see I see water hash right as a
process that does not like some of the
cultivars that are like water soluble
terpenes I call them soon as like they
touch the water right they totally just
disintegrate and your yields are super
low and you're really left with nothing
so it's pretty much just a loss on
everyone's and you're pretty much thrown
thousands on the way down the drain
so to help that my my my years of just
kind of like poking around with the
plant and you know breeding have
searched for these bulbous bat heads
that like to act and feel like sand so
like that's kind of like the grain you
know the hedge structure that I aim for
when I'm searching for the hash plant as
I like to call it so with that you're
really finding it's a lot easier of
extract or a separation from you know
plant and hash at that point because
it's just it's like house and is sink to
the bottom of the water and you still
have such a something that a head that
doesn't want to like fall apart right
but are you only looking for one hedge
around
right and what the rally I mean we're
talking microscopic sand like bags
screams I wish there was technology that
like I really wish I had that I'm sure
it exists Stephen and maybe I just need
to get better with using certain tools
but it would be really cool to actually
have something that we could take a real
generic measurement and size of a
trichome head to know how big it is in
ratio compared to the stock the head
ratio also I'm sure we can kind of see
how thick the cuticle actually is and
determine you know maybe possibly how
quickly it will potentially dissolve in
the water or if it will not or whatever
but yeah I don't think it's necessarily
about looking for the actual physicality
of the trichome that it's more about
finding that right texture or that right
dryness is what I think he's trying to
say and to me the only way to fucking
figure that out is to wash it I have
people who asked me on consulting gigs
all the time to come and be like tell me
how to use a microscope and determine
what a hash strain is or they'll send me
weed like this is gonna smash look at
this it's gonna yield and I always say
if we're washing for fresh frozen cool
if it's dried material it's probably
gonna work out if it looks trichome rich
cool but if we're washing for fresh
frozen the only way to figure it out is
to wash for fresh frozen as far as I
know or that's the best way to know and
you'll know really quick into it you
know just by your paddle but like you'll
know if it's sticky or like oh this is a
really shitty resin and this is gonna be
hard for me to work with I guess like
not just the dry granular like head I
was like I'm even talking like live
fresh plant like that's how I know it
will good be a good fresh frozen I can
actually just like slightly touch the
plant where is it it bursts almost you
know what I mean or you can see well you
I can see literally you know the heads
pop right off like fresh fruit right off
the tree you know and still be in that
solid head form I mean to me the shape
but oval shape I don't know
so but that but but getting it right
before you know you go down the rabbit
hole of did we waste the wash or not you
know that's to touch it to feel it right
then in there to gain something from
that Games a lot yeah I mean you're not
gonna know exactly you know
percentage-wise or anything you're just
going to know because yeah I think it's
just like those some plans you could
touch and if we want to talk to some
plants I think alignment the lime lemon
lime terpene lime I mean that terpene is
harder terpene to get into that type of
resin and I think it's because it comes
from more of a sativa dominant plant
that's closer to the equator like
Frenchy was saying the the rain and the
climate and the plants are adapting to
these places you know though that
equator area to me doesn't make a type
of solvent less hash of the ice water
extraction way so I find it's the
mountain plants the you know the
Pakistanis the cushions that have you
know adapted to that climate that you
know make those heads and that's the
thing so when we step out of that
Afghani you know Pakistani pushes
breeding out of that into like what we
found today and these are the hash
plants of today you know I think that's
another big thing to bring up is it just
like when you're a hash maker and you're
just washing other people's material
it's really not it's not that big of an
investment it's not that much of a
commitment all it is is your time you
know right I could take someone's yard
in and process it in an entire day a
hundred pounds process it in a day and
again what did it take it took a day in
my time that gardener that it took them
to grow that whatever took months you
know possibly if it was outdoor six
months so all I'm saying is like to be
someone who simply washes other people's
material to me is just a completely
different journey he and I both
single-source
I choose to only pretty much wash my own
material I don't really I'm not
currently interested in washing someone
else's material maybe one day that will
go my path but I grow enough material to
keep me busy keep me interested and
that's really what intrigues me is to
take the resin from clone all the way to
the end of harvest to then process it
through hash and see what comes out on
the other end it's like the resin wants
you to harvest it it knows you you grew
it you made it you created it it wants
you and I feel like it gives it up to
you more you know we're like the yields
I get I tell people them and they're
just like all those percentages aren't
real you know and it's just like I don't
know there's something to that there's
something real romantic and deep about
it you know 100% yeah this is yeah we're
waiting for terpenes we're breathing for
obviously yield good yields so it's
worth our time and we can get more
absolute like what are some winning
genetics right and you asked what
flavors are you growing I'm growing some
we got a whole bunch of bunch of
different ones but like some of them are
ice cream cake we have that's a good one
golden strawberries you had
just made guava punch there's a no one
and there's a lot really I'm trying to
go down the list but what's something
that you watch that you were excited
with high hopes and then Alegent
disappointed you four or five years ago
as purple diesels just the other day I
watched mimosa it's like kind of a hype
California strain it's a tangi crossed
with purple bunch there's two different
like cuts out there that are circulating
in crowds one's more tangi leaning ones
more purple punch leaning they say oh
the purple punch leaner is a hash strain
because purple punch is it's a pretty
good hash sure tangey stereotypically in
my opinion is not a great hasher so
again I was told I had the purple punch
leaner structurally it looked purple
punch I was like this is gonna do it'll
be decent it's gonna be alright 2% or
something like that
it was literally Oh point zero four
percent
I got like 30 grams off of four pounds
what would be dry material it's not
sustainable and that's the whole thing
is is like yeah we love making hash yeah
we love and that's the other thing is
like it's not only if it was maybe the
world's best hash
I wouldn't fucking care I would eat it
that hard and be like whatever I'll keep
this all for myself and I have the
world's best ash but it wasn't even like
that great of a hash string and that's
what I find is like a lot of people
sometimes think that well like sometimes
those low Yolo yielders are just great
and like in my experience it's not that
way either the resin is capturable or
it's not either you can grab it and
harness it or you can't and like I said
yeah I watched some mimosa and I ate it
it was awful it was terrible I usually
like the ones that you eat it on like
and it doesn't work you can find that
terpene and another
usually fuck yeah yeah or cross it with
something else so that mimosa if I loved
that I could just find something better
myself and go hit it with it and maybe
next season get it you know and I mean
but yeah you gotta mess around with
lines out history so it's a cool little
like adult toy you know what I mean like
it is what it is what I'll find is like
it worked really well indoors on like
your coffee table out here with like it
being cold and you know it is even just
doing dabs outside like the temps never
the same when I said this temperature so
to me it wasn't working really well
outside but it is what it is it was fun
it was cool to do it like inside fun
little toy not necessary by any means so
again the I have a bunch of like you to
saying drier resins that run really well
man like animal cookies that was 3% it's
really good like GMO I rot 8% off that's
the best I've ever gotten like you know
what I mean like it's north its
strawberry banana like that's hash
strains motorbreath hash string key lime
hash strain last year at the region I
had some
they evoke oh yo so this is literally
from the same batch I just had it in my
fridge forever you know and I mean but
please smoke as much as you want man
it's literally from the same plugin I'm
sorry I apologize
he basically grows his own he's never
smoked the flower he just turns it all
in the hatch sure sure I thought it was
a cool story cuz heat like yeah fuck
yeah I got you man
I'll get you want a GM oh yeah yeah oh
yeah I'll give you that too animal
cookies yeah
I'll get you it's that cold cure like
flan shit so he's whole plant washing
and and and is he dumping like is he
bringing all the material back into the
greenhouse how was he working for it was
he feeding with I know
that's a big thing for me with living
soil for me I've been building like my
soil for quite slike handful of years
now and like a lot of people have been
building in the last like hope like two
years or even year and I noticed what I
did it in the first year to like I had
to really like take a detrimental like
crop like yield loss because I wasn't
fertile oh yeah we got better yeah it
gets better but yeah just wondering how
is like how many years like well yeah as
long as you dedicate and stay true to it
and I feel like when you cut corners and
you want to like supplement add
something in because you feel like it's
necessary
it ends up maybe taking two steps back
sometimes you know and sometimes it's to
each his own but I feel that from a
strong have you tried this California
hash oh yeah I love I grew up on the
East Coast
always cultural like New Jersey and it
was just it was it was a religious thing
in a young kids age over there to to
roll up a bunt in between just about
everything you do so yeah
yeah totally there is this like whole
nother like do this is right no like
part is new you know new not like
brand-new but freeze dryer is not that
old it's probably like five years old
you know but in the grand scheme of
things it is yeah yeah because they just
came out the pharmaceutical yeah that's
new so of course young people are doing
it you know so honestly I Butte baby I
just used trash Burroughs man and I am
helping my friend who has like a nice
facility back east that I'm helping out
with he's went and got those things and
you spent $16,000 all um and I literally
told him like man I'm gonna go to
Walmart and probably buy some food trash
barrels and like go maybe we'll go ahead
maybe maybe we'll mess with those
they're cool they're really nice I'm not
knocking it you know like if you come on
if you're gonna spend it's not cheap if
you're gonna spend all this money on
like you know I have the be-all-end-all
lab and you're a big brand yeah cool get
it man but like what I try to tell
people is like you can invest in a more
money
minimal money that you can instantly
recoup in solving this it is not rocket
science mechanical extraction is not
hard
I truly believe yeah yeah no machine
that gives you the ability control and
that's the whole other thing was like
once you start to know the resin so
intimately I can soak my material and
just look at it and be like I need to
hit it this long I need to wash it this
many times I should row it this hard you
know and I mean and I'm gonna make Mel I
should ease off I'm gonna make rods and
I'm just gonna get it you know what I
mean like
there's just yeah I wash different ways
for different things and that's why I
like and rowing I'm on in a snotty way
like oh it makes the world's best ash it
gives me control that I don't have with
the machine because I couldn't afford
Oh 100 are you here hand I draw look at
people get those flip palms really
people like those really expensive
presses and like again well I know you
can make an SOP and show someone how to
run those machines and like it's no
problem but like me personally I just
like using that hand pump and it's like
a fish on the end of a rod like I can
feel the bag resist yeah and then I'm
like go slower yeah and then I feel it
ease into it and you ease it out and I
don't know just something more about the
physicality of it I just feel like
that's what we have to like remain in
this to keep it craft is to be really
meticulous about everything we do and to
do what kind of well you can't your own
type in online you can't read in a book
right now what our hands are feeling in
that machine or what iPad or what our
minds and our eyes would see you have to
do it for so many years you have to lose
so many dollars and then
you know you realize what the hell is
going on I got I live in Humboldt County
which is the land of abundance so like
there's a lot of hash drinkers there
fortunately they helped me out a lot
where like when I like have questions
and early on and like freeze-dry or
knowledge and all that and just people
to reach out to but there's a lot of
good hash makers up in home little
county man like say what you a lot of
people will follow solvent list mine and
love and hate him he's up near me he's
he's a good dude he's always worked and
he's always making hash say what you
will have hash Jacob
he works for talking tree he makes a
really great product for talking trees
in the recreational market it's a great
kid makes great hash select solvent less
works for Popham Barkley say what you
will about poplin Barkley he's he's
loves hash he makes it fester sift is
another homie I know a lot of hash
makers you know and just like you know
everyone's ganja people up and up around
these parts he's a little further north
of me you know what I mean but I got a
whole country in my neck of the woods
there's I like Bryant black Ram organics
yeah he's actually introduced me and got
me into dragonfly this is
six years ago this is way back and yeah
for that I mean he he had some really
good product
underrated I feel like a little bit you
need to be on every table for sure she
holds it the fuck down so if you can
ever get some black RAM farms hash and
they're lying
your honor yeah that uh somebody called
out where BC Bowman I did a field test
it's like field test star tech might be
our that's a wide
I call it jarred tech but well it's just
field test with a jar it's a works I
guess
I mean people should probably do it
because if not you might lose thousands
of dollars and just come out looking
like a fool so yeah ice and water you
just need some knowledge of hash making
a sense or you need to have something
that you know that yields well to base
it off well that's the whole thing in my
opinion is like I would know that they
would already know that you know goes
without saying right goes without so
yeah just a little bit he's a little
further north up in Oregon if you wanna
if you want a GMO rip I got one for you
right here yeah I'll give you
I love that GMO yeah a lot of people are
acting like it's like dumb for them but
it's a great it's a great mastery and
sort of me people crashing it in years a
fruit fruit fruit skunky pcgame yeah I I
grew up back east and like Massachusetts
where chem dogs come I was born in
Bridgewater raised in Rhode Island there
you go I was Little Compton just a very
small little little town knowing those
but 34 yeah I'm from back there so I
grew up on gas yeah absolutely I wasn't
trying to be rude I apologize yeah yeah
yeah I just always wait for people to
ask so I don't feel like they put him on
the spot here pressure him into taking
ribs they don't want
yeah for sure
Rhode Island I mean yes from a young age
luckily yes luckily I guess oh where the
real high-grade came where when my
little Mecca was like Vermont we got all
our high-grade from Vermont we used to
like joke about getting the high grade
from the hippies in Vermont and it was
real you know they had it that was the
scene that was our Humboldt was up there
and that's where I went after as soon as
I got became an adult I moved up to
Vermont followed ganj up there and those
are myosin so it was to the
east of there actually for skiing or
snowboarding would you melon I used to
ride Jay Peak that was my spot I was up
in like eating area and Jay but uh those
are my fondest memories when I was a kid
like yeah like I said we didn't I didn't
really know what high grade was we got
like be stirs that was what we got and
like they like it was like Canadian
indoor hydroponic weed and I thought
that was the best because it was better
than the Mexican weed that we would get
you know I mean and then someone showed
me like Trinity weed it was called the
Trinity but it was from Vermont that's
when I was like oh this is what real
weed is and it just changed my whole
view on it and so again they were
growing this shit skunk number six that
if I could uh I would do things for if I
could get that today man I would do
things for sure and uh had white grape
Afghani had a green spirit the show
called the Elvis at Trinity was really
the most elite stuff that like everyone
grabbed up that we would get mr. nice
guy over there that was way different
than the West Coast mr. nice guy it was
like green and it was fire and that's
the thing
even the a K we used to get back there
was different than like the West Coast a
K not saying one's better than the other
there were just different different cups
in my opinion yeah those were the ones
that really burned in my head you know
used to get this other one almost called
gnarls burg you know I was probably just
some cheese some kind of cheese cross
but uh I was really fired man that's
cool to like date your life I can like
think back to different points in my
life and be like what was I smoking them
there was Manhattan haze coming around
Brown hey talk about the AIDS in the
south the haze in the shower was
irregular for us I had friends that
would eat sleep and breathe office our D
there was yeah it's a it's a sour diet
the dour diet called sour D haze and
what we called pith which was sometimes
like some people call it from the haze
but the results is it's like really
cushy it literally we call it like
almost like spongebob was like this
spongy hippie like just the first like
craziest-looking really chronically and
we always called that piff so and then
blue dreams I think it was around 2010
blue dreams started coming down from
SoCal I'm cutting open the first vacuum
of vac bags and that's and then I left
to Jersey to Jersey yeah we were smoking
the real blue dream we're smell like
dryer sheets and that shit was 2010 and
then I do remits
on the East Coast oh yeah if it's a real
cut if it's that cut they grown whoever
they drew it yeah I don't know but I
don't smoke anymore so poor I mean it'll
come back around but I don't smoke it
anymore today yeah so I did some
laughing because that's what everyone
always argues it's like well no but the
blue dream I had yeah I'm sure I'm not
saying it wasn't I agree with you though
the blue dream 2010 yeah no I hear that
the current phase yeah yes a real shit
so yeah that was fuckin awesome good
things good things always from the haze
so we don't get that out west here so
I'm gonna try to I think in the future
find a haze plan that washes really well
yeah I'm always chasing like that new
turf you know and I mean just that new
something like I got some like Tropicana
fucking cookies crossed with papaya
recently seeds that I'm only getting
forward to croc like pop it in like
papaya chirps are really popular right
now I'll probably be played by the time
I have them in my hands but you know how
it goes but uh yeah I'm always just onto
that next thing man you know for sure ya
know I go for that haze effect when we
can take a dab of that uh that type of
shit that makes your heart want to pop
out of your chest and you get like
freaked out in a big crowd when was the
last time you got high like that for me
it's been fucking forever so I kind of
like I'd pay big money to have that
again I need that dude I yeah I want
I'm pretty chill like I can't well and
to get the work done so I do a lot of
work at home one of the fuck you know
take that rip and you have like that
speedy coke vibe you know and that's
just like I think that's the canvas
plant working in its mysterious ways of
bringing you so high up where you know
some people can't handle it you know
it's not for beginners but some people I
can handle it I can get so much fucking
work done you know and maybe skip out on
a meal if I have to it's a little fresh
that's cool then again warm
that's just a rosin though I like the
hash anymore I have so many flavours
coming soon like some my lungs that all
like that no one's ever tasted in hash
Florence sometimes be knows if you say
you got to buy a pack of seeds and hung
out the hash piano but it's really
common to you know get the GMO but to
have something like super unique it's
really it's a good hunt it down yeah
yeah everything goes the same exact way
it's just different from the harvest you
know I don't look at the plant on who's
the biggest who yields or who flowers
the fastest it's not that it's the best
field with the best chirp best quality
you know just overall and then some of
them like always come out different you
know like I say like they're all gonna
come out white or something they have
different tinge is a color from a look
of gold to maybe an even amber you know
but it'd still be like wait consider it
is the best of the best you know goes
through the same process it's just you
know different flavors different shades
and stuff it's really cool
[Music]
I think that Jar