I've been doing that since 1986 so talk
to me about strains from the past that
you can't find a skunk wad true skunk
one the golf-ball indica nobody has it
anymore
that's that one
the original mando purple golf ball in
because it's gone you saw there you saw
it coming out of Mendocino Ukiah that
area and it was just phenomenal and it's
gone you know it disappeared in the
early 90s both of those both of those
days the camp raids were more effective
than people think they were I mean yeah
a lot of grills were left intact up
there but a lot of stranger lost a lot
by just attrition or by by bolt by both
crossbreeding the seeds you know
pollination that people didn't really
know where that pollen came from you
know we had some great sticky weed in
the late 80s early 90s
to talk about the SS f v OG so I still
have that string I've had it for 27
years week long what's the history of
which it actually came in through Point
Mugu Naval Air Station in a backpack
from those old Navy SEALs that we're
working in Afghanistan that's where it
came that's where it came and you got a
cut and I got a cut I got a bag of seeds
directly out of there and and what made
that a stand out purely affect it is the
original PK so sfv og its original name
with PK you know the pure coach and that
is the original ffs empty what's just a
pain in the ass to grow it was like an
ivy plant it went everywhere you know it
was just compared to like your Northern
California indica plants that were nice
and in uniform and bushy and you know
grew up like this this thing you
switched it into in the flower its
initial stretch could be as much as two
or three feet in 11 12 14 days like
maintaining a light height on those was
just like wow you know super hard you
know and and your bud structure was
nowhere as close together that's the end
of us out of Northern California you
know it would be like a bud and then a
blank spot for eight or nine inches
another bud and then it was like an ivy
plant just going everywhere so getting
that plant to respond properly and get a
tight bud structure what's this really
really
top play it's still it oh yeah oh yeah
what is your firm called you know so mr.
nice guy LLC is is our farm in Santa
Barbara
it's licensed from half baked yeah dave
chappelle is a brand ambassador exactly
exactly yeah