navigating the regulations trying to
figure out how to get into the market
how to get into the market legally how
to build partnerships that are scalable
has been you know a big part of what
we've been trying to do and then on the
fundraising side there's obviously like
a lot of interest and a lot of money but
again finding those partners that can
bring value as well as those partners
that are strategically aligned to the
type of growth that you want to have and
kind of keeping this especially as I
guess Outsiders to the industry is not
those that have been in the gray market
one of the things that's been important
to us though has been actually working
with small farmers and we have an
established relationship with a licensed
farm in medicine oh it's a big part of
it but some of the pushback we've
actually gotten from some investors as
well as as well as some manufacturers
that we've talked about partnering with
has been oh like you don't need to do
that like we've got this stuff that's
grown in this warehouse and you should
just roll forward with this it's much
cheaper and it's much easier and like we
can make that happen much quicker so
finding those partners that are have
that value alignment has been a little
more difficult for us but something that
we're working on and what's your product
oh yes if the product drew Martin is a
line of botanically infused freerolls so
cannabis with a specific blends of
botanicals that have been formulated by
by drew Martin himself herbalist