[Music]
nobody thought that they wiped that
conventional market out so quick and and
nobody thought that you know they'd wipe
out the small farmers on the legal side
to sow the effects of it it's like we
beat it to death and then people feel
the effects but I guess that what you're
saying is yeah what do we do about are
you talking about what's the action plan
from there I've talked about a subsidy
for a lot of these small farmers or
they've been there for 30 years or
something I mean they should just come
up with billions of dollars and give
them a couple hundred thousand and a
piece or something because that's it's a
two-fold effect cuz you know most of
they've lost a lot of the value in their
real estate because because the farms
aren't worth as much you've seen
depreciation especially in those
outlying areas like Bell Springs spy
Rock Island Mountain and everything else
it's really been heartbreaking so what
do you think the action plan is I mean I
think I think tax relief especially for
the small farmer would go a long way you
know there's just the inability for the
small farmer to compete price-wise
against you know corporate cannabis
that's coming in and growing you know
tens or hundreds of thousands of square
feet of yeah of canopy you know if there
was some relief there for the small
farmer on the tax side of things they
could actually compete with that market
a lot better I mean like - how to just
complete you know well I mean I was
really sad to see you know there was
movement to have the cultivation tax
canceled essentially for multiple years
and then reinstituted in a more
responsible way down the road that bill
didn't make it through and I feel like
in a lot of ways that was kind of the
knife or the dagger into in the heart
for the small farmer is to you know not
pass that through the legislation I was
like a thousand cuts like Swami says cuz
they're different ways they've just
chopped us you know one piece at a time
but definitely that's their and I don't
know how like you said I agree
completely small farmer can't compete
against have one big company's got 500
acres you see the stuff that they're
getting right now it's just amazing the
size of scope
you