yet first of all I do I do see coops
working together and there's more to it
than just crop coordination there's more
to it than just trying to mandate
everybody to grow the same things even
in the formation of our local
cooperative we've been able to learn
from successes and failures alike from
the different incarnations of Emerald
grown over the years and being able to
reach out to farmers that are going
through parallel permitting process
processes in other counties learn from
an extra year or two of experience has
been very very helpful um and so you
know I'll just speak to emerald grown
specifically emerald grown is not a
cannabis cooperative it is a federation
of cannabis cooperatives and so there's
a certain level of efficiency and scale
you can achieve within a single chapter
22 co-op that is limited at four acres
cumulative so the membership of the coop
as a whole can only grow a total of four
acres but if you link together ten four
acre blocks then you're a much larger
scale and so the Federation structure is
relatively common in agriculture it is
relatively common to two agricultural
producers there there's a rice growers
coalition in the northern half of
California's Central Valley that is a
bit like a Federation of co-ops that's
that nobody's ever quite made a model
like the Emerald grown model it is
intentionally meant to be a place where
all of the coops can come together at
the end of the day cooperation to me is
about much more than how we structure
our businesses cooperation is the reason
why humans Homo sapiens persisted when
other upper level primates didn't this
is actually to our very core it is my
belief that our ability to work together
makes us who we are ability to empathize
to care about other people's interests
needs their feelings and so cooperation
runs much much deeper and so this isn't
just about forming a co-op this is about
creating a cooperative global system and
what better resource to do it within
cannabis and you know we have been able
to flex some of those efficiencies of
scale to talk with some of the leading
experts there's a law firm out of
Arkansas where agriculture coops are
very common
these folks would literally wrote the
book called special laws pertaining to
agricultural cooperatives 0% chance that
any one of our farms would have been
able to afford them collectively we've
been able to spend some time working
with them and so we've hammered out I
think a pretty cannibis it was
definitely born of cannabis and it's
meant for our market one last point on
being able to work together you know
sometimes we take flak that the Emerald
triangle is the Emerald triangle and it
doesn't include you guys and and I just
want to make very clear that that to me
there's something deeper than the place
where I grew up there's a culture that I
grew up in like Casey said when he
crossed the river like this was home
this is where our people live and I felt
that since I decided to be an advocate
and get to know growers all over the
state you feel that in these different
pockets so the Emerald triangle may be a
three County geography on the north
coast but the culture the the Emerald
grown culture is something larger that
transcends and it's something that as we
go global I think it is something
recognizable that a much larger group of
coops can stand behind at the end of the
day I think we should be the supplier
the primary supplier of flour globally
and I think we should do that by working
together I think that's the pathway
forward at this point and you know kind
of piggybacking on that there's a
difficult that there's a loss in
translation a lot of the times in in the
you know you talk you really hit the
nail on the head Jonathan with the two
circles the industry circle and the
culture circle and when those overlap
magic happens and a lot of times that
overlap isn't happening and one of the
big questions for us has been how do you
in trying to convey the culture like how
do you accomplish that and with the the
the co-operative statute only allowing
four farms 10,000 square feet and
smaller that creates a definition that's
a that creates the potential for a
paradigm there and so that's one of the
things that I'm really excited about is
this idea that cooperative cannabis can
come to mean and to be synonymous with
the culture that we all come from
because it was cooperative like if you
know if the one neighborhood got cleaned
out that by the Fed then everybody
chipped in for the winter you know
so it's it's been this thing over
decades for a long time and it's both
like I think the most challenging and
heartbreaking thing right now in terms
of seeing the transition but also the
the biggest point of potential moving
forward is that this thing has been real
and and has meant something and if we
can communicate that to the marketplace
in a way that that is understandable
then it's it's gonna stand on its own
for the future and especially you know
that the state market it right now is
really really challenging but when you
look at you know this this whole thing
happening with like acreage and the
thing being hinged on federal
legalization when like that kind of
money starts to move in that arena
you're like well this is gonna happen
really soon and so when we start to look
at what happens under federal
legalization cooperative California
cannabis I think has a tremendous
potential and it's like you know fed
legalization has been kind of like the
pie in the sky thing for a long time but
like I say when you start to see that
kind of monetary happening it's like oh
boy this this thing is shifting fast and
so for us it's about like I you know I I
feel that it's it's about getting
ourselves together and being able to
agree on a paradigm that represents what
has been and what will be in commercial
horticulture we've typically seen coops
gathering together to just bring a
similar crop to market with more
efficiencies what do you guys see as the
the possibility of working with the
special genetics that each of our small
farms have that we've all been breeding
on our own pieces of property I mean you
know all the large scale farmers are
growing acres of diesel and all the
desert flavors and all the batik flavors
and and even as a small farmer yeah okay
we can we can most likely produce a
higher quality product of that strain
but but what value do we have of having
the genetics that aren't available to
these large scale farmers this is both
like the tremendous blessing and
something of a curse like the first year
with emerald groves like we had 40 farms
everybody had 10 to 25 strains 2 to 10
pounds 20 pile
son it was just like oh my god happy so
it's like like start start small like
start with something that works and
branch back out into it one of the
things that I'm really hopeful for is is
cooperative nursery processes cuz it's
like everybody knows old-timers that
have a barrel full of seeds of all kind
of things that we didn't know what they
are we don't know what they test we
don't know what they do there's there's
been no systematic genetic sift and and
a lot of those seeds are in danger of
going by and so you know I think it's
it's a dual facet of like figure out
some baselines that work and then
develop into and I'm saying this because
this is what I'm trying to figure out
myself right now is like what are the
things that work and then what can I
develop into moving forward because it's
like if you show up with four hundred
strains of two to ten pounds of each
it's just it's like a marketing
nightmare and so that there's a there's
a I think a balance there of like
figuring out what are special unique
things to each terroir to each
neighborhoods and then being able to to
propagate those forward within the
cooperative and then also sift along to
find other things moving forward so you
know first I think we could look at
coffee as a relatively decent analog in
terms of other commodities that I'm
checking on and keeping an eye on there
we are seeing a proliferation of more
genetic diversity there and we are
seeing co-ops and connection between
market and-and-and farm build some of
that so to me you actually when we when
we formed Emerald grown the goal was to
sort of document to catalog to
articulate the craft and the culture the
culture of craft cannabis and we came up
with four elements microclimates
genetics culture and heritage and so
genetics are the point of this whole
experiment is to proliferate more
diversity the way that we're dealing
with this operationally this year you
know we our marketing strategy is the
tool with which we sort of balance
between consumer demand and suppliers
needs and it's not a one-way street it's
it's very much a two-way street and so
we're trying to create opportunity for
both we're encouraging that folks who
participate in the Emerald grown program
grow for the house brand the house brand
is prescriptive it
a couple genetics that we've picked out
you know a good upper a good downer good
in the middle and a solid CBD everybody
grows a little bit of that so we will
have a consistent house brand around the
state if you need it but then we also
are building spin-off brands whether
they're regional brands to highlight a
place whether they're cooperative brands
whether they're brand collaborations and
these brands get a lot more specialized
the one that will be bringing to market
first is farm cut it's a minimally
processed process on the farm the farmer
is getting not a great price for the
pound but because they're also getting
the labor of packaging there's enough of
a value add on farm that they're getting
a living wage for that pound it's that
and and that farm cut product is meant
to highlight a very small batch
specialized nobody touched it except the
farmer from plant to jar when you get it
you're the next human to touch it since
the person who loved it that's meant to
be an ultra small batch we're turning
away anything more than ten pounds and
so to have these different channels to
explore the small batch to explore the
art and the craft while putting this
bedrock of a house brand underneath of
it we think that this two-way
conversation between farmer and consumer
is going to produce what we all want
which is tons of choices that's really
what this is all about so we're pretty
sure we might get there if not we'll you
know have fun growing good flour on the
way and just to break it down a little
bit in terms of you know for instance on
farm like I'm not packaging into eighths
it's it's not cost-effective it's not
time effective but if I can do half
ounce and ounce increments and you know
take the big leaf off so but it's
minimally processed that's something
that I can still accomplish on farm at a
small scale and so the goal like
Hezekiah said it's to minimize the
packaging cost by going a larger unit
and minimize the processing costs so
that I can still do it on farm myself
without having a commercial building and
a crew which for a lot of small farms at
this point is very difficult like I
don't have a commercial building and so
to try to figure out a way to keep some
of that value on farm by being able to
do you know the those those steps and so
and and ideally to be able to deliver to
the consumer something that's cured
excellently that's in a larger
unit size that is at a valuable price so
that because what we're all seeing out
there is like patients who are and and
consumers who are paying these huge
prices for small amounts of weed and
it's like man that's that kind of cuts
out the tradition of the thing and so
the goal like I say is to be able to
hold value on the farm and also get
value to the consumer you bring up a
good point I went into one of my first
dispensaries the other night and
thankfully I don't have to go into
dispensaries but it was it was a it was
an experience oh it was a but give
thanks to all the dispensary owners yes
absolutely absolutely because not
everybody has the opportunity to to grow
all their own and one of the things that
that I really experienced while being in
there well there was a couple things and
I've been saying this for years its its
how do we tell our story and more
importantly how do we communicate that
story to the consumer because our best
friend is small farmers as an educated
consumer because once they're educated
about the product they can make the
decision of who they want to support and
what products they want to buy but
overwhelmingly when I was in this
dispensary it's just a bunch of boxes
and some guy that's doing his best to
tell me everything about it but really
at the end of the day you know I would
just look at what what's the coolest box
you know so so how are you guys working
with your farmers to tell not only the
story of the coop but the story of the
farmer well I mean I've stopped going to
cannabis events which you know a lot of
you know that I speak a lot you're an
exception I'll come to any event you
host ever but these days I talk to other
folks because like the cannabis
community it probably already has access
to cannabis let's be real it's the rest
of the consumers that need and it's sort
of like Casey's don't know you don't
know thing earlier there's a lot of
consumers out there that don't know that
they don't know where their cannabis
comes from and you don't even actually
the cool thing at least for me like I
don't actually have to push a farm I can
just say hey cooperative cannabis you
guys like go check out a co-op and then
it doesn't matter you know which shop
your
in where in the state it might be happy
day it might be down-home it might be
somebody totally else but having that
cooperative that recognizable center of
gravity that we can all come back to
that we know means values means culture
I think just you know the more it feels
putting my consumer hat on because I am
a consumer of lots of things
cannabis one of them I don't like it
when people tell me here smoke mine it's
the best but if you let me smoke it and
I decide it's the best then cool I'm
stoked and so you know show somebody the
door don't tell them which door to walk
through has has really been you know my
approach on that
you