let folks know that their that this
place exists you know the two three
gosh it's 2019 now four years ago on the
floor of the assembly the assembly
member for the North Coast said to hit
the rest of his colleagues like hey you
guys there is no weed fairy every gram
consumed in every community comes from a
farmer and a lot of them are in my
district and a lot of them are in
Brian's district Brian you know being
the guy who represents just north of
here who may be your next state senator
but like there isn't a weed fairy and
people just have never really like water
comes from the tap
cannabis comes from the DEA the hustler
like that's all there ever was and so we
need to start breaking down that
paradigm in general but I think giving
people a win showing them that door is
it's a gateway it's a gateway into a
whole greater way of being an awareness
and just show them the gate I would just
add that here locally Grass Valley
growers has only begin to scratch the
surface in telling the story and the
culture and heritage of this place and
the people that made it happen going
into the future I really look forward to
being able to involve more people to
tell that story you know it's
interesting there's a lot of
similarities in the small farms and so
how do you articulate what makes each
one special and I think there's a few
different ways to do it from you know
location and terroir and history and
then also for me it's it's you know from
a personal perspective like that that
concept of the the ethos of homesteading
which you know I draw a really clear
difference in in cannabis reality
between homesteading and resource
extraction and we've seen both paradigms
you know and and so for me it's very
important to be able to articulate the
reality of the homestead or the food
production the fruit trees the chickens
the weed all of the different facets and
and to try to communicate that in a way
that that connects and you know asked me
in five years and I'll tell you how it
goes
Casey I'm really glad you used the W
word so I've seen a lot of change in our
culture since we'd became cannabis since
everybody talks about ganja as cannabis
and and everything has as shifted you
know for better for worse what do you
see as far as the cultural perspective
of how you you are working with these
changes as we has become cannabis and
people are looking at a different thing
because there's there's honestly you
know again for better for worse there's
a bit of a gentrification happening in
the coal in the cannabis culture right
now and you know on a lot of levels you
know gentrification is nice you know I
like to eat out at nice places and this
and that but I also have to be aware of
what's happening in order to create
those conveniences you know it's it's
really interesting there's a lot to
unpack there this idea of you know words
have power and the words we choose to
use convey a lot of things and so in the
process you know it's kind of this
iterative process in which early on you
know the the newspapers it's the pot
growers did a bit a bit a bit of it and
in the legislature it's like so you're
here to talk about marijuana and they
can't even say it at full volume and so
you know that transition from marijuana
to cannabis was was very important
because it was it was a taking of an an
ownership of the process and the
terminology and and we said every step
of the way like look right now we're
we're working to support the process of
creating regulations as soon as
regulations exist we're gonna be like
any other industry we're gonna be
fighting about the regulations and so
that's really where we are now is that
it has come to that point where now
we're not asking for something we're
trying to push back against something
and and so you know I don't necessarily
have an answer to like what the
appropriate terminology is yet because
we're all still iterating it but it's
it's definitely the the transition has
happened and now we're trying to figure
out you know essentially how to pick up
the pieces I think that when when Nixon
Claire Dewar on the anti-war left and
people of color with the intention of
disrupting communities incarcerated
leaders that there was more going on
there I think that stoners which I'm no
longer ashamed to be I struggled with it
a lot growing up but I am a sodor and I
do like to smoke weed and that's just
what it is and we're actually the
majority and our communities have been
intentionally and systematically
disrupted for many many many many years
now since I think that was the 68
election that that conversation was
actually had and so to me I would never
call it weed if I were advocating you
know when we went to the legislature it
was cannabis that was the accurate term
that was the correct term but I don't
use other slang words when I talked to
Senators either right it's it's there's
a time in a place and so to me pivoting
into cannabis as a term for the purpose
of advocacy was the absolute correct
decision it gave us the ability to have
a conversation without all of the
triggers and the stereotypes but I tell
you what I am a stoner and I like to
smoke good weed and I will never change
that that is what I am and so are all of
you and so are most of them and it's
cool yeah and the heart of weed that
just didn't really flow as much as the
heart of cannabis you know thw like the
throwback right like I do a radio show
and I called the farm and reefer report
because that's what like my dad when I
was a kid he was always like that it was
reefer and so you know the different you
know the different iterations over time
is something that I think like we really
you know we really hold on to and and
and do honor unto and then there's an
even older generation that referred to
refrigerators as reefers and it almost
got us in trouble once when our landlord
got us a new refrigerator in college and
stopped by to see the new reefer well he
walks in and he says he says I'm here to
see the I'm here to check out the reefer
and and I'm just like and I'm kind of
like I'm like well I guess off with the
bay we
and my other roommate is like the new
fridge is excellent Dave we're really
and I'm the old that's what's going well
bring it bringing it back to the coop so
Daniel what what do you see what are you
looking for in a farm when somebody is
interested in joining your coop and what
if what do you as a coop offer to the
farmer well first of all I don't think
of it as my coop it is our co-op and
whoever takes part in it has ownership
and control in that cooperative just the
same as everybody else me personally as
a farmer I'm a polyculture farmer I like
to bear fruits and vegetables right
alongside my cannabis as well so on a
personal level I would like to see more
farms of that variety come into the
group but I would not expect everybody
to jump on board with something like
that it's more of an attitude of
cooperation like these guys have
mentioned before there are lots of
standards and regulations put down on us
from above
whether it be category 3 testing
determining that we're completely free
of pesticides or anyone that can get
through the piles of paperwork we have
to do probably has a decent level of
competency anybody that's actually
achieved full compliance is likely a
good member of a cooperative if they
have the attitude of cooperation it
there's a there's a certain level of
selflessness I think required to go into
it because we are working for a greater
good I know I've put countless hours
into this since I first started working
towards cooperatives and yes it is to
see my own farm succeed but without
seeing other local farmers succeed I'm
in a failed community and I don't want
to live in a failed community word yeah
big up and that's you know I think
that's a commonality here that drove all
of us into the the regulatory process
the dialogue around regulatory
development was seeing the community
survive the community thrive
and one of the things I think that's
really important there's a lot of
resources on mo groan comm there's a
cooperative how to develop a cooperative
presentation that's that's really
helpful it's you're starting a business
with other people right and so you've
got a bunch of partners you're all
owning and running this business and
it's really really important to figure
out what your foundation is and where
you're going with it because it's really
easy not to have because those
conversations can be difficult and too
if you don't really drill down into it
and nail down what it is you're trying
to do you can get a couple years into it
and have a whole lot of different you
know we got two years into emerald
growing and like some people wanted it
to be a distribution cooperative some
people want it to be a marketing
cooperative some people wanted to just
wanted to sell the weed and and so it
you know it's it can be it's it's really
important to nail that down and so from
a personal perspective like we're we
started right now it is very very small
we hope once we sort of nail it down
some that will make it a little bigger
but there's two farm families involved
habitat farms and emerald spear
botanicals we call happy happy spirit
cooperative and and the goal is to have
a cooperative based around diversified
production that you know farms who are
also engaged in market gardening for
farmers markets and CSA food production
and cannabis because one of the things
that I found was like from my
perspective and what I'm doing is is
different than a you know for instance a
rapid rotation multi light depth of
rapid rotation greenhouse operation and
so for me as as a single season outdoor
farmer with a lot of food production and
farmers markets like I've got a really
specific reality and so I want to build
a cooperative that is that is based
around that specific reality and so I
think it's really important to like and
and the presentation goes through this
but there's a there's a personal values
worksheet and like you know we
acknowledge the collective I role of
like cool I'm gonna write down my
personal values but actually like it's
it's really cool like you you come out
of this thing with like well I've really
articulated for myself something that I
think is very important and then I can
take that forward into this business
project and and we can nail down what it
is we're trying to do and we can figure
out if it's a good fit cuz like I say
this is a this is a
partnership you're going into business
together and so it's not something to be
taken lightly and it's really important
to really like solidify that foundation
and I just want to speak briefly to
tangible benefits to to joining a member
co-op of Emerald grown which Grass
Valley growers is you know this year
we're focusing on a few key things over
the next five years we want to reduce
production costs increase margin to
Farmer and provide you know a broad
range of price to consumers it's gonna
take a lot to be able to channel
products in a way that we can achieve
those goals so in 2019 participating
farms that is members of a member co-op
because we're a co-op of coops so you
know locally joining Grass Valley
growers or forming a new co-op and
joining emerald grown we have an
inventory management platform that
Salesforce based and metric integrated
it's the best in market we provide that
to farmers at no upfront cost this is so
all the things I'm about to describe are
how we're structuring the house brand so
we give you the clones to grow for the
house brand first and foremost that way
each and every person is growing the
same clones so at the end of the day
we've got a relatively consistent large
batch so you get a handful of clones you
get an inventory management software you
get a compliance oversight and audit
software that our compliance team can
help use to audit you to keep you on
track with permits help support your
licensing efforts and we have a
collective marketing you know we've
contracted with an agency that again too
expensive for any of us to have on our
own but collectively we can afford them
very powerful marketing agency so you
know participating in that brand program
and then you know the big thing that
we're working on is is building out a
handful of aggregation centers around
the state we we basically
cross-referenced where there's a lot of
growers in the pipeline and where there
aren't a lot of support facilities this
is one of those communities I was hoping
to be able to announce the location
today but we had lawyers and they did
the lawyer thing on the phone together
and we're gonna do some more changes to
the thing before I can sign it but
Nevada County will be one of you know
Nevada County Mendocino County in
Humboldt County are the three counties
that we'd like to
to put these centers in first and so you
know as a part owner of an aggregation
processing facility a lot of the
traditional farm operations are being
disrupted you can't dry you can't trim
you can't do whatever our goal is not to
prescribe to anyone what they do with
our Center but for it to be there to
pick up the pieces wherever their their
process gets disrupted whether they know
it now whether they learn about it in
October when it starts raining to have a
solution avoid waste efficiency that is
our number-one goal this year is to not
waste a single dollar not waste a single
drop not let a single gram go to waste
so inventory management software
compliance support oversight a unified
marketing program and and you know
hopefully by the new year will have
these centers online to be able to
provide more tangible supply seen
you