[Music]
I told people they're gonna have to like
let 30 to 50 acres open up in Willis
Covell Oh like and we'll you know Layton
Ville you know all the small valleys and
you'll get like 15 jobs for per acre and
then you gonna have like $70,000 year
jobs and a lot of the small communities
can at least survive and they can have
like livelihoods and live well but
you're not gonna see the the freewheel
and you know people making big bucks
anymore no I don't think on small farms
you're gonna you're just not going to
even on large farms any of the margins
not there you know one of the you know
kind of macro-environment things that
exists right now is if federal
legalization was able to happen in any
sort of reasonable rate if the walls
were able to come down and California
cannabis was illegal to you know send
throughout the country you know there
would be jobs jobs aplenty for farmers
all over California you know the small
you know five ten thousand you know
twenty thirty thousand square feet would
have a place because you know the
country is is a much much bigger market
than just California right now with
California we have a glut well also
break open worldwide obviously once you
go across the country you open the
worldwide markets up and then people
said that they for us they're more
triangle name will mean a lot more
outside of California outside of LA then
it will inside I think going around the
country but all that's definitely true
but it's holding on until then and at
this point it's such a rapid extinction
event you know most the people will be
gone before it ever gets there so it's
sad to see happen because you know at
our core at bloom farms we've we've
really built in to the culture of the
company our desire to support small
farmers you know 90% of our biomass
that's used to make our products is
sourced from small farmers and they're
just kind of starting to stop returning
calls and again and shutting down
operations and going out of business so
it's it's heartbreaking to see we've had
a similar experience at rosette we've
watched our farmers just implode and
it's been very difficult over the last
year to sustain their costs of getting
compliant getting their licensing
as a small farm one of the things that
I'd like to see and I'm not sure how it
would happen would be some type of
access to non predatory lending for
small farmers so they can actually get
ahead of their costs so they can
actually create a business that's what's
really killing them right now if you
notice pretty much everybody's going out
and getting funding right now and it's a
business that's going to scale that's a
lot easier than a small farmer to
conceive and so you know I'd like to see
companies form that actually would bring
these farmers in and help create some
type of fund for them or government
funding for them of some kind because
that's really what could save the small
farm just like all of us really we need
the funds to get ahead of the Machine I
agree with that but also you know
systemically you know you can borrow all
the money in the world you can raise all
the money in the world but if the
margins just don't exist due to taxes
regulation costs for licensing the
margins don't exist there's no scenario
where you know any you know any amount
of funding in the world just doesn't
burn right through it's true but
everybody needs to get up to speed
everybody needs to basically get up to
speed they need that runway time for
something like national legalization or
the ability to cross borders into other
states so if they just like everybody
they have to be able to sustain that
transitional period and people say that
it could be legalized tomorrow or a year
from now but it seems like unless
something significant happens that we
are on the path towards federal
legalization when do you guys think that
would have you been a handicap yet when
do you think that's gonna happen
I
my gut instinct says that it's gonna
happen probably based on the next
presidential election and I think that
it's not going to happen till after that
because it's too much of a tool for a
president
so election that's just a guess but I
would say what happened sometime after
and I would guess that it would be it
that it's going to be a fairly hot topic
on the primary tickets and eventually
the real race
you