[Music]
hey I'm see you and raise me with potent
ponics I do a lot of work with aquaponic
cannabis production and we're here with
Chris Trump to talk about how you can
utilize Korean national farming and
lactobacillus ferments to improve
aquaponic clothes fish production and
plant production via cannabis or
vegetables so why don't you tell
everybody a little bit about what
lactobacillus for men is before we get
into how it helps local parks
so yeah lactobacillus is this family of
microbes that really does all kinds of
things in nature you're outnumbered in
your body ten or a thousand to one and
seventy percent of the microbes in your
body that you rely on for nutrients in
your gut is lack Peaks like the gas of
bacteria and so it's reasonable and
understandable that the digestive system
of a plant is similar as we find all
these interconnectivity in nature so
yeah it's um it's the cultivation of it
to have a high density serum of lactic
acid bacteria is what we're using in
farms tell everybody why it is that
you're an expert on Korean natural
farming you're pretty much the biggest
expert that speaks English as far as I'm
concerned yeah is by necessity we we
farmed 700 acres of macadamia nuts in
Hawaii and there was there was nobody
holding my hand through it so it was a
lot of learning through trial and error
and it's it's been a blast
so we now farm exclusively with Metro
farming on 700 acres of macadamia nuts
organically certified and this is
organically certifiable quick plug to if
you're doing natural farming and want to
mess with certification don't try and
teach your certifier what natural
farming is and don't try and go to USDA
and define terms and create a new system
you're making plant-based compost or
actively aerated compost tea there's
there's all kinds of regulations in
place it's solid it's simple it's a few
simple steps just a little protection
for us if you start making up term so
you might run into problems absolutely
so I've been after meeting Chris and
hearing about all the awesome stuff he
does I started using different aquaponic
components or I'm sorry different Korean
national farming components in
aquaponics and what that allowed us to
do with specifically with lactobacillus
allows us to eliminate the fish waste
and parts of the system where it gets
passed the filter it also helps
eliminate pathogens in the system by
eliminating them by consuming them um it
also helps mineralize the fish waste a
lot faster and also increases fish
growth so it overall there's a study
it's going to be coming out later this
year through the university of kentucky
state there's a really awesome guy over
there named joe pate that helped put a
lot of that research together and
they're gonna it's gonna talk about how
it increases fish growth rate by fifteen
percent and in plant growth rate on
average by eighteen percent and it's
gonna be really really awesome so you
can take things like lactobacillus or
even WCA to provide bioavailable calcium
or all different types of things
everything but basically FFA so you
don't intimidate the fish too much or
FAA I'm sorry just to make sure that you
don't use the fish stuff but everything
else from Korea national farming can be
used in aquaponics and greatly benefit
the aquatic food web as well as the soil
food web and really help people on both
ends I would mention I would probably
avoid liquid IMO or IMO in aquaponics I
think that the soil microbes as if
you're really trying to induce introduce
a lot of them can mess with your ear
balance and actually I think I've told
you this before I had a commercial
aquaponic system hooray just baby
romaine four chefs in Kona in Hawaii and
the one I ran into some walk eNOS when
adding IMO I was playing with all of it
la be fpj all these things were just
awesome but IMO cause some just just
strange things so I think like you said
and you've talked a lot about the
aquatic food web being pretty uniquely
different from the soil food web and I
just I think respecting that
understanding that nature has those
lines here's where water is your soil is
and there's a little bit of crossover
but there is a pretty big difference
what what kind of things are different
what have you experienced so I found
that things certain minerals will
oxidize a little faster and maybe need
to be supplemented a little more often
things like iron would be the biggest
example but aside from that just with
aquaponics we can run much lower
nutrient levels so have lower
bioavailable in nutrients because we
have a wire biodiversity so we have
different multiple different microbial
chains that are making things
bioavailable and when you combine that
with a something called a dual root zone
which is a method that I talked about
regularly where we have this terrestrial
soil layer and living soil and all the
wonderful things that all of a lot of
the other speakers here at the
regenerative conference are speaking on
can survive and thrive and benefit the
plant and the upper half of the root
zone then we have a layer of burlap just
to keep that soil from getting down
below and then below that way over there
of hydrogen we get flood and drains and
it allows us to have all the aquatic
microbes and the fish waste and all of
those microorganisms that are aquatic li
based and allowing them to break down
nutrients in a whole different way along
with the fish waste so it really
and usually the fish waste is their main
mineral source so this allows us to get
70 to 90 percent depending on strain in
the nutrient base and having very little
supplementation that we only need to
provide with the soil zone which if
you're doing living soil requires next
to no supplements so as long as we have
an iron rich soil zone or or other
things we can use all the Korean
national farming methods in the soil
zone even FF FA or FAA or I'm sorry
whichever one I've had one too many
joints today I'll admit it but as long
as you you can use all those in the soil
layer
and it really can make a difference and
you can use all the practices if you're
a soil grower and hybridize that and
really increase production especially
for veg or clone production and even get
enhanced our different terpene profiles
as well if we're trying to really change
up the terpene files for your resin
production and in your own hash making
have you ever messed with red soil so I
did some red soil work in Jamaica but
nothing here in the States I did a lot
of work with green sand which is high in
iron in silica just because iron and
silica or two things were often lacking
in the water part of an aquaponic system
because it oxidizes or in Silica's case
isn't super highly bile available to
begin with so that might be an
interesting study I wonder if you mind a
bunch of red soil and used it as that
soil layer I wonder how that might
offset some of that increased
oxidization and in imo for one of the
things that I didn't teach it in my
videos but is a component is you can
bring in red soils like a 25% when you
make IMO for and it's so that you have
that increased mineral content as you
apply it for plants but I wonder if you
made like that whole layer red soil
that'd be fun that's cool what you're
doing with the with the soil layer not
anything I ever messed with I did the
floating floating rafts and but I loved
we had lava rock in our in our worm bed
you know biofilter and lava rock broke
down so fast in the aquaponic system it
just became this powder oh it was it was
incredible nothing you you would get on
an on the soil grow the microbes will
just plow right through it in an
aquaponics system and really unlock and
make those minerals bioavailable we
found I've done a bunch of side by sides
and with dwc or the floating rafts we
found that you don't really get the
proper bud formation that's why you
don't really see if you look at all the
commercial aquaponic producers that are
that are growing THC can invest in
particular all of them have a soil layer
in the upper half of the root zone and
that provides us a space for micro
Raizel fungi all the terrestrial
microbes that really help with
phosphorus potassium and other
micronutrients bioavailability
give it a time-release area so the plant
can adjust it you know it's gonna have
the bulk of its nutrients built from the
fish but it has the option of choosing
nutrients from that soil zone as well
and the plant knows better than any of
us ever will with any supplementation it
can pick and choose whichever group
whichever store it chooses the shop at
it can pick and choose to get its
nutrients from so that allows us to
maximize the bioavailability and there
was a study done by NASA when they did a
bunch of bioavailability research with
aquaponic farms where they tried to see
okay which microbes are responsible for
the the nutrient processing and nutrient
cycling of different nutrients nitrogen
phosphorus potassium blah blah blah blah
and what they found across all those
different farms over 50 different farms
is none of them were identical all of
them were completely different and when
they tested a group of soil to try and
figure out the same type of microbes in
soil and they compared the two data
sheets the aquaponic system was even the
worst aquaponics system compared to the
best soil system was a hundred and sixty
seven percent more bio diverse in terms
of number of different species when they
did genetic testing to see just biotin
abroad biodiversity so your aquatic
biome is how he has more players in its
nutrient cycle than even the soil web
does now I'm not sure if you go up maybe
up to the redwoods and you find
something that's ten thousand year old
old growth that might be different but
we're talking a normal average garden in
someone's home or in a normal average
commercial system the idea of diversity
is really the key and in natural farming
that's that's what we're focusing on
taking all these collections from
different times of the year or different
places around your area the idea is that
nature's so capable of finding a balance
if they have diversity but it's it's
like who who wants to you know be in a
town with no doctor you know like you
need the parts of a community to work in
community and we don't even I was
talking with some friends we we have no
idea how microbes work in community
where we barely even have the tools to
look in the window and we have
and so what we do know is that nature
can balance itself so if those
indigenous microbes or the microbes that
belong in that place are introduced
they're gonna find balance and they're
gonna work together and all you're gonna
get is benefit in production and disease
resistance and it's it's a lot of fun
and and so yeah maybe we'll have a
biodiversity competition between the
aquatic food web and the I guess your
study already did that that yeah I like
this we'll play with this cool yeah yeah
so the University of Hawaii actually did
over seven years of testing in aquaponic
systems sometimes intentionally
introducing pathogens some you know and
then other doing all different kinds of
experiments with pathogens and they
found things like Pythium and other
pathogens in a healthy aquaponic system
are simply out competed by by other
microbes that either consumed or there's
not enough metabolites that they need to
feed on to colonize to the point where
they start to threaten other you know
other microbes in the system so if you
have a really bio diverse oil or really
bio diverse aquaponic system whichever
one it is be the soil food web or the
aquatic food web it's going to eliminate
most of your pathogen issues not all but
a vast majority of them will be
eliminated automatically and that's and
that's where you know the the organic
hydro guys and aquaponic guys and the
soil guys really any you know can focus
on banding together and we're not that
different
we're both against chemical cannabis
we're both against pollution pot you
know we can work together and really
push you know organic as a whole you
know any food wherever the aquatic food
web and and something that's you know
great to see everyone kind of getting
together where a lot of people saw each
other maybe didn't get along quite so
low and when everyone thought eh well
that's not organic because it's not soil
well it's just using a different food
web that's all yeah yeah and yeah
there's um so for me I feel for the
farmers that are using
chemical fertilizers that there's many
that would like another way but it's
scary there's there it's there's some
risk involved in making a shift and so I
just I think that if if it's kind of not
like hey bad on you but kind of an
invitation like hey check this out so I
like that were for something you know
for learning to farm another way that's
both profitable and productive you know
and probiotic yeah my goal and like soil
farming soil is hopefully to like
sequester carbon and to create the
enhanced you know the environment and
maybe remediating you do while using for
Mary products absolutely so and for
aquaponic systems right now on average
for both lettuce and cannabis for every
10,000 square feet of canopy we averaged
around to one ton or two thousand pounds
of soil production that we get composted
through the vermicompost of the fish
waste and by the plant material so we're
actually generating nutrients rich soil
that we can either use for our own
projects for other parts of the farm if
we're doing a fully sustainable farm or
even providing it for our our neighbors
that are doing regenerative no-till soil
or other things like that it's extremely
rich and it gives them something that
you know they can come and buy from your
farm and it's a value added for you on
your cannabis grow or use it on your own
user for your top of your door your dual
root zone pots and you know you utilize
that for your own for your own systems
incredible incredible biomass I
developed a whole worm system because I
had to have somewhere to put all these
root balls and you know as I cut my
lettuce it's it's amazing how much
biomass you can make in roots and and
how good that is for making soil like so
it's like the best high quality compost
and you bring worms to bear on that and
it's a lot of fun you can also use those
same cuttings if you'd cut a big fan of
Dubya and hissing cockroaches they
provide a much more nutrient balance
waste than even worms do I know a lot of
people don't like creepy crawlies but a
two inch band of azulene and on the top
of any plastic container will contain
them
throw a heat pad in there like a CD heat
pad and they will breed like crazy they
are super easy to raise will consume
anything and a great for feeding
chickens or fish or anything else on the
yeah good in milkshakes but uh you know
they're looking at things and trying to
close your loops you know even with with
your new your nutrient supply with the
fish and the fish food can be a great
way even if you're doing sustainable you
can just raise a bunch of fish as
aquaculture mineralize their fish waste
and use it for your soil you don't even
have to have it be an aquaponic system
and still get benefits of it you can
also take that same fish waste and
ferment it with lactobacillus or in an
FPGA and and allow those same microbes
to get even more mineralization in an
entirely different way machu picchu for
for this where did where was the like
ding moment of soil and water the ding
moment was so we were trying to figure
out how to go walk cannabis in
aquaponics and we tried straight media
beds we tried dwc and it wasn't working
and i was trying to figure out how can I
get like a mineral retention layer on
the top part of the pot or it's
somewhere in the root zone so I could
have some kind of supplements we first
we tried a bunch of sea sponges in the
top part almost like a more organic
rockwool and put the plant in there and
that kind of worked and then I met a
gentleman from Serbia and he had an idea
of doing the soil on top he did it with
cucumbers so I did that and tried that
with the cannabis and it worked really
well and he was doing just maybe like a
15% soil layer on the top and that
didn't seem to be quite some enough so I
split it down to 50% and that seemed to
work really well and then by setting the
flood and drain timers a little more
often so you get the diaphragm action
and how would I do a root zone is is a
pot and the top half again is soil
separated by a layer of burlap halfway
down and the hydrogen in the bottom with
a bunch of holes or a basket bottom pot
so it allows the water to flow in and
out and when the water goes up it
flushes the air up through the soil and
when it goes down it pulls fresh air
back down through the soil and into that
root zone so gives you a rapid gas
exchange and rapid microbial growth and
allows you to supplement the soil zone
separately from the water zone and get a
lot of control in a very organ
like way that's right but what cool
technology and what else can we come up
with in the next 10 years if we stop
focusing on Frankenstein you know
chemistry and and start start looking at
how to use just physics in nature to to
benefit farmers to reduce labor and and
I mean they're they're making cool
robots and whatnot but as we understand
the interconnectivity of microbial life
and make use of it I think I think the
sky's the limit to the work that you're
doing and I think taking and isolating
different groups of microbes from KNF or
taking groups of microbes from different
parts of the world that have work
similar to KNF and figuring out how they
make certain things bioavailable and
then I think that's the future of
products for the soil industry and
everything else both both you know for
modeled and and just methodology and
because it allows people to take a field
they've been fertilizing for the last 80
years and unlock all that there's a ton
of there's more nutrients they need for
the next 500 years sitting in that field
but if they have the right microbes it
unlocks it especially with all the work
that you do and on a wonderful microbe
do you teach everyone how to do and it
teaches everyone how to unlock the
potential of that field that's already
sitting there it just isn't in a
bioavailable form yeah you take I mean
we actually just did this so we we farm
700 acres of macadamia nuts we had a
neighbor who had just kind of I guess is
a hobby farm he's well off and lost
money on it for years but he just would
dump endless amounts of chemical
fertilizer on there and finally he you
know knocked on her door and said hey I
don't want to find this anymore will you
guys lease it from me and and run the
farm and so we went in and the first
year applying microbes everything just
yellowed you know it was just and I told
my family to expect that I was actually
not directly involved in beginning that
my team who's running our natural
farming now began that project and I
said you're gonna have a drawback in the
first year just as the trees have to
learn a new way to eat their roots all
have to change and so the trees in the
first year of introducing Mike
had to literally shift their their their
root zone and but now this were near to
of that and the trees are beautiful my I
was asking my brother I was like hey
take me soil samples from this place I
want to see what's changed and he's like
no I don't think we need to bother this
place is so pretty and and productive
and so it's it's been really cool to to
watch those changes but we literally
have a mine of mineral there and salts
that that these microbes are all just
gonna be pulling on making available and
kind of redeeming the the ground for for
I don't know how many years we're gonna
benefit from that so yeah you're right
it's I mean it's really what we'll deal
with a hard pan you know it's it's the
microbes that mine the salts in the
first place it's really awesome it's
wonderful all the awesome work and all
the great videos you have on your
YouTube channel and all the classes and
stuff you put out it's really really
great
[Music]