[Music]
did you guys have any of the money that
the bank is the cannabis that came and
thank you yeah yeah shit was rampant but
I mean it ended up not being as big of a
deal as we're really concerned about it
but it didn't affect more than banker
plants are just the barley yeah now
we're looking for would you do
insecticidal soap yep to knock him down
and then at after the the bud set they
didn't really like infest in there they
were like elsewhere they didn't like to
be nesting and gradual iterating in the
bunny or grateful thank God but the the
green lace wings the they started
showing up in force and ladybug larva
and they were they're voracious you know
and I think in the future we won't spray
insecticidal soap because it it affects
the green lace wings and ladybugs other
bugs the good guys yeah
that's cool I'm glad you're aware of
that yeah take care most people don't
get that part yeah I mean right you kill
the fungi yes you killed all the good
guys too
oh yeah I know totally totally like
we're transitioning we've been in the
process of transitioning from fuel beds
from smart pots to Hubel beds and
wherever there's Hugo beds there's a lot
less pressure for sure and that's that
film on which is that fungal-dominated a
smart pots are not smart I'll tell you
that right now
I got a solution to that for reals
it's called jeolban they make a compost
bin I use it all the time it's super
great but this year I cut it in half and
it makes an 18 inch tall bed and you get
it's a hundred and four gallon pot but
here's the cool part the way it's built
you can leave them together so I played
with I think they're there they're like
almost like a dovetail or like a Lego
stack kind of thing okay I'll show you
this cool it's time not all my I tuned
all my beds this
and your son's party what are they made
out okay so it's like do weird work with
weird companies and put it together
because I think they're doing
work because of smart pots now I'm
really smart yeah we're gonna do for the
Hugo bed smoke will mount it up and we
have a plethora of fallen logs that just
fall in the road right and we'll just
make some beds out of those is it and it
makes sense like you've got a larger
decomposition zone you betcha we don't
have to bring anything in really it's
all the stuff that we need is pretty
available in abundance you know like for
the horsetail grows wild everywhere
around the ponds we've been playing with
that like fermenting it and losing is
broth yeah yeah the oak saw some really
good results so yeah and the silica from
the horses oh okay you have to heat it
up with honey right to break it down
because it frees up like at a higher pH
then like the acidic like the black
coating servers that will that make
sense so yeah it's really authorizing
mm-hmm so yeah honey is like the there's
something about it like user disagree in
a certain pH this your brainchild the
Canada's project do that was a pain in
the butt last sound sister the future
cannabis project this this is your your
brain baby beautiful baby I love it
thank you so much
tell the salary boys
cute what's you've enough to like what
do you spend your energy on this year
lately yeah oh man you know trying to
get these microbes to grow bro yeah what
cultivating and encouraging you know are
you working with Katherine definitely
right all right we're team since oil
okay cool gotcha all right all right I
got a question
as a farmer trying to be more generative
we don't want to bring in truck in bulk
soil and is there anything like I mean
we would like to amend the net the
native soil and the soil that we've
already trucked in you guys offer
something that could help us with that
right you know you can never amend
something until you figure out what it
needs so that's the problem with a lot
of amending or recommendations just
because your neighbor needs you know
more nitrogen or more potassium doesn't
mean you necessarily do so we always we
offer various types of soil testing for
soil biology as well as soil chemistry
interpretation which we're mostly
biologically based we think the microbes
should do the work so you don't have to
so once you can determine what microbes
you have and make sure there aren't any
bad ones that are going to get in the
way of the good ones doing their job
then you can really dial in a system you
know based on what your soil actually
needs using cover crops you know top
dressing and compost you know whatever
waste streams you dealt with but you
definitely don't want to just go throw
in everything in the child so can you
give some examples of recent projects of
like what you notice
looked at the soil whether it was
microbes or nutrients and then like what
your prescription was yeah well a lot of
times we deal with very bacterial
dominated soils because people are just
overly applying nitrogen you know and
and also phosphorus and that doesn't get
broken down so it's just sitting in the
soil so you see as you look at it
through a microscope it kind of looks
like a bunch of clear crystals just
overlapping and I always relate it to
like that game Plinko you know where you
drop the thing and it kind of goes down
the same like the the price is right but
when there's too many particles in the
soil too many minerals they're
overlapping the water which would be
that little like token you're dropping
down has nowhere to go and so that's
like compaction so that's being a
lattice condoms yeah exactly and you
think about how you would want water to
flow through soil you want it to go
laterally and spread out and then down
when it just either goes straight down
or it just puddles up at the top you
know that's not really plant available
in capillary action though so yeah so
when I look at soil through the
microscope I like to see a lot of big
chunks but with some flow in between
them so you know that's airspace and
that's where the water and the oxygen is
going to be to keep you so that would be
like a texture or like a consistency
that you're looking you're analyzing
definitely well and so that's the thing
as you use the biology as the organic
matter is is you know giving back to
that soil structure then the byproduct
of those microorganisms like reproducing
and processing and eating and chelating
all these minerals and and this organic
matter is that they they're gonna change
that structure and they're gonna have
the glues the ghulami lens the humic
acids the phobics that will then bond
those particles together to to make the
structure different changes that crumb
structure you know gosh and do you guys
recommend any cover crops in in
conjunction with your your amendments
and the testing
yeah I mean I think you should always be
growing cover crops for the season just
not just for the microbes but for your
plants to increase terpene profile - you
know ward off and attract beneficial
insects you know the only you should
really never have bear exposed soil it's
either subject to the elements in one
way or another yeah try and keep our
soil charged you know and always alive
with the worms and some type of cover
crop and usually some type of native
what do they call it lambs corridor I
think and mint and wild stuff just kind
of occurs and we actually we used a lot
of the local oak that is decomposing or
we've been kind of collecting it and the
Melody's been collecting it for a long
time - and that as mulch it just makes
mushrooms explode out of the beds like I
think they're called inky top mushrooms
or something but every day it's like
boom oh and those beds produce like the
stank comes off of those beds a lot more
than like that smart pot when you're
introducing microbes that are already
acclimated to that environment so it's
all like you know I think at every level
diversity is key but you still don't
want to go outside of whatever is
available to you like it's in that
environment those microbes are already
they love that they love the temperature
there that's their home ground it's like
the home team advantage a little bit you
know those guys there's no delay they
immediately start working for you the
other thing about cover crops - is
collect using cover crops that share the
same mycorrhizal relation
with cannabis specific cover crops rise
you guys can can guide us towards that
because I know that there's like like
native and native pollinating mixes and
you played with different clovers but
we're hearing from our neighbors that
some of the clovers are spider mite
prone and like trying to navigate we
don't want it we don't want to
jeopardize this ice-cream cake number
nine it's like it's not the the one that
we answered in the cup it's like the
purple Fino but uh I think it looks
pretty cool I think I've rolled up some
some Han Solo if you guys want to smoke
so well farm this is raised cannabis
raised goods is the brand that it's
entered in the competition under we grew
it at Humboldt sunrise farms in bed this
was light death in not a Huebel bed but
a raised bed with cover crops with
native pollinators and stuff but we
didn't have any like big tree branches
and stuff that we buried underneath
she's she's been grown for forty years
so she's accumulated a lot of soil and
every year she'll like Rio mend it with
some herb goat worm castings so she's
like she empties out the barn and puts
it on this huge wind row and the goats
just moved through it and you know after
the rest of the team yeah after a season
it has no smell it's just in the rain
the rains hopefully washed out a lot of
like stuff that we wouldn't want to
accumulate you did not season to your
advantage
yeah that winterizing
it helps for sure as the crow flies I
don't say like between 20 and 30 miles
maybe closer we're at 1,700 feet it's
about an hour drive to the coast hour 15
minutes drive to the 1700 feet
whereas that in relationship to that
pretty pretty high in that range no I
mean it's there's there's a lot of
variation one of our properties will be
at 1,100 another at 1,300 this one's 17
and there's another one at like 21 or
something like that and we do see a
little variation in quality mostly
because the temperature is different and
the humidity is different in those areas
then you get some of that coastal
effects though yo yeah you definitely
have a maritime climate each morning
that fog rolls in and it's it's right in
that little pocket where it's not too
much fog every morning it kind of burns
off around 11 o'clock and rolls back in
and it's pretty sweet so every time it
rolls in a lot of girls like oh crap
here comes the moisture right but think
of it as an inoculation sure yeah that
out those I'm oh you're getting all that
marine
all that stuff that's come up off the
land and been trapped up into that
moisture and it's coming onto the land
and in some places that have been abused
[Music]
that is one of those first steps that's
one of those first steps of Mother
Nature shifting that succession and
introducing the bacteria onto the land
which it then progresses and continues
to grow and it gets more complex and
more complex so what you're doing is
you're just speeding up the process
that's gonna work with the natural
systems as much as possible
you know adaptively man job forest with
the goats a little bit and it's really
really helps with fire prevention like
all of our neighborhood went up in smoke
it was really sad actually and melody
she has she's got water for the
neighborhood in case there is a fire and
so and so much brush cleanup you can do
I mean if everybody had goats there
would be a there'd be a lot less
wildfires going on a really cool
benefits of goats which is something
that in the soil profile that we're
always looking for are what are called
micro arthropods which is another way
Safety's teeny tiny crabs okay
and their job is to shred up that
material like a hypo aspis my hypo a
smiles you want to know it's really like
when you're looking through the
microscope
it's like Godzilla walking through Tokyo
that's what it looks like
it is spring to grab no no like straight
up king crab with long spindly arms and
and so it's just best friends mal to my
course its jaw though right yeah it's
well there's macro arthropods which are
what you're referring to that you can
see with your naked eye or with like a
very mild objective and then there's
micro arthropods that you can see we had
about a hundred to 200 X but to really
like see them you're you're going to
like 400 and they do is like I don't
have you ever worked on the microscope
when you see a nematode you know how
like you can see everything moving
around where the nematode like you think
about the t-rex going boom boom it's the
same thing with the micro arthropod it
just pulls everything so just imagine
like a wrecking ball coming that's
happening in your soil or it's supposed
to and that's creating air pockets and
what you were talking about cue with
aggregates that crumble like when you
haven't abuse or soil you go out there
you should be able to do that and it'd
be like cottage cheese you know where
the curds and stuff like it should be
I've literally I've literally worked in
a heavy heavy clay so that you could hit
it with a dig bar and you're only going
in yeah concrete your son yeah and
literally from like a cover cropping and
topdressing and name like sheet mulching
it and like stoking it out and teeing it
up taking care of that soil the next
year you could literally go and like
break into it and and and it was crazy
because like the clay would literally
just break up and like crumble up the
color change like that and it doesn't
have to take 20 years ten thousand years
mother nature's scheduled one season
yeah you can go from dirt to reaching
your arm into three feet of alive it's
crazy and it's because you add the life
where you guys recommend that the life
come from like you're like good shits
you know we've been doing some wood chip
in and caught in trying to compost that
stuff down with the width of the goat
manure but like the hey I guess is good
and cover crop making our own residues
and stuff but like to really get like to
get three feet of 4,000 square feet you
know that's like that's a lot of that's
a lot of material this is where yeah
wonderful companies who understand this
reality go we have that so you can show
you yeah we could either show you and
teach you where we can show you a
product that can do it for you it
depends like you know what you put into
is what you get out of it you know I
think they think of it as a wheel with
all the spokes in it if you don't have
one of those spokes
functional the wheels not going to go
down the road so you have to kind of
look you know what are my waste streams
what can I do to lies that's available
to me thank you
yeah true like the the PGD companies
they'll do clearing and they'll chip in
they'll just leave it Wow look you
really want to charge it like go maybe
go crazy you add the life soak this so
then you get an extract or a compost tea
or a gravy to go to those piles that
you're just gonna let it sit for a year
it doesn't have to be on your property
but you can put those microbes to work
changing that biology and then take that
as long as you set it up correctly it
gets stronger over time like though the
longer it sits the better it gets that's
like so anybody tells you you're gonna
see this decline or you know that's not
correct you're just not doing the steps
in the right order
biology concentrates life like it takes
the forces and it concentrates it into
like a denser form right and and really
that's where that amino acid complex is
coming from from the diversity of life
and eating and processing that matter in
that mineral and then it puts it into
the amino acid which is like the body
force right and then from there we
laughing the plant that's complex eating
and that's flavor complexity and that's
like you know all the turqu complexity
that's that's that's where that comes
from working with the exodus of the plan
you want the hands yeah you're putting
the planet
oh you're like I want to eat this I want
to eat broken shoes because it has the
intelligence yeah but it's not just
juice the plant could help this yeah
signal hey I know it's not out here on
the buffet line with 50 options but
could you really make me some of
grandmas pie and it will encourage that
growth and then be able to access it
see it's in UC Davis right now is saying
minimum of 15 cover crop species remain
in them of like 23 five or something
it's like if you want to talk about
diversity and sugar
you know distribution and because
there's gonna be different microbes for
different plants you know I'm saying
like like different preferences of food
types for different folks so the easiest
way to start is gaining that knowledge
of your place and what resources you
have but also the life that lives there
it's part of the team and Jeff Jeff's
got an amazing but if you talk to Jeff I
mean it is part of the teaming with
microbes teams nutrients who the fungi
needs to be the other meaning of the
word - it requires a active diverse team
robust some somebody needs to initiate
the symbiosis
but over the last sixty to eighty years
we've killed everything oh it's sad the
situation is bleak I mean dismal and a
lot of like how we get our food is
pretty messed up taking the idea of what
plants grow in and turned it from soil
which when I spell that out of my phone
it auto corrects the soul like the soul
of the plant right that's where terroir
is right when Frenchy and Elaine were
targets like yeah that's where it's at
starts with the microbes you take that
and it translates through the plant and
it it changes to idealize itself in that
growing environment
it's like magic man it is but you can
see there is a guy doing some work you
know with can it with CBD growing the
same you know CBD cultivar for like 20
years
switch to more fungal dominated soil all
of a sudden the plant started showing a
complete diverse cannabinoid profile you
know and it's having all of those
enzymes all those amino acids available
so where those little complexities or
nuances can you know actually be
produced it's not limited that's hidden
it switches that's him the T GHC that's
those genomes switches that are getting
hit by the enzyme getting hit by the
amino you know genetics turn it on yeah
basically triggered by different
conditions to produce
our own gut biome microbiome inside of
our bodies and if you eat crappy food it
makes you feel like this you know where
it gives you you know some on the back
side or something yes and that's because
you don't have what it takes literally
to process that material your plants
don't have what it takes to do what they
want to do what they need and if you
think about it the root hair of a plant
is so fine it's sucking in the mineral
right sucking in that and but but so the
focal on the on the root tip right it's
sucking in molecules like super small
right of that nutrient mineral micro
micro yeah and but it's not digesting it
doesn't have a stomach like an animal
right animal has a stomach it can
micronized it and if it's the
microscopic animals then they can digest
that food and then when it comes out and
it hits the root here it's going in
right because it's that it's small
enough to like make the trek yeah that
makes sense that I mean that makes sense
I see like yeah we're kind of on a
debate transitioning from these like
salts and minerals and organic salt
mineral things where you need to use a
lot of water and if you require like
because we have all of that here in
California yeah right and with like
these are you guys implementing water
savings you're like strategy that's part
of the whole system right yeah we have
quite a few and a lot of it like I said
it depends on what works was your
operation and process you know you
utilize biochar in a lot of different
ways which you know the the char that we
work with can hold it even up to Lake I
think 13 gallons of water per cubic foot
for cubically that's seven and a half
guess is too much where it's like you
have to use like a jar
five to ten percent five to ten percent
biochar listen very carefully it has to
be inoculated the biochar is a structure
it's the carbon sponge if it's not
inoculated with the lamppost it's a
sponge that will suck nutrients and
stuff out of your soil that's why you'll
often have a lot of people who use a
bunch of raw wood chips and they'll have
a big nitrogen sink yeah initially sorry
yeah your plants aren't growing quite
right yeah because what they need is
being sucked up they gotta get soaked
with all that water and the color starts
to go change and those are humans that's
actually because of the fungi breaking
that down and breaking up the lignin and
turning it into the most beautiful
complex organic molecule that's
literally just made by these little
creatures exuding different things and
gluing different things together it's
why did you say if you think about it
right on the simplest level like a
simple salt is it going to give you a
complex flavor right I see it in the
finished product no now the join doesn't
last long the bugging Bowl would last
long it's clean and all the charred shit
out of Matt what do you got what is the
all right so the microbes are breaking
down the lignin and making these humic
acids but like what are the worms due to
that like they're making a plant
available nutrients they do so so if
you've gone from micro to worm you've
like giant jumps in Hui to
the worm is like the the great white
shark swimming through the soil in
comparison to that but what it's doing
is the worms don't eat the mineral
they're eating the bacteria on the right
where'd your pot down for a day and
there's a worm underneath and if there
isn't there should be right because that
means that you're great they've got some
visuals of Lake at the bottom of the
pool looking up from the perspective of
below the roots without seeing the soil
and just seeing all the life moving
through it it's gorgeous but that's what
we think we get we get locked off
because we can't see what's moving
around everywhere or should be and it's
there all right I've noticed I can feel
it when I when you are monitoring the
moisture level and the soil every day
and it's like pretty much your main
focus and you're watching how much
moisture is in the Solvers how much has
transpired through the plant
how much is evaporated because of you
know humidity and the wind and heat you
see when the roots fill out like you get
x-ray vision down there and then it's
like okay I'm starting to develop this
relationship with the soil where it's I
can't really put words on it have all
those nutrients present otherwise you
just get those tap roots you want those
little feeder roots you want those
lateral growth those little feeders that
are like your foot soldiers out there
reaching for food all of the time but
just to touch on the worms another cool
thing about worms so there's only two
ways to like sterilize organic matter
it's there's thermal composting at
reaching up temperatures between 130 and
160 for a certain amount of time
and then passing through the digestive
system of a worm it does it only two
ways and that little worm does just
shovel it and turn it we win the concern
about not thermophilic li composting
this goat manure you know process and
you you want it there's some things you
want to like test to see with it but
like also it's like aging is also that
time where the goat manure it does get a
little bit hotter but manure it depends
what they're eating on the spectrum of
manures it's not like it says it depends
if it's miss mixed with urine and then
it definitely will be a little spicier
yeah but the worms will chew it up the
thing with the worms you got to watch
you need it to be moist so you have to
watch that moisture level a little bit
more with compost it's more like a 70
percent moisture opposed to like the 50
percent already the microbes need water
so they can drown which we all know when
you overwater but if you let your putz
dry out they literally shrivel up and
are like hey it's not okay the little go
dormant for a little while and it'll
take them a minutes of reactivating a
static get re-established but what has
happened to your plants at during that
time period oh yeah literally your
entire team went we're out right no what
about their bodies literally frivolous
their bodies are 70 percent water and it
when you're watering your soil really
what you're doing is you're rehydrating
the life that's there and you want to
have you have you played with stress
factors in the plant having a beneficial
you know having any benefit in the
terpene profile on the finished product
cuz I see like it's important for the
plant to experience that and when you
choose to you know put the plant I can
break that down too because there's
microbes that are keyed into the plant
that when the plant is sending out
stress signals they start producing
polysaccharides sugars to feed the plant
and that's where you see that from a lot
of times there's one type we use in our
grow cubes a type of bacterium called an
Indo fight it's a type there's an actual
there's a couple hundred different
species of them but they colonize within
the plant tissue and that's literally
it's only job is to make sure that plant
has food because that's how it stays
alive so when that plant is like ah it's
this is like okay sugar sugar sugar
sugar whatever you need don't I don't
hey leave me hangin buddy you know and
that's I think why our system a lot you
know sometimes but it's like that level
of stress and how fast like the microbes
can survive if that stress level or like
climate change or environment change is
gradual but if it's like boom within an
hour or two it kills everything so
that's where like you why you see mixed
results I would imagine with like
stressing the plants because I've seen
it go both ways alright I did a test
went on some CBD Ringo's gift right and
I didn't water
I stopped watering it in the in a Huebel
bed granted I stopped watering it in
August I didn't water at all September
and I chopped it off over it in water at
one time it rained a couple of times but
it was delicious the flavor and the
resin heads and I looked at him under
the scope they were so full and robust
compared to everything else it was
saying like when you're stressed out
doesn't your saket smell differently the
same thing let's take it everybody get
stressed your plan but where it grew was
in this giant fungal community of right
right within that time fungal community
that giant fungal community actually
will share water so it was tapped into
that whole bed but because it was tapped
into it it had to depend on his friends
and he's like hey buddies I hate some
help here this guy's not watering me
anymore and I got some things to do and
so they gave to it and it changed his
profile I was playing with the bacillus
mega terraeum bacillus lactobacillus
bacterias but I noticed like when I put
the bacillus on there the stem the the
diameter of the stem double standing
here you know and it seems to help with
drought type situations mm-hmm it's that
same thing where it's like colonies
colonized is so close to that root zone
that you're putting it's like the
gatekeeper for the root and if you're
putting that bacillus in and that's
where it likes to live is really
could you take like my brother and his
wife have a yogurt company so one of the
byproducts is play and they make a way
for a biotic drink but you can basically
read those you could like make it tea
and like keep mother mother it or make
similar to like kombucha scoby or so or
you know it's a little bit different
process and kombucha cuz with kombucha
you dealing with yeast more down the
path of how do they knock you late labs
like how to make some labs or how do you
guys do it yeah I mean there's a lot of
different ways to do it you get like I
like to do use a variety of different
seed washes you know everybody says rice
but like I also was using for a while
when I was making bubble hash the best
labs I ever made I would use the
recycled bubble hash water I have
pictures of it on my Instagram and it it
would come out you know the curd would
come out like almost iridescent yeah I'm
changing the water for that and
different grains would have different
patterns like the barley was like really
look like brain my mind that's it that
looks great I can show you I have to dig
up a picture but barley barley seed I
really like blue corn seed wash like I'm
a big fan of like the sprouted ct's or
enzyme teas so like hold up genius
that's that's it works but the hash
water cuz it's like they got all those
polyphenols in there okay and that's
with those like those tough-guy
bacterias really like to chew on or
there's like kind of like so we're
adding compounds that break down slower
it's same white people say not to use
eucalyptus and compost it's not that it
doesn't break down it just takes longer
because of all those polyphenols an
aromatic hamhock compound
sir pepper they're very bullish on also
don't know if it's other fumbler or
other growth
what about brassicas someone was telling
me that the brassicas are hurting Mike
Mike they don't call him a crisis fungi
they pretty put out an acid your cold
family kind of cozy in that entire group
is delicious so that's your cauliflower
and you things things like that
so it's not good as a companion prop if
you're trying to promote specifically
mycorrhizae growth and support that but
it doesn't inhibit it's not allopathic
has a part to play prefers a different
soil biome like it's kind of a simple
very simple kind of basic or the same
and a little bit of bacteria
do you know it's ours are like grew with
dinosaurs they're like some of the
vertical dance that wasn't once
something very similar to Legos really
nice and I'm gonna do they don't need
that rich environments why you see them
pop up as weeds I'm gonna show you and
you don't have that biology on there
when you have a lot of fungi they will
pop up because they can grow and that
you know don't pit on cross my fingers
let's rewind that and listen to them one
at a time is he gonna hurt Mike Anders
they're like grew with dinosaurs they're
like some of the first plants that grew
on land so they have wants something
very similar to like rock or sand you
know they don't need that mineral rich
environment so that's when you why you
see them pop up as weeds to and you
don't have that biology there when you
have a lot of fungi they won't pop up
because they can't grow in that
environment and Ryan what are your
thoughts is he gonna hurt my cannabis no
this is a cool place it has a different
survival spread rash because they're
like I'm doing my thing
I'm gonna do my little it's gonna look
the roots what different I can see this
plane is a different agenda I'm gonna
throw a ton of seeds because I'm a wee
that's all you must know and then you
know dump it on cross my fingers
I like brassicas but my buddy Steve was
like you know brassicas they're bad for
your micro for your micro Rises and I
was like I can't go brasses I've been
grown brazos with the weed all the time
Brassica shit man I actually use them in
my garden as banker plants for pests
I'll notice that if I do ever get any a
fit or whatever it'll hit a Brassica
long because think about it the biology
in the soil is more complex complex
therefore the the guys who kind of just
doing their own thing don't have the
team to support them right when that
Brassica is all by himself it doesn't
have the team support he's more
vulnerable therefore those are the ones
that the plants are the insects are
going to go after not the strong from
the nutrient content - like aphids like
go after whatever has no sugar in it
like that's what a lot of times I've
seen where you're able to not brace so
you know that most people don't even
know about Brix testing so the higher
the Brix rating it's not based on sugar
they use sugar to to calibrate it right
it's based on viscosity like how much
stuff is in it right and so we know that
there's a lot more than just sugar in
SAP so that's but that's the missing
so if the bricks rating is high enough
like even to the 10 to 12 which is
possible that really just means
everybody's working together that plant
screws their cell wall is thicker and a
athan cannot pierce it like the plant
literally is like you can't bother me go
mess with that broccoli no go over there
leave cannabis alone you know that's
really what's happening I'm a big
believer in the chitin kinase process
you know and how that activates within
of the cells and you know it starts to
produce its own chitin ace and deter
pests and stuff I've been seeing I
learned it from this guy John Park and
he's a farm called beard asur had a farm
called Venus and the corporate stalkers
he fucked screwed they fucked him over
big-time but he developed the world's
largest aquaponics certified organic
aquaponic system down there in
Watsonville and the man is just yeah
dude legend legend he was open sourcing
everything just teaching people how to
feed themselves and stuff but they're
using this high chitin worm casting
extract to reverse pine beetle
infestation
like montana and stuff yeah well it's
like that PFR 97 there's like maroon bio
makes a couple of the same it's like the
insect eating fungi you know they feed
off of chitin that's why they eat
insects because they're high their
exoskeleton skeletons are full
like a heavy crazy fact about some heavy
control like that's those chitin chitin
kinase based solutions seem to be like
pretty ecological you know like but
you're you hi like a support life not
what do I have to kill right you're
progressing the plant you're progressing
the biology you're making a more diverse
more complex and with that the plant
becomes more diverse and more complex
and I don't know anybody trying to say
can I just be more middle of the road no
flavor no nothing no we're trying to
push it it's trying to push
differentiate the genetic potential
which is where we're talking about
Tarawa and populations and this is very
awesome that the microbes of more place
change your plants which makes them yet
how can we get more chitin in our system
you know
well you guys recommends different
options right there's always you can
always go buy some which is somebody
else collecting it or you can go and
collect from different sources and this
is where understanding the resource
opportunities and waste streams just
talking about resource right resource on
your farm right your soil and your
fertility like that should be the
biggest resource because like that
complex that is the soil right that
structure is what's gonna grow your
plant right and other than that it's
temperature and light right but that
structure is like all that minerals so
really like on that budget and on that
plan that fertility planning that soil
plan that management playing like that's
gonna like you know I mean that's your
men should be on the books like as this
is important to like investing be court
with there are creatures your flavor a
whole ecosystem you have an opportunity
to interact with it as someone who's
like hey I know that I want to promote
this and because that I'm gonna feed
this material either a fish amino acid
or the robust structure of you know the
compost because the compost is that
bacteria fungi protozoa and nematodes
all these creatures breaking down
organic material and making it plant
available like that's literally what
they do the end result of really good
compost if you just let it sit it's
called topsoil that's what that soya by
zation and Micronesian of organic matter
and that's where like you know you
talked a lot about this they go back and
forth you know cuz it's like it's you
know it's not so much how you get there
it's just the fact that you're you know
are able to create this closed-loop
system using your own your resources
that you have on hand you know and what
works with your flow if it's gonna cost
you more time or labor energy to do it
then it's not really that probably you
know gonna work for the
got a pencil yeah yeah well and that's
that's a good way to describe it it's no
production I don't want it to look like
a bunch of plastic jugs filled with the
liquid nutrients you know if we need
some some plant-available nutrition i
would like to be able to make it on site
somehow you know you claim so like
because the the the compost is it's the
key it's a twofer terroir like you're
saying but sometimes you are in a cold
spell you know and you need like you
need something right now and that
compost you know it's gonna have that
nutrition short and long term but thing
right now like what do you like it's
gone it's gone through an undesirable
stress factor it's just being cool the
Sun hasn't come out you know there's no
like there's some serious inactivity
there's there's no calcium moving but
it's really a mobile because the physics
aren't there you know and the compost
can be great you know but when there's
calcium and mobility because the physics
aren't there I'd only know that we need
to put some calcium chloride on there
and do it for it that's where you come
with the enzyme this is where you're
right that's a short term but the short
term will often inhibit the long term
you say in spraying some calcium
chloride and do it with like some sticky
conditions will it inhibit here's an
example if you're growing on old farm or
or old work land there's so much
phosphorus dumps on to work land and it
doesn't leave
that phosphorus is hit inhibiting
mycorrhizae growth because they don't
need the the plant doesn't need it it's
everywhere
why support this other guy I don't need
the middleman so that that understand
what's going on in your soil
what changes that is the biology and so
now what are we adding I don't want to
add comic I want to add the things that
make it available who's doing the work
and if there's an abundance from like an
over input of phosphorus then we want to
use some fixing plants like some some
cover crops to fix it and try to
remediate the okay so now we're talking
because you're using life to promote
life so now I'm gonna have a plant that
has a job so I don't have to and that
job is can be anything like if a
dandelion fixes calcium in the soil that
we just turned into a part of the team
you see what I mean I like like the idea
of you know making the dandelion plant
extract a liquid plant extract does so
what it is speeding it up a bit and
you're putting that into the process too
and that's where the enzyme barley like
that if you want to like get you know
you talking about calcium uptake you
want to get your buds swell on a little
bit and like did you everything
everything that's in the soil get them
to kind of take up you know the barley
it's full of AMA lace it's actually the
enzyme that's in our saliva that breaks
down things it's got a ton of other
enzymes and more complex sugars in it
you can either do like a barley sprouted
CT or if you're trying to do like a
large-scale you can just get the malted
milled barley put in a teabag seep it
for let aerate it for like 30 minutes
and within a day or two like there's
different ones they also are full and
with hormones so far Leesville and
auxins that's going to be your like a
pickable like vertical growth and then
like I use blue-corn more in bloom and
that's lateral growth and like bud
strength and branch strength but I
that's like the two like feeds where
within 12 to 24 hours like you're just
like okay you see that she's come out
like you know like I have to see that
shiny planet if it's not shiny it's not
healthy right what is that smooth that's
actually the fat that's how the plants
telling you it's fat and happy
it's literally making its learning
lipids lipids huh it's called the waxy
cuticle that makes it tracks I didn't
know its facts the plants will grow a
new growth ice I will plant but I'm a
fat flinch I saved all the new growth
where it looks almost like plastic
that's almost like plastic and then what
happens usually people the temperature
increases and what happens like they'll
start to spread out a little bit or the
life in the soil got stressed yeah so
therefore it was it able you know no
that plant knows how to grow you have to
give it it can adapt to tremendously
good it's real good at that right right
you know I agree on the genetics right
well in my garden literally if it
doesn't grow sorry we tried you know
it's one of those things where no hard
feelings I'm not going to stress this
let's check this out though so like will
be cloning right and sometimes we'll
have like we'll just have really good
success on a clone and from the clone
form to a finished product it's not a
whole die that way looks healthy mother
no no no say mother say mother plant
TRAI clones from same mother but that
one tray or no like a handful of plants
in that tray are just like me like they
yield more they're they have less
problems they grow faster they just
they're like they they're just dumb
I would find out who's that cutter is
there a way to like even it out
afterwards you know because we seem that
it seems to be the only workaround is to
make twice as many plants as we need so
and then it select the best of half of
those to get the most robust ones but
you know for to take a plant that's hurt
and bring it back you know to full
strength is like why can't you because
we're out we're farmers on a time crunch
basically scale that's all the time yeah
it's a produce to survive and make it
pencil we have to be at a certain scale
that's right so now we're just talking
about having the right tool to do the
right job so that the force whatever
team you have can get the job done so
you can then go and have fun with your
friends and take your kids to the beach
right you know it's like okay there is
an entire world and universe of
creatures that their sole purpose is to
love on your planet I get that you're
trying to cut 1,500 to like I have
another place so it's putting 11,000
clones a weird you know like so there is
like that degree and there is like when
you're with anything with more like more
margin for error because you're
increasing in your numbers and a lot of
it I think is like accidental
contamination in between how like the
light cycle the moms are and like where
you're cutting you know compared to the
health you know cuz like and you could
solve that by a testing like doing brick
testing or like tissue testing in the
top middle or bottom to see you know if
it's if those nutrients are actually
going all the way up where the cuts are
coming from on that mom
but he was determining even then I mean
we did like a lot of clone trials we
have a grow cube product that we're
really seeing that it's like inoculated
with all of our biology so I'm gonna
introduce it to the light even if it's
not in soil because it coats it and then
helps it's called the biosphere platform
it's beautiful knits this whole world
right along the route that can happen
inside an indoor go - you guys got a
product yes so we've seen a lot of like
you know we're creating it pretty much
you know generates the plants immune
system from day one so a lot of the
issues like the biggest thing to of like
when production if you have a tray that
goes bad and dies well they're going to
mold you don't find them or there's one
that's bad in the middle and it just
takes one and it spreads and so that's
where like we came in and we were
working with these cats it has like whew
sorry oh I'm they had like three
different kinds or like in my sees like
water mold in their clone room and it
would just contaminate and recontaminate
and so that's the biggest thing we saw
from our cubes as they didn't get p.m.
from it they were
there's enough good guys to eat the PM
but a lot of it was cloning like actual
routing and success of cloning its
humidity
it's like you want 90% humidity for like
three to five days then 70 and then like
over 14 days you slowly acclimate to
room canvas every time I walk by though
my spray what the water like I take some
like cytokinin Zoar like something
that's a high-end trace metals or fulvic
acid that's going to be so much and
digestible like if you want to think of
like a little baby like it's you yeah
yeah they like calcium I think your
mom's before you cut doing moms in Swift
alts like versus moms and soil there's
no comparison we we had like a thing
that says they hired us or we were doing
working with them for and like I finally
just applied some of our compost on the
moms they were like in this coco coir
mix and within 24 hours the moms look
great and the compost was white because
it had literally just like pulled all
the salt out and the plants are like oh
I can drink again
working with salt based systems like
there's definitely like an ebb and flow
you can get into with it but you're
still always going to have to add more
and add more and that's the difference
it's like just add it once and maintain
it and your it's gonna save you a lot of
money your guys are here like this but I
went and worked on a indoor farm a real
big thousand lighter for a day and they
don't use their soil more than one time
it's crazy
no there's it's nuts and all that the
rock wall is what kills me the rock and
the plastic trays oh the twofer just
it's painful it's certain you have to
put on your like barn you know your
blinders you just like they're like
we'll play by the rules but we know
plants grow in the soil yeah it's it's
really sad but it's just more a lot of
it is like just lack of information and
people also don't feel like it applies
to them or they can't it's you know like
oh I have to tear down my whole system I
have so much money I can't lose a day or
production it's like finding a way to
integrate it just like you know it's a
succession scale you integrate it over
time like you should always be you know
it's all it's a business its profit
oriented you know a lot of times with
big operations your profits come from
efficiency not from numbers or yields or
anything it's just being efficient not
having somebody walk back and forth 20
times you know and then he's tired but
he actually has to go do what he needs
to pay attention to just like little
things like that I feel like make way
more of a difference in like when you
know I think that there's we have a
really big challenge with product
differentiation and product like the
inner door brand just like indoor weed
is being better is like so entrenched
it's it's wild it's bad it's it's so
like fighting against that educate
providing some type of platform or
educate
and like places like this should be open
24 every day of the week where you can
go to a farmers market and get some pot
that's education right there and then
people will start to experience where
their weeds coming from they can meet
the farmer you know and hopefully we
work in that directory you know people
out at the farmers market hell yeah hell
yeah man that's what we're right there
doing it right now we're living the
dream where there's a lot of stuff going
on and it's really cool because of
Technology because of events and because
people are feeling more comfortable to
come out of a shell type you know I mean
that that there's there's no longer the
same feeling of aloneness right the
garden got bigger and because of that we
have almost it's called a quorum right
and then the microbes have it - it's
called quorum sensing and when you have
bad guys on you and in you right now
like the bad bacterias and other stuff
they literally talk to each other and
when they get to the right level they go
let's party and then you get sick
the same thing happens in your Soyuz
right so the plants try it the soil is
talking to you long before your plant
turns it color because that life isn't
what's actually helping that plant
processing growth and so no matter how
that plant grew the plant literally just
needs the right team to work with yeah
I'm loving it man I'm loving seeing like
the the regenerative stuff really work
it really really works like without a
doubt there's no comparison living soil
pot is better than salt based
mineral based longer shelf life lasts
longer smells fresher stronger every
time more cost-effective higher profit
margin greater market value better smart
or apron right all the things you you're
supposed to talk to your marketing guy
about like if you grow like this like
here's another example how do you prove
yours is different well there's actually
tests that you can do that says my plant
was grown in a 98% alive soil it's
called a Haney test and you're like what
you know it's like but you can say that
this plant is special is different
because of how it was grown that's
something else they can be added to the
value group
okay I heard of the hey me oh man that
the microbes are the what creates a
terroir
we have tests for the microbes so you
can literally make it tangible that says
no this is why I'm different these are
my creatures my team you guys have any
like isolated like specific the like way
doable striking derma or Glomus or
bacillus or like or do you guys is that
your NOC Yulin is yeah like a full
spectrum kind of thing or you have to
select microbes to like because I know
for like mother plants to get more
apical growth the tract of dermis and
the route seems to really work well and
also for like botrytis prevention you
know in the root it's it's tremendous
the hard c annum its benefits to me it's
like kind of like you know you don't
want to use that until like you know you
really like it doesn't it overtakes
everything else so you have to use it
sparingly a lot of the Trichoderma
products like i've looked at under the
scope and they don't really germinate
and a lot of people don't like you have
to refrigerate them for sure and there's
definitely ones that are more viable
than others and different strains that's
like we don't really work with it at all
I haven't need to but I do believe like
I think they all work better together
it's when like the the bacteria you know
that like in the nematode eats the
protozoa and that's cycling and
digesting and you create you know I
think but we also do offer we have our
endophyte product that's in our grow
cubes that's a specific class of
bacteria and that colonizes in the plant
tissue so it's really good for moms
there's something in a pox it's never
gonna wash tout it's it's actually a
specific type of in a fight that helps
like what a song about polysaccharides
are systemic
it's an Indo fight so it's that's what
it's inside the plant tissue that's what
that means for so yeah you could say
systemic organic systemic plant booster
the game I like to think it was like the
gate keeper you know it's just like it's
really good also for for breaking down
like salts or Crees increasing salinity
tolerance you know salt soil yeah we see
a lot of success using it in like
hydroponics situations but you can
remediate salt soil too with compost
really well yeah and you just cycle it
mix it in let it sit you know and by
spring also in the East Bay and soil
salinity is a big problem out there with
like the all the farmers pretty much are
you guys doing anything with non
cannabis farms help them grow like
remediate the fields with and stuff like
that they could use some help with that
definitely be open to it you know oh
okay all types and stuff if the job is
the same and we have the team to do the
job all the microbes you just got to get
them to the right got to create the
environment the conditions in the system
do you always give them analogies in
micro terms the cakes in cooking
my children have their own plants they
helped bury genetics my kids play in the
garden they
no different it's so fun I love it they
don't have any of the drama it's
literally just the happiest place on
earth my kid this season is you know not
very start but he's like dad I want to
do an experiment I'm like sure whatever
and he's like I want to see if peas
changed the pH he's seven
right and I'm like I don't know let's
check and so we put out and did a little
soil or a water pH and he tested it he's
like how many peas because he
understands about dose because we
measure stuff to put because there's
small life a small amount packs a punch
like they do that job right and so he's
like let's start with ten peas and he's
like chuffing peas and putting it into
the peach and then we tested the pH and
guess what it doesn't it is open now you
don't because they did holy crap
we haven't had a new way that changed pH
who knew you know so she's okay to
experiments are you talking about the
pea the plant peas are urine we've done
both okay but you're talking about
you're in the whole time that's what I
know we're gonna have to be much okay I
gotcha I would think that maybe alkaline
but you're saying nitrogen is there's
different types of nitrogen though like
we're playing with nitrate based
nitrogen versus ammoniacal nitrogen
there's a difference in how soluble they
are right yeah all right
how much nitrogen does your plant we
have been honored not as much as a lot
of people will give them
we have bacteria that literally fix
nitrogen out of the air into the soil
the azo spur ileum right you got that
part of the team too right if like I
only had one thing to a change farming
stop make like nitrogen illegal if you
change that one input and you just stop
doing that it would change cover crop
with legumes and get plenty nitrogen
right change clothing howes it's like a
hundred pounds an acre they can fix a
and then I think like the legumes can do
like 200 or something yeah it's like
this is where your cover is is it like
working all your livestock at leas yeah
no it's it's absolutely amazing that
it's alive and the more diverse through
more crazy the more intensive how high
is your garden what do you mean your
Gardens three-dimensional you can have
understory plants and the middle story
plants and in the middle right here
because they branch out over like you
can change everything with layers of
life with the understanding as above so
below
all that life is like an exploding the
surface of the earth and it's feeling
the plane
and us and the buses yeah absolutely
cool right on yeah we're going for a
minute