[Music]
my name is Colin bellum the co-founder
and chief growth officer for mammoth
microbes our company develops liquid
organic microbial soil additives to act
as a catalyst to maximize plant nutrient
uptake to significantly increase plant
yield and nutrient use efficiency across
many crops I was attending to talk today
on maximizing a fertility program for
cannabis and it was just an amazing job
of dialing in the function of specific
nutrients across the growing cycle and I
think that's the critical part of
understanding how to grow a crop with
precision is understanding how the key
nutrients incorporate into the plants
and how the plants are using those and
this stock was very very well done about
understanding the timing of nutrients
and how they're incorporated into the
biomolecules for plants
you
I'll go real quickly into that number
one the the highest requirements the
cannabis has our four nitrogen calcium
magnesium iron and boron it has it needs
all of the nutrients like all plants but
those are the hot-button
nutrients the other requirements are
very pedestrian most all potting media
that people produce cannabis in our
phosphorus deficient plants need
phosphorus early to grow a root system
and of course beneficial microbes can
help with phosphorus availability and
maintenance as well I didn't really
comment on microbes today because that
was not the topic of my talk but plants
need phosphorus really to grow that root
system out during veg I like a 1 to 1
ratio of nitrogen into potash when you
start to flower you want to drop your
nitrogen down and increase your potash
you know at that point and you kind of
do that through late bloom as well and
then it finished most people just flush
all the nutrients out for the last
couple of weeks so there's four distinct
phases of growth in cannabis and if
you're doing it correctly you fertilize
them all a bit differently
well cannabis has one of the highest
requirements for boron of any crop I've
ever worked with I also mentioned that
almost all mother plants are deficient
in magnesium growers don't put enough
magnesium on their mother plants and so
you often see marginal yellowing in the
older leaves of mother plants which is a
lack of chlorophyll which is caused just
by taking cuttings all the time you're
removing a lot of magnesium from the
plant as you harvest your cuttings or
your clones and therefore you need to
replace that magnesium with
fertilization here's the short version
of that cannabis is a pretty heavy
feeder but it's also very soluble salt
sensitive in a normal situation if my
fingers are plant roots the salt content
in the plant roots is higher than the
surrounding soil moisture so moisture go
is very easily into the roots by osmosis
the plant doesn't have to work because
water molecules are a little bit
kidney-shaped in their charged water
molecules stick together and so as water
goes in it goes up the plant and out the
leaves ultimately when you add too much
salt around the root zone that that
osmotic advantage is lost if you put
enough salt surround the roots moisture
is pulled out of the root cells back
into the soil by reverse osmosis and
that's how fertilizer burns and that's
why a plant with high soluble salts
looks wilted even though the media is
wet it is wilted because the plant can't
take in the moisture that's there
because of the salt differential so I
was just trying to explain in simple
terms physiologically how fertilizer
burns I have a great I have a question
that I'd like a Lindt opinion on and one
of those things is you know as growers
are evolving and trying to distinguish
themselves everyone needs to still get
that yield and maximize yield but
they're trying to maximize the quality
within their phenotypes as well and one
of the hypothesis we have is the the
deficiency of micronutrients to enhance
the plant's ability to incorporate those
those molecules and maximize cannabinoid
and terpene profiles do you feel like
that's true and the growers that you've
seen where micronutrients might be under
undervalued in their nutrient program
sometimes yes : also for organic growers
getting good quality available microbes
can be a little bit problematic for the
organic
growing but I mean sure you know you've
seen the the barrel thing probably in
your first week in in college where you
know we need more protein than we need
vitamin b12 as humans but we need them
both equally and plants only need about
five parts for me and copper but they
need copper just as much as they need
nitrogen and phosphorus and everything
else right and the main things that
micronutrients do in plants is they
drive enzymatic chemical reactions in
the plant to make things like terpenes
and cannabinoids or you know you can't
neglect those so although the macro
elements incorporate and make these
proteins or enzymes which do all the
work there's cofactors that actually
incorporate into these proteins or these
enzymes to allow them to function and
those are typically in the form of trace
nutrients not exactly iron is another
one is iron important for cannabis oh
yeah it's one of the ones that has the
highest requirement for there is no iron
in chlorophyll but plants need iron to
make chlorophyll which is why when they
become deficient you lose chlorophyll in
the new foliage iron is also involved in
a lot of respiration and energy type
processes which is why when you often
see a plant with iron deficiency you'll
see it kind of stunted as well it's not
only lacking in chlorophyll and the new
leaves but the the carbohydrate
management is not functioning
functioning optimally I have another
question what do you think the biggest
education gap for a Tillet fertility
program is in general for cannabis
cultivators as as this industry
progresses hmm tough question Colin I
would say number one there used to be a
lot of Voodoo in this industry a lot of
eye of Newt and you know everybody's got
their own little secret you know
formulas and stuff and that's fine you
know I don't have any problem with that
but I think that's going away slowly and
being replaced by science and chemistry
and microbiology I think roads are
gradually growing they're becoming a
little more technical and a little more
knowledgeable in that area and sometimes
they blow me away with how much science
some of them really do know now
horticulture to me is an art as well as
a science that's right you know
I mean there's a scientific aspect to it
but sometimes it's just that greenthumb
feel thing and we do things that
cannabis responsible you don't always
know why right we just know that they
like it yep but I would say they're just
becoming more scientific and less artsy
craftsy if I can use that well I think
its inherent parsley with the history of
this crop where it has been in the gray
market so to speak and now we're able to
work with it more openly and we can
gather that science where in every other
crop we have pretty good agronomy
science around the fertility programs
corn all the way to tomatoes or
strawberries cannabis is quickly growing
even man with microbes we have a 65 acre
high CBD farm and several 5,000 square
foot greenhouses and all we do is a
Granada Cree search to understand plant
responses and is not only with yield but
root development terpene production can
a baloney production and everything we
can do just to maximize the phenotypic
potential across different strengths
so for us as microbiologists and I think
you know some of our team we can be
characterized as world thought leaders
in this area we're understanding and
we're trying to figure out how to stress
or instigate chemical signaling with the
microbes there's obviously a nutrient
use efficiency aspect that microbes
provide where you can maximize nitrogen
or phosphorus or sulfur or potassium or
even micro nutrient uptake through
simple or pretty pretty standard
biogeochemical cycling
that's what microbes do in nature plants
interact with microbes in nature to
maximize plant nutrient use efficiency
maximizing availability of nutrients
microbes do several things but plants
are environmentally triggered and Lynn I
want you to key in on here if you can
initiate some chemical signaling where
microbes are trigging triggering a
chemical or a signal to allow plants to
say hey I need to respond to this and
they can respond to it through a
cannabinoid production or a terpene
production and we can actually engineer
that meaning that we can introduce that
particular chemical signal through a
microbial interaction you can train
plants not to do things that they're not
genetically capable of but to express
that gene to maximize that particular
trait how do you feel about that well I
would say two things number one for
years we couldn't do research on
cannabis legally yeah now that's all
pretty well out the window and we can do
the type of research that you and others
are conducting right number two nobody
knows this I'm sure you do Colin but the
average tablespoon of healthy field soil
contains four billion microorganisms
about one percent of the dry weight of
that soil if I cut my hands like this
and hold soil I have more microbes in my
hand than there are people on this
planet that's how important microbes are
to plant production that's a good key
that you can use Rob in your in your
customer calling and you know soilless
media that we do with indoor growing is
often you know well deficient in
nutritional content so you know that
needs to be inoculated and you need
carbon sources to help maintain those
you know this better than me yeah but
yeah don't don't know you know to answer
your previous question what's the thing
that they're most
not familiar with soil microbiology is a
big one one reason it's a very
complicated subject
you know it's deep you know what you're
getting into is deep in the pool yet in
terms of chemical signaling and
microbial interactions and all this
stuff it's a complicated field and it's
hard even for more technical growers to
understand yeah
I stated earlier boron has a higher or
Canada's has a higher boron requirement
just about any crop I know I said in my
talk that boron is involved in
translocation and utilization of
carbohydrates which is a fancy way of
saying boron helps the plant make sugars
and move them around and you need that
when you're come to forming butts plants
can grow perfectly well vegetatively
with not very much boron but by flower
time you better have the boron there the
problem of course is that boron toxicity
is the most common toxicity in
agriculture because in most plants if
you are 25 parts per million in the leaf
tissue or below you're deficient and if
you're above 75 or 100 you're toxic it's
only about a 50 to 75 part per million
window in the leaf tissue so the boron
requirement was very surprising to me I
would say that's probably the most I was
also when I started working with
cannabis a bit shocked at how soluble
salt sensitive it is in almost every
grower I've ever worked with at times
has gotten into soluble salt trouble
which is why I did this finger thing in
the talk today to explain to them what's
going on one cool trick if you have a
girl with high soluble salts sugar water
irrigate with about five pounds of sugar
per hundred gallons or some molasses
it's a carbon source that stimulates the
microbes to eat the fertilizer salts up
yeah and if growers do that oh hi Oh
State University came up with that I
didn't yeah okay but my experience with
it is if you drench with sugar water
you'll lower your salts by 50 percent in
about two weeks yep and that's because
of the microbial interactions you talk
about how the microbes interact with the
plant roots to reduce what growers
typically call the lockout where
nutrients might be unavailable but
microbes can actually cycle that balance
the rhizosphere or the root zone out so
roots can actually take up nutrients in
a healthy manner and not have to worry
about focusing below ground that can
focus on above ground because there's no
lockout or stalemate of nutrient uptake
in the root and rises here some people
some people swear by it and some people
say I think it depends on your growing
strategy in your strain you know I think
they're stressing the plan a little bit
nutritionally and trying to get you know
bitter terpene production and better CBD
production with the flush some say that
with ingestible zorse MOCA bowls that
you get a better flavor less harshness
but it you know it's not a universal
thing it is a point of contention and
you know yes and more so in cannabis
than any crop I've ever worked with
anywhere in the world I probably worked
with a thousand crops you know doing
what I do is a diagnostic laboratory
you know when growers would get into
trouble they'd send me stuff just like
I'm sure they do to you cough yeah and
so just the genetics
we've been breeding cannabis for sixty
five hundred years on this planet okay
and so the genetic diversity in cannabis
is ridiculous and therefore yes you need
to grow you need to learn how to grow
your strain both with fertility inputs
and lighting and irrigation and
microbial inoculants and just the whole
thing and I'm a believer in Flushing but
not everybody is and I respect that I'd
you hear from growers that when you
flush you get a cleaner end product
meaning if you even look at the color of
the ash it's white instead of dark and
it's allocated or are associated with a
high salt or chemical buildup
that's not burning cleanly and so I
think about that as just diluting the
salts that are taken up by the plant I
don't understand it well enough most the
growers that I talk to at least the
synthetic growers do flush the organic
growers not so much I don't think that
there's a real a real need to do that in
organic systems just because of the
nature of the of the or of the nutrient
inputs and it's harder to flush when
you're going organic of course please
understand I'm not against organic
growing in any way shape or form it's
just different and so you know but if
you do it right you can grow a heck of a
crop so we were talking about you were
talking about
foliar nutrient applications and they're
very popular in many crops especially
nitrogen and my question was
specifically is
they're different uptake for different
nutrients when you try to do foliar
applications and I think your answer was
yes you want to go into that the answer
is yes absolutely the corn and wheat
research shows that urea nitrogen and
potassium 50% of that can be absorbed
within eight hours of application the
micronutrients are really slow it's it
takes like four days to get 8% of the
foliar iron into a leaf at least in
those crops yeah some plants don't
absorb foliar nutrients well at all
plants with thick heavy waxy leaves like
rhododendrons or privets you know just
don't absorb very mother just figs yeah
yeah a lot of those things but it plants
with thinner leaves with thinner
cuticles you know absorb nutrients very
well palm trees are terrible at it yeah
you know I live in the tropics and palm
trees just don't absorb foliar nutrition
but some plants like cannabis which has
a pretty thin delicate leaf are pretty
good absorbance but the ratio and the
speed of absorption varies quite a bit
with the nutrient I have a follow-up
question you made a really good point
that when you add a foliar application
the nutrients are only going to be
absorbed whenever the it's still wet
when the leaves are still wet once it's
dried right no more absorption can yuri
wet the leaves to take up more than
solute yeah in outdoor agriculture once
it dries there's no more absorption
until you get fog or Dew or a little bit
of rain forgot it and so they if Yuri
wet the leaf absorption resumed yep so
that residual will become soluble and be
able to take up be able to be taken out
by the leaves yes yeah I also don't
believe in applying real high amounts
really high rates of foliar nutrition
like to keep the rates lower like what
is there a range that you could give
just very generally in cannabis if the
conductivity of your nutritional spray
is above about 1.8 I'd be a little
uncomfortable the reason is the other if
you spray real high rates of foliar
nutrients the osmotic concentration in
the droplet is such that as the droplet
dries and the salts become more
concentrated in the droplet noise Chur
is pulled again by osmosis out of the
leaf into the drop yet and so you're
actually promoting transpiration instead
of absorption yeah and
so I'd rather apply lower rates more off
yeah
also the absorption isn't that terribly
efficient for most of the nutrients yes
the analogy I always use is if this
microphone is a Pepsi bottle and I'm
trying to catch Niagara Falls in the
Pepsi bottle if I double the size of
Niagara Falls what goes in my Pepsi
bottle is still the same amount because
the Pepsi bottle to me represents the
limited ability to get fuller nutrition
into a plant polio nutrition is real
efficient in correcting deficiencies
whatever the plant isn't getting it's
real easy and efficient and
cost-effective to just put some foliar
on there I'm a big believer in foliar
nutrition in Moe in many plants it goes
in better from underneath the reason is
that a lot of the absorption takes place
through the snow mates which are those
little pores in the leaves many plants
have more snow mates on the underside of
the leaf than on the upper side honestly
I don't know if cannabis is in that
category or not do you have any ideas I
think that's true but I actually don't
know wonderful I need to get my
microscope out and have a look yeah but
number two there's more snow mates on
the underside be the spray stays wet on
the underside longer yeah so you're
gonna get better absorption from the
underside so to the extent a grower can
their folio nutrition should be directed
upward you made some really interesting
comments about silica applications using
a foliar spray to add silica alekan
silicon thank you so go to the beach
yeah there you go
silicon and there's some really
interesting functions that might be anti
pathogen or anti pest properties of the
silica where it fills in those spaces
and actually physically blocks infection
sites and I think there's an interesting
property of the pH it's very alkaline
typically the the silica do you think
the pH pressure itself would might
represent an anti microbial for example
against powdery mildew I think a lot of
the mechanism of that resistance in the
literature is from thicker cell walls
the alkalinity may have an effect yeah
you know
a lot of fungi grow better and I guess
in lower pH yep you know I was wondering
why can you put a bottle of Louisiana
Hot Sauce on a restaurant table for six
months it doesn't go bad it's the pH
bacteria don't grow well at low pH and
there's a lot of vinegar in there and
that's why it's hot sauce almost never
goes bad yeah it's well documented in
the literature that silicon helps plants
resist a fitzsimmons as well as powdery
mildew that's very well documented
scientifically and that's that's one
reason I like to have silicon in my
program yeah another reason is strong
shale walls for heavy bud formation it's
all about bud weight ultimately and then
the oil that you get out of there last
question for me regarding silicon do you
think it's equally effective being
applied as a root drench and or a foliar
both are fine okay
I mentioned the potassium silicon tends
to precipitate with other fertilizers
yeah so depending on a growers delivery
system sometimes I'll just say let's
just put the silicone on Foley early
yeah if they have an A&amp;B tank dual
delivery system yeah I can put potassium
silicate in with compatible nutrients in
the B tank so we don't have
precipitation but calcium silicate is
completely insoluble in calcium in
silicon and it's bombs away yep
could you add it in with that irrigation
on a day off for my fertigation another
way to do it yeah that's another way to
do it but I did I did all kind of
compatibility studies with my fertilizer
program I didn't have any problem with
anything until I put potassium silicate
in there for sure yeah so it doesn't
play well with others and so you either
need to put it on generally by itself
either through a drench or irrigation
application or as a foliar we're
extremely high dilution how would assume
corporate hundred gallons on most of the
products which is a one to four hundred
dilution yeah so you know and I'm again
I don't like to put a whole lot on of
anything of one time I don't want a
reputation of burning people's crops up
but for sure so I I'm a little
conservative in my application rates
yeah I have client to say whatever Lynne
does you just double it you know but I
don't like to take those chances so you
know can go on Foley early or it can go
through the roots your roots have to be
healthy yeah and functioning
so what Lynne is saying is less
is more yeah-yeah-yeah if I were a
cannabis grower commercially which I'm
not the medium that I would choose would
be a combination of coconut fiber
Canadian sphagnum peat and perlite
number one most container media have
multiple ingredients the reason for that
is as they fall together in different
combinations they create different types
of pore space for the roots to grow
within secondly Canadians Magnum is
naturally hydrophobic it repels water
coconut fiber is naturally hydrophilic
Magnum peat is a fine medium it's been
used for many many decades you grow a
heck of a root system when you have
coconut fiber in your mix that's partly
due to the physical structure of coconut
fiber and partly due to its high
potassium content I like to put a little
gypsum in there for buffering and for
calcium and sulfur availability coconut
fiber is naturally high in potassium and
low in calcium but it has a pretty good
pH in the 6s so it doesn't need dolomite
or limestone but to add calcium to it
gypsum is a great in an inexpensive way
to do that you get the benefit of
calcium and sulfur nutrition and you
also get some buffering to keep your pee
pH on
[Music]