so just quickly Lydia do you have time
to give a quick intro to solar bio
solarization yeah I do I have a okay so
wait before you go before you start it
let me cut the one graphic I could pull
up so people know what we're talking
about is that is that a reasonable
graphic for what we're talking about
look at those fun where it's digest
States and mesocosms yes this is okay so
this is bad this last image is real
helpful so basically the the general
process and thought that we're talking
about here is the the use of different
types of plastics to cover up to cover
soil and heat it up to a certain
temperature for a certain number of days
that basically thermally and activates
weed seeds and pests and disease within
a certain you know depth of the soil
surface and so we were chatting about
this privately
one of our other IPM France and the
cannabis space had shared a slide from
Jim Stapleton's work over at UC Kearney
AG research and so basically you know
this is a practice that you see
implemented in like strawberry field so
when you drive past a field and and
there are furrows and then in between
the furrows there are these sheets of
plastic that are just covering like long
long rows and these big fields
essentially the purpose and the point is
to like I said like knocked on anything
that would be causing a difficulty in
measuring professor disease once the
actual crop comes up they they utilize
this type of thing when it comes to
managing spring mix you know like the
greens you know there's a zero tolerance
policy for having weeds in your spring
mix crops right but you can't go through
and hand weed you know acres and acres
that's exactly right right there that
you just put up you can't go Henry
acres of spring mix it's just something
that's you know it's a limiting factor
the number of people that you're gonna
have to do that you know they could
their capacity to get it right every
time like it's pretty intense and so
what's been going on with the bio
solarization is essentially taking the
soil solarization topic you know the
whole background of heating up the soil
to inactivate these these things that
you're not wanting in your your system
and then the bio part is adding organic
material into that heating process and
as the organic material decomposes it
there are toxic breakdown products that
eliminate soil pest organisms you know
we're talking about something that's as
little as an addition of five percent of
something like they tested tomato pumice
white wine grape pumice and red wine
grape pumice saying that the tomato
byproducts from the traditional you know
food AG was really helpful in
eliminating some of these plant
pathogens that they were concerned about
but you know as with everything it does
have limitations on its effectiveness
you know you wouldn't want to complete
the this type of solarization and then
move all of all of your soil or till it
or you know give it all mixed up because
you're only inoculator you're only
really in activating those first top
inches you know six inches ish of of
topsoil up top and then the kind of the
thought process is that the beneficial
organisms you know earthworms and other
you know fungi bacteria that you know
they're used to a larger range and
change in their environment they're
they're much more like plastic and
capable of of managing environmental
stress and change differently than
perhaps disease and pest organisms that
are going to more similarly need an
environment that matches their host
plant so you know there's there's
there's lots of information that UC
Davis UC Kearney has put up
there's other scholarly papers that had
put out and put out about this you know
when I worked for BASF we would put all
of our all of our media into this like
deep deep freezer and freeze everything
for a period of time and they'd have to
take of the big bales of material and
let them thaw before we use them in the
greenhouse
for pesticide research and so it kind of
works on the polar opposite in is that
if you create this like massive
environmental change or in temperature
shock that you can reduce no pathogens
and pests and disease and I bet that
that Scott and Eric and Kevin and Sarah
have all seen this employed especially
down in Salinas Valley and other places
where there's a lot of a lot of crops
and a lot of dirt instead of soil for
sure there's a cannabis company that
does like a whole steaming thing
actually and I don't know what they
bring in to do it but they tarp
everything over actually inject steam in
there wow this is where I really started
to defer to what I learned from dr. Lane
in that like all the problems live and
decreased oxygen conditions and all the
good things live in the increased oxygen
conditions and there's like a gray area
in the center and you know I think
what's been missing on the growing
community at wide whether it's big AG or
the small cannabis farmers that you know
there's aerobic strategies for dealing
with problems and I think that's
something that dr. Lane has discovered
and communicated that hasn't really
settled in with the market too much you
know but it still wouldn't this this
sounds like you're also dealing with
weed seeds which is a pretty good
strategy for dealing with that are there
doing this in preparation then on these
rows for four do years yeah okay yeah
and the thought process is that plants
will or the soil solarization can take
four to six weeks you know at a certain
temperature during the hottest part of
the year you have to
you know brights on really high
temperatures for it to be effective and
what they're implementing the bio
solarization is they're trying to reduce
that time and then also reduce the
temperature window requirement and so
they're changing something that's like 4
to 6 weeks's of your field being down
you know not not cultivating anything to
making it you know seven to ten days and
achieving a similar effect without going
anaerobic like Scott mentioned right you
don't wanna like drench your soil and
then put a bunch of plastic tarping on
it just hope that's not was just
interesting Peter brought it up it
sounds like it sounds like what they're
saying is by adding plant material they
shorten the duration of what's needed to
be effective because they're composting
in place essentially so by adding the
grapes or the you know any of the
agricultural crop residues you're adding
an organic matter that probably probably
gets hot or quicker or something because
it's composting I don't know yeah I'm a
little unclear while that process is
totally you know layer yeah you must
have to do it in a crop rotational form
where you're doing grid a and then grid
B is the one where you'll do
solarization and then application of
material to develop better tilts and
then you know you'll into into mixing
that next year you would reverse it so
you're you're taking like you know a
hundred thousand square foot you're only
growing on fifty thousand and so you do
fifty thousand this year for 2000xt here
but this way that solarization would
work in the hot part of the summer
because how can you cut a chunk of the
growing season out and get paid yeah you
know exactly that's the hard part is
that some of this stuff is just tough
for us with because the benefit outdoor
is doing it outdoor and catching the
season you don't have anything but that
window maybe maybe this sorry I was
gonna say maybe that's a strategy for
like you're seeing a lot
Hemme people move into old agricultural
grounds so maybe this is like before we
start strategy or something like a three
year fallow pride organic yeah you ran
which is exactly any like disease as
long as it's you know the goal and the
actual effect of it is to bring it down
to something like neutral and they're
not actually causing disease I don't see
a problem with it it seems like it could
fit somewhere you know as long as I'm
always mindful that whatever we do
produce as a solution has a it doesn't
linger around for eons of generations
and plastics and things like that as we
go forward if we can come up with
solutions that don't that biodegrade or
whatever as they come into the
environment but but it sounds like to me
that if you did bring it down to neutral
and a strategy like this you could
easily then revive it with a good
inoculum and this is where like you know
we spoke about some of the obstacles
that you know maybe a lane dr. Lane has
but like this is where I put her as the
undisputed world champion like we have
yet to run into a facility that had a
soil pathogen problem that we couldn't
get under control in a reasonable amount
of time with the same strategies that we
use to increase yield and that that's
where what dr. Lane has not missed once
you know you know despite her views on
mineral balancing or what she thinks is
the correct goal you know when we take
strategies and cultivation that lead to
an arabic root zone we don't have those
problems at all yeah i mean i could see
it being utilized as a first time
strategy to implement in a field and
then as you go forward so the way that
in soil ecology as we deal with weeds as
we move along the ecological succession
underground in the microbes and so
that's how we start just selecting for
which plants then thrive in the system
but that's a much longer term strategy
depending on you know what your base
soil is starting out with so i could see
this being something definitely utilized
as a start of a system if your system is
a young system so let's say you're doing
greens all the time and it doesn't take
much to inoculate it every time and
could do this every time because you're
not growing trees that need a very long
you know growth ecological ecological
growth time to get that fungal component
up that's a they have a much lower
threshold of biological numbers that
they need so for for something like
greens I could see that being a good
strategy yeah introducing this is an
alternative to conventional fumigation
that's how they do organic walnuts
because it takes four years before
there's nuts so they dig out the old
tree methylbromide the whole plant a new
one
and in four years when it produces it
can be deemed organic yeah what one of
the most profound moments in my entire
you know growing career was I was at a
greenhouse in Salinas and you know the
owner of the property also is growing
strawberries and they brought in like a
flat of clam shells of strawberries and
all the weed all the white weed people
were just devouring down but like not
one of the non-english speaking
agricultural workers would go anywhere
near those strawberries and I even kind
of was like you want some and their face
was like oh really that was a really
profound moment like they've been in the
trenches they know what goes down and
which I think is the beauty of regulated
cannabis right now like we're getting a
real strong snapshot with major
financial losses tied to the things that
we regularly do in agriculture yeah that
effect cat 3 testing which i think is
really the kind of poetic aspect of
cannabis is so good at bio remediating
that it's like cleaning up agriculture
that's next door because of the
contamination that's leading to a cat 3
failure and a loss of investment so now
there's a motivation to look at how
toxic our farming is and how far that
spreads away from the actual
cultural field is remediating the
cultivators do
[Laughter]