I'm gonna get a religious reference in
so talking about a Laningham soul food
web there are a lot of Elaine disciples
in this conversation today but we like
if I think of Christianity there are a
lot of Forks right like you had
Catholicism and then you had the
Protestant Reformation where you know we
agree with 99% of Catholicism but we
disagree with this one thing and we're
gonna go down our own path so can you
all talk from your own perspectives kind
of where you have a different philosophy
where your philosophies are slightly or
very different than Elaine's like some
of the differences between how you see
her approaching things and and your
personal approaches well I guess I guess
to tie it into your religious thing is
within the agricultural sector people
are as devout as religious people are
and you know each religion lives and
dies by their uniqueness and and
nonetheless so we're I think we're
personally in a stage where we're kind
of going from this you know religious
approach where it's us against them it's
you know you've seen this mineral
analysis against biological analysis
like Sarah went to the bio nutrient food
conference convention last year and met
up with Todd Harrington another big soil
food web guy from the East Coast and
they went and talked to John Kemp and
introduced themselves and in that next
segment john kemp is talking about how
you don't need to measure soil organism
populations you know and it's just
elaine kind of does this thing i love
and adore laine i would not be here
without her but she responds in kind
with all you need is biology and i think
we're we're unique is that we
incorporate everything I come from a
very qualified group of hydroponic
cultivators in Southern California I
absolutely take that into my living
style strategies you know and so you
cannot just quickly what are some of the
things you've adopted
hydro community it's the mentality you
know growing up in Southern California
like like you couldn't you couldn't be
fake about it like you had to actually
do it or you had to completely be quiet
and so in the organic sector it's much
more important to be the Guru know the
Guru or regurgitate the Guru and
actually be good at growing pot and
that's the biggest disabled aspect of
the organic sector is it's much cooler
to be like you can cut down
three-quarters of your garden each year
and you still be a guru like that's
insane to me from my hydroponic
background like you had to be good or
nobody even listened to a word you said
and so I've taken that mentality and
tried to be as regenerative as possible
and you know you know just take a
holistic approach
sare comes from medicine my family's in
medicine I was raised in a hospital with
my single mom I spent a lot of time
sitting in a nurse management office
listening to patient information prior
to the HIPAA nonetheless but you know we
take a holistic approach we take a
science-based mathematical approach that
I can approach it without emotions and I
can make a quantified decision that
leads to a result that's either
predictable or unexpected but at least
measured so that we can come to a result
that can be repeated so Elaine is
biology only the a mineral people are
mineral only and we do as full effort on
every aspect as we can and then we
follow your feed like we're doing
hydroponics holistic biology yeah and so
so what happens is as there's a
disruption in one component of the
system so like within organics or living
soil the soil minerality moves at such a
slow pace that if you're correcting a
mineral imbalance you might take two or
three harvests to get that under control
you need to balance that with your soil
feeds or your foliar feeds and that's
why all these water only people either
don't do water only or they fail same
water only is because the soil moves so
slow you have to you have to correct
the context of the situation with soil
feeds or foliar feeds while using the
biological population as an indicator
the main anchor of what we do is making
sure that nothing we do reduces
biological populations and I think
that's what makes Sarah and I actually
unique is that lots of people say
biology
everybody says soil food web they all
hashtag it but like by what measure are
you doing any of these things and we
govern all decisions based on what my
wife measures through the microscope if
something I come up with that I think is
a good idea
wipes out populations it obviously was
not a good idea from a biological
standpoint because we harmed the most
sensitive biological members in the
system
and so it might still lead to a yield
but if you're compromising soil
organisms you're also compromising plant
health because it is also a biological
system and I would say just to kind of
touch on your your religious little
opening there is that you know the first
law of chaos is that the truth is
different for everyone
and that's the beauty of science is that
science can unify us on what we can all
you know achieve if we adhere to certain
principles whether you're KNF whether
you're soil food web whether you're
hydro anything there's certain
principles that underlie biological
systems and so that's all we're trying
to say is just quantify it know what
you're doing and and integrate that into
your IPM strategy as your number one
thing you do is get that system in place
that you know what you're doing
nutritionally to support that plant and
if there's something that's been going
wrong a messenger being sent to you via
a bug or a disease then you start
looking okay where it where is the crack
in the system what are you know is it
nutritionally based or we pretty sound
there do we need to do more analytics
there do we do we look at like Lydia was
saying do we need to we're seeing a
certain pathogen do we need to look at
our water system are we cleaning that
enough
just those kinds of sound principles but
just to wrap that all in the only real
issue that you know Elaine and I because
I respect the out of her I think
she's brilliant woman but and she came
to me to speak to me about remember we
had talked about driving those viruses
out of those plants dudes in the earth
boxes and so she was fascinated because
if that's anaerobically driven using
lactic acid and sub-irrigation and so
what we can do was that what's the
definition aerobic because really it's a
certain parts per million of oxygen
present and so in this gray area of
interpretation there was which method is
it considered an anaerobic delivery or
aerobic delivery and that's where like
my mom was a scientist and she's
brilliant but she always makes sure I
remember that you used to be burned
alive because the Sun rotated around the
earth and if you didn't say that they
crucified and that was pretty current
science at the time and so she always
kind of let me understand that we only
see snapshots and we know as much as we
can right now and we have to work with
that and it doesn't mean that we don't
know but it means that's our limit of
understanding and I think when you get
into this religious dogma what happens
is you start to take away reason and you
just follow blindly and what you need to
be able to do is take the education from
the individual and understand how to
apply it and if other people are having
success with contrary methods you need
to investigate and try to find out what
is the common success of all methods
because something is occurring that's
succeeding and so I think that you know
with what we're all trying to do is is
understand there's an art and a science
we're trying to merge and we only know
so much about either and I think that's
where dr. Ingham gets jammed is because
I don't think she could be any smarter
what she is mean she's if you spent some
time with him and she's brilliant and
she's got such a nice rhythm with it
it's she lives that but that's what
she knows and then when you run
something that you don't have this
understanding but it's doing something
it can't be wrong and so it's really
trying to bring everyone into the same
area to say hey look with all our
understandings we maybe can get our arms
around part of the problem but none of
us are so comprehensive that we control
the information on a thing because the
thing is so complex so totally and it's
always evolving and that's what she
always says but what Scott ended up
doing and why I kind of why I mean I
appreciate what he's done and actually
there was a guy that was one of the
advisors Elaine has these advisors and
these are the people that go and do all
her work all the way through and you
know for for the street explanation of
things is what I'm given right now I'm
not the scientific like you guys but
basically was in her group of advisers
they all perform her work and like the
disciples so to speak and Scott and Sur
are those gone through that process and
there was somebody before them my homie
and my name Ian Davidson he started a
company called biologic crop solutions
and a lot of people use but he ended up
moving to Hawaii and getting this other
stuff and Scott and Sara when I met
Scott he was basically jumping on as an
advisor and learning and doing and
saying the stuff where Ian stopped his
work and moved into something else and
that one of the examples is going from
brewing compost teas to do in these
extracts well what Scott did in Inserra
is they took her information and geeked
out on it and went deep and deep in the
cannabis you know a lot of people kind
of with Scott sometimes going do
you grow and stuff and I'm smoking some
of his weed right now but he's been on
big facilities doing big work and I've
been to those and even Kevin you've
recommended something to a farm to have
me go check out and then after I do my
work I recommend Scott next thing you
know the place is blowing up and so
there's a day yeah so at the end of the
day what's happening what Scott decided
to do was create those events and we did
them with Elaine because the lane was
kind of like you know something that
really drove a lot
people to get in there but Scott's data
that had been collected in cannabis was
the real eye-opener I remember the first
one we did Alain was at the edge of her
seat like holy by the third one I
don't know if she can handle the
spotlight that Scott was taking anymore
she kind of started deteriorating those
events and then we had Kevin jump off
with us and we had some good ones after
that and then eventually I'm no longer
with the situation that we were doing to
create those and so subsequently a lot
of that has stopped but the information
was insane that was coming out of that
stuff and that's what I cleaned on to
was Alain seated but Scott and Sarah
sprouted and it's much easier for me to
understand because I've read her papers
or looked at some of her and I
don't even know I don't even speak that
language yeah Scott so that's what you
said like I called you on the phone back
in like 2013 trying to get some compost
tea brewing products I got you on the
phone and I was asking like really
specific questions about dr. Alaine and
regards to my family's farm and you're
like look if this is important to you
like you got to find this dr. Lane woman
and figure out what she's talking about
and then you you must have had a bowl or
two because you're like look man all
these cannabis people they keep saying
soil food web but I don't know anybody
that's measuring it like this woman is
saying you know so if you like growing
pot and you think you can swing a
microscope like get down and I took that
really seriously and I did do that and I
don't think the market wide really
understands the level of analysis that
we can and have provide and aggregated
and distilled down into really
functional advice and it's just I think
it's a symptom of the markets not quite
ready yet still you know we well we were
trying to take that two big AG too and
so I had already spent a shitload of
time spraying walnuts with with compost
tea when oh we needed to get it into the
irrigation system spraying it was barely
doing and when you called me you
were like yo we're gonna set up this
thing and spray these fields or hay or
whatever fields and I was like you've
got a drain
that I saw we did basically you
know again it was you know the
comprehension of these things in the way
that was laid out to us everybody that I
knew and at that time was we only
sprayed compost tea
you know you maybe put a little into the
soil but it was a big spray thing at the
time well but what we did was we we did
the data points so both Sarah and I are
capable of doing the full microscope
process and we showed up to a farm
that's exactly what we did and to my
knowledge we're the first people to
really provide that to the market and we
went crazy because both you know Sarah
comes from Medicine where lives are on
the line and if you don't document
properly baselines then you know a lot
of problems come from that and I had a
construction business that had a lot of
liability working in schools so when we
got into commercial cannabis officially
you know the first thing we did was
establish all those baselines so we
could know where we're starting so we
can know where we're going and what we
ended up finding was you know one
particular facility had like a perpetual
harvest model and we came in and took
samples of each of the populations that
were on this two-week cycle and we were
able to drill down to a decision that
was made by the cultivator that turned
things into the direction of mold and so
as far as four years ago we were able to
come into a facility and within 48 hours
figure out the week that led to all the
problems and what that decision was and
I just don't think people are still
really ready to wrap their mind around
that that's an analytical technique that
can be executed and what they can learn
from it but you know the people that
have figured out how to use it you know
back to square one of not saying
anything about it and so people don't
know that it exists because the people
that have used it most definitely don't
champion it you know more than anything
else is that you know she came in were
you know the papers didn't exist on any
of this material you know like so oh my
biology wasn't a common discussion
certainly wasn't anything that was able
to be communicated to the point that you
can have a conversation in an eight or
six-hour class in one day and give
people more information than they had
ever been exposed to in their entire
life you know and they've been
cultivating or farming for a real long
time so you know she also comes from
this point I really like Elaine I think
she's she's phenomenal just like
everyone else has said that you know she
her position at least originally was you
know very defensive against you know
traditional AG you know she has a lot of
people that are trying to argue with her
she has issues with you know you know
grant money and you know who's funding
the university that she was working for
at the time and how all that's like
changed and modified in her life and how
that's impacted and driven her to you
know author over a hundred papers and
really you know initiate the science in
this realm in a whole new way and you
know just like I said earlier about the
gut microbiology this is something that
we're gonna be watching for you know
decades to come
all of the different tiny little
intricacies of how these microorganisms
work together how they work with
minerals how it all like works with pH
and gets into the plant and how all that
can be very finicky you know especially
with cannabis stream eyestrain or with
different different species of plants in
general this is just something that's
gonna be developing over time and as we
all know you know what works what works
for some person you know one guy doesn't
work for the next one you know five
miles down the road and there's a series
of reasons why that's the case and so
you just have to tune into your own your
own farm what your what you've got going
on what the benefits you know what the
drawbacks are of your current situation
and research it to the best of your
ability because that's the other thing
too is like we live in a culture where
everybody just wants to look at
something on Instagram instead of
actually reading a paper and then in
there if they actually do go read papers
they don't know how to determine whether
or not this paper is sound if it has you
know if there's a large enough sample
size if there's any statistical
relevance to what's being what's being
spouted at the end in a conclusion and
you know taking those jumping-off points
you know Elaine does really you know
spectacular science but taking the
jumping off points that she's providing
and the stuff that Scott's giving and
putting it into practice in your own
facility to the best of your ability and
and coming out with something that was
better than what you had started with
before you know and I think that we're
seeing that a you know the quality of
the material just increases day by day
which is great context is everything
needs to be appropriate to your context