Scot we have a bunch of living soil G
damn KNF enthusiasts watching right now
and I know you run a lot of you you do a
lot of experimentation and so can you
talk about maybe like I love that you I
don't know if you still have your home
bro but like it seems like you were
always experimenting there to you know
prove or disprove things so can you talk
about some things that you've been
experimenting and what you've learned
whether it's related to pests or plant
growth but generally the kind of
ecosystem of microbes plant roots and
plants and soil and all that stuff
mm-hmm yes deep I guess yeah I guess to
clarify yeah my wife Sarah and I we we
use our personal home grow to really
just go bananas on and it's one of the
reasons why I really should is because I
don't think the mindset of the average
viewer from the internet can really wrap
their head around what we're doing they
just see that there's mold in my garden
and they sat on no shit but they don't
understand that we're purposely putting
in there so that we can get repetitions
on how to defeat it so that I can
confidently go into the facility and fix
things and so yeah so the last run that
we did we were I purposely let him get
moldy so we could clear it out the run
before that I took in some spider mite
infested clones and duked it out with
those and then and so that's what we do
because you know my job is fixing
problems and I come from a sports
background so if you're gonna be asked
to hit home runs in the World Series you
better do some batting practice so the
stuff that we've seen is pretty much
completely removed any fear of a problem
from us just because we've seen such
horrific problems and navigated people
out of them using living soil techniques
to kind of tie in what Kevin was saying
earlier is we come into these facilities
that have a dysfunctional attachment to
genetics and there's a lot of times we
come in with a new cultivator to
renovate a property and the property
owners insist that they maintain
genetics so we've had a lot of
experience taking clones that were
contaminated with things like Michael
butanol and avid and all the things that
you're not at all supposed years but
during the times of problem they did use
and so what we found is if you have good
mineral density in your soil and you
have high populations of good soil food
web organisms all the things that tissue
culture claims nature also has a
strategy for and so you know if you have
really high biological populations if
there is a virus in the plant the plant
has the ability to kind of quarantine it
to a branch and it'll form like this
really weird callus almost like it has a
like scar tissue you know a lot of the
things that tissue culture claims that
is the benefit good living soil biology
and good or mineral density can also
provide those same benefits there was
one particular farm that had plants that
were you know coated in systemic
fungicides they were treated with avid
things like that and we actually put
them into a good living soil system vege
dam out we hacked out the that first
biomass that came out and threw it away
that next round of biomass that came out
we cloned ran through propagation and
into the flowering and all that flower
tested clean so in about a you know six
week period we were able to clean some
plants up get them ready for production
and the flower tested clean which
actually kind of blew the mind in the
lab stay all all the lab said that there
was no way that was gonna work we didn't
know we were just tinkering and so I
think there's a lot of untapped
potential out there that people have no
real idea exists because you know the
peat the people that did that study they
definitely don't tell anybody about it
and I was back in I was in like mid 2017
when we did that and you know that farm
is definitely not that information
because that's a tremendous advantage in
the market if you can clean up
in a few weeks you're not gonna share
that with your neighbor we did that with
when the years ago would before it
before dark heart said that they found
the virus Rick crumb was a virologist so
I don't know if you know Rick but crime
and a couple guys from I say UCLA
brought us plants and Alan Atkinson and
I had a conversation about using
biologically driven methodologies to
increase natural resistance and would it
work against a virus and so next thing I
know I got some virus plants with me and
I was able to do the tests and we were
able to get the plant back to
functionality to where it had no change
because we had already had labs on a
prior so I knew what it did when it was
clean and then we saw what it did when
it was affected and then we saw what it
did after the cleansing but it didn't
remove the virus it just brought it to a
level that was workable so we kind of we
what we used an analogy of it was kind
of like the way magic Johnson was able
to get HIV to a level that it was almost
non detectable and non-invasive in his
life it doesn't change the fact that he
still holds it in his body
and so TC doesn't change the fact that
good biologically driven methods of
production are to me are the the best
way to get a plant resistance high and
and I think that it helps shed and scrub
issues but TC is is by far the only it's
you're not going to get that virus
problem any virus out of the plant
completely you'll just get it to a
workable level and what we found was we
took those plants and then put them into
any other environment other than that
biologically driven went back in the
like a chemical situation the bio
factors that allow that to function
weren't present and we don't know which
ones they were because the you know it's
too complex it's a combination not a
single thing and distress would then if
the plant got overheat it if it had too
much salinity you would see it start to
exhibit these viral traits and I didn't
get a chance to do the any work with
them after that point but I would love
to seeing the change in viroid issue
within the plant meaning how much of
structure was
vascular bundles relative to what was
there prior so I'm someone who is like
my farm is biologically driven and I
don't seem to have any issues up top and
I'm grateful for that
but I do a lot of containment where I
don't let anybody go up the hill I don't
have any neighbors and I make sure that
my mineral density is as high as I can
drive it so that the plant has as much
natural response as possible but I still
think that you know science in in
prepper and preservation of things that
are damaged and to protect the nursery
operations the tool to hold and clean I
don't see us ever going away from it
yeah and I definitely have a Kate tissue
culture I wasn't necessarily saying it's
definitely a tool it needs to be
implemented and from providing great
benefit I was just necessarily saying it
like Nature has a lot of strategies for
these things yeah you know yeah yeah
totally totally and I fully agree
because you and I've had this
conversation many times about once the
bottom end is right the plant seems to
work out the problem pretty well once
once we have the correct nutrient
balance the plan isn't exhibiting stress
symptoms that bring insects on once our
once our epidural layers are adequately
built we don't seem to have probing
insects penetrating and causing the
problems but the the thing is that I
know that it's a it's a secret you want
to keep for the for yourself because
it's a market advantage but the
situation is that you're you're I mean
that's why I try to give information out
all the time it's that we're in the
beginning of building an industry and
that if if more of us survive the better
and what that'll do is it allow much
better unity as an industry you have the
ability to have success success builds
finances finances built lobby lobby
builds influence and that's what we
don't have you don't have any of these
things and so a lot of this information
that's why you know these type of little
symposium we're on today is killer
because it's all unfiltered shit but you
get it in a real opinion and I think
they know that that's the part that has
to get shared is that
the big picture has to be shown and then
the details that has to be worked out
individually
yeah we can only if only everybody would
get together we've all all of us have
had common interest on projects that we
wanted to see succeed and we try to do
the best we can and I think that's what
the the public has to see meaning the
grow Republic is that so much of this
stuff is complicated and a lot of times
the only way you're gonna succeed is if
you share the information the larger
corporations they all believe they are
proprietary IP each one less we know now
we have all this top-secret shit and I'm
like it's a fucking sector yeah the
hybrid state of the yard all these you
know we're about to show the world you
know it's pretty easy yeah I'm like
you're gonna show anybody shit uh-uh I
see a paint sprayer in there
[Laughter]