[Music]
versus what are we calling it like the
living soil crew or you know the soil
food web crew and kind of how their
begrudging lis coming to at least
acknowledge or accept that there's
something interesting with kind of the
KNF world whereas initially they
dismissed it mm-hmm and so can you kind
of talk about what maybe you're like
what KNF is why the soil food web people
maybe initially kind of pooh-poohed it
and then kind of how they're bridging
that gap and maybe coming to accept or
even eventually become enthusiasts yes
so basically what we're seeing that one
of the things that we talk about in
these groups especially groups of
regenerative farmers because we really
do see a divide between you know the
Korean natural farming and the you know
food soil web biological protocols and
so in that divide like how do we come
together and how do we acknowledge that
both methods work and where does that
misinformation and misunderstanding
happen and what we're realizing is that
a lot of the people who followed a lot
of elaine adams work she's very much a
staunch proponent of making sure that
your inputs are what you think that they
are and making sure that things don't go
anaerobic because anaerobic is generally
bad and generally you get pathogenic
things happening and it's it can quickly
become a problem so when you talk with
people who you know kind of believe in
that mentality what they're thinking is
that Korean natural farming is a ferment
and since it's not an aerated situation
it's going anaerobic and therefore an
aerobics are bad but when you talk to
the Korean natural farming and you start
getting into this you see that it's not
really an anaerobic process it's open to
the air you have breathable lids there's
a ferment going on so there's you know
things happening inside with gas
exchange
and I think that as time goes on and
more and more people are going down this
methodology with Korean natural farming
because it's so cool and it's so
effective and it's just a really fun
process to get into they're saying well
this works really well and plants aren't
dying and there aren't pathogens so
there must be something to it actually
and for me I have my microscope so when
I'm making my indigenous microorganism
collections I'm actually looking at it
under the scope so that I do know what
I'm putting in there
my opinion is you know you can go just
as easily really wrong with a compost
tea as you can with your rotten rice if
you don't know what your basis of your
microorganisms are that are in there
doesn't really matter which method you
do you could blow it on either side you
can do things different ways and still
have it work out and still have it be
beneficial just maybe not exactly how
you thought of it originally
can you talk kind of with each
methodology what could go wrong and and
what like what are you actually seeing
under the microscope like when someone
messes up the KNF process can you tell
me which microbes are showing up to the
party I actually can't tell you which
microbes because the microbes are still
so small that even with our shadow
microscopes that we're using we we don't
know which ones they are necessarily but
I have definitely had inoculation zuv
bad fungi like they're clearer they're
thinner they don't have a uniformity to
them they don't have these septums that
separate them so what you want with your
beneficial fungi is like a big fat
mycelium that's dark in color has little
walls basically in between them and is
uniform throughout the whole thing and
of a large size so if I have that I know
that I'm pretty good to go
learning other things that can be
pathogenic like what a Fusarium spore
looks like is a really good one to know
so if you see tons of those you know you
have a problem if you end up with a ton
of Scilly it's swimming around that's
usually not a very good indicator that's
an indicator of an anaerobic condition
and that's more on
compost tea side that we see that rather
than on Korean natural farming and yeah
I mean with most of the firmaments that
we're making I mean it just looks like
you know happy bubbly things so as funny
as you mentioned ciliates and i remember
the first time i you know looked at
stuff under the microscope and I saw
these microbes whizzing around and they
looked so cool and I was so proud of
them and I filmed it and I put it up on
YouTube and people were like those are
those are an indication of an anaerobic
environment that was like yeah yep I
think my first flageolet I found I
followed it for like half an hour I got
the worst kink in my neck I was like
this is so cool oh my gosh but
flageolets are good you just talked
about kind of after you go through the
KNF process what you're looking for
under the microscope to see if you did
well or poorly in in like brewing teas
which is an aerobic activity what are
you looking for into the microscope in
terms of I'm gonna put this on my plants
or not so when I'm doing my compost teas
I'm looking for something different
because we use a lot of our own
earthworm castings so ideally what I
want there is I want some of those
larger microorganisms so I want some
testate amoebae in there I would love to
see a nematode but those usually aren't
in the compost tea but you know if
you're there in the compost or if
they're in your soil like that's a
really good sign as long as it's a you
know bacteria eating or I've never seen
the omnivorous nematodes I've only seen
the bacterial feeders and I don't think
I've ever seen a root feeder which is
really good says something that we're
doing something right with our
composting process and our our earthworm
castings but definitely looking for
those tests date amoebas still looking
for the beneficial fungi and then
there's a way to do your counts where
you're counting how many microbes in
each slide and you're figuring out what
your you know call informing colony
forming unit CF use are things like that
I usually don't go that deep into it
because you know I see my
J and I say Miami BAM I'm a happy camper
so I think of these two processes when
you're making compost teas do you kind
of have different brews for different
stages of plant growth like maybe you'll
do more fungal dominant in the early
stages and you know progressively move
towards more bacterial dominant and then
certain specific bacteria maybe at the
end that are known pathogen fighters and
then with KN F is it kind of are you
dialing things in the same way that you
do with tears I actually dial it more
with with KN f than I do with the t's so
the t's I want it fungal e dominant
always if I can get it there
we know that cannabis really responds
well to like up to a 30 to 1 fungal to
bacterial ratio so that's a really
really great thing to to see is make
sure that you have that fungi in there
all the time and then with compost teas
a lot of that we temper it with you know
like a little more heavy on the nitrogen
side like green grasses or something
like that or we'll add some fish amino
acids or fish hydrolysate at not we
won't brew that into it but we'll add it
in when we're using it for our drenches
and then with kns you get it's it's more
so Korean natural farming is
traditionally a foliar method it's not
meant to be a soil drench you have your
indigenous microorganisms you inoculate
the soil with those but all of your
ferments that you're making are just for
foliar so it's a little bit different
because what we're finding is that
cannabis it doesn't quite have the same
nutrient cycling that like a tomato does
so tomatoes go through some very
distinctive phases it goes through
flower it goes through you know
vegetative and then it puts on flowers
and puts on fruits and then it dies but
with cannabis we don't ever really let
it do the fruiting part because we want
it to be sinsemilla so we're not
pollinating it so you just see it's got
it's got a different kind of rhythm to
it especially when it comes to what
we're using and when we're using it so
we're finding that and a lot of us have
found it
things you know some of us like to
continue spraying some of our sprays
further into flowers some of us like to
do it you know end it later one of our
one of the farmers that we speak with
does turns it into a drench at the end
so he stops foliar feeding and starts
drenching the soil instead which I've
done also when I started Korea natural
farming I didn't know it was a foliar so
I was using it as a soil trench which
worked really well but as a foliar it
works much better and a lot of that has
to do with when you're using your sea
water your water soluble calcium and
your water soluble calcium phosphate
normally they're used at very specific
times but we're finding with cannabis
you kind of have to tweak it a little
bit more and really read what your plant
wants and because it's a full year it
picks it up and responds very quickly so
does that imply that you kind of have a
mixed process of what's your that's hope
yeah that's what we did a lot of last
year we did have one area of our garden
that was strictly KNF and then the rest
of it we kind of did a mishmash of the
two and so this year were actually
really excited we've got our 8,000
square foot full term outdoor garden
that's gonna be separated into eight to
ten different cultivars each one will
have 10 to 12 plants and we're gonna
split it right down the in two-thirds
one-third is gonna be strictly Korean
natural farming so we'll do indigenous
microorganisms on the soil will do a
liquid indigenous microorganism extract
at a few different times during the
cycle and then Korean national farming
implements for the all the foliar the
other far side we're going to do a
strict food soil web system so we're
gonna use compost compost teas some
fulvic acid as a full year after the
compost tea and I believe that's gonna
be about it on that one and then in the
middle we're gonna do both so I'm going
to use indigenous microorganisms and
compost tea and compost tea extract and
liquid IMO for the for the soil and then
for the foliar we'll do a combination
also of the compost tea and
KNF and we'll just kind of take it out
through the year and see what happens at
the end you've already gone through a
season with KNF correct yes and can you
give us kind of a a can you distinguish
between like pre-k NF and post KF and
turnt like what have you looked for or
noticed have you had any more bountiful
harvest more terpenes less pathogens
what's what are you looking for and and
what's happened as a result of adopting
KNF methods um we've definitely seen
higher resin production so we were I've
been very impressed by just the overall
quantity of the resin is way higher than
we've seen in the past which I was
really fairly surprised about actually
so frenchie can only we'll be very happy
yes French would be right she's gonna
love KF when he gets into it destroy
those tri-coat everything for the hash
[Laughter]
so lots more tricone production
healthier plants overall they were just
easier they just seemed to be more
resistant to kind of everything we did
have thrips last year which was the
first time and I'm I'm sure I manifested
it on accident because I heard the rips
were coming back to cannabis and I was
like drips we haven't seen thrips in
cannabis since like the 80s that's crazy
what I was gonna be my question is that
something that was unique to you or was
that endemic to kind of humble overall
to the cannabis industry overall like
thrips kind of hit everyone last year a
little bit more than you know then than
we expected or than I've seen in a
really long time and I happen to know
Suzanne Wainwright who's one of the lead
entomologists for the United States for
horticulture most she used to be in like
hanging baskets and cut flower industry
and as she sees more of how much
cannabis really needs some help with
their integrated pest management plans
and you know IPM strategies she's come
into this space and so I actually you
know caught these little thrips and put
them in this little vial and sent them
off to her and it's a brand new species
of thrips that is all over the west
coast well and I don't know if it's a
thrip specifically but I remember there
was something that was unleashed
somewhere north of you know you're
shaking your head but you know the story
I'm telling to combat something else
yeah but is that a false it's a really
bad rumor it's this is this is one of
those rumors that just makes me cringe a
little bit because it got so widespread
and it took me maybe 10 minutes of
googling to find the information so what
it is is that Caltrans workers created
this biological assay to combat star
thistle and tumbleweed and there were
yeah there were two different predator
not predator there were two different
pests that they released and one of them
was a type of might but it was a grecian
gall mite I believe or a grecian blister
might I can't quite remember exactly
what it was totally different species
totally different you know very very
different animal altogether and somebody
found out about that and went oh my gosh
Caltrans released mites and that's
basically where that whole thing came
from but it's not the same mite the hemp
Russert mite is very specific to
cannabis it doesn't go to other plants
so people worry about like oh it's gonna
go to my tomatoes and live on my
tomatoes and I'll never get rid of it
and then it'll you know move back and
forth it doesn't actually work that way
hem press it my it's very much a hemp
recipe exactly
the proud canvas enthusiast it's not
like vegetables okay so it seems like
thrips hit everyone yeah nobody was
spared how did it like when you were
talking to other cultivators who weren't
using some of the methodologies that you
were using kind of what was the the
comparison and the damage done or the
plants rigorous defense against the
pests yeah I mean that is the
interesting thing that I hadn't really
thought about too much most people with
their thrips
it damaged the plants pretty bad I mean
we had them pretty bad it was they were
like you know it was not hard to find
some to put in a little jar but we don't
really like spring pesticides or
anything and we were getting close to
the end of the run so we were just like
well you know we'll just kind of I don't
know wash them down with water and you
know try and mitigate and manage them a
little bit but the interesting thing is
the end result flower was still really
good I mean we still had really great
nutrient uptake the plants didn't really
suffer at all I mean unless you got up
close he couldn't really even tell there
was that much of a problem and we did do
a lot of predatory releases we released
aureus which is a my new pirate bug is
what it's called and so that's a
predator
we released a predatory wasp and then we
released them my new pirate bug both to
kind of help us combat them and it took
down the population it made it
manageable but it didn't again it didn't
seem to impact the plants terribly
detrimental II so so your main strategy
was predatory bugs mm-hmm yeah did you
have any friends who had other
strategies that were effective or people
still kind of like to pretend like
things happen that didn't so like I know
a friend there was like oh we totally
got rid of our threats of like by I
think they use doctors AIIMS or
something and I was like that's awesome
and then when I looked at you know one
of the leaves them all no you didn't
like almost like everybody feels shame
yeah yeah I want to just come out and
say we all got it yeah I have no shame
I'm like people are like Oh have you
ever dealt with russets I'm like oh yeah
plenty of times
of course I mean any time you bring a
plant onto your property you're probably
bringing russets in but the great thing
is if you deal with them once generally
that's all it takes to get really good
on your quarantine process and then
after that you're like oh whatever
russets aren't a big deal spider mites
easy to take care of the West Side Story
yeah two gangs in the West Side Story or
the Bloods and the Crips or any the
Celtics and the Lakers
being from Boston what would you say to
kind of the living soy or the soil food
web cam to to get them to give KF a
chance like what are some of the
compelling arguments you know it's
really there's a I actually just spoke
with somebody at one of our regenerative
conference because point me two years or
how many years ago did you do zero kfm
yeah four years ago so it's only been
three years for you so talk about the
finding Jesus and I will be honest like
when I first heard about it I was like
Korean natural farming but we're not in
Korea like we're using rice to collect
our indigenous microorganisms but we
don't have right like we don't grow rice
and I'm like Locke California does grant
rice but um but at the beginning I was
kind of like I don't know about this
this seems like pretty bizarre to me and
what turned for me was we went out to
the beach and I collected a bunch of
seaweed and I was talking with my friend
Layton who's a scientist on the East
Coast and I was like okay so I have all
this seaweed like I'm kind of thinking
should i dry it out and like pulverize
it and like how much work do I really
want to do on this maybe I'll just dump
it in the compost should I feed it to my
earthworms I don't know what do you
think Laden and he's like you know what
you should do you should ferment it and
it was like oh boy are you going down
the rabbit hole - he's like I am I've
gone down the K enough rabbit hole I'm
going deep it's pretty interesting
actually like why don't you just just
try it just give it a shot see what
happens so I took the seaweed that we
had which was a bladder wrack and it was
the weirdest thing and I loved it it
turned into this like when you poured it
it was like thick yeasty cake batter
almost and it was like kind of slimy and
gooey and it was just so fun to play
with and by the time the ferment was
done I was like okay if this is this
much fun like if this is this cool I
have to learn more about it and and then
just started using it and
for me I really like the fact that these
are all inputs that are made for our
human body as well so as soon as I
started getting into that and I made our
first or oriental herbal nutrient or o
hn and started taking that internally I
was like man this stuff is gold this we
do not my family doesn't get sick
anymore I have a four year old and an
eight year old and I guarantee you
they're swimming in germs the only one
who got a cold in the last two years
pretty much has been my four-year-old
who doesn't like the Oh HN and myself
when I was on vacation and forgot to
bring it with me and I knew I that my
kids were sick and I was like aha man
but you know it's just like wow if this
if this can help the human body this
much against pathogens and diseases and
things like it's got to be good for our
plants and so just you know started
using it pretty minimally at the
beginning and again like I said when I
first started I didn't know it was a
full year so I was like you know making
a big huge vat with a had some fpj and
some Oh HN and a little bit of thought
about was I putting it at the time brown
rice vinegar and I didn't have recipes I
was just kind of going off what people
were saying online so I was just kind of
well that's what I was gonna ask man
what was kind of your original recipe
and then kind of what's the iterative
improvement of that yeah the I don't
think they even had an original recipe
honestly I was just like you know how
much do we put in guys people like I
don't know try this much and we're like
okay Oh an L a B that was the other one
actually Li B was our first first foray
into can F so that's lactic acid
bacteria serum so you're basically
taking milk and you're letting it kind
of ferment and turn into curds and whey
and then you take the curds off and
you're left with this beautiful la B
that is just phenomenal I mean like we
had a micronutrient deficiency I think
that's what it was at some point there
was something going on and that was all
we had made because that was the first
thing I tried and I was like this was
easy like let's do this more and my
husband was like well what do we do with
it now and I'm like I don't know what do
we do with the people when people are
like I don't know water it in we're like
okay so we did and with
two days we saw that micronutrient
deficiency just disappear and I still
like I mean you know I'm going from
memory from a couple years back so I
don't know for certain what exactly else
was happening but I was just like okay
this is cool and so then playing with
things finally last year I went to Boise
Idaho and studied under Chris Trump and
that was where everything started really
making sense because you leave there
with this beautiful sheet of recipes and
you leave with all this intrinsic
knowledge about how to use each recipe
and when to use it and in what ratios
and it's like okay how do you make
fermented seawater and why do you want
to do that and what do you use it for
and so then getting to come back and
really start implementing that and doing
it the right way and then having a
background in growing cannabis and
knowing how to see nutrient deficiencies
and be like oh I have the input for that
that's gonna be a little bit of this and
a little bit of that so we'll kind of
you know there's some blending of
recipes that does happen now just
because I've done it enough where I know
like okay this I know this needs
potassium and I know that water soluble
calcium phosphate phosphate pardon me
and I know that WC AP as our phosphate
for this so I know that I'm going to add
that but we're not in this particular
stage of development so we're gonna add
it to this one instead and then I also
love doing the side-by-sides so that's
been really eye-opening this year as
well we did our seed so treatment and I
did the same seeds same cultivar started
them in the same soils the whole nine
yards and I did the SES which is our
main institutions or a seed so treatment
I did plain water and then a few years
back I'd soaked in a fulvic acid
solution and it worked really well I got
really much faster germination a better
germination rate so I was like well if
SES is good and fulvic acid was good I
should add them together and then it'll
be like gangbusters absolutely incorrect
absolutely incorrect I was shocked we
got the worst germination rate worse
than plain water and the plants did not
grow as fast right now I've got some
pictures up on our Instagram that shows
you can see this was SES and this is SES
and fulvic the ones that we had just the
straight korean natural farming darker
green they don't have any leaf drop
showing they're not picking up any
micronutrient deficiencies the ones that
had fulvic acid added and this is months
ago months ago they've been treated the
same ever since micronutrient
deficiencies lighter green is having a
harder time with up taking nitrogen the
bottoms of lilies are yellowing and
following off I mean it's it's just like
I was like wow this is so cool
to actually see this and you know do a
side by side and really know that like
it's been developed a certain way and
it's probably perfect the way it is for
the most part yes like these two drugs
should not be together yeah and we found
it was even worse for our loofah sponges
so the loofah sponges was an 85 percent
germination rate I think yeah I think
was 85 percent is what we ended with
with the SES and they started
germinating within like 24 hours loofah
sponges can take two up to three months
for these seeds to germinate I was like
oh this is really fast the plain water
we had I think 80% germination rate but
they were last I measured they were a
good two and a half inches shorter in
average height than the SES and the SES
and fulvic we had a 40% germination rate
and they just kind of like grew up and
fell over I was like okay good to know
that was that was not a wise choice spj
I think is a really good one for people
to start with it's really easy it's
pretty hard to mess up FPGAs ferment and
plant juice so basically the only
difficulty with that one is that you're
supposed to be up in the morning before
the Sun touches your plants and you want
to just take the growing tips of your
plants not the whole plant not the roots
if you go off information online or in
old books there's all kinds of different
ways to do it that are not the right way
and one of the first ones I made had
like the roots and it was like not the
soil off but you know gently it's okay
if it's in there and turns out that no
that's not really a good idea but yeah
like I said we do our fpga
with seaweed so that has this whole
different profile than like the growing
mustard tips from the you know wild
mustard that's in our yard a lot of
people do FPGAs out of aloe vera so
there's just you know it's just it's so
widely diverse and it's so easy to do
it's a great one for people to start
getting into but you never spray fpj
alone so you always have to at least add
your Oh H n which is your oriental
herbal nutrient and that's a tincture so
you have Angelica garlic ginger cinnamon
and licorice and you ferment it first
with either sugar or sugar and beer and
then you do a tincture and you stir it
every day for three months and you do
different five different extractions and
at the end you end up with this really
amazing nutrient solution that's really
healthy for you and it's really healthy
for the plants and when you add it to
your fpj it just creates this beautiful
microbial colonies on your plants that
make it extremely resistant to pests and
diseases and are you applying a
consistent concoction throughout the
lifecycle or like the what was the first
one fpj o hn f pj and o hn you basically
create those two solutions you mix them
and then that's kind of your foliar
spray for the entire process or are you
adding other things at certain points
yeah you can use that that's that's the
maintenance spray so it's brown rice
vinegar o HN and fpj your F PJ's I have
one too
let's see FPGA is one two five hundred I
think and then Oh H n is one to a
thousand and brown rice vinegar is one
to one thousand so you're using very
very minut amounts of this maintenance
spray you can use up to once a week any
time doesn't matter but what you really
want to do is dial into your life cycle
and the nutrient cycling of the plant so
if you're at the beginning in the
vegetative stage then you want to add
some other things to it so FA a which is
your fish amino acid so that takes about
three to six months at least to make so
a lot of these are processes that you
know you have to really start them and
this is all
foliar fullier yep yep so you want to
start some of these way ahead of time in
a pinch we've used fish hydrolysate
instead of FAA because we didn't have it
but and then you have your water soluble
calcium and you have a water soluble
calcium phosphate and those are used at
different times to see if your
maintenance solution good to go anytime
you have a vegetative growth solution
you have a you know flowering or
finishing fruiting solution you have a
changeover solution so that's generally
used like if you were doing light
deprivation or an indoor you'd use that
during your transition phase which is
usually about a week before your light
cycle changes in a week into it and then
you also there's a ripening formula a
ripening enhancement formula that we've
just kind of started playing with in
tinkering with a little bit and seeing
how to use it and when to use it and you
know what the effects are yeah and what
the effects are because that's the key
so that's when those control groups
really come into play like if you put it
on everything you don't really know what
worked and what didn't because you put
it on everything but if I know that this
plant got it and this plant didn't or
this section did and this section didn't
and I have that control group I can come
back and really say listen this isn't
subjective this isn't means thinking
that this has a better terpene profile
or that this was more pest resistant
this is me actually having data to prove
it and I think that the cannabis
industry has a very difficult time
collecting some relevant data because we
get excited about things and we just go
you know hog-wild and do it on
everything and we forget about the fact
that we now really don't don't have
anything to show that it actually did
what we think it did so I I'm a big
proponent of like at least just at least
you know a few of them leave them alone
and see what happens and make sure that
it is doing what it's you know what you
think it's doing it seems like nutrients
are there is nutrient intake through the
leaves mm-hmm yeah absolutely okay
which is why KNF is so cool for cannabis
because it is so responsive like you
really you do really see changes in a
day or two men
if you're doing if you're doing it right
and if you're doing it wrong you'll see
that pretty quickly - which is nice
because then you can bounce back and be
like okay fix it with that whoops
so you could I mean as an example just
to test things out you could have like
soil that's deficient in some critical
nutrient and you're providing these
foliar sprays where the plant will the
leaves won't turn yellow the plants like
I'm still cool yeah like I may not be
getting it through the roots I'm getting
the suppository or so like I'm not
getting the suppository but it's still
it's still doing its job and then Korean
natural farming also does implement a
living soil very much so indigenous
microorganisms is like the base of it so
without that you have a harder time I
mean we did one in I think I had a
little isolated bed that didn't have you
know the soil wasn't great it was
there's one the ends of one of our beds
it's just always lacking it still can't
figure out what's going on down there
but those ones even with the Korean
natural farming they were lacking so
we're gonna do a better inoculation with
our indigenous microorganisms this year
and see if that doesn't snap that area
out of it but you usually are using
these you know mycelial mats to keep
your soils up to health and to keep that
fungal a dominant as well and what do
you are you growing and like raised beds
or pots or in the ground or all of the
above no no pots no pots we don't do
pots anymore so we have raised beds we
have mounded they're not like cool you
know Hugo who do gorgeou yeah yes I
actually my mother would pronounce it
correctly but I love my I have my Hugo
beds at home and oh my gosh the water
usage on that is insanely small like I
was shocked i watered it one third of
the time compared to the rest of my
garden I was just like absolutely mind
blown it's it's so cool and just the
fungal dominance of it I mean I can like
dig a sample of soil out and get it
under my microscope and immediately find
beneficial fungi it's not sure like you
basically have Roddy
logs yep dank environment yeah so with
the raised beds are you like what's kind
of the typical dimension of a raised bed
oh gosh everybody does it differently
ours happen to be four feet by eighty
feet okay
three feet by eighty feet and so
basically what you're doing there is
you're and so in that eighty feet how
many plants are you getting well our
well it depends I think that we depends
on the size so you know generally are
light depth we're using clones and we're
planting them every foot two foot and a
half and we have I think two rows that
go down the bed and I know that in the
entire five thousand square foot garden
we run nine hundred and sixty plants
okay and that's in 1/2 that's in 8
different beds but I guess where I'm
going is is the idea here that like a
lot of people historically have done
pots where each plants root system is
isolated but you kind of want every all
the root systems to be partying together
and with the microbes and the fun you
know the fungal just everything together
not like pot one its own ecosystem pot
to its own ecosystem like silo siloed
ecosystems you want kind of everything
and then I guess with like your like
drip irrigation are using like blue Matt
or anything like that to kind of keep
sort of the the moisture level
consistent like you're using tensiometer
x' or anything to like so do you get
scenarios where like you know the the
warmer sunnier side of the greenhouse
maybe is drier in the soil then like the
far end of the greenhouse that's maybe
cooler and less light so are in that 180
foot raised bed right so our light
deprivation is actually open air
we don't have it enclosed so there is no
house effect happening we don't tend to
see that much of a difference in I mean
we do have drip tape irrigation but it's
just on a timer and you know we hand
water in our you know our soil drench of
whichever it might be usually at least
once or twice a week and really just
yeah I don't see a lot of difference
with that and I mean I don't know I'm
kind of an old-school farmer people take
this they're like oh you got a pH your
water and you gotta get your blue mat on
your little thing that measures all that
and I'm like or you could just talk to
your plants and go stick your finger in
the dirt and find out what's going on
so generally that's kind of what we do
is we you know watch our plants and we
see what they need and we take it as a
you know as part of our interaction with
what we do and with what we love to do
and I think that makes a difference too
I think it you know you you notice
things a lot faster when you're out
there you know if you're assuming that
your blue mats gonna take care of all
your watering needs so that you're you
know doing something else with your time
and you're not in your garden it's
really easy to miss those things and all
of a sudden you know you see these
horrible photos of people with like it's
like aphids like I've seen cannabis
covered in Athens and I'm like how did
it get to this point like where did that
how did you not notice you had a fence
before they were so encrusted that like
there's just no salvaging that and when
you're out there you know in your plants
with your face you know in the leaves
and your fingers in the soil and you're
really interacting it's just you you
notice things way faster and that's
another great thing with the Curie
natural farming is you're in there and
you're like oh you know I this is I got
a little bit of a zinc deficiency okay
let's see let's go check out our inputs
and you know figure out which one of
these might have zinc in it and go do a
foliar
all right well Wendy I appreciate the
time it is probably like 8:30 at night
on camera all day and I think we're
gonna do a course out of this right
specific video but you're gonna do a
seminar a six-week two-hour each week
workshop and we're gonna film
and make an online version of it so that
people who don't live in humble - can
yeah
come enjoy and appreciate so I'm excited
for that I'm really excited to teach
people cuz that's or one it's a it's
really easy to get bad information
online and you know having gone through
it myself and really made a lot of
errors at the beginning because I'm
trying to figure out how to do things
and people say oh you'd do it like this
and I'm like okay and like no that's
actually that's totally not right at all
maybe one day helene yes well we we
still meet she'll be in the front row
she will be in she'll be like I'll I
don't know about this I don't know
and then eventually I'll look at her to
scope my rice and she'll be like all
okay it looks pretty good
[Music]
you