so you have a farm up in Santa Barbara
yes yes mr. Knights guy LLC is our farm
in Santa Barbara Santa Maria line you
know are you growing just cannabis
you're growing all sorts to vegetable
yes where were cannabis grower up there
we have seven acres under roof outs
we're doing it in large box marked 100
gallons two hundred gallon 260 okay
donar 60-gallon smart box we use you
know worm casting biochar peat moss
obviously some micro highs and stuff
makes it into the soil we found it's
something we've done in the past but
it's it'll be better soil this year than
it was last year because they got hot
you know there's so as you probably know
when you first get raw biochar it has to
be primed it has to be activated because
there's a thin sheen on the surface of
the char that's an organic material
that's partially blocking the binding
sites for the NPK so unless it's fully
activated you might expect it to be hot
but if the char is is activated its
prepared that eliminates that problem
entirely so I think you probably see
this year or maybe even next year you'll
see it starts to see the benefit right
for sure so that's one of the value
propositions of char is it allows you to
be more efficient with your inputs
whether its water or nutrients we have
to be more efficient I mean that's kind
of one of the bottom lines of
regenerative farming model is be
efficient with your uh nutrients no
runoff yeah we had zero runoff you know
it's advantage of smart pots you know
and I'm a fan of letting it dry pretty
thoroughly so I mean we were only in
both size pots we are only needing to
feed once every five to seven days
that's kind of the beautiful thing of
this these cocoa media so if fiscally
got two cups of media here we've got a
more traditional mix peat perlite and
Koya and then these are pure cocoa
obviously we need we really should leave
the peat in the ground and this is again
more of a traditional propagate
condition if some people want but the
difference between we've got these two
right here have about a day's worth of
nutrient in these three if about four to
six weeks with the nutrients so we're
taking advantage of that ability of the
shark during a hold on a difference so
it creates this system where the plants
release exudates
out of their root structures signaling
the microbiology to mobilize nutrients
so instead of using salt based nutrients
I'm not saying you do but you know saw
based on the tree in feeder is
essentially forcing the plant to feed
correct
with osmotic pressure this way since
they're living systems the plants get
exactly what they want when they want it
how they want it that allows them to
more fully express their chemo type
whether it's the trip annoyed or
cannabinoid in these signatures we're
seeing a consistently boost of that
again because these systems are
optimized for efficiencies driven by the
plan not by the farmer so have you
noticed how you know note your salt
nutrient mixes react with the biochar it
will read you will have to cut back on
your nutrient packages pretty
dramatically
and that's the part of the savings as
part of the efficiencies right you know
consistently forty to fifty percent
we were actually we're down to about
twenty five percent at what people would
normally expect you know I'm not I'm a
fan of the less is more sometimes you
know yeah and I found that over years
and years of growing actually indoors
indoors is my expertise I did it for a
long time Santa Barbara's or first go
and a big big outdoor situation where
man permitted before you know it's a
weird spot a San Fernando Valley and
then I was also in Montana for a long
time
so on the my indoor shows I became a big
fan of Coco
specifically because Coco and the reason
for because is the lack of bugs in it
because it's sterilized day on our
degrees and it's worth the extra money
to debit sterilized oh yeah you know and
then you know yes I mean I've heard it
described a million times
you know Coco is like you know
hydroponics for on training wheels yeah
but you know but I like it because
there's a buffer there there's room for
mistake you know growing in rock wool
for a long time you fail a pump you fail
a drip system it's overnight you have a
nightmare problem
not to mention rock was not a
sustainable material its extraction from
the planet it's just not a good idea
they're better solutions there are
better solutions and I mean Coco for me
was the solution because it just it was
alive number one but at the same time it
was sterile so it really allowed me to
monitor my you know pH balance my
feeding program you know yeah there's
some potassium in there but it doesn't
hurt me you know and it allowed me
you're training a crew right I mean I
mean let's face it we're we enjoy the
cannabis plant sometimes things get
forgot it provides a measure of
resilience in the practice and the great
practice which in general we want
climate resilience we want to have
flexibility in the system would like a
reed blowing in the wind doesn't break
you just modulate with your environment
around you and then you can dial it in
and and this obviously provides some
water retention capacity so this is long
and short fiber cocoa what we've done is
we bundled two different strands to
create to maximize air-filled porosity
and then added the biota we add the base
so the base is as I said we take the
char we inoculate it with beneficials at
the organic different packages and we
incubate it for a month out comes our
base and the amount of Base so do you
find with this you don't have to use
additives of the beneficial bacteria and
stuff it's already there you can all
it's going to do is boost the
acceleration of a biomass of chlorophyll
so it's not like it's bad but I don't
know if you get anything better out of
it
frankly yeah that's that's fascinating
that's fascinating I wouldn't have
considered using a biochar mixing it in
just because you're so conscious of
being sterile and inert yeah when you're
doing an indoor think it's an air
monitor we create this mix indoors
intentionally to eliminate pathogens
but couldn't you create something
outdoors where the beneficials
out-compete the pathogens you can't I
mean it's a pretty delicate system I'm
not sure I can actually modulate that
system I think in theory with ecological
theory yes but we're interested in
efficiency here we're interested in
creating mixes that can be scaled that
people can use I mean the these are
essentially climate smart soils that's
the narrative we're trying to describe
we need to adopt climate smart
technologies whether it's in
transportation like the Prius
regenerative farming all of us have to
activate climate smart technologies and
this is what this is this is bait draw
down this is based on atmospheric carbon
yeah unfortunately it's pretty hard to
transport you know a pallet of dirt and
a Prius yeah that's well so I was on the
previous design team literally I work
for Toyota before I started this company
and that took us a long time to dial in
but there will be a word there we're
working out on a hybrid truck I'm still
involved with toy-like once the Toyota
guy you never really leave it I work for
Google for a couple years like once at
Google are you always a Googler yeah I
mean the problem with problem with that
whole thing is you're gonna have to get
him to have a range of 700 miles and
until we hit that mark an electric truck
is just you know cuz I'm I'm the kind of
guy you know I'll have to run to Santa
Barbara to Salinas and back in the day
and a 200 mile range 250 mile range will
leave me abandoned on the side of the
road one solution there is the fuel cell
you know Toyota has a fuel cell car
right now they're working MRI the next
generation it comes out in two years
instead of having a range of 250 miles
and have a range of 450 miles that's an
electric car you're just making the
electricity real time so they're testing
a fuel cell semi again giving you range
that's competitive with diesel but
that's what we have to do is be
competitive with witness with the
subcision fuel
right right absolutely and then and then
you're off to the races that's why I'm
stuck in a diesel truck right now I'm a
farmer what are some nutrients that
between the two of you you think farmers
don't pay enough attention to like in
terms of what their benefit is the plan
they kind of neglect I noticed it's
mostly silica it's what people leave out
of their the regimen you know it's
mostly sick and everybody's familiar
with your NPK and your your two step or
three step you know a and B kind of
thing but I find that most of them have
no concept of the necessity of silica
just a little bit it only takes a little
bit protec it's an amazing product you
know I mean that's the number one thing
I see with most growers leaving out most
of them are familiar with beneficial
bacteria is most of them are familiar
with micro I'd say they're all over it
but they're leaving out the silica and
it's it's essential and what is the
effect when you you're deficient in
silica silica just it keeps your roots
cleaner
everything's picking up faster I mean
it's just it just helps everything and
you're able with that little bit of
silica because it's picking up so much
better even with the the micros and and
your beneficial bacteria is that like my
feeding program is a quarter of what
most people would think a quarter he's
saving 75% of his inputs if I optimize
the efficiency of this system with with
smart micro macro nutrient application
and living soils because I would say
that's one of the missing pieces I see
is there are the regenerative farmers
and then there are the salt based
farmers force feeding the plants as
opposed to activating microbiology to
deliver nutrients on the man I don't I
don't dislike salt based nutrient
programs
it's just 90 percent of the people that
I watch do it
over feed them they feed them to death
you know it's like they're they look
great through week seven or eight of you
know veg and then all of a sudden
they're burning tits they're you know
it's it just becomes horrible really
quickly and it's feeding them to death
it's loving them to death oh it's like
less is more
it's a former control system instead of
a biology control system right right you
want to activate the biology let's let's
find them in natural systems so you know
if you activate the biology get that
plant picking up its nutrients really
well and then use a feed program so
outdoors you know we did us some serious
tests on our soil to see what was in it
to begin with and what we can now leave
out of our feeding program what we had
to supplement later on so your your
plants in the ground
so yeah this year we're going into camp
and I got a lot to learn there cuz this
will be the first year row cropping it
directly into the ground you know we
have our soil test you know we have that
we will be using a salt based program
because it's efficient to feed but not
heavy dosages not getting carried away
we have seven strains that we're going
to be working this year on the hand side
on the hand side and you know going in
blind
I mean literally you know
I have found just like cannabis I expect
it to be just like cannabis the seed we
got isn't necessarily the seed they
advertise what are some of the strains
you're exploring and why so I would have
to get my list out but basically I got
two strains out of the Colorado market
I got a strain out of Kentucky I got two
strains out of Oregon
we got a strain out of Spain and we got
a strain out of Israel they're all the
Mubarak's your farm is where so it's in
Santa Paula we have 60 acres we're
putting into the ground in Santa Paula
Santa Paula just this side of Fillmore
in the Oxnard Valley Santa Rosa Santa
Paula Fillmore and so is the idea that
you have no idea what's going to respond
to that microclimate I have no idea
what's gonna respond so we're gonna try
or what the final tests are gonna be you
know with hemp we've got a maintain
that's ridiculous less than 0.3 right I
mean
yeah yeah it's this year we're growing
sixty acres and you had mentioned
biomimicry so like what are some
biomimicry concepts that are applied to
making soil well our case were by making
your by mimicking fire fire creates
biochar that's the natural mechanism to
regenerate soils so I have a question
can you a harvest biochar and help out
with like charcoal power plants and
stuff say more about that how would I
have what a harvest well you know in the
burning of charcoal you have you know
all of those carbon emissions that are
such a problem and if we could directly
harvest those back out because they're
not bad for growing you know like power
plants you know the things that are
coming off the smokestacks all of that
carbon and co2 that's being pumped
through the atmosphere you know how do
we go about harvesting that back well
I'm putting it directly into a soil and
there's a whole immersion industry
around direct air capture but you're
probably not yeah help yourself
you're probably going to use that carbon
not to create charcoal but to create
graphene batteries or roads right or
cement there's a bunch of emerging
industries that are going to repurpose
atmospheric carbon and do something
useful with it since you're rebranding a
problem molecule co2 into a solution
molecule whether it's for each other
bags whether it's for next-generation
cars I was just one of the thoughts I
had when I was playing with the with the
biochar for the first time this year was
I wonder you know because you know
because you know obviously fossil fuels
are with us for a while longer but if we
can figure out a way to make them not so
dirty and reclaim some of that carbon
yep absolutely
put it into the growth cycle it's a
win-win
unfortunately what most people are now
doing with that captured co2 they're
injecting into old oil wells to get more
oil out right that's the big market
right now for co2 I could I can see that
I can see that you know it's just one of
the thoughts I was having you know I
mean I was just in a discussion where a
guy's figured out how to make plastics
out of seashells which I thought was
amazing so you have to stack some stacks
and stacks of oyster shells can you
imagine making biochar out of hemp
residue well why not why not I mean we
have piles and piles and piles of stock
right now that we can't do anything with
I mean we don't yet have the empar c't
right there's not the processing
infrastructure problems yeah but you
still left your main your main outputs
gonna basically be oil no we don't have
that infrastructure yet you know so I
mean much as we'd like to Bale up the
stock and ship it somewhere and make a
dollar off of that that we don't really
have anywhere here set up are you
allowed to compost it on site
and so do you have sort of some sort of
composting strategy so you know our plan
actually it'll be pretty much the same
thing we did with all of our our stock
this year off the cannabis garden just
make a big pile light it on fire spread
those ashes and use it in our soil I
mean that's what we did so from a
biochar perspective would there be a way
to not light it on fire but to turn it
into biochar well it's not just carbon
though it's all these micronutrients as
well so the ash of a fire is all the
other nutrients besides carbon yeah it
becomes an awesome Pro - and just make
sure you do biochar as you heat it -
just before it does combust kind of like
you're not like bye we are almost making
it a pole yeah so this is here's a
diagram so this the axis here is
temperature this is the low temperature
this is high temperature the ideal
temperature is about 600 degrees see
where you create these highly irregular
surfaces with lots of surface area that
provide habitat for microbiology the
hotter it gets you get these ordered
sheets get graphene on this end it is
very irregular they're called fullerene
molecules and we think that's one of the
reasons why biochar is so stable because
of the irregular orientation of the
carbon rings themselves because the idea
I mean the idea is to like store carbon
in soils like draw it down and store it
and then do something useful with it and
designing the charcoal so it can be used
for Ag markets
but the first idea was just like this to
dry down carbon
not in the oil well but on the surface
well that's super cool that you're doing
firetruck thank you for doing that man
if there's any way we could help you
yeah well it's an experiment we did this
year the only thing I really found as a
problem this year is our soil was caught
you're like a soil chef so when you have
a recipe like what are you thinking
about as you build up a soil like you're
like okay I need this to give it air I
need this for the microbes I need this
for that like what's what goes into
creating a soil recipe so it's the
architecture of the soil to start with
the physics of the soil and it do what
it needs to do then it's the chemistry
the combined chemistry biology and you
optimize both of those for efficient
delivery of nutrients to plants I
actually have a question today that is
why did you leave paralyzed because we
feel like perlite in some ways is taking
up space where a root should be you
don't really need perlite you know
really helps with drainage you know and
getting that water to penetrate deep
into the soil because we have the short
and long fiber cocoa that really
provides that the air-filled porosity
you don't find it packs no no we really
don't
in fact we would prefer people to use
these than these just because this is a
renewable resource right I mean I
understand the bare light thing that you
know I mean even we should if you'd be
interested we'd be happy to you know
support a trial so we could show you how
this actually works you'd be interested
well yeah it's somebody give me your
card we'll talk about it as soon as we
get the plant because I actually have
240 pots that we haven't 240 260 gallon
ups we haven't filled yet I haven't
purchased dirt for the hoop houses in
place I'm just stalled because I know my
permit expires and you know I don't want
to invest in soil if I have no permit
kind of a tough spot because before you
could just do it because you're under
the radar yeah now that you've come out
you're not it's absolutely killing me
it's making me regret yeah I can imagine
in this you can't turn back the clock
you can't turn back the clock my wife
called me out for going legal you know
for doing it it's just like it'll just
be a nightmare and she's right she's
absolutely right for going legal
oh yeah she is just like she saw the
people in charge you know she saw that
you know we went through so much effort
to get permitting and then I like gave
up you came from the traditional mark I
came I've been doing that since 1986 so
talk to me about screens from the past
that you can't find a skunk wad true
skunk one the golf-ball indica nobody
has it anymore that's that one
the original mando purple call falling
because what's gone you saw there you
saw it coming out of Mendocino Ukiah at
that area
and it was just phenomenal just
absolutely phenomenal and it's gone you
know it disappeared in the early 90s
both ago both of those days the camp
raids were more effective than people
think they were I mean yeah a lot of
girls were left intact up there but a
lot of strains were lost a lot by just
attrition or by by bulk by both
crossbreeding the seeds you know
pollination that people didn't really
know where that pollen came from you
know we had some great sticky weed in
the late 80s early night where were you
going to talk about the SMP okey so I
still have that train I've had it for 27
years continuously clone but what's the
history of which it actually came in
through Point Mugu Naval Air Station in
a backpack from those old Navy SEALs
that we're working in Afghanistan that's
where it came that's where it came and
you got a cut and I got a cut I got a
bag of seeds directly out of there and
and what made that a standout because of
our purely affect it is the original PK
so sfv OG
its original name with pique you know
the pure coach and that is the original
FF s empty what's just a pain in the ass
to grow it was like an ivy plant it went
everywhere you know it was just compared
to like your Northern California indica
plants that were nice and in uniform and
bushy and you know grew up like this
this thing you switched it into in the
flower its initial stretch could be as
much as two or three feet in 11 12 14
days like maintaining a light height on
those was just like wow you know super
hard you know and and your bud structure
was nowhere it's close together that's
the end of us out of Northern California
you know it would be like a bud and then
a blank spot for eight or nine inches
another bud and then it was like an ivy
plant just going everywhere so getting
that plant to respond properly and get a
tight bud structure what's just really
really a tough tough play you know it
still it
oh yeah oh yeah what is your farm called
you know so mr. nice guy LLC is is our
farm in Santa Barbara is licensed from
half-baked yeah Chappell is a brand
ambassador exactly exactly yeah but the
soil building I'm a fan of worms kill
those worms in your soil but but if
you're growing in pots release worming
your forms and into the pots right into
the box both red and night crawlers
night crawlers will go deep red will
stay on top and they just and in terms
of like are you constantly like I think
of kind of the moisture level and soil
like you want to keep it in a bend you
don't want it to get super dry and then
overwater it like keep going blowing
passes like the band that the micro
right they don't want to live in a swamp
that's for sure
that's for sure you know so you know I
don't water to run off it's too wet it's
too much
but like we watered our pots every 10 or
14 days all through the offseason just
to keep the worms alive so the worms
were doing their thing and breeding and
growing and so you're leaving the soil
in those pots and what are you doing to
build the soil back up are you doing
anything or yes we turned it and letting
the worms go letting the worms do their
thing like I said this year because of
the biochar I think because of the
biochar the soil was a little bit hot
deep in deep in the soil it's not
because of the biochar I mean I think
that as I said char needs to be
activated it takes a couple years so I
guarantee you that certainly next year
you won't have that problem at all
we don't have any problem whatsoever so
you know it may be the worm gas things
that we've added in there but the church
is just a little bit hot we were hot
we're on this has enough nutrients for
six weeks in it right here I mean this
should be hot but it's not right so so
that was my one complaint this well one
of my complaints is our soil it's hot
yeah we were understand you don't want a
hot soil no definitely don't that's a
that's that's inefficient and it creates
stress on the plants it's unnecessary
so I'm looking forward to this year
because I know what calm down
and I know those that live release a
worm you know how big a green Gretna
door was the chart selfie you got was it
heterogeneous was it consistent you know
it's close to what we see here you know
maybe a little bit little bit thicker a
little bit coarser this is so you can
see it though this is really you can
feel it as well at the time we were
mixed in it was you know pretty awesome
you know I mean we're mixing an
old-school style with a bucket motor so
I'm just turning and turning and turning
and turning I love the fact you are
using worms because you're creating worm
castings so it's soy death to buy oh
that's ridiculous we just bought worms
and let them go and fed the hell out of
them and they do nothing but clean your
roots and take care of the soil and give
you love all in the soil you know so it
sounds like you've drank the kool-aid
around biomimicry natural but totally
make sense why waste the money right
waste of money plus you're really
championing it over general farming you
know and then you get all those little
tunnels that the water can freeze down
in and you know win-win-win air filled
porosity right well it's super exciting
I joined the conversation thank you so
much for doing what you're doing thank
you thank you and I'll give you a call
and we'll figure out how to get some
soil up we really see this as kind of a
transition soil like farmers who are
doing really well you have a situation
where we can pick it up by the dump
truck load we don't it's either in super
sacks or in bags because that's made
indoors we don't like using dump trucks
I'll be honest with you for pathogens we
just really want to make sure you get a
clean soil but we have four yard super
sacks and those can be in a dump truck
so yeah I mean that's just how we had so
I'll delivered out there was dump trucks
came up we mixed it
we actually mixed outside I told you old
school style bucket loaders and you did
you see any pathogenic behavior later
because of that see that's what we're
trying to control for so it's hard
outdoors it's really hard you know I've
had I liked indoors I like the control
of indoors
I prefer indoor controlled environment
agriculture yes I like is a huge huge
opportunity I've been a fan I've been at
it for a long time I'm really good at it
I understand the problems in be honest
this year we struggled outdoor you know
a little bit little bit you can go
backwards can't you I mean even though
you've you're legal you can still pivot
from oh yeah well we're working on
getting indoors permitted we just
haven't been successful yet you know and
that's where I prefer to be you know
it's just I applied I applied I applied
so I actually have a volatile license
out of clean city I have a distributor
license out of King City
I have retailed non storefront license
statewide out of King City
risking city got a two and a half hours
north of Santa Barbara okay so sevens
yeah up there by building stuff yeah so
further north so we'll use that as our
processing distribution center our first
big permitted growth in Mata Santa
Barbara we're trying for permits in
Santa Paula San Fernando Valley
for indoor operations are you part of
any growing Association so you know I
work with Justin a little bit but no
stated independent so like Ryan Martinez
it was the Edgar for jungleboy he was my
best friend since 16 I'd laugh because I
hadn't particularly gentlemen it was
funny
just the way the world works my wife and
I are up at a show in and Northern
California at the High Times event we
hit up the drum the breaks down I don't
give out aids very often when we're
judging weed so we walk in and I'm
standing there at the counter I'm like
honey check it out that is an A+ and so
is that and so is that she like looks at
me in shock she's like what those three
right I get the height bed yeah those
three right there are a pluses that
stuff over there is kind of a beat but
these three right here those are a
pluses those are solid solid genetics
right there so like four months later
I'm in another conversation with a
friend and he's like oh yeah do you know
the head girl for jungle boy system I
know no idea it's like it's Ryan
Martinez I just started laughing I'm
like had to be one of five people I know
okay add to be that I grew up with he
was a big grower right here in Malibu
and he helped me develop my program back
when we were 18 years old we worked
together you know like you know screwing
up plants feeding him to death
live and learn right this iteration so
it was so funny when I just died of
tears when and it just was like oh my
god what a small world call him up I'm
like hey dude
[Music]
right you had lost touch with him I'd
just yeah I've been in Montana growing
for seven years and you know he came up
actually when I set up my program in
Montana yeah cuz he was my best friend
that we just
they've gone gone our ways and doing our
thing and you know he got married and
had a kid and he was down here busy as
hell and I was up there just busy as
hell you know just living your life
right and we just you know a few highs
but not any real communication you know
and I just died of Tears what I'd like
had to be one of five people it was
either Ryan Martinez Marshall Davis
Kelly bellissima
you know who grew that our jungle boys
out of LA they wanted me to come on
board with them but they're their
culture isn't exactly my culture they
have a certain swagger you know where
I'm more of the low-key quiet farmer
yeah I don't play with anything white
I smoke weed what do you think of the
emergence of the plant medicines as a
viable life strategy like psilocybin and
like like like sighted to see the
research you know so being in the
medical industry for a long time and so
I jumped into the medical industry few
people 15 compliant right when it
happened in California in 97 so DC
collective and and a couple other
collectors in the valley you know I
worked with starting and in 2006 when
Montana went legal that's where my
family had moved to when I was 18 it's
like you know what let's do Montana so
we went up there and for seven years
eight years we really worked hard up
there Montana was a unique opportunity
because there there issuances medical
carts were so restrictive that the
people who got cards were truly similar
what you're doing in your agriculture
practices what we're championing is the
tip of the regenerative expir that will
influence the whole industry in the next
10 to 20 years yeah it'll be uh it's
something that needs to happen because
intense training of our water the
salting of our fields and I mean I suck
because I'm a farmer and I understand
salts and and it's easy and it's quick
and it's an instant fix and I get it
from both sides you know that yes using
them long term contaminates our soil but
I'm down to a quarter of what a normal
farmer would do you know and I mean I'm
still amusing alfalfa pellets and
it's another thing I'm using in my soil
so you know I'm creating a rich soil of
nutrient based solution you want to see
what's in our soil is it