go down the line so so right here we got
some Clementine which great even though
really high Mersin it's still a sativa
and keeps you going and focused with
really great pain relief with that
that's the climate time right there well
I mean we we've been growing these
strains just this one season trying
things out we're chilling we've switched
up our switched up our way to do these
things we're getting them from some of
the local legal nurseries
this year we're running hendrix stuff
we're running mother's know Charlie's
girl we run in blueberry muffin and so
do you kind of like pick what you're
gonna do next season based on what's
available or what you think the markets
gonna be interested in right well they
it's the kind of combination of what
what the markets gonna be interested in
we do know currently we need to hit
those high THC numbers to make sure that
it's easy to sell it's a silly game and
not really how I pick my own weed but it
is how I have to sell it Todd talk about
what you like to smoke oh it would be on
this table of
listen to you I mean we grow this wigger
this amazing Colombian gold Oaxacan gold
cross a couple years ago I want to get
that going again it was called savage
I'm here tonight I don't have any of
that here today no that was some really
great sativa but you know I like smoking
against sativa is mainly for the most
early half of the day so that I can
focus and work and so that Clementine
it's a great job with that and then this
Sour Diesel here that's really you know
nice focused and a totally different
flavor spectrum then they been the
Clementine was still good focus energy
how we were the entire visited with the
names pretty fresh and these are from
last you know September is the latest
you know so they you know they're not
super super fresh but they're at their
peak there's still you know they're
testing at twenty five percent twenty
four percent so just quickly talk about
what we were talking about before where
you're growing and why having
greenhouses like what having greenhouses
now allows you to do that you couldn't
do before right well so currently we're
using the light deprivation so we came
once the Sun Goes Down off the hill
we pulled tarps down over over the
plants and makes them thinks at
nighttime and that's the thing that like
an indoor scene you can have multiple
harvests through the year and we can
also bring it in early and before the
rains come and so then that gives us a
chance to use a microscope and really
live the trichomes and figure out where
you know
when they're at their most peak
perfection and bring it in that way
versus harvesting one versus raining you
know being like okay this is starting to
mold and this is gonna mold now so okay
it's time to harvest it and I did that
for a long time so you've reduced your
mold problem oh definitely really you
know in and we're really you know we're
we're getting on it now we're we're
inner planting other crops in there
we're talking about what crumber crops
here you dig each week well I mean we've
really been liking this clover we've
been growing it's a perennial clover and
but it's growing underneath the ganja
and so we can take and harvest that
feeds the soil mulch is everything out
we don't have to bring in any straw or
anything that's where's that coming from
does it have pesticides on it is it
gonna mess up you know our product so
it's just closing those loops and
keeping everything from on-site and that
yeah a perennial clover is definitely
part of that it breaks up pathogens and
all that because they don't it's just
not straight one type of plant we're
breaking that up there's the other types
of plant house raised beds or as a
sponsor it's not raised beds it's yeah
we're a little bit of a hill and so
they're across the the hill in a contour
fashion whether you're in the ground in
the ground oh cool awesome we visit up
in that area there
we're in the ground and we make
researching one another we're we've been
nurturing this soil it's a its no-till
it's all like I said there's that
perennial cover crop growing in in their
bed in our beds and so we just take and
replant in those same spots again we
have four greenhouses actually how many
oh Anthony
so it's 900 plants in each right
sorry 450 all right for 450 450 plants
in each green so you have generally
about 1,800 plants right per run and I
do two runs a while where this the both
runs around but yeah and that way it
gives us chance to have eight different
strains really easily and keep them all
separate and clean and and use onyx
about reading and developing a strain
that you guys want to be known for is
that you know that's in the long term
we're definitely we're gonna be planting
some different different plants it's
always interesting to see that how
something does in the in this greenhouse
situation versus what we used to do the
full long-term plant we grow those big
monster plants this is this is a whole
different game now I have a question for
you said you're in between Humboldt and
tree
yeah we're in Trinity talk about Trinity
a little bit because you know we don't
really hear you know it's treated it's
the Forgotten emerald that's what I know
totally you know it is the Emerald
triangle it is some of the really ideal
and there's just not as many folks out
in the Trinity and so that we kind of
get lost on the on the way side on that
but is it a tight community none the
Hoff well so we're actually in the
Humboldt community we're right there on
that border like I say so yeah we have
we have a lot of friends that are in
Trinity they come in Willow Creek is
their town too and so it yeah it's just
a beautiful community out there we've
been out there for 20 years now
and you know just trying to improve that
land we got pigs chickens goats you know
grow our name right it's all trying
trying to close those loops you know
trying to try to not have to import you
know anything really is the is the
long-term goal so we're just trying to
grow the cleanest flour we can and what
are your like pest management strategies
Yeah right no we so we bring in good
bugs there's one thing and we surround
our plants with various types of
supporting plants that will help keep
those good bugs around some of them oh
s--- good bugs that you this editorial
on they they thrive off a perennial
flower that doesn't die every year and a
lot of bad bugs are annual so we give a
perennial flower that that particular
bug likes or right and so if you want to
keep it out of the
marijuana's then it might be a host
plant for them but or a barrier plant
just keeps it like you do what you can
do in a organic way as a living thing
right right choice right train you know
cuz the like he was saying those bugs
are transitional especially as bedbugs
are here here for a moment and dawn and
if we can build those perennial cultures
where you know live in forests and
living in living surrounding structures
that are just helping support the best
way have you found that your loss to
insects has decreased over the years or
is any season different I mean you know
we haven't had any issues last couple
years knock on wood right we had some of
my to take a picture of like ladybugs
just crawling all over and yeah that was
nice and we've we've been yeah we had a
rest of my problem a few years ago
everyone happy everyone did everyone did
and so we just you know kept bringing in
you know good bugs until finally hit the
right one and you know then like say
bringing in then supporting plants to
help keep those alive and trying to just
build that ecosystem you know there's
three four of us right now fight oh you
know we've community with the plants up
definitely they're you know they're
they're this special medicine I you know
that's why I grow is because the ability
to provide this quality medicine and
it's earth conscious that's not
not using lights better than like having
to be cooled off in an artificial
environment and trying to keep it just
as natural as we can and I grow grow
what we can in the same quality as any
indoor a better in my opinion but you
know I the and you know the test results
are showing the same to its these are
some of these are in the twenty four
twenty five percent THC and plus a
couple percent terpenes and so now
you're down here in Southern California
Holly right but the land of this sort of
like outdoor bias right but it is it
changing
you know I mean I've always people come
look at the flower and they they don't
recognize this they don't as being
outdoor doesn't look like outdoor and
that's that's been my goal and we're
just we're different right well I have
this idea but you know we talk to them
right know they have this idea what's
good right
so aware I have a hard time with the
vernacular I kind of know what they're
doing that terpenes and whatnot yes
learning as we go
well it is exciting you know it's not
all about the THC Orion I mean and what
about the minor cannabinoids and all of
that you guys yeah you know we go to the
state test and you know it it does not
test for a whole you know there's only a
very short list of the the cannabinoids
that are being tested for and I really
could say yeah we had this gelato some
of the tests did but 17 somewhat tested
lower than that and it's really nice
flower it tastes great it covered with
crystals really nice looking yeah ya
know all those flowers are available
then those are probably the last ascetic
because they've got that low number but
yeah correctly ethylene is
there's two propane so that's for
anti-inflammatory the larger molecule
then the motion in limine so making its
bitten so like you feel like the effects
of no pain like it doesn't affect in you
you have an effect in your mind because
you have an absence of danger and that's
from the CB to you sure
which is what this is crippling is the
largest molecule it's the only terpene
right that is a CPG I think is what I
read today so educating myself in that
regard
mostly I think about finding a way to
get the most that we can in a healthy
way right so yeah what's the general we
don't want to be what we're capable of
excellent yes so
it's just that understanding relax so
we're learning everyday and responding
and spiraling up and it's like you
figured that like six strange is a good
number of strange for you guys to have
like you know what yeah so yeah that's
six to eight yeah somewhere in that
neighborhood I like that you know plus
you got a couple of little experimental
plants or whatever just just keep keep
that learning looking for that you know
special plant so what what are you
currently experimenting with you know
you I mean what just weeds right every
time so far way of growing stuff you
haven't right exactly right
we're going yeah Charlie's girl
Charlie's girl and Mack melon
[Music]
even though they say oh yeah it's gonna
be different it's gonna be different in
every farm it's gonna be you know the
terpene profiles are different from the
same clone grow in a different place the
weather is different you know like these
numbers don't need anything if I don't
know that on average we're right where
we should be or right where or not like
it just it just gives you a volley a
percentage of what is in that particular
one and then you kind of weigh in
measure oh what's a smells like pepper
well that's a big yeah yeah we we don't
think that's really where the exciting
future is with with you know cannabis
grown as a mono crop you know we're like
every result is exactly the same I don't
know a cigarette or something no no you
know you'd be more like open oh you know
there are certain years are better than
others for whatever reason ya know the
weather you know when it's that time and
that's gonna make a huge difference we
had some crazy weather is last year we
had rainstorms when you know I wanted to
be harvesting this this year coming up
so I'm like well shit that would have
been fine for the last 18 years but last
year no no that wouldn't have been okay
did you have any green house last year
we're puttin green houses up last year
and so we had some temporary green
houses right so this is all future
happiness right oh well we we've grown
with the green houses they were just the
temporary and you know getting that and
we did get the permanent ones up enough
to do a crop and a half last year but it
was only we did you get them from a
company did you
you know explain to us what you're about
to light electric electric electric
sucking in butane yeah I don't think so
I was thinking you can have a lower
temperature so people could
please tell us the story about your farm
well we've been growing up in the
Emerald triangle there for almost 20
years organically we just take now in
the in this legal market and that we're
doing a light depth and able to bring it
in when the weather is just perfect
and be able to bring in the indoor
quality while growing it outdoor and the
full Sun needs in the most
environmentally conscious met the best
of both worlds yes exactly
yeah we're kind of kids come by it's an
interesting combination of almost of the
indoor and the outdoor in a way where
they you know we can that do multiple
harvests a lot of people are going for
three or four harvests I've chosen to as
I can do that with the least
environmental impact and not need much
lights using mainly the Sun you know
whereas some folks or I try to push a
little further you got to use a little
more light how many different range
eight strains eight strands eaters or
the current number or looking for trying
one per greenhouse and you know it's
this big is the goal common example the
table say you know check out some of the
new strains see if any of them are worth
keeping we ran this 398 bubba kush this
last year and we're gonna run that again
that was
oh absolutely fire oh man it's I mean
it's awesome 25 almost 25 percent so
yeah we saved that for the evening this
is a some of our hybrid and some of our
sativas like smoking though from the day
you know still work and not get all
distracted what's coming I mean we're
running some Charlie's girls for
Mother's Milk blueberry muffin I lost
another one you know
run run some nice new strains this year
we're also gonna be running the pre 90
Bubba we're gonna maybe run some of the
sour dee if we can get some more of that
again so spirit farm calm
it was really appreciated looking
forward to chart your course and possums
around years to come
thank you so where were we I just filmed
his whole thing and I was like I'll just
post that - thanks for cutting right now
so the conversation don't mind us
oh shit yeah but so yeah and then I'm we
got that pre 98 bubba kush as oh my god
that's that's the killer in the evening
strain just like sit down and finish
yeah I had smoked that purple punch in
the evening that the one won't knock my
ass out but start hitting that fucking
pre 90 Bubba crushed a little too early
and I was i sat down on the bed the
other night and just what Pam was out in
seconds of the other shit so what about
taking some of your top score like resin
or rosin you done any other have we've
made a little bit of at home and we have
done coat collaboration with some
friends hella dink they're doing a
little collaboration with us yeah yeah
cool that one's empty haha oops we
smoked that one let's see here we go
and the Terps on that you got to give
that a smell it's really amazing yeah
they really did a beautiful job
I always thought hash had that one note
hash and this is like fruit right yeah
and it's so fruity and tasty and is like
what this is ash endless endless
oh yeah it's it's so amazing I mean well
look where we've come in just few years
to where we expect them to be 20 plus
percent THC and like that right that was
fucking that was the pinnacle you know
15 years ago you see there's this new
Washington State law they're considering
that old cap the THC for all
concentrates and everything at it's
something like ridiculous like 10 I
that's not you anymore
wipe out all the every patient right
yeah that's ridiculous because some of
us have a higher tolerance know there's
I would put myself in that bucket
I see the whole proceedings where
patients have come in and started crying
at the idea that they won't have access
to not just you know the medicine but
the type of medicine that they know i we
you know we're it's unfortunate like
this whole legalization thing is
definitely almost almost broken us
financially but at the same time I want
this to be an organic natural evolution
I'm not looking for outside money I'm
just all in-house and so you know it's a
little shoestring at times but we're
making it and just trying to
and it counts right ya know the county
has been helpful
so sometimes definitions of words change
like right in the spirit of things like
what do we need to do and then worth
right with things that they did and
didn't know and this is humble Trinity
actually yeah yeah the guys we've been
working with the men because he had to
spend so much time educating himself and
becoming aware and he's quite aware
however like had a legal right well in
how to do the legal hoops wait we got
right bigger what you could you could
get away with anything on the
pharmaceutical level that we're not
we're being regulated so much harder oh
my god I hate to raise that a the word
but metric you know we've actually right
right now we're using it now and the the
we have one person that that's what she
does is metric and so she's been doing a
good job we're not doing job more than
everyone else's
you guys draw straws to see you guys we
know what we know where the tachi the
weights like we have a cute lady this
thing and do I do like so that means
right we're just making all this plastic
tags each plants got its own tag and
when we're growing a bed of this plant
all right we can label this bed all
right and that's one label versus now
there's 150 plants in that bed so that's
150 tags
oh where does the tag go from a dead
plant usable right well the number well
they are digital they're all they got
you know barcode and all this but then
but they because they don't reuse you
they won't reissue that same number you
know because they want that number two
now is done
all right yeah we're not whaling it man
what about light the labs like if you
guys are far from so the labs know so I
so we don't have any problems with
pesticides or anything because we are so
far out and we keep our stuff with clean
and we know that it's then it's another
selling point for the brand right right
well it's it's super water well we have
nice clean water we use the rain
catchment and we're all off the natural
yeah yeah that's why that's what our
water sources is rainwater catch hard in
the pond yeah no it's regenerative
farming where we were up up for the
region of farming award doesn't leave it
better than exactly we're trying we're
improving the property and trying to
build what we've from what we had which
was abused by some great farming and
trying to regenerate it into the most
productive land we can make the pigs new
grand
takes a concept of land and a
blackberries like mad which is very
beneficial to pigs
we're on 20 cent makers it's huge but we
really don't know we live on it we built
a straw bale house that we live in
actually I saw you taught you're off the
grid or you're well so we have a little
bit of grid power up on one end of
property and then the other end of the
property is off grid so we're working on
it we're gonna do a little great inner
tie to take the rest of the end of the
last bit I mean it's not too hard for us
there was a few buildings that had nice
metal roofs already and so we just got
her got her them over into a pond and it
just happened to be that guy some pole
frog her like we yeah there's totally
bullfrogs and we gotta do something
about that
right they haven't said anything yet
all right I know they're anti invasive
species don't they eat insects they do
eat insects but they also eat it exactly
they push it out so ya know that's
that's on the list we haven't gotten
there yet you didn't realize that yeah
that's on the list
yeah so how you just talk about this a
little bit bowing down we're having fun
it's the first time you've done it yeah
we've done some of these events before
this one's the best so far I believe and
we had good well I I did grow up down
here not not quite in West Hollywood but
a Glendale so not far at all not far at
all you know just can't it's you know
it's nice to come back and you know been
because I've been hanging out in the
hills for 20 years gonna be a girl
you know somewhat gorilla growing in the
hills and now now we're out and it's out
in the open and you know yes we can
claim yes now we can we can farm this
piece of property a little bit and then
turn it into you know help support you
know five six you know small families on
our property and grow this really fine
cannabis and you know I have some people
come out camping glamping we call it we
have set up these bail tents and we have
people come out to our farm float down
the river his picture of our farm come
up in the sky yeah tell me how amazing
it would be if every farmer could you
know
people come onto the farms yeah we're at
this point we're just hoping were true
but we've done everything we can we're
all legal but caring you know we're been
well with rose received by shops high
tides been taken over our distribution
down here and big trees has been taking
it up north and it's just high died
distro they also have Fiddler's greens
or these guys right around the corner
[Music]
everyone looks at our product and
assumes it's indoor and just we're
trying to maintain that quality
[Music]
Cannabis sports competition