can one of you be our hand
can i ask you for a favor can you be our
hand clap model can you just put your
hands right here and make a big clap
amazing thank you
[Music]
all right walter walter is going to roll
us a joint
all right and this is dealer's choice
so walter is going for what he grew
at home this past season correct right
yeah we grew this in
our huge culture bed brand new huge
culture bed
uh almost no inputs at all really stoked
on how it came out it uh
placed seventh in the emerald cup so
we're super super proud of it and what
cut is it
it was a fruity pebbles og seedling
um which i've heard tends to be a rather
terpene dominant
strain and that this is no exception
there yeah um
and who gave it to you um
you know it was a freebie seed i think
from
equinox seeds i believe okay yeah i'd
have to double check on the
exact detail on that one but i'm pretty
sure that's where it came it was
it was just you know it came with
another pack of seeds
what are your expectations for like year
two and three of the same hugelbed
oh i think uh it's like you're one kind
of like
get it going and then like your highest
hopes are for
year like three probably but so one of
the things we did to
uh kind of jump start our eagle beds is
we used a lot of wood that was already
starting to decay a little bit you know
usually like the inner two-thirds is
still good and solid
but just outer bit still uh decomposing
already
and so it has uh those mycelium networks
running a lot quicker
and so my experience has been those
first year hugo's kick butt
and uh we've got we got some huge
culture beds now that are three and four
years old that
they're they're raging strong still um i
couldn't say they're really better or
worse
than they were that first year but i
have heard a fair number of people that
have had
you know it require a lot of compost and
stuff those first couple of years
uh because probably not using the
decomposed wood let's say
year seven or whatever when everything's
totally broken down like
are you moving on from that hugo bed are
you loving it
and still using it as just regular soil
that's very
nutrient rich right so you know that's
something to be
to be determined a bit you know i'm
fairly new to the human culture thing
one one thing we've heard is that you
can kind of put wood in from the side a
bit
uh and that's what i'm doing with some
of my
20 year old soil because i don't want to
dig it up
and flip it uh it's it's been where it's
been and we've been you know growing
there for a long time
so we're uh we're on a little bit of
hillside so we're just infilling on the
edges
with uh with a little bit of
wood to to add you know that huge
culture effect to it
by the way do you want stronger winds
when you're trying to roll a joint
outside
you know i'd have to say that normally
stronger winds when rolling a joint or
not
or in general when even doing an event
like this
stronger winds are not the preference
and this is the wedding cake you guys
did last season
right and what's this one that one's the
mother's milk
yeah and the macmelon in the next jar
and then there's some blueberry muffin
over there too
and the papers are challenging today
not just the rolling papers all the
papers
this is the walter technique right
you know the goal is to get as much weed
in as small of a paper as possible so
otherwise you have what i'm
what i consider an improper balance of
paper to weed
yeah so you got to minimize the amount
of paper
maximized and what type of paper do you
like to use personally
so i you know i enjoy the raw organics
and the elements uh
clubs i really like um
anything that's you know clean enough um
you know and thin
it's gotta be thin it's gotta be clean i
used to use just the clubs the
without glue but uh at this point
they only are making the smaller papers
so
i can't roll uh i can't roll a proper
grower joint with that
you know just a little and so tell me
about the smoke for this one
what do you like about it so this is a
the terpenoline dominant is less than 10
of the flour out there uh according to a
couple of labs
uh and it's it is that really focused
daytime sativa
type of flower um so you know if you've
got a meeting to go to but you know you
still need to take care of your head
if i have like sort of a hundred seed
packs to pack
up i will be focused on the task right
exactly this is not a
right because so this mother's milk
great sativa also
not so focusy though it's like it's on
the hybridy end of
sativa for sure this is just this is as
uh
as sativa as i've smoked in a long time
so we're really stoked
uh fruity pebbles og did not sound to me
like
sativa i sound like og and fruity
pebbles i don't know
i wasn't expecting this out of it so you
never know though what
what seeds will do and you never know
maybe somebody mislabeled a jar
somewhere
it happens to the best of us here's your
doobie
well thank you yeah it's exciting
all right let's uh i wish we could sit
in this car
i believe he probably could think anyone
would give me a hard time if i
it's his car right there uh back to us
flavor x shirt there yeah
should we ask him
is this your car yes it is could we sit
in it and smoke a joint
i mean if you as long as flavors in that
video
what's that still as long as the flavor
branding is in that video i will get the
flame brandy
yeah let's do it all right walter you
want to come sit with me i will i will
all right so we will this is our sponsor
for the
joint smoking
[Music]
all right we're gonna go for a cruise
here i'll let you fire that up
all right i trust you as a
man in a in a reclusive area is not uh
carrying coronavirus right now wow this
is this is a ride
i feel like i'm getting on the ground oh
yeah they say they make an electric one
that's what i want to check out what it
what kind of car is it
bander hall there you go that's what it
says on the wheels too
i need a bit oh cool it is a stair all
right there we go yeah that's
but there's no uh there's no
flash nope you know i think clutch has
gone out of style
that is confusing though but that would
imply that it's like a modern built
it is modern built okay very modern
built
it would be amazing if we both had a
little cup holder right here with water
bam i don't see a cup holder
and i have to say even for for two
people we're cozy
i'm looking around to see if i spot new
water
water i've got some water over yonders
it's not within reach though technically
all right so we could drive over there
when that guy's not looking this is
fucking windy the wind yeah
i could not imagine being jody playing
golf right now and not hating my like
nothing makes you hate your golf
abilities more than wind
all right see i don't win or win enough
i don't golf enough to know about the
wind
although you know i frisbee golf
sometimes so
not very often but it happens
so what do you think about the flavor of
that one
i like it me too
often that's my abnormal thing
you don't see any water anywhere to you
[Music]
watch out for that phone on the corner
there all right so give me your
assessment of uh
where the california market is right now
are you sad
are you happy are you optimistic oh i'm
totally optimistic
i feel like california market is a 13
year old boy
running into the liquor store and
grabbing the airport clear
i'm good thank you you are amazing
no that's that's where i think the
market's at it's a 13 year old boy going
well i get every clear i'm going to get
really really messed up really quick
um and you know a couple years maybe
we'll get a little more mature and we'll
move on some craft beers
and then even a couple years later we'll
be on to the fine wines
and once we get to the fine wines and
you know what there's some of us that
are there already
right you're enjoying fine flavors you
know it
there's there's there's those of us that
are are in the know already
and we have to find find those you know
make those connections
they have to find are we there's so much
noise and and it's just so new they like
you know it's going to take some time
for this dust to settle
i guess the other the other part of it
though is like can the craft farmers
survive until
that time when like even the other part
would be when you can sell
globally right so i mean
there we we do have some advantages
as the craft farmer some of us
uh have been doing this for 20 years
these new farms they don't have 20 years
under their belt
they um but they were trying to they got
a lot of money
but they're trying to go from from you
know zero to run in a marathon
without having to run the 5k first
without having fucking graduated from
the 5k
and keep moving you know so
yeah this that's where that's where
we're at and uh
i think so we've got some advantages
there and yeah we can't compete with
them on mids
they're going to kill it they're going
to crush the mids market
very comfortable
it is strong but i'll be focused on that
drive focus
clear in my car
when they make an electric or like they
say
they say he said they make one when i
can afford one yeah
that might when i can afford one and
they haven't let that be a badass
fuck yeah that thing would be fast as
fuck too this thing is
he said it weighs under a thousand
pounds thing must squirt out and go it's
got a four cylinder
although not quite a highway car well
you know
instead it goes 140 that'll that'll get
you on the highway
yeah then you get hit by like the suv
and
yeah no there's those things too
yeah yeah no i'm really stoked of the
strain it's really
tasty pungent
be happier with the coming seventh of
them so then
would that be something you'll now put
in the commercial but yeah yeah yeah
yep so we we uh we had some seeds of it
and we're growing those out on the
commercial side of it and then are you
fino hunting too
yeah yeah so you're like this is really
good but i'm gonna see if i can push it
and even better
i've got well so i've got one that i
just i pheno hunted out
but i don't know i haven't pheno hunted
it in the light dub yet
but so we know that in in outdoor it'll
do a
25 thc and it'll do uh
almost four percent terps so i've got
high hopes for it
um and it was dense and super nice so
i got you know it was epic
i'm excited to smoke what comes next
like yeah
well we have a couple other new strains
coming out too that we're really excited
about
i ran some uh burmese mimosas
last year that uh fino hunted out a
couple of
and i'm gonna keep going on the fina
hunt but the flavor
i think you know i'm hoping it'll it'll
cross that 20 thc number because the
teenagers in this
13 year old market are grabbing that 20
thc and they're like the retailers won't
won't buy
the lower stuff it's odd too because
it's like a vicious
circle of like a negative feedback well
and and here's the thing is
leafly did an article where 60-something
percent
of the consumers said they wanted less
than 20 percent
but those aren't the loud guys coming in
the end of the place those are the
old-timers going in and looking and
reading the labels
and the young kid comes in i want the
stuff with what's a 100
thc and that's what they're paying
attention to and so i feel like there
actually is more of a market
we actually did have to put some lower
thc stuff on the market
and and we have a hard time getting it
into a dispensary but once it's in
that one develops a fan fan base because
there isn't that much low thc stuff on
the market
not everybody wants to get ripped out of
their gourd on one hit
some folks would maybe even like take
the second hit before they get ripped
out of their gourd
and some people don't even want to get
ripped out of their gourd it's crazy
right we're all different we're all
looking for a different thing and a
different
you know different tolerance levels and
all that and we're
just lumping everyone into a couple
categories
so you're looking forward to the choir i
am i am
no it's just you know we got we got to
get that consumer education is
is the key that's that's what i think is
amazing about what you're doing is
uh that's what i try to do like it's
it's like
that that's why the whole event thing
where like i want to smoke la people
out with like amazing outdoor norcal
weeds and just be like what do you all
think because that's what we're doing
yeah yeah that's why i do these
these events that's why i for me it's
worth it making it here and they're like
oh yeah that's outdoor
outdoor sun grown organic and like
i really think that a lot of people have
been buying
you know whatever what came out of
humboldt and the emerald triangle
trinity mendocino whatever came out of
there that was really nice and dense
outdoor it didn't get sold as outdoor
when it got to the
buyer they were buying it as indoor
because it looked nice
and it could pass and you know i mean i
know they're changing the name three
times
you know like it wouldn't even stay
in like it wouldn't stay the same name
as i'm selling it to the first guy
he'd be like no no i'm calling this this
and this this like what but it
is what i said on the bag like no no
all right so i don't know there's some
great things about legalization for sure
and uh one of the things is we can come
out of the indoor closet
and we can grow in the full sun um
kind of make hurts my stomach when i see
all these inversions smoke people out
fuck yeah you know i love giving away
weed
um you know a little personal share
stuff here and there and
and turn people on to uh what what it's
all about
because it is that sun growing
is the answer we can do it
regeneratively instead of killing the
planet
and that's super important you know i
want a place for my kid
i think that's pretty important those
are all
good goals to have in life i support i
believe in everyone yeah yeah
right on right on
this thing's meant to go faster than
this
i like it's like that i don't i forgot i
have sunglasses
oh fuck yeah me too we're sitting in the
sun now
we had a little umbrella
i think the umbrella at 140 miles an
hour would be hard to hold onto
that's my guess yeah because i would
my legs would not stay this pale
they would have a hard time staying that
pail i keep from this pail by being
upright
and then there's not a shadow or there's
a shadow yeah yeah that's not
that's how we say that it's crazy to
think that people used to race
like uh like old car races and cars like
this with like the
like pilot goggles
how's it going like the le mans and
stuff
like that and that car like the skinny
ass wheels and shit
yeah please do
you can open a jar and grab a nugget too
if you want
really i just said that it gets better
wait
it gets better
well it depends on which one you like
better
i love that mother's milk i love that
mac melon
and the wedding's gonna give you a
massage after that it just keeps getting
better
he's like i just came for the free
frisbee and i got weed and a massage
all right i'm hot fuck yeah me too
well thank you for that yeah and uh
thanks for doing what you do i really
appreciate the you know
help getting the word out about the the
emerald triangle
sun-grown love and that you know we can
do this in an
environmentally responsible way i think
those are super
super important to me too i agree
ah
now i'm trying to think when's the next
time you guys are i want to try to get
up there but i
right i have like two little kids and
another one on the way
yeah all right it's our personal
photographer
he's the weed con photographer that's
what i was guessing
all right i'm sweltering high yeah this
car needs to move faster
so i'm gonna head home
[Applause]
right on so you should grab that uh box
[Music]
yeah
typically but there's a lot of genetics
out there all right