all right well we're here with walter
and judy from soul spirit farms and um
we're doing a farm interview today so
let's get started with some questions
for them
so can you tell us about your background
with cannabis and how you got started
uh yeah i started uh
using cannabis as medicine when i
injured my back in
92.
i found it was the only thing that
really
took care of my pain and also you know
was it did a better job than the
pharmaceuticals and i didn't like the
pharmaceuticals
so yeah
that was the that was that was what
started it yeah that was that was my my
intro 92 92 and you started farming at
that point
no i started farming pretty shortly
after we went uh
i met judy and uh when when jerry garcia
died and
we started uh
touring around the country
and went into louisiana and there was no
flower there and it was really bad and
uh i got to
you know i need it
it really you know it makes me
functional
and so
i sat down read the growers guide from
cover to cover and went to the hardware
store and bought some lights and classic
yeah yeah right it was all in the
hardware store at that point yeah
not in baton rouge louisiana yeah uh not
in 96. like 150 watt metal halide street
lights porch light porch lights yeah a
couple of porch lights uh combined them
into a single housing and yeah yeah
definitely
and then you know had a couple of seeds
in a jar like it was
just luckily i would save some seeds at
one point and that experience of taking
that
you know inanimate object or seemingly
inanimate object
and then
a couple of months later being able to
share
[Music]
super tasty homegrown loving medicine
with did it turn out what the flower's
all right the flower feet it was fluffy
and whatever it wasn't perfect but it
was it was really good kind buds in
baton rouge louisiana in 96. which uh
yeah
there was no hiding it i i'd share a
little bit with somebody and they'd call
me out in seconds you know they like
where did this come from yeah
there was no no
that was just that
i fell in love at that moment with the
whole experience of it every part of it
so it's like for you farming cannabis is
about the medicine and the experience
yeah yeah that sharing that medicine
yeah with people and being able to help
other people out like that is special
too for sure
and yeah needing it myself
yeah yeah amazing so um
tell us about your farm like what what's
going on with soul spirit how long have
you guys been in operation right well so
we've been farming out there for 20
years now um years 20 years
no till the whole time
um
i we have a permaculture background uh
took some courses
previous to even buying land and that
helped with the search of like okay we
need some good sunlight we need you know
be efficient you know with things right
we have two wheel drive access to our
farm we have uh gravity water we have
you know yeah all these little things
that make it a pretty good little spot
and um
so we've been like i said practicing
no-till for 20 years in this in this one
area where we're farming the cannabis
there and just working on
reducing our inputs the whole time never
have
never have brought in the heavy
equipment and and you know flattened or
or graded or anything so we're in the
true native soil yeah it's a true
permaculture-like experience i've been
following you guys for a while now and
you guys really are a shining example
for this model of permaculture type
systems you guys are dragonfly earth
medicine certified is that right yes
and sun and earth certified yeah i mean
because you guys are the one farm that i
know of that actually uses animal
husbandry is sort of connected with
the cult the the farming practices that
i in willow creek
is one of the few that do that so i i
agree
it's definitely not not the uh everyday
farm yeah we do we do try and you know
like i said everything we can to reduce
those inputs and all the ways we uh
gather some leaves out of our forest and
you know right now we have these uh this
problem with um
too much small brush and trees in our
forest uh from previous logging and and
bad management and so using that
material to
build our soil and so then we don't have
to go out
to
you know somewhere else to you guys in
mulch yeah yeah
heavy heavy mulch heavy multi yeah yeah
yeah heavy mulching is is one of my
main you guys have like a chipper i've
always struggled with like large-scale
mulching right now and and uh you know
so previous to having good access to a
chipper we used a lot of the forest leaf
and stuff like that and uh you know we
would buy some organic rice straw or
something like that or whatever to
supplement just you know trying to buy
things from local locally produced but
um
we now uh are working with the the
willow creek fire safe council oh and
chip in yeah so i have access to their
chip
oh my god so yeah i'm using that to uh
to help out with the forest area around
us and at the meantime we get to win
when we put some of those chips on our
own i think you know
actually we both ended up in humble
originally
as environmental activists like when we
first
came through it was right during redwood
summer and there was a lot of uh
activism direct action going on trying
to save the old growth redwoods and so
once we kind of decided that we wanted a
homestead of our own i mean that's the
perspective that we came to this all
from
that's our background and what's
important to us is is living sustainably
working in concert with the land and
that is also how we go about
farming cannabis because it is
ultimately the most important thing
that's an expression of our activism is
is this farm this homestead and all that
and to be able to share that with people
is super important to us because i'm
slowing the flowers it's not it's not
about hiding anything it's it's about
like let's let's be regenerative yeah
let's um let's build this let's
sequester carbon as much as we can and
you know make it different so you talked
about using mulch and and leaf
from the forest you guys have any other
interesting
methodologies that you uh work with you
know i mean i don't know we're dabbling
in a little this and a little that for
sure and trying trying to find you know
what is what is the most regenerative
we're working with you know so those
those mulch piles uh
naturally give us those indigenous
microorganisms right we can put that
pile of uh wood chips in the forest and
and use it like a rice box oh sure it's
like imo right right right right now
it's your own version of it right so
instead of doing that rice all that well
i have a couple of yards of
over here and a couple of yards over
here and a couple years over there just
scaled up right and so then i can just
mix those chips in and then we can
spread those out and now we would use an
imo on our thing and
do you have any um opinion do you know
if any types of wood work better do you
have like hardwoods that work better so
i mean for me it's what's local is super
important right and
you do want you know i don't think it
wouldn't be good to be all
um like doug fur yeah right that would
be a little bit much probably but as a
little bit for a little bit of pine in
there but you know as long as you can
let it sit for a while
and and let it start decomposing let
that mycelium start running through that
pile
it's really not too much of a problem
and if you can chip in the leaves with
it then that helps with that you know
and not be such a because it's carbon so
it's it's acts like a carbon filter and
it grabs onto things right and so at
first it can lock up some nutrients if
it is just
wood chips but this is whole tree chips
and brush and all that right already
pre-decomposing well and then so then
yeah we run it through with all those
material and then yeah then let it
pre-decompose some and then that really
you know yeah that gets it all going
yeah and and it really makes it so that
their
any of those problems should should you
know yeah let your nose know that that's
you know that's that's going to smell
that pile and make sure it it's got that
you know earthy yummy smell right
yeah if it smells super pungent like a
crazy walnut whatever sort of or you
know i'd be a little wary of that you
know but and then if you mix it too you
know so our we have you know when we're
mulching those trees it's madrone it's
doug fur it's tan oak it's all that
and you know yeah and it all it all
becomes good love in a while that's
amazing that's really interesting thanks
for that info that's amazing um
so as far as you know they always say
that growing is half the battle and
harvesting and drying is
another half of the battle for
preservation do you guys have any
you know have you have you dialed that
in do you have any you know techniques
you like to for your flowers that make
your flowers well so we do a couple of
things i think that help for sure is one
thing is we're
we're all right there on site close by
so the
there's no hauling totes of weed halfway
across the country or whatever in the
back of a truck um
it's just hand carried to the drying
room and so that reduces impacts and all
that i like to not feel overfill my you
know just be careful and appreciative of
it i always cringe when i see the
people on top of a ladder throwing their
nuggets down into a bin i'm like no no
no there's trichomes on there you know
let's let's keep those right because to
me it's it's all sacred medicine and i
don't have like
the special jar here and here that's
what i'm gonna save for myself and or
what no it's all special it's all you
know and so i want to treat it all that
way so yeah like we do that we
we do light depth and so that gives us
the ability to stagger our harvest
and so that gives us the ability to dry
for a little longer dry cure you know
take that and slow that process down
yeah that's that's what we do nice too
often just a nice low temp and all that
i think is is super key to not
losing your terpenes and that's i mean
that's one of the
major differences too as far as like if
you're talking craft cannabis versus
mass produced is someone who's trying to
squeeze every little bit of profit out
of it is gonna speed those processes up
and ultimately
things are lost when you do that so to
really create craft cannabis you take
your time you wait it's like well does
this cultivar take you know 10 days in
the drying room to be at its fullest
expression or you know is it
you know maybe it's 12 maybe one year
even the same thing is 10 days but the
next year something's different and now
it's but you have you can't you have to
do what you're doing based on what the
plant
is doing you can't have it sunset
regimen in your head or on paper and be
like forcing your will upon the whole
system it's about listening and smelling
and using your senses to figure out when
something's ready and go in with that
right and letting those plants finish
yes all good things to those who might
be in a hurry to you know harvest that
because you know oh
you know you gotta kind of wait that's
right well speaking of waiting we've
been waiting i've been waiting to check
out some of these flowers here
can we see what the three samples are
you brought yeah we brought this soul
shine which
i think it's a
it's a pretty special uh
really
refreshing um pretty loud yeah yeah it's
a terpenoline dominant which is a one of
the rare uh terpenes to have dominant in
your in your flower and a little bit
like a train wreck
right yeah which is true
yeah yeah train wreck
yeah jack it's got that sort of yeah
some of those characteristics to it
which
a lot of people think of as pining but
it's it's another terpene that is in a
pine tree
so it does have that that piney right
love all the pine turtles yeah so it
doesn't have much pinene but it had had
a really good amount of terpenoline and
and uh well-rounded um
i know it's like not the proper term to
use anymore but indica or sativa right
right right it's sativa it's activating
yes yes yes it's a good good breakfast
focus like you got to go to that meeting
and and maintain your focus but it's
also still potent it uh
it tests well amazing yeah
amazing product
all right let's see round two round two
well
this one here came out just
just glorious uh looked amazing as the
white rice the white runts yeah
nice nose on it uh just really special
all together i was really impressed with
with that
plant all together now yeah i've been
hearing some really good things about it
yeah i've been breeding with it a little
bit
yeah it's a good set of genetics yeah no
it worked it worked but we ran the other
the
ones without the white in front of it
just right right just right i think it's
all the same parent just different
phenos of the same uh correct yeah
that's what i
know it is i like this pinot better yeah
it worked better for our yeah you can
tell it's a beautiful flower oh yeah
like you've got some permanent and it
checks all the boxes this is a good one
for converting people who think they
only like indoor right right i mean this
looks like yeah no and that's always one
one of my favorite things to do is to go
down to a place like la and pop jars out
and be able to you know show people once
they come out oh man really fire indoor
i'm like no no
you might have been buying it as indoor
for the last 20 years but it's not check
the technique
i love that about kind of the like
regenerative cannabis and permaculture
community they just
they produce quality of flowers that are
really comparable to some really
high-grade cannabis and it's just all
about the
the biology i believe
the highest grade i mean there's nowhere
you're going to get you know um
three three per less percent terpenes
and all that without the sun and the
earth now that's one i haven't smelled
in a while headband yeah yeah i think i
grew it like 10 years ago and i just
haven't seen it around very right now i
haven't been around it that's one of the
things too is we liked you know for me
more important than
that thc number is well how is it how's
the effect
yeah right because i found that that
doesn't correlate very well with the thc
number that's one that doesn't tend to
test over 20 even so it's hardly
marketable right but yeah you tell
people headband and like yeah that's the
that's the jar that gets hit the hardest
at the at the emerald cup vents or
something like that right because oh my
gosh you know and and it does it's you
know it smells amazing
you know what terpenes these are this is
dominant in i believe that's
caryophyllene dominant yeah it's the
it's that
yeah to me it it really kind of reminds
me of uh
an oil refinery
we lived in louisiana right for a little
bit yeah yeah he's got that let's go oh
my gosh talk about gasps
yeah i know it's a classic i love the
headband and
the og well and it's important for
people to keep the classics growing yeah
right because if we don't if we lose all
the stuff that tests you know around
20 or even lower
it will be gone you know and we may
discover like oh wow there was
properties in that that
healed crohn's disease or something who
knows yes
we'll lose it right if we get so focused
on
these high thc producing cultivars that
that there is a risk you know and and
it's so tempting to go down that road
like well if they all finished in eight
weeks
right yeah well but then you're limited
to
right and that doesn't yeah that doesn't
that doesn't please me
right i'm you know i'm not pleased i'm
that daytime activating sativa you know
i'm farming i'm working i i want to be
awake and focused uh i don't find i need
that knockout
variety except to knock myself out at
the end of the day maybe right yeah and
so i do mostly smoke you know like a
sour diesel is another we grew and i
just love it and you know i came out you
know close to four percent terps and
just
you know
super fire and you know like that's
that's but it takes a long time to
flower and so it's not on very many
menus now i didn't bring that you guys
want to talk about where you can find
your products or is that yeah
not right right well you know it's uh
that's a challenge we're trying to get
out into more more stores for sure
that's always uh as a heart hard thing
is without a page marketing but
sebastian poole yeah um they have
[Music]
maybe not all of these in particular but
they have several of our different
cultivars and they're a really huge
supporter of small regions
so they're amazing amazing yeah so
support that those types of businesses
is what we need to spend our money with
yeah yeah because the retailers who are
going out of their way to support small
regenerative farms
if people go and support them then maybe
others will think oh you know that is
actually like a it's worthwhile for me
to
create space on my shelves for these
types absolutely flowers you know yeah a
great place uh down in the la area we
have a sesame that's really just yeah
the sesame creek collection collective
in ojai they're probably on sun grown
regenerative flower and and uh have
created
because that's what we found is if if uh
if we can get that retailer
to put in a little bit of that education
and when that person comes in and says
well what do you have that's 500 thc
you know you're like hey well can we can
we talk about that a little bit like
because in our experience you know
that's not
the number that matters we've had some
really good flour that doesn't test high
for sure yeah i'm trying and i would
prefer it usually over you know
something that's test really high but is
is uh
less of a broad spectrum right because
when we're focusing on any one thing
we're going to lose some of the some of
the rest of that yeah there's this like
you know for lack of a better term
entourage effect exactly loosely coined
but has a lot of interplay dynamics with
all of the combination of all the
secondary metabolites right so if you
get a story a little that'll help uh
help
you know with that narration then
you know we do great that sounds like a
great push for the industry yeah
terpenes over thc is the new
you know and also
you know
for
the customer who is looking for
earth conscious flower you know people
who go out of their way to buy organic
food or spend a little bit more money on
something that's fair trade
those are the people that are looking
for
flour like ours right and and really for
flour like everybody in the willow creek
cannabis alliance because that is
the difference definitely ultimately
between what we're offering and what you
might get from
a 100 acre farm somewhere in
a place that has a lot of other
industrial agriculture with risks of
you know all sorts of pesticide drift
and
you know
all sorts of stuff like that and so you
know we just think it's really important
that
farms like ours
are able to remain in the market
because there are people that want it
it's just unfortunately sometimes they
don't know that it's even an option
and so it's great that i need that
education able to you know provide
content like this you know that
helps people find out
that it's an option that it's a choice
that they have that's a great look and
you know there's probably you guys just
said like a dozen different things that
we could spin off but
i guess the final question would be if
there's one thing in the industry you
could see changed either regarding you
know like education or regulations what
do you think like the most important
thing would be that you'd like to see
changed if you had to pick one
to pick one it would because it's a big
one it would be the tax
because that is
creating just a chain
reaction of problems
if because we don't have those economies
of scale that those giant farms have all
of our little costs are a little bit
higher
and then that all gets taxed and then
taxed again and then taxed again and up
to seven or something different times
that that's getting taxed or more even
and to where and then that gets to the
retailer
who then you know has to make their
margin too
and so
our little difference in price keeps
getting amplified and amplified and so
what
what we're looking at in the current
market situation that the tax is
completely out of control
and it is crippling the entire industry
i hate to call it industry but whatever
it's it's crippling us as the farmer is
crippling the wholesaler or the
transportation it's the whole
there's no margins because the
government is taking such a huge cut
they're taking so many slices that it
adds up so they had that event yesterday
at in sacramento i didn't i didn't
follow it too closely but it was you
know to repeal the taxes to repeal the
cultivation tax and then also to give
the equity farmer uh sorry equity
retailers equity retailers a break on
the uh
the 15 state excise taxes do you think
newsom's gonna follow through with uh
uh you know he's a politician and and
following through isn't there
necessarily their specialty but he's
definitely made some
some
noises in that proper direction and we
can just we have to keep up the pressure
yes and
let let them know because it really like
so much tax on anything is going to
direct people to going
elsewhere and elsewhere is the
traditional black market whatever you
want to call it the old market
and
and that's you know crippling the legal
market and then and then you know to
have our prices be just so high
really really prevents people from being
able to get access good medicine
if i had one thing i would change i
would be i know it's a pipe dream but
direct to consumers and i agree with you
because so we operate a little bud and
breakfast at our farm in the summers
and right now i cannot
sell
our own cannabis to our guests
and
if you think about the vineyard model
and like the wine tasting model which is
a huge tourism
boon for napa and other counties and
you know
it is odd to me that the government is
fine with people drinking alcohol
basically driving turning around
right and it's okay for those vendors to
directly sell bottles of wine
to the people that come for those things
and yet i
cannot do that when somebody comes to
stay at our farm for sure i would have
to actually have my flower you know it
leaves the farm and it goes to the
distributor which currently our
distributor is in southern california
they would then package it down in long
beach
and then if i want it
to be able to
have it access for my guests i would
actually have to then get it shipped
back to a retail location
nearby
and i would have to have my guest
go to that retail location to get it
what it's just a supply chain fiat
and so yes i totally agree with you the
direct to consumer sales and i think
that they should allow some amount of
on-farm sales sure as well that would be
amazing
this is great and people want that
experience
yeah they do they're looking for it i
know there's all sorts of things popping
up with that um farm you know farm
visits and
it's really cool you guys are doing that
so the people that have stayed have had
this
amazing time it's really been it's been
yeah we don't even really talk about
that i mean might as well just plug that
really quick you guys do
offer this service right this glance
well i mean one of our whole original
reasons for settling on this particular
piece of property was that we wanted to
be able to introduce people to
permaculture and natural building and
you know just sustainable living in
general and so it's fun now that they
can come and we have the cannabis
growing on site as well and so it opens
it up to a whole other
group of people who maybe they actually
think that they're just coming because
they like weed
and then they find out like oh wow
actually look at all this other cool
stuff going on and i do think that
sometimes it like sparks a little
a little change little spider little and
then you know shift and yeah which is
sort of what we're doing that's what
we're all about yeah that's what we got
to do make through all right well thank
you so much for uh coming and talking
today it's really been interesting so i
appreciate it thanks russell yeah thanks
maybe i'll smoke some of that headband
yeah