[Music]
well should we wash the watch touch its
to her about to watch yeah let's do a
quick little wash here you should have
told me I would have brought some some
trim too fine a wash part yeah there's
the big old wash party hey puppy can I
baby yeah well then you could also like
I think that's too much aye sir oh I
think that's like yeah that's about how
I would run it you know what it means
what I'm doing is I'm putting ice in
here and then tell me that trim please
absolutely cool now this is some sick
indoor weed know this was grown this is
grown down here this is uh this amazing
purple dragon scale weed then my friend
Joe grows and he's licensed and it's
just amazing what this is it used to
squirt out purple rosin his buds let's
go ahead and put some in here
put some ice down and what we have in
here is we've got our 45 or 160 and our
190 so we just got these little short
bags so what we're gonna do is not put
too much and maybe just like and then if
you don't mind you hand me that other
bag ice there well my hands are so
sticky bro yes right there see oh yeah
totally sticky that's the sticky shit
and it's just tasty amazing
[Applause]
all right let that hang out for a little
bit put some water on it give me a lot
of love nice if you use pure water yeah
I like that pure water is always the
best I like la tap water a lot of places
they have a lot of fluoride in the water
and minerals and copper and too many
metallic things all the good stuff yeah
not to mention lithium so we just kind
of mix this around a little bit
a little mix I should put some more
water and can I have that water please
for this one yeah perfect
let me just take one last sip before I
give ya where we get some more from
inside yeah you mean your water
everybody actually there you go I got
some RO water all right fortunately I
have perfect
thank you sir oh now you got tangi
before the pork belly in there no no
it's necessary this is so oh it's very
fragrant it's funny I was buying beer in
the grocery store yesterday and it's
like everything's either super hoppy or
like mango or a bird and I'm like or
pumpkin spice right or yeah I was like I
don't want the Thanksgiving seasonal so
if you like vanilla like for Christmas I
like vanilla cinnamon so
let's let that hang out for a bit I
should put more water in it really but
go grab a couple yeah go grab a water
oh yeah all that Peter try this sure
now that the blowtorch isn't on in there
and the wand order isn't ready so this
bag is gonna save all that organic
material yeah how you're already pulling
it up that we're gonna take a TV timeout
- oh yeah we'll do TV timeout yeah I
like TV templates it's a go we can keep
talking it's almost like producing a
cooking show we're like yeah you gotta
think about okay this meal takes an hour
so like we can't talk early oh yeah and
then they were like the breakthrough is
like let's make it before we even start
the show and have a fully cooked one in
the oven so as we put one in we're just
pulling out so we need like the the
other bag that he did before we got here
you're like fast-forward 20 minutes so
that camera gonna take pictures of each
of these oh my god I keep forgetting I'm
normally that Mac one is
hi hi honey
yeah I love the different consistencies
or just how different they all are like
you have different colored labels yeah
he makes it easier to sort them out it
all started with the red but yes we just
mix like this very frosty this is our
new new thing we're offering the new
mixing stations so you make the
stainless now and we have big huge ones
we sell two we're setting up a lot of
hash labs now all over and they want to
go as big as possible it's all about
size scale this whole like setup would
go for retail within three bags and I
had just maybe like I don't know exactly
to tell you the truth we haven't yeah I
don't
we haven't pricey yet but you go on our
website bull banks calm and check it out
nom Instagram but yeah so people want to
most labs want to do at least like 10 10
thousand grams a month get production up
and people are scaling right now it's
crazy but what if what see this being
used really well for test runs you know
of a certain strain yes you're gonna be
always happy you can just grab you know
a quick couple plans
yeah they're like equipment uncle man
just put it in there mix it up and go
okay it's worth it I put this in this is
what came out let's cut that whole
freaking crop down that's exactly what
the big companies do yeah that would be
very they buy our little five sets and
they do
test run or they'll run even like one
gallons before they run the big 200
gallon systems just as like the little
Barbie batch just to make sure they
dialed it in and also it's a good way of
saving your product too before you go
into a freeze dry cuz you have to have a
full freeze dryer full because it cost
money to run that freeze dryer and you
don't want to run it half full so these
are great to save your product in
between runs it's another way bags
holding bags would you actually leave it
in the bag and just set it aside oh yeah
in the bucket - yeah totally and then
you just put it on your trays when
you're ready to rock and then come in
here and check this out this is really
awesome it's like almost orange it's
gonna be beautiful it's gonna be yummy
really yummy you smell it yeah it's
pretty tangerine ewwww
yeah give it a squeeze let it melt then
sometimes you just hang it above just
give it a hang but I'm just gonna put
this aside for now I could let it drain
and melt for maximum yield
but for TV purposes or just put it
balanced a lot of yeah we're gonna waste
a lot of great hash yeah this is going
to be great
so being obviously being in a really
cold environment is the best and best
situation so most of the labs are we set
up or all like walk-in fruit freezers
basically you need full-on cold gear in
there I run it like 46 degrees roughly
with a cool box so so the people so the
people doing stuff at scale I mean
they're they're having massive walk-in
freezers right massive walk-in freezers
just yeah and what temperature do they
usually keep it at I'm like 40 46 you
see yeah I read it 46 I mean you can you
can have it colder but it's it's not
really necessary and if you really
actually it's in a freezer you can't it
literally freeze while you're while
you're doing this you wanted about 46 to
50 I've noticed that even at 55 your ice
isn't gonna melt as long as it's moving
but anything above that and it's
definitely gonna start melting off
really good you're gonna get a lot more
condensation on the side of whatever
you're using even if they're jacketed
they'll start to really condensate I
like the colder the better the colder
the better is the best but then but then
it's exactly comfortable and working
with it I was in the other day and you
have to have your full-on beard cover
you know your beard net your tat net
your walking suit and it's just like too
cold too cold you need like next time
you gotta bundle up
you'd be surprised though how quick you
get warm once you start really paddling
down the river so we got a little waste
material here no big deal no big deal
just a little you know we're just we did
like double sifting basic there's a
really good handful so anyways we're
going to put that aside and then we're
gonna pull out of our 45 here this is
the gauge this is the goodies right here
it's just kind of like you wanted if you
can see over there yeah you kind of want
the ball to kind of congeal together
kind of get together and obviously a
little water action would be nice but
see the beautiful little healthy little
ball there that is gorgeous
that's nice yeah that's gonna be um yum
yum and this is what I would consider
full-spectrum because he basically did
42 159 yeah
just with a couple of little strokes of
the paddle mm-hmm you barely even beat
that was maybe like three minutes of
washing it at the most
check this out that's gorgeous that's a
lot more than I was expecting from that
from that train man that looks really
good it looks good in the light
yeah not bad man yeah that's how we do
it that's gonna be nice little freeze
dryer put that with a lot more and
freeze dry it and it's gonna be
delicious I used to like it you did this
table like 20 years ago you would lay it
out on the table or something this
tables been in our family a long time
actually seen a lot of hillbilly hash
bashes right I love it yeah so let's
hash everybody
that's a 45 that's a good bubble hash
right yeah that's gonna be really fun do
you smoke later and then also check out
the hue of this water in here yeah I
mean this is delicious product here too
and what you can do with this all of my
water all of my hash to water my plants
is you could actually boil this down and
distill all the water out all the water
out and you can get more solid material
I don't use so what's great about this
new mixing bucket is that you can
actually really maximize your product
and then turn this into something useful
instead of throwing it out so this is
stuff that only made it through all
three bags right yes this is the final
smoke product you can go down to a 25
micron to but but my point is that super
filtered with jism yeah this this is
after you boil this down and you get
solid material this will be really
smokeable or edible too it'll be really
great for edibles
yeah fantastic because it'll also be
it'll be activated with heat which will
make it really psychoactive when you eat
it that's a lot of work I just like I
said I use all of my hash water with my
mixes and my teas it's thanks a little
bit and you said you feed it to your
plants all night they're like fuck yeah
dude I'll be honest thanks man regular
mix as soon as it gets those they're so
happy they they immediately just go
crazy so yeah I love the color of this
look I would say it's like almost orange
it's fun it's fun like to play with
different kinds of trims like indoor
Sonics and things because you get some
amazing results sometimes you get purple
water and you've got purple water thank
you crazy sometimes water yeah you get
blue water fed like all kinds of colors
pink at times also it's always different
there's so many amazing strains and that
have been you know not even testing even
as you wash as you go through your
washes the color of the water will
change like it'll start purple and then
move to this like like you know greenish
tannish orange colors or wow this is so
cool yeah that smells delicious good job
man that'll be far out and so when you
left it out drying I guess its climate
dependent but like how long because
you're in Humble right I'm sorry good so
how long would that take to just sundry
it like a week maybe it depends on the
you know if it's the summer or you know
when yeah so this is wild so we made
some hash you guys with some this 45
mesh full mesh bags and it's going to be
delicious and what's amazing is this on
a large scale yeah alright so so in kind
of the biggest size that's on the market
now that are being used by these larger
facilities what's kind of the yield per
walk like what are you seeing yield wise
it depends on the strains like how many
grams is this would you guess I would
say like two after that after driving
maybe maybe two am lucky yeah we weren't
doing it as fast as what we were doing
it you know I've gotten more absolutely
I'm just throwing a couple handfuls
anything and also it's really a hot day
today too
yeah I think that I need agree so you
don't want to do hash on a hot day
because your yield
really shitty what's nice is if you
crank up the AC in the house or do it on
a cold night all night or if you're in
the snow go out and get some snow that's
what you do and make it a nighttime
manner right now it's um I mean
everybody's wearing their full-on like
you know like cold work it's so cold in
there I'm wearing like I have snowboard
jackets a guy might be yeah and it's
cold we have to come out with new like
cold gear now because we're in the cold
all the time not only that but you it's
weird cuz you get both them you're
working in that cold so you're gonna get
warm - so you kind of have to like be
able to take your jacket off sometimes
and like I mean it's 50 degrees in there
but I'm not cold sometimes and then I
usually I'm in shorts but I'll usually
wear a jacket but my feet usually get
freezing and my air conditioner is
pumping and it's freezing in there and
I'm always adding ice - I'm really anal
i-i-i I'm very picky I guess you could
say but I guess it comes out in the end
product - just once I will keep it gold
I once had to work as a butcher and I
sold that stays in the freezer room and
it reminds me of that but making hash is
so much fun there's nothing better than
stupid no thanks no thank you I'm not
into that at all
and then you I've noticed that people
are doing different temperatures at
their presses and I've noticed also what
they're not they're not pressing in a
warm room but they're also not pressing
in a freezing cold room they're doing it
about like 65 at 60 to 65 degrees and
I've noticed a lot of people are up in
their temperature where it used to be
like Oh 190 200 max and now people are
pressing up to 30 to 40 and the to 30 to
40 just allows a direct press so you can
kind of squirt directly into a jar I
don't know if that's all for
visual purposes or whatever the case may
be and the a lot of other big-name
companies like monopolies extracts dang
Zara
ice wax that guy they're just they just
pump directly onto parchment and then
they just ball it up throw it in a jar
and let it cure then there's also a lot
of different curing techniques where
people say Oh put it in a in a jar with
the lid closed for 200 degrees for 45
minutes and let it do its thing in the
jar and then other people are like that
ruins all the Turks you're gonna you're
gonna ruin everything and then other
people say oh just leave it in the jar
75 degrees wow I've noticed that I kind
of play with the best of both worlds
where I go a little bit warmer I have a
mmm have a closet in my house luckily
that hasn't water heater in it so it
stays about 85 degrees all the time and
I let my hash sitting there in a dark
room at about 85 for about five days
that's where my separation occurs and
does everything does this and this and
in all honesty you can have it any way I
can fresh press it and freeze it and
it'll look bomb and it looked like
shatter but then you have to keep it
cold
you have to seven ten labs just started
to talk about how they're finally
starting to explain hey this is what our
hash looks like at the beginning this is
what our hash looks like after it's been
to store your hash in the frigerator in
a nice little Tupperware jar with a anti
moisture yeah back inside keep the
moisture out that's what I that's what I
prefer and recommend you not freeze it
freezing it's bad yeah freezing is very
bad I don't like to freeze my hash the
only thing those threes is my is my
flour I freeze my flour when it's fresh
frozen and cut down because it doesn't
seem to expand much because it's already
full of water and doing its thing and
even then I've seen fresh frozen last
like if it's sealed good and a good
freezer like six months to a year no
problem and still produce exactly the
same as it did the day was cut down but
after it's pressed and made like you
said it should stay cold and it should
stay at least humid as possible you have
to have those
whatever those that's a great hat it has
a great shelf life does it does it'll
last a long time I remember the big
bricks back a long time with the stamp
on it yes and you just they lasted you
just put it in your closet or in your
drive wherever and they you know issues
but Trailer Park Boys status hash blocks
I love that cam rock walks around with
his igloo cooler is little mini cooler
he takes his seriously he is very very
serious yeah but he also has full milk
he separates them so you have to keep
your full milk cold or else it'll turn
black or not black but it oxidize and
turn brown which is still good it still
tastes amazing but over how long a
period like the next day or next day
okay yeah yeah from from from literally
like white is this you know why does
this lid it'll it'll turn so it's
basically like carrying a heart
transplant from like LA to keep it cold
well you you how I figured it out and
learned was before I even started doing
this you approve of his wash you like
his work is that what attracted you to
him good answer
she's she makes better hash than me
really at a spa like a spa day yeah I
was oh you were both already at the spa
I thought she was like you need to meet
my daughter and you're gonna go on a
date to a smart
if you're smart you always listen to
your mom that's one thing I always
learned my mom agrees with that advice
totally yeah yeah well so who are you
seeing that uh like when you like as you
see people post stuff on Instagram or
wherever like who's doing cool stuff
that you're you'd like that you'd like
to smoke their hash or that you've
recently smoked personally smoking
others hash I really like let's see what
if I what if I tried that I mean of
course like I said supe
Michigan made melts makes amazing hash
7-10 Labs is always good it's always
consistent and that that's really the
the hard thing to find is somebody that
makes a consistent product there's a
company called Bloomfield's also they're
close to me they've they've given me a
lot of information and helped me out
with a lot of stuff - those guys are
really solid they make great hash they
grow great weed it's it's like I said
consistency and finding people that have
good strains Cameron
I'll buy his hash all day long it's
amazing he does a great job and I know
where it's coming from
there's nothing better than knowing
where your product is coming from start
to finish and having that peace of mind
and and also having the peace of mind to
give your your customers and your
friends and family product that you know
is healthy and good and quality you know
like I'm trusting you yeah I don't want
it like I don't want to have a bunch of
like you know like avid and people
spraying their plants and you know I
just I don't want that so I don't I
don't I make sure to stay away from that
and I'm always like in the room right
before I'm the one cutting the weed down
so I'm in there a couple days before
their harvest cutting their weed down
doing a test batch for other people's
harvest yes okay I have my own harvest
but there's no way to sustain that like
as a one person you'd have to have all
sorts of rooms to have the consistency
to have a point is that they're letting
you come in and cut yeah these are my
good friends we we also kind of have
like a conglomerate that we we consider
ourselves we call ourselves to the shoot
family farms we're all kind of in this
same area in West Hills California one
of the guys used to live on Shoop and he
kind of like had like a Wi-Fi passwords
like shoot game and we're just a bunch
of dorky white guys I go surfing and
grow pot like it yeah and skimboarding
you know so like you know so so you get
first right yeah yes yeah that's that's
all it's been is I've been very luck
lucky and fortunate to have the the the
connections to the good material and
knowing that it's good and watching and
learning and these guys have taught me
so much I used to work for the bank for
a long time I was I used I was in
foreclosure as default for B of A for 12
years man I work away
middle-management I was a sucker you
know they make your own slaughter you
yeah animals - yeah exactly
they laid me off men and when they laid
me off they gave me enough money to
start a nice grow and and - you know and
do what I do now we're gonna ruin
people's lives you know I that same
question I gotta tell you I'm amazed by
a couple hash makers I work on the front
lines with yabin humble are making
insane hash right now it's like you
wouldn't believe this kind of like white
like like talking trees I've made them
some bags and Jeremy and those guys
they're making from talking trees and
wicked wicked hash like insane and
barren panache is making some great
great product very proud of him he's
like the all-time awesome man and then
of course Frenchie you know French he
makes great hash all time he's just got
the touch you know he's he's still he's
old-school is still the fucking master
you know I love smoke it sounds easier
to get a lot of the the craftsmen that
are out there because it's so it's so
nerve-racking you know you don't know
who you're dealing with and then there's
these people out here that are making
some amazing hash but there's no way to
acquire it it's not even available in a
store but you see these tall short run
that's obscene man I wish I could get
some I want to try it I want to see what
I'm doing
there's a guy that's called his name is
form ahead he was like a Grateful Dead
logo I don't think he's in Washington I
don't even know where he's at but men
some of the best hash I've seen is
coming out of that guy I don't even know
these people you know what I mean I just
wish I could I could sample all the
different stuff that's around the
country and find out what's going on
everywhere you know I've I've had
limited selection with you know with
what's available just due to people's
you know safety concerns of not wanting
to get in trouble into not wanting their
brain to random do that one in there not
wanting to get I'm not wanting to have
silver bracelet
you know just things like that it's like
I feel like we're doing something that's
so harmless we're literally growing a
plant chopping it down washing it with
water and sifting it with bags like how
harmless are we like dude are you
serious right now we're not doing
anything be honest you are pretty
harmless looking like come on I love I
love how people are learning how to make
hash and they're turning it into a you
know ritual and then a lifestyle and
also a way to support themselves which
is amazing like people are my neighbor
is easy and then also there is
celebrities you know people that are
able to make these glass bongs that
people can actually afford to have a lot
of funerals itself yeah when you see
like glassblower after glass blower with
like a hundred and something thousand
followers and tell people stuff all day
long it's really cool it's really cool
and then they appreciate this too they
give these people love the people that
are that are you know supporting the
fact that people need these pieces and
people need this medicine it's really
important it's it's people need this so
that they can eat and not be nauseous
and not be sick this is something that
makes people so that they can breathe
and not have seizures oh it's amazing
what this product does this is a from
outer space cure you know seeds when
they come up they come a counter
clockwise the opposite marijuana seeds
are the only seed that comes out
opposite of every other seed that's true
man is a fact every day you learn
something new right yeah I don't think
I'm not sure if it's left or right but
it's opposite okay so a seed of pretty
much every plant they own all kind of a
seeds and then all cannabis go to the
opposite direction it's like a toilet in
the southern hemisphere so it's an
amazing thing it's like a galactic
product very galactic
I'm sure the aliens come for this that's
why they always land up in humble
product there's more sightings of aliens
up and humble yeah that's cause
everybody's baked as hell man but no
they come for the weed I'm convinced you
up for another one sure all right what
are we at now I'm gonna let you try the
the Mac one this is the one that's
extremely gassy it's it's not much of a
marijuana do the hash bar at the concert
this weekend I told you man I would if I
didn't have hours away and extremely
short notice
okay it's harvest time oh my that's what
I want to do down here is basically
create a venue where people can bring
their stuff and share it with other
people who are appreciate the same stuff
that's what I would really like and not
only that but you just find out like
what people are doing and have like
mines coming up with good ideas cause
hammers families help me out with saying
things it's like the salons in Paris and
like the 1700s like a idea exchange well
that's what the shows have always been
about you know like the High Times cups
in the very beginning they were small
intimate was exchanged small intimate or
are no longer know when it was in
Amsterdam it was really cool it was very
small those women are Jean you met Frank
oh you met DNA you met they were there
they were doing their thing everything
was was growing and they were figuring
all of these things out you met all
those people all those strains that were
getting built the chocolate the LA
Confidential all those strains were new
and never even around and they were said
it were you and Amsterdam for a while
yeah well I wasn't there but I was going
every year and I was like this is what I
want to do with my life I want to figure
this out I want to know what the pulse
is around the world and it was funny how
many Americans you found going to
Amsterdam trying to also figure out what
I was like you know we were just like
the Canadians to Canadians to know all
the claims are we wearing their red and
white shirts and rolling around
everybody was having so much fun
the cannabis community it was like so
refreshing where you don't have to like
you all like outcasts and black sheep
and you're running around everybody's
like oh man here go to this Hedgehog
you're gonna like this this flower if
this is what you're interested in try
this try that
oh the hash that oh my god the hash and
it first got real hash like real a hash
man stirred a myself holy crap
like there's nothing like this like
nobody's and if anybody's making
anything like this then giving it to me
yeah only like 18 19 20 maybe you know I
certainly wasn't under yeah I got some
good chronic it's a weed is tight you
know chronic and man that you know yeah
but when you found it and it was all
like you says come from Nepal was coming
from Morocco and it would be blonde or
even even the dark stuff was so good and
you would barely get any and it would
last you so long it was so delicious and
then you know just trying to figure out
fun seeing the bubble man and then
seeing people with the washing machines
and seeing people with the straighteners
and then seeing people smash everything
and then people coming up with all sorts
of cool ideas on ways to smoke it's
changed you know people using the Ember
that was the first time I saw someone
with like a hot rod you know a hot stick
connected to a you know a plug and
you're smoking weed without a flame it's
like okay oh and the volcano came out so
it was like oh this is like there were
so many different things changing around
that time right around 2000 2002 it's
really cool it was really awesome and
I'm just glad that it's still
progressing and we're not being stagnant
these new oils these all the new oils
stimulate new smoking products and it's
just a full circle I was just talking to
Ben from rising tech because I was
asking I was like is there any reason
why you make THC a besides just kind of
a show either I want to get really
fucked up or just to show people that
you can do something that I don't I I
know that the process is insane I've
never even attempted have you seen a
little white rocks a little basically
you're gonna miss again yeah and you're
gonna repress this
at a higher temperature and yeah you
actually to cut the bag open scoop shit
out it's like I think it's time for that
this delicious is that something I'm not
going to take my red wine yeah yeah I'm
really I'm really happy with my product
I don't need to go that far down the
rabbit hole I don't think I've seen it
done and I've looked into the the
research on it and I've seen some other
people do it but I've also seen it I
feel like people do it just to get super
fucked up not because it's like how much
more fucked up can you get just smoke to
dabs of that well that's my point that's
why I'm wondering why people do it is it
just to show other people that they can
do it I think so okay I think so I don't
I don't see any benefit to it right I
don't see any nice technology it's a fun
topper for your that that's my foot yeah
product people like it it's nice pure
pure that's the year the yurts back
there right yeah that's my babies yurt
yeah
now you mentioned that yard I was like
sweet I want a yurt I've seen them
yeah I've seen really interesting new
derivatives of hash now from the widest
white powder oh yeah yeah from the black
to white and I've also every grade when
when I'm making this before I I've
turned it into like this color or this
consistency like I can I could probably
cut the top part off you know all of the
Terps and save all the white underneath
and it would be a completely different
smoke but again I like it all together
do you know what I'm saying trying to
say that I like that mixture of
everything feel like even with THC
diamonds or two nodded Charlie's in
there diamonds like I said you're gonna
reap put it back in another bag into
about a 15 micron bag I'd give it a go
you should be good
so 15 micron bag and then you're gonna
repress it hotter and I've heard that
actually you started a super low temp
first or something like that Lincoln a
hundred degrees and then you press and
then you can gradually increase it I do
you guys keep talking we're gonna go
visit the car I'm gonna do a DAB please
please feel free
very nice I like this rig this is
fucking very cool let me clean that
actually real quick sorry
you want to grab that butane real quick
I don't mind hot hot you know dabs - you
really get a lot of the extra you do
chemicals yo you certainly are these are
our vape tool products that I've been
making for like 10 years and I designed
these stamp them out of steel and
they're great for packing bowls you know
for the discreet for pebbles just go for
it thanks man
it's all about necessity you know I
never would have thought I'd be making
his bags ever in my life I mean never in
my life I thought I'd be making hash
bags it's not since you were a small boy
you had this dream but it's a wonderful
like you know people depend on me for
them a lot of people get pissed like I'd
say I'd stop making them because I don't
make a lot of money doing them so I tell
people and they get mad you know he just
try to keep your like it's a great you
know thing that people need it's still
and I enjoy it and I enjoy being in the
cannabis world I do too I really like
the community I've literally been in the
cannabis world for over 20 years there's
a big part of the community I do not
like there are those people and there's
a community I do like I mean luckily
I've got you know and I know the best
people and really good many good people
in this business but after 20 years you
know you learn a few things sometimes
not the easy way yeah sometimes they
cost you a friendship or a couple bucks
but you know you just try to remain
positive is is the main thing and I
found people get greedy in this business
that's sort of one thing that's
it kills it you know people get a little
too greedy sometimes I mean they should
just sort of like just sit back and try
to be part of the big picture mm-hmm you
know when you're building something like
Pepsi Cola you know it's like gonna be
part of it you know like when you're
building something big cannabis
businesses so that's full of a lot of
different stories like that I hear a lot
of stories especially with legalization
now do ya know I've had people burn me
like it's still a gangster business
basically kind of I can't believe the
robberies go on like they do like people
just like breaking and smashing and
grabbing I'm like what he is doing like
it's the cannabis community we're so
tight-knit usually you're gonna get
caught anyway like yeah there's a lot of
desperate people out there still it's
sad it sucks but there was a cot
all right so what would you you'd
basically dry that now that be dried or
you just let it sit in the Sun or just
kind of get the water Christ okay this
gets by I can't remember if I asked the
question but if you let this sit out in
the Sun here in LA how long would you
like it one day a week yeah give it a
week right I'd say right now right now
degrees out maybe not even you could
smoke it tomorrow I mean I think you're
joking right now if I put it like you
could definitely yeah yeah probably
smoke it tomorrow no problem
it should make a nice ball we have ever
straight press that no because it's
gonna be water right so when you squish
that and there's water left in its team
concept yeah well it'll literally squirt
out the water yeah you just kind of do
it's great to drink the water yeah so
you can't do a super hyper fast drying
it freeze dryer the freeze dryer is the
way to go always that's why you can't
that's why you can't press fresh flour
you have to wait for flour to dry before
you can actually do flour rosin so you
have to have to dry it out
the other humming looks delicious I'll
be good tomorrow
smells good yeah oh yeah I love making
ash yeah I definitely love disgust
getting a big bag made a custom one and
maybe even yeah we can do that for you I
would really appreciate that we we just
did these hundred and eighty gallon bags
that's huge huge like size 180 gallons
we just did 180 I'm like trying to think
of what that would even look like like
it's just a big tank you know the size
of that couch cushion right there while
it's like just like you know it's a big
tank it's not too big you know they did
have an agitator in the middle yeah an
agitator goes up on top I did this for a
good friend up in the hills of humble
company and so still massive yeah yeah
we love doing that but but so did I ask
the question where it's like we yielded
like oh the Precision's
we made going fervour on volume depends
on the strains of course some strains
nothing
yeah I thought the strains that pumped
flour and pens just like for exhaustion
it's like 2% nothing just like why does
the strawberry banana just squirt out
some john and rosin so because your
mom's amo 80% 7% you're like what every
time and it's really hard to find oh
geez that produce at all thankfully my
wife I does like a 5% which is it's
still really good for an OG usually
you're happy with four but you're not
gonna be making much fun here's my
question are there machine returns the
larger you go he says I believe so no
traditionally making hash like you you
got a pound of hash I mean a pound of
weed or trim you're gonna get about
thirty percent yield sometimes twenty to
thirty percent yeah yeah dry if it's dry
you know yeah you're gonna get that much
hash you
that exact return but then this more
refined product it's all depends on you
you have to weigh out potency versus
flavor and and just work your way
through mm-hmm and work your way into
the best quality but like 20 percent
average I'd say yeah yeah and 20 percent
average that's on dry flour and then if
you cut down and it's wet we do five
times the ratio so like a pound of flour
is 40 for 450 grams roughly will 450 for
exactly and then when I do a pound of
fresh frozen it's 2250 so it's five
times that amount so that's why we
that's how we roll that and then you get
a four percent but if you do 4 times 5
that's 20% and you're hoping for those
20 percents anything more is a lot of
icing on the cake and for some reason
like you said those strawberry bananas
those those GMOs there's some strains
the cookies and cream they're pumping
six to eight percent repetitively
over and over and over again so that's
what people are making the most hash out
of obviously my problem is just keeping
a consistent supply finding traffic is a
problem it is definitely consistency
problem huh just kind of that's one of
the ways I wash and I I wanna wash in a
44 I've been doing in a 32 but my bag is
a 50 because I can't actually find a bag
that will fit a 30 44 that's not six
feet long
like I said go on a website make them
the right thing please I'd love to find
out bullpens comm I there i lo I'll send
you some later but so I wash I wash
roughly and I wash in a big bag with no
light like my big bag is my work back so
I'm just washing directly in that I tie
it off I put a slip knot on it and I
have a hoist and I pull it straight out
of the trash can and let it hang like
you did you know what I'm saying yeah
the hoist is a great way just to wrap it
in the middle I do I just twist it
straight up pull my bucket of water out
and then I dump into ten
I do 10 gallons and I use ice extracts
packs right now but I use the same exact
what you're doing I use 40 and then I go
from 40 to 179 my I have I wash into 220
then I dump into another to 22 to clean
that and then my 180 to 219 I throw that
like just to the side - that's just like
you know hash for bond loads or
something like that
I my my full spec that I press is 42 179
and that's what I feel like the best
heads are so that's my yeah it's all
about the precious heads if the precious
heads are there you're gonna get them if
it's not I mean I look at trim every day
and it's amazing under the microscope
it's either there or it's not out there
it's just fucking fact
yep and I'm in the fact also as our eyes
are getting any better as we get older
yeah
I've seen even the the other technique
where people are just putting a couple
nugs in a mason jar with ice and water
shaking it up and just holding it you
know to the sunlight see him okay is
there enough sand down in the bottom is
it worth running this contests good
people are also you know be innovative
you know be be it's also a little frugal
you know so you're not you're not
wasting a bunch of product but so what
end consistency do you guys speculate
that's gonna look like it's gonna look
like one of these two cuz it's a trim
these are all full fresh nugs and this
is only even dark because it's been in
here for two months you know be in this
color range
yeah after it's pressed and in all
honesty it's funny how it might look
darker here but once you dry it and you
put in a freeze dryer comes way lighter
that's a fact and then when you press it
then it turns yellow and you're like oh
crap cool
yeah everything's dark the one that's
wet and I'll be honest when I press
these they came out super dark they were
almost like like black and then after a
week of curing and whipping they start
to look very nice and they start to look
like this consistency and they're
extremely delicious to smoke
they are I think there's unanimous
agreement alright well thank you for
having us come over Q for happen it's a
pleasure to meet you or shall I
appreciate it thanks for Peter I'm just
joshing maybe you should do a short tour
oh you gotta guys'll feel mighty might
as well do the whole thing