[Music]
let's fire though yeah yeah yeah man
that garlic you butter one guys
describes it as garlic shrimp parts I
literally thought it was like a mushroom
onion yeah yeah it really does smell
like that soup like mushrooms and garlic
Spencer used to work at and someone with
like thought it was super garlic mustard
onion garlic wanna get that to the
patients I was like stop calling it that
but I like they want to be a dick and be
like it's not called oh yeah Tim oh
honey we have a bunch of funny
Sunfire farmers man can't beat it
oh thanks man I'm doing for GMO or this
Ronnie and I are good at this are
awesome for the first one yeah I'll take
you gotta do that makers choice yeah
yeah like not too strong but still still
good my class piece is very interesting
man oh yeah it definitely isn't
interesting like pull do you rip it hard
you gotta get go in too slow you don't
really have to rip it hard
oh my god I think like snap that's a
little cold snow here you go yeah watch
I got waited to see what he did to grab
oh yeah
and then open I'm showing the hash
version true I'm sorry that's what
version oh that's the live rosin
full-spectrum live rosin and then here's
the full melt right there that's the 92
159 Oh once it says 150 it sounds good
so that into this yeah really go like
148 that's a talk of a thing the pipe
yeah so flavorful coming right away
thanks nice
perfect good temperature perfect I know
yeah I love that bubble cap that's still
my fear I like it better than the
binaries word uh yeah so this cap made
by brick glass brick glass yeah just a
bubble cap a lot of people are like on
the spinner cap wave which I still love
like I have this mud like the binary cap
but yeah I just like this one because it
just kind of is a little more like
restrictive and kind of gets I feel like
it gets everything a little better you
can move your to have around and whatnot
it's more interactive or yeah it's more
interactive they both have their they
both have their fun definitely have you
used this cap would it just sit on top
and that would spin automatically yeah
yeah you'll just set it and it'll just
like hands-free Wow pretty easily too
and quick yeah this pipe like it's
pretty restricting so like if you have
like a straight tube like it makes the
bead go like way faster so I kinda like
the bubble cap on this guy but very nice
this is where an email would be having
do you know right I used to have them I
got friends that have them for sure yeah
and they make some pretty cool ones you
they look like a like ice cream truck is
like this they do the hoppers up like
that it's very simple you know I think
they're all for you they work pretty
well
did you want on it for a banger yeah or
like a that's like okay there's normal
like the highly educated cops
the highly educated talks like the ones
that are like you have to use the old
carb caps for you know like the like
there no I can't remember the names
they're kind of pretty old-school goes
around it's like a titanium Yale oh yes
no about me males with the hole on the
middle and shit yeah yeah some some
special bangers for the emails yeah dude
that'd be ideal setup have an email set
the exact temperature right and used rip
it all day yeah for sure let's do a room
view of the the of copán yeah do you it
because I've never well you're this yeah
I think why I think what's cool is you
you've used the other one you said you
have you are you gonna go in on one of
these Peter yeah yeah just give me one
second show you in some of the
strawberries yeah yeah so this is pretty
much fresh press right your heart yeah
that's the fresh press and that's like
you did about to cure either pretty much
yeah I just like fresh prostate kept it
very cold packaged it cold you back hold
less than 30 seconds Peters want to grab
it quick down yeah tell me what about 10
seconds okay yeah oh you can probably
hold that one user pin it now you're at
ten seconds yeah yeah he's your sword
your weapon of choice
it's like so small it's like that's oil
anyway I've been press on that tempest
being so long again minutes usually what
I put mine yeah dude and especially with
the be dinner like still holds a lot of
obviously have you seen this of work no
wait it's for hookahs there's no nice
yeah so the clothes looks like a bunch a
hash are there cause you put the hog I
think it was that was on Instagram yeah
yeah see if it works
Kevin you can't tell yeah you can't tell
that's why I got the black little
attachment on there yeah do you I think
I might have got some water like when
you get water on this it like sizzles
when it's heating up so hopefully right
now and we're gonna review the puff co+
yes so we're your first what are your
expectations of someone who's never had
that because you've already hit the
first edition of yeah this is a puff
coke plus I think I just hit the of
cocaine
this is edition number two and what are
the things you notice that are different
well right away the the poker I guess
when I thought I called poker or the
yeah applier no no well mini dabber yeah
it was just it
was the just like a sphere like it's
just a straight like point but now you
have a little scooper to it and it's
angled so that's nice too
you know yeah picking it up for sure and
the ceramic itself too was a lot deeper
and that's helpful because it was kind
of pain yeah it was good for one hit you
know right
bigger dab size yeah that's always good
so um let's see you should try the GMO
for sure read my mind
yeah good now this is all set to go
how does it work the same I guess you
could grab it out of let's scoop some of
the Sun Fire farms and you grew this and
like light depth right yeah so this is
all that grown and extracted by me just
like light up living soil here in
Southern California yeah and what could
give me some description like are you
yeah we are actually more a little a
little more coastal so we are not too
high in elevation kind of more just in
the valley so I guess all day man oh
yeah my favorite smelling ones
definitely it's like the stingiest yeah
it's like always prevalent it's not like
a fruity smell for sure it's very
attractive totally okay so it has
settings I know that from the other pen
so you hit it five times and it will
change and that'll turn it on okay on
for sure I think was already on before I
streamed it off so back on and then four
times will go like from white which is
the hottest to like greens of blue or
red or something probably blue two three
four or maybe whites please stop easy so
yeah bounce the blue one two three four
green I think Green is the lowest I
think white is the hottest that would
make sense so let's try one two three
four blue white one two three
or oops that wasn't bad push all right
so blue now there's a session to the
other one if you hit it like twice you
do it twice it'll burn for like 12
seconds yeah
nice so I just hit twice well first
we'll put it in there and ideally it
just falls off the scooper right yeah
yeah you gotta aim it down like you
can't be smoking with a straight out so
I'm missing a piece here
ah did you screw it up you just screw it
down if you push and then the white part
will push it ah it did yes that's
another new feature they didn't push up
so you gotta put a little pressure on it
yeah very cool all right so two times
we're in session
definitely able to taste it I think
hitting it twice a second hit might be
better yeah
don't we'll hit I what double tap it and
then just just rip it you know slowly
and long with the whole time but that
was full flavor in that first in the
first rib though for sure it's not like
heating up a rig and hitting that but
definitely got the taste you might see
you might see more smoke I think it got
some more smoke coming out yeah that
wasn't like a full job oh yeah pretty
tasty for sure Cheers we have the GMO
turf in there feel like some pens I just
get like a super burnt profile I was
like better than I expected
there's a little part it's still a
little bit on here and didn't it yeah oh
yeah it's like pretty you've got most of
the dab I guess right yeah it did most
of it fell off yeah see there's a third
hit to it and I was a good little bad
dude especially if you're just like
chilling out somewhere in need of
discreet discreteness you know
at the soccer field you know on the
sideline kids soccer game while they're
eating sliced oranges got bad calls I oh
come on walk away or that pair is being
an asshole across the way you're
drinking a beer next year so I think
forever that was like that was gonna fat
dab or a small dab it was a kind of
medium yeah yeah yeah I guess you could
put a little bigger one in that amazing
and then you'll get yeah cuz that wasn't
a that third hit kind of taste but it
wasn't I could definitely taste like
some right to it for sure wasn't like
the hit you want and then you cue it
after every dab and I guess if you're
gonna switch it up but if we're gonna do
a little more DML that's true yeah your
dad I'm down it's my very favorite yeah
it's my first wash the GMO too and it
does yeah oh yeah I guess it yields like
I mean like people would like maybe one
of like you know run it for like
hydrocarbon - Oh true um mica probably
yeah actually I'll do this one but yeah
yields better for solving less than it
does for like yeah yeah as much as I've
never made it with anything about water
hash but that's what I've heard
nice yeah this is definitely a bigger
dab right I hear it grows pretty yeah so
talk about the great lake as a nonce
packed full so yeah I wonder that's not
how it's gonna handle that one the
growth of the GMO netwo yeah but like in
the living soil and kind of like your
way of growing like yeah you're you're
close to the LA scene right and you're
close to the Santa Barbara scene and I
was saying neither like la is indoor
hydro a lot totally it's so ran a barb
is like like even the like a lot of the
big green houses are all like cocoa and
stuff like that
yeah it's definitely a pretty rare thing
to like see living soil cultivation down
here and just like how
not like sustainable like biodynamic
regenerative mindset because like most
people yeah exactly like in LA or
growing in door they're growing not in
soil they're they're not doing it with
that intention and yeah same with Santa
Barbara like a lot of that cultivation
up there
like you said it's in cocoa it's not
it's not with like the mindset to be
doing good for the earth as well so I
feel pretty like just stoked to be doing
that around here and trying to like
spread that awareness and movement and
whatnot so yeah I just CC you feel
pretty good about yourself I I'm still
doing it yeah it feels much better to
not be like throwing away so many
rockwool cubes after every run and just
like how with this one you smoke people
out in this market are they like that's
pretty fuckin yeah they do seem to
notice a difference so like wow that was
very clean like the high is very clean
it was very smooth and ladies are indoor
smokers yeah they're people who are like
smoking there used to like everything
most of the stuff that they're finding
around here is indoor you know it's
hydroponics so it is they kind of notice
that difference when they see it I think
this is ready I found my friends like
noticing a huge difference maybe like
coughing but how's it going man oh good
good this and that I told my have
something like ah I'm coughing I'm only
smoking right now well what are you
having been smoking on they tell me what
it is
again it's in my step like oh dude way
more amazing they they say they could
take the big difference like be more
clearly but in your hash yeah it's just
my hash Mike and so that implies your
sourcing from like someone who grows
like he does cuz I think yeah endure and
he claims be organics you know okay yeah
I don't know the full details there but
uh yeah so I would imagine even more
sourcing from a guy like and you the way
you're growing regenerated yeah way
better
the proof is definitely in the pudding
you can see that when you're washing
like look at this is super clean leaving
no residue you know I'm not sure up the
heat how was that that was good dude I
got a really tasty dub off that that's
all I don't know I feel like
I might have heated it late though I'm
not sure I just pressed it twice and
then started ripping it yeah so go up so
what consistency like you can smoke this
out of that but like at what consistency
do you think you can't really use that
anymore for ash maybe the temple balls
maybe you know you're not gonna smoke so
we're lower melt like a fire like a
four-star Mel might be a little hard to
clean anywhere in there I think this
would be their third haze so yeah I
think there's enough for another little
Ripper in there so just hit it twice
right you can put me twice already just
hold it I just thought Oh long as you
want to hit it for you no okay hitting
it because twice as 12 seconds or
something something like that yeah it
just eliminates you having to hold it
down yeah okay I give this one a pass
it's a little better hey hold more you
know cuz the one before it held less and
I took own part is bigger yeah the
bucket I guess is this is a lot bigger I
would say double the size we definitely
just put a good-sized dab in there for
sure let's say now now there's some in
there still so and it's oh fuck yeah you
can take another head out yeah or if not
again let's keep in rotation right yeah
very cool
all right so we like that yeah not bad
and it has a charging to write an easy
charger yeah yeah I like that part it's
somewhere in there right yeah yeah that
thing so it's like standard right USB
yeah yeah this so you can you a twist on
yeah yeah but at my point is that's like
a standard thread which is a good thing
sure it's not like a proprietary like if
you lose it you got a yeah I can only
buy ours oh you think you can be able
you can use other charges with the pen
if you do lose this I think so
that looks pretty standard like with
other cigarette with other vape carts
when are you finding every shop nice
perfect not bad alright so what would
you want puff co to improve on with the
peak like if you could give them some
constructive feedback damn that's a good
question
I feel like they've done a really good
job to be honest um like maybe the only
thing they could do would be like
include a quartz atomizer like a quart
not of course atomizer a quartz bucket
instead of just having the ceramic
bucket I know
I mean I've dabbed off the quartz ones
and I definitely think they taste better
it'd be sweet to have like a puff Co one
because not every quartz bucket like
aftermarket like fits well on these so
other than that like everything's pretty
awesome I've had this for like almost 16
months now and you model it really well
thanks man but uh I was telling him like
I haven't I barely clean it like the
atomizer he gets pretty gunked-up and
like I leave it in my hot car well I
mean while I'm working and stuff and
like it's never never failed me I've
just had to replace the little $39
miser so loosely maintained yeah loosely
maintained so I'm pretty stoked on the
I'm the puff co it's very cool it's not
like I'm taking it for every dab but I
like that when you show me what you
carry around in your bag um here you
have like the torch oh yeah
so everything's on the table but we got
like all the Terps in this little like
plastic jar plastic Tupperware thing
that goes in the cooler and then yeah I
like you carry it around show oh yeah
just in case anyone wants like that
fresh press you don't want that to
butter out yeah someone walking around
with a six-pack all day right yeah I
love this thing it's like my dad's old
cooler it's like pretty it's like from
the 90s it's pretty sick playmate yeah
and then we just got a couple mats we
got all the caps and then we have the
Pelican case with the pipe this is the
not a pipe maker this thing's pretty
sweet crazy yeah I just got it it's
fairly recently it's definitely a fun
fun little apparatus to clasificado
product placement yeah say all right
he's the binary cap she she goes nice
she's a little sticky though for sure I
want to try that binary cap that has
that function yeah it's pretty fun you
can try it whenever but yeah and then
the puffs go good for wrong ago yes it
goes right in the side that's about it
know how those topicals for you guys
right here yes you have tappable - yeah
just I like just started making them
like messing with them so this is like
my first batch ever but like pretty good
I know a lot of people do it you know
it's like don't mix these up with the
door you ever done this I have
confidence that you probably do oh
thanks man
and you keep these cool - um you don't
have to buy like yeah keep them in a you
know like not in the Sun or anything
small places like my wife would have
yeah yeah just beeswax and coconut oil
with live rosin like full-spectrum la
cookies live rosin and then there's some
like full-spectrum sea
as well it's like a four to one ratio
Verizon to CBD so it's like teats I know
just rub it like on your face and your
yeah wherever you want to have really
from have some pain it I just kind of
rub down on my shoulders I didn't really
have much choice when it tries to I
don't ever have any aches and pains yeah
it kind of makes you chilled out and I
want to have them so I can like right
that's what I wanted like the other day
I was like why don't I hurt right now I
want to test this on myself and like I
was like I'll just put some on my neck
it doesn't really hurt but it my neck
did feel like yeah yeah thank you man
for sure alright so why don't we do you
want to walk us through the line um yeah
what you brought sure I'm down and why
you're proud of it for sure yeah um I'll
go for it okay so let's see first we
have this right here cream day mate so
it's cookies and cream crossed oh it's a
mixed wash so cookies and cream two
different fee knows of creme de menthe
both of those strains are from exotic
genetics and then mixed with GMO which
is like a staple in my garden something
everyone yeah especially if you make
hash especially um so yeah there's that
and then we have some strawberry banana
this is probably my favorite strain in
my variety of cultivars that I grow do
you like it as flower - um I honestly
don't really like smoking flower that
much okay just because when I first
started using cannabis like I got right
into concentrates right away it's like
the the flower smoke is like a little
like gnarly for me but I still love
smoking it from time to time like I know
yeah yeah but I'll still be stoked on
some like song foul rips you know I got
a little bong sovereignty and stuff to
rip out of here
there once am I on this yeah well you're
smoking a lot of good hash it's like I
don't know it's it's different when
you're it's so goodbye like it's
different though I have my favor hold on
one second I have a height like my fair
share of years of smoking ripping flower
me yeah yeah like just today I try to
rip a fat bowl right like I used to I
got halfway through I had to stop but
he's in hospital I feel you I was like
what it guess what they're learning
Brett before that I took a huge dab yeah
no problem right guys like oh my gosh
oh yeah sometimes I'll like smoke flower
for the beginning of the day and then
I'll like go to take dabs and then it's
like damn like I can really like smoke
the dabs it's like even more smooth you
know because you're like yeah nicotine
those guys oh damn
that's what they roll is absolutely
literally a stop coffee well yeah so now
imagine doing that and then imagine
having to work two cameras I know that
all the cameras people on the state like
hey I was in the audience and you were
you were you're doing good
yeah the mic could get questions and
everything yeah I was impressed oh yeah
that was that was a fun time right but
yeah yeah well what do you guys feel
like once you get to solve unless you
get the better full flavor yeah and it's
not that harsh and it's kind of hard to
like yeah you can spoil yourself
sometimes so yeah I see it plenty guys I
still like monopoly melts is one guy
that would be like saying I can get my
cigarette so why would I ever smoked a
cigar oh I feel that I feel or
cigarettes in general right cuz you guys
easy yeah maybe they just shouldn't be
compared they should be enjoyed yeah I'm
saying I'm saying yeah yeah being a
champion right flower I'm saying to you
guys give it another chance
no there's some great like honestly all
starts I wanna you know what I want to
do alright you don't smell like the
flower
yeah I'm sure that I'm safe from some
flower for me yeah cuz I want to try
like it in flower for a man cuz like the
reason why I don't think I really like
flowers cuz there's no like there's
amazing flower around I
but there's no like true like like
living soil like consciously grown
flower and like the rare north yeah I
know the rare time that I've seen that
around here like one of my my buddies
ogre farms like they do like an indoor
living soil garden like it was a while
back there Gorilla Glue was like some of
the like cleanest it was like I was like
smoking like a hash table smoking the
flour it was like and I know that
quality is out there and I will like
happily smoke that all the time in labs
I had a buddy that bought some of their
stuff and I tried their flour and
actually smelt the way yes I'm not a
proper yeah so really they're doing like
where they run where Colorado yeah well
no no there but what about it I assume
you got it in California not yeah
there's they have a few dispensaries out
here they drop off this one was I think
they don't put a safe port and pour any
me that's where my friend got it and I
think they're grow is out of Oakland and
I put them on camera over I'm like you
but tender like oh cool shot coherent
Lee's like camera start talking around
the shop and he's like to clean spot
they have their yeah I've never been
over there I've been I was H what is a
port hueneme page the other one there's
another man shot I used to be a third
floor and that one was packed with
people yeah no no it I used to I used to
be like all about that scene for a while
yeah and for sure scene yeah I guess is
my senior remember you from last week
yeah I used to make it a purpose to like
stop it and he just passed by you so
bate have a sales job like all over
Southern California and if there was one
nearby right near one of my calls I'm
like sure he what's up it was pretty
cool compare I remember going to like WH
TC and like those studios to these stops
I would get like the select little like
hash drops in like 2016 and like be
waiting at 10 and there'd be like a like
a 10 person like line of like hash
smokers at the door is pretty pretty
sick those were the good
it's prop 215 days so quickly I can't
remember how far install yeah oh I the
other question is where are you getting
your genetics yeah
for each okay all so far um so as you
continue down okay well this is where I
got it from for sure right this is a
exotic yeah so I'm so just real quick so
the creme de GMO the GMO I got it's a
clone only so I got that from ogre farms
he was kind enough to let me grab that
from him and then the other two the
cookies and cream and the cream D GMO
were grown from seed from me there's
like two different phenotype creme de
menthe in there so you were breeding and
basically I was at you bred yourself um
I didn't breed it because it's just like
a mixed water but I did Fino hunt them I
just taught the seeds and and found like
my two favorite fie nose out of like the
12 that were growing and washed the only
the two and like just dried the others
for flour and whatnot and then the
strawberry banana this was I got from a
clone the live rosin I grew from clone
from cloneville I got like I kind of
took a chance on this clone I wasn't
super familiar like how this Fino washed
most strawberry bananas do great for
solvent list aim it this way yeah but I
grow a lot of it yeah it was an it's an
amazing cut yeah it's a great one for
hash I'm super stoked on the Terps it's
very like strawberry dominant for sure
so there's the live rosy right away yeah
yeah and then the melt is right here
first wash 90 you to 159 so there's like
the 90 and 120 bag in there I feel like
that strawberry banana is very potent
kind of like a GMO yeah the melt I
prefer it way over the bras like the
nozzles great but like the metal is just
we'll talk the press some jobs out of
this so there's those two and then we
have straight GMO this is just some live
rosin right here that's for my light DEP
these other two strains were actually
just full-term from this year
voltar mating like yeah yeah
so this is really light depth in in the
hoops right yeah I got two hoop houses
that I did light that over the summer
and then I did some other just full term
full season was like oh yeah it's um
pretty coastal coastal yeah so it's like
cool and then like cool nights like hot
days it's pretty we had a pretty warm
summer it gets pretty warm where I'm at
actually but in the wintertime it's like
a drastic change like warm days cold
nights it's not crazy humid we're pretty
dry but it's definitely more humid than
like the San Fernando Valley and places
like that in my opinion so is there
stuff that you tried to grow there that
you're like this doesn't like this
climate and other stuff you're like yeah
for sure like um it's like I definitely
I definitely selected it down to four
strains but there's a lot of stuff that
I had to wean out like there was like
this lemon cake that didn't do very well
oh is that something that you know has
done really well somewhere else
I don't yeah and it's a lot of it's just
like yeah like all grow things that I
maybe feel like they take longer to veg
or they're a little harder to grow if
they're worth it
for hashing because everything I'm
growing is for hash like I'm growing for
resin not flour so that's okay to me but
like there's definitely strains that are
just like completely like you know a
Miss but you have to have those losses
to like find the gems
so yeah it's hard to find a podcast did
you say you're growing and like raised
beds or pot sir yeah raised beds okay so
they're uh just homemade raised beds
with wood like four by four there are
three by twelve and then I have some
four by eights as well for like three
and H or something um I'll put so
there's actually three by six beds
there's four
so they're like next to each other
making them 12 feet long and I'll either
do two plants by like 10 plants per bed
or I'll sometimes do three but I've been
kind of trying to do less plants as of
recently and just get them larger so and
so the soil you're putting into these
raised beds where's is it local is it
are you building it up with stuff yeah
so I'm building soil um a lot of people
are familiar with build a soil calm so
they have multiple recipes I use like
their number one recipe so I use I
didn't use their ingredients I use like
locally sourced ingredients like a
locally sourced my compost might say you
want to buy like what they're showing
right in there they're wrestling yeah I
use their recipe and just sourced all
those ingredients locally and then like
all the dragon Earth fly medicine group
is like very influential in the garden
too and like I use they're huge on
native soil because that already has
like the intelligence of your area right
so anytime I'm building soil I always
like to add some of my native soil in my
yard and like I hope at some point you
shouldn't need to buy anything from
right tackle is to be like now how
sustainable yeah and now I have that
soil training wheels come off exactly
yeah
this so it's just like it doesn't happen
overnight but every step you take like
it's just gonna get better and better
and like it's so amazing after each
round yeah yeah it's like it's my first
year of doing like full no-till full
living where it's like we're not buying
any new soil or putting like worms yeah
so we didn't add any worms um but we
like do methods to like attract worms
like there's like an avocado method
where like you can cut up an avocado and
lay it on the bed and it'll be like a
breeding ground and like an attraction
for for worms can get into the raised
bed yeah so though cuz my braised bed
you like connected to the ground yeah
yeah so they'll call come up but
sometimes like I have indoor moms that
are living soil and they're just
containers so those I will have to add
worms separately but yeah it's crazy
anyway people come in and really like
are you like composting on site or
we have a compost pile on site we have
like a Hugo Hugo culture if you're
familiar with that to you yeah there's
like a little spot on the side it's just
like such a rich area yeah you can see
take like you dig a hole you put like
logs and stuff in okay and then you
cover that yeah and then that's tough
break like think of how nutrient-rich
like if you walked through a forest like
smell rotting log yeah that's what
you're planting your plants is - yeah
and they're just like this is amazing
yeah and that stuff keeps breaking I've
seen it yeah that was the name of it
I've seen like pictures of that stuff
right yeah I like slowly breaks down so
you're doing that with a portion of what
you're growing not all of what you're
drying yeah we're like I'm planning on I
keep saying we but it's just me yeah my
team of two hands but uh we yeah next
for next year's season I'm like building
Hugo's right now and stuff this is the
time of year to like be building soil
and like beep referent preparing for
everything to be breaking down and
getting ready for next year so I have a
couple spots that I want to like do some
more new Hugo's and then I have the
other spot so very cool yeah yeah I'm
pretty stoked on on this coming season
even though it's like a ways away but
it's coming I only have between my two
greenhouses it's only about 400 square
feet of canopy and I have another like
300 square feet of like full-term
growing space basic so if we're talking
craft you would fit that definition yeah
a very small batch craft for sure yeah
very good craft yeah thanks man yeah I'm
saying what do you think of the quality
of this small batch craftsman thinks as
one hash maker to another yeah holy
OnPoint thanks man appreciate it
you didn't let down any expectations
today at all nope though we still have
plenty flavors to try I know yeah that's
I think I use this over here a little
closer right as you show it I should be
trying Yeah right
yeah so that was a strong animal we got
the crème de GMO yeah we did the normal
GMO this is some normal straight GMO
melt right here this stuff is pretty
special I feel like it's some of the
melty it's like hash I feel like I've
washed it's kind of like a soil it's
pretty nice pretty noise yep I'm pretty
hyped on that so this way check that one
I don't want to compare to the GMO right
yeah yeah that's all the melt in the
rosin yeah yeah that's what I came from
right right
that was that yeah well this it's all
melted in here now but this is the hash
that makes the rosin so this is your GMO
rosin yeah GMO and this is second press
rosin so it's not like top notch it's
new usually the fresh the first press is
a little a little bit you know why this
is this is second second press yeah Wow
I think yeah so you talking about you
have the bag you have the hash in it you
press it on the press yeah that's your
first press and then you repress that
right I got this right exactly yeah oh
Andres yeah cuz like now that's even
more impressive thanks man
it's not like I feel like a lot of us
like you do with his hands tied behind
his back right like he's gonna yeah if
not the best material material well no
it's like a lot of guys don't do the
second press they they'll press it once
and then that bags done yeah it goes
away
yeah and I got it I'm like hard times
like I need to smoke I pull out a bag
rosin you have ten bags the sonic we're
pressing every little well like I'll put
like all the bags together at the end of
my pressing session and press it and
like that'll just be what I'll dab out
of off of like the peak for a couple
days there's nothing you know and it's
still of quality like I'm not pressing
like super high and I'm not pressing for
a long long time so there is still some
press depends
yeah yeah but I feel like I'm definitely
getting the majority I like there's only
two grams of second press from like
because you know 100 grams of first
press if you didn't go full crazy
pressure on it you know like you ain't
yeah halfway and not to owe it right
press coupie fire
this fire yeah it's Sunfire right bring
your press right it's heavy but like no
I didn't bring it
I didn't uh wasn't think about that but
we have that guy there
nice do you feel like trying to figure
that out right I'm super high as I'm
sure you are too but you've used those
before yeah it's easy plug and play for
sure I have some flour actually do we
have anything like a bags
oh yeah and I think that comes with like
all that stuff right there right hey
people I do have some toasted oat flour
and they kind of go kind of cool let's
just plug it in and see any hashish the
press see what happens here we move
beside some of this glass yeah why don't
we we can actually maybe take that stuff
off the table okay right cuz that we
just put the whole thing up there right
check this guy was it beveled like that
interesting
oh it's a hat Oh put this stuff like
over here
okay so pretty much as heavy as the
other one that's good these two plugs
back here I mean pretty simple yeah
that's what I figured that's a lot of
buttons or anything there's not a lot of
wires hanging on the back here that it's
got two two wires basically that has
like your thermocouple in there and your
heating elements plates this is kind of
cool so you know I kind of bring my
finger on it
cool so then there's a came with that
stuff see here 160 that could be here
you go
120 yeah let's see if we can set the
temperature let's see for a flower I
think like wait you have flower red yeah
what do you think camphor flower usually
like a low 200s I feel like that yeah up
to 10 maybe 220 I can't remember what
you so much flower a dude fuck I was
usually at 207 and like it's high like
230 maybe yeah so you you don't ever
press flower
I don't I usually punch I started
pressing for this flower do you like
doing it yeah so what don't you like
about it um it's nothing alike don't
like pressing it I just like don't
really like like smoking flower rose on
that ledge I don't know I'm texting with
lipids and waxes I think yeah like I
don't know it's just all so it's like a
very time-consuming to make I feel like
it's like you have to press prep so much
file I'm like pressing her ashes just so
much like more fun but yeah another
flower kind of like butter is up
I don't know flower awesome was such a
big thing and it's it's such a no it's
super awesome there's an awesome like
meditate this seat is strategically
placed perfect but I think sauces like
shunned upon now in a way not really
look like ya know it's sick it's just
like some people are yeah yeah you gotta
pack it and tight and yeah has to be
really the Vittorio yes you have a good
start
people they don't want to experiment
with their good stuff yeah there's been
some bum flour rosin for sure so this is
interesting so they have a little pre
pre press here and what is this
seventy-three micron stuff this is stuff
that my you know I would say this is
washable found some Mac C I think will
do the one to the 120-mile Ron what do
you think Cameron and then this this
said these guys do the Hugo beds oh for
their in Sonoma oh yeah
sick and Jodi's here in LA like half the
time so he the other part I know and
then this was the indoor stuff that bar
nice so this is where I went today
yeah right no progress interesting so
here's the bags no gloves but do you
heard of all textile pressing no I don't
know I don't think so so like they Nook
smashers like what was the first Rossum
press that I got a little minnow yeah
yeah my buddy how's that yeah they do
very good tutorials and videos you know
nice for teaching yes getting started
and they did this bottle textile for
this kind of situation where you're kind
of doing smaller presses you know right
and the way they fold the bag they
invert the corners and then they fill it
up you know once you pre pack it yeah
hopefully this is how they have it
worked out should slide in here right
but they they have a pre press like that
where it kind of works perfectly with
their bags
so let's see how this one works out but
this way when it smashes down it's like
a cylinder it makes a good puck so it
has a nice tight surface area word so
there's like a method to folding it in
like this yeah interesting so let's see
how this is gonna work but it's find out
anyone ever told you you should be a
hand model
I should probably cut my nails body out
of the shot right hands just these man
hands yeah so let me grab some flour you
don't have a scale usually like and I do
yeah right
see yeah yeah this cherry punch looks we
go yeah nice oh they all think is it
enough I mean this probably enough to
press but I get probably small price out
of one of those yeah let's see how it's
dosey doe goes no see yeah a little
endured Oh see this come off I think it
just lays out yeah okay I wasn't using
as a tray we'll see let's go raw yeah I
think these were all like 2.6 oh
definitely done smokes are you saying
this stuff you brought yeah I'll press
and look it saved
we could try pressing one of those you
want to we're gonna start with that yeah
so where'd this come from
this came from the indoors of Ojai
undisclosed location see this is super
dense some good rosin yeah so there to
get 3.8 3.8 right there so I compared to
the one you use how would you describe
this like in terms of the price yeah
functionality is very the same you know
pretty much so I mean it's pretty pretty
straightforward you know you
the bottle jack press the plates up here
I like how he has the so on one does
this is that thing like the mat like can
you do your own this one's all manual so
you have the manual
that's what I'd rather have that yeah I
kind of die I want to learn kind of just
how to like manually work it uh-huh
and I like this too because you feel it
you get you kind of feel it tightening
up as you press it and you know when
it's too much is you know you don't want
to blow out but I like this easily
quickly manual mine I like having mine
out of this area you know it was back
here oh yeah so that can kind of stand
right here get it up in here it's like
but you know this is cool
so yeah I've been to the releases here
as a quick turn and it drops it down you
turn the right way it must be down ya
know so I when I was trying to figure it
out I like unscrewed that completely and
I was looking in there as I did it and
this oil started shooting out and I was
like ah fuck and I quickly screwed it
back in Oh interesting
we're good here I should loosen this
it's just not turning the and maybe
because I completely unscrewed it could
be I don't think I'll be able to get it
release back down
the press yeah is there like something
wrong I think so it can't know I've
never used one of these rosin these are
one of the og ones huh
what is that nob supposed to do release
the press release release the plates
down gotcha cuz it should you should be
able to loosen it see I'm loosening it
but the nuts coming off with it and it's
not moving the threaded bowl
yeah you know so I think it's like if
you had to if we took this off we could
probably loosen it ourselves
yeah you see that he's gonna come off
yeah that was fall off yeah and if you
just keep tightening he's just gonna go
in there yeah I just tightened up
against the metal yeah cuz if we could
tie in it and that thing supposed to be
like you could pull it out or you lift
it up did you really just loosen it like
right now it's super it's like yeah
tight backfield is cranked yeah it's not
loosening the plates yeah because this
because the bolts on the wings of this
one this won't do anything I know see
this so what if we did press a we just
won't be able to release it at all yeah
oh we couldn't get it in there and you
just press forever that's interesting
how they have this no cuz this isn't
moving this is what a when you and when
you in screwed it you loosen this bolt
why I wonder if I just get a something
to grab on to it
yeah we could definitely tighten and
loosen it but then we're gonna ruin
these threads so we're gonna leave you
with a little cliffhanger until the next
time we all get together we're not going
to review the rosin press today because
when I first got it and I was playing
around with everything before I even
plugged it in I basically unscrewed this
thing till it popped out and as I was
peeking in here
I saw the hydraulic fluid starts
squirting out and I freaked out and I
quickly twisted it back the bolt back in
but I had twisted it and I didn't
realize it and so we were shooting and
we finally turned the thing on that it
was off thread so when we're trying to
twist this thing it wasn't grabbing the
bolt to twist it and what this bolt is
is the release valve so that when you
press and once you're done pressing to
release it you just twist it like a
quarter turn counterclockwise and the
plates come apart so we will review it
very soon but let me just quickly show
you so what I did to fix it was
basically put this thing on its back so
that when I unscrewed the bolt so the
hydraulic fluid would not come squirting
out so basically what I did was i
unscrewed the bulb and then I screwed it
back in so it's I guess threaded or not
off thread whatever the word for that is
now actually I don't even need to plug
this in to show you so basically this
sorry all right here we go
so now take two so now this is screwed
all the way in snugly look at that so
this Ron you kind of stop it right there
for a couple seconds and then you finish
it and then now when you want to release
the plates oh look at that it is back to
normal a perfectly working unit now let
me just screw that in so I wanted to do
it again anyway we'll review it again
shortly sorry about that and on to the
next episode part two of this extended
two-and-a-half hour conversation