[Music]
foreign
how's everyone doing today
I guess we'll start out and have
everyone introduce themselves my name is
Taylor tviesel I do solving this Viking
company I'll do little egg Valley Seed
Co
op and so what did you say everybody
see
my name is Alice I do a bunch of like
hash with Flynn in the underwork sauce
but I'm also an educator throughout the
company I own called girls and drink
and I'm Brazilian maybe though
maybe bring a different Brazil
perspective
hi I'm Flynn and uh I do walk sauce
Winery and then also fully melted at a
southern hub
hello okay all right I'm Todd resin
Ranch extraction uh obviously like these
guys I do non-solvent uh I'm out of
Nevada County these days
welcome
so I think we'll start out and ask
our panelists here about how they go
about selecting their plants for
solventless
and how they go about in the garden
choosing the right plants like when
they're Fino hunting
and uh so Flynn once you start us up
okay
um for me I guess like the first box
that always needs to be checked with
like anything that I personally am
looking for Fino hunting and stuff is
like Terps like I'm looking for
something that has like at the end of
the day is amazing when it's growing but
we all know sometimes when you are
smelling a plant growing and then you go
to Hash it you get a very different
version of things and maybe not what you
expected and sometimes you don't but uh
for me it's about Terps first and
foremost and then at the end of the day
like resin per square foot because you
got to make things work from uh you know
I guess commercial perspective from a
business point of view and things like
this so when you're doing that at that
level that's definitely a perspective
you kind of always need to take into
account so that's kind of the next thing
but the first thing is something unique
and something that I haven't seen before
and something that I'm you know stoked
on myself I guess is someone that you
know sees a decent amount of hash so
yeah
how about we have Marley introduce
himself oh yeah all right here we go
all right my name is Marley
There you go yeah hello there you go all
right we're we're live live and direct
Middle Town let's go
yeah thank everybody for coming out
um my name is Marley I do conjuna
extracts
um and big shout out to Humble local and
Joey you know and tomorrow for putting
this on it's super cool
um having something like this in the
community and we all love good hash you
know so super awesome to see and uh yeah
I'm just a local here you know I just um
grow hash and grow weed and make cash
and you know keep it rolling and
my brother does a little farming too and
we collab and uh yeah just all about
putting out some good products for
people to uh smoke on
go ahead Tom yeah about your selection
on the garden how you start out oh boy
that's a tricky question for me uh grow
it and fucking send it pardon my French
send it through the wash and see what we
get on the other end no uh
I mean Flynn Flynn covered a lot of it
there the these days specifically more
than anything it's the Terps everything
it's all about the flavor so the first
thing we're looking for is something yes
that is unique that pops out flavor-wise
we're not looking for you know the same
run-of-the-mill stuff that everybody
else has for me particularly I'm kind of
on a a little bit different trip these
days to kind of go back and find
older flavors that I remember from when
I was younger that I smoked in high
school that I loved like you know sour
D's making this comeback that was one of
my favorite favorites cushes stuff like
that but
on the selection note yes Terps first
um another thing that I've started to
focus more on personally is the plant
structure itself too
and uh things that are Hardy because in
the past I have selected things
basically just off the turfs and how it
washed and not the plant structure or
the hardiness of the plant and after a
few years of growing those things and
having them in the mix with other plants
it tends to just sometimes bring
problems that I just don't need like
some plants will be way more susceptible
to pests
and it might make great hash but the hat
that the structure on the plant sucks it
needs a shit ton of support it just kind
of grows like crap it likes to get past
so it's like after a few years working
with that kind of stuff I'm kind of
moving on from that and focusing a
little bit more towards the Terps and
the plant structure and the hardiness of
the plant itself versus just is this
good
because I also want to be able to have
be able to give that possibly give those
genetics to other people and them have
success with it and it not be a finicky
pain in the ass that
everybody just ends up having problems
with
um
yeah I mean I could probably go on for
days
Marley we were asking the panelists to
talk about how they go about first
selecting plants uh where they even want
to go about making starting to make the
hash like where do you start out in the
garden for looking at plants
um I guess we're starting out
um I go basically for stuff that I want
to smoke personally you know I like to
uh bring the flavors that I see out
there and bring them to people who might
not have access
um so I just kind of go for seeds mostly
uh I'll run some clones you know if I
find a nice cut of something but I feel
like uh there's just a lot of diversity
in the seeds and a lot of vigor and so
that's usually how I like to start out
you know start with the seeds and make
some good selections
[Music]
yeah you know the structure is a huge
thing for me too you know like you said
um you know it's popping a pack you know
I don't want to have a some plants that
are just kind of weak you know I kind of
try to call those off the bat
um but then also like for potency and
Terps
um I love the Terps you know but um
I gotta have that potencies too
um smoking a lot of chirp heavy stuff
lately has definitely made me like okay
I need to run something that's high high
potency that's just gonna like hit me
nice so um so I like to select for that
type of stuff
and now what about a resin structure so
after you guys have obviously most of
you are selecting for terpenes at first
structure those sort of things so after
you find the plant that has the terpenes
it has the structure
how are you going about
selecting the plant that you even want
to test wash like what signifies to you
something
that you can observe and you're like oh
okay I actually want to test wash this
plant compared to something you're like
yeah I don't even have to test wash this
I mean oh shit I'll go first
um yeah that's what I was just thinking
to myself because we didn't even get
into the resin and When selecting these
plants
um I'm gonna be totally honest and say
that
these days the things I used to think
and I used to look for
I've been thrown for a loop so many
times the last two seasons
I don't know okay I've been thrown for a
loop so many times the last two seasons
with doing the like you know touch the
buds you know how stringy it is how
Sandy the res it is
you know is it is it super sticky is it
like the cherry pie that you touch it
your fingers literally just wet
obviously that's something
forget about that that plant is not
going to do anything
I don't know what's up with this mic but
can you guys hear me
everybody hear me okay
hello hello hello hello
I lost my train of thought because I'm a
stoner
uh okay yeah so going off of how you
touch it it's wet yeah it's just wet
like you do you touch it you just see it
on your finger it's just wet where other
things like we were just talking about
cookies and cream so I'm going to use
that for example you touch that and you
can literally see the heads whole just
sitting on your finger like little
Marbles and it's it's like sand between
your fingers that's obviously that's
gonna wash usually pretty well however
I've ran into a few in the last two
seasons that I touched that are Uber
grease and still washed well
so
now I I'm kind of it I'm kind of at the
point when it comes to the actual resin
I I send it through a jar I do the jar
test which I'm sure a lot of you people
have seen and Adam does the resin dial
now
and I I just you know I get a visual
representation for those that may not
know what a drug test is could you see
yeah yeah absolutely so we take uh a
large mason jar and I I specifically use
20 grams of fresh weed so I will throw
the weed in there the ice a little water
let that sit in the freezer for like
five or ten minutes just to get
everything to the safe temperature we'll
shake that for 10 minutes and then we
will just let that sit and settle for
like a half hour or so and see what
settles to the bottom and then kind of
work it to the corner let it settle to
the corner and after doing that a bunch
of times and then washing that material
you start to be able to get a visual
picture of okay this this is about three
percent or this is about five percent
and I use 20 grams because visually we
kind of all know what about a gram looks
like and if it's a gram on 20 grams then
it that's a five percent return which
you're killing it then so
you know that's always a really good
sign so I'll do the jar test just to
kind of see what is there
but I I'm still a fan of
doing a larger test wash batch like
maybe 2 000 wet grams so I'll do the jar
test first
I would prefer to always do a test wash
but these days I'm just committed to the
hash so if it does a decent jar test we
send it and we wash it and then we get a
full representation of what is there
unfortunately the jar test doesn't tell
you if it's a sticky bag strain which is
just going to stick to your bags and
dunk everything up
so the selecting the plants you know
just off of field I've kind of gotten
away from that and I I do use a
microscope to
not so much to check the color but to
check the structure of the trichome is
it a long stock with a big head or is it
a really short stock with a small head
and we're you know we're generally
looking for a little bit of a longer
stock with a big fat head on top of
there usually those will fall off pretty
easy too much of a stock
sometimes you end up with a lot of stock
in your house so
I could probably I'm probably going to
start rambling here but so I've kind of
personally gotten away from the touch so
like I don't have really a straight
answer to that question it's a lot of
experience and uh uh for me it's just
committing to this is what I do and I'm
gonna wash this anyhow so
I tend to find out
good or bad you know
okay
um
yeah so same thing like he was talking
about the finger feel like um that's
probably like my main indicator
um just feeling like how it feels on
your fingers if it's sticky if it's
Sandy or if because like you said you
know the oily ones
um you can just tell right off it almost
feels like you like touched some type of
canola oil or something you know and uh
so I feel like that's kind of my first
indicator of something that's going to
be hard to wash
um and I feel like the second thing I
look for when like popping a pack of
seeds and doing a hunt through a pack is
um just the ones without any Terps at
all because sometimes you'll get all the
way through the cycle flower to plant
out and it uh it still doesn't really
have strong chirps you know so I'll try
to cool those ones pretty quickly
um and and if you're gonna like mix the
phenos you know into a wash I'd like to
call the ones that are turpless so it
doesn't affect the quality of the rest
of the wash
but yeah that's mainly what I that's how
I select
yeah I'd say honestly I agree with title
I've moved away a lot from the hand feel
stuff just because I feel like I've been
proven wrong A lot of times on things
that I thought one thing and then the
whole opposite thing happened compared
to what the hand feeler even sometimes
the microscope told me but
um a lot of the times like
it's surprising too when you start to
measure like resin per square foot some
of those two percenters depending on
like if they're really putting out a lot
of fresh frozen weight and flour you
know even though it's greasy even though
it's hard to work with like Smarties for
example is my per you know our example
for explaining this always is like
struggle to hit like two and two and a
quarter percent with that strain even if
you crush growing it and it is the
greasiest most annoying fucking resin to
deal with but it is
crazy good A lot of people really like
it you know it's like one of those
things that's just like you don't see
that type of like blue candy flavor if
you guys have had like blue Diesel and
stuff from Oregon or no like kush for
breakfast genetic stuff like that
um it's just a very unique terpene
profile and even yeah and uh I think
like a funny thing that we figure out
what the smarties do is like starting to
wash strings together which is something
that we would not do and then the
smarties was so annoying that and and so
much from it would stay in the back that
we started using the super dry resin
like the cookies and cream that we were
discussing to wash together so when we
started washing together all that resin
was falling in the bag and it was not
sticking to the bag anymore
yeah I mean considerably yeah like it
would just like make a like get the bag
stuck you know and then you could work
easier with it so it was actually a good
strategy to have that cookies and cream
on the side and make sure sure you get
actually better yields and can work with
that material better because I'll say
sticky strains are very frustrating
because they do all the hard work to
grow it and you pay the power bill
depending if you do it indoor or not and
then all of that is in the bag and then
it goes to the iso that you clean your
bag so it's what do you do you
I I'm on a I'm on a thing this year of
purposely washing the sticky
strange that most people hate because I
personally think those usually make the
terpiest and best hash every time bro
okay
that's crazy every time like the
smarties it only hits two percent but in
a way it's worth growing because it
throws down on the flower weight like
even though
uh like cookies and cream it's awesome
it hits five percent but you do the
numbers like on a per square foot basis
they're actually like very neck and neck
the only reason the cookies and cream
comes out on top is because it puts out
more melt it's very hard to get melt out
of the smarties above like the 90 U bag
whereas the cookies and cream has like
90 up to 150 bags sometimes
yeah it's just one of those strains that
has like very clean dry resin that
you're gonna get a like very clean Melt
from but it puts out like half the wet
weight of the smarties so even though it
does like
more hash in a way it's way worth it to
run Smarties and way more than you would
think if you're maybe not the grower or
you don't look back and understand like
resin per square foot
um yields and stuff it definitely ends
up being a little more on the production
side of like washing and stuff but when
you're a cultivator and you take like
multiple months to grow something it'd
be that's very much less a factor that
you're thinking about a lot of times
okay uh what about
you know story of the ages right now
fresh pressed to Coke here do you guys
have certain strains that you have
practice on and you feel that the
bouquet of the strain is brought out
more in a fresh press or more in a cold
cure or do you guys you know just have
strictly you know certain things you do
like oh I only do fresh press it cures
on its own uh certain strains that you
only do cold cure on like uh
those sort of things
all right we're just talking about this
um excuse me
yeah uh the cold cure versus
fresh pressed debate it's kind of like
the skiers versus snowboarder debate
back in the day to me
um I love both okay I used to I'll be
totally honest I used to hate cold care
I thought that it was just a way for a
lot of people to hide stuff this that or
whatever I was a fresh press guy
working with more cold cure and I'm
going to be honest this guy here
listening to one of his interviews and
him talking about cold care and certain
strains
you bring more out with the Cure than
leaving it fresh where there are strains
that
I personally think aren't necessarily
left better fresh but are suitable for
fresh fresh pressed
um some some strains are just it's it's
kind of too potent and too spicy and
fresh press and uh the market doesn't
really like that and a lot of fresh
press doesn't have a nose to it and the
market doesn't like that so for me
specifically if it's got a good nose and
fresh press
and it's a strain that doesn't want a
butter super fast I will put a little
bit of it out in fresh press I'd ever do
anything just all fresh press or I will
do stuff all cold here but I usually
will only a couple strains pull out a
little bit of fresh press to do
because I I just got thinking about it
more and really looking into it more and
I I have to agree with Taylor down there
that a lot of strains end up better
after the Cure you can bring out more
flavors it gets a little bit of a deeper
flavor I think uh
so yeah that's where I'm at on it
yeah
uh you know I I agree with a lot of that
I love the fresh press and uh you know
it definitely does happen where a lot of
stuff isn't
um as
um loud on the nose and fresh breath so
I wouldn't say that necessarily there's
ones that I like better in one or the
other as far as the nose goes but
um as far as some strands of fresh press
just don't happen those you know so
there's ones that when they do really
smell good then it's it's a go for me
you know um but I like putting out more
too just because I feel like it's um
very saturated on the market right now
the coke here and um so I just feel like
off offering another option is uh is
nice for people and then they can kind
of experience just the um the like
complexities of the rosin as it changes
from fresh breads to cold cure
um but uh but I love stuff in cold here
too like you know they're they're both
just uh we all love rosin I I got one
other thing to say on that but he made
me think of
there are certain strains that I
wouldn't even cold cure going forward
honestly like I I've been hunting this
new 24K cut and the old one that I have
is like super terpy like
you kind of can't beat it if you like
orange Citrus but it cures out so dry no
matter what you do to it you can't get
that nice wet batter
and I don't mind that but the market
hates that so the 24K that cut in
particular I think is way better
represented in fresh press because it
doesn't have that dry cakey cold cure
and it has a really good nose the only
thing I don't like about it is that it
it tends to butter fast which is why it
dries out when it cold cures but that
that's one strain specifically for me
that like going forward if I keep
running that Fino it's just going to be
to do fresh press with
um I don't know I'd say I think it
depends on like and at the end of the
day the person who's maybe like
purchasing it what they would want I
think things can be represented well in
both ways I would definitely agree that
some strains you know for whatever
reason when you do the cold cure it
definitely adds like another level and
for me a more enjoyable experience maybe
versus the some strains in fresh press
but I would say that
fresh or a cold cure is like a little
bit more accessible for some people
especially that maybe are just kind of
coming into the solventless market and
maybe aren't used to
don't have maybe the education behind
like how to treat a fresh press so that
they have a good experience like
consuming it because some people will
buy a fresh press and maybe not
understand once it gets to a certain
stage how to whip it into a batter to
like keep it you know not get that dry
crumbly consistency that kind of gives
those like dry caustic dabs on your
throat stuff like that similar things
can happen with full melt people who
don't understand like gotta keep it in
the freezer basically to keep it nicer
you know to keep it out for like a
couple days unless you're going to smoke
it pretty quickly this type of thing so
some of it can come down to that type of
thing
um you know customer education around
like different types of products and how
to treat them and stuff but I would say
I really like a good fresh press and I
think it comes out and adds like a
different level of terp
um and definitely a different on a lot
of strains you get a different look kind
of depending on if you cold cure or if
you fresh press it and I don't know I
feel like we put out a lot of cold
turkey too because a lot of people that
would tend toward the fresh press would
actually really also tend toward full
mouth hash which we do a lot of as well
so it kind of allows like a lot of the
people who would want fresh press really
would also probably prefer hash anyway
so they're gonna go for like a full
amount you know like preserved resin
oh I think they covered everything so
I'll keep it as personal preference I
come from the traditional hash world so
I thought I was going to be a fresh
press person and I'm not I like cold
cure more and more in most of the stream
in most of the cultivars unless they get
super dry because if they start getting
super dry I split it out
is
um I spliff it out so I
um I had this jar of Z Light that was
traveling with me for a few months and
uh it was a full jar like a full five
gram jar and I that's always my to go
when I need something to calm me down
and I literally travel with it for three
months and in the third month it just
kept getting better and better and
better and then I hardly ever see that
with all the fresh frozen material to
work with I
when I was doing more like traditional
hash world yeah the Cure and the Aging
was something more special but uh I'll
say that I'll keep with the cold care
um
because if it's something fresh I'll
choose the hash
that's not okay and uh how about we
finish off and talk about maybe
something new exciting you guys have
found this year
uh a new strain you guys are really
excited about something you're really
hopeful for maybe uh something you
haven't washed yet you got still frozen
and you're like man this is you know
this is gonna be the one
I'm actually most excited to see
something from two different people one
of them is Todd he grew the Bop gun
number seven selection from me from the
trails from like a female hunt that's it
and then also uh Enzo who is 420 Nomad
707 who I you know we work with quite a
bit
um the uh the work sauce collaboration
stuff and uh they both grew it and
they're both in like very different
micro climates because Todd's in Grass
Valley where it's super hot and dry and
he's right in Sonoma County where it's
like very cold and wet for the most part
so I'm actually super interested to see
like the differences and how it came out
and then they both approached
cultivation from a very like similar
ethos so you know I definitely am
excited for that for me this year
because we took a break from growing
this last year after having some
civil fine difficulties I will say
I'm still thinking
it's so delirious
I'm really excited about the Z cam I had
that one out there I don't know if
anybody tried it but I really like the
zcam it's a z the Sunday driver to cam
uh and that one's from finest genetics
and uh yeah I like that one a lot it's
really stable in the fresh breath so far
it's been going on like almost five six
days in the fresh press at room temp but
it's pretty you know it's pretty cold in
the temperature right now but um I'm
really excited for that one
um you know I did five and a half
percent to hash and uh and a lot of it
came out nice and melty so I like that
cultivar a lot and uh you know I'll
probably keep it around keep working
with it and and pancakes is coming back
next year for anybody who got to who
liked the pancakes that is coming back
it's getting mommmed out it's got the
whole veg space
is coming back thank you man
um yeah it's kind of a hard one for me
no I know what it is I'm smoking on it
right now uh
we're calling it three-way Kush it's uh
puke
all right let me get it straight Ken
Valley Kush by pure kush by strawberry
Kush
from seeds I got at area 101 seed swap
probably in like 2017 maybe 2018 from
some old guy up on spyrock no idea who
the guy was but it had chem in it so I
was like awesome I'll take some and
honestly put those in the ground not
even knowing what to expect not really
thinking that I would get anything that
special from it uh
this is fire I love it
the uh the flower is way different than
the hash the hash to me came out like
that sweet Bakery Kush that kush can get
sometimes but like I had sex with a
chemical Factory or something
so like to me it's like right up my
alley somebody today said it spelled
kind of like cat piss which sounds crazy
I'm kind of totally into
um but yeah like it was a total surprise
I'm totally into it so that was kind of
like Kirby personally the one
out of the garden this year
but things I'm most excited about is
probably
I popped a bunch of Z by chem dog from
skunk Tech I'm pretty hopeful on those
and I'm gonna find something really
gassy in there nice like that's
that's kind of my trip right now so
bring that gas back
okay
ready have any questions for any of the
panelists
I know you had a bunch of questions for
Todd
I do have one question okay all right so
I see a lot of people post like 150 and
like the 120u like belt that's like just
mad clean
yeah you know super clean and I watch a
lot of outdoor material so obviously I'm
not pulling like the cleanest like 150
you heads and things like that like what
are these guys doing to get such clean
like big heads from outdoor uh clean 150
like that yeah I don't know man I rarely
see it very strange specific I will say
like we'll keep going back to cookies
and cream
y like these guys get like such a clean
120 even outside uh you know for me it's
I I just preached dust mitigation I
don't I don't do like a pre-rinse or
anything
uh I haven't found it to be super
effective with fresh frozen though I
have maybe a different tactic of doing
it if I did it again
um I have heard I have heard and I
haven't tried it myself of people
running double bags running like a two
two 150s this stuff is gonna get through
you know uh the other thing you can do
to like clean up the 120 on Outdoors
Don't Spray the 150. just like don't
touch the bag and whatever 120 and stuff
that gets caught up in there it is what
it is you know but I
you know we're we're pretty anal about
how clean that we can get it from the
outdoor we can only get it so clean yeah
so for me you know the 120 it's it's
hard to get it
like melt Quality Clean on the outdoor
it's really hard kind of no matter what
you do that's why I I will run the 120
the 104 bag and the 90 bag and usually
just put the 90 out as Mel which you
don't have a fat pull with that 104
really you'll clean the 90 up a lot you
know but keep going back to cookies and
cream just because it's it's just the
hash monster and I've seen it do things
I haven't seen other strains do like
pull clean 150 here on outdoor I
wouldn't
I wouldn't say it was clean enough to
put out his mouth
and I think I know what you're talking
about the 150 and I think I would say
the same thing on that yeah personally
yeah
yeah and maybe one of these guys has a
trick for yeah yeah let's hear it let me
learn something all right I got a little
trick for the 150 because uh I haven't
been big on the 120 150u for a while and
uh I have just kind of uh I realized
that part of it was the bags that I was
using there were some bags that I don't
know if maybe the Micron was
something wrong with it in the 120 but
it just wasn't pulling and I switched
Brands and it started pulling a lot more
in the 120 but but can I ask what
specific yeah you got to tell some
friends uh well the ones that I'm using
now are Bubble Bags okay
Bubble Bags 120 years yeah and then the
other thing that I noticed was um what
were you using before
I love the company so I have nothing bad
to say about them but just I just
noticed you know I tried but uh but I
would also say light diffused Greenhouse
cloth or plastic like I've been using uh
cloth that's even more diffused than
this right here you can see this is like
I don't know what it was maybe 30 or
something but I feel like I do like a 50
diffused cloth and I don't know if that
just gives better protection to the
trichomes it makes the heads be able to
get bigger maybe because of less
um you know less uh strength from the
Sun beating down on them
um but that with the greenhouse is also
from the wind I don't know if that
correlates but I've just noticed that
since
um like and this spring too I ran like
totally clear hoop houses and then my
brother ran all light diffused and I
noticed his definitely yielded more in
the 120 and was uh less of uh less of a
stable
um gland around the trichome you know
like the outside of the trichome was
more strong on the totally clear Hoops
to compared to the light diffused ones
the uh fresh press from that just kind
of melted into cold cure without much
agitation so I'd say the light diffused
is a big thing and I'm definitely going
to be running all that from now on like
the fuse cloth
uh yeah it kind of is yeah okay
definitely definitely it's a cloth it's
not a plastic yeah and it's yeah it's
almost white you know it's like pretty
diffused yeah I'd say anecdotally this
year uh ABR a farmer we work with uh
looks us a lot he moved Farms actually
just slightly just like one property up
the hill and actually one of the plots
is a lot shadier and I found like the
clean the berry crunch like the cleanest
resin I think I've seen from like depths
or personally that I've produced at
least from depths or stuff up here that
we've produced from depths and stuff has
been uh
just incredibly clean resin like as
clean as some of the stuff we've made
from our indoor and stuff it's just like
incredible which I usually don't see
from a lot of at least steps and you
know full sun full season I think it's
very hard to produce like good foam out
in the 150 full sun full season it's
Gonna Come
a lot down to genetics and then having
the right seasonals like so many things
you can't control it's just like the
coming together of you know the perfect
storm in a way
I was just in Chile now and I was very
impressed with like the quality of the
hash there like even though I'm from
South America I never expected what I
would see there and then one of the
cleanest hash we saw there was 150 to
179.
and I was like indoor but um I mean but
still you know like it's still like it
was just very impressive and uh I don't
know I'm a big fan of the big heads and
I know that on the out and on the
outdoors pretty challenging unless you
have all this like uh wind mitigation
like strategies but
uh with a berry crunch that he was just
mentioning it was very impressive to see
like such quality from like outdoor I
feel like the cleanest also I've ever
seen and it was nice to launch like
three different like microns like the 90
the 104 and the 120 so everyone could
just like taste it and actually taste
the difference like between the
different microns because that's
something that we get to do at home most
of the time right
when we're doing like the mount tests
and stuff but 104 definitely is
different yeah it's very different yeah
anybody else have any questions
oh bro you guys are off the hook
I'm ready I'm like just getting started
oh man
come on any any like I got another
question
obviously wash like material from a lot
of different people have you noticed
like a different in like people that
grow with salts and people that grow
organically like does it really make
that big of a difference in the hash
I could do that personally it definitely
does in like the size I've noticed like
we had a guy switch over to organic
growing from salts and every time no
matter if you pulled right no matter
what he did you'd always get a larger
percentage in the 73 bag the 120 and the
90s would be minuscule then we switched
over and got him into like living soil
and all this stuff and his plants
freaked out I mean we're starting to get
stuff in the 150 bags like we're talking
about yeah it just seems like the plants
just the way they responded they just oh
they literally blew up yeah yeah outdoor
growing yeah
I don't I only have you know my little
bit of personal experience
um and that's
fuck what was the question
oh yeah the salt I knew what it was okay
the Salters organic
um
I was totally thinking on the indoor
versus outdoor
um I mean
I I think that like the quality and the
flavor of the hash like it totally can
all be there with the salt
but
I mean I don't see that much of a
difference I don't feel like but I don't
feel like I also have really enough
experience
washing a lot of salt grown stuff that I
can really sit here and say like that
was probably a pretty decent sized Farm
I'm assuming that yeah you saw that at
so yeah he's like a 10 000 square feet
yeah I mean you know he's a good size
yeah I'd be seeing it on like nine
lights you know versus like 10 000
square feet so like I don't I just I'm
not really comfortable to say that I
think salts do anything bad
for to the resin or that there's a ton
of difference you know but I'm I'm
guessing there's a little bit
that in a way like when I started uh
growing together with Flynn Flynn was
growing with salts and then we did that
I did that for a while with him and then
we switched to organic and I feel like
the most drastic change I experienced
was ethical ethical you know and less on
the like resin quality because I seen
him like pulling the 150 full milk from
like uh uh indoor with salts around for
I remember when I met him he gifted me a
jar that's how he tried to like that
that's how he was like oh is this is if
he gave me like a baller jar of 150 U
full milk I remember that wash
good on the Progressive commercial with
the fishing pole but that's that's kind
of interest to interject a little bit
that's what I was kind of thinking about
but I can't get the thought out is that
what you're gonna see on salt versus
organic indoor and salts versus organic
outdoor I think are going to be very two
very different outcomes because pulling
a of a real proper organic indoor room
is breaking hard especially at scale and
at any scale even on nine lights it's
hard as hell to do a good healthy
organic indoor run
or outdoor that's really pretty easy
like you kind of throw some water and
worm shit at them and sun and they just
kind of rage you know but inside they
get really finicky so I think what you
you know what you're saying on the
indoor I that's why I didn't want to say
that like salts is better organic is
better because I think on the indoor I
think you can run some salts and some
bottles that are gonna like really make
those those strains perform and like
shine and I'm an organic guy and I'm
saying that so okay can we say that
organic is better because there's all
the ethical parts of it yeah
so even though I don't see that much
like Joey's not in here
that's what I'm saying like I'm an
organic guy and I'm saying this is
I'll put it like this I think under an
organic like more biologically based
system you are gonna see a wider breath
of strains be able to thrive versus with
a salt regiment you are going to have to
do a lot more tailoring to dial in what
each strain is really going to need
because you're really micromanaging
things at like a very small level which
is also why I think okay there are
definitely good
you know I've seen good resin grown in
indoor salt rooms but I don't think it
makes sense on a greenhouse or really at
scale in a lot of ways if we can figure
out how to do organic living soil
indoors like it makes sense from every
perspective cost of goods like
economically ethically it's just it's
been tough for people to apply that at
scale because big AG has created a very
simple system that basically relies on
these kind of exogenous costs that are
outside of the the supply chain and you
know cause things on the world and
individuals and things like that it's
not actually built into the people on
the production side and it creates this
kind of like
what I would call you know uneven
structuring in the market so sadly
that's how it's structured right now but
if we can change it and do it in a way
and I think in the Cannabis industry we
have this very interesting opportunity
because of where we're at in the
industry your margins are so slim on the
you know on the regulated side that if
you're the person who's growing into
organic living soil and your cost of
goods sold are so much lower than the
guy who's buying fertilizer which has
been getting more and more expensive
every year your business model actually
has way more longevity so from a
long-term perspective and not just this
growing a plant for one cycle
perspective I think
creating a balanced organic soil system
is always going to be better and give
you a larger breath of genetic variety
that will work well easily in that
system without having to change it
because we're talking about business for
a second
um resin per square foot
that's my shit yeah what's up with the
numbers if yeah listen so this is
important basically when you're doing
whole plant fresh frozen and you're on a
more vertically integrated system like
when you're just buying fresh frozen on
the open market you're really just
looking at what did it cost me to
produce this cramp but when you're
looking at your your vertically
integrated single Source washing your
own stuff you need to be looking at
resin per square foot because for
example you fresh freeze Smarties and
cookies and cream one hits two percent
one hits five percent what are you gonna
keep running cookies and cream but you
just bottlenecked your menu in a way
because you didn't realize that actually
if you do the math for resin per square
foot and understand how many square feet
did it take me to grow that kilo of
fresh Frozen versus this kilo and do the
math on like
basically you just have to say how much
resin did I produce how much square
footage did I produce it in that will
give you your resin per square foot so
however you want to do that if you're in
beds and you say okay
you know I grew a 60 by 100 of this
strain and I got this much resin for
that square footage that's how you're
going to want to measure every other
thing that you do so you're going by the
same standard and then looking at it
you're going to be able to say wow the
smarties even though it does are a
strain even though it does two and a
quarter percent when I go resin per
square foot it's actually only maybe 10
percent less than something else that
when I grow it in the greenhouse I'm
going to get three quarters or maybe
half as much fresh frozen because a lot
of strains that are
very good for hash you know not all of
them but a lot of them that produce a
lot of resin might not put out that much
flour weight so you really have to go
back to the resin per square foot like
we always used to do pounds per light
you know what I'm saying that's the real
measurement in a way not pounds per
light you really want to be grams for
water or grams per square foot depending
on what you're wanting to like base your
business model on and what your most
restrictive costs are and stuff like
that so I think
when you're when you get to the single
source and like vertically integrated
level and you're not working with like
fresh frozen on the open market looking
at resin per square foot is so important
and in the future like choosing genetics
based on that
is going to put people miles ahead
because you're not bottlenecking all
your things into this like five percent
model that a lot of people are on with
the fresh frozen because they're kind of
you kind of have to because you're
working with cultivators you're buying
it at a price point and then that's your
you know your economic variable that
you're working with so that was actually
my question was what is the number
you're trying to hit as we're at the
engineering farm with your grams per
square foot or resin resin perspects but
what is that number that you're looking
that's that's desired I know it's more
more is always desired right but what's
the number that's average or what's the
one that's kind of like topped here and
will catch your eye or Draw you in that
direction
it's hard to I guess compare because my
resin per square foot is based on like a
wholesale price that my assumption might
be like vastly different depending on
what I'm working with but you're you're
always going to be basically want to
compare things at your same wholesale so
you'll get a comparative but you're not
really amazing you're not maybe looking
for a certain dollar per square foot but
when you do your comparative across your
garden based on your wholesale because
if I say my number if your wholesale is
a lot different higher lower you're
gonna be at a way different number you
know I mean the number is Grand per
square footage it's like resin grams per
six foot okay
um
no no I just I'm honestly struggling off
the top of my head to remember what that
would be grams per square foot because I
always convert it honestly into Revenue
because that is my ultimate end
measurement is revenue also because I
have a tiered thing of like we produce
melt and rosin so some strains it's hard
to compare them at the resin per square
foot level because for example Smarties
and cookies and cream
it puts out like two and a half percent
just melt so the variable so the
variable and the and the wholesale rate
of that is different for me I look at it
different so it gets to be this kind of
like hard to compare but when you go to
revenue per square foot or grams per
square foot if you're producing all
rosin or you just have a equal wholesale
for things but in reality from a
business perspective you should be
looking at dollars per square foot so
you're gonna always convert your grams
per square foot to your wholesale price
and then look at your Revenue especially
when you maybe create multiple tiers of
product because one of the biggest
advantages in business and in the
Cannabis industry from a solventless
perspective is you have the ability to
create multiple products from one thing
so like when you do a bubble hash and
you do an ice water extraction you can
get a super high quality foam out a nice
rosin grade A food grade all of those
things versus someone who does the
solvent extraction is going to kind of
be able to give you back like one one
grade of things so a lot of people are
finding that
to really get all the profit out of
something like uh just a common like you
know business tactic is called Product
differentiation and it allows you to
actually extract all the profit possible
out of like uh manufacturing process so
when you're looking at that that's kind
of I guess the way I would look at it
and why it's hard to answer grams per
square foot also because indoor outdoor
Greenhouse you're going to be looking at
a lot different things too so yeah but
I'd say
let me think let me think about do some
quick math and then I'll get you the
grams per square foot on average on like
uh you know a like five by five type of
square foot oh yeah let me add to that
quick yeah not not on business but
something I've been talking about a
while and I don't have a straight answer
either because the first run I started
doing resin per square foot versus
percentage I did some mix loss it washes
so I couldn't
say exactly I got this much resin off to
square footage but I'm asking people to
start getting away from wash percentages
because everybody is tunnel visioned on
high wash percentage
we are missing things because they don't
wash at five percent it might wash it
two and a half percent
I'm just going to use the sour d for
example was the last room I grew grew
all right the strain next to it pulls
one let's just call it 1.5 pounds of
light sour d pulls three pounds of light
this strain washes at six percent this
strain washes at three percent in the
end the revenue is the same
that's that's the big thing to take away
from resin per square foot versus versus
is it a three percent wash or a six
percent washer and I think we're gonna
start as hashmakers opening ourselves up
to different genetics that we aren't
necessarily looking at because the hash
walk the percentage isn't so high but
the square per square foot number might
be you know the revenue in the end might
be the same so
that's my personal Vendetta to get
people off of just looking at percentage
and get more into resin per square foot
and resin per square foot is going to be
different for everybody based on how you
measure your square footage are you
measuring the table itself are you
measuring the room are you measuring the
canopy per run you know so everybody's
gonna have to start to come up with
their own Baseline of what is acceptable
in their Garden
and yeah so just food for thought
for me based on canopy size if my quick
math is correct like low end five and a
half high end like seven to eight grams
a square foot if you're in like GMO
numbers or like something that's hitting
like seven percent type of hype five to
seven grams per square foot of resin if
I'm if I did my quick math right that's
probably wrong
no maybe that's for yeah
come on
nope I'm sorry I'm being dead anybody
else have any questions
that was pretty
cool all right
well we'll end it with shout out to Gold
Country resin Drew he's in the house
love this guy right here another another
really talented hash maker
shout out to Hash camp that is happening
from the 2nd to the 4th of December uh
we are going to be back here December
2nd through the 5th for uh hash Camp
which we're gonna have watch demos I'm
gonna be doing a dry sift demo it's a
multi-day thing we're gonna Camp all
hang out for the weekend it'll be a
blast so something to look into are we
going to watch demo too I don't know
somebody is
um
it's gonna be fun it's gonna be a heshy
weekend like whoever loves hash and
resin and wants to come hang out learn
this because it's changed herbs
everything it's gonna be amazing
they're they're messing it up here
hey bro we can show the numbers
on average like one light let's say get
like 3 200 white grams on like a five
percent yield so 3 200 and like a
sixteen three times like 16 square feet
about five five five I I usually grow in
a four by four table but I always got
that little extra so yeah thank you guys
thanks for coming out thank you guys