[Music]
let's start with you as a hash maker so
how long have you been because you made
were you making hash first and then you
started the company yeah it started by
making hash necessity and where were you
living I was up north and my mom had
cancer and I had five sisters who
happened to know how to sew and they
help me sew a bag together because my
other bags were either they would get
confiscated coming from Canada happens
several times yeah it was a fun bill do
they even know that loss is a felony
back shit making hash was a bad thing
like five 10 second and I sort of can't
get over how it's come around full scale
now you know there's big factories
making hash with tables of people all
pushing that butter and massive scale
yes holy cow for these new states that
are getting legal we're getting calls
from Oklahoma now and they've got these
Oklahoma's blowing cash factories
they're Boston Chicago is going off the
hook right now
well Oklahoma is amazing because they're
like anybody that wants the cannabis
game go for it
no they straight said it was $2,500 for
a license and then after the first year
if you don't live here you can't get one
so you have to have residency so they
like they let basically you know free
for all for everybody and then after
that then it was like nope only if you
live here so my house or no yeah we're
setting up labs they're helping people
set labs up they're like every week we
get a new call from from a new company
and now it's big it's big management
companies that are involved it's a
different market salt corporate now
that's what I don't like it's like
corporation shouldn't be doing this and
if they are they should have people that
have been doing this for a long time at
least as some sort of consulting
or allowing us to like join that
workforce allowing us to pay our taxes
allowing us to have a real legitimate
job we're working our asses off like
we're not sitting around like we're not
like we dealers selling 20 bucks like
we're not that we want to we want to
help people provide a service like
what's the difference between us and
some guy that makes really good beer in
his garage that opens up you know Golden
Road or 805 brewery or monkish or any of
those big high-end beers that were
nobody that we're all growing in an
amazing the craft market still strives
what we are we are craft cannabis in
California and that this is craft
cannabis this is so neat there's not
people that are able to go spend you
know 60 70 80 150 dollars a grand Lowell
Cafe come on
you have to be on vacation to do that
sort of she can't smoke this stuff every
day this is gourmet shit right here all
right so you were making and sorry you
said this was like up and humble oh
we're talking about making hash yeah you
had 20 years ago it was something else
people it was very on the down-low put
it that way
they made the hash making hash we got up
and humble everywhere everywhere you
know I'd come down to deliver bags to
places in Los Angeles different
dispensaries and I've been working with
dispensaries for 20 years and helping
them make the best hash what and what
was the market very late like 20 years
ago
it was always explosive hash has made a
couple ups and downs and it's honest
peak again right now but every like
eight years it goes up and down and
popularity and different kinds yeah in
different kinds the shatter was
explosive for five minutes and then it
like dwindled out and now it's like more
of a back east thing you see a lot of
the shatter still available out there
and then now everybody's turning it to
butter and it's like wait when I used to
make hash if your hashed if you if your
BHO turn to butter it wasn't worth
anything
now it's worth more like how does this
work what are what it what is going on
with I don't know I mean and this whole
vaporizer thing just smoked hash it's
pure
it's healthy it's it's always it's
always just healthy hash pills are good
too oh yeah if you want to take a 16
hour nap I've had a couple I've had a
couple where I'm like like what did you
give me
I mean ingesting marijuana is very
different than smoking marijuana if done
right with proper legend and proper
mixing medicine the most important thing
is is I have friends that need this
medicine correct and they rely on it
they're there they're in chemotherapy
right now and without these things their
life is miserable miserable they're
spinning out of control on chemo madness
rollercoaster throwing up and I'm so I
feel so bad for my friends but they they
need this product and it's really um
it's a good thing that we can help
people make this product with our bags
and help people we help people we teach
them how to make it and we're always
trying to develop the best product
possible and I love where it's going I
really like to the more people having
backyard groves doing little washes
making their own dot that's the way it
should be just like people should be
growing a little bit of vegetables in
their backyard they should be having
some tomatoes and maybe a chicken coop
and if you don't have the room for all
of them you and your neighbor trade off
and you know what I mean like those
little sustainable things would go a
long way with the environment and it
seems like everything wants to go big
corporate big money big lot like
overboard it's like it doesn't need to
be that way especially with cannabis it
doesn't need to turn into a corporate
mongering and in a cash grab and a well
Walgreens started out with cannabis and
they're finally coming back to it which
is wonderful albeit there are very
different Walgreens today than they are
a hundred years ago oh yeah we have a
lot of pharmaceutical customers who are
making amazing medicines with these
products now with with cannabis and
Israel right and all over the world
you know Israel is huge I'm intrigued by
the making making it yeah it's amazing
to hashr out the products that are
coming out right now they have huge labs
I have a couple buddies which is where
some of these strains came from they run
a company called smart B they make that
yeah the controllers yeah the indoor
controllers they just went to Israel and
did a whole bunch of stuff they were
there for like two weeks and some of the
videos that they were sending me I was
like that's an Israel like that's crazy
that's it looks more sophisticated than
what's going on here and I was just
blown away that they even had any type
of weed market let alone these insane
industrial labs going on like there was
literally like a girl in a lab coat I'm
like what the hell are you guys doing
out there so it was really cool to see
that I'm glad it's expanding it should
expand throughout the world there
shouldn't be people persecuted for this
plant it's ridiculous it's absolutely
ridiculous it helps so many more people
than it hurts there's no question
there's agreement all around on that top
you should have a toast you guys let's
have a toast you know cheers man here's
to the future - bring it around bring it
around you gotta try this the Mac one
though I'm telling you it's just it's
utter gasoline
alright so staying on focused top they
on focus went so you you so you're up
and humbled making hash and you decided
you wanted to make your own bags and you
had sisters who yeah we had another with
another brand called trash bags on the
very beat this is back in the 90s they
were called trash bags and you turn your
trash to cash and those were
industrial-strength bags those are a
really strong heavy-duty
big huge 32 gallons you'd be pulling a
big grapefruit sized softball size
beautiful chunks out of their big oil
balls at the ends of the bottom and they
were just amazing and everyone loved the
bags and they just were you guys drying
it that long ago what was your technique
we would make patties we make these cow
patties and we just put them out in the
Sun and we just now freeze dryers are
the way to roll of course I mean the
four freeze dryers I was washing I had
my washing machine you know and my
technique was you know the pizza box
technique but I had a friend that was
like dude try printer paper and I'm like
what do you talk me is like just layout
printer paper and put the hash on the
printer paper and I'm like okay you come
back the next day and the printer paper
is soaked all the water out of the hash
and it's all like warbly and like well
and the and the hash is like dry and I
wanna try those see I feel like you the
faster you're drying your hash the less
time you have for oxidization so and
always keep it in the dark and it was
coming out bomb back then I mean we
could pack it down you know roll it like
weed all the French guys and you're up
you know rolling it with the cellophane
with a hot water bottle and shit and I
was like man this is crazy
we have a tray liner we make now I know
I said you just come out with yeah if
you go on our website you can see them
and they fit in the freeze dryers but
it's a really good just stop up the
water and it saves time also that's
another development and I heard even
just freezing it and then micro planing
it and that's something I didn't know
about until recent getting into this
after I don't even sorry man I'm like
just as I get you focus and you start
talking after after a you to a tripod
proper tripod one day it seems like as
I've gotten into this I go way overboard
with my research and looking up stupid
stuff and trolling people and not
patrolling people like just I guess just
following sake stalking people you know
they mean and yeah I'm not talking shit
but I'm I'm just following any
information that I can find it's just
like the the amount of techniques that
are out there I just I didn't know and
and I thought I knew it all you know
what I mean and it seems like people are
doing so many different things and it's
so cool that we have the internet we
have in
we have the kind of social acceptance
that's slowly seeping out and you know
more and more people are doing this so
people are just like just let them do
their thing and leave them alone they're
not hurting nobody you know kind of and
the techniques like I said the micro
point in the freezing it you just tell
them you set it out in the Sun I'm like
that's the coolest we used to give
directions in the very very beginning
and we put instructions in the bags and
it would say lavender making so we'd say
how to make lavender and extractions and
we just do you know explain how to do it
or we'd say exactly what not to do do
not do this do not do that do not do it
or the lavender essence making the fans
out is for you dedicating about lavender
essence making we might switch it up to
eucalyptus next week but I love how I
love how legalization has helped us
expand and really develop new technology
it's helped us take things forward to
maximum level I mean we're like up here
now we're like miles ahead yeah when I
just turned like Oh hair straighteners
squishing stuff oh that's crazy that's
crazy that's not gonna happen you can't
just squeeze oil out and clean like
that's the craziest thing I've ever
heard
and then I'm like oh now I'm squeezing
really expensive bubble hash and it's
it's did the first time you're doing it
it's nerve-wracking you don't know if
you're gonna lose money if you're gonna
you know like you're gonna ruin
somebody's crop you're gonna you know
it's like so nerve-wracking you're like
oh my god like this is there's a lot of
emotion yeah oh man there's and there's
everybody just told me just get your
hands dirty get out there and figure it
out you just know I can tell you a
million things I can tell you well isn't
that like when people first started
dropping this in the water other people
were like I went in 2004 and he dumped
it in the bucket and everybody lost
their mind and it was anyway two of us
the bubble man actual bubble bags that
you know he's like a goofy look from I
think he's from huzi from Humboldt or
something nice Canadian is he Canadian
are you serious oh well I didn't even
know but you know that they're really
nice the the velvet yellow bag with
a little shoulder strap he walked in
with that and nobody had seen it yet and
he did it right there in the warehouse
right at the like right across the
street from the milk leg and this is
like in 2004 and I'm like there's no way
that I was gonna make DNA was there for
the first year they were kids man I was
a kid I was like 21
well Mila just told me that when she was
first selling her bags like they were
you know she had a booth at some event
and they were all hanging like with you
know clothesline clips and people would
just kind of walk by and be like okay
like what the hell selling ice bags and
then I think what was it soma soma seed
stole man I started giving him some love
and people were like what what do they
do and he's like this is what you do
with them and they were like but it's
been for 2,000 years in China I mean if
you do the research it's been around
1,000 days they have these times they're
saying like make yourself a genius they
used to eat it they would say have
genius days indeed hashish and they used
to have hash pills that they would take
back in the Egyptian times the Pharaohs
loved hash so it's but wait but but I've
always heard that like nobody thought of
adding water until like 20-30 years ago
it's been they've been doing it you know
there's definitely been and and when I
found out like BHO was made like 50
years ago like some of the first BHO was
early 70s I'm like what like why didn't
we know about it I remember growing up
and eat her like honey oil or something
and it kind of smelled like patchouli
oil or something you were smoking it
wasn't it was even good like maple syrup
or something you were smoking I didn't
know what the hell is smoking in this 18
but I just I'm just so glad it's it's
progressed so far to this and obviously
it's healthier there's no there's no
question so what are some of the like
innovations that you're both seeing now
like over the past year or two or the
majors like does anyone post yourself on
instagram whether it's a consistency or
device or a product that helps make it
that
like oh fuck yeah the only thing that
really changed the game over recent is
the free Shire I mean I I mean the bags
are always fairly similar some people do
different sizes no offence separation
you get what you pay for you're not if
you don't pay good money you're gonna
get a crappy so job it's gonna come
apart it's I've seen these things did
you're right fine you gotta have the
right strain preferably a nice full term
strain yep and then you got to have the
right process and you have those
together and the right cure people don't
even get the mix of the of the water and
ice right you can have a winner
so and winner that's it well so what is
your is your mix of there is no there is
no like that you will never know like oh
I want four gallons of water for 10
pounds of ice or sometimes there's no
mix like that you feel it when you're
doing this and you've done this for a
long time and you're mixing it by hand
you know that feel there's a sound
there's a sound you know when it's those
those ice cubes are breaking the heads
off and it's and it's crushing through
that weed properly without releasing a
massive amount of chlorophyll so you
don't have green hash it sound like
lawnmower it doesn't sound like one
sorry about the lawnmower it's all wrong
but you know yeah totally you mean like
all around like when we first started
we'd be using buckets and and paddles
like little canoe paddles and you just
want to just agitate ever so slightly
mm-hmm ever so slightly just
I I have a very the guy who helps me
mostly I have an assistant nobody can do
this one-handed by themselves except for
cannabis Cameron that kid does
everything by himself he will not let
anybody in his room he will not let
anybody anywhere he doesn't let anybody
touch his crop he doesn't he's like a
Rain Man he's like not only am i amazing
at making hash but I also grow amazing
living soil weed so I cultivate and I'm
like also mastery in that craft he's no
joke dude he says he a guitar player and
be like and I dabble in the piano a
little bit just being like you're like
and and he's super like quiet and humble
and it's weird I met him skimboarding so
yeah you're like hey fellows skin border
like what do you like to do when your
nails game board ends yeah like well I
go skimboarding I'm gonna smoke a bowl
on the beach you know or whatever and
he's like no man what's up I got my peak
listen you know and then was this over
Instagram no like if you skim board it's
a very small there's probably like 20 of
us you know what I mean and there's not
very many places you can actually skim
board so where do you like to do it
skimboarding here is done mostly in
Malibu and north like as soon as you get
north of county line and is that because
you have like one like high tide to look
okay yeah the APUs Beach and you always
go like about an hour before high tide
it's clutch but the skimboard mecca of
the world is Laguna Beach and don't know
yeah sure
never ever change listen we're not in
this skimboarding it's a way the beaches
are set up every Beach around their
breaks perfect the only one that like is
out of Laguna Beach that's that's
awesome is the wedge and that's very
finicky so but it here is the
skimboarding mecca just like here's the
mecca of boutique weed and they're the
stuff that you well just don't go for a
lot of things I went to Amsterdam so
many times you can't find we'd like
here it doesn't exist it you go to go to
Colorado I don't care
they all got it legal you can't grow a
wheel I can grow wheat here specifically
because the elevation can't grow
bomb-ass you think about 5,000 feet up
almost got the same exact kind of
exactly climate like they have examples
of Istanbul and up in the hills of
Afghanistan the same kind of climate
same exactly humble is is built
perfectly yes very much for it it's a
little colder but for an outdoor loves
for old for out well yeah yeah but you
can't grow in January that's humboldt
yeah I mean and you can't hear and the
indoor that comes from here is unreal
it's so on I can't I've sir can't
despised you can't dispute that sir I
wish I could find better
well bodies we got some good weed down
here well how about this of the indoor
you like like is it grown and soil is it
grown hydro is a it in all reality I've
had every single way grown and enjoy all
those and have every single wade you
know cocoa soil hydro if it's indoor and
it's grown in Southern California it's
gonna be better than anywhere else I
don't care what anybody said this if you
do it the same way it there's no
possible way I could come out better
just geographical it's like geography
matters with indoor oh yeah absolutely
wonder percent anybody who says that
that your indoor is not determined by
your outside factors is wrong your
indoor no matter how sealed your room is
you can't seal prep you can't make
pressure you can't make atmospheric
pressure you can't if it's if if the
Santa Anas are out in the valley your
weed will drop the driveway slower than
it would if it was raining outside I
don't care if it's indoor it changes
there is a difference from growing it
anywhere in the world then grow in here
I don't know if I totally you don't
believe in really slimy indoor here in
door there
it's I still do do you not agree with me
that outside factors will always they
will must still control it less less
right like like elevation barometric
pressure
like certain things will have a factor
but other things you can't say so you're
having fewer things that are out of or
that are microclimate dependent yeah and
what I'm telling you is the fact that
you don't have to actually put any
effort into having the perfect
parameters which is what is here through
a B hey smell the hash yes I mean
there's so many little details you can
dial in now and but that's what I'm
saying is so something tied in perfectly
in another area you have to keep it so
dialed in here you don't have to do
anything that's why it always comes out
better is this is the optimum
everything's optimum here so you don't
have to have huge skill level and you'll
still do well you still need some sort
of yeah but it's like playing with an
oversized tennis racket or something
what I'm trying to explain to you need
spots much bigger let's just say you're
taking one factor of it just one factor
of it just humidity okay one factor of
humidity okay the humidity levels here
where we live growing indoor is way
easier to combat and to deal with with
one freaking dehumidifier then it would
be anywhere else in the country to grow
pot in Florida in the summer do
Minnesota okay anywhere you're gonna go
it's gonna be more humid you're gonna
have harder chance to do things you have
to humble very humid or even more dry
you can't go to bury the Bay Area's got
a great climate but Stella's you're
still saying California share you're
still saying how fortunately III will I
will agree with you go from roughly like
like our Qaeda to San Diego is the
greatest and you can't go very far
inland either the further you go inland
the least the worse the minute you go
kind of around that band globally and
find other spots that are kind of
similar like as they say exactly on the
other side of the the map is at the
Afghani mountains and and those rejects
so so that's why it does grow there also
but it's not the same topography its
topography ocean the way the the way the
freakin currents is all that BS yeah do
you think just the Oh
hemp that's planet they don't even water
it they don't water that in camarillo it
grows like wild and it looks like crazy
you're like okay there's that's crazy
you're like and there's and there's weed
like all along the side of the road you
just walk up and grab the plant they
don't care that's crazy yeah it
literally and they said they barely
water it due to the geographical area
where it is and how much ocean you know
mist and all that overcast comes in they
barely water it and there and there's no
harvest and they're harvesting this
massive amount of hemp and getting a
huge amount of money for it and now they
don't have to water their crops like
they were watering you know the peppers
and the in the cabbage and whatever else
that they were growing they've just
legalized it up in Humboldt County too
and for him for him is that everyone
yeah farmers aren't too happy about it
and thank you what they're doing is just
by the way I did it like a two and a
half hour conversation with cam
and him and Fred had like he's amazing
like thirst-quenching drinks and I
realized as we started to fill me that I
had no water or anything we got super
high so for two and a half hours I had
nothing to drink while they're like so
thirst quenching the worst yeah so
they're growing hemp up in Humble now
finally it's been on a moratorium for a
long time they were not allowing it but
where they're doing it is in all the
farmland in the bottoms to grow they've
got different hip zones well I saw
something recently posted like Humboldt
now is gonna have more cannabis licenses
than Santa Barbara and more acreage of
cultivation and I was like say what yeah
because Santa Barbara is the biggest
right now
bye-bye-bye like multiples anything I
want to understand what that means like
did something just happen local
regulatory why's that changed or well
they have this moratorium thanks we're
happy this is going what's going on with
cultivation in humble give this like
tell us a sec you to say who it's hot
yeah I got you don't worry yeah they're
um I like the building opportunities the
sustainable building opportunities I
think you should build building
materials fuel out of him that's where I
think him should go so I'm really
excited about that yeah I think you know
the plastics and stuff that they build
with him but is is the way to go they're
building houses they're doing all sorts
of crazy things
yeah well the kind of the infrastructure
to get stuff from raw material you know
Robert like petroleum has how many years
of creating equipment and processes to
get to every form factor of biomaterial
it's ridiculous the amount of trash and
waste we have I can't even know some of
the like I'd love to start like I want
to start reaching out to see who makes
just like hem fabrics I want to start
playing with it these are really nice
have how to go in your pants but where
could you get like just the fabric right
like that's right like working you buy
raw fabric yeah and make your own brand
new yeah but I'm pretty sure living in
LA you can go to the garment district
and you can find people that can get
that for you for sure okay so how about
cannabis cultivation Humboldt County
snapshot in time November so people have
harvested they're curing our people
excited our prices going up prices going
down right now things are a little low
cuz supply and demand but prices are low
a little bit cuz there's a cuz everybody
is now coming to market right today
right today November 18th prices are
kind of low but they'll go back up they
always do it's always a consistent up
and down cuz they've gone up recently
from
historical lows right last 2017 was not
a good year I would take 20 18 was
probably the lowest year right 2017 in
the 2018 but then but he was just
because of legalization yeah it didn't
matter whether it was indoor outdoor up
north
beautiful weed crappy weed everything
took a massive massive hit like indoors
usually like 2,500 and then it dropped
to like sixteen seventeen hundred
dollars for beautiful pot beautiful and
then the outdoors were going for like
five hundred six hundred dollars like
that were decent yeah it was insane just
now it's fine to fill it back up for
sure it also is just the gourmet
products always sell quality always
prevails people need the proper quality
and they'll pay the price that's all the
construction project going on they're
building a big house there but do you
think it's it like what the roof the
roofing tar I think we got a lot of
dabbers in this neighborhood
well should we wash yeah let's - we're
about to watch yeah let's do a quick
little wash here