[Music]
you should go wash it right now I love
when you when you make something new and
the whole room smells like a flavor you
weren't ready for I got some stuff that
guy was like oh yeah it's some type of
like guerrilla og or something and then
I washed it and it's the whole room just
stunk like blueberries I'm like dude
there's no way this is a new type of
gorilla that mean can you stand up this
like yeah yeah I can smell that
no 220 how you sit 190
just carry it curiosity that's all I do
uh I'm all big on making sure I get as
much contaminant out as possible so I
wash in a 220 kind of like these but
much bigger which I might want to talk
to you about if you can make me a custom
bag I'd really really like that because
it's so hard to find bags that fit the
what I want to use I'm very specific on
but what kind of size are you thinking
my big um yeah it's a big I'm looking
for I want it to fit a 44 gallon trash
can but here's the problem every single
place I look doesn't matter if I order
from Canada wacky bags doesn't order if
I order from Europe with where they're
using leaders you know what I'm saying
nobody can make me a big enough
circumference you know a big enough
diameter that fits and is short enough
the bags will be like six feet long and
I'm like I only need it like three feet
long but I need it wide yeah and nobody
makes one I do yeah I make that size 44
I make a lot of those now that's like if
it fits in that peer pressure being less
but we also make them fit as we roll
them around grow them around and like a
pump station and that pumps out with a
water pump like I don't use any pumps
I'm a gravity-fed guy I don't like my
half through a pump or any any type of
tubing I just feel like you're gonna
lose some are you're gonna weigh some
because I'm just it works good I know it
works and especially if I'm on like a
massive scale like some of the massive
scale guys that's what they do of course
yeah just you can't lift it you can't
even I I is the dam hoist a you know
freakin block and tackle base can I see
your product yeah yeah this is indoor
that's wicked and these are outdoors
this is a really older batch of some
good so this is this is solvent let's
hash all of that amazing that's
beautiful you are you're amazing person
thank you
starting up this is amazing Brown yeah
I'm pretty good with these oh my god
thank god this is a wicked stuff I get
super high and I'm working like normally
I do I need a rig for this or what this
is like you could fucking dab this on a
rig so so soft and beautiful
Oh we're gonna use a rig Joshua you're
an amazing artist are teasin hashish n
hard road wicked so did you hear license
are you all ready to rock nope I have a
lot of friends with licenses that have
been asking me to to join the team and
I'm a hundred percent ready but every
time that they get you know where
they're supposed to go there's another
red flag of rigmarole do your kradic
nonsense that doesn't even seem to be
real that they have to shell out another
50 60 grand for oh that sucks
you know what I mean like I've seen the
rooms where they can't that they've been
spending money and paying rent and
building these things in the town year
or a year it's been there for a year and
they can't open it because oh well this
paperwork didn't go through because some
jackwagon doesn't want to sign something
you know what I mean it's like this is
ridiculous
and the fact that we're just that we're
only allowing rich people to to work in
this industry is not fair there's been
so many people that put in so much hard
time and effort and and risk and risk
and they they need to release people
from jail that sell sold weed it's just
ridiculous that they're reducing
sentences I have some friends who got
arrested and it was actually good
because they got like all their stuff
expunged well they're a be a complete
expungement if you're gonna let rich
people do this just because they have
money that's not okay that's not the way
it works you
totally I'm doing nothing like you know
volatile you know there's I mean I
probably those closed-loop systems
that's not what I want to do you know we
made but there's places where you know
they're mixing a bad trash cans and
buckets left or right you know that's me
that's all I do
ten thousand grams like like some of the
big companies do ten thousand a month
there's there's like black market people
doing that much a day up there and big
barns just mixing they can have yes and
no ever yes and no because you can have
the small batches but you can always
just pour into it into a into one do you
know what I'm trying to say like all
your workers are going to the same
location Zac there's no need to drive
seven different cars they're just have
your mixers mix mix them all I mean you
can do large scales for sure I've seen
where like I've walked over to a guy and
he the guy has six trash cans going with
six different dudes and I'm like your
guys are way out of hand here I'm like
you're gonna clog all your bags you know
especially if you have a sticky product
in whoa why they got this to me one of
the questions I have is like as you see
more and more hash makers popping up and
you have a lot of people who want to
just be washing the best material as
their starting material like how do you
all like even if everyone's really good
you're all competing for a limited
supply of quality starting material so
how does that play out well that's
always the major factors can you get the
good material right so that was why I
did this because I knew the material was
there I have those connections with
local growers that are small boutique
growers where I'm gonna get the quality
cannabis and I'm gonna be able to
produce the amount that I need so that
everybody can be happy and it also helps
you know like the trimming situation is
going lower and lower and lower they're
paying people less and less and less and
they're giving them less and less and
less when you go to a trim used to go to
a trim and you would get catered to you
would get lunch you would have waters
and food and drink and you'd be able to
smoke and drink at a at a trim now it's
like corporate oh man
Erica and they're putting like I've gone
to a trim where there's like 15 Russian
girls that don't even speak English and
they're just like working these people
I'm like this isn't our this isn't our
community this isn't our group of people
like I don't know so now chopping all
the weed down putting it fresh frozen
you eliminate that entire step and
there's a lot of trimmers that are upset
with that also so there's the game is
changing on a major like it happened so
fast too and you don't notice it I mean
we used titanium nails four years ago we
didn't even know what quartz was right
like the way things are smoked the way
things are done thankfully I'm glad
bubble bags came back hashes in right
now hash is so in yeah well that's what
I was saying so now you have everybody
making hash and if you want to be truly
good at it you got to start with that
but that was my point you got to start
so everyone's fighting for this limited
supply of poly it's like when you talk
to a Frenchie he's like once I can't
find what I'm looking for anymore I'm
done I tap out and I'm not gonna make
like b-grade hash mm-hmm no it's not
worth it to your company either right
but all the contracts have been made all
the big companies have their next ten
years all their farms like literally
locked in for the next ten years
all these farms that's one there's no
way you're gonna get the quality it has
a giant farm that you're gonna get out
of a batik grow that's why black market
will never go away it needs to be it
needs to be you know divvied up amongst
I guess maybe a couple local
dispensaries because the fact of the
matter is is the best marijuana is grown
in California there's no question about
that I've been all over the world I've
searched for it and you're not gonna
find better weed than here and to try to
like take that away from us the small
groups the small guys the small people I
just it's so wrong it's like we put me
putting so much effort in yes quickly
before we start can you open each one of
those and quickly talk about
yeah you're gonna aim it at me yeah for
sure here I'll maybe talk about a second
basically these right here are my
indoors these are my outdoors everything
is a whole plant fresh frozen we chop
the plant down freeze it immediately
wash it freeze dry it after freeze
drying we I place it in 15 micron bags I
go the smallest that I can possibly find
and get I get those from rosin
devolution I press on a flux rosin press
most of my technique I take directly
from a good friend I think you guys have
actually interviewed him
Sunfire farms kidding him cannabis or
cannabis yeah yeah he's he's really
knowledgeable and he does really good
work and really passionate about what
like this is going on you know and then
most of my actual technique like
pressing and how I press and stuff like
that I get from superior solvent list
yeah they've been super super kind with
me and giving me you know information
that I can't find anywhere and in
reality though the the best information
is just getting your hands dirty and
figuring it out for yourself and you
know messing up but these right here
this is Wi-Fi this is locally grown in
San Fernando Valley by a good friend it
was chopped down maybe a week ago yeah
washed the day after it was chopped down
and then pressed the day after that and
it's probably had like a five-day cure
yeah so this is this is fairly recent
and I like to give it a cure because
when you're when you're when you're
chopping down a fresh frozen plant it
hasn't had time to actually have all
those those smells and all that like the
plant is decomposing and it's doing a
lot of things it's fermenting it's doing
all sorts of cool stuff and when you
leave it in a jar close it it'll really
start to change and and make a really
good flavor this right here is the caps
cut the capital ater cut act one this is
maybe two weeks old this is a really
good batch it's extremely gasoline like
there's not there's not much marijuana
taste it's like extremely just Terps
it's almost all Terps it's almost too
heavy sometimes I like more of a OG
taste or I really like GMO just a little
more malware don't get me wrong GMOs
super stony this is an older batch of
GMO this is probably two months old I've
had it sitting and curing and you can
you can tell a major change and you can
see different colorations as I turn it
over like how it's much lighter on the
bottom and all the Terps have sort of
moved to the side and this is after like
like I said two months of sitting in a
cold room in the dark so there's just
stuff that I like to experiment with
this is like kind of you know how you
sees cannolis stuff cannoli stuff turns
a little darker because he likes to let
it sit for a long time yeah and no
matter what if if you let hash said it's
gonna darken because oxygen ruins
everything that's dead so the only thing
well it's also gonna make it a lot more
kind of couch lock yeah I mean people
say that but I think once you're smoking
hash of this level I mean it's so stony
right come on you know what I mean like
you have to smoke so much to be able to
tell the difference between one to the
next I I smoke them all all the time and
the outdoor gets me just as high in my
opinion that is there some that's like
if I want to go like clean my house for
the next four hours
I think super Turkey and you know that's
what I think the person based because
there's people that smoke weed and want
to smoke and clean their house all the
time and then there's people that smoke
we didn't want to sit and play video
games and sit on the couch and do
nothing in Cheetos I I feel there's not
much of a difference even from sativa
indica where if you're high and you're
smoking hash you're gonna get high to
the point where you're gonna do whatever
it is you want to do I don't know if
there's the only thing that I know that
like makes you want to like clean or
like actual pharmaceutical drugs so you
know what I mean and I'm not I'm not I'm
not about to take some vicodin so I can
clean the house I'd rather just get
stone to clean this one this one for
sure yeah I mean that I recommend
[Laughter]
that's Wi-Fi so should we smoke yeah
definitely you guys can try whatever you
want feel free I brought them all here
for for everybody I'd like you to curate
the experience yeah for sure is it all
the most definitely it's not a problem
powerful this is a really really nice
glass piece made by Eric Krunk and is he
local where is he from
Eric Krunk is a gypsy he lived a long
time in his car wandering around
Grateful Dead shows selling his pipes
and now these are like one of the most
sought-after pieces it's awesome in the
world there's maybe like ten other glass
blowers that are on his upper echelon
he's a really nice guy makes awesome
pieces and I don't know just a craftsman
super craftsman who would some of the
other people be that your respect at
that level or you think are at that
level there's a there's a few I mean you
got Darby you have you Xin there's a few
of his apprentices that are super super
really talented but you know I
they pay him the respect which is really
nice those guys are like chunk and
hermit there's there's so many good
glass blowers out there and there's so
many lower glass blowers that are doing
such great work and for whatever reason
they're just not getting this extreme
blow-up of the of the market where these
are going for you know thirty to fifty
thousand dollars and they're making
something very equivalent but it's like
maybe two thousand dollars or fifteen
hundred dollars and it's just uh it's a
it's a weird it's a weird niche market I
guess you could say so but let's look
there are pieces that just go into
someone's like art collection basically
well no a lot of it is is these big hash
companies these newer hash companies or
these people that are I guess brokering
a lot of the hash it's all monopoly
money and they need to wash their money
so they'll buy something like this and
you know fifty thousand dollars then
they look cool they have more followers
on Instagram they have all that sort of
stuff oh don't tell them a secret huh
but yeah that's the way it goes man
so this is this is what's going on in
our world right now of our cannabis
community and it's really cool that
there's a lot of good cannabis coming
out from Michigan
there's cannabis that's really good I
was surprised when I went there I wasn't
really expect it was like I'm in the
Midwest and I met a lot of cool growers
and superiors all the list does insane
good work out there Michigan man melts
is awesome
they have great strains and they're
purposely not letting them out because
they know we got great strains to which
is hot which is cool I understand that
and I don't know I'm just happy that
that there's someone else and some other
communities out there that are taking
the time to to perfect this and to make
it more healthy make it more enjoyable
you know what I mean the the fact that
we're smoking it this way is there's no
question about whether or not this is
the healthiest way to smoke it you can
vaporize it and that's all good but
you're not going to get all the terpenes
and and all of the mix of the plant that
you need the way you're smoking this
there's no question about that wait so
where are you mostly sourcing your local
all very very local and if not it's
grown in my backyard and what do you try
car you sourcing all outdoor mats area
everything's indoor that I source
otherwise if I do do outdoor it's very
very limited and it'll only be in
october/november when the outdoor is
ready you know so what are your thoughts
on like what do you like about outdoor
and what do you like about indoor is a
kind of a loser is is 90% of the time
gonna be growing in soil first of all I
like so you'll always get a better taste
I'd feel from soil you get usually a
better return on soil of your of your
hash and I could yield yield you will
always get a better yield in growing in
soil that's that's not a scientific fact
but that's just what the hash makers
have noticed you know none of this has
been written down nobody's writing a
book you know what I mean I wish they
did but it's it's more of hearsay you
know or whatever it may be
but do you need a damper yes I do need a
dabber I was just about to say that I'm
like huh you know what I did forget one
thing I'll be going now outdoor will
always come out a little darker I feel
just because you're gonna have more
elements the more Sun the more exposure
dirt and everything and every time I
wash outdoor the water is dirty you're
cleaning the water washing indoor it's
obviously going to be much nicer so
sorry
these are outdoor these are indoor well
I'm looking at the consistency's so this
has not been pressed right all of these
have been pressed all these have have
been exactly manufactured the exact same
way this is all strain dependency well
that's okay yeah yeah and you'll also
notice a little bit of different
consistency in the washes because the
first couple of washes if you mix them
you'll get more of the oils from the
plant and that the oils are what will
create this
that's it yeah no I I assumed it was
processed dependent and no not even I've
even had the exact same strain grown at
a different time of the year turned out
different thrown in the same room with
the same nutrients the same exact way
processed everything the exact same way
because of the time of the year the
plant doesn't perform or it doesn't you
know do the same things it's doing at a
different time of the year just based on
outside parameters of whether it's
raining or whether it's windy and 115
degrees like it happens here it's
stainless perfect that's nice one I'm
gonna try it first you first okay
yes first and so you you said you did
press all of this so are you or
everything's pressed are you doing
anything that you don't press or I do
pressing everything I press everything
people are like the full melt but then
you're separating a spectrum of the of
the plant you're pulling only 90 you
usually - like 120 or once some people
go to like 150 160 and it'll still melt
pretty good but you're gonna have a lot
of contaminant on your nail and these
things are expensive they're 180 bucks I
prefer the taste to this don't get me
wrong you get a slightly different high
I've noticed off of off of the full melt
and you know before it's pressed but oh
and I don't to sit there and use four
q-tips to clean my banger every time and
I just don't want to do it that's
interesting that is kind of a functional
thing it's like if you had done banger
if bangers were disposable you'd be like
maybe but then also you're taking that
spectrum away so now you have your 40
you - 9000 or what 89 what are you doing
with that I don't ever see I've never
seen a single company sell 4289 you tell
me one that does I can't see a single
one on the market so either one they're
lying to you or they're doing something
else with their product where is it
going where is that massive amount of
hash going I want to know nobody will
answer those questions I'm just like
screw that I'm doing full spec here's my
spectrum I do 40 - 179 everything's
pressed on extremely small micron
so I know I'm getting all my
contaminants out and yeah you might end
up with a bag full of hash still that
you've pressed and there's a shitload of
stuff in there that you didn't get out
well that's all you're contaminated so
that's why my hash is usually so clean
and burned so well you will never hear
no sizzling you know and all that stuff
so that's done you set this up nicely
I'm actually pretty fired up to try it
that's the way I've asked everybody and
nobody gives you straight answers the
only one that gave me a straight answer
was superior solve unless he's like I
want my full spectrum
I want the whole taste of the plant of
all of the hash that I'm getting and I
want it all mixed together so is it
consistent what you're getting out of
each spectrum like the 40 to 50 the 50
to settle I don't separate them because
then you're just wasting your time
pulling bag after bag after bag I know
but just to understand for like
educational purposes like to like try
the 40 and be like okay I understand
what I'm getting but then you got the
that but that's all based on different
bags like his bags that he has he does a
different size some other bags go 40 to
70 40 to 104 you know it's like who
knows purse train exactly what heads are
there were correct heads that were
supposed to be smoking I don't the
amount of time that that would take to
figure out it's not possibly we haven't
created a device that could figure it
out I don't think so I don't know of one
you know I mean I'd love to have that
but it doesn't exist so that's why
scientific now that's what I'm saying
I'm like I'm trying to break this down
yeah it's basically thinking about the
different bands right different sizes
what's what from a terpene standpoint a
cannabinoid standpoint other compounds
like and then what effect each of those
hasn't because you're marrying them
which I love I want the planet full but
I want full spectrum too I'd also like
to understand what the different bands
do whether it's how they make you feel
personally and personally from all the
experience that I've gathered as much as
I've done this and all the people that
I've smoked hash with it does give you a
little bit different high that that that
90 to 120 you it gives you a little bit
different height but that's before
pressing it if you were to press it it's
it's the same thing it just looks better
it comes out like white you know what I
mean that's all it is and that's just a
color thing and that's all mental right
I mean people are see are seeing Brown
BHO and now it looks gold and now
everyone's like oh my god it's the best
it's like no you just you can do
anything different you know you
same thing with distillate it's sludge
you just took
you just took raw sludge and you
filtered it down and you used a rotovap
and you and now it looks like distillate
and it's clear and you can put it in a
pen and smoke it but is it good
no it's not good I want I want what I
want my whole plant I like traditional
that's what I'm saying our long science
aside I wanted a making hash
traditionally with good product it just
naturally occurs it happens and just
happens you have good trim like this
right here you get a gray hash yeah
there's nothing about it all comes
together right yeah good bags help too
you know traditional bob ways it just
happens and it's the best tradition the
best ritual and it just if it's there
it's gonna come I always says and then
you have other people that are like man
I love finger love it I love it all I
still smoke weed out of the bong you
know what I mean like I'm not like what
what was funny was when I was talking to
cam he was like yeah I don't smoke the
flower I was like really he doesn't
smoke flower I know and I was like next
time you harvest can you save me some of
your flower because he just I've never
seen any of his flower yeah that's crazy
that you even mentioned that now that
now that I think about him like I've
never seen any of his flower he just
turns it all he's in and I told him that
he dated himself as being super young
because he's super young yeah he's like
why would I want to roll joints and
smoke flower when I can make it even
cleaner that shit I gotta let it cool
down give me a sec it's timing it out
yeah how many more a second we got seven
we're good we're good this is a
yeah that's delicious I love it when it
comes out good the real technique I've
noticed is everyone can wash it everyone
can put it on a tray and put it in a
freeze dryer everyone can stick it in a
bag and press it and have it come out on
parchment but what you do after that is
the real the real test of how well it's
gonna come out you need to be patient
you need to leave it in a jar
you need to let it cure and do its thing
for a little bit some strains are harder
than others they're like like I can't
even get in there with a chisel when
it's cold right
like which what give examples for
example this Wi-Fi right here looks all
nice and buttery
not before I whipped it I couldn't even
get in there I had to actually set it on
a heat mat for like 20-30 minutes just
to get it malleable so I can get in
there and break it up it was so hard
like I never see anybody's hash turn out
like that I don't I've had a lot of
people just telling me like whatever
you're doing keep it up I'm like I'm
trying I'm trying I'm trying real hard
so oh I don't think all of it will come
off
was there a can of butane everyone
thought I brought one well we're good
for now
I don't know if you recognize the logo
it's an old no-smoking logo from like
the Northeast they have them a lot in
like Washington and it'll have a puffin
but it says no puffins like you're not
allowed to puff and they'll be like a
red line going through it and I was just
like man that's such a good idea
very cool
hash has come such a long way like when
I first started making hash thought 20
years ago I started making it from my
mom I'd cancer and we used to make this
like full Mel black hash and then we'd
make this blondes and the 73 micron is
so flaky and good we should be about
good to go yeah it tastes good yeah it's
got the flavor definite flavor very
tangerine if did has she should my
friend thank you that was good smoked
Peter I do feel free
and I definitely if you guys are still
gonna smoke please try this the cops cut
back one this stuff is it's a it's
unlike any of the other hash I've ever
made where the crystals nice very pure