okay it's like we have an egg that hatch
it's a little baby a spider mite in the
top right
predators though unfocus
I've introduced some predators
some California guess
mmm mmm food everywhere one big leaf for
me this is for time zone where are you
God
yeah
coppy little spider mite
off the screen again
Oh fucker you just went on ok
look at this is this a spider is that a
good might that's a California nice and
look at this guy this guy looks totally
dead so these are eggs yeah so he's
munching on the eggs right that's a
slider so he's not gonna eat the spider
but it'll eat the eggs right because the
spider is looking pretty big compared to
him