[Music]
zelich riot sir yeah yeah so what do you
what do you what do you do man what's
the deal bro show me anything let's let
it grow right yeah yeah are you a little
beater or what's going I don't even know
what's going on we're just gonna hang
out yo right on Sox oil yeah yeah
totally
- you're gonna share about the this the
reality what it took to grow that this
year you don't want to know nobody
I knew because it was a tough fucking
year I mean yeah it started with a
atmospheric River and 150 year flood and
where'd you grow are we I'm right here
how's it go where do you go yeah just
has it arrow in Sonoma County 150 year
flood yeah I was a maybe I'll
exaggerating bite then it was your deal
with well every year water every bit of
a hundred year flood and then so did you
see the worms like literally rise up out
and try to find shelter from the soil
like guys actually didn't flood oh great
you know but other farms did flood so
you're up on a hill yeah you what yeah
yeah where we're at about 800 feet in
elevation so we South self base no no
not at all we have north east and west
facing I like it actually which you know
like perspective is everything that's
right so they're you know it just really
depends on what what how do your girls
like it like it changes on how do they
like grown with the different light
profile
well I mean I do mix light like that oh
you do yeah okay so it's not just only
an outdoor yeah I specifically focus on
like full spectrum lighting so I'm
really push it to the edge I use like I
have you know I I kind of have a
hodgepodge of lighting but I have like h
PS is t fives far reds and then the
light depth cover itself so you know
which you're manipulating the Sun then
so you basically have about 400
different ways you can just come at it
and then you can control the photo
timing of the photo period so you know
you can really manipulate a lot of you
can get the plant to express itself
you're working with it in a lot of
different ways really great one of the
things that I've really worked on doing
is like this silver og which is a 63 day
plant I've been able to finish it in 53
days a hundred percent for real no
bullshit and like in 2017 we took third
at the Emerald cup in light debt with
our silver og that we grow grew in yeah
I was like those 10 days short from
where well that was in like our 12 year
old soil at the time so we've got this
you know still grow yeah we've got this
- you're not tilling you're not rip yeah
no no I'm I do this no-till we've been
doing no-till like that for like 16
years 17 years so you know we haven't
bought bottled nutrients basically in 15
year you know everything great for
pretty much ever you know now and then a
little a bottle here and they're just
you know for maybe for some but at this
point yeah I haven't bought anything in
ever in 2017 when we placed third at the
Emerald cup we really were eliminating
everything opposed to adding stuff to
our system we're in a problem in a
process of eliminating refining getting
rid of less is more
look is more if it's not broke don't fix
it so I mean
getting rid of it or fix it I'm really
what I focus on is trust you know that's
what it's about it's about trusting
nature trusting your relationship with
the plants and and doing what they tell
you and not imposing your will on them
and just do what they say and and it's
it's really simple except it's really
not that simple you know so it's not
simple because literally everything we
thought we knew tells us to do something
a little different than right right yeah
I get to spend time with my kids and I
don't and and I have no fear of them
eating anything in my garden there's no
poisons there's no pesticides that right
I use life to grow life and then people
go out and they buy a probiotic and they
take a pill that life is on outdoor
grown living soil no tilled mature life
that it's on it you don't have to take a
pro body your food is like yeah yeah I
grow potatoes South African ground
cherries anything invasive basically
with my cannabis for a you know first
several reasons you know whether it's
IPM or just for food to just because
well they're part of the same just
different flowers we have two
chrysanthemum
and yarrow and nettles I mean the
Stillman it pretty much marigolds are
often recommended together so many I
found this year that the sunflower like
it was the indicator species if I was
going to even see an aphid and then it
became red based species where I never
had a problem on any plants but there
were a few on flowers yeah cool yeah
there for me I didn't have a lot going
on this year because it was kind of a
crazy year and we were actually not
going to plant at all we weren't really
planted at all until the last minute you
know because we started the year with a
atmospheric River which you know brought
down like a hundred year flood which
kind of fucked everything up slowed
everything down we didn't have a foot
you know phones or you know okay
everything did you get more overwatered
yeah on our road slid out so I was
literally doing tractor work for from
whenever it for up til when when I
should have been working on my farm
installing my mic cultivation my outdoor
site which so I wasn't doing that
so then I'm doing road work and then by
the time and then plus the state they
were you know stalling so it was like
you know you're kind of broke at this
point as a small farmer you're broke you
got like five grand and you're like
should I spend it on plants or should I
you know just keep my pocket because if
I spent on the plants which the state
hasn't renewed my license yet so and if
they don't renew my license then I'll be
out of compliance so then I'll have no
money I have to cut down my plants dig
them up sell them try to hustle plants
or whatever to recoup whatever your last
which you know your last dollars so we
decided to just not plant you know which
was like at that point you're playing
Russian roulette because they're like
will the state renew my license on that
date if I'm planted and then well
they're going to just come in like you
know slam you if you're out of compliant
oh you had plants and pots just waiting
weird you know I just didn't I usually
do seed and would have a whole bunch of
plants
to anything because I didn't know what
was going to happen so I did nothing so
then when it was like Sunday night at
like 6 o'clock they call us when Monday
morning it's going to expire they called
Renu at Sunday night but that was like
in July you know so then it was like you
know so then you know July 17th like the
or that first week of July I'm like
everybody numbers almost oh good
everybody's out of everybody's out of
out of plants I managed to find like
desperately like give me anything you
got like I'll do whatever you want to do
blog whatever I managed to get some of
my yeah no I I'm Anna to get some good
you know I got some silver og luckily
for my gosh oil and some mimosa oh yeah
if you you know I'm yeah I can work
anything and I got this - I had some 24k
which beautiful was challenging because
it literally like quadrupled in size
I've never had a plant grow so much and
maybe it was because of my the regime
that I was doing what this jadam liquid
fertilizer yeah it's some stuff starts
you happy I really I really feel like
have you done Jude yeah yeah okay and
the Cana practices that the IMO's it's
it's beautiful and the science behind it
is on point like this is not guesswork
anymore like you can prove it like you
can prove with scientific tests that the
plant grown in your soil is different
then the same cultivar grown down the
street alright in crappy well the
bacteria you know there's just it that's
what I am most about yeah that's why
that's what I am oh is and you're just
working with your team
already there you just got to give him a
hand yeah and there they're like dude we
like the work you know that guy wants to
hang out at the bar but definitely hate
how they start I just feed my soil like
twice a year I don't even I'm not in
like a plant feeding schedule I'm
running a soil feeding schedule yep nice
in here I'll feed my soil like basically
like hi fungal woodchips worm castings
you know just keep lots of green matter
grasses you drive around if whatever I
get the Genoa leaves where everybody
else is driving to the gross store
you're like that wood chip pile has good
value that gardener over there I know
that lady doesn't use any pesticides I'm
gonna get that ground like rotten log
rolled off and get my Road it was like
full white you're like a fun guy yeah I
was like this I'll take that home with
me you know just pretty much anything
you can and I ever do I go to the beach
once I get on the coast so I go to the
beach with my kids and it's buckets of
kelp oh right on yeah has the
micronutrients yeah but I went to the
beach with my kids yeah yeah I do you
have any kids
oh yeah yeah I have two kids yeah I had
two boys well you have a boy and a girl
congratulations yeah yeah yeah oh isn't
it great
oh they gotta go in the dorm with you
you know not in the cannabis garden
right your I understand they're not
allowed to yeah that would be breaking
the law and know how it works
okay personal what I mean is thank you
for your prayer don't know about plants
yeah it changes how I interact with them
because I'm growing them too you know
and so they're they're learning about
patience and character and my
seven-year-old yet is big he's got like
104 gallon you know here that's his you
can do whatever he wants he chopped and
drought the whole damn thing in the mid
and I'm like okay but it's his learning
experience because he's in the garden
with me you know what I mean
where do I want them that's where I want
you you know and it sounds like you're
your garden is beautiful yeah you know
it's it's a learning experience you know
this year the beautiful beautiful thing
about focusing on the plant spirit
medicine end of it is that it distracts
you from the the pathogen the pathogen
of compliance
that was some Josh from Dragon I want
you to wait and repeat that because
that's not funny that's from like Josh
they're doing beautiful JA share that
with me today close and that really is
what it is the it's like a pathogen but
you know so we just have to find on a
microscope I don't know
we know I'm kind of like I'm really I'm
really like if it ain't broke don't fix
it less is more so you just listen to
the plants
you know you know this is where there's
all this science and science is great
but technically you just don't need to
know the science it does not matter it
doesn't change anything it only change
it you only really need to know it if
there's a problem if there's no problems
why would you spend your whole life
researching something when you don't
have to if you just do it this way with
with you know which is like a very
specific way you know yeah this this way
the way this way the way is basically
like five things you know as long as you
do the five things you don't have to do
the loop it's it's not what I do it's
what I won't do the list of what I won't
do is like huge but the things that I
need to do are five things yeah which is
focus on the ground you know focus on
the light you know you know fire or
light air and water and then the void
or this plant spirit medicine end of it
so as long as I focus on those five
things and stay on track that guides me
and I don't have to impose my will
because everything is done for you you
bring that it's like so I don't need to
know all the science in the world so
because it's just like you just have to
listen and do what you're told is really
simple
except it's it's it's challenging
because you have to build that
relationship of trust which takes time
and you got to put in your time to build
relationships of trust with your plans
with your plants which is kind of like
grabbing smoke you know what I mean
ropes of sand
yeah you just have to like yeah I'm
listening to so yeah we're dog is like
right there you know like well we're
like a great a second wagging their
tails then yeah all the time
where the plants are like you know it's
just like you got to hang out it's like
a whisper and the wind you're like wait
wait sit well if you think you heard
something you did you know like have you
I know you have what but most people
don't hang out in the garden yeah it's
wait don't tell me that I don't want to
hear that but that's no I hear that's
what we work I know there's a remind a
bunch of you know no but there's there's
no I hear that Needham now that you can
grow a plant
I'm just on it yeah and just be a piece
of fish yeah and go hang out with your
kids yeah
Castle is allowing for that too yeah
yeah and your personal space you can
have your fat your whole family yeah and
the plants are part of it because
they're part of the ecosystem and you
are part of that ecosystem and so when
we build soil yeah when I type does your
phone ever autocorrect do you have a
phone yes I did get a phone I did just
get one year ago it's a monster it is
it's her knee it'll teach Rachel's eggs
and you're just like hold on I literally
have the rule when I go out to the
garden
I'll I'll record like time-lapse oh yeah
so that I can't be on my phone my
phone's doing something and I'm doing
something you see what yeah I don't want
that yeah we did a time-lapse of us
rolling 150 joints last night it's
beautiful I love it yeah yeah we're like
so tell me so so tell me about your
strengths
oh my favorite that's words tell me
about your girls right I mean I can run
anything it's not like rock it's sort of
not rocket science you have to be able
to adapt and and feed this you know just
adapt okay so are we talking about
feeding soil we're talking about feeding
the biology the life is in the oil you
can do that a lot of different ways
right so it's not a lot of ways to skin
that cat so it sounds like you use cover
crops yeah oh yeah so you have all their
life growing it's not just a lone
soldier standing out there by themselves
oh yeah I have okay I'm gonna lay it on
you my system you're gonna love this
it's it's a a scaleable high production
no-till micro remediated subterranean
full-spectrum light depth bioretention
pit
technique so yes that's what we've been
missing that's like that's beautiful I
know what that mean you know what that
means you know you know that use the
layers upon layers of like took a while
to realize even realize that's what I
was doing because I've always been doing
that technique honestly since the
beginning because that's what I was told
to do so I did that and I true now I
just trusted the process from the
beginning and it's kind of like now now
the benefit of having a microscope and
learning all the science it's like when
I when I learn some science after living
it for 15 years right I'm like oh my god
that's what that's called yeah I
definitely think I didn't even know I
didn't even know I was doing no-till for
12 years doing it it's a point those
labels you know I went to fate MJ for
the first year MD vision Vegas and I was
like I was like I'm doing no-till I
think I was like I think we're doing all
these you know you're dumb now I'm doing
Jaedong which I've been doing for 15
right scenes and I'm doing living soil
yeah yeah now the newest one is you Dom
that you're growing man yes so you just
it's just yet exactly that's what it's
about it is adapting growing you're
growing yourself that's right that's
been the the bet the the most beneficial
thing I mean you get to actually work on
yourself that's some real shit and it
takes a lot of work and dedication I've
been doing like Depp so long right like
I've got like 5,000 hours into just
pulling covers alone so that's equal
that's equal to pulling a cover every
day twice a day for the next ten years
straight every day for ten years
straight
that's dedication that you know that's
discipline you know the main beautiful
man
so that's with the leg
the things you learn with experimenting
with different parts of the spectrum
well just shortening shortening my
harvest times I can take a sixty-three
day strain and finish it in 53 days or I
was taking a purple punch and and that's
like that was finishing it out and I
can't even believe it I know it's have
to do it again it was like 35 40 days
like completely 40 days it was like it
was like dying now there's so much
because a lot of people like oh it's
like you know it's like you must have a
degree Yale because it planted blades or
you know no I mean the silver oh gee
I've been doing when I took third at the
Emerald cup I did that not only do I not
only do i shortened the harvest time by
10 days but I don't water for a month
because of my soil so yeah I I charge my
soil I charge my soil and then for the
last month I don't water for 28 days
straight you don't but who does I mean
the funds rise oh yes yeah they're
literally feeding your plan and it's
it's it's allowing that plant to control
that very fine too much they're just
like diving and just but you know they
also grow out that a lot of young spread
but it's it's the other life that's part
of the team yeah you know and so you can
literally like I know people that dry
farm it yeah they do have water at all
right right yeah I'm not quite in the in
the environment but you got to have the
environment and part of that environment
is that the life and that's what turns
dirt into soil yeah no and you're me I
mean trying to focus on like high fungal
you know wood anything - like in Gap
yeah you know so you know there hasn't
been a lot of this is all kind of just
coming about so you're just kind of
winging it you know we're all kind of
winging it on some level
but it's working oh yeah it's totally
working it's totally working yeah yeah
I'm really just in love with that
connection and that relationship so yeah
now that the science is just gonna be
like if that's what blows my mind is
like learning like really it what it
creates just a different language yeah
it allows you to interact with people
yeah they did instead of pulling light
depth arts they spent the last 10 years
looking through a microscope so with
that same intensity and passion and they
figured some tricks out that you've
learned to write right pulling tires you
don't do it the same way you did the
first day do you know yeah and so having
that bigger picture right right like
your soil creates that depth I go to
farms that like good cannabis in Hampton
but also strawberries and spinach and
baby squash you know whatever you know
right and those plants grow in dirt it
is not alive it is like and you can see
I can show you like it it's that
clear-cut
and we miss yeah it doesn't have to be
like that with with it doesn't have to
be like that yeah and and you don't even
have to like know all the labels yeah
and that's the nice part yeah you don't
have to know that it's really easy to
get like hung up on the label you need
to know what you're intense what you're
trying to do I'm trying to encourage
fungal growth what do they eat right
lignin wood pulp yeah I'm gonna add it
yeah I feel like it's a with the wood
pulp there's a lot of meat on the bone
good description I like they know it
really breaks down super quick the wood
it's gonna just hang out on it I just
like yeah you know cuz it's just me so
it's hard to apply you know it's just a
job you know so it's in the way every
day you're working yeah I hardly I
hardly even grunts touch the planet no I
mean but you hardly even touch the
plants these days because you're doing
paperwork compliance compliance word you
can go out to the garden
oh yeah that's what's I changes
yeah yeah it it's not working anymore
right you know what do you mean you
exhale maybe you inhale there's there's
time that you spend out there that women
my wife you know there's not like you
kissed on the my knee and that's going
to work if you're not to focus just on
money then you can enter that zone where
that's where the magic happened here's
the nice part it's not work as in I need
to make money
no it's work is in I'm gonna go
ro
my plants my community my kids my race
for my ancestors out of respect for our
ancestors it's for seven generations for
the earth the generations back and forth
that's that I want to do today I want to
do those that's those three are like the
Trinity as far as in my mind when I when
I'm like what am i doing why am i
fighting this this beast are they to do
this simple act of growing a plant for
all of them because this is why yeah
that's why I'm doing it also to help
people good mind to remind you know so
that I can be reminded by pushing it's
reminding me so I can help other people
remember so we can all remember why
we're doing this for each other
the real reason on what's going on we
had to do to get by not what we endure
not where I would right now we get to do
yeah we did I do get hung up on that
because it's so like well there's a lot
right yeah well in three hours we're
going that where's this day's out of the
garden yeah yeah that's the where we're
going not where we've been we can't grow
it yeah like we can say like I asked
farmers who are so overwhelmed by today
which is really they're overwhelmed by
yesterday and last week and everything
else right paperwork and ridiculousness
oh yeah oh yeah me the wife like yeah
it's like bugs down the line yeah have
you felt like when you're out in the
grub garden like time is different and
it's not just cannabis cuz I'm I do that
all the time but you have this like it's
a different rhythm and it doesn't settle
right with this sometimes
you know what I mean and the rush and
the pace or the the phone call that says
hey you gotta pick up your kids from
school yeah yeah exactly
oh my gosh what right you did I'm
literally in fish emulsion I smell like
the fish death right it's beautiful for
the London I smell like gendarme like I
get a booklet like the sulfur or whether
off I get a phone call from this school
they're like your son just puked I'll be
right there
you're covered in like what but that's
what we grow you know
how do your little ones six and nine
a nine-year-old house house they take to
it
oh she's a little Savage
[Music]
basically I'm teaching her martial arts
she's learning to be an herbalist she's
learning to like work on you know trucks
run a tractor books you're a deer you
know real skills yeah real life skill
yeah
you can't fake calluses kind of like a
you know we could work a shovel we come
shields they'll protect you right and so
the boys will be like I got a new seal
today my spike Alice last year developed
into like a claw I could have like
climbed a building with that
motherfucker it was like a ninja claw I
was like gosh dude yeah yeah it was just
yeah I was not past two years working
like 1820 hours a day
for two years to get to this point you
know just about killing yourself a case
you guys go totally yeah yeah yeah
no it's awesome right that looks like a
a part of a scuba rig that I write
that's funny a scuba ring I haven't
heard that one okay yeah tell me more
it's part of a scuba rig it's the
regulator on a scuba tank that's a good
cover
Wow today I with helps me breathe
[Music]
it's I call it the industrial
steamroller the safety is on right now
because it's not really in steamroller
mode technically so you know it's it the
safety is on because it's dangerous
it'll fuck you up it hits hard
it's not fair that's why I don't
necessarily pass it around so you have
an inner chamber and and tubes that is
there water no there's no water it's
just direct drive okay it's got a manual
transmission it sounds like a car I love
it
hi righto they say it really started as
a joke but like all good things that
start as a joke there's actually a
really good idea and then we just kind
of kept rolling with it because you know
it worked you know I had a buddy he says
you know what you take the shit and turn
it into some good and I'm like yeah I
make compost you know it's like
sometimes you can do
for real and it feels really good to do
it for real
do you like metalwork um a welder
upgrades I do shipping container
buildings I do my building
I've been they're afraid resource like
expedition vehicles nice right
like that I I have a 40-foot I use it
for everything like a 40-foot shipping
container see train but I you there's
like three grand
it's cheaper than one of those sheds at
Home Depot man and I grow I have worm
bins in there
I've got like it's it's alive and it
allows me to have a habitat that's out
of the elements and I can control a
little bit more that's just little
cruising all year long it's pretty
amazing stuff yeah I built this 3,000
square-foot shipping container building
out of scrap and surplus steel by the
pound by the pound so I built the
building essentially by the pallet and
then I built all the decking out of
old-growth redwood 2x6
that i milled from my property trees
yeah there are trees from our per they
needed you know they were not the
healthiest trees because they're all
growth they've been through a lot of
fires and bugs so is more of a culling
it was more of a culling of the forest
it's not like I'm fucking cutting down
old-growth you know I'm calling I'm
calling the forest for sure for the
health of the forest so the trees that
are not scarred to shape I am full of
logs
rotten and burnt out and we're gonna
fall over on your how whatever you know
you you know it's better to take those
down mill those clear the forest out and
then the trees that are there will grow
like thirty to sixty percent more so
your children will most well be more
likely to have some millaa millaa
boyhood in the future or and protect the
forest you change the photo period of
that space right you've changed the life
and it explodes and stuff that you
haven't seen in years because it's just
been waiting you know it takes a long
time for those Giants to fall on their
own and it waits for years it's so great
yeah like what is that my puck here Mike
yeah no you really have to yeah plus I
have this new thing for my excavator
this flail mower yeah
so I can reach like 25 feet in the air
and just like mulch a tree to the ground
and tato three-dimensional it totally
takes away that brat yeah I don't have
to touch it
I don't have to touch it I can take like
down to a five inch tree just right to
the ground and just in my emotion like
literally just working them I can suck
all the branches in and just shoot the
leaves down and just mulch the whole
tree and I'll have like mulch like this
deep needy knee-deep mulch the forest is
like so happy about that
it could not be happier because that's
what the forest wants to eat is it's
only it's that's why that's what that's
why I've been focusing on just feeding
my plants cannabis leaves because that's
how they're meat even the male's out of
the garden eat they have purpose right
but the cannabis leaves fed to your
plants in it yeah yeah in an anaerobic
process so it speeds up the deferment
you know the process of breaking down
the organic matter and makes the
inorganic nutrients available
I mean think of Italy growing with life
yeah
and what does that mean like it changes
[Music]
basically instead of it taking a year
you can you quick you know you speed it
up to like three days two weeks a month
and three months this season or whatever
we do soil testing and it was a total
total basket case of the site and
nothing there except what they call
silty clay it's like concrete or moon
dust it is no in between it's ridiculous
it went from a two inch to a three foot
soil death
just by adding lights and feeding the
soil it's amazing if you throw grasses
like Sudan grass cut it down and keep
laying it down and then spray it with
like an IMO for yeah laid out that light
it'll go travel down 50 feet or whatever
into the ground and just bring it to
life that's it that's incorrect that is
magic that's straight-up magic as far as
them that's impressive
oh I need coal bulbs I can go get it
back or I can go to this or you can just
feed the light and it goes oh thank you
so much good sir hold on hold on have
you introduced yourself oh yeah we know
each other
it has been a pleasure sitting with you
oh yeah yeah totally yes it's been it's
been a wild awesome ride
an amazing experience just these past
couple years you know
he's passed like three years they've
just been like mind-blowing for sure we
never we you know what I mean and where
is it gonna go from here
not in a million years three years ago
yeah we do have thought that right now
you'd be sitting here this is what be
going like you know ya know you know we
were about to sell our property we were
we were selling our property and then we
won the Emerald cup and we were like
fuck now I'm supposed to stop
we were about to you know we were gonna
give and then my I'm like I'm gonna give
up now so we took that as a sign and
then I that was 2017 we took third in
light up with our you know 13 whatever
decade old soil you know with just water
you know with one compost tea water and
like one super light top dress and I was
just really like trusting the process
that's what that's what was it that's
what one is the process the methodology
the soil the bacteria the funk that's
what you know by trusting them that's
what they produces the highest quality
you know so for the least amount of
money you know so most consistently and
and I've been anybody to and I've been
able to hit my you know 50 pounds per
thousand square feet on have you done
testing like I go like 250
like a hundred fifty bucks
well in 2017 it's not in 2017 when we
wanted to see if we had what it took to
stay in the game so we doubled our
production cutter cost in the half in
half and then won you know 2/3 in like
that in the Emerald cup so we were like
okay I guess let's keep going and and we
were testing out at like 30 29 to 30
percent consistently 28 to 30 percent
with our so Jesus silver oh gee that's
earful total cannabinoids like they're
about 29 to 30 I've been holding spring
yes oh and then we took the third at the
weed con this year
we were in the harvest box for organic
farming in Spring Creek Farm
yeah we're Sonoma County where Sonoma
County's oldest living soil brand and
like that technically I think you know
because we've been it's a funny one that
it kind of gauges your growth right have
you when you go out there at night juicy
worms cutting around on the surface Hey
like they come out to play what you go
home and go to bed they're still out
working like you know it's a kindly love
spending time in the dark in my
greenhouse I'm really like addicted to
that tree and with the green light the
green light I have a you know I had that
with the green light and I'll just hang
in there and just I did the vibes are
just have you heard of method seven
they make these lenses that they
literally were designed scientifically
because a man was tired of seeing his
friends go wrong lines and he knew about
filters he was a photographer I like
visually going blind Oh from right he
was going back to these girls
year after year and he's like what's
going on with George
people are getting blinds in the indoor
and so like it changes how you see
things right and so now they've
developed it enough that you can put
these glasses on and it can be purple or
HPS orange or you know there and it's
like walking out in the garden it's
amazing and more people need to remember
that that's where plants grow and I
think it'll change the industry
right that if you remember that plants
go out in the garden it's just that
mindset
I'm not sure how to use this if you
there's no car just
[Music]
yeah it's definitely and that's your hat
on the top yeah yeah it's it's some Keef
yeah it's Keith that's just like hand
pressed you know yeah Wow yeah yeah I'm
a ninja
I didn't Forge the metal but you know I
mean yeah I put the pieces together and
I assembled it yeah it's it it's quite
functional actually it's a bottle opener
has many uses conversation oh you can't
have multi tools oh dude it's it's a
hammer I've used it as a hammer it can
be you know used as many things it
straight up like a bottle opener like
right there boom that a drip pop like
give me that boom like it's it's perfect
my views as a hammer it's like a it's
like a handle you could put like
shopping bags from it if you hit a whole
drink up in the face when you're
carrying oh yeah your arms oh yeah plus
it's
I've got a solar attachment for it too a
little leg filler of it would know as a
magnifying glass but it's in a thin
amount too and I just if yep it bolts
onto here but I just I fucked that up so
it's it's not working right now
literally light it with widows done yeah
see I'm straight I just heard like a
chunk of hash on there and you can just
like hit it with the Sun that's what uh
super clean it
nothing but sunshine
where's that where you got the money
Oh give me a lighter here let me uh
let me get it let me put let me refresh
it
[Music]
yeah when it's in steamroller Road
steamroller mode yeah it's like it'll in
its heart really hard why I thought what
you said it he took it the steamroller
mode
you know I won't go steamroller mode so
I want to hear about the safety though
and how you choke the car button or
however it works you know if I remove
the end you know and you just use it as
a steamroller you know like you know
what I mean but I just usually roll with
it like direct drive it's just safer you
know in public it's safer in public like
that you know what I mean
I don't want to fuck somebody up too bad
that be like fucking kill somebody you
know I'm looking at trying to find a I
need more volume and I don't do constant
you know what I mean more volume I'm
thinking like vaporizing it's like I do
just flower you know yeah but I don't
like Dirty Pair wait let me let me put
uh let me put a chunk on it that's how
it gets going there you go
so you you've been on this property for
18 years you've said no I've been there
for like Inc in Casa Darrow for yeah
like seven seventeen years 16 17 years
or so that's right and then on this
property for like 10 12 13 right I do
are gonna come out 14 years I guess the
return on investment thing oh yeah about
30 Nia working the year as you were
saying that because of how you cared for
your lands you spent a hundred and fifty
dollars that's what you the cost yeah
yeah and that's when I was buying stuff
this year I didn't spend anything except
from brown sugar
I don't why Brown shit I don't be a
jeweler I don't do that Alondra Dom I'm
not doing like an INF K&amp;F is like that's
the difference like ANF is like sugar
right the DOM is more protein based okay
K and F is more sugar right right focus
well just warm gets it out of bacterial
down versus e more complex
protein is more protein at least break
fast complex white stinkier whereas KN f
is like sweeter smelling which you know
can draw bugs in there in the spring
I'll I'm just I'm not right by sugar and
in springtime I mean cars it's like I
have to go by she where's the sugar
I don't waste it on my property right do
I fix your bags of sugar go get me some
sugar right
no I was already like kind of that's
just my my minimalist extremists that's
kind of who I am anyway so you know the
jus Dom stuff a methodology really
I already what I've I'm very vocal about
about how I operate okay very cool boys
you know right like that's why I say I
do like a no-till nothing style I heard
it you know I'm not like nothing I'm not
like no-till trying right you know
there's like there's like you can do
no-till but then you're like doing it
yeah if you're doing anything then
you're like doing it but you don't want
to do it you're trying to not do it
right between not doing it and like not
not doing it
there's doing it I totally get what a
sign but because you're not it's a fine
dicking around with your plan right
you're feeding you're focused you're
being so efficient effective that it's
you know yeah it might look like I'm not
doing anything but that's not what I'm
doing I'm totally doing some shit but
some shits going I'm just doing the
right it's just gonna take three months
for you to really see it indirectly you
know because the plants now we're not
operators like the turtle right you know
the rabbit in the end and the lower you
know and then plants yeah
please be it's a different rhythm right
you know what I mean yeah there's like
the the rabbit the turtle at the
tortoise and then a plant speed so then
but the plant just like beats the rabbit
because it just connects into the
mycelial network and pops up here the
plant can do it all you kind of play a
ball not even moving it's like boom and
nothing even changes they mean nothing
even happened practically it's like
magic you wake up one day and you're
like wow plants are that matter that's
growing really well yeah
one day hate sunshine yeah make sugar so
here let's make this like you know as
scientists science can go they really
thought I really have networks you know
like this one round I did I just was
giving it water didn't didn't feed it
didn't even give it a top dress no
nothing just water it was perfect
everything looked perfect my wife was
like you know do something are you dude
how's it I'm like it looks great she's I
got to do something and I went to the
plants and I was like she wants me I
should do something I was like well and
the plants were like well if you really
feel the need to to you know if you want
to do some if you want to met you know
if you really want to do something you
know go ahead but you we don't need you
to do anything and if you want to mess
something up to make yourself feel
useful right as a human if you want to
mess like everything was so perfect why
mess it up alright in the garden and I'm
like so I was like alright I won't do
anything I'm like yeah I'm like I'm just
not gonna she's like so what would you
do and I was like nah I had to talk with
the plants they told me like do you if
I'm just gonna fuck them up but like why
yeah I know some time in the garden
hey isn't that idea and then I get some
time for myself everything's just
functioning it's in and then I can go
mushroom hunting and spend time with my
children that's right and you know
working my tractor or something like
that I get my equipment
you know do some welding I'm a knife
maker I do like Bladesman thing you know
so I got no shortage of a lot of irons
in the fire projects to work on whatever
metalwork
or something like that build a truck
building you know my trucks or whatever
you know so I just like to keep busy
then with your light dish are you doing
artificial light it's other seasons or
is it only son I'm just supplementing
just you know it's like sometimes we'll
have like no Sun for six weeks because
there's a fire and we have to affect you
know so I'll need to supplement I'll use
I'll use my HPS because I mean I got
them and it's not ideal I know sorry I
paid like 300 bucks for you know all of
them and you know as somebody shutting
down that it worked for me hey you know
it's not ideal I don't feel that is your
plant it helps me stay in business you
know if you know that's about the worst
thing that I do is use some HPS you know
what I mean you have blessed soil and
compress it along that's about the worst
thing they do for real I give it more
light when there's no lights yeah when
there's like no light I up lament it
maybe I'll hit it a little bit and you
know finish it with at the end just to
pop off but it really doesn't they
really hate the spectrum honestly the
plants literally tell me I hate this
spectrum I'm like I know I'm sorry
that's what I got I'm Rick I'd hate it
too it's not good for your eyes it's not
good for our eyes it's not good for you
I'm doing the best I can as I can if I
if the banks would just if the fucking
if I could just get a loan from the
banks would just you know if we can just
figure out this fucking banking thing
and I can just solve it yes you know get
the LED lighting that I need instead of
having to do pay some stupid high I know
rate just to get like the basic lighting
I need which is like the most important
tool when you're a grower it's like
doing finished carpentry with a fucking
piece of shit saw you found on the side
of the road
you know liking within fucking soft and
still making it look cool there and
still making it look like it grew there
because that's what at it that's what
it's that's what's up
I don't know that's what I know I just
rollin we just know I just we rolled 150
joints and we're just like gonna smoke
everybody the fuck out just like that's
it you know what I mean I just didn't
even I don't know I was just so busy
doing stuff I couldn't even like get to
town to really enter and I don't know I
probably should have because this mimosa
actually is like that what this is no
but that I think this one the joints
that you guys rolled yeah these those
are 24k but yeah this is my most I mean
you can see you know that's just like
cannabis leaves and like some some some
thistle I was fed like this a horse tail
and all
you know as that like licorice I do I do
yeah I I have yes no let me smell this
all that yeah yeah
oh it like warms on the backside yeah
it's really nice yeah it's pretty strong
- it's got like uh that's I've got a big
jar of it and I'm blowing through the
jar yeah I'm halfway through a large jar
so I'm like do have the mumbo it's a
mimosa is that right yeah the most of
that I've grown was it was a really nice
sativa without being racy how's this one
grow for you you know it was like really
strong it's just like freestanding more
indica style didn't need any trellising
basically it held its own
yeah some of it wasn't even trellis it
was like didn't need any it was like the
ones that I did didn't even need I could
have just not done it where the 24 K had
like three layers of trellising was
falling apart all over the place like
every whichaway 15 pounds from that
would let three layers of trellis thing
to just try to hold it up it was such a
oh you you did that well I've seen no I
had a full greenhouse full of it oh my
god and it quadrupled it I planted them
in June July 17 I've until last minute
and they were like just close I mean
they were tiny and they got eight feet
tall they got eight feet there they were
just Patrick King I got him up there
yeah and uh yeah the soil King his uh
his uh little facility his facility
there he hooked me up with those and
then I got some others from somebody
else and I just ran with what I could
get and hit the crunch man made it
through yeah the fact that I have any
weed this year at all product and that
we ended up in the harvest box with
organic as well because we were in there
last year
so you know it was I'm really honored on
so many levels so the fight that we've
been fighting it's it's you know it
feels good any any win anything good is
huge anything positive is so huge right
now you know just to connect with people
and you know just to be like yeah all of
it it's just you know it's amazing it
eats the soul yeah it's bringing us all
together it's what we needed cuz I mean
I was like as about as lone wolf as
anybody you know what I mean you don't
even come off the mound for sure yeah
it's the only new bro if you only knew
the stories you know so but it's it's a
hundred percent necessary for all of us
it is that's why you know I don't want
to be doing this necessarily you know
but it's necessary I have no choice we
all need it I need to you know
understand it in myself and cultivate
your you're growing yourself I'm trying
to cultivate that in myself so I can
become a better person and and so my the
things that I'm teaching my children
right now that have taken me this long
to learn I'm just like lighting them up
man right my daughter is a spy say she's
pretty Savage yeah she's Savage I'm in
the garden it's like six months you
should see her flying me like Tony Jaa's
and she's a healer she's learning to be
a healer my wife's on the healer marshy
to grow you know grow you know grow food
and medicine how to use them how to
protect people how to protect yourself
honor and respect yourself and and the
earth the people around you and
everything you do how you work walk
through this world
do you play like like cannabis like as
an entity does that sound weird but you
know what I mean like it's like coming
out of the closet
you know what I mean like it's it's not
having to be grown indoors it shifted
the culture like even in I know like
people who are doing yeah we're going to
what we're going back one time we're
sitting into it yeah but it's in living
soil
yeah and it's changing the plants and
it's helping the Kim we're going back in
time to move forward yeah a hundred
percent of water levels I mean that's
been said many times lately yeah
it's really I agree unnecessary you know
methodology the mindset to focus on