[Music]
we sound on a survey to licensed
operators all across the supply chain we
asked and feedback on specific questions
we asked for their comments and we
largely based all of those replies that
we received and put them into these
questions and then you know there's
about 15 questions that we sort of got
in mind from from that if we have time
we'll definitely you know do some QA if
we can but they're pretty dense and
meaty subjects so I think we can just
like go through and have a good time
with it
okay everyone cool all right that's how
we're gonna do it but first all right so
Laurie thank you for being here it's
really a pleasure to have you here I
don't know if everyone knows but Laurie
his husband I had a huge milestone
yesterday and it was huge celebration
and she drove up for this event while
something is going on with family and
everything it's great thank you for
doing that you're welcome thank you for
having me yeah it means a lot we're like
come on Laurie please say yes so last
time we were here we were in the
amphitheater over there right I don't
know if everyone remembers and I kind of
wanted to just take a moment and retrace
what we've been through in the last year
and I think you guys are all gonna get a
kick out of it so right after we left
last year we had July 1 and if everyone
remembers July 1 there was lab testing
and packaging requirements and the
destruction of products that wasn't
really fun we had emergency regulations
number two and then public comment
period we had the regulations when we
submitted it to the O AO and waiting in
that that time frame
we had in parallel temporary application
process and annual application process
and then you had a trickling of
Provisionals that went out
temps you extended but
we had to legislate to get permission to
provide extensions while processing
applications or not and I don't know if
anyone knows this but Lori's team
definitely in in December her she I
remember you saying on stage you're like
we will process every single application
and you guys did you were working
through the holidays you were working
weekends you were working nights your
entire team and you finish the entire
queue which I thought was really
admirable amazing so thank you for doing
that
then it brings us to 2019 where the
writing on the wall that CD CD F a and
CD pH weren't actually allowed to give
extensions yeah and then that led us to
a round of licensing attrition from
temporaries to nothing or temporaries to
Provisionals and enables then we have
the new legislation that's being pushed
around sampling white labeling non
licensing all this other stuff that
that's going through and then about like
last month your the agency BC seats are
pushing out Provisionals and then oh and
also the 10 million dollar equity grant
money was announced on a registration
process but then put on hold right guys
that was just like a high level of last
year I mean does it feel like oh my god
it's crazy but we've had a lot of wins
and this is why well and these come
directly from the survey responses
cannabis is legal people are not going
to jail right amazing we have clean
medicine maybe a little too clean but uh
a little too clean I think the metals
may be a little bit we could accept a
little bit more metals deliveries are
allowed everywhere so we're not
restricting access to California's in
local governments who enacted a ban
which is huge and I credit to your a
group you've advocated for that you
stood for that and without your support
in your fight I I doubt we would have
had statewide delivery so kudos to that
issuing temp licenses thank you for
extending it and giving people time to
catch up
transparency for the consumer
what's interesting social equity is more
of a focus than ever from last year this
year that is a driving point and many of
the conversations we're having after
some setbacks the the compassion program
is being reconsidered so that's great
too for compassion thank you for that
event licensing we were having more
events provisional licensing and just in
time for Meadowlands the QA database I
mean that it's phenomenal thank you for
doing that I mean I can't tell you how
many questions that we all I mean even
this weekend share and to have a
legitimate source that's saying hey this
is the answer no misinformation we can
go to helps a lot so thank you for
making that happen my team did a great
job and we're just gonna keep adding to
it by the way and these are a lot of the
questions that we're answering by email
and instead of just going to one person
we're just gonna share it all with you
folks I think it's gonna be helpful yes
yes for the consultants that make money
on just that piece you know sorry but
let's let's tackle some other things and
help us help each other out all right so
that was like boy I mean that's a lot
right any thoughts on the winds or the
past it's it's been brutal that's what I
for you guys too right I mean like the
last year 2018 is like a blur and I you
know I almost forget some of the things
until you mention them and I I will say
this what a lot of you don't know either
is that the first four month of 2019 we
were statutorily mandated to have a
Department of Finance audit so for four
months we had about eight auditors
looking at everything so that'll be
coming out on July 1st they have to
report it to the legislature so it's
something you might
want to keep an eye out for Wow so you
go through audits - it's like a report
card you guys got me I was on your
report card I'm like oh no and then yeah
everybody's Wow yeah it's pretty
incredible a cat Packer was here
yesterday and she's like at least we
don't have to go through everything that
we just went through again and if
anything everything that we did go
through hopefully has made us more
resilient and knowledgeable about the
process and kind of what we need to do
to kind of continue to navigate and move
ahead all right so let's let's dive in
here so the journey is largely focused
on creating a successful regulated
supply chain for the largest cannabis
market in the world it's a tough job in
the last year we've taken both steps
forward and backward what do you need in
terms of support to realize your vision
of a successful supply chain currently
so I think that when we talk about big
businesses middle medium-sized small
businesses we want a little bit of
everything right you want a balance and
one of the things in the statute when
you have a full vertical integration it
does make it difficult to strike that
balance because you know the big guys
can hold every license so can the small
guys so that gets it gets tough but I
think as for the state of California we
really start have to look at the small
businesses and how do we make you know
the new business is coming up how do we
make them successful and I don't know
that we've struck that balance yet I
think our regulations are are hard for
new businesses starting out and of
course when I say what kind of support
we need well and I think for one thing
you guys are a big voice and that is we
need more enforcement on the unlicensed
market we can't ever expect you to make
it if you're going to continue to
compete in this market with an
unregulated unlicensed market that
frankly there's a lot of you know some
of them are trying to get a license but
there's a good chunk of them that have
no intention of getting a license
they're almost saying hey we're just
gonna wait til somebody says something
or do something and so for for us at the
bureau
I talked with my staff I mean I say this
and I don't take it lightly it is a
fight every single day but I see the
industry your voice I think means a lot
and to continue to say hey we need more
enforcement we need more to go out and
make sure that we can compete in this
market so I think enforcement is a is a
big deal and it touches so many of us so
I'm hoping over this and I just want to
crush the illegal market and I don't
usually say that out loud but I feel the
same way you do because we didn't work
go through all this for the last few
years to have this market be undermined
for people that don't want to get in the
licensed market so we feel it personal -
because you don't want to sacrifice
always sacrifice to see basically people
just say well we're not going to get
involved we're just gonna you know not
get licensed it's not fair to all of you
here that our license paying all your
fees and taxes so yeah so you know to
summarize more like having an ability
for small businesses to compete and you
know going after enforcement in a way
where the illicit market you know does
not exist and we can continue to thrive
yeah and one more thing I had a
conversation I don't know Maya's he or
she was a perfect example she asked me a
question and she is a manufacturer and
the hardest thing for us like when Alex
and Andre from my team is here when
people come to me and say hey you know
something happened we had two real able
all our product it would be nice if we
could do something a different way and I
have to say well we don't regulate the
manufacturers at the BCC you have to go
to another agency that's really hard to
do and you have to deal with three
different licensing agency and that's
not including all the other agencies and
so I want to solve problems but it's
hard when some problems that it's
difficult to solve because it doesn't
fall under our Authority and so I think
we need to find better ways to
collaborate with ourselves at the state
right and just make one agency and guys
on top of that can we yeah
can we do that I guess about the looking
tonight is that ballot I don't even know
but like but what you're saying is that
there's just so much inter agency work
make it through I think we gotta really
think about that going forward and but I
I want to I'm committed to we gotta have
better communication I'm gonna tell you
if sometimes it's hard for me to get an
answer from other state agencies I can
only imagine what it is for the industry
right and so so we've got to do better
there and I think we're going to
concentrate on that that we got to have
consistency between the agencies and be
responsive and I think you guys know we
we want to hear from you we really do we
want your feedback but we know there's I
mean you just mentioned it like lab
testing maybe we need to relax a little
on the heavy metals I do think I think
lab testing is very important I think we
all think that but where's where again
where's the balance and do we need to
look at those things yeah I think what's
interesting and specifically the labs it
was you look at other states and their
lab testing requirements California is
pretty stringent and when you're failing
on something where other states it's
okay and you're failing by you know 0.1
or whatever it's it's detrimental to
these these operators it's a huge
setback so last year we asked you if you
had a Northstar metric and I think you
are at the time just saying well there
is a lot of change it's very difficult
to have a Northstar metric processing as
many licenses was a metric currently is
there a Northstar metric for 2019 for
the BCC well as you know we're our
metric is like the end of July right now
we got it we have about 1800 temporaries
that are expiring so and we're in a
provisional yeah getting a provisional
we don't want any gap in licensure I I
am my my staff understands I don't want
anybody expiring nobody's expiring we
got to get you in a provisional and if
that means we got to call you on Sunday
morning we're hoping we're calling you
on Sunday morning do it can you make
that happen for CDFA and NCD pH
I mean I just wish that was shared
across all agencies well yeah so that's
a short-term metric but just but that is
the direction we say I don't I mean I
don't want anybody slipping through the
cracks but we also don't want you
staying in a provisional we want to get
those annuals out and I think that's
important for a lot of you I don't like
the word temporary or provisional I like
the word annual because that means
you're here to stay
and so that's that's a big I mean
obviously still going you know working
on that enforcement and then just so you
know we're looking at where look we're
already starting to rewrite some of our
regulations where we have there's a lot
of things we need to correct where
there's a lot of things we need to
clarify and so it's not this is no time
to say hey you know you're stuck with
the regs I think if you have feedback if
things that you think aren't working now
is the time to start telling us hey take
a look at this or that and that's what
we're doing right now and and depending
on what happens with legislation you're
probably going to see a regulation
package at least clean up and
clarification and new legislation
towards the end of the year Wow you are
busy
I mean BCC is a really tough job I can
only imagine what you and your
department has to go through because not
only processing applications going to
these meetings talking to all these
agencies you're hiring more staff you're
integrating them into the process you're
talking to multiple stakeholders those
stakeholders often are changing too to
try to keep track of everyone you know
it can get I don't know it could get
easy just to just like alright maybe
this is too much you know what is
motivating you to continue to show up at
everything participate keep you know
pushing forward still having a positive
attitude about everything like you know
I'm just Curt you know curious about
that
so there's many times when I it is
overwhelming and you do get down you see
we see the struggles I think the hardest
part right now is because we do most of
my staff we take it personally and
normally when you're a regulated
you don't get that kind of emotion but I
don't like to see people struggling to
just survive so I think what motivates
me is I think there's three there's more
we can do it's not enough that we I
think I've always said this is not
enough just to put in regulations and
say oh we got our final regulations our
work is done I feel like I'm my work is
quite not done I got to make things
better I got to leave it in a better
place for those who come after me and so
I I don't want to see so many people
hurting and painful because if anything
you guys have taught me canvas isn't
supposed to be that and it shouldn't be
that right absolutely yeah
last November we elected governor Newsom
who was part of the Blue Ribbon Campaign
on actually moving 64 Ford so he helped
design the framework and and you were
tasked with implementing it and now he's
seeing that implementation process he is
you know been more aware of what's going
on the industry is more connected and is
also hired you know advisers like Nicole
Elliot who was head of Austin camp in
San Francisco was here yesterday to his
administration and what's your
relationship with governor newsome's
office and how things change from
working with Governor Brown you know
what are their priorities and
specifically you know how does your
mandate changed so I in governor
Newson's office has been actually really
responsive they really understand the
issues and I think a lot of that came
from him being so involved with the Blue
Ribbon Commission Nicole Elliot came on
just a few months ago and she's just hit
the ground running and she really has a
good overview of cannabis so it is nice
that we have somebody directly in the
administration that we can go to when we
do have issues that come up so for us
that's been a that's been huge for us so
and we have a really good relationship
with them so I'm really looking forward
to the next year because I think
together I mean it again there's so many
there's only so much the Bureau can do
so having someone like her on our side
it really helps and the administration
that actually won
to move forward and push compassion and
all these always exactly exactly yeah I
think that's really a key so I'm gonna
have you play doctor from a moment so we
as part of the survey collected data
points and basically said it's to
measure the overall health and industry
so we've got some vitals here and based
off of these vitals love to give you
know your thoughts on the diagnosis of
it so we had five questions here and
they go from the scale of one to five
one poor five great how would you rate
the transition and and so these people
just marked off between one to five how
would you rate the transition to current
regs two-thirds rated it one or two how
would you rate the metric roll out so
far
seventy percent rated a one or two are
you more or less profitable than you
were last year fifty-three percent are
less profitable are you hiring one third
is hiring two-thirds or frozen
do you believe California has created an
environment in which small cannabis
businesses can succeed ninety-five
percent said no so these are the same
questions we asked last year but of
stark difference in just the financial
well I'm not going to be the doctor
those are the vitals what do you think
doctor yeah it's sort of terrifying
right and when you see that that's one
of the felt like that's not a very good
report card and I don't know how long
I'd be a doctor with those that's right
yeah it's it's it's definitely alarming
I think but to your point on what
success looks like you know getting
those numbers up will tie into helping a
lot of the operators here that are going
through that and you know your
commitment on doing the QA and all that
stuff it's just like we're gonna have to
attack it from a lot of different angles
so this is on the interagency one do we
need a task force or Commission with
representative from the BC seafood and
Ag Public Health tax and fee
Administration to facilitate interagency
communication is that something that BC
C is your quarterback I mean it goes
back to
I said about coordination and yeah I
think that that's a great idea came up
with that that's a great idea no we're
just uh putting some ideas out there we
got a lot conference we've been talking
about and getting feedback from
everybody I think I think what you guys
I mean I think your ideas I mean we know
the state certainly you guys figured
this out we don't have the market on all
the good ideas you have a lot of good
ideas and you know we work for you you
you're paying your taxes you paint your
license fee fee so some of this stuff is
is good to demand like hey we need
better inter coordination how about
putting a task force I actually like
that idea so I am I'm in favor of
something like that I don't know should
I don't know about quarterbacking it can
you know but I'm a Mac every team needs
a quarterback the doctor I know doctor
stuff so this relates to metric so you
know seventy percent related one or two
I mean not a lot of people have had
access to it yet so I think that what
the data is a little skewed our
experience at Meadow has been pretty
interesting you know our engineers had
no access to the UI we had to build
pretty much in the dark on it and
metrics not that user-friendly it's a
little bit slow it's prone it's really
prone to human error if you don't know
the system intuitively it's it's there
so it's pretty cumbersome to account for
especially when you're building software
to integrate something that that's there
and we also have found a lot of
artifacts from other states that weren't
California specific as we were going
through so you know one thing that we're
seeing is once you get access to metric
you have to order your tags and then
once you get your tags I have to put
your inventory in right but the clock
starts 30 days from the time you have
your training not 30 days after you get
your tags which i think is we basically
lose two three weeks of getting the
inventory in so these are just some of
our experiences what's your experience
with BCC what is the feedback they're
your gang from licenses is this working
the way you expected to I know it's not
to your purview and control otherwise I
feel it would be in a better position
that's just my opinion
but you know but here you're it's a big
thing that's coming so it's here so I
think we're experiencing some of the
same things you are
we're seeing as it relates to even our
licence types like micro businesses for
example it's very difficult if you're a
micro business manufacturer distribution
and retail how that looks in metric that
really wasn't accounted for very well
and for a lot of us at BCC we probably
got to look at the system around the
same just recently we didn't have
recently this to the system so we were
relying on another agency to sort of
navigate our regs so we're we're finding
we need to we're already asking for
changes from metric because I don't feel
it's intuitive now at least we get on
there and we're like I can only imagine
that if you're having to do this every
day you really do almost have to have
someone that understands the system hire
someone specifically just to do metric
so I think we need to make improvements
there and - I like you were saying I
feel like the rollout probably wasn't is
you know didn't go as well as we thought
it would for us we know like I I don't
even know if it was a good idea telling
you guys that you have to put all your
inventory that our regs say that you
don't put all your inventory yeah and
we're unfortunately if I think if we
knew - understood metric and how it
worked better last year because we
didn't have access to the system I don't
think we would have asked you guys to do
that so one of the things we're doing is
if some of you are retailers or
distributors we've actually turned off
your ability to get tags because we want
to we want to reach out to you first so
we can explain what we expect because we
had we had retailers asking for like
50,000 tags because they planned on
tagging every single product and we've
saying no we don't want you to do that
we just want you to tag one like candy
bar and say hey we've got 5,000 units of
candy bar instead of doing every
so we've been trying to like yeah we've
been seeing that too yeah
fixed that a little bit so you're not
spending so much time at the though at
the beginning trying to log your
inventory and so we're learning like
right there with you which you probably
won't really that's sort of scary but
what we are finding is it's taking up a
lot of our time and so we're pulling
from position percent it's it's it's a
it's a lot I've got one full time person
I'm bringing in a whole unit just on the
BCC side to deal with the questions and
the issues and what we have so you're
gonna see from us in the next coming
months putting more resources to help
you guys because I think that is our job
this is the state system we got to help
you navigate it and that means we we've
found that even with BCC we have to have
the the folks on our side that
understand metric too well so we can
walk because I we're not we're not I
don't know that going to metric is the
answer we've got to have the answers for
you and walk you through the process but
I think we'll get there I but I want you
to know on the BCC side we're not I mean
as much as we say you got to have that
inventory or tags order you know we're
very flexible on those timelines in our
regulation very variable
we are very flexible great so thank you
okay one thing that has recently
happened with metric anyway I just want
you also want to get you credentials I
think we're just like we agree we're
happy this makes us happy okay smiling
faces okay
metric recently opened its additives API
based on a request from the state how
our request from the state to metric
handled and prioritize our they're going
to go are there going to be any metric
user groups where people and Industry
can weigh in on feature and API
prioritization I would love that that I
think if you leave here today and you go
back and go to see DFA and metric and
say that I think that would be great
because here's the problem
we've all asked for a few things - like
one I don't know if any of you knew this
but the certificate of analysis that the
labs fill out there was no ability for
them to upload that yeah I know that you
knew that or every see I don't know if
there's any lab folks here but if you're
you would have to go through for every
test and right right you know click you
know pass fail pass fail and so we did
we are having that change so you are
gonna get your results faster right you
can just upload it and store it so
though that's just one of them but we
like again we've had some issues with
the distributors one so of course when
you're BC C we want to say we're top
priority right but then Public Health
may have a priority and food and AG may
have a priority so it gets very
difficult when the three of us are
trying to prioritize because we all
think that's a priority maybe the answer
is and you guys are brilliant here is
the industry prioritize it what's
affecting you the most what do we need
to work on first and what can wait so I
think that's you got you're onto
something there yeah we've actually
organized or self-organized
in a lot of the trade organizations
track and trace groups you know for the
cannabis distribution Association we
have a weekly meeting on metric calls
where we're just troubleshooting and
providing advice and saying hey this is
what you should do here you know
recently the transfer API is open if you
request it which is really important if
you think about the transfer API before
that you had to create everything within
the system and now I can can use it but
a lot of this stuff isn't being
published like you don't know unless you
know so I really encourage everyone to
get engaged with their their
associations and the regulatory bodies -
to really get a handle on it because
there are a lot of nuances here but I'm
glad that you you share the pain of
metric do and I think if you're if we're
not putting good data in the system then
what uses metric right so we we have -
right
it's absolutely yeah switching gears
what social equity mean to you what does
a successful equity program look like
well I I don't know that I know what a
successful program looks like because
apparently we put one out and then we
took it back so we're working on it
again so you think about it we think
about a little bit more which isn't a
bad thing by the way I think it's always
you know it's always good to be able to
look at something and say hey maybe we
didn't really hit the mark on that let's
pull it back so I think for for us at
the bureau I think it goes back to
struggles and who are the pioneers with
this product and getting legalization
and are they sitting at the table and I
think it's making sure that it's open
for anybody that wants to get a license
or be in a business or be employed by a
business in cannabis that it is a very
positive experience I don't you don't
want anybody left behind you're right
we're not we're not arresting people
like we used to but it that I don't
think that's enough we need to as a
state we need to bring be more inclusive
and bring those that were really the
ones that were most affected by the war
on drugs into the system and I think
we're still navigating that I do think
you're seeing a commitment on the
administration because not only do we
have the ten million now we have the 15
million and you know I I think that
conversation and and it has as people
are talking and so and I know money
doesn't solve everything but it sure
does help because one of the things we
even putting out our equity application
in the month of March we were seeing
jurisdictions passing equity ordinances
at like a like a real tremendous rate is
like wow they made this happen pretty
quick yeah and so that was a good thing
and I think that that was what sort of
triggered we're gonna need more money
there's a lot of jurisdictions out there
that are putting social equity making it
a priority so I'm happy that we're part
of this I think we're still trying to
figure out what is a successful equity
program but I think you're gonna see
some frontrunners
up from some of these cities that have
been doing it for for a while and I
think you're gonna see and I'm hoping by
you know we'll get that money out
because I think the important thing it's
one thing to waive money around but you
got to get in the hands right you gotta
get in your hands because you guys can't
wait and and we get that so well
actually it was interesting Risa and Kat
and Joe and Nicole yesterday they
mentioned something about they had to go
through all these hoops and setting up
their social equity programs at the
entire structure and they were thinking
about trying not so much open source but
create documentation and process and
help other counties and cities staged up
these programs and when it comes to
social equity a more homogeneous system
throughout the state which you know
allows it makes it more frictionless you
know one thing that we've been seeing
that's alarming though is how do you
prevent equity programs from being taken
advantage of by predatory actors who are
not intended beneficiaries of these
licenses I think any time the state is
giving money to the city and county it's
our responsibility to make sure that
money is being used appropriately and
that we are monitoring things like that
I don't know that we're always going to
be able to catch that but I think for
the most part I think we will have a
good system in place that we can at
least audit and make sure you know it's
going to who it should be going to and I
think we rely you know like anything
like complaints or anything I think we
rely a lot on the industry to bring
information forward to us all right
that's great thank you for your sharing
that taxes it should be no surprise that
taxes are a major point and contention
for licensees up and down the supply
chain when there have been opportunities
for reprieve from these taxes the
attempts at reform seem to consistently
fail in a recent example bonta's bill a
B 286 would have put a pause in the
cultivation tax and given a one-year
reprieve to farmers to show that
decrease in taxes will lead to an
increase overall in your opinion you
know what's this
axes why aren't we moving forward on
lowering it or you know why are we what
were you thinking and are we on taxes
I know it's under your butt just well I
think it's like you know I mean taxes is
not a you know that's not a popular term
really when you think taxes you think
negatively right and I I think when you
have different tax structures from the
state and then your local local
jurisdiction has a different tax rate I
think it just makes it very difficult I
think one thing I've been learning is
like I think everybody just thinks
you're making all this money and so you
can pay all this taxes but I think again
it's a balanced approach because it's
not just the taxes you're hit you're all
getting licensing fees now I mean you're
having to pay licensing fees and all
that so so our feeling is is I want
whatever it's going to be more
successful for the industry and I think
it's very difficult for you to plan when
there's different when you have state
taxes you have different local taxes I
think it would be nice if we had a more
I think thoughtful approach when it came
when it comes to taxes but and then it's
hard to pay for your taxes and I always
say if it's gonna be hard to pay for
your taxes who's gonna do them right
yeah I mean and it's in cash and all
that I mean one of the things that we're
really scared of on July 1 is or at
least I'm scared of you guys can be
scared of whatever you're scared of is
the possibility of Sidi TFA raising the
excise tax and you know in my mind if it
goes from a 60 percent markup to 100
percent markup or 80 percent whatever it
is you're gonna see an effective tax
rate go from 24 percent to 30 percent at
the distribution level to the retail
level and then to the consumer you're
gonna see 8 to 12 percent because you're
gonna see the the excise is - built in
the cogs that local tax is going to tax
it the state tax is going to tax it so
you're looking at yeah another 10% of
increase in prices to the consumer and
you know if that happens it's being done
on data that isn't in the state track
and trace
so there's no way to really verify or
anything like that but you know I'm
curious to hear your thoughts you know
have you heard rumblings of seed ETF a
potentially doing that you know Nick was
in the CCI a summit he says we have the
authority to do it we're looking at it
he didn't say it was going to be done
this but this is months ago and I'm just
trying to prepare myself on July 1 so I
and I by the way we talked to CDT cafe a
lot and I I do think they get it do they
think the markups higher perhaps but I
think they understand that it's gonna
just create volatility oh it's super
fragile right now but I think again
having that mark a wholesale price
markup that can change every six months
it does doesn't create like comfort
level right because you think you're
good for six months and then the next
six months it could be something else
and it was a big reason why we changed
our licensing fees we were basing our
licensing fees on that wholesale markup
and so I think that's the difficult part
for the industry is just that every six
months you're always like wondering
what's going to happen and you know if
and I think as state agencies you know
it's not good when we're creating this
anxiety right I'm gonna tell you like I
know all of you worry cuz I worry - but
there's nothing worse when you guys
don't know what's coming and have that
anxiety and I think that again creates
folks maybe not getting into a license
maybe because they're not sure and
things of that nature and and really I
think we need to give you guys more a
better comfort level of what's coming
down the road I mean especially as their
operators are not marketing up 100%
they're at 60% or 30%
I've seen some at 30 I don't know why
but there are 30 and without track and
trace I mean they're looking at what you
know they're looking at some of the
invoices and our Manifest but it's not
giving them the information they need to
make that informed decision so but I
think they understand that though but I
think it's for us we don't we don't know
what they're gonna do either though okay
that I'm trying to cause anxiety don't
yes it's all gonna be okay nothing is
wrong everything is great nothing is
wrong everything is great it was just
this mantra we had at the Leadership
Summit that's like you are perfect
nothing is wrong
okay I mean do you anticipate and you
were pre from taxes on the horizon
no all right no more taxes all right
moving on I'll give you a good one all
right to your point on the illicit
market has been a pain point for
licensees we know this is not lost in
the BCC and your office has taken
measures to battle this can you tell us
more about the public awareness campaign
you are undertaking to point consumer
behavior toward licensed businesses do
you think it will be sufficient when
consumer behavior tends to be driven by
do you think this will be sufficient
though when consumer behavior tends to
be driven by price and convenience so do
I think is completely sufficient I think
it's one part of what we need to do so I
don't think it's going to solve I don't
think the public awareness campaign is
going to solve the illicit market at all
but I always look at it we got to come
at it at all angles so you got to have
aggressive enforcement you've got to
keep licensing people we've got to work
with the jurisdictions to make sure I
mean it's it it's getting weak we can't
issue licenses and a majority of the
cities and county so we got to keep on
that and then we wanted to have a public
awareness campaign too because sometimes
I think we forget a lot of us you know
cannabis is 24/7 but for the average
consumer they're just looking like you
said for the price point and we're where
I can get cannabis they're not living
this they don't understand so they're
gonna get it where they can get it
cheaper but if we can sort of change
some of these California consumers mind
that we want you to shop licensed shops
we want you to get safe cannabis is it
gonna change everybody's mind no but I
know this is California is you know big
on organics and you know you know craft
products and so I think you can sway
some people to go over there way to say
hey do they have a license or not
and ask that question so that's one part
of the campaign and again it's it's
something is it going to change
everything no the other part is to
really inform the illegal market that
we're you know we know where you are so
yeah like with me yeah you like that
yeah all right you know it's time to get
licensed and this is how you get
licensed and so is it gonna change
everybody no but I you know I'm a big
believer you just hit everybody on all
fronts this unlicensed market and you're
hoping that you get more people into the
regulated market and so that's Alex
where's Alex traverses over there he's
actually leading up that so you know he
is very good about taking feedback
they're going you know they've been
going to the associations and running by
some of our ads you know it's always
good for us to get feedback because you
know the state trying to do ads
sometimes they you know you probably are
going this is not gonna work right so
see CIA's been very good California
minority alliance so you guys have a
better idea of what's gonna work so so
it's it's been a great learning
experience and so I I really encourage
you guys if you have any good ideas
please let us know because again what
works up here in Mendocino County
probably doesn't work in LA so it's it's
it's been a pretty big undertaking I
think a lot more work than I expected
but I think it's a good thing yeah
that's great I think any message to help
educate the consumers I always say
nothing is easy in cannabis is that what
you guys feel something it's like
whatever it's but it's all worth the
effort by the way and I truly believe
that it's not easy but it's worth the
effort I agree that we're crushing right
now I think we have four more questions
so we may have time for like two more
two or three questions what are your
biggest fears for the viability of the
regulated cannabis industry in
California I'm pretty simple I we we've
got to make sure the regulated market is
successful and what I mean by successful
that you're
you're able to hire people you're able
to make money and that is as far as I'm
concerned that is our task here is to
make you successful and we need to do
whatever it takes to make sure that
happens because there is no I don't
think anybody here well maybe you do
wants to go backwards I don't want to go
backwards but read for it but it it does
it's it's not just the bureau by the way
it's the entire state it's all the state
government it's the industry it's the
consumer it's really making sure you
know i i'd like to see cannabis really
nor i think it's already you know when i
looked at three years ago and now I mean
cannabis is becoming normalized although
in you know invent and you guys are
innovative and all your products and
it's just incredible and you guys know I
come from alcohol and it's like such a
departure you know you have beer wine
distilled spirits and cannabis it's just
like what it's it's it is truly amazing
what the entrepreneurs out here have
been doing with cannabis and so you guys
I mean I just think you're gonna be I
mean this is where it is I think this is
where it is I agree though we'll this is
kind of interesting you know another
thing that's coming is hemp now there's
a bill that's moving through that would
possibly bring in hemp agriculture in
California and also within our license
market how do you view hemp and how do
you think about regulating it and we're
yeah are you thinking about it I think
about it a lot you guys think about it a
lot because we get a lot of questions on
him so um I I don't have any I think
hemp is and again I think it's a great
product that if we read it but right now
the the bureau or food nag or public
health it doesn't fall under our
Authority it doesn't fall under a
cannabis or a cannabis product and the
definition under ma you see our say-so
I truly feel though if we're going to
bring hemp into
you know I know you can get I mean as
you guys know our regulations don't
allow distributors or retailers to
transport or sell hemp but and and you
probably think why if you say you're ok
with hemp and I'll tell you why I think
hemp does need to be part of the
regulator market I think it should be
regulated for so it falls under cannabis
so that way you're benefiting from
selling hemp because you're already
going through such strict standards with
cannabis it makes sense that it comes
through you guys the proper supply chain
so our retailers and can sell it so
we'll see what happens it looks like
there's movement
yeah there's momentum and so I think
that's a good thing for the industry
because I really think that's going to
help boost sales I think you know
consumer is demanding more of these
products and I think it should fall
under us I think that is good for the
licensees yeah because if anybody can
sell it and get it from anywhere in the
country and it can have and we don't
even know what's in it I don't think
that's good I agree right that's that's
what we like to hear how do we reduce
plastic waste I think less packaging
standards or restrictions yeah I mean
that's that's the answer is it easy to
get there maybe I think I think you know
we had a lot of childproof packaging and
I think though that will change as
people understand the product better and
what we do really need to protect and
childproof packaging but I we've heard
you guys that's a huge issue for and I
mean I think rightfully so you should be
bringing it up and continue to bring it
up is there a possibility of
establishing B corpse for cannabis what
would it take what would it look like
what do you mean by B corpse you know
nonprofit for good
oh yeah we're doing them we're doing a
feasibility study right now for
non-prime
if it's if it's in the statute that PCC
has to have our feasibility study
finished and our report on whether it
makes sense to have nonprofits and that
is due on January 1st of 2020 so we're
right in the process right now we're
working with University of
california-davis
feasibility study so if there's
something anybody has you know questions
about or you want to provide us some
information we'll be happy to have you
change especially if you know when the
compassion bill passes having those
outlets having that ability of being a
non-profit would be helpful to a lot of
people and I think part of it if you're
wondering what's the feasibility study
is its I mean do we I mean I think we're
looking at do nonprofits should we just
have nonprofits that are able to
continue to give you know care whether
it's our elderly or veterans or you know
low income and should we continue
without being part of the regulated
system but we have maybe some you know
you know restrictions in place so it's
you know going to those populations or
do we want it part of the regulated
system and so I think that's part of
that feasibility study to see what's the
what's that best model yeah that's great
yeah I'm sure we can provide feedback on
that that's the last question I have
we've been doing fantastic look at that
there are there's still friction between
you know what the state wants and what
the locals want right and if we look at
an example like a B 1356 that was being
moved through the committee it was Tings
bill essentially said it was trying to
open up retail licenses right I'm not
sure if you were following but for those
that weren't to summarize it's basically
you have one license mandated for every
15,000 people in every jurisdiction that
voted in favor over 50% for prop 64 or
one license for every six alcohol
licenses I think that was the last
iteration that I saw something around
there it didn't move through committee
but it was a bold move in trying to push
retail licenses and licenses in general
in these counties you know as its as
we've seen it's been pretty slow for
people to get regulated it's been slow
for people to make decisions and get
keep offices stood up resources are thin
to create another department to do that
you know so our thoughts around like how
do we work on state and local where's
that relationship you know you can only
do so much
local is where the rubber meets the road
and you know a lot of us are stuck and
working in in areas that may not allow
it or prohibit it or we have to travel
through areas that may not allow it or
prohibit it so there's a lot of friction
there but I think there's a way to make
it better if you know and open to your
thoughts and how we get there well I
think it's like anything you're you're
trying to open up hearts and minds to
cannabis regulation right and that's
sometimes is not an easy sell so for us
at the bureau it's making sure our folks
we're competing out to the jurisdictions
providing them resources where they need
them I think for a lot of cities and
counties it is a resource issues they
don't know where to turn to for answers
they don't know where to get started
Andre who's my governmental affairs
don't know where he is he's somewhere
Andres back in the back there is right
over there that's what he does 24/7 is
going around to all these jurisdictions
how can we help what can we look what
can we provide you what do you need from
us
we also are establishing our local
liaison unit so we have 10 analysts
we'll be hiring just to reach out to the
local jurisdictions to help them or when
they come you know a lot of times you
know you're going to them they don't
know how to answer questions and so I
think it's education education and
having resources and at least at the
bureau we think it's important that just
like you that we're responsive to them
and that we provide resources and if
that means we need to go do regional
trainings we can you train their staff
we need to help train their applicants
that's what we're doing the Provisionals
with the temporaries that's sort of
we're I'm hoping by the you know by the
fall we're fully staffed in our local
liaison you know unfortunately we've had
to we do have people in that unit but
they've all been there everybody's
working on making sure there's no gap in
licensures from the temporaries to the
provisional that is like that is number
one from that is our number one priority
and you want us to have that as our
number one priority right now
so thanks not for like waiting till last
minute when your temp expires and you
get your provisional you're like you're
sorry yeah we're trying and and just so
you know I know we mentioned CDFA and
and I I understand it's been tough on
them I think we did give ourselves a
little bit more room because we pushed
out temporary expirations and that
really helped us you know get prepared
but we have been sending our own staff
over to see DFA to a system we did in
March we sent six staff we have staff
there for staff right there so I don't
want you to think just when we see
another agency hurting we're also we
understand if if they're not successful
we're not successful so we do look at
those things and provide resources there
to wherever we can't help ya that's
appreciated and Andre if it's helpful
for like people the industry to go on
with you to these local governments and
talk and you know just show who these
stakeholders are
that were normal people that were
parents or family we're brothers or
husbands or like wives we can we can do
that maybe we just create this SWAT team
coalition and we just met SWAT team go
through systematically I mean locals
have you know local regulators have a
lot of they should be you know we need
get in front of them alright alright so
we have a few questions here and how
much time we have five minutes okay cool
we have some questions hey all right
when I get the mic over high five a lot
of questions are you doing today
so you were speaking earlier
enforcement and we know that the state
committed a lot of resources towards
enforcement and while I agree
enforcement need there's a need for
enforcement there's like ten times the
need to make sure that everybody's
licensed in everybody who wants that
opportunity gets that opportunity
license so in thinking about that
hundred million dollars that was that
was put towards the bureau of
enforcement how it relates to equity so
I deal a lot with the equity community
you talked about the money
ten million dollars in and now having to
rethink that adding 15 million I think
that you're asking the community that
can lease afford to wait for those
resources to wait for resources and and
I think some of those millions that
Wintour's of forcement could have been
provided for the equity community and
they can't wait any more they need those
funds now because they don't have access
to real estate loans family members that
have money they're struggling right now
in these equity programs are struggling
with with funding to be able to process
those licenses we need that money now
and anything that you could do to make
that happen
like urgency is necessary please III
agree so we I it's one thing they have
to say you have all these millions of
dollars it's another thing you got to
get it out to the folks that really need
it and they need it now and so we are
I'm going to tell you we're making but
we also want to make sure it's getting
to the right people and I am gonna say
I'm happy that we're getting another 15
million and I'm happy to see some of
these local jurisdictions start to come
on board because that's going to help
more people
my name is recent posh green and I know
you were talking about enforcement but
we all know the biggest problem that we
are having as people that own
dispensaries people down deliveries as
weed maps we all know we maps is a big
problem I don't understand what is
taking so long to get that under control
when other people have started on third
third party platform ordering systems to
take you off if you don't have a license
so why isn't we Mouse able that's why
we're seeing the prices at 30% low
because we cannot complete with the
black market I get calls daily from
other people there in their business
vendors and they're hurting and they
don't call they're like oh how you're
doing I'm like actually check my
delivery down to my store opens because
I can't afford it and I can't afford the
store especially being an equity
application so what people are saying is
that we're we're about to we're not
gonna make and I mean people that's been
around for for a long time way before me
or it's having trouble because the black
market I don't mean just flowers I mean
teachers I mean babes they're getting
real crafty out there and it's killing
us and before you know it you guys are
not gonna have people around to get
money and to pioneer this industry
because of what's going on reading math
needs to be shut down
interesting hi Laurie hi hooah
my name is Jackie McGowan K Street
consulting thank you so much for this
event it's been amazing
my question is about BCC enforcement on
licensed operators and I'm going to use
a specific incident in Santa Cruz where
BCC enforcement agents showed up on an
unexpected unannounced flashing badges
forcing their way in pulling products
off shelves interrogating employees and
basically conducting a raid without
kicking the door in so first I want to
ask is there anyone in the audience that
knows what a BCC badge looks like raise
your hand one one person no okay so I
want to know if there's going to be a
hotline that we can call to verify that
in that an inspection is occurring
because then this incident these
employees didn't know if they were being
robbed and there could be copycat
incidents like that but I think there
has to be education or at least in an
announcement as to when enforcement is
or an inspection is going to occur so
Jackie I don't know what specific
premises you're talking about but yeah
normally our enforcement staff is very
professional we do not announce before
we go in you're right but they do have
ID saying they're from the Bureau and
they have business cards but if there's
something more that can give comfort to
our licensees that they know who's there
I think we're open to I don't know if
that's a hotline I'm not that may be
that that is I'll say this hotlines
something to verify then we're open to
something like that okay thank you for
that thank you thank you for providing
such a great format for collaboration
within our industry as a statewide
distributor I would like a transparent
way to make an employee purchase and
give samples to my staff to responsibly
use yeah I mean there's a bill moving
forward
Skinner's bill which would would
definitely help that and it's looking
really good I agree it looks really
promising so you may have your wish yeah
I think you're gonna have your wish
can't take credit for it these guys can
take yeah I mean it's definitely a
collaboration but yep non cannabis
company and Trinity County of a very
specific question for you is bulk flour
not in its final packaged form but with
a CoA allowed to be transferred from
distribution facility to distribution
facility the language in the BCC
regulation 503 seven there's one
sentence for this language and it needs
to be clarified can you tell me yes or
no if it can be transferred on the spot
right now that's why you're here
uncomfortable questions and a
comfortable environment
[Laughter]
that's not that uncomfortable the
question I just want to make sure I give
you the right answer so I think think
that needs to be on our new FAQ system
because we get that question all the
time so I will get your information and
we're gonna put that on the FAQ and
we're gonna email directly with the
answer and make sure it's the right
answer how about that yeah that sounds
great yeah FAQ well we can do it yeah hi
my name's Chris I'm a manufacturer in
San Francisco and I think as you can
tell there's just a lot of fear we don't
know we don't know if a dispensary is
gonna ask us to take something off of
the shelf because of the way they're
interpreting one of your rules we don't
know if we're doing the right thing
according to the other agency one thing
I'd like to suggest what what CD pH is
done with us is they say hey we want to
come learn we want to walk through your
facility and see how you're doing it
because we're both kind of learning
together and then we can help you
understand what enforcement will look
like as we figure it out
so the BCC I'm wondering if you guys
maybe just like don't need to be
enforcing people who are trying to jump
through all these hoops right now and
instead you can just come and ask how
we're doing it and learn from us because
they're we're trying to do our best we
just jump through the hoops I don't
really understand why you're enforcing
dispensaries who are licensed right now
instead of saying let's walk through and
see how you're doing it let's take some
notes let's come back and say hey we
actually don't like this way let's do it
differently but people shouldn't be
scared that if the time stamps off on
their receipt they're gonna get a fine
when they're trying to make payroll you
know and some of these aren't my stories
but I'm in the middle of the supply
chain and I have the fear of both from
so for the most part when we say
enforcing most of when we're going out
into the market probably the biggest
thing that we are enforcing is when we
come across product that hasn't come
through the legal supply chain so that's
probably the biggest thing we're
enforcing other than that we are trying
to still educate our retailers I don't
know
Oh about a timestamp that sounds pretty
well that sounds sort of I give you a
ticket yeah let me give you one just
specific example because I think this
would help in the conversation around
July 1st some people from BCC came to
one of our dispensaries SPARC and they
pointed out our packaging as
non-compliant but actually it was
compliant until July 1st and they add a
spark got nervous since they pulled the
product during our last two weeks to
sell the product that would be
non-compliant July 1st because they
flagged it and SPARC said just in case
we can't sell this and we said we have
two more weeks as our last two weeks to
sell it and so just a summary is two
constructive if you guys just came and
said hey we're learning right now we're
just gathering information and like
we're not concerned about the outcome of
what we're seeing right now because we
want to work with you to figure out
what's gonna work for both of us I think
that would go a really long way that
would have been a better approach a
really long way you're right yeah I mean
July 1 was crazy right I mean if we
think about what was happening around
that time we just feel like we are it's
like we are your partners and that we
are learning together because neither of
us know how to do it we have to build it
together but we need your help to not be
scared of you I don't want you to be
scared of us and I think you're
absolutely right
July 1st last year was was was it was
very crazy I think we were all stressful
and that would have been a better
approach I agree with you but I think I
don't want to just hear about these
things when I come to the Meadowlands I
want you to reach out to the bureau and
if it means you say forward this to
Laurie Ajax I want her to know I'm
saying I don't want you to be scared of
us but I I want to hear it before it's a
huge problem and and it's great I'm glad
you told me now but feel free to reach
out to us - oh I thinks I think that's
the best theme of this whole weekend has
just been let's talk more yes I love it
I love it yay that's good theme that's
just just because Reese Reese asked
about weed maps but we didn't really get
over on whether or not anything was
gonna be done about that any times
they're recessed question
are you blaming it on her wait is it I
agree that weed maps as a problem and we
should have Internet platforms that are
advertising for the license market not
the unlicensed market and so we are
committed as a state and to make sure
that those that aren't getting into
compliance we get them into compliance
and that would include wheat maps yeah I
mean if you're also like targeting
people there's a list of people you can
go after if you want to just I don't
know that that's why we need weed maps
though but you're right you are right
public anyway that was the end of the
questions that would all the questions
we have thank you Laurie for your time
here thank you please show our
appreciation and thank gratitude for you
making such a long trip to get here it's
you know really appreciated