[Music]
Lynn is going to talk to us about two
things today Federal so you're going to
learn about the feds and also she's
going to give you a short summary on
what's going on in the state so thank
you so much one of the greatest
challenges right now is lack of
information and misinformation about
what's going on so this is a great way
to educate the broader Community that's
directly interested um in this issue so
um on November 8th we legalized cannabis
in
California it was a long haul and I know
a lot of people had different opinions
about it and and that's okay and there
was a lot lot of people involved in in
the Drafting and I think um it was it
was really the best piece of legislation
um that we could have possibly come out
of there with given the broad array of
stakeholders who had a say in this
everybody from the governor to the
police to the industry to patients to um
anti-marijuana groups and on and on and
on and so um but really the biggest task
ask is implementing this law um a lot of
people say hey we won we're done and you
know you have crazy things going on like
the prop 64 compliant Cannabis stores
that does not exist and there is no such
thing you have lots of um people taking
advantage of new folks like you trying
to get into the industry um saying you
know give me $20,000 I'll get you a
license there are no licenses well just
a few cities in the state have licenses
but for for the most part there are no
licenses anybody who wants to say um you
know $20,000 I give you a license don't
believe them so there's there's a lot
going on what I'm going to do tonight is
um really just talk about two huge
issues um the first is probably the most
important uh because with what's going
on in Washington DC we may not be able
to actually have a legal cannabis Market
here in California despite what happened
uh on November 8th so you may know that
um the Attorney General of the United
States Jeff sessions is um thinks
marijuana is the worst thing he's ever
yeah boo how many people know about Jeff
sessions just raise your hand if you
have a good sense okay most most of the
people so I'm just going to give you one
of his quotes to give you an idea of of
who he is he said he thought the klex
clan was a pretty good group until he
found out they used marijuana
so he continues to threaten yeah so this
is who we're dealing with right um he
continues to threaten to come in and
shut down uh marijuana markets in the
states that have recreational marijuana
he he has said for the most part he's
not going to interfere with medical um
unless there's a gross violation going
on but he is threatening pending the
resources he can Garner to come in and
shut down Colorado Washington California
um so what we've done at the drug policy
Alliance and I I don't I don't know if I
mentioned that you said who I was okay
okay so I'm Lyn Lyman sorry I'm the I'm
the state director for the drug policy
Alliance um so and and we work on more
than just marijuana let me say that we
are trying to end the drug war outright
that's what we're trying to
[Applause]
do so um so we have a bill this year in
the legislature it's assembly Bill 1578
and um we have information about it in
the back my colleague cat Packer back
there by the table razor hand cat a lot
of you may already know
her so there's information about the
bill there but essentially what the bill
does is it says that California law
enforcement and tax dollars cannot be
used to help the feds interfere with our
marijuana
Market AB absent a court order so um
that that doesn't stop intervention
completely because the feds can still
come in on their own but there's only
4,000 DEA agents for the whole country
so there's only so many people they're
going to be able to send in without the
help of our local cops um as you might
imagine the police Lobby is pushing back
really hard against this bill as is the
league of cities the league of cities is
one of the strongest lobbying arms in
Sacramento they represent the 480 cities
um but they are lobbying along with the
police Chiefs to stop this bill because
they want to be able to cooperate with
the feds and shut you down that is
exactly what they want to do they want
to bring in um The Wrath of the federal
government to get this done so um so
that's assembly Bill 1578 the author is
assemblyman Reggie Jones Sawyer right
here at a South La if you don't know who
he is you should write it down and
Google him there's only a handful of
cannabis friendly truly cannabis
friendly legislators in Sacramento and
so you should know who they are you
should contribute to their political
campaigns they really stick their necks
out there um for our
issues so um so uh I I would ask you all
if you work for an organization or a
business we we are asking for letters of
support um and we can if you go see cat
in the back or see me afterwards we can
tell you how to do that but also please
sign up with the drug policy Alliance
list because we'll be sending out alerts
about what's going on the next vote we
we did make it through our First Comm
committee which was the Public Safety
Committee we did we did win that vote
last Tuesday um but the next vote's
going to be on the assembly floor and we
expect expect it to be a pretty big
battle um if any of you have
relationships with your um local mayor
City Council Members we're trying to get
um cannabis friendly cities to come out
and say that um that that they uh
support this bill West Hollywood I
believe will be the first city to do
that that vote's coming up next week um
here in West Hollywood
so that's that's the assembly bill
that's the that's the federal piece
other things going on um from the
federal level uh really at this point is
just trying to stop the madness um the
the bills that we've been moving for
many years in the federal government are
still there you know and they're
bipartisan bills they get more
Republican votes each year and these are
bills that address the the banking
problem um dress PTSD for veterans so um
in terms of an actual marijuana
legalization bill at the federal level
nobody's bothering with that at this
point right now we're just trying to fix
some of some of the issues we've been
trying to fixed for
years um so I'm going to move on to the
state because I think that's where um
there's so much going on and
um way more than I can talk to you about
tonight uh but but how many people have
heard of the governor's trer Bill
language raise your hand okay okay so um
prop 64 uh like Mera or now M
mura um are both uh intended to be uh to
go into implementation on January 1st so
licensing is supposed to begin on
January 1 under prop 64 because it's a
voter mandated initiative um they have
to or or they will be in violation and
we would be able to sue them um so they
have to start recreational by the 1 they
are they already started on medical so I
I do believe that both um both licensing
types will go into effect then but there
is a bloody battle going on between now
really just the rest of the next month
about what those regs are going to look
like and what the framework is going to
be so there were differences between
prop 64 and and the medical regulations
um and so you'll hear this term
reconciliation that's what everybody's
talking about how how is the government
going to reconcile the differences
between the two bills and there's a
number of issues at stake uh again if if
you are in this trying to get into this
business in a serious way you really
want to know about the trailer Bill
language it's trailer Bill 200 um and so
what I know that there's some people in
here who who have specific questions it
touches on everything it eliminates the
so the governor put out his language
again that's what reconciliation is
there's the medical regs there's prop 64
and then a couple of weeks ago the
governor put out his hybrid um
essentially of how he wants things to go
forward and the process is that for the
next month he has to negotiate with the
legislature uh about what's going to be
in there there are many people in the
legislature who aren't happy with what
he did there are some people who are
there are some Advocates who are happier
with him there are others who aren't
there's people all across the Spectrum
on the issues and so uh the final
language will be part of the California
state budget that's how it works and the
budget has to pass by June 1st so
there's not a lot of time to weigh in on
everything from Dual licensing
collocation um medical cards testing and
labeling I mean he's that everything is
almost like everything is up for grabs
again and now we have a month to figure
it all out um so I'm just going to pause
and see if anybody has a specific
question about reconciliation or or the
trailer Bill language because there are
dozens of issues and I don't have time
to go through them all does anybody have
a question you said something about
cocation
coing can you explain that collocation
cocation so um what the governor is
proposing um on one hand is a unitary
regulatory system between recreational
and medical with two different license
types and a medical license and a
recreational license that part we think
is a really good idea and the reason is
that that when the feds come they're
coming for recreational so anybody who
really wants to hold on and and hold
their place in the medical Market it
makes sense so you don't lose everything
that if you are going to lose something
you just lose the one side of your
business what the governor also did that
some people have more of a concern with
um is he said that you can't be in the
same space so you can have both a
medical and a recreational say um retail
license or manufacturers license you
can't be in the same physical space
so um it's it's not the kind of issue
that that me as as a as a social justice
Advocate we're going to weigh in on but
they're important issues for those of
you in the industry um and there's a
number of groups who represent the
industry in Sacramento the California
Cannabis industry Association the
California manufacturers Association Etc
there's a number of them and so if one
of these issues pertains to your the the
part of the business you're in um you
going to want to get involved with those
folks so but that is the issue at stake
that he's saying you can't be in the
same physical
space hi I'm Aaron with kisur Brands um
can you just go a little deeper on that
uh medical and recreational side in
terms of uh you know where what they're
allowing you if you go recreational that
will affect um the the licensing itself
sure so um in
2015 the legislature passed um so in
2015 I see you're getting your camera so
I'm going to say it again for you so
he's like videotape so in 2015 the
legislature passed and the governor
signed was then MCA the medical
marijuana regulatory act or something
like that um and it was the first time
in California's 20-year history of legal
cannabis that we have had state
regulations but those regulations are
not set to take place and to go into
effect until January 1st of
2018 so when we wrote prop 64 we aligned
the timing
so they have to give out the
recreational licenses in January 1st as
well um if if there's been a lot of talk
about um they're not going to be ready
it's not going to happen particularly
from the the assembly members who want
to delay licensing um we are saying if
you delay recreational licensing you
have violated prop 64 we will take you
to court um we can't say that about
medical because but we can say that
about
recreational um on the other hand the
safest license to have right now because
of the federal government is going to be
the medical license uh because Jeff
sessions has made it clear that he's not
as interested in shutting down medical
marijuana he's interested in keeping
recreational marijuana um to keeping
prohibition going on so so there's two
license types that answer the question
it does and my followup is uh if you go
medical and don't opt for the recreation
right now
um will that impact future to get
recreational or would you still want to
be on a list to be able to get that yeah
I I think that anybody who's a good
actor so you know you try to set up your
business you know you try to follow the
rules hire an attorney you know take the
time to get all the right permits make
sure you're a th000 feet from the school
Etc so if you're doing that as a medical
business right now you are going to be
in believe it or not a very small
percentage of what we call the good
actors and those are the ones that the
cities want to get the recreational
licenses to so it's about building a
relationship with your city with your
community you know do you give back do
you have some kind of you know Community
give back program community service so
so those are the medical actors who are
going to be first in line for those
recreational licenses so it I don't
think it takes you out of the running to
wait I think there might be an argument
for spending more time really working on
your cannabis bus your medical business
building your reputation and then in a
few years when things settle down um you
know going for the recreational
license when you said they needed two
different spaces how apart two different
addresses right next to each other what
yeah that wasn't addressed and that was
exact our question so if you're just
door to door is it okay do you have to
be a foot he he didn't say so it's also
not the best written piece because it's
very vague it says no collocation
essentially the same premises is what it
says it cannot be on the same
premises yeah so those are the kinds of
details that are now being negotiated in
Sacramento there's another question a
quick question about Transportation
right now when we try to move it to our
store we can't move it legally and I'm
just wondering if they're going to give
transportation licenses or how we can
legally move our
stuff yeah no absolutely the
Transportation license is key so right
now um under an ounce so obviously not
for business purposes but under an ounce
is now legal for transporting 100% no
violation of the law if you have under
of an ounce in your vehicle um more than
that um you are definitely um in the hot
water right now but in January 1st I
believe the transportation licenses
there's not a lot of controversy about
that particular license type I think
everybody knows we need it and I just I
think it's going to happen I haven't
heard anything about not doing that can
you have more than one license yes yes
absolutely um and however so so yes
under prop 64 and yes under Mera
um the how many license types and how
you can have is one of the topics of
negotiation under under reconciliation
right now so the and it's sometimes it's
called vertical integration so can you
have you know the different license
types we allowed that under Pro 64
except for testing testing always has to
be a separate license if you have a
testing license you can't have any other
license type um under Mera there was
more uh restrictions around which
license types you could have depending
on the one you already had so the
governor's reconciliation essentially
says we're just going to go with the way
it is in prop 64 and let everybody have
um you know ver basically allow vertical
integration except for testing um the
other thing that the governor did though
that doesn't concern me again we wrote
that into prop 64 but what concerned me
is that he stripped um he stripped it of
the anti-monopoly language we had put in
so we are concerned about about
monopolies and about big businesses kind
of taking this over and we had done two
things to prevent that we delayed the
large cultivation licenses for five
years we said nobody gets you know the
type five licenses which was 22,000
square feet or larger fiveyear delay on
that and then we said you have to get
your license renewed every year and one
of the issues that The Regulators have
to review specifically is whether you're
trying to build a monopoly whether you
this license um would could possibly
lead towards a monopoly and they get to
make that decision every year the
governor took of those pieces out in the
current reconciliation language so it
feels more open to to Monopoly and and
so you know we we will probably have to
weigh in on that but and if you're a
small business and that's something you
want to weigh in on um again some of
these industry associations are are
certainly doing that let me talk about
one last issue that might not be as
important to you but is so important uh
to us at the drug policy Alliance and I
think uh for people who've been in the
Cannabis industry for a long time I I
think um this is an important piece so
under prop 64 we denied discrimination U
I'm sorry we prohibited discrimination
against people with a prior drug
conviction on their record so right now
most most of the people who've been in
this 20y year under regulated quasi
regulated market in the medical cannabis
industry been risking their lives and
many of them you know have done serious
time in jail and in prison and um and
even Beyond cannabis we know that when
you look at who uses and sells drugs in
this country it's roughly equal across
racial lines when it comes to marijuana
white people sell and use at higher rate
but for all drug it's roughly equal and
yet if you are black or Latino you are
far more likely to be arrested and
convicted for a drug crime if you're are
black you're four times more likely to
get a marijuana felony if you're Latino
you're two times more likely to get a
marijuana felony so we have been
building in this this discrimination you
know and then it becomes institutional
racism and then once you have a record
you can't you can't even get a
certificate to be a hair stylist in this
state if you have a criminal convic
fiction on your record so it just it it
seems so crazy for the first time
legalize something that has been a
controlled substance and say and yet all
you people who have been doing this you
can't get into this Market because you
have these records and the people with
those records tend to be predominantly
black and brown young men so we fought
hard to have this provision in prop 64
to to basically say they cannot deny a
license based on somebody's record and
they're trying to Undo It particularly
in the assembly the police Chiefs the
law enforcement Lobby this is this is
the one that really sticks in their craw
um they got it into medical into the
medical regulations that you
discriminate against somebody based on
their record um it's one of the reasons
in the end we had to oppose that
legislation even though we worked on it
for a decade um but because we could go
to the voters with the initiative we did
the right thing and we said there will
be no discrimination and Licensing under
prop 64
so the other thing I'm going to ask of
you if since you're on this list or ask
Jackie to ask of you is to sign on to a
petition about this to the State
Assembly that we'll be Distributing
probably in the next week so please when
you get that email from Jackie or from
US Open it take the time to sign on
because we have to let them know that
the whole industry is not okay with that
kind of discrimination and not just let
it be me and the NAACP standing up there
by ourselves opposing it and that's what
happened two years ago so please don't
let us go to sacri loone on that issue
thank
you next up so we just talked about
Federal we talked about the state now
we're going to talk about the county so
LA County what is going on in Los
Angeles County and why are they doing
the things that they want or saying
trying to do the things that they want
to do
we are going to find out about that from
Jonathan fetco right over here from
Angelus emeralds is that right he has
been working his butt off in the county
okay everyone else has been focused on
state and city this man right here is
taking charge in the county so he's
going to really fill us in you're going
to be shocked if know some of this stuff
so thank you let's bring up Jonathan so
in the next few minutes let me try my
best to Crunch down what we've been
doing in a little over a year about year
and a half now within LA County
uh my journey on this started uh back
around February March of last year when
we had the band craze that went up and
down the state the states at the time
Mera regulations pretty much said that
if the local jurisdictions did not uh
regulate that they had the option to
either adopt what the state did or just
ban all together uh around that time is
when the LA County ended up deciding
that they were going to put in a ban and
they already had to be a little clear
here they had a ban already on
dispensaries within what is called the
unincorporated La uh territories of LA
County so LA county in general is or
they have 88 cities that are
Incorporated within it and they have a
very large portion of that territory
that is unincorporated which is where it
came to affect me the ban uh that
already existed there was for
dispensaries and delivery services or at
least the dispensaries part but the band
that they ended up putting in coming in
last year ended up extending that
expanding it to manufacturing delivery
services and cultivation so while they
never expressly allowed for those um
portions of the Cannabis industry to be
in there within the medical they also
didn't ban it until that moment so when
that ended up happening pardon me when
that ended up happening um we quickly
sought out any organization any group
that we could attach ourselves to to see
how we can help out what we can do our
little part in and along the ways we
certainly met each and every one of the
LA City groups that certainly have been
working together as best as they could
on that towards the fight on there but
none of them did we notice have any um I
don't want to say interest necessarily
but their focus wasn't in on the LA
County unincorporated areas at the time
so we quickly found ourselves pretty
much alone trying to stand up against
this ban uh we ended up taking a uh we
went to a uh conference down in San
Diego where we end up meeting California
Cannabis industry Association and down
there someone in the audience ended up
uh asking uh what are they doing in the
LA area and uh there was no Focus again
at that time from that group itself in
LA and I foolishly raised my hand and
said well I know a little something
about it and turned out and said that
that conference turned around with
everyone else kind of asking me as if I
was someone that was an authority on
that when it wasn't when all I'm doing
is try to get the word out there and see
where I can get help shortly after that
I had one of their uh I had the deputy
director of California Cannabis industry
Association reach out to meet with us
and he was thankfully located in Redondo
Beach where I myself am and from there
we started making plans on how we could
fight back against this span uh reaching
out to anyone and everyone friends that
we could at the time uh you many of you
probably know her Tracy Ryan from canak
kids certainly came out help us out with
that and I will be always grateful for
her on that um and so we stood up there
the first meeting we had and there was a
good six of us six to seven of us I
think total at that time they went to
speak against this and what we were
looking at is the county was looking to
introduce a ban that would have been
extended for up to two years so they had
their first portion that would have been
great we're going to have this in for a
year with an optional second year and
what we ended up uh finding an affecting
change on is they ended up coming back
and saying you know what we're going to
hold back and we're going to just do
this for 45 days and review this from
there so we had our first chance of what
understood to kind of play Within this
game and also what that Victory kind of
meant for us to where rather than just
saying we're going to do the full two
years we're going to start off with the
45 days um since then we obviously ended
up uh organizing better trying to get
our efforts going on there and we were
quickly introduced to drug policy
Alliance and they have been phenomenal
Partners in trying to uh you know change
what's going on in the county the
education piece that Lynn mentioned on
there it's something that I can't stress
enough how much of a moving Target it's
been not just for uh us as operators
because the conly keeps changing but
also for the county and so it's not
something that you can we've learned
quickly you can't expect them to know
everything and anything all the time so
which gives us an opportunity to educate
them as best we can and along the way we
had a discussion last year with one of
the supervisors and they were very
active in trying to understand how they
could raise funds towards their um
efforts with homelessness fighting
homelessness within LA County some of
you may have heard last year but the
county end up introducing at one point a
bill that would have actually taxed
cannabis uh to help towards that
Homeless uh cause they were looking for
and that was due to the efforts that we
came out there we end up speaking to
them and it was interesting that they
had no clue at the time that Aurora
Colorado ended up using its revenues
from taxes on cannabis to go towards
their homeless crisis they had uh that
unfortunately was not as much of a win
as we wanted to and while we disagreed
with them taxing us before regulations
we saw that as a great opportunity to
have a foot in the door to start the
discussion uh a couple weeks after they
passed the idea of let you know having
that bill put on there in November for
that they actually repealed that because
unfortunately uh United Way one of the
largest homeless Advocate groups out
there decided that they did not want
cannabis money to go to them so they
ended up repealing that all together and
that died two weeks afterwards um since
that time to speed up a little bit on
this stuff uh in January January
February or so the supervisors ended up
uh finally putting in their
recommendations as to how they want to
see some regulations go forward uh there
are two aspects of it one one on the
recommendation side that we disagree
with strongly one is if you end up end
up taking a look at the unincorporated
area of LA County the richest resource
they have is the agricultural Zone land
um that land takes up 39% of the zoned
areas within unincorporated La the
supervisors proposed to not allow any
type of cannabis based activity within
the agricultural land and instead they
want to uh allow for cultivation
manufacturing so on and so forth but
only within the Industrial and
Commercial zoned areas
by comparison we look at those two parts
they they together make up just about 1%
of the total zoned areas within LA
County so when the supervisors have
already stated that their goal is to
maximize the transition of this illicit
Market into a regulated market if
they're going to be looking to do that
we don't agree that giving us only 1% of
these zoned areas is going to allow for
that so we disagree with them on that
and of course we have more education
process going forward on there but more
curiously was really disturbing to us is
towards the end of that um first meeting
or that meeting where they introduced
their regulation recommendations uh we
had one supervisor that tacked on a last
minute amendment to where she had
suggested that she wants to clean out
essentially all the illicit operators
within the county itself and when asked
where they would pull the funding from
the CEO's office quickly volunteered
that uh last year they ended up winning
a uh settlement against Wells Fargo
which we all kind of heard how they end
up doing this up with their consumers
last year and that they have $25 million
setting around sitting around that they
can use towards this that is extremely
alarming to us because again if their
goal is to maximize the transition to
the regulated market why in the world
would they spend $25 million towards
closing down these operators
first uh so we've been fighting that now
for the last several months and maybe
some of you might have gotten some our
emails from an Cal or have seen some of
stuff around it's been an interesting
battle because we're trying to do this
education piece again touris them trying
to tell them that that is not the proper
way to be spending these funds if
spending them at all makes sense uh
we've been waiting for a while to get
this report that there was going to come
out from the sheriff's office from the
County Council and the DA's office as to
how they would propose to spend these
$25
million and the report's been a little
elusive for us and thankfully along the
way we had cat that did some great work
on this um to where we uh discovered the
report was actually attached to the
previous um mention of the well spargle
settlement back in November so had cat
not been looking back in November to
find out where this report was we would
not have seen that their recommendations
came out to actually using about $20
million of this 25 to actually close
down all the operators currently they
have a list of about 70
operators so 70 operators and that is
focused primarily now on the uh
dispensary side of things because
they're certainly most um visible when
it comes to this industry and they are
using thirdparty data practically just
using weed maps to find out who these
guys are at least that's her stated um
statement on that uh the $20 million
piece is a little concerning us on there
because uh part of that if you look in
the footnotes on the report it ends up
saying that the sheriff's department was
actually um asking for about $15 million
alone so out of three different groups
the sheriffs wanted $15 million of that
the County Council or the the report end
up suggesting to give them only 3.8
million but if you do the math and you
read between the lines there still is a
potential where altogether there's about
$30 million that they want to use to
shut down the
operators so as we keep doing this
education piece trying to discuss with
the Board of Supervisors on how that is
not the right way to inform before
regulating us we have been um fighting
that to where they have delayed this
report to be published around six times
already in the last 2 months uh this
last Tuesday though they finally ended
up sitting down to listen to this report
and in the report part of that was a
presentation given and the presentation
end up showing that they have currently
closed down 31 operators in the last
couple years they have 49 that they have
enforced against at the moment and there
are an additional 26 that are currently
under
investigation so they want to use these
funds now to actually go after them to
shut down the operators and it's been a
challenge for us as far as trying to
organize everyone for it so that we can
you know fight back against this part of
this is then because there is what
everyone pretty much calls this
whack-a-mole game many people in the
industry certainly understand or have
seen how they will shut down the
operators they'll pop back up in a
couple days and continue on including
some of the operators themselves it's
not been something that they have seen
or taken as serious iously as they
needed to for this uh this last Tuesday
though we had enough uh people come out
to the meeting and something that I'm
going to call out for you guys as well
too to please understand that this fight
is still not over but while the report
Was Heard over there 70 of us ended up
showing up to this
meeting 70 of us let me stress that
because we started this with only six
seven of us actually showed up the first
time a year ago 70 of us showed up to uh
give our testimony to show them why it
was not the right way to regulate uh to
enforce before they regulate against us
to show them that at the ended of doing
that it would also promote a illicit
dangerous Market as opposed to having
safe access for patients if you look at
the map on there you'll see clearly that
in the northern part of the county which
is the largest unincorporated areas on
there patients would literally need to
drive about two hours in order to get to
the nearest Legal dispensary so they can
get the medicine that they need that's
not something that's very practical on
there uh I'm happy to say that at the
end of that meeting the supervisors
decided not to vote one way or another
on this and have withheld it I have only
at this moment accepted the reports
coming in
so we take that as partly a victory that
we ended up holding back the enforcement
piece on there um but is also there was
another important in this thing that was
really interesting to see the change
happen uh they have now started to use
the rhetoric that there are good
operators within a county The Narrative
has changed so one of the supervisors
who ended up previously at the meetings
ended up stating that she recognizes
that we have one as far as prop 64 goes
and some data on that I want to give you
on that real quickly is that on the the
county side of things the county voted
actually 59.5% in favor of prop 64 and
that means each and every of the five
districts end up voting in favor it as
well
too the um that same supervisor at that
previous meeting end up stating that
while she recognizes she has to regulate
according to what the people have said
she still said that marijuana was a
gateway
drug of course we took qu quite some
exception to that and when we had our
meetings with them afterwards on that we
tried to understand where they were
getting their information from what is
it that they're pulling their facts from
and quite frankly in the end what we got
was a lot of crossed arms and telling us
that that supervisor has a doctor friend
and the doctor friend told her and that
is what she's basing her opinion
on fair enough of course we're angry on
that too but let's let's give it a
little chance here as well too I want to
put that out there because it is really
about educating them so they understand
what it is so part of our education
piece has also been we've been fortunate
enough that they have a um Department
within there that is called the office
of marijuana management and the office
of marijuana management is made up of
several different departments in the
county about 12 of them or so and they
all together are going to have to
coordinate their efforts on reg writing
these regulations for it um we ended up
having the opportunity to take them out
to Palm Desert and to Palm Springs so
they could see what a license facility
looks like so we took them first to a
cultivation at the cultivation site it
was something it was good for them to
understand because they did not
understand the power consumption piece
that comes into restricting a market to
strictly indoor cultivation we don't
Advocate that it should be um one or the
other we're looking to obviously uh give
the largest amount of opportunity for
people to make this transition so we
want that agricultural piece within the
county opened up outdoor Greenhouse so
on and so forth uh it was it was hopeful
it was nice for them to see because they
didn't understand this one cultivation
site ended up using 4,000 amps worth of
power when on average for those of you
who may not know your home will have
about 100 to 200
amps so they understand now the they're
getting to the point where they
understand the electrical concerns that
we go on the great as well on there um
and also on the dispensary site we got
to take them for that and we're going to
continue on with the extraction piece so
on and so forth um on the so we have
that opportunity and the reason I bring
that up is because after Tuesday's
meeting we had uh ended up having joined
to a second meeting on Wednesday on
there where we were informed that this
office of marijuana management is
actually going to be changing its name
to the office of cannabis management and
we take that as a really good sign as an
indicator that County does intend to
regulate soon they understand the issues
that are behind the stuff and the stigma
that can be caused by causing calling it
marijuana if you will and uh you know so
those are some of the successes that
we're seeing this thing on here but um
what I want to kind of point out more
than anything else and sum it up to give
you guys a chance to ask any questions
you may on the county side now going
forward we have held them back obviously
from putting this enforcement piece out
there but that doesn't mean that it's
finalized it's not done by any means the
money itself is still there they still
can use it they still have the
Temptation for it and we need to still
start continuing on this discussion this
narrative with what it means to be a
good operator so you will see our group
along with DPA and others and ccia to
start doing efforts and in the next
several weeks as to defining what it
means to be a good operator doing
community outreach showing that we want
to obey the guidelines that are set
forth many of the operat themselves
haven't had a chance to really read
through that stuff to understand what
they need to follow
by um and on that piece that's where we
say we want to reach out to everyone
here and if you can tell others as well
too we need more support as this goes
forward because we are fighting a huge
battle the county itself intends its
regulations to be a piece that will be
distributed towards the other cities
within the county that have not done the
regulations yet it's going to an
interesting thing because one thing that
we've uh recognized as well too for
instance the county ends up having uh
their environmental um Department that
actually is contracted out to 85 of the
88 cities the same also kind of goes
through with their fire department as
well so when they're writing these
regulations these cities that could also
write their own regulations need to find
a way to be copae between the two
because you're not going to have fire
department come in and say oh I steep
into this side of the street so that
means I've got to regulate differently
than I would on the county end of things
but all that's going to be a group
effort so whether you are yourself
within the unincorporated area
um that we're discussing we're fighting
on this at or within one of the other
Incorporated cities I really would like
you guys to have your help and please
join us come over where you can so we
can work together towards getting that
figured out that's great that's great
thank you so much Jonathan so we have
time for like two questions for him and
uh he'll be around afterwards if you uh
need to talk to
him hi Aron with Canada sewer Brands
again um can you tell me how this County
regulation uh
would be uh associated with the Bureau
of medicinal cannabis regulation from a
state level is there any are they
talking between those organizations or
is it just kind of isolated um
regulating um so on this one I I I want
to refer back to the meeting that cat
and I ended up attending on Wednesday uh
it was really encouraging a previous
meeting were there we she ended up
hearing a lot of rhetoric that was very
discouraging as to what they understood
the issues to behind as as regulations
go the county has proven this last
Wednesday that they are finally
listening they are seriously learning
they're educating themselves on how this
enforcement piece along with regulations
and everything else will work on the
state level as well as local so uh if I
understood your question correctly it
was a matter of are they discussing this
with the state is that
correct we we seem to see indication at
this point that they do finally but at
the same time we also have um we have
their ear so we are able to educate them
and and provide them the information
they need for that as well
so are you suggesting to them to have
some continuity between state and local
because I mean it gets really gray the
state can say one thing but it really
comes down to what the the city itself
says or the county in this case well on
on on the county end of things their
their concern their Focus right now they
they are recognizing that the state
certainly has their piece to take care
of the county has the other stuff that
they're we certainly were concerned with
right now is how do they regulate in a
way that makes sense with also the other
surrounding companies around us so that
way you're not literally going to be
different from one side of to the other
and also how that affects all the other
cities within the county itself so
they're understanding at least enough
this is their Lane this is what it's
been a challenge because they've tried
to introduce certain ideas that we're
trying to educate them from they don't
have to spend their resources and energy
on because the state is going to be
taking care of that So Courtney right
here who is in addition to being one of
my volunteers who's amazing and also
working with Cana kids you're all over
the place is doing a lot of work in the
cities and uh she's going to tell you a
little bit about what's going on we'll
just give him a quick update um for
example in what city are youing Monica
right so tell us so here's the thing
before you start is a lot of the work
that you're hearing about tonight that
for those of you who haven't gotten
involved yet and maybe want to get
involved as you can see there's a lot of
different levels to all this so if
you're the kind of person that likes to
speak out and fight for things the
places you can probably do the most work
is in cities in the county there's
definitely room in the state but
obviously a lot of people up in
Sacramento doing things so but in your
cities is where your your community the
city councils all over California right
now are having these conversations more
and more and more every day about what
is going to be their cannabis policy in
their for their community so it takes
people like us to go out there and do it
and actually show up to these meetings
and speak and let them know that hey
we're there we don't want the story to
just be dictated by law enforcement
that's just one side of of the of the
story we want to have Fair policy So
Courtney tell us what what you are doing
thank you Jackie for inspiring me to get
involved uh Santa Monica passed an
ordinance permitting two dispensaries
and that was over two years ago so with
the passing of prop 64 uh clearly it was
time to move forward I'm pleased to say
that uh they were very responsive to
cannabis and they also I think had some
change in their mindset about what the
concerns were uh one of the issues that
I raised is that because cannabis is
illegal in Santa Monica just working out
of my home office and working with
cannabis is technically illegal so uh
Lord Jones was there to of the founders
and they spoke uh they interested in
manufacturing out of their home for
their product line Lord Jones and uh so
that was another another party that was
also kind of hoping to have a presence
in Santa Monica outside of dispensary
zonings uh there were a number of people
that came out to to address address this
issue and uh one of the concerns they
had was how do we have a dispensary with
this zoning restriction if we have
Nursery schools all over town how do we
figure out where that's going to be so
uh some of the residents came out and
said you know made some suggestions
about where they might want to place
these dispensaries there's also
consideration about how much traffic
those dispensaries will encounter
because that's something that you want
as a thriving dispensary business of
course uh but now um this the purpose of
this particular event was uh to have a
study session to to address those issues
and learn more about what those issues
were and that's why I attended because
Jackie inspired me to get involved and
one of the ways of getting to get
involved is to present those issues and
say hey I'm a resident uh this is my
concern and I would like to be
represented in this fashion so uh that
was that was how that went down and I
would say it was successful um nothing's
moving forward yet but they are putting
together an Advisory Board and on that
board will be uh individuals who are
involved in the Cannabis industry and I
have requested to be a part of that
organization so uh here's hoping that's
great thank
you you know um just to to really give
you some a punch on what she was just
talking about in Santa Monica because I
was there that particular night and so
here's a City Santa Monica you you would
think that they kind of are hip and know
what's going on and right two years into
deciding that they're have two medical
marijuana dispensaries forget about
adult use recreational they want no part
of that they didn't even really
understand until this brand Lord Jones
which is like a you know medical brand
chocolates and I don't know what else
they have anyway topicals Tropicals and
stuff so but so they got up there and
were like hi we live in Santa Monica we
work in Santa Monica we're manufacturers
and they were like manufacturers and
they didn't really even understand that
there were secondary products in the
Cannabis industry they just thought it's
all about flower but right bongs or
bongs they really they really truly
didn't know and you could see the looks
on all their faces they were like the
light bulbs were going off and they were
like oh you mean there's other
businesses in cannabis that don't need a
storefront we don't have to watch
cannabis being cooked do we well no of
course not the warehouse areas or
whatever they didn't even understand
that and this is two years into them
having the conversation so it takes
people like are in this room and
Courtney and others to go up there and
tell them this stuff because otherwise
they're going to make bad decisions
right so that's what we're here to talk
about uh and I just want to add one more
thing uh if you did want to get involved
one thing I did was just go to the drug
policy.org website thank you and uh
there is a a section there action action
toolkits and they have some Pro tips
there on how to get involved uh I also
wrote an article on Direct Canabis
Network that you can read about uh to
see how we can change things looking
back at prohibition uh when alcohol uh
prohibition ended we can we can start
new and have uh 2020
hindsight that's great thank you
Courtney you could put that right down
there and there and and while I'm here I
want to tell you guys about West
Hollywood because here we are in West
Hollywood I spend time in West Hollywood
at the city council as well so this
coming Monday May 1st
6:30 right over there on the other side
of the park is the city council chambers
uh they are putting marijuana on the
agenda to actually le start to have a
discussion about what they're going to
do ironically West Hollywood was the
first one in California to really get
behind medical marijuana a lot of that
having to do with HIV and AIDS at the
time so they got in front of that now
they got to catch up with adult youth so
Monday May 1st 6:30 if you're a West
Hollywood business or thinking about
being West Hollywood business I
encourage you to get there and speak
anybody can speak but of course if you
live in the community and work in the
Comm it's even that more powerful but
we're going to need to even keep a city
like West Hollywood which is as
Progressive as it may be we still have
to make sure that they have Fair policy
like some of the things ly was talking
about they don't have discrimination and
all those things we still need to make
sure even in the most Progressive cities
so encourage everybody to come down to
that okay one more short speaker and
then we're going to wrap this so this
person Terry Bev I just met recently
Terry come on up Terry is in the law
enforcement security side of cannabis
and as we go forward in with licensing
and compliance security is a big issue
so Terry give us a few minutes and let's
talk about some of those things that you
do say hi to everybody first thank you
for having me Jackie I appreciate it
absolutely now you're a a member of leap
as well right that is correct what is
Leap tell people what leap tell what
leap was and what it is sure leap is an
amazing
organization uh the whole time I was a
police officer I I I always had a
conscience about the drug laws and the
things that were going on and I never
agreed with it and I never knew that
there were other police officers out
there that felt like I did but uh uh
leap is made is a National Organization
it's made up of over 5,000 people uh
mostly law enforcement and former law
enforcement officers who basically admit
that we lost the war on drugs and say uh
you know we recognize the fact that uh
that drugs probably shouldn't be illegal
at least you know the the softer what
might be considered softer drugs and uh
that during the War on Drugs a lot of
harm was done to certain communities
within the United States and it's
basically things that uh Lynn has
touched on and you've touched on and
Jonathan touched on it's uh it's
something that uh that has gone on for
decades and and uh leap basically fights
uh they have lobbyists in Washington DC
and they uh uh promote drug policy
reform uh uh fight against over
incarceration and mandatory sentences
and all of those U laws and policies
that uh that inflicted harm on certain
communities great cuz we need law
enforcement on our side right or even ex
law enforcement we definitely need that
and there's a lot more of them out there
than people might think so you have a
company called arlex security right that
correct so what kind what types of
security do you do to help cannabis
businesses well you know cannabis uh
businesses require a special type of
security and uh that's why we're uh we
provide security for all types of uh
Industries but we specialize in that
specifically just because it is
something that that requires a unique
type of uh of uh approach uh one of the
things that we do we start off by
helping businesses that are applying for
for their licenses because uh one thing
that some people might not realize is
that when you apply for a license a
large percentage of the points that are
attributed to or that are given to you
have to do with your security plan so uh
I've seen people try to do their own
security plans and it doesn't always
work out that well so that's one of the
things that we do we're happy to help
with that now I'm I've been told by some
people in the room that um security
plans are usually required as part of an
an application to assist a license is
that have you seen that I have not seen
any uh regulatory agency that does not
require a security plan and sometimes it
can be um up to a third of the overall
points that you get for your uh for your
license the other thing that we do is we
provide uh uh security design for the
space because if we can get involved
early on we can help design the space so
that it's it can be secured more easily
uh we provide uh installation of
CCTV uh Access Control Systems uh
biometric uh Access Control Systems uh
alarms we also provide security officers
and another thing that we're working on
right now that I've had a lot of
questions about this is uh The Insider
threat a lot of cannabis businesses have
said uh you know how do we keep people
our employees from stealing from us
because uh it's you know it's bound to
happen and so we're developing a program
right now that uh it's an employee
training program and it uh involves
engaging employees uh so that they're
less likely to uh steal from you and one
of the things that we find in the
security industry is that employees who
steal didn't feel engaged with their the
company that they were working for so
that's one of the things that we're
working on right now and uh well I've
had a great response from people in the
industry so far that's excellent so to
finish this up what advice do you give
to uh canab businesses that are going to
go for license as they're thinking about
security well I know that we've talked
about it a lot but I don't think it can
be talked about too much anybody that
decides that they're either going to go
into the Cannabis industry or stay in it
for those businesses like you know pre
propd other um businesses uh that may be
operating outside the law who want to
become legal it's going to be all about
compliance compliance is going going to
be really huge and uh it's going to be
uh possibly the most regulated industry
in California and so owners right up
front need to have that compliance
mindset and what they need to do is they
need to create a compliance culture as
an owner if you're interested in
compliance you can't do that by yourself
you have to uh get your EMP employees on
board so you need to create a compliance
culture and a big part of that is uh sec
securing your facility and training your
employees and that's one of the things
that we can help do so well that's great
let's thank Terry for giving us all that
wonderful information thank you so much
Terry B
[Music]