hey everybody greenlight productions
here
i apologize to loud noise the fans in
this silly mask
who are in a highly regulated indoor
facilities that's just how it is
now recently kiss organics and child
science both put out a video
sharing their opinion on the use of
cover crops companion plants
and living mulch indoors now these are
two credible individuals
who brought up valid points that
shouldn't be ignored
if in fact you want to use these systems
successfully indoors
in fact the only thing i disagree with
that they said
was just their opinion overall
and the only reason i'm sharing my
opinion with you is because both of them
name me in their video so i feel an
obligation at this point
now early on i didn't have a lot of
places to look or resources
resources to look for information
so my primary teacher has always been
mother nature now mother nature has been
doing this bigger
longer and more successful than any of
us could ever imagine
so to say that we can't take those same
natural systems
that we've been studying for thousands
of years and apply that science
and those systems
in indoors controlled environment to me
just sounds kind of silly
so i'm going to share with you guys my
perspective and my opinion on this
from a martial arts standpoint more
specifically using jiu-jitsu
sounds silly but hear me out
now in jiu jitsu your opponent's
strengths can be used against them
and that's kind of the concept he pushes
i pull he pulls i push
uh you know you don't know you you go
with the flow versus trying to fight
things head on
you anticipate your opponent's moves
i grab his arm he pulls his arm i go
left he goes right
when you start to anticipate you know
the probability of what your
opponent is going to do you can make
better decisions
on how to trick your opponent how to
trap your opponent how to
do all these different things now let's
apply that
to a living system more specifically
our living mulch
now when we first started off we were
super clover heavy
that's what everybody was doing that's
what we were doing
after time a little bit of time we
started noticing that yeah clover
is definitely more problematic than the
solutions it provides
there's a lot easier ways to get
nitrogen into the system
than putting a nitrogen-fixing plant in
your soil that attracts and harbors
pests
so we cooled all the clover and we ran
brown mulch for a while strong wood
chips
didn't have much much cover crop going
down our soil
and we actually had bigger problems we
actually had more threat
pressure uh the spider mites that were
in our clovers
we're now crawling up our plants uh
things of that nature so then i started
studying these plants their strengths
and their weaknesses
and how i can use that to my advantage
so i'll use a couple
points would be the first time i
encountered green aphids
not a big deal but we'll get there so
when i first encountered green aphids
was in a large facility
commercial facility and
one of the things that i noticed right
away just by scouting my rooms and just
doing my due diligence
was the green aphids preferred
the clover over the cannabis and i had
clover all over my beds so they're going
from the clover to the cannabis from the
canvas to the clover and just this big
buffet aphid buffet going on
so what i did was i cooled all the
clover from all my
all my beds all my soils and then i
planted the clover in a small pot
and i placed several small plot pots to
be precise
and i placed that pot in the corner of a
room
and i drew all the aphids in that room
to that pot and then i busted out my
trusty old blow torch
and i sent them to help it's the most
organic way you can deal with things in
my opinion is fire
a little risky at times i i get it
so that's just one case where i took
something
that presented a problem i flipped the
script
and i made that problem a solution
so that brings me to my next point is
that everything can serve a purpose
if you know its strengths and weaknesses
and how to apply them
so just let's take for example this
country for for
for example we have a diverse population
of people
from from multiple countries all over
the world speaking multiple languages
so much good food so much good music so
much good parties
it's a poly culture america
is is a poly culture of people we have
we have multiple cultures
that coexist and it's an awesome place
now can you imagine if we were to
monoculture the united states
and now we have our rich white dudes
that would not be a fun place to live
i'm sorry
same concept goes with this soil in our
plants
our plants don't want to live in a in
beds surrounded by
clones of themselves there's no
biological intelligence
shared in that system so it doesn't make
sense to try to
to treat it like that i i don't see the
value in that
so going on to my aphids thing
green aphids were my first experience
using trap plants from there i learned
about banker plants
and having pollinators in the system
that can feed my predators
more in between pests out breaks keep
them around longer spend less money on
pests
and been successful at it now i'm going
to talk a little bit about some of the
plants we use and why
because i get this question a lot so
the primary plant that we use that
everybody always sees
i'll try to get it in here that's
dicondra
so that's basically the use what we use
that for
is just simply to cover the soil it's a
ground cover
it's easy to manage it it doesn't
need reseeding um it grows good in low
light but also
will die off in low light
and it's just an easy to manage plant
indoors so we use it to cover the soil
to keep it from eroding when we water
and all that good stuff
also we use chickweed another really
good ground cover
um it has a really good um
consistency to it as far as fluffy it
adds a really good aeration to the mulch
layer
it's not it doesn't uh get super heavy
and layered
it says fluffy like a sponge and it's a
really good environment
now both of these two cover crops are
are really
unfavored to most pests not to say that
pests won't linger on them
that would be untrue but it's not what
they want to eat it's it's not what they
look forward to eating
so i don't have to worry about an
abundance of problems growing down there
and then we also use from time to time
you'll see grasses
something to take into consideration
when you're choosing your cover crops
your companion plants or whatever
is their roots see our dichondra has
super
shallow roots and creates a thick carpet
across the top of the soil
where it's not really pumping sugar it's
pumping exudates deep
so it's not really expanding the biology
in the soil
to the depths that it could go so that's
why the grass is good it's going to have
much deeper roots
than the dichondra than the chickweed
so it's good to take into consideration
just how you're occupying that soil with
what
we also then use various companion
plants
like marigolds and brassicas and things
like that that produce biotoxins
that may kill an unwanted pest or
pathogen don't want to go too far down
that road it's a long one
with a lot of big words i can't
pronounce anyways
so with the combination of companion
plants
ground cover both brown mulch
and green mulch we have found success
now it's not to say that we haven't had
problems it's just that we always pay
attention and learn from them
we evolve we're not just going to give
up
the first time we see something that we
don't like when i find out
how to defeat it we're gonna rise to the
occasion
so that's my perspective on some of the
values of cover crops is at the end of
the day
you're gonna get pests you're gonna
they're gonna show up eventually
and if you don't have something else for
them to eat they're gonna be on your
cannabis plant
and the beauty about having a living
mulch is i can find things that they
like more
than my cannabis plant like i explained
about the aphids
and then i can take the fight there
so deep in the flower or in the flower
in general i can't spray nothing
not that i would spray anything bad but
even compost teas and organic sprays
i can't even use because i'll fail the
microbial side of the test
so by having companion plants by having
a living mulch
what that allows me to do is it allows
me to find plants
that my pests like more than my cannabis
it allows me to take the fight
somewhere other than my cash crop so
i'll plant whether it's clover in a pot
i bust out the torch
or it's dichondra chickweed marigold
whatever it is in my beds
that i can spray with the compost tea
when i can't spray my flowers
either way it takes a fight where i want
to take it
and it puts me in control so
those same problems that people have
found
again i have found ways to make those
solutions
and you have to be persistent you have
to mean it you have to have good
intentions
this isn't fakeable i mean it is on
instagram i'll be honest
but in real life when you're walking
people through this facility
they see it they feel it they can
breathe it they can smell it
the energy is in the air the product
speaks for itself
i run these rooms again with two
people two women so it can be done it's
just
are you willing to put in the work are
you willing to put the science to the
test
are you willing to have faith in mother
nature