you know when when when Ronald Reagan
started his escalated war on drugs that
was back in the days when most of the
weed that came into the country was
coming from Colombia and a lot of it
most of it probably was was coming on
boats was coming on ships and so one of
the very first targets of that war which
started with the war on cannabis were
boats that were carrying cannabis that
was when the zero tolerance policy was
first implemented and the Coast Guard
went around seizing people's boats and
ships and even rather sizable vessels
because they would find a joint or a
half a joint and that's that's where
that first zero tolerance term was clean
so I think it's really significant that
as we are here gathered to think about
the state of cannabis and where we are
at today that susan was able to report
this news that we have liberated the
Queen Mary that she has Pluto buried the
Queen Mary I think it's a great sign of
what's coming in the future so how many
of you are working harder than you ever
have in your lives before okay and how
many of you are loving it more than
anything you've ever done yeah okay me
too right so I'm like so busy doing
stuff these days I never have enough
time to prepare as much as I want to for
anything that I do and I'm afraid that's
a little bit the case this morning so I
got a lot of important ideas that I'd
like to share with you I may wander off
and get a little lost from time to time
and need to come back to my notes and
get an anchor back again so bear with me
as we go through this the state of
cannabis right well I am really pleased
and proud and happy to report to all of
you if you don't know it yet right that
the state of cannabis is strong and
getting stronger every day and our
future is bright and getting brighter
every day
we're not entirely out of the shadows
yet but the worst of the darkness is
behind us and our ultimate goals are
within reach there's good news almost
everywhere we look right there's only
ten states and the united states now
that have failed to pass some kind of
cannabis reform law only ten every year
the Congress passes the far Rohrbacher
amendment which protects those state
laws by blocking the DOJ from
interfering with them by larger and
larger margins every year including many
many Republican votes right and the 9th
Circuit Court of Appeals has just
affirmed that the far Rohrbacher
amendment means exactly what it says
the DOJ cannot prosecute anybody who is
acting in compliance with their state
cannabis laws take a look at Congress
now in the Senate and in the house we've
got several really groundbreaking
cannabis measures that are pending and
and they're gaining more and more
support we're not sure when they're
going to start passing but more and more
of them are gaining support and it's
only inevitable that we'll see their
passage
presidential campaign for the very first
time in history we have both both the
general election candidates from both
parties Democratic and Republican who
have publicly expressed support for
medical cannabis I remember when we
couldn't even get a joke out of them and
then all we got was jokes for a while
right well not anymore not anymore and
this is going to continue right this
will continue for the rest of the Obama
administration will continue to see this
gradual dismantling of federal
prohibition and if Hillary Clinton
becomes president yeah may slow down
okay but federal reform won't stop and
even if Trump is is elected okay he and
probably more importantly the people
associated with
may be able to completely stop reform at
the federal level that could happen but
they will not they will not be able to
roll us back here in the states of the
state level we will continue taking a
territory and making a reform more good
news more good news a new legal
profitable cannabis industry has been
created we went from no such thing to
the most rapidly growing industry in
America in a decade in a decade right so
we've harnessed the engine of free
enterprise to the Train of social
justice and there is no stopping us now
there's no stopping us now increasingly
moving forward a funding from that
industry is going to supplant and
supplement the funding from
philanthropists god bless them who we've
had to rely on all of these years for
funding this movement okay time for the
industry to step up and start doing its
job so you know we don't need to
speculate anymore what happens when we
do reform the laws right there's like
this long long demonstrable track record
of benefits that flow to reform stays
okay jobs investment up tourism up
construction up pharmaceutical drug
fatalities down 25% 17,000 lives
17,000 lives we've saved binge drinking
down domestic violence down violent
crime down okay the list of benefits is
so long and so impressive it's just
going to powerfully powerfully
reinforced the efforts of all of these
activists who increasingly are going to
be funded by industry and this
acceleration this acceleration of reform
right has brought a whole new wave a
whole
new wave of professionals into the
industry people who just didn't feel
safe before and they're bringing with
them a whole new range of experience and
skills and credibility that we've never
had in the industry before and some of
those professionals have started the
first dedicated investment funds in the
space and the investments that those
funds are making are in turn attracting
even more folks more professionals more
seasoned people coming into the industry
and they their presence is really
powerfully dampening the stigma that's
associated with cannabis they have lots
of friends and lots of influence and so
the stigma is being reduced reduced and
and reform is accelerating as a result
of their presence right and the the
financial success of the industry is
encouraging and motivating ever
increasing numbers of individuals of
businesses of organizations of elected
representatives who maybe they were
opposed to us a few years ago or at best
neutral and now they're like turning
into our best friends they're promoting
and defending the industry right why
America loves a winner and we're winning
now it's a big difference it's a big
difference so that doesn't mean there's
not bad news there's still plenty of bad
news in the world of cannabis we just
saw the Neanderthals at the DEA for the
umpteenth time
despite the mountain of evidence to the
contrary refused to reschedule or D
scheduled cannabis right and of course
big pharma right there by their sides
one of the most disgusting things that
I've seen recently in the world of
cannabis as this company called insists
insists is the large is the manufacturer
of fentanyl one of the most
deadly and addictive substances on the
planet you may have been hearing about
all these people who are dropping dead
across the country because of fentanyl
well these disorganisation right is the
largest funder of the No campaign on
cannabis legalization in Arizona is that
despicable so still bad news still way
too many of our sisters and our brothers
who are getting arrested my friend James
Slavik is here somewhere and and James
was just had this horrible thing
happened to him and there's far too many
people that are getting arrested and are
being put on trial and are being their
lives are being ruined still to this day
in California across the country around
the world and and they're
disproportionately people of color so
yeah there's still some still some
things we have to get done sometimes
sometimes the bad news is just like the
flipside of the good news right
so regulations we're seeing the passage
of regulations it seems like everywhere
I see counties cities states that's a
good thing it's a good thing we're never
going to get cannabis into the medicine
cabinet of every American family without
those kinds of regulations but for some
people for some legacy cannabis
entrepreneurs for many people they're
gonna have devastating effect like the
mercer regulations are going to on small
manufacturers and small growers in
california and it's wonderful to see new
entrants coming into the industry with
new skills and new abilities to reach
out to the mainstream and new ways to
influence decision makers but they often
also come along with a much greater
ability to get financing to get capital
to scale up and sometimes they introduce
to business models to the cannabis
industry that forced people like me to
change the way that we've done things
for years and and and sometimes decades
right so we're gonna have to learn to
adapt all the folks who have been in
this industry for 10 or 20 years are
going to need to adapt to a greatly
heightened level of competitive
intensity and we're going to have to
learn how to work together with people
who come from very different backgrounds
than ours
very different cultures and maybe
different value sets and the financial
success of the industry is it's it's
wonderful right it's great to see people
coming in who really know how to make
money but sometimes we see those folks
who are coming into the industry using
their established financial power and
their political influence to create
protected niches for themselves in the
marketplace so a one really close to
home example of that in the state of
California is the mandatory distribution
requirements in the newly passed medical
cannabis regulations they were enacted
at the behest of what I call the unholy
alliance big alcohol the Teamsters Union
and the law enforcement organizations
none of those organizations have ever
been friends of our movement or lifted a
finger to make cannabis legal right and
the provision that they're backing could
double or triple the price of cannabis
for medical patients in California
there's other examples of this kind of
nonsense around the country so Nevada
initiative has a provision in it that
exclusively gives all distribution
licenses for cannabis to alcohol
companies exclusively where Florida's
kind of sorta maybe almost medical
cannabis law that restricts licenses to
nurseries that have been existence for
30 years or more so manipulation of
legislation of regulation has
already become a central business tactic
and new and existing cannabis businesses
are going to need to be prepared to
engage with regulatory agencies to
engage with legislators to defend their
interests and make sure that this is a
market they can continue to participate
in and more flipside to good news right
it's great to see capital finally
flowing into the industry because for a
long time it was one of the major
obstacles we had to growth but that
capital is coming in largely at the
service of the strongest and most
successful companies and those companies
are using the capital to grow and to
consolidate their positions and as they
do that there will be more of them and
less smaller companies right we're at
the the beginning of the classic bell
curve that you see in all boom
industries it goes like this
the bell curve and and we're right at
the beginning of it now where it's
shooting up really really quickly right
we've got new entrepreneurs and new
investors they're jumping in every
single day and that's gonna keep
happening for a couple of years but
eventually at some point the market does
it what it does it does its job
and the weaker players are going to
start dropping out and the stronger
players are going to start consolidating
and that curve is going to level out and
then it's going to start dropping and it
may go down as deeply as it went up and
we'll eventually level out so what does
that mean for us what what does life in
the bell curve mean it's really
important that we consider this and one
of the things that it means is that the
first ones now may later be last
the person who today is your employee
may well in a few years be your employer
or your investor or vice versa none of
us really know how this horse race is
going to turn out so let's be kind and
gentle with
each other let's seek out the human
qualities that we really love and
appreciate in one another let's build
real relationships that are enduring
enough to carry us through whatever
turbulence these times bring us we are
all brought together by this plan okay
we are all one people so what is very
told you what it meant massive change
massive change okay so we're seeing all
this massive change all over the place
new entrants new laws new strategies new
capital and new tactics we're seeing
increasing numbers of general
practitioners who are recommending
cannabis not cannabis Doc's but GPS
right because there's this increasing
acceptance of cannabis in the mainstream
you've got so guys like Sanjay Gupta
saying that it's that it's okay and
we're seeing the creation of more
standard forms of cannabis therapeutics
more capsules more tinctures right and
and and that in turn is encouraging even
more GPS to to write recommendations
which in turn is creating demand for
more of these products right so it's
very beneficial loop that's going on and
now we can look ahead to the - that just
has some really fascinating
conversations just like 20 20 minutes
ago about this I mean we are now coming
to the day where instead of just working
with THC and CBD and one or two other
cannabinoids we're gonna start pulling
out all of the many cannabinoids that
there are in the plan okay we've looked
at maybe 15 out of 450 okay that
treasure chest
that treasure chest is opening up and
and we see other stuff right that that's
pushing us forward other innovation new
cannabis formats products like vape pens
and beverages and transdermal patches
more socially acceptable forms of
ingesting cannabis than sucking on a
bong or rolling up a joint and those new
formats are bringing in even more new
adopters ever
we see more and more people who are
willing to consider cannabis because it
doesn't look like the stereotype that
they had in their head national brands
okay we now have National cannabis
brands that are like known across the
country
well institutional finance is not going
to be far behind
I can hear their footsteps in the
hallway already okay
and and and when they come there's going
to be a wave of really big acquisitions
and rich access exits for cannabis
companies that have been smart that have
played their cards right and I mean you
can already see it right look at
horticulture where Scott's miracle-gro
just bought general hydro okay next
quite possibly probably I think are
going to be cannabis companies focused
on the science and medicine of cannabis
analytical laboratories extraction
technologies geneticists right because
we will see rescheduling or D scheduling
and when that happens it will kick off a
wave of pharmaceutical Rd and those
pharmaceutical companies are going to
want to acquire the research the data
the techniques the team the brand of
these companies that have been focusing
on cannabis for a while so that they can
get first to market advantage and then I
know then after that maybe we see
cannabis beverage and food companies
that have developed a lot of traction
and brand equity in the market being
acquired by large corporations that have
already existing footprints in in food
production and beverage production
distribution and they're basically
perfectly positioned to just add
cannabis to their list of ingredients
so that's what's gonna happen there will
be more waves like that that come and
what we're seeing is the first signs of
what's going to be a monumental
collision between the world of cannabis
and the world of corporations that
collision is going to be wrenching it's
going to be jarring it's going to be
shocking like all collisions are but
really if we take a moment and we think
about it that collision has been
inevitable ever since we started working
on legalization all of those years ago
because nothing nothing in the United
States of America is mainstream until
it's in the mainstream of Commerce and
so taking this plant into the mainstream
of Commerce which is controlled by the
world of corporations has to be it has
to be a part of our job and I say that
to you as a legacy cannabis person
there's some of my very dearest friends
in this world people whose children I
was there to see their birth and watch
them grow up and have children of their
own are going to be really seriously
hurt in this collision some of the
people who some of the people who are
most responsible for bringing us to the
state that we are here today this good
day that we're at ok so I want to take a
moment to speak directly to those of you
who like me carried this plan so
faithfully for so long through so many
years of the darkness of prohibition
around 50 years ago probably by some
divine stroke of Providence this plant
fell into the hands of our people and we
opened our arms and we embraced her
we gave her a home
we nurtured her we protected her we
watched her grow we defended her against
the people that would have ended her
existence and we fought ferociously for
a long time for her liberation and it
has not been easy it hasn't been easy
we have been made sacrifices there have
been all kinds of sacrifices by many
many people over a period of many years
the most painful kinds of sacrifices
that human beings really can make we've
had violent raids on homes properties
seized our cars and our bank accounts
taken away even our children yanked away
from their mothers arms
we've been arrested and jailed and
subject to extraordinarily long business
terms sometimes people have even lost
their lives but we still gladly welcomed
cannabis into our homes and into our
lives and over time she came to feel
like like one of ours like like one of
our family members and so in those years
it's only been natural for us to develop
a sense of possessiveness a sense that
this plant should in some way belong to
those of us who have loved her so well
and sacrificed so much on her behalf but
we need to remember it's hard sometimes
you know these thoughts I feel them
almost every day sometimes multiple
times a day right who are these people
this is our thing what are they doing
and we have to remember what we really
in our hearts to be true right which is
that no creation of nature belongs to
any human being we know this and so this
plan no matter how much we love her does
not belong to us we are not her owners
we are her stewards we are her
caregivers we are her protectors but she
didn't come into our hands so that we
could become rich she came into our
hands to help us change the world so all
my brothers and sisters they're okay and
I'm talking to the dreadlock warriors
I'm talking to the rainbow
revolutionaries I'm talking to the
radical fairies I'm talking to the wise
earth mothers you all know who you are
we're going to be called upon to make
one more final sacrifice we are being
called upon now okay and that's going to
be to let this little sprout that we
have tended and with such care to grow
up and claim her real destiny to be able
to reach out all around the world and
come into the hands in a legal way of
everybody on this beautiful planet
because we know that the promise of
cannabis belongs to every human being
because every single last one of us has
an endocannabinoid system so we can't do
that alone hey our arms aren't long
enough and there's not enough of us to
do that we need help and and fortunately
that help is coming and it's coming in
the form of new comers who are coming
into our industry and so we need to
welcome them and we need to help them
if we don't we're never going to finish
this job but I also want to talk to the
newcomers those of you who have come to
the movement come to the industry after
a lot of the heavy lifting has been done
so some respect appreciate the decades
of struggle and sacrifice that it has
taken us to come to this day understand
that for many of us this isn't just a
living or a way to build wealth or a
product or even an innovation cannabis
is our teacher and our guide and in some
cases our sacrament who don't write off
the legacy cannabis industry we know
this plant and the culture that we have
built around it better than the very
best of Wall Street analysts we're the
best subject matter experts that you
will ever find anywhere
okay so we got this collision happening
right and obviously it's like I said it
is gonna be shocking and it will be
painful okay and it is happening okay so
what's the key to turning all of this to
something that has value and meaning and
purpose and is consistent with our love
for this plant okay I think what we need
to make absolutely certain of is that
cannabis changes the world of
corporations more than corporations
change the world of cannabis this plant
has been doing just fine for millennia
giving sustenance and healing to human
beings and doing nothing to harm the
rest of nature but corporate culture has
taken us to the brink of planetary
extinction in just a few centuries it's
only been a few centuries we've had
these things called score per a shion's
okay and look where we are so we need to
make absolutely certain that we can
advise corporate corporate that we
cannabis corporations more than
corporations corporatized cannabis so
big goal big goal big dreams for dreamer
dude they told me that 40 years ago too
you know and I'll tell you why I'm
hopeful a couple of reasons I'm hopeful
about achieving that goal one of them is
the many conversations that I have with
people who have just come into this
industry from the straight corporate
world and over and over and over again
they're like Steve it's so different
here you know I don't have to put a mask
on in the morning I don't have to hide
Who I am and what I care about during
the day my life has a meaning and
purpose people are more tolerant of me
and and my quirks and and they're
they're more forgiving they're more
caring I enjoy my life more and when I
look at them I know it's true right I
can see it in their eyes I can see it in
the lift in their step I can see it in
the smile in their faces and so why why
is that
think that that one of the reasons is
the inherent properties of this plan
right its ability to to spark creativity
and to extend patience and to inspire
togetherness amongst people and that's
that's not going to stop happening and
another reason another reason I have
hope is because our industry is
different it's different in a lot of
ways the product that that that we work
with is one of those big differences but
another is that this is an industry that
grew out of a social justice movement
it's a very strange dynamic think about
it how many industries have grown out of
a social justice movement so the people
who created this thing we weren't people
who cared about creating wealth so much
as we cared about changing the world
when we started this thing 50 years ago
we didn't know that cannabis feature
cancer or prevent Alzheimer's or help
epileptic kids okay all we knew was that
when we smoked this plant when we smoked
this flower it helped us become more
like the people that we really wanted to
be and so we've tried to carry that
sensibility into the organizations and
into the businesses that we've built
we've tried to infuse that sensibility
into the entire culture to to use what
we're building as a vehicle for social
change as a way to create this new way
of life that we're all looking forward
to I mean I think everybody is looking
forward to it right it's like do we
really need to create just another new
industry like every other global
industry out there do we need more of
them no okay we need a new kind of
industry that's going to unleash
transformational change that's going to
break the corporate mold and we can do
that right there's going to be a lot of
wealth and fabulous careers that are
going to happen in this industry and
many of the people who enjoy those
benefits are in this room today
but if all that we have to show for
ourselves at the end of the day 20 or 30
years from now when we look over our
shoulders are those riches will have
blown the most valuable opportunity
that's in front of us okay and that's to
create this new kind of industry the
future is in our hands it's a blank
slate we're starting this really from
the beginning we're still just in the
beginning the revolution has just begun
okay and what this thing is going to
become is in all of our hands so let's
make sure that what we create that the
world that we leave to our children is
the world that takes the lessons the
cannabis teaches us seriously okay and
what is what does that mean okay that
means a world where leaders are no
longer so ostentatious and they're held
more to account a world where gender
roles are more fluid a world where
bottom line calculations always include
returns to communities and workers a
world where sustainability is a basic
threshold of all new ventures where
people are kinder and gentler to each
other where disputes or solved
peacefully more peacefully more often
and where parents spend more time
playing with their kids where couples
spend more intimate moments with each
other where violence of all kinds drops
and where we finally have a place an
honored place in our society for all of
the flavors of human beings that we are
blessed with okay that's the future of
cannabis okay that's the future of
cannabis that's what we can really
achieve some people say Steve you're
playing the long game yes I am playing
the long game okay that's the future
that I want and that's the
that is in our hands that's what we can
achieve if we really take the lessons
that this plant teaches us seriously if
we really demand of ourselves that we
become the people that we really want to
be this is an amazing chance and we
should take it okay I don't think that
we can afford to blow this opportunity
this greatest opportunity that any of us
will have in our lives because look
around at the world today look at what
we're dealing with
we're created technology that's on the
verge of cooking this planet into an
uninhabitable cinder every time I turn
on the news and I see what's happening I
hear about more people blowing
themselves up more people are killing
each other for the most ridiculous of
reasons
so is there ever a time has there ever
been time that this plant that the
wisdom that this plant teaches is more
in need by the world I don't think so
okay I don't think it's going too far to
suggest the future and the fate of our
world could depend on the future of
cannabis so let's all get this job done
let's win on November 7 and look forward
to partying with you that night
throughout the coming year