[Music]
he was coming from Las Vegas Nevada he
operates a dragonfly earth medicine okay
a dragonfly Eric's medicine certified
and clean green certified indoor
facility no-till a no-till indoor
facility under LED light he's able to
pass the strictest microbial toxin in
the nation and he is here to talk to us
about building a successful brand in a
competitive market maintaining efficient
and sustainable all right thanks guys
thanks for having me thanks for airplane
treehouse crabmeat thanks for now guys
yes so did not
anyways 27 so yeah so don't mean
actually talking about building a brand
in the competitive market I'm some of
the absolute down to one to I need like
able to come prepare anything just go
over our story on some strong points
potentially avoid or you know kind of
tend towards so years ago have a kinda
can this way I was actually in a fighter
so I grew up like as a kid like most
people here probably welcome in to visit
an extra days I became a professional
athlete he chased this whole UFC dream
and picked up a lot of injuries on the
way got into canvas and then they had a
medical marijuana program some of the
California's we can apply for a
prescription but in Nevada it was crazy
hard to get any other freaking yeah
corner taxation is doctor's appointment
everything in your fingerprints done FBI
you can check all these crazy things to
get it once they're all defeated three
can visit and my personal garden for
years got really comfortable growing my
own really good cannabis evolved as a
grower from flood tables - Coco - soil
with nutrients - looking sorta amended
soil - living soil had my own little
personal evolution it was awesome
and then you can see that she comes for
them all the guys are coming to town I
was talking about you know this
corporate takeover and all this stuff
and and you similar to what California's
going through now this idea of be having
at home grow personal garden they're not
was slowly shrinking so I got nervous
and started putting together some
concept and how to run news on a larger
scale I got bigger than the four lights
I was running in my personal garden for
them sorry six likes so let's try put
together some ideas I bring into the
movie next oil over the years in
permaculture it was something I was
extremely passionate about so that I
could stand behind
I thought okay I'm gonna build my
company around that that's something I
want to really focus my brand on is
something that
and behind some people to stand behind
I'm something that she's bigger than me
so we really focused on that and the
whole regenerative movement so I said I
have a permaculture and then basically
putting together a local team together
in my hometown and from that I've no
small group that basically back in half
is saying let me do what I wanted to do
they basically they're a bunch of
construction contractors general
contractors so they built our whole
building out on the old days Hardware
completely renovated this rusty old
lumber yard into a state-of-the-art grow
okay again four years ago state of the
art nowadays I look at my grown it looks
like a dinosaur to me it's technology I
guess I don't know so anyway so we put
together this really cool local dream
team we build this really cool concept
around a living soil system of
regenerative movement and then we hit
the ground running four or five years
this was actually five years ago we
propped out our first crop about four
years ago and when we first opened up it
was a joke people thought we were the I
got so much slack from every single
angle living soil living soil indoors
led everything you could possibly think
of no one thought would work but four
years later we're the only brand still
operating with the same ownership under
the same roof under the same everything
so it's definitely something there a
long time basically say it make sure if
you build a brand first of all build it
on something that you stand can stand
behind don't just building on some
random trend or sometimes AB or a strain
building on something that you can you
know definitely when days are bad that
you can definitely you know manage to
get through it because I guarantee right
now if you open up shop based off of you
know some trends some bad and you have a
hard day you're gonna be hitting the
road hard I guarantee it anyways back up
so we built up I grow out will
again fairly small my shipping you guys
are familiar with GLP but people tend to
think that were this really big
corporate bro
but no we're not we're just a really
small a fishing bro that would just keep
constantly a perpetual cycle going so
anyways so we built that bro we did a
whole living organic soil thing and we
stood by it I'm not sure if you guys
again are familiar with this but again
we're living organic soil indoors with
LEDs and one our sixteenth cycle I
preached a whole lot of water only and I
really truly mean it we do a lot of very
minimalistic with our nutrients we do a
lot of poly culture in our soil so we do
a lot of we run clover no more but a lot
of different dynamic accumulators that
conjure chickweed straw grasses rye
things like that as part of our soil
program a lot in England indoor guys
don't really truly do that and you see a
lot of guys running soil but they're
also running a bottle nutrient line
behind it so that's one thing that we
try and trade away from is we're going
to really keep it real again I want to
build my brand behind something real not
just some again some living soil fad
like you're trying to see people kind of
box you know against that's why I'm
saying that so again we want to
everything that we do we do for real
I've worked with some of the best people
in industry from with Jonathan and his
crew to some of the best oil people some
of the best permaculturist
and put it all together under one roof
it's really gonna be key building a team
is going to be key if you're trying to
build a successful brand and be
competitive one of the things that I'm
really big on is having people that I
can play devil's advocate with I'm an
owner operator so I have the freedom to
make decisions but I also utilize the
people I have around me I always try to
get as much people in the room as
possible before I make any decision
especially if I make it season they grow
I always put my growers in wanna make a
decision and the trim team I'm gonna
pull my trimmers in I try to build this
really good solid team because at the
end of the day that she's really gonna
build your brand for you I have about 30
employees and my firm team and and they
do more for my brand than any admin
magazine
than any Instagram posts than any
anything just happening those 30 people
go home happy and say that they work for
a good company that stand behind what
they do it's the best thing you could do
for your brand treating employees
respect make sure that they're heard is
really really truly important that's one
thing that we managed to do that we're
going to successful at but yeah so so
building a brand being competitive make
sure you have your competitive advantage
for us and the data everybody who was
really this corporate breed motto our
model where they're trying to cop out
really big really fast and chase trends
chase strains and do all those things
for us we took the whole living soil
approach I didn't know healed the most
didn't make the most but again it was
our niche that again we could stand
behind that we were truly passionate
about and it didn't pay off at first I
mean especially with the microbial
testing in Nevada I'm sure you guys are
going through it now here in California
the stage 3 I think they call it right
that's what the microbial Razak the
heavy metals stage 3 is heavy metals
right yeah they say so Mike Mike Mike
Rowe toxins on phase 3 okay phase 2 okay
so you guys are going through it now
it's extremely challenging on and early
on especially with the with the
biological system that's one of the
biggest things you can fear in like in
Nevada one of the things that helped us
the most is that we opened up first we
were one of the first cultivators in the
entire state to actually crop out we
actually have a brand no one was even
planning on having brands I'm back in
everybody was kind of envisioning the
Starbucks model where they're going to
grow a flower of a bean if you will and
they're gonna sell to a shop and their
shops and a seller and you got to
Starbucks you don't asking hey who grew
this beans know you're drinking
Starbucks you know and that was kind of
that's what all the corporate model
wanted and that's what everybody was
kind of heading towards so we got lucky
we opened up first and we were able to
kind of differentiate ourselves from
anybody else from behind us we focus on
strengths and focus on how we grew
now I'm welcome grew in me actually they
gave us presents in the market where we
lack of where there's a cultivated we
don't have a dispenser we don't have a
friend to work so by about building a
brand but having a strong brand you're
able to have a demand to have people ask
for your product versus if you just
trying to sell your products when
somebody walks into the dispensary and
ask recurring like productions that's
what most powerful things that I can
have somebody do in a market where I
don't have a front door again so
building your brand is would be one of
the most key things you guys to do and
again building you know something or not
trend but and I'm something that you
actually stand behind it be important in
Nevada they're all trying to chase it
strange so you have somebody opening up
and they're they're selling a box with a
gold sticker and this whose box has the
prettiest gold sticker with the best
labeling and the best packaging and
that's essence that's what you're going
for that that's in the data market he
has the best
and that's consumers educate themselves
it's okay hot-hot
everybody has their centers now how the
ground now nobody using pesticides even
even synthetic guys aren't pesticides so
how you differentiate yourself from from
not being presence add something organic
now you're not using or now are using a
bottled line are you going water only
are you curing properly basically you
have to do everything right if you want
to build a brand for me it's what do I
want to smoke that's what I want to grow
that's what I want to share with people
so for us it's I groped I try to grow
the best way that I could possibly grow
and sell advice with that Cosby so and I
have the freedom to do so as not only an
operator but as an owner it's a really
good thing so for like for me one of the
biggest fear is when corporate canvas is
coming and I thought I was that leaves
that Billy to smoke good quality
medicine I thought I wasn't be stuck
smoking synthetic mids you know people
blue dream or whatever you'll get the
most that year so you know I hate no
blue jean shock hopefully trainers
against it there's a good strength you
know we all know that but no one getting
that is is don't build around things
like that don't draw on things again
that you can see I'm behind for us I
wanted to set trends not follow trends
so again four years ago we open up this
living soil permaculture driven system
we were forced to go indoors because in
Nevada market really wasn't sure what
they were going to do with these new
outdoor was a no-go greenhouses were
currently getting frowned upon they
weren't sure what they were going to do
with it so we really focus I really
focused on how can I make the most a
single indoor grill and that's again
that's what we added to our brands so it
really fit in with everything the LED
lights of the living soil everything we
do kind of a screams regenerative in the
most under genitive way we're in a
market that's is just completely toxic
in the middle of the desert where plants
don't flourish and we're cropping us on
the best earth possible in our Piper
per pound whatever however you want
talking to chuck it up is extremely low
we're extremely successful and we have
presence in an industry where we're not
supposed to because in Nevada one of the
hardest licenses to get and I'm sure you
guys again this in California too is a
dispensary license is an actual to be
able to sell a product to the public so
again if you don't have that and you
don't have a brand you really don't have
anything you're going to end up being a
THC farmer that basically sells to
extraction artists or white labels and
you're never gonna be successful and
you're never gonna be able to grow the
quality that you want to grow because
gonna be chasing that bottom dollar and
racing to the bottom and that's the
beauty there's no children excellent
that we run is that you were able to
compete for that bottom dollar I be able
to race to the bottom and still produce
the highest grade quality product in the
market like when you're running a
no-till the organic soil system inputs
are low
everything's regenerative plant feeds of
soil it just makes sense so I highly
recommend anybody here if you guys are
doing I mean obviously we're here in the
organic capital of cannabis in the world
I guess I'm guessing preaching to the
choir as far as that goes but just know
that your your your competitive organic
or your competitive advantage is the
fact that you guys have that organic
back on that do your ability to use the
Sun the ability to you have to bring all
these pretty materials around your
resources around you that's huge
build your brand around that
you