mm-hmm
[Music]
yeah that's how they describe it
uh well Bill from Logan Labs yesterday
and I've been here it's a new term
that's been thrown around like the last
year or so I saw I'm a little bit aware
of it so
um you know you can talk to an
agronomist about soil they're going to
relate to particle size sand silk clay
organic matter a few talks like an
Elaine income student that's the
definition of birth uh and then if you
add a biology to it now you have soil
but so now these are grown in this so
they're saying instead of using words
like engineered soil or or super soils
or all these old words that we used to
use or try to use the word soilless
medium based off of the lack of part of
certain particle sizes so that's
becoming a really common way well
yesterday bill is giving this dope ass
presentation on how to read a soil
report and he starts using the word
soilless medium and I said I'm sitting
in the back of the room and I just
watched half the room
and her soil is medium they're thinking
they're thinking core and yeah
but he wasn't the only one he was the
only one that spoke up
um I was watching the rest of the room
from the back and I'm telling you the
whole room kind of went like this yeah
for sure so I just had to say I went to
Tyler I was like hey man bill so I can
give him some valuable information he
just lost half the room by using the
word soilless medium and it's made in
Tyler real quick with a man I was like
if you want I can explain this real
quick and that's when Tyler got after
the break he's like Hey Stephen has to
explain something I'm glad I did
again uh yeah so if you add the soil
agronomist uh the definitions for our
soil acronyms will explain soil
depending on particle size sand silk
clay and organic matter to them that is
soil to like a soil biologist that's the
definition of dirt
um so you take that dirt and you add
biology to it now you have soil now you
have an ecosystem uh so so when you talk
to an agronomist when they look at an
engineered soil uh they don't see sand
silk clay they see this repeat base
um to them that's not a soil that's a
soil-less medium um so yeah we might be
inoculating it with life we might be
trying to do the muscle as much as we
can to replicate nature in that Medium
but to our garden is without those
without those mineral sizes it's not a
soil so when he said that well then like
indoor Growers are like Hydro Growers
soilless yeah so so yeah so exactly it's
what we just said so it's into on the
growing Community when we hear soil it's
medium we're thinking rock wool cocoa
core bottle nutrients so the whole
everybody's like look at it I'm like Hey
we're all living like a living
foreign
I want the old school huge three-part
mix the 30 30 heavy compost if we didn't
use the Malibu compost we did a pumice
and then uh peat moss heavily amended we
use a clay I can't remember the exact
clay I looked the recipe a long time but
we did add the clay since then I've
added clay I've added Sands I've added
all these different photographer sizes
not just green sand but other Sands too
for drainage
when my first that's about five Cycles I
started a heavy layer of castings I got
real worried about it because I wasn't
getting the penetration the water as
fast as I wanted to to like top dressing
machine Rock uh I hadn't had a problem
ever since
um but anyway so I consider my
engineering soil a soil because I do
have those particles in my mix now I can
see again I see both sides of it though
so if someone wants to be like called a
Flawless medium or I'm going to shoot
you okay
just like vernacular it's like as long
as we both know what you mean by
whatever work you're saying like it's
okay and yesterday that was the
confusion yeah they weren't on the same
page there's times
yeah right exactly
even take it a step further though and
I'll probably hit this in my speech
tonight
um most people growing
most people growing in living solar for
being honest aren't growing and living
soil because they're only focused on
their cash crop the plant they're
growing in a dying soil using life
support to keep it alive
is the one getting us to come and beat
it right yeah so I think that's a big I
think until until producers start
focusing on the life of everything in
their ecosystem their their their
protozoa they're their fungi their
bacteria their companion plants if they
don't focus on the life cycle of all
those organisms again they're growing in
a dying a dying system a dying soil on
life support uh so in order to be a
living system you have to consider all
of those living organisms that make that
complete ecosystem like Elaine if you
don't have certain numbers of certain
organisms you need to consider it a a
full ecosystem you have dirt to her
so she has high standards before she
will yeah
well that's funny kind of on that topic
too though it's like a lot of people
like at the end of the season especially
outdoor will be like cut the plant down
and peace on the pots you know and it's
just like you take all year long you're
putting in compost you're doing your
extracts and then you just like walk
away from it at the end of the season
and just like Let It rot to die yeah
and then it's like then you're gonna go
back next year and dump all that same
energy back into it and then leave it
again it's it's insane it's like get
keep plants in that system keep things
growing so that your hard work is still
being used
yeah I love that conjure I think Elaine
was the one who really put that into
motion I I got word of it to Scott from
back in the day
um I made the base switch because I was
having trouble with the Cobra indoors it
was just harboring too much past that
high knife It's Too Tall sometimes it
was just it was just riding a fire on
any press that made into the building
they were on the Clover and they were
blowing up so it was causing more
problems and solutions so it would be
cold all the Clover and I was looking
for a new ground cover I want Brown most
for a while I literally backed off
companion plants like a cycle too that
was actually worse we had more pest
pressure down there at that time so all
right that backfired and then uh then we
learned about the dichondra so we
started pulling ticondra it doesn't
really serve much of a purpose other
than it's just a fucking ground cover
you know it's not really the hottest
plant in my bed as far as pest pressure
goes nothing really wants to eat that
konja the things will Linger on it if
it's their only option you know but at
the end of the day no one's excited
about that condo the test wise that I've
seen
um so it's a safe cover crop cover the
soil with a leading mold cutting roots
and she as well pumping sugars and
organic matter into the soil again if I
have I'm sending a lot more money on
light than the outdoor guys if my plant
doesn't catch that light I want to make
sure something does yeah I want to turn
that I want to transfer that in the
sugar I'm gonna put it back in my soil I
don't want to waste any money
dichondra also has established
connections with mycorrhizae fungi so
when you don't have plants in there it's
holding that mycorrhizae in the ground
so the next time you throw a plant in
there it can like start branching and
repairing with the plant you're putting
back
at this level so if you have other stuff
but they're definitely more shallow than
some of the other Alpine grasses for
deeper roots and things like that um but
yeah considering root death I think is
definitely an occupying root space or
soil space where Roots is a key
component am I correct right of course
[Music]
[Applause]
my experience with uh cereal grass and
it's uh pest resistance
as far as like a trap plant
I'm not sure if I use that actual cereal
grass I know these uh like Rye these
barley uh I can't say I've ever used
that actual but that's pieces of grass
for that purpose though I use it more
just because it's a quick growing so
like if I if I have a really thick crop
and it knocks the back my dicondra and I
have exposed soil
um and certain times a year I will go
brown mulch heavy I like to try to keep
roots in my soil so I'll throw a grass
down to get deeper Roots really fast it
germines really fast so that's kind of
my thing and it dies off if it gets
shaded uh so but you got to be careful
so again God know what season
um like ganja Gill actually told me be
careful planting grasses because in his
farm his aphids he has a type of aphid
that tax grasses uh so I'm just keeping
a food resource around for the whole
year so you guys
[Music]
yeah exactly
um but no I try to mix it up their
companion plants we all put different
sugars in and attract different microbes
occupy that root space with as much
Foods or that soil space as much Roots
as we can it's kind of my my Approach I
do things a little bit different as far
as everything to me is a system uh you
see a beautiful garden you see plants
everywhere people just think I'm going
around just throwing seeds and we
haven't done it but no everything has a
place in and a reason it's like it's
like a Einstein so don't judge a fish on
how well it can climb a tree you gotta
put something in the proper spot in the
proper Bowl I think he said that
he's like don't quote me
well I'm pretty sure that said that and
that's what I'm saying so yeah I'm not
gonna put you know a cactus as a
companion plant and judge it as a
companion plants are bad because I put a
cactus in the wrong place yeah so I
think that really plays a role to make
sure that you're you're making these
systems efficient now if I have a mayor
goals for example I got them plants all
over my room Miracles can be a they can
be a banker or they can be a trap plan
for my case they're more of a trap plant
for trips so if I have Miracles all over
my grill I'm just feeding the enemy um
so what I do is I just place them in the
corner of my beds or I walk by them the
most now it's an easy to monitor system
it used to be in their own pots uh when
I put them in the middle of a room
that's Clover similar technique I like
you paying attention
by them you can't help us here if you
see a pest pressure on them cool cut it
down go torch it there's no trash can be
done with it but we don't want to create
systems that create more problems and
solutions you know but I don't want to
have a I want to do breeding
trips or whatever my the problem may be
I want to be controlling them you can't
control you just go ham again throwing
seeds everywhere
yes
[Music]
do you want to do you want to give us
like what we wanted people to take away
from your presentation and then these
guys can ask questions as if they were
there watching your presentation yeah I
did get to catch some of us yeah
I got to see the um
oh yeah like the large scale off Alpha
Farm up in Montana
yeah
um I mean I honestly yeah like the big
takeaway
what we were trying to put out is you
know that there's a lot of different
ways to use the tools that we use when
we're Consulting so we are pretty heavy
on compost extracts compost teas
um solid amendments um but just showing
that there's such a broad way of using
all these tools and like getting that
extract out there and
I don't know it's like now I'm all
tongue-tied but trying to summarize
like kind of activating it before you're
actually putting it out there yeah
that's something huge that we'd like
all right because he's not mics
yeah what did you say
talking talking Bavaria basiana
um yeah we kind of developed I don't
know if anybody else is doing it yet or
not but we use it because it is a Spore
when you buy it in a packaging it's
putting that into a tea and actually
waking it up before you put it out to
use it it just you can drastically
reduce the amount of it that you have to
use because it's you know when you're
using it in powdered form putting it in
liquid and spraying it out immediately
like a lot of that's it hasn't woken up
yet and so you're trying to over extend
this out there to make sure enough of it
wakes up that it deals with your pest
problems but by putting it in a t ahead
of time you're waking it up and so it's
already active when it goes out and
you're going to have a lot more success
rate so you can use a lot less of it in
that mix and save yourself a ton of
money in the process
for 250 gallons as opposed to like six
cups or something something
that's
ten times five times yeah
I think ten yeah and when you look under
the microscope when you see a a sport
that's germinating versus sport that's
not just look at the size difference now
if you're throwing that say you're yeah
that's a bullet yeah you have a lot more
surface space to hit something too yeah
right instead of at a pinpoint then it's
got a web out like that it's like a like
a net yeah this is also just using the
microscope right so when we when we're
adding the very bassianas for to the
extracts we see them actually wake up we
know they're germinating into the
microscope and I think so much of what
we were trying to get across was when
we're talking about living soil everyone
uses living soil you know regenerative
practices permaculture all these terms
are pointing to the fact that we're
growing microbes that we're working with
microbes which are invisible and so the
fact that we have a microscope to check
ourselves like that is so much what
we're trying to help people understand
is that you don't have to be a scientist
Master be highly trained to be able to
use a tool to check your own work and to
identify the different ecosystems that
are you know not available for us to
look at with our eyes and our growing
systems right so I mean you can you can
put your mulch underneath a microscope
to see if it's got good biological
activity your soil your extracts your
your biological innocuously people
brought you samples to look at here yeah
so we've been getting samples all day
interesting things
yeah okay I would say uh I have one
person I really want to go back and
speak to because I I just I was left
their sample within notes
um and they didn't tell me what the
sample is
this medium of some kind of the texture
I've never recognized before I believe
there's a high percentage of biochar in
it because when I um run it between my
fingers it's very gritty and it leaves a
little bit of a blast Trace
um
and it also has a bit of a wood like a
wood dust to look to
it has very little life but it has all
the functional groups spread way out
which isn't typical usually when we see
a lot of um you know protozoa president
you're going to see bacterial bacteria
aggregating you're going to see you know
fungal hyphae around but in this sample
it's on the scissor somebody's spreads
everybody way out it looks like a
different kind of ecosystem yet there's
life throughout
exactly it's not typical of things
yeah yeah well I'm wondering I'm like is
this what uh you know active biochar
looks like it's not as active as a
typical soil or a compost that I would
look at more um just more space but uh
yeah and then we've had a lot of people
bring in samples but they just
accidentally made fantastic compost
it's really rare rare it happens but uh
there's been you know three or four
different samples at this time yeah
exactly I just put some stuff together
in the backyard and it just turned out
good and it does happen for sure and
I've seen some soil samples that look
you know fantastic they look just like
our compost test which is really the
goal right
um what we would like to do in our in
our living soil system they should look
far more rich and vital than any compost
products because you know the compost
reality is like there's nothing growing
in it we're taking microorganisms we're
taking organic material we're mixing
them together they're growing but that
doesn't even touch what a plant can do
with a microwave they're taking the
sun's energy and feeding it specifically
to microbes so I'm excited for the day
when I start getting soil samples that
look better than our compost
in the future I use soil to make tea
sometimes like if I have a room that's
you know in an early stage of its life
the veg plants are pumping sugars brooms
nice and warm I'm seeing mushrooms
everywhere good looking soil I'll take a
handful of that I'll scope it first
obviously I'll put a brew from that and
I have great results doing that yeah for
sure it's like you're re-inoculating
with what your plants have already grown
in that soil and then you're putting it
right over there so you should have an
easier
to a room that just is waking up you
know I'll use it to wake a room up yeah
well it's like what we do with our
compost as well like we keep a little
bit of every pile we've ever made on our
compost lot is in a pile and then we
take some of that pile we put that pile
back into every single pile we make and
so it's just like this endless back Loop
feed
actually the thought came from sourdough
bread yeah before before we found a lane
we were obsessed with uh you know
fermentation of of food products a lot
of people got in this industry where we
got started with bread I finally yeah
because it's yeast some other culture
man yeah yeah it's the idea of growing
out microbes to serve a function in our
in our lives to make something more
nutrient dense and easier to consume
more flavorful I didn't know you guys
were on the bridge
I mean
sometimes I'm not on the card train
right now I am you guys are kidding when
you said you got culture man
Ager eye products you're making yogurt
as well
[Music]
like I get five gallon buckets from them
to play with
yeah and I want to start introducing
that I mean like what would you do if
you had like a gallon and away I would
make some lacto fermented soda for
myself to
benefit to the Garden that that could
create I mean I lack the bacillus is
like a great facultative anaerobe right
like it's really good at mitigating
uh anaerobic environments right
like Iron Chef or they're like the
secret ingredient yeah like this is what
you have I'm gonna throw kombucha
and the way from yogurt bacon is your
two secret ingredients and you're out
there on a grow side what are you gonna
do with it you could use it for powder
mildew the way it would be you know you
could mitigate powder mildew with whey
they use milk all the time it doesn't
hold for a long periods
and if you have enough of it you know
you have plenty since you got these Five
Guys
you're from Maine
[Laughter]
is
it'd also be you could use the the way
if you had a compost pile that it went
you know horribly awkward or maybe
you've got your your recipe smelling
really bad spraying it with a lot I
imagine you could do the same thing with
the soil too just preventing a soil with
some whey might bring an aneurope smile
back I haven't heard anybody like
including way in their gardening
practices so when you said that I was
like where's he going with this kombucha
though on the other hand I have no idea
it might be a little bit risky spraying
kombucha
for sure
and I'll add like a schmill from a
little like beer if I can get it um
I'll take the kombucha mother and I'll
dilute it a little bit even like some
raw apple cider vinegar the mother from
that too and that'll end up in my bucket
and like these buckets can sit weeks
months you know they're fine and you can
if you put kombucha and apple mother or
yeah
but if you put them in the same
container one would eventually I'll
compete the other you would imagine so
yeah because they're both super strong
they both are like two things that like
to dominate their environment right so
yeah you're basically like good luck
yeah the same with the beer too like
like thick thick ale or something like
that yeah
[Music]
because I've seen some success
that is interesting even when you're
looking at these different k f preps and
compost a lot of these microorganisms
although the the way that we make the
preps or the complex can be very
different the organisms that come out on
the other side can be quite similar
especially when you're looking at you
know the DNA of the compost you can
actually suss out everything that's in
it you can see that we do have a lot of
the lactic acid bacteria in the compost
and under the microscope you see it when
you actually drive the compost sample
anaerobic so if I put our compost in a
test tube and then let it sit for a
couple days or I put it in a jar and add
some food resource and let it sit
overnight the next day I'll see those
you know big rectangle uh bacillus rods
you know soaring through the sample and
you can see them in great diversity
right so they have they when they move
they Bend like this so they look like if
you've ever seen a little kid draw a
bird
oh yeah those are the coolest
like
a windmill
so do you see them like different
if you took different soil samples from
all the people who brought stuff and
then you let them all go anaerobic
you'd see like different starting
faculty
microbes definitely based on like what
exists in that yeah soil yeah I spend a
lot of time driving soils and aerobic to
understand you know both sides of of the
reality and um the thing that always
blows my mind is the more Arabs I see
the more diversity of arrows the more
diversity of anaerobes so as like it is
our goal to grow aerobic microorganisms
on our compost at the same time I would
somehow seemingly like magic on the
other side of things there's anaerobes
there present too and so as soon as it
gets uh you know overloaded with food
resource or a lack of oxygen what's
trippy is that those are like actual
parallel universes yeah like you know we
talk about parallel universes and it's
like those microbes in certain
situations these ones are all alive yeah
right and it switches and like they may
go dead for a thousand years but like
these ones have like four years
yeah however long yeah and where you
have to be I just spoke to us actually
you don't want to hear anybody talk
about this this is something from
personal experience but where you have
to be careful because like she said
there's faculty at microbes everywhere
then they serve a purpose they're it's
not like they're back even anaerobes
they serve a purpose
um
but the problem with facultatives is
that facultatives have enzymes that both
work and oxygen rich environments or
oxygen reduce environments and obviously
Rich environments okay so they go both
ways we know that I'm just for people
who didn't now but why that's a problem
in the regulated cannabis industry uh
and we're in where a lot of the knife
bags are going to struggles because we
all know KF is heavily not all but there
is a lot of facultative microbes used in
their preps and all that stuff okay so
you get a faculty microbe it can survive
on a leaf surface really well because it
does have the enzymes for the oxygen
environment it could also survive but
what I'm getting at is you cut that
plant off you take that for testing okay
they're going to take that plant they're
going to put it in a Petri dish you know
what a petri dish is that is an
anaerobic environment with a lot of
sugar and they're not they're not
counting they're not looking for for
Arabs they look for an air robes and
when that facultative micro grows inside
that petri dish you're gonna get a fail
now even if you try to then fight that
feeling hey I want to retest as a false
positive doing some whatever qpcr I want
to see the DNA
um that still costs you extra money per
per pack you know like in Nevada we have
five pounds per lot so if I have the
percentage of 500 pounds to get a lot
tested that's a hundred dollars I just
took a hit on it per pack
um so even if this is something you were
talking about years ago so this is still
an issue it's got worse though what
people don't understand is
we're growing cash crops now okay so
like if you if you're using knf to grow
almonds and whatever walnuts and all
that stuff cool great if you're having a
good success and this isn't a desert
work versus doesn't it work this is a
is it USDA validated processes because
if you're using knf and I I there might
be so someone out there can correct me
and help me find this please I have
friends who need the information
um if there's UFC validated K net
processes please let me know
um because if there's not people can't
do them yeah okay because you can grow
whatever little regular coffee you want
I have a produce Farm I don't get
regulated at all I had I had the
Department of Agriculture out one time
and they didn't ask a whole lot of
questions not like cannabis they don't
care but if you're going in
okay and if you if you're showing them
hey I'm making whatever even if you're
making a compost right you can make you
can make a compost whatever type of
technique you want to do
um if you don't show that your compost
was made using a validated USDA method
if you don't track every parameter of
that pile
you're using death to grow stuff and now
it's a consumer making your compost a
lot less fun
we have like books of records and every
single day what the temperature was what
the moisture was with the outside
regular you know and then how much
compost leaves are a lot how much
compost you know what I mean like it's
insane the like regulations we have to
go through just for and I can imagine
that's why we called you guys when we
started going through yeah we're here
we're local to the Grass Valley we're
just like right up we're the only
permanent composting facility in Nevada
County Nevada County doesn't even happen
we are highly and we are like Mom and
Pop size too like we're not one of these
Mega industrial spaces I've even receive
waste like we buy all of our ingredients
more heavily heavily regulated
let's have those big gang fight about it
arguing about it and let's quit arguing
about it and listen be more proactive
the knife guys got things at work and we
need to work to make sure that those
things get validated if they want to use
them it just isn't a hybridization that
can go on there and again I couldn't
find anything spray biology on your
flowers by any means yeah right but
perhaps what is your opinion just
through a vegetation so just quickly you
guys can all smoke right now right yeah
yeah
again my problem isn't even it with knef
doesn't work doesn't it work I've seen
beautiful plants around can never
actually yeah my thing is more or less
can it work in a regular Market is it
more risk than reward
um are you thinking in trouble if you
use the non-validated process because
like every single thing I do I have to
have the SOP for my cover crop plants I
have Sops for cleaning my floor cleaning
my Brewer cleaning every single thing
that we do we have to have an sop for
and I don't think people realize that
they see this beautiful thing and the
thing is just happens to be like that
every single thing has a piece of paper
behind it and it's tracked and that's
what they want to see if you can't show
them every single little everything they
want they want quantitative not
qualitative
um data you know
yeah some of their rules are just rules
to be rules too they don't even
understand like The Faculty at anaerub
it just happened to be on a list of a
DNA sample or something like that that
they don't even understand if it
actually is going to do anything wrong
they think it could be and so they're
like okay that's excluded and now you
fail yeah 100 100
yeah how is that not happening with the
compost extracts and teas because if I
if I were to say take the compost tea
that we make and to put it in an
anaerobic environment and feed it those
anaerobes would wake up like our tea
isn't exclusively just Arabs right it's
just the condition so how do you how do
you deal with that with your current
processes have you failed or had issues
with that at all no I've never had any
issues I try to make sure I grew
everything keep it as aerobic as
possible
um I would acknowledging with what you
just said
um but I gotta be very careful you know
I drenched the soil I spray it in veg
foliar uh you don't spray a flower yeah
well I'll fail for Good Guys well back
in the day when we first started They
removed this test they used to be it was
a Tac total aerobic count or something
like that oh yeah they literally counted
any microbe like it was good but they
wanted sterile yeah so I I the first
couple years of me growing and living
soil I got prepared for that test uh so
that it's a trip
first week or week and a half you could
get away with well the first flower
development the first two weeks the
first ten yeah
yeah but pretty much before the pistol
show up
um but yeah for my homegirl that's how I
go but I'm thinking for production too
look at the facility I work at usually
as 10 to 14 days is a cut off Mark
certain strange systems changing start
to piss a lot of 10 days most of them
because that first two weeks is a
stretch period they're still in the
vegetative stage they're transitioning
to a flowering stage they're not there
yet
um they're stretching so I would say
anytime between 10 to 14 days is where
your cutoff is going to be
and then how you keep them from from
feeling the test is you set the stage so
if I have high humidity if I have my
temperatures are off now I'm setting the
stage for whatever God knows but if I
keep the that sweet spot I'm setting the
stage for the sweet stuff yeah
I'm good sure
that was very very good to have your
point of view on that it's just the
concerns I hear people so arguing does
it work that's not even like that's not
the question anymore it's just if you
want it to work we got to be proactive
you guys gotta make sure you're talking
to USA Regulators um and just making
this an official thing but how about
this in a world where The Regulators had
sensible regulations as they relate to
the microbes and which world is that
[Laughter]
completely I mean there's there's some I
think um similar to like using an
extract versus tea a tea is a little bit
more dangerous a little more volatile
it's a little more hard it's harder to
repeat over and over again versus an
extract I feel like there's certain
things in the USD where they are looking
out for our best extracts now yeah I do
way more extra absentee's um but similar
to way back if you do more teas oh Jesus
yeah oh my gosh
started from the bottom now we're here
I can't remember where I was going but
uh yeah that crashed I don't even smoke
yeah that's why I don't smoke he's in
the test
oh it was are you using more extracts
and teas uh oh no and then can have
inputs
I'm not again I'm not hating on the
impulse um but my thing is like I say
thermophilic composting is a safer way
to mitigate the the risk of pathogens
versus other non-usa validated processes
knife type stuff so I would tend to use
I'm thermophilic junkie too I I think
it's there's a reason that's selected by
the scientific Community as the way to
compost I think it's the safest way to
go so I'm going to probably always stay
heavy on that side regardless of what
other preps or or jadam this uh whatever
that I might use yeah
I would say my Foundation is going to be
thermophilic compost always like there
might be some other cool things I could
do if I was on Mars and I needed to
bring dirt and Mars to life yeah it was
a Matt Damon movie with it yeah I think
about like food it's like I cook most of
my food but I do pickle some of it you
know what I mean but the majority of
what I eat is cooked you know what I
mean
exactly not everything yeah I don't
ferment mistakes in my chicken
but yeah no I think kf's cool man I I
know people who are really successful
with It Outdoors I haven't seen too many
people successful at the indoors I need
people who do hybrid versions of it um
you know there's a soil food web
approach with some candy crush whatever
um but yeah it's it's we're all still
learning asking in 10 years I'll
probably have different yes yeah it'd be
pickle on everything
to changing your opinion when I'm
presented with new information
absolutely man I'm not I think it's kind
of it's a bad idea to be stuck in one
area
especially in the industry something new
for sure
you guys are just like
shit
I usually you're just in a little box
smoking by yourself
[Laughter]
you want down
yeah
which which can
no down
down yeah
yes it is
yeah yeah
he's got like four alpaca on farms so
he's always right okay yeah I was
talking to him about it I didn't
actually get to smoke as herb though now
you get to smoke this pie but we did
talk no we just oh you didn't smoke oh
yeah it's in the air that's when we were
smoking
farms uh what was it oh
great stopper was it grape stomper crust
I love it it's like my favorite well
we'll find out when he comes back
it was right in front of you it was very
good I liked it a lot
did you guys like it it's tasty yeah
we've actually held some like workshops
and stuff at Daniel's Farm because he's
local to here too it's nice
that's awesome so all right so fun
things you've seen under microscopes
so many fun things I think my favorite
thing that I've seen under a microscope
is we're showing you the nematodes which
are you know round worms in the soil and
I started to observe
um it looked like the nematodes were
tied together by their tails so a Medusa
head so it would be a ball of living
nematodes writhing through the soil and
so each one of them like a snake is just
pulling the ball around thrashing
through the sample and and they're all
tied together by the Tails and every
single nematode is a different species
so some of them were predatory some of
them were never seen this bacterial some
of them were fungal feeders and then I I
asked Elaine uh Ingham what it was and
she said I've observed this a lot of
times I've asked plenty of nematologists
what it is nobody really knows what it
is so it's an unknown
it's an unknown happening in the soil
and we don't know what makes this occur
so I've shared over and over and over
and over again these images online and
somebody told me about a rat king
yeah so and that's another and they
don't really know how it happens or if
it's real but these Rats end up with
their tails knotted tied together like
20 rats all their tails are knotted
together um
super weird look at that it's called
stumble across it's called a rat king
yeah
exactly so I started just it
reinvigorated me to start researching
again and just with some clever
Google search I realized that it is
actually a bacterium that lives in the
soil uh it lives in the soil all the
time and it's activated and woken up
whenever it's flooding and what happens
is it makes the very tip of the
nematode's tail sticky and so when
there's swimming through solution and
they touch and then they try to get away
right so it makes the ball move and so
you have these writhing nematodes that
are alive
against the other ones
and that bacteria really likes to be
imitate so at something and eventually
it dissolves them and eats them yeah
[Laughter]
yeah it'll be a ball like that and
there'll be like 50 nematodes and
they're all facing out trying to get
away from it and they just can't yeah
super nice and then this this microbe
like majorly comes over and just starts
yeah it basically starts multiplying and
eating all of them yeah
yep
[Music]
commentary
I know that Steve's going to talk later
about the bottom spots
yeah
you had just finished your presentation
tonight so as I was as I was just saying
the bottomless pots yeah yeah I would
just smoke about uh
at work because
they're watching they're still they're
seeing what you're up to high Striker
Farms has also been doing it
he's been using the Grassroots beds in
the bottom of the spot cool cool on
their living soil they had some
custom-made soil biochar added to it and
I was excited to hear you speak and hear
what you were going to talk about in
regards to their successes
yeah it started off by just trying to
save labor you know um it was kind of an
accident I had a overgrown plant a seed
plant and then in a black pot it's a
regular standard you know veg pot with
some holes in the bottom and I meant to
plant it I said on a bed
um
got busy forgot about it came back a
week later and that yellow plant was
green as can be and I went to grab it to
transplant it it was stuck all right I
was like that's kind of cool I was like
just I immediately pictured a rock whole
cube with a with a Little Rock little
cube a big Rocco Cube the Little Rocker
Cube on top of it I was like all right
this could work I said the gear is
rolling uh so I started doing it uh one
bed at a time in the room I didn't say
nothing for a year because uh people
look at me and I might do something
people tend to follow sometimes so I was
really hesitant to like introduce this
new technique and have everybody in the
industry bomb doing it yeah
yeah not yet so I did it happen I did it
for a minute I started off with just the
black pots which is I literally just cut
the bottoms off um and yeah you said on
a saucer you filled up with soil you
plant your plant in there um once you
give your plant two to three weeks to
filter fill that soil space um this
usually like a nice little crown on the
bottom of roots uh you can just easily
pick up that pot without you know any
soil dropping out and you just set it on
top of your soil so we did it again it
was more labor this is more first uh for
scale because digging a hole while
you're disturbing the soil that's that's
kind of not really our deal I'm trying
to avoid that as much as possible
um so you're not streaming the soil but
you're not digging holes and making a
mess either digging pulling that dirt
out and if I can do whatever you're
gonna do with it then transplant then
you gotta refill all that and then you
gotta clean the mess up you just made it
usually take us about two days to plant
a room uh now it takes us to to my uh
Growers half a day because you're just
moving pot yeah they just you just said
and they're done
um but so it was originally
thought out they were just gonna save
time in labor but then we end up seeing
it over time was that they're growing
faster now because there's no
transparents transparent again we're
just setting them down they're just
continuing to grow
um so we we had way faster growth rates
um one thing you'll notice when you
switch over to bottomless pots is your
plants are going to be six inches bigger
day one yeah right because they're in a
pot
so uh so like for the vertical guys it
might not work um that's the only time I
tell people to be hesitant if they are
running a vertical system and they are a
little tight on Space it probably isn't
the best setup for them um but if you
got the Headroom space and you're on a
commercial scale I can't find a single
reason why you shouldn't do it uh it's
lit you might need to buy some old soil
or some more soil because you know
you're not replacing that soil no more
you have to actually have to buy some
more soil to get the assist of this
style started
um but it's it's a game changer it's a
year ago less labor more yields game
over
you can say
you can sing good on yeah and we had one
row at the very end and a few cells were
not the best plants that ended up in
there and two weeks later they're on par
with the rest of the room
that Tech is definitely I'm super stoked
to see people use it because they're
gonna make I've seen like
people make their own little tweaks to
the system to their little styles to it
it's like oh that's kind of interesting
I'm curious how that turns out you know
and sometimes it's like tried that you
can like that but it's better
nice dude thank you so they're small
um now but as they're learning their
startup that's sick they're gonna be
getting their Cuts better and better and
better but I love seeing it that's what
you showed me before right yeah that's
cool that's awesome yeah
I heard you guys got some pretty
straight ones out there so uh there's
medical and Rec and it's
backwards to
I think that
um recreational has a lot more
um stricter testing than the medical
Market requires that is that's crazy
that is crazy and that's how it's been
but uh
so then that's not necessarily a problem
for
that but we do do the testing regardless
for the medical guard and you know we
make sure that we're doing good with
that we're working with Coastal Maine
soil company um
numbers beforehand and they work with us
for what's going to happen after each
run we can send our soil for testing um
and for Reinventing
so what was your favorite part of it
really think about it the honestly the
bottomless pot
got it right off the top of my head
the most influential thing he said
well that's what I can remember
those spots yeah so far yeah
can I ask you guys a question
um just being you know uh onto the
microbes what is your guys's stance on
my aspergillus testing um on flower
because to me I think it's the most
stupidest thing if there's no Rhyme or
Reason behind it um
like if I felt like because yeah if I
put 10 lots and I had a 99 password so I
have no problem feeling I just want to
throw that out there um if I take 10
flower samples from 10 different lives
I'll go to the same room save my Miss X
I'll get a 50 pounds test at 10 Lots I
will have one pot for aspergillus and
none of them will and there's no Rhyme
or Reason for it uh and so then it goes
both ways so no no I'm gonna take it
back I'll have three pops just for
example I have three pop for aspergillus
they test for four aspergillus strains
seven of them will come back squeaky
clean and then three of them will fail
for three different aspergilluses well
think about the way Spore works like
there's aspirin where you're probably
breathing it in right now you know what
I mean it's everywhere and these guys
are testing for a potentiality so
they're like if they happen to capture a
Spore on that one leaf that you have and
they put it in that petri dish and now
it grows out yeah you know what I mean
they're literally farming aspergillus at
that point right you know so it's like
it doesn't really make sense you know in
that term because spores are abound
they're everywhere that's why you find
similar mushrooms on every single
continent you know what I mean it's
because those things can get into the
atmosphere and travel around so I don't
think there's unless you're operating in
a sterile environment I think there's
always going to be that one off where
you're going to fail for it even though
you're never seeing signs of it you're
never having issue with it you know what
I mean do you think it's a public safety
your crop is going and you walk into a
room and everything is covered in it
yeah it's probably not very good for you
but I think that's something interesting
to focus on right now too is this we
need to
just get rid of that we all need to kind
of just together just agree that it's
stupid to get rid of it well the issue
yeah I mean you probably have companies
like medicinal genomics that are putting
out these essays that for after jealous
and they're trying to sell they're
trying to make money and they're the
ones not just them but there's other
groups like that that are really the the
pushers above this and they're scaring
people they're they're get boosted get
this yeah they're the ones pushing the
heart on it so I just feel like we need
people educated people to that know the
system that don't understand micros and
start pushing back and letting people
know that hey you're not gonna get sick
like an example I can fail for
aspergillus in Nevada and they will
allow me and I don't but they will allow
cultivators to radiate their cannabis
because it's a live or dead test okay so
yeah yeah yeah yeah so so there's toxins
left behind but check it but here's the
point what's the worst so what they're
saying is it's okay to smoke dead ass
fragilis if it was killed by radiation
but I can't light it on fire and kill it
as I smoke it so there's really no Rhyme
or Reason behind their thought process
and I just think you know like we're
trying to fix things like Hey how do I
pass aspergillus testing how how do I
pass heavy metal testing the problem
isn't how do you pass the problem is how
do we fix this stupid testing and these
stupid regulators and have them better
understand what's going on so we could
actually all have you know sustainable
business models because if I'm running a
business plan and I got to account for
you know an accountable
draw that into my to my uh to my
finances that's not really an ideal
situation you know the public health
officials who know what's detrimental to
for the biology detrimental to human
health to have that and not what's not
on there right like well like how about
some smoking but arthritis don't ever
fucking smoke or try to spot I'm not
saying do it but it's not detrimental to
yeah like human health yeah so it's like
put the things on the right lists and
include things it's unfortunate because
most of these Rags come from people like
you know like who just like dipped their
powdery mildew weed in water and then
try to sell it you know what I mean it's
like so you don't see it and so it's
like a lot of this stuff is in place
because of that but then they don't they
don't ever go back to like reassess
these things and be like okay did we
step over too far or is this actually
something that this test is actually
valid even you know what I mean like
once it's in place going back to it is
not something they're gonna do without
like a heavy pushback
you guys think that for the most part
like what you're saying that you could
be killing the spores and who you light
them on fire and that most you know
small amounts of fungus
well I would say too though like you're
smoking a joint you're gonna be pulling
a bunch of that Spore in like through
the entirety of the joint you know so if
there's a bunch of it in the ground yeah
yeah stuff that's not being combustible
yeah exactly because the stuff at the
tip is getting burnt but all the extra
stuff that's getting pulled through
there probably not so it's like depends
on the molds you're talking about and
the quantities right that's what it all
comes down to because quite literally
right now you have probably inhaled some
type of aspergillus in the last hour
well you've been out here you know what
I mean like the likelihood is that
you've inhaled one of these things but
it's just not in an amount or in a form
that's actually going to affect you
certain different roles different forms
yeah I mean you get to the point where
you're touching it and it's spoiling
like you can step back for sure because
that's quantity right because now you're
being overrun with it yeah
tapping it out yeah yeah I definitely
don't recognize
[Laughter]
wait guys wait but but let's also look
at the the history of cannabis so we've
all smoked moldy weed yeah
that's what it was
[Music]
unless it's like
moldy weed
stuff on shelves
I've seen people look at powdery and be
like how much crystals on here and
you're like that's powdery mildew
it's either fentanyl it's a great white
yeah
the not so great white
I mean but but that would be like a
state by state battle like does Maine
have the same they're all state they're
all aligning they're also States who are
adopting kind of I mean it's not like
they're all going over tomorrow night
and having the same exact relations but
there's an under there's like a group do
you know what's called
yeah there's a there's a where all these
all these State officials there there is
this little group where they all get
together and they start to talk about
these regulations
the Nevada guys so and what what's his
position in Nevada he's a director of
the cannabis
okay so the California equivalent would
be the department of cannabis control
yes right
so he's your equivalent of whoever runs
the department of cannabis yeah so
you're saying all those people are
talking to each other well the big thing
is they write these huge bills and in
order to save time they'll just grab the
other states and then they go through it
and they kind of form fit a little bit
change a little bit of verbiage so they
don't have to pay somebody a million
dollars to rewrite a 150 page doctor
you're talking to those people
the thing yeah we just need to start
making changes at a political level now
because again none of us like to go and
talk to these type of people we want to
be our hands in the soil we don't want
to put ourselves position that's why I
love like
[Music]
come they kind of want to like the like
hippie Camp events like and she'd be
sitting there with farmers and like
hearing directly what their issues are
like that's what we need stuff like that
where that person is like those people
are like looking around here these are
pretty like good people like what like I
could help them by doing well it is one
simple thing is this industry that we
don't like to put ourselves in positions
where we're not comfortable we'd make
this comfortable we don't like to be
uncomfortable let's be honest uh and
sometimes we got to put ourselves into
those uncomfortable positions we got to
put our rooms our position ourselves in
those rooms full of politicians who
don't know this industry um that those
Regulators who don't know those names we
can't just sit back just don't get high
first
but we can't just sit back and expect
them to do to do what we do to know what
we do without us you know working being
in the room you got to be in the room
you got to put yourself as an
uncomfortable spot if we want to make
positive change in the story
I'm down with that that's what I try
like on a Friday morning we had uh know
any better so they're going to go with
whoever's telling them it's not it's
what are they going off of they're going
off of the existing business model or
existing model so the big one that they
go off of isn't alcohol and tobacco it's
actually the food industry like what's
regulation so like when you walk into
from there walking through your facility
you have someone who's working in the
restaurant facility or uh industry for
20 years that's just walking through
your facility so they're six inches off
the ground you got hot water um your
appliances working so that's the minimum
you have to be ready for because that's
really the the primary inspectors that's
where they come from primarily I would
say
I like like guns yeah and if your
water's not hot enough they'll shut you
down for a week or until you get your
water so you go and turn up your fucking
hot water heater
but yeah this is a problem again it's
people aren't talking so like we think
that like it's oh it's his problem or
it's my problems I want people to know
my problem it's all of our problems if
you don't start talking and getting on
the same page like no that's why I love
kind of breaking silos that like you
live in a Nevada bubble of like shit you
have to deal with whereas like someone
else lives in Maine or wherever and then
like you guys talking to each other and
then talking to like I tried to get
Nicole Elliott who is governor newsom's
cannabis Czar I don't know what the
actual place is
that's probably not what it's called
uh
she she's come on the YouTube like on a
lot not even like let's pre-record it
and then if I say anything I don't want
to say like you can edit that part out
she was like I'll come on a live show
she's come on live shows and I wanted to
connect her with like the Mendocino
people who are dealing with the issues
they're like for her to hear from their
mouths
this is what we're dealing with you need
to notice and like start working with us
to make it sensible and uh
I think like because we're all in Cal
well we're in California
but like Nevada I mean whatever
it's Unique in Maine we have a real
Grassroots medical community it's all
caregivers small mom and pop caregivers
and we have allowed I think eight
dispensaries and three or four of them
are you know you know like like big
money
the green Tank's awesome he's so he's uh
his story is a recreational store but I
think he's getting a cultivation in
Medical Group oh you're talking about
eight medical stores are open in Maine
like medical office okay so like a 55
maybe 10 years ago I can't remember they
allowed anybody who's a main medical
caregiver to like develop a business and
get a storefront or be a dispensary
without having to obtain a dispensary
license that's awesome um yeah it's
amazing and the caregiver Community is
allowed to do business with all of each
other too and collaborate on projects
and Gardens and you know
put each other's products in each
other's stores without commercial
loopholes which is great so I think
there's like 3 000 registered caregivers
in Maine
um and like only eight of the dispensary
storefronts are like the dispensary
licenses that were grandfathered in from
a while ago and then the hundreds of
other stores are really like Mom and Pop
shops
the way it should be yeah the
recreational marketing is a little bit
more difficult and pricier to get into
because of the testing restrictions and
the loopholes to jump through more
recently they've allowed it now anybody
can really get a main caregiver license
wherever you live like you could live in
Hawaii and be a main caregiver and be
involved in a company and they also
recently I believe the canopy
restriction
like a collective can be like an
unlimited canopy depending on different
caregivers that are under one LLC
they can instead of have like limited
canopy from like either 500 to a
thousand square feet
it can be like a team of like-minded
individuals that have like a farm or
something like that you know which is
really cool
definitely letting
caregivers Association that they all
they meet with patients there's a couple
of patients a couple of doctors a couple
of caregivers I think someone else
dispensary might be on it and
yeah they have constituents just like
representatives and I guess throughout
the main community and issues are
brought to them and they're talked about
and and like they try to have a
legislative session that works with
this uh Team I guess so Hawaii uh Jason
last uh
September I think and he kind of
developed a few relationships with some
of the people in this Association and
they're trying to model what they're
doing out there in Hawaii and off of
main site medical systems are having
trouble right now due to the things that
we're talking about with like heavy
metals and microbiology and I like the
legislative process not
really knowing what to do and just like
their constituents would maybe money
coming in and having their Consultants
kind of drive driving away so let's uh
do you have a resale trick like can you
sell retail in Nevada or do you are you
working just through retail Nevada is
very different man they they protect
their dispensaries like no other
um they they can't home grow within like
25 miles yeah every single law that gets
free and you can tell that they're
dispensaries they know how they know how
to play it again they're they're getting
things written in their favor they have
lobbyists that they're doing their job
and they're good at it they're they're
to be honest I think Nevada has the best
industry I'm not saying it's perfect but
I think if looking at all the other
models I definitely think Nevada has the
best one I'm not the biggest fan of the
CCB style of Regulation right now but I
still think the industry is holding it
down pretty damn well
um
but again it could always be better be
regulations could be better
so you're I mean the only like Nevada
dispenser I know it was 2013. as far as
guns
as far as retail goes plugging them
right now
I'm gonna be honest I love playing 13
man nobody moves more weight than
playing 13 years of your stuff I'm just
anybody stuff they move a lot of weight
they did Vegas big they did uh the Vegas
has a style Vegas you do Vegas it's very
Vegas yeah
they're definitely one of our favorite
dispensary Partners
um they they do really good deals during
the week for locals and stuff like that
so um they move a lot of weight
um I was back to do we have retail store
no uh they do not give out retail stores
very easily in Nevada
um they they limited what are the retail
stores that exist are they allowed to
cultivate it yeah they're they're fully
vertical most of them so they have
retail production uh and then dispensary
they won't give out any more production
or dispensary licenses or any license
for that matter so so does that imply
that their ultimate goals would be to
grow enough in
I think that's what a lot of them were
hoping to do um but I think that's not
how this community or this this industry
really works you know I mean uh I know
like when we were first opened up again
we're just a cultivator and we just got
a lounge license to be clear so we have
kind of a distance yeah they just gave
up Lounge licenses that's like the best
kind of license it's just it gets better
uh it means it depends what the
regulations look like and they can make
like yeah yeah
but that's a single service a single
serving Direct customer in your building
yeah
oh you can go back and finish it yeah
all those are great questions and all
those are the reason I don't want to be
first because right right we were the
first cultivator and we paid a tax it
was good because we got the exposure of
being first but we also had to pay to
train the state to do their job and have
all these jump through all these
loopholes that after we jump through
them the state realized that's a really
dumb loophole or a really dumb he'll
start another one let's get rid of that
Loop and now everybody else didn't have
to jump through it but we jumped through
and spent a lot of money jumping through
it because we were first so as far as
the rounds go I want to be last I want
everybody to figure it out I want to see
good models bad models honestly the big
race has changed yeah so I'm not serious
but you know that doesn't mean you need
to open it didn't give us timelines
didn't give us timelines so we're gonna
have to play it smart and in geography
as we can and get extensions after
exchange tax extensions until they say I
can't have any more statins yeah
we're looking we're currently we have a
bunch of ideas I want to do because I
have the cannabis farm we have the
produce Farm um it perhaps a small town
so it by itself won't really generate a
lot of profit so I want to create a
destination spot because we're between
Vegas and Death Valley we get a lot of
traffic
um so I'm trying to do a Farm to Table
restaurant lounge so where you can eat
it's organically grown food on site and
then smoke flour going from the same
process yeah oh yeah yeah so to me that
that's the thing so I'm trying to get
the property right next to my my produce
farm so it would be a new property yes
oh yes got it because I'll be honest my
grow is in the middle of the Town
there's nothing there's it's not a
destination no one from Vegas is gonna
stop at my warehouse
restaurant right off the side of the
highway so I live on one of there's
three main roads in Pahrump the Highway
160 there's 372 and arguably the third
biggest road feeds us outside is
Homestead that's where I live on it
happens to be the cool kid Street that's
where the winery is that's where the
dispensary is that's where one of the
main casinos are and that's where the
two poor houses are so it just makes
sense
so we've got a lot of supporting
businesses
pahrump's going vertical
[Laughter]
this guy was starting one of those hemp
fire I forget who I could dig up his
name but uh
evidently he's not doing Hunter anymore
no I don't know anybody who is yeah the
one who did the best I would say is
dangerous was it just that it was
competitively cheaper to grow I think I
think it was a combination of things I
think China from what I heard China
dumped a bunch of uh like CBD crew type
stuff on which dropped the price
I I don't don't know
[Laughter]
if I heard from people in the industry
but my opinion is is a combination of
that and then did everybody see what
ninety percent of the hen farmers were
doing
yeah it was just Poor Dad it was just
horrible practices I've seen people
planting 100 Acre fields in early
September
they grew little popsicles with Bloods a
hundred acres of hemps
then they had people out there hand
harvesting and hand trimming this
popsicles
okay and I watched all of this there's a
block away from my house I'm like oh my
god dude popcorn every day I remember in
Ventura County someone came to me being
like and this was probably in like
September
that they planted a ton of Acres of him
and there were like do you know any like
big warehousey spaces we could try all
this stuff and I'm like
you guys in September are just asking if
you're just thinking about what you're
gonna do next
oh God I don't have a spot to harvest
and dry all this and then you got the
stories like you're saying the web
bailing yeah shoot yourself Farmers that
they grow hey just wet baling hemp and
then molds out and now they don't have a
single Castle what's funny is there are
farmers but of other crops well it's not
like even like hay Farmers they have
chemicals they can spray two Bale wet
which would never pass a hemp rig so
they probably just did their same thing
that they do with hay but usually when
they're pale and hey like they can spray
chemicals on it it's an issue we run
against when we compost we can't buy
that kind of hay see I don't even know
this I should be looking out for that if
I find most I don't use it really most
of my indoor but on my outdoor we'll buy
like a sudan grass or something like
that yeah they can spray preservatives
on that shit to keep it from molding
that test I didn't even know that yeah
are you putting seeds down or what are
you putting down for mulch I think
yeah so yeah you talk about a bale taste
I like we have I think the couple months
ago we scored some Sudan have some big
bales of Sudan grass it looked really
good so we got it but I didn't know that
yeah
I I imagine it was growing there I can't
imagine anybody trapping that she was
Heavy it was a big round yeah no they
weren't around they're actually square
but the Giants yeah
[Laughter]
but uh just like are you guys exploring
stuff that's kind of more drought
resistant
as like climates change in California
well bikers have you guys seen that more
drought resistant like the microbes are
they able to operate in there yeah so
when we when we're actually looking at
DNA analysis biomeakers from time to
time and
they'll tell us of the known
microorganisms the species that they
have information on what percentage are
drought tolerant what percentage or you
know salt tolerance
see that underneath the microscope and
as far as growing you know greens for
our compost we use you know whatever's
going in the pasture so we're not
um it's not really economical to come
and fill up the perennial pastures and
put in new seeds so it's kind of the uh
we're letting whatever grows each year
just grow and we do see it change just
the natural seed bank is popping up with
different plants all the time as we're
getting more or less rain I
barley and buckwheat growing in my yard
right now
where are you at
you're done you're down in L.A where
it's warm and cozy yeah
I don't know about Cozy yeah
sometimes it's quite windy
for cannabis flour I know in Nevada it's
really easy it's just a regular it's
like a business license I know you have
to have water rights out in Nevada
that's the only thing you have to prove
so as long as you show water rides for
my hair it's not it's not really an
issue
I don't know anything about it in
California I don't
know California by County yeah like like
Ventura county is doing more I think
down by San Diego
yeah I think each County kind of makes
their own
kind of even on the hemp front
what kind of California is Mo
SS
[Laughter]
a design agricultural Department
Brunswick and Licensing too yes I think
only 25 an acre for somebody to just
like
Paul license you need like show water
rights or anything like that there's
water there yeah
this thing probably don't worry about it
yeah
I'm from the desert
[Laughter]
or in the soil too so who's that to
consider
into
what's in there
just bad luck with that okay
all right should we wrap it on that
yeah Steve your presentation once again
yes amazing
I love every moment of it thanks for
joining us
now I feel more pressure than ever yeah
right
it was definitely
the in-depth knowledge on bottomless
yeah
well thank you Peter appreciate you
doing the job and being you yeah thanks
for having us let me grab uh
[Music]