you're up here in the and the triangle
Emerald triangle I mean that that's you
build your brand around that what makes
you different you grow organic you're in
the mo triangle you have a set of
strains grown the best you can market
I'm really good and just keep keep going
keep going keep going don't get
intimidated when you see these huge
corporate grows open up Danvers area and
all these crazy freakin huge corporate
monsters don't even worry about it man
I've really at the end of the day just
let your enemies kill themselves either
they're already doing it they're there
they're shooting themselves in the foot
- stand back do your own thing stay in
your own lane there's plenty of
blessings out there for everybody so you
know I've got I get jealous you don't
gotta see your neighbor cropping out
bigger than you and man he didn't lock
his trashcan I'm gonna call it no you
don't got I think things like that and I
just need to be happy be to be thankful
for what you have and try to create more
of that community effect you know I get
about it where I'm from it's extremely
competitive it's it's it's crooked
it's the corruption is unreal and
there's not a real community vibe there
and now that the dust is kind of settled
a little bit we're starting kind of
starting to get it but California you
guys have a good community and don't
lose that you know definitely stay true
to that don't don't get don't get
hostile toward your neighbors because
you know they're able to pay for their
license or they're able to crop out
there able to make a sale they're able
to do this because that's the most toxic
thing you can do is spend your energy on
that but anyways back to the Brandon so
yeah so we start off in Nevada
competitive market we did things
completely different I tried to focus I
didn't do these things to because they
were trendy back when I did them four or
five years ago nobody was hashtagging
freaking living soil or no-till or any
of that stuff I'm none of the cool kids
were doing it again for me it was more
about this is how this is the pot that I
want to smoke this is the pot that I
want to bring to market so for me it was
just it was what is the purest way to
grow
no as an indoor farmer that's one of my
biggest like annoying things that I have
to have a roof over my head every single
day and I walk outside in the desert and
we have some of the most the most Sun
you could ever freaking ask for almost
too much Sun it that that kind of suck
would again work with what you have make
the best of it build a brand around it
and just just make sure that you're not
you're not chasing trends for that I see
a lot of that going on these days I'd
rather I rather see a group of
individuals setting trends and chasing
trends because there's too many of this
this cool kid stuff going on where
everybody's kind of going in the same
direction and it's the total wrong
direction it's it's it's almost like a
sheep getting led to the slaughter kind
of thing in one of the main things that
you can protect yourself is just is
having a voice having a story making
sure that you have a brand that people
support that people can stand behind so
I for us again it was a whole word
gendered movement we do things that
support their gendered movement again as
a farmer I can't save the world
single-handedly but I can try to plant a
seed in each individual's head that just
turns on that hay it makes them think
more generally so some of the things
that we do to kind of highlight what I
just said it like we have a radar
recycling program so years ago when we
open up our facility my investors are
like if Ames you guys are have investors
are probably have done like hey you want
to go cheap cheap cheap on packaging we
want to put good weed and I fucking the
cheapest bag possible no-go obviously so
I fought really hard on this gentleman
right here actually helped me
we found jars that were the best jars
they're not the best looking jars they
actually looked like something to get
like tomato pasta sauce and or something
like they're not they're not the best
looking jar I'll be honest but it is the
best jar my opinion to store reading we
did all kind of trial and error and it
the best sealing lid he just opened it
easiest to close a whole night and so we
ran with that I got a whole jar packing
program basically to protect the quality
of the product in sight
you'd only be selling you want to grow
the best herb in the world put it in a
ten cent bag and then by the time it
gets in consumer it turns to dust so
basically to make sure that you're able
to make those proper decisions we're in
that spot because you see a lot of that
ruin a good grow it doesn't matter how
good you grow but if you don't put it in
something a quality packaging you're
you're screwed anyways I was doing that
jar my dad but does so what that was
with our door again is that we do a
recycling program so what we do is we
actually ask people hey if you're a GLP
if you have ten GOP gr7 I think it
starts at seven GOP jars you get a hat
ten twenty GOP jars you get a pre-roll
so on and so forth so what that does is
we get this huge thing if people are
hash tagging us and how they reuse their
jars with candles coined this ashtrays
that then we got people bringing you
know hundreds of jars coming and
sometimes I don't even want the pre-roll
they're just like the idea that they're
do you feel like they're recycling and
pitching into something and we have a
whole program to where we then peel the
sticker the secret that we use I use the
peel for that reason run through a
dishwasher cleaning them putting back
into rotation that's just one more way
that we're kind of spreading that
regenitive that thinking process not
just the open rev reviews throw away but
as far as the agenda of movement the
whole idea is basically to look further
down the line you know I mean you can't
just sit there to build this huge trash
piles of heaping piles of garbage and
you try to get rich so
we use what they and try to make your
soil better more agenda by reusing all
the things that you produce and try to
basically not have to open your front
gate become a consumer I try to be a
producer and not a consumer and I try to
produce without without having to intake
intake intake without without be able to
produce on my own property so even with
the coil company our flour company right
now we take very little from the outside
I mean I might get a little bit of
coconut powder here and here and now and
then that's one of my plants some
mycorrhizal haven't figured how to make
that yet for most the seeds like we
capture on seeds everything we have
drying racks for we have drawing-rooms
for cannabis we have drying racks for
plant material because anything I grow
I'm gonna want to put back in the soil I
want to just take take take we have
different things for different purposes
like half my room gets put into a dry
room half my room we just put into dry
racks and put back into the room or into
a composting process and then that
compost now gets you know used into the
into the system so everything we use
everything cut down ends up getting back
into the soil the only thing doesn't go
back and so the bug that we sell so it's
people we do things like water catchment
so indoors we have the ability to
control our environment the sealed
environment so any water that we we put
into that room we have to remember
room with the humidification or HVAC
HVAC well we catch that water we reuse
that water yeah we have the filter and
purify it make sure that our coils are
copper not aluminum there's there's
there's things like that to make sure
you look into you don't want to be
dumping a bunch of heavy metals you guys
in California had that problem you only
be watering your plants a bunch of heavy
metal so there's definitely make sure
you have the right equipment to do that
but water captain's a big one you know
we're in the desert so one of the most
valuable resources in the desert is
water we have plenty of some and plenty
of that we don't have a lot of water so
that's one of the things I try to focus
on the most I'd say right now we're
probably capturing about reusing about
70% of water only taking about 30% from
the city when they did our water Kouts
we used about as much as the average
household to run 10,000 square-foot grow
facility or residential household so
that was pretty cool and making that
they I think they thought something was
broken is why they actually sent the
people out there like this can't be
right you guys are stealing water kind
of thing I kind of had to explain to him
this whole mechanism how you can you
know you have water from air and it's
like yeah you never heard of rain like
it's this whole thing but uh but there's
often two ways like in like that I was
forced to go indoors I have a lot of
experience indoors but I looked at it I
didn't look at the negative side of that
look at the positive side I took those
challenges and I use them to make me
better not to limit my potential but to
make make me better
so indoors was just one of them the
microbial testing was one of them micro
boat testing is a huge challenge you
guys will pass that and grow a quality
product that's why so many people
struggle with pesticides and fungicides
because they don't have the ability to
grow in an environment that won't have
you know those pests those pathogens see
one you gotta be good at what you do to
get there but then you gotta understand
what it is that you're up against your
epic when you're when you're facing
biologicals
anaerobic microbes so make sure that
you're not that's why I'm not a big fan
personally of KNF except I don't
thinking of works about thinking of
grows great but I've smoked great
breaking her bills KF is I don't think
Kaena who work in a commercial setting
or they have mold and yeast testing so
things like that just know what you're
up against as far as that goes but as
far as the regenitive stuff goes yeah
just it's just going green focusing on
using less again we use LEDs so our
power consumption indoors is you know
cut by 50% and things like that just
kind of just chasing that that goal that
that my goal as even an indoor farmer is
I want to be able to shut my front gate
and it's only to only just only be a
pretty or sorry a producer and sell
stuff and I have to intake anything I
want to cash my own water I want to make
my own nutrients I want to grow my own
if I use our Falco cool on a girl
they'll feel the velvet right next to my
mind or grow if I need predatory bugs
cool I want to know how to make pirate
bugs I want to know how to make score
see my soror bring them populate them so
that that's the direction that we're
going is I want to be able to close my
front gate and not need anything from
anybody and just be able to apply
everybody with everything it's kind of
the goal and from my regenitive mindset
as a returning the farmer oh yeah it
goes further than that to obviously a
virgin in mine sake that also goes into
the community you wanna make sure that
you have a healthy community because
without a healthy community supporting
you you can't support your business so I
mean there's a whole there's definitely
layers to that question but for us
that's the approach I took we have a
voice to have a stage I mean can't I'm
in the cannabis industry in Nevada
that's a huge stage for the world so I
thought hey if we could use cannabis if
cannabis is known as a gateway drug to
to fail yours and to heroin and rape and
all these things why can't be a gateway
drug to something positive to
permaculture to rajendran farming to
plant medicines and things like that so
try to flip the script and that's
and use it you know as a tool of picking
things up and up and down but yeah
so so we did that we chased that and
indoors in the desert we have our
challenges in Nevada right now there's
there's probably 15 to centuries really
15 I mean there might be 20 brands but
there's really or 30 brands but there's
really like 15 ownership groups and
there's like 200 brands so again how do
you really separate your and they're
good like they're not all garbage I
assure you there's like there's 200
brands yes
50% of them are probably a fish nowadays
but there's there's really some really
good guys out there they're grown it's
like how do you compete with that you
got people that got every strain in the
world now is out there for grabs so it's
not like oh I got the best oh gee you
don't have it or I got the girls tell
the real girl stop cooking you don't or
the you know whatever it is wherever the
Mac one whatever that whatever it is
that you know you got they don't you
know everybody's got everything now
so how do you separate yourself you know
you again you gotta build a brand behind
something behind that people you don't
know never met will stand behind - so in
the regenerative movement is something
that if you don't stand behind it you
need to wake up and real quick and for
all of our sake because it's it's real I
mean we really need to start focusing on
I'm being more gentle more sustainable
and that's the thing too but we're
generally God first in order to be or
agenda you first have to be sustainable
you can't just go straight to being
regenerative
you have to first create a sustainable
business model is the first part to
being a sustainable farm or a
regenerative farm
so first the single business model make
sure that you can make money pay the
bills keep the lights on keep the pump
pumping whatever the case may be and
then you can start to work on that next
phase being or genitive I know people
kind of the word that used
interchangeably a lot of times but I in
my own mind I kind of separate them a
little bit sustainable or magenta have
two completely different things that
coexist with one another you can't have
one without the other in my mind but
anyways so yeah so that's kind of what
we did in Nevada in a highly competitive
market if we focus on our strengths we
focus on on on a quality plant where I
felt was right and we built our brand
around that I have a really good team we
have really good reputation for what we
do you can go to any dispensary and it's
not just that hey they grow the best
weed it's like no those guys they they
grow the best weed their sales team
sells the best weed the delivery team is
always on point from from the front door
to the back door we get compliments and
that's really really important because
at the end of the day one of the biggest
hang-ups you're than a half as a brand
as a as a as a business it is again is
is getting that sale so once you got to
get in the door of the dispensary and
then you got to get out of the
dispensary someone's got to buy your
weed so you can't just focus on the
person buying you meat you got to focus
on that person you know who's got a buy
it from you that the the purchasing
manager so if you make your wheat hard
to buy for the person who buys they're
not gonna buy weed from you you don't
seem like you think about it if you had
a weed dealer and every time you call
them hey I'll be there in 20 minutes he
shows up fucking three days later with
with fucking the wrong thing and they're
looking for a different weed guy you
know I guess it's just how it is so if
you're if your business isn't on point
it's in structured tour you're just
hitting those every every single thing
you just hit an on point you're not
going to be competitive
you