you got to make sure that you're easy
your your your product is as easy to
sell on the back end is it is on the
front end because again if they're
purchasing managers at these stores
don't want to buy your product I don't
care how cool a logo you have how what
kind of catchphrase did you run how good
your your your branding your this your
that is you know they're gonna blackball
you they're not gonna want to deal with
you if you make it a pain and I ask
every time you show up to their story it
takes fucking three hours to take it
your order in with all the metric
systems and all this well guess what you
only take this to the half-hour they're
on point they're in and they're out I
got nothing to doing these here they're
gonna go with that guy even if you grow
sucking meds and you go the best weed in
the world that's just how it is so
that's definitely one thing you want to
focus on is making sure that your your
whole operation you know it's just
growing the best cannabis but you're
also have a really good sales team have
really good marketing team and you have
a really complete picture because it's
it's a different breed out there that
the market nowadays I mean you have good
grower you have you have a grow team
that there's nothing but grow the best
cannabis and they have geneticists and
have all schools and they have a sales
team does nothing but sell camps then
they have a marketing team that there's
nothing said on Instagram all day I'm
posting ads and writing people and you
gotta compete with that if you want to
be successful so you really do gotta
focus and really hit it on all on all
points again you can't just have LG Kush
and growing it you can't just have OG
Kush is growing it really good expect
you to expect to be successful you've
got to be good at every aspect of the
game and another thing you got to
embrace is the state in the regulations
if you want to be successful you have to
play ball to a certain point I know you
guys in California going through some
things now and it's not easy but
unfortunately it will it will weed some
people out and early on but if you can
just get through it it'll get easier
like Nevada the the rules and the
regulations like even with branding we
had a had a product called baby J's we
can't do it we ran it for two years and
they told us that you can't do it the
regulations are too strict
the big baby J's is slang J's is slang
you can't do it so we had completely
rebrand our brand from NASA cube but at
the same time I think they want to spend
50 grand arguing with the state in court
and making them wrong and proving them
wrong and all these things because
that's nothing to help my brain I saw
the helmet business that the way the
waste time in the wrong place so be able
to pick your battles with the state
regulations something like that is gonna
be really key now there is a time to
stand up to him like microbial testing I
was on every phone call I could for a
longest time about microbial testing
there the microbial testing with a joke
the longest time and if you don't voice
your opinion it'll continue to to help
the people example uh synthetic growers
they don't worry about microbials like I
worry about microvilli because I use
microbials you know back in the day we
had a total of aerobic count that they
tested for total over I mean is anything
that grows on that plan you will fail
for that was a problem so that was like
something you'd want to argue to state
about so to pick your battles with that
because again there's to be lots of
challenges and there's there's so many
things that are wrong with the industry
right now you can't just go in there
guns a-blazing every single day trying
to make it make what's right what's
wrong right overnight anyways some new
data yeah so should we can pay the
market tons of brands one of the things
that you guys are gonna see going on
very shortly is that brands will start
to get bought out and I started to
consolidate and all these cool things
that's not always a good thing so don't
try to when you see that happening
getting bought out and all these things
it's not always a good thing I'm gonna
tell you is it can be but just make sure
you be careful who you partner with
coops here are you guys have a history
of coop coop
can work if they're they're written down
correctly and properly placed there
they're very beautiful you guys can get
a lot of strength by doing that so I
definitely recommend that that model but
just make sure that you're not getting
into business and building a brand with
the wrong people so because that's one
of the biggest things that could really
take down a partner
- I'm sorry accompany - is part getting
into bed with the wrong people so make
sure - trying to build a brand and
trying to build a brand with people that
stand for what you stand for because
again if you're trying to build a brand
or build a brand around the regenitive
movement and you've got somebody who's
trying to build a brand around they
don't care they just want the Green Rush
money it's not always in a jive that you
didn't have issues so just make sure you
pick a good team that can you know stay
in their Lane and back you up where you
need to be backed up and not try to run
the ship like I was blessed in that area
I have four general contractor's as my
team they know nothing about cannabis
they're good old country boys they they
work 12-hour days and they're all in
their sixties and they still work
12-hour days and they trusted me to
build their brand to build their company
and they stay in their lane for the most
part and that's a really good thing I've
seen other companies that all the tools
in the world for success there's no
reason they can't be successful except
for you know people didn't know how stay
in their Lane people didn't know how
stick to their strengths and it
basically cancer just basically rotted
out from the inside so anyways you guys
in California you guys didn't going
through a lot of things again there's
more farms more people going careful I
know how to grow cannabis then probably
anywhere the United States so being
having a good brand I have a good story
behind your brand isn't a geeky because
if you don't have something again you're
just a white label and anybody can grow
able to dream anybody can grow oh gee
coach and your book and Girl Scout
cookie so you definitely want to make
sure that you're putting your name not
just on the strain not just on the grow
method but on the whole package like
when you point you by GOP you're not
just buying you know a no-till in
organic soil you're not just buying or
LED Brown you're not just buying any one
thing you're buying a note
iled grown properly cured good packaging
product you know you can you can
guarantee it's going to be what you want
to be every single time it's consistent
it's it hits on all points and that's
really what you want you have to be at
this at this stage if you're not copping
out at freaking 100 acres if you don't
have freaking coca-cola as an investor
trust me you wanna you want to take a
small niche organic market and that's
that's what's on the save you right now
because I assure you all these big
corporate farms that do have that
coca-cola backing this at that hundred
million acres of light depth beautiful
freakin state-of-the-art greenhouses
then trust me they're not thinking like
that they're thinking how do I make the
most money how do we get the cheapest
deal in rockwool how do I mix my own
nutrients so I don't have to buy them
from something I could just you know
make my own and dump them down the drain
and all these crazy things so they're
not even thinking about attacking the
regenerative organic side of things it's
like you have a couple of small people
that will try and then and I hope they
are successful because we need more to
be successful but the end of the day
it's really the only saving grace for
the small farm small farmer that doesn't
have you know the billionaires behind
them I guess I got lucky
four years ago I thought everybody was
gonna be doing it I was super nervous
and I was like man freaking I didn't
wish like show nothing on Instagram I
thought everybody in their mom would be
flocking to this style and we started
cropping out and we started doing her
brainy way start branding hey well you
know vatted know we had branding if we
start chasing our branding and trying to
follow our branding ideas and things
like that and nobody tried touching our
soil as samples I really blew my mind
and nobody was trying to sleep in our
gang soil indoors or outdoors anything
and yeah just a just show that nobody
wants to even attempt it I was it was
like my safe spot that I thought it
wasn't and it completely wasn't scared
is here the big-money investors away
they you tell them that you grow a weed
with bugs in the state
microbial testing they give me money for
shit it's a fact so it but it works
it truly does it I I probably say at
four years we probably have about what
80% success rate failures bill pass
about 85% it's a failed success rate and
keep in mind other first startup here
man
well you know about indoor
dehumidification and things like that
[Music]
yeah we got Aspergillus now since I was
my guide when you guys one of my guys
anyways so a lot of things watch out for
man and I just just know that when you
build a brand it's not one thing again
there's a million things you gotta be
able to hit on all oh it's like a race
team yeah have a good driver you gotta
have a big car got a good pit crew got a
good manager you gotta have a whole
thing running really smooth and
efficiently if you want to be
competitive and of course and that's
where we're at right now there's no
planet when I get to it this that willy
nilly you really gotta be on point and
data is your best friend in this new age
in this new industry there's so much
data out there that we can now for the
first time start to collect and actually
make sense of so again if you want to be
successful really looked at data I
probably one of my biggest leaf we were
just talking about this just the other
day and in our grill wasn't okay I use
this nutrient liner oh I did this
technique there's no we actually looked
at the data locate this drain test the
most which therefore makes the most
money this drain yields emotion which
then obviously makes the most money and
we've sort of weeding out the ones that
don't yield don't test hide this now the
other thing we start structuring our
grow more based off of the data that we
were getting over the last four years so
now I know how to plant my rooms to hit
certain target yields but the same time
I got any sure I hit certain I can't
grow five pounds of a 10% strain you
know I gotta grow I really go five
pounds of a 30 percent strained and you
know
20 pounds of a five percent strain any
sense so knowing your strengths knowing
with knowing what the plant when to
plant it is gonna be key and there's a
lot of data out there with this new age
of testing with all these regulations
that the state makes you go through it's
all it's at the end the day you can flip
it on and talk good data they're making
you take good data unfortunately making
sure with them but at the end of the day
it's good data is useful and you can use
it to build your brand to make your
company stronger to make things better
and more efficient
so definitely utilize that don't be
afraid to a lot of people will just will
bark at it like I said it's a chore oh
it's a burden if you look at it like
that your whole business is gonna be a
burden everything about what you do is
gonna be a burden the love of going to
plant is gonna die and you'll just
you'll hate what you do every single day
so first it's fighting and I recommend
embracing some of the things that is
best you can but yeah so again what we
did in the battle we were we were
blasting we were in the first market I
know you guys up here aren't don't have
that luxury of being first to market I
like I think I just heard Johnathan say
you guys just got some of your first
like ordinances passed or something like
that you guys and finally start to grow
out here up here up north so with that
being said it's an even more harder for
you guys because now you guys are
stepping into arena full of people it's
hard to get your voice heard so again I
recommend doing things right doing
things that you know greedy people
aren't even to think of and that's just
what's best for the planet it was best
for the patients what's best for the
people if you're thinking like that if
you're thinking more generative you got
the competitive advantage already
because again the 99% of who you're up
against ain't thinking like that so
you'll be alright other than that guys
pretty much out of words
[Applause]
you