[Music]
there seems to be a disconnect in this
industry we have we seem to have a weird
line just going down the middle of this
industry we seem to have people that are
fighting the fight working on the regs
working on the policy working on the
ordinances spending time with state
county city officials trying to make
sure that we all have fair equitable and
inclusive cannabis policy going forward
because let's remember this is the first
and only time California will do this
the first time so it's really up to us
to make sure that we get it right as
right as we possibly can given the
limitations and circumstances that may
happen in you know with everything going
on what I wanted to try to do tonight is
sort of shine a light on the advocates
and the nonprofit's because here's the
deal those are the people who are making
all this happen those are the people who
are working hard with all of the
government to make sure that there is a
solid foundation for businesses to sit
on top of and actually make money we the
other side of the coin is those people
who are in it for the money only or
they're in it for their own
self-interest and they're not
contributing back so we have a problem I
think we need to talk about it it really
hasn't been talked about that much I
really just want to commend everybody in
this room for showing up tonight we have
so many amazing people and organizations
that are out there every single day
making sure that there's good policy
when you're talking to your friends and
you're talking to other businesses
cannabis businesses encourage them after
tonight after you listen to what's
happening encourage them to get out
there and support encourage them to get
out there and volunteer and curse them
together go speak to a city council and
Curson to get out there and put money in
if they have money in to support some of
these funders with these foundations I
mean MPP is here in the house tonight
Marijuana Policy Project drug policy
Alliance is here tonight I know that
these organizations
who are really doing some of the heavy
lifting they're struggling for financing
they're struggling for funding why is
that these are the people who help carry
the baton over the line and get us to
legalization and yet we can't seem to
get them funded so and it's not just
them there's a lot of people who work in
this industry every day who get no
dollars $0 but they're still going and
doing it because they believe that it's
the right thing to do so that's what
we're going to talk about tonight so I
want to start with a couple of quotes
from the people that are not here
tonight and also one that I'm going to
read to you right now so there's this
amazing woman her name's Susan Burton
some of you may or may not know her okay
got becoming Miss Burton I know some
people in the room know this is so Suman
has this amazing folks she does a
re-entry for women that have been
incarcerated and are trying to go back
into their real life she has a quote in
this book that I want to read so so
she's actually quoting somebody else
telling her this story a long time ago
and here's the quote she said they said
there was this book I read as a child it
was called The Little Red Hen where a
hen finds a grain of wheat and goes
around asking all the other farm animals
to help make it into bread but no one
will help finally when the hen manages
all on her own to make the bread
everyone who wouldn't help shows up to
eat the bread welcome to the cannabis
industry all right I'm going to read you
three quotes there fact so some of you
in the house are familiar with some of
these people so Diane Goldstein from
leap which is law enforcement used to be
law Enforcement Against Prohibition now
it's law enforcement Action Partnership
Diane Kyne made an interesting comment
here she said the Greek playwright
Aeschylus once wrote in war truth is the
first casualty his president summary of
the nature of conflict and power has
played out on American soil over the
last 40 years as we have strived to make
our country drug-free it's clear that
the industry needs to rep
knives but they are not just
entrepreneurs but that they are drug
policy reform errs and advocates as well
and can help by continuing to support
drug policy reform organizations that
have been instrumental in rolling back
the harms of the drug war while
protecting all of our civil liberties ok
Lynn Lyman state director for drug
policy Alliance you're walking you're
walking in today to this whole nice
legal world where everybody can wear a
name tag that says there with some
cannabis association whereas five years
ago even people were still doing federal
time for having a dispensary the advice
I give to all of those people to come in
who's coming into the cannabis industry
is understands a history there is the
sense that people are just wait waltzing
in as if it's just any other industry
I want to discourage that and reminded
of you that a lot of people have died
people have been incarcerated they've
had their families destroyed making sure
you're a good neighbor and you're
working with the communities that you
are based in and finally Kris didn't of
it all who some of you may know in the
room Kristen is a chair of the
International cannabis Farmers
Association in NorCal Chris DeRose
donations from Canada businesses at
Humboldt have built a community center
km UD radio the Civil Liberties
monitoring project local volunteer fire
departments technical rescue in sports
and art programs that are rural schools
that's a farming community for you she
encourages folks to get involved with
their local community by supporting and
volunteering our schools Fire
Department's parks and so much more need
time and donations so we are strong as a
group but we need to continue further
onto that
as we're talking about advocacy there
are people who've been doing a really
long time and they have lots of stories
and there are people that have are new
like myself I'm only a couple years in
but some of these people on this stage
here have been doing this for a really
long time
so if I'd be really good to be able to
ask them some questions listen to their
stories and then figure out how this
conversation so we could figure out what
we do going forward so first thing I'm
going to do is just have everybody
quickly introduce themselves and tell
you just a short story about their
background okay so here we go with Mary
Pat thank you I started as an activist
of the 80s when Ronald Reagan was still
president and back then there wasn't a
whole lot of different organizations to
sign up with it was mostly grassroots
people you know maybe new in your
community do it normal that was pretty
much it and so what we do is organize
with people we knew in our community and
we did a lot of wiring and we did a lot
of meeting and events and eventually you
know I started with moving to Seattle
and lit up with this group of people
called the P seasons and we started this
little event called the Seattle Hempfest
which is now the largest in the country
or probably the world 20-some years
later we may be myself but take it a
long time we've seen a lot of momentum
so for me I'm always the optimist like
you know every time they try to throw
some kind of Jeff Sessions at us or
something like that I'm like whatever I
lived through Reagan okay I have a
friend
we've come a long way I'm really excited
about the progress that we've made with
the problem that I'm starting to see and
that certainty in the last couple years
is when the culture clash started
happening the suits and the stoners or
the activists and capitalists and they
weren't getting along and like water and
oil press just about always getting
along because they just didn't
understand each other and I don't think
you have to be one or the other you
really can find a way to do both and I
think that that's part of what we're
trying to do right now is remember that
this was a movement that started out of
compassion and it started as a movement
about freedom not about money I mean
money we all of course want to make a
living and and have a good livelihood
and we're excited and privileged to be
able to do that in this industry now but
we have a lot of work to do so 25 years
later here we are
great Howell you want to go now breath I
don't care which one even hell's going
alright sure I'll go okay my name is Hal
Lewis I know a lot of you in this room
which it's really cool
I want to take a poll real quick how
many people have been in industry for
the last five years raise your hand
excellent how about ten years
raise your hand excellent
15 years nice 20 years 30 years cool
there's a few people in here that have
paid their dues okay and somebody's
raising their hand instead saying 50
okay the first thing I want to say is my
first detainment was in Los Angeles the
Federal Building and Wilshire in 1978
petitioning for normal okay I was with
Jack and Steve and a few other people
and we were all smoking at 20 on a
federal building grass feeling really
good and they came over and he came desk
and I'll never forget it because they
said we could arrest you but we're not
going to because there's a lot of you
and some of us believe
you're doing and Jack said no I want to
be arrested he was arrested he was sent
to Lancaster for that week in 1978 I'll
never forget it because we ended up
bailing him out finally and he went in
from the judge and then he took the band
down to Venice and talked about him
see what got me into this was hemp back
in the day and was medicine because I
lost both my mother and my father to
cancer and UCLA was studying it then the
one thing that I look at now is where
we've come from 1978 to today everybody
is fighting for a piece of the pie and
the problem is there is no pie in the
oven yet okay bottom line and that pie
is really a cake and that's what it is
in the oven okay and there's enough to
go around for everybody but it's
something I saw that happened in Nevada
a couple years ago when everybody was
fighting for licensing and I started a
company there called Las Vegas kind of
its information center because I do
things like this to bring the people
together and we didn't party every three
months and what we did was we brought
all the license people that were out
waiting for application so he said all I
want you to do is find a common bond
with somebody else in the room reach
your hand out your neighbors not that
bad and in this room I could tell you
the same thing there's a lot of people
in this room some of them are really
good some of them have ulterior motives
but they're not all bad it's up to us to
find the good in each and individual
person out there right now you know
advocates we've lost a lot of advocates
that a lot of us know over the last
couple years okay and some of them bring
it here to my because some of them were
called crazy before they passed away
because of their ideas they Jeff rest in
peace
Jeff and I went to battle all the time
on Prop 64 I was an advocate
and I worked my ass off for prop 64
because of the hemp part in there and
for to help people get out of jail but I
had a lot of people hate on me because I
was that old hippie
that's what taught me that there is a
big divide right now in this room
there's still a divide
you know and it's cannabis and back in
78 there wasn't really a divide it was
like okay can't we all just get along
but can we just smoke a joint
just really help each other and you know
if you needed help your brother or
sister would help you no matter what and
right now the questions I get on a daily
basis are how can I get in this business
what will it take how much money can I
make can you help me get that done over
there because I want to get to the next
level in business and that goes against
everything I was taught about in the
cannabis sector the chemical sector
first and foremost is medicine okay if
we forget about the patient you should
not be in this room or in this industry
period the patient is the number one
thing period okay that comes from all
forms of cannabis marijuana hemp all
forms okay I'm sorry I'm going on myself
ahead if I get Brad an opportunity right
introduce themselves enough those are
law all of our panelists are very
enthusiastic these are all passing to
people and sorry I thought were just
introducing ourselves but I guess I was
wrong my name is Brad Lane I producer of
a television show called cannabis planet
I created that show back in 2009 and I
am a cannabis activists and my activism
of like this gentleman stems from jack
harries work I was in the Haight Ashbury
in 1986 or seven at a debt show and I
ran across
book the ever wears no clothes and I've
looked at this book and I thought oh my
god look at this thing and it was
amazing because you didn't have to read
it in linear form like most books it
just was filled with vast voids about
cannabis and how hemp could save the
planet what the fuck is HAP so I read
this book on the airplane on the way
home and it was just it was amazing
much like a Grateful Dead show it was
you know coming of own in my life and
and enlightenment so I took that book
and I gave it to every member of my
family for Christmas because I wanted to
show them that hey this proves that my
ideology and using cannabis is not wrong
it was kind of a hard sell but that's
where my activists have started does
anyone in this room know what the
three-foot rule is no one the three-foot
rule anyone ever heard that it's a
multi-level marketing term and anybody
within three feet of you you're chatting
up about your downline have you heard
about have heard about cannabis it's
pretty amazing stuff hey funny
so that was my activism it was the
three-foot rule and any by had read the
Emperor wears no clothes and anybody
that came within three feet of me I was
explaining about cannabis and the reason
was most activists have an axe to grind
and I realized my axe to grind was I
wasn't taken seriously in life because
of my cannabis use I was an athlete I
played football call it on a scholarship
if I lost my keys on the stoner if the
Academy was key is it so you know
mindful so I've often taken seriously in
life so I fast forward I have retired
early but some other you know the German
business ideas I had was snowboarding in
the mountains and every year I go to
Europe and I would go to Amsterdam
because cannabis was like you were
treated like a normal person there was
like paradise
my father got ill when I came back out
of the mountains to Long Beach prop 215
against of momentum and Long Beach oh my
gosh it was like
Amsterdam had nothing on long beach it
was like what the hell happened was gone
to the mountains so I decided to bring
that three-foot rule to television and
originally I thought you know what
I was already producing some booty TV
and I went through the OC Weekly to get
ads for the sports programming I was
doing and there was all these cannabis
ads I was like oh my god I need to
produce a show about weed so it was so
the first instinct wouldn't make money
but when I started doing my research I
realized no way we're like the Jackie
Robinson breaking the color barrier and
so we were active as a base and we
became an extension of jack harries work
food fuel fiber medicine we produced 36
episodes around it for 13 weeks we ran
them for 13 weeks and that will be
season one rent three seasons we went to
a little bit of a hiatus we've been in
hiatus the marketplace is caught up our
show is coming back and we're one Jeff
Sessions memo away from there not being
a PI to be bait I was just denied going
on Direct TV last week we don't show
anyone smoking we don't show you
recreational use of the plant it's like
what equipment you're broadcasting vice
land that shows Bon Appetit and we two
kids but oh that's okay you're taking
their big money from the network but if
I want to make a paid programming by
your standards and practices says it's
illegal
we can't Bank is an industry whoo it's
just an article today I said that some
Senate bill where they're going to
prohibit marketing on t-shirts so the
point is this it is a plant the plant
comes first if that wants to be medicine
and patients for sure but the whole
reason Canada's was prohibited had
nothing to do with the medicine it with
the industrial applications so today
those industrial parents don't give a
shit because it's so far antiquated
sands burst pearl Owens no D quarter
the point is is that tobacco alcohol and
big farm that's the money trail they're
the ones pushing back right now but it
was industry they'd be pushing back - it
was paper or nylon who do we think
should be giving to us the industry and
simultaneously who should we be giving
to and when I say giving again I'm not
necessarily only speaking about money
I'm speaking about your time I'm
speaking about your brain and I was
speaking about anything that you can
give so it's not just financial so that
would be the question I would say oh the
suits showing up one of us said to me
what do you think of all of us coming
into your industry now and I said that's
what I've been trying to build the
biggest army I can build for my entire
life I've been waiting for you what took
you so long I'm glad you're here this
industry is open to everyone and every
characteristic a STONER a Deadhead or
whatever there's a place for you but I
just have one request and that is to
remember everybody that made this
possible for you to be here and to quit
stoner shaming all the people that have
paved the way for you to be here all
these so-called stupid stoners or the
reason every one of you is here today
they did something right
you know and then we'll we'll welcome
you into our industry and happily we
want you here
but you know there's so there's that and
then also I always say to every business
that I'm working with I do a lot of
consulting that it's vulgar and obscene
for you to try to profit from this
industry if you're not willing to
actually contribute to moving the needle
and if you're not willing to have a gift
back planned and I don't even want to
buy what you're selling
so there's consciousness that I think
needs to happen with this type of
capitalism I'm not anti capitalism I've
been an activist but I believe in a
conscious capitalism because this is a
movement of compassion and we're
conscious people and we're very you know
people were really under estimating the
consumer of those stones on earth as we
can in flattening me or packaging on it
from us know their figured out that
we're left harder than they realize and
that we actually care who is behind the
brand and how they run their business
and the ethics that they have and how
they do their business that's really
important to most consumers in the
canvas industry and there are a lot of
servers in shipping so don't ever
underestimate the consumer
anyway remember there's still people
sitting in jail for doing what you're
trying to do right now and we know it
doesn't Rattata them and I think we also
should never stop trying to give them
the evidence
Mary this would resonate over there
Marisa Angie everyone's idea of activism
is different from the three-foot rule I
mentioned to someone donating money
donating their time collecting
signatures receiving the information to
disseminate every one site is different
and it all important so giving back and
give s in many different ways but to
meet the evidence thing is really
important because like I was missing
earlier with my show of being Jackie
Robinson breaking the color girl we're
being watched people so I mean just
common sense tells you to try to market
yourself if you're trading in the tree
of your RAM in a responsible fashion not
you know marketed kids with the
recreational cannabis is great and all
about recreation we should be able to
alter our level of consciousness as
human beings but that was beautiful than
the prop 215 and patient I have ADHD
that's why I use Janice we're pretty
compassionate Society right if I had to
answer just that simple probably it was
okay but Bobby ADHD is all you stoner
you don't take this bill so we should
fill the user all those in terms saw
mean we should be able to use herbal
medicine
Steve Rasputia for menstrual cramps not
just spasticity or Crohn's or he's no
debilitating diseases so it slowly
educate the general public re-educate
them his Reaper manage mentality went
down eight years ago and per visit
everyone's mentality so I don't know how
we end it except everybody stands up and
says hey what the fuck this is a herb
reasonable to use it so if you donate
your money you donate your time and your
city mark yourself as possible
great now I wonder if you could tell us
about what you want to talk about the
other day with like investment and being
able to second off percentages to go yes
I think so
I remember an old yeah I love things
right now I actually had a company to
get into sector and part of my company
gives back there's a lot of companies
out there that does I know Jenny gives
you one for one into cancer patients I
know there's companies that you give to
veterans Miss Mary Jane's an abandoned
veterans program you know giving back is
really important to me I'm actually part
of the group that I'm proud of and
hopefully my Lexi doesn't take off
Angeles emeralds or Elmo's yeah I did a
right there you go and
those are back there what are the things
that we've been working on as a
community or our dispensary owners is
setting them up with ways that they can
give back to the community and it's real
simple one of the best ideas that was
has been around for a long time is go to
Home Depot pick up one of those barrels
that you chill your drinks in and have a
good Drive we're people bringing
non-perishable items and if they bring
in ten they get a prequel and you can
donate that food to the hungry see basic
things like that is a way to give back
to society it doesn't have to be big we
don't have to write checks for hundreds
of thousands of dollars that's not where
it starts it starts with the basics is
somebody hungry in need and so that's
what I'm at right now with a great group
that's in the back I know
led task force has a program that
they're putting together two rooms in
here somewhere
so definitely see Jonathan moving about
about some of the stuff that's going on
out there how to get back and can I just
learn about is what others are asking
him about is and what's lately myself
included and talking to investors and
people are committed to the industry I
know I personally do and I know she's
doing it as well which is making sure
that out of a hundred percent of the
funds that they are going to donate X
percent it could be eight seven ten
somewhere in that range must go to
nonprofit must go to advocacy otherwise
don't want your money because if you're
not willing to help this industry then
you can profit off of it you're not the
right investor and that's how I live
right now in the show-me kilometer so if
he's walking off and I've got a lot of
big investors that want to come in and I
want to turn down two of them and where
we get into of and possibly to buy this
piece of property and that's what Jack
and I were talking about if they buy it
what is their endgame what is their plan
what is we're gonna give me that because
the bottom line is I don't care about
money they're the most important thing
is to people and also in ermine Brattle
think all of us but also some of us
myself included spend time speaking with
state and city council members and I can
say for my own personal experience that
the conversations that I'm having when
them are involved in community action
are involving and they're don't look at
who they're going to license how many
licenses and who they're going to choose
how to license in their city when they
go through the vetting process they're
going to be paying attention to what
kind of giving back you do what kind of
programs you may want to create they're
going to be looking at that stuff
because it's not going to necessarily go
to the highest bidder
I managed to buy a better too great for
money but it doesn't necessarily help
the community you might but it might not
so when the cities are thinking about
license just keep in mind and that's
going to be a factor it's going to be
the criteria and you know what I'm all
for it because it's time for us to be
able to bring this industry into the
into the mainstream let's do it the
right way and show everybody how awesome
Canada's people walk right well yeah the
one I want to make it and that's the
gelled earlier dimension for entire
space here in LA I live in Orange County
on a little tunnel sets of beach once a
lot of time we have five collectives in
our little unincorporated Hamlet who's
beautiful I was patient number one
within my street unincorporated see what
block there and now there's not one city
in Orange County
Sam Sandman where there's legal
collectives to offer San Diego County
Savannah where was the salute
interesting it's also all delivery
services all black market so it's a big
problem and I think this whole of your
message acuity got it would be activism
we've gotta punch the conversation we've
got mister conversation to the
politicians we've gotta push the
conversation to the City Council's and
we've got us about this reefer madness
mentality but we know it's not
technically alcohol is more dangerous
the cannabis is literature from every
corner yet we can't have a dispensary
but part of me dispenses for profit we
can't have an optical activity of
patients to share medicine that's lunacy
married a lot talk to you about
technology as we are in the social age
and we are using we're taking our
messages socially how do you think
technology is helping and how is it may
be hurting our mad look at the everand
elder I've already had a low
with it as you know because with one of
the things that obviously is the number
to medical probably really one of the
best tools that helps really careful a
lot of our movement but at the same time
what I've also seen is like Facebook
activists we're all I think that they
have to do is like post a link in their
an activist you know and I say come on
it takes a little bit more than that
I appreciate that that helps but it's
not enough and we need to really
motivate people to do more and to show
up and have their voice heard and to and
I know people are going to do this with
their actual voice anymore but call your
local representatives and talk to them
and the text and send the email it just
goes into a digital file of bits and
bytes that they don't they can't really
keep that registered when you write a
letter and you make a phone call there's
more human connection and tell your
story telling how is this change your
life or what's happening to you because
they listen to those stories and you
know a long time ago yes you work for
The Oprah Winfrey Show and I have never
million years she needs to read all that
mail with all that mail would come in
and she herself did not is true but she
had pile of the people that we sort
through the mail looking for those
stories and they would synopsis
everything and give her a report of all
the remaining stories for a person that
got as much mail as she got amazed at
how much she actually did read but you
know it was important to have that
personal story so tell me your story and
tell us to the right people because they
need to hear it and they're not watching
your Facebook beat so tell us to the
people who matter that's one of the
easiest things you could do I write
letters all the time how I started as an
activist when I was 8 years old my third
grade teacher said we're going to do a
project today write a letter to the
president and that was the first time I
realized I could do this and I got a
letter back and then that's what started
this whole thing really because
eventually I realize I could do that to
talk about marijuana ejectives very
short about teenagers but my point is it
got a response and it's something I
continue to do to this day because I
can't show up to everything there's so
many things to show up to a hot ass a
lot maybe I served everything I can so
we can't all show up to everything show
up as often as you can and write letters
and make those
so it's a continuous conversation
so how do we choose what they were
donate our time or our money to other
organizations how do we choose how do we
know which ones to you know we've got n
P P P P a normal all these organizations
and they're all doing wonderful things
how how do we choose how do we figure
out what we can do and and you know and
make a decision because everyone has to
give their hearts right and we want a
pie
it has to be they Bradley looking it no
I don't know how that is support my
television program at five Edison but we
do have a pretty loud microphone you
know one of the way that we don't choose
is to look at the organization it's very
important there's a lot of organizations
that have popped their head up in the
last couple years saying if you join me
I will guarantee you a license just give
me ten thousand or thirty thousand
dollars these people how I look at it is
what are they doing what is the
organization really doing out there what
are they giving back it's most important
to look at what an organization is doing
and how they're giving back because all
these organizations even if they sit
there and say we're not making a dime
they're making a dime okay there's this
line you know and the bottom line is
what they're doing yeah oh yeah well I
mean I'm at these big orders these big
few organizations let's put it that way
they've been able right but the ones
that are working on the front line that
are on the ground every day many of the
business review I read yesterday we they
all need help doing all they need
volunteers and they need funding
although how do we get that - that was
there's so many different ways to give
and you know but I think what we're here
for
as a group is because we're interested
in in being entrepreneurs or working in
this industry and I think really the
most important thing we can do as an
industry is hold each other accountable
to certain sets of ethics and support
the people that are supporting us
because we can't drive as a business or
an industry we're not willing to invest
in creating the business environment
that's going to allow your business to
succeed which is why you need to support
people like MVP and BPA and the people
that are making the love possible for
you to be in business at all
so that I think is why we're here
there's a lot of different ways to get
it there's a lot of different you know
things that you can all be doing I mean
I was poor in college for the supporter
community but yet I found time to raise
money and to get our voices heard and to
put on event and you know sometimes you
can find the money if you're really
willing and if you're going to try to
turn a profit I think you should invest
in your own best interest by supporting
the movement as well I want to fall on
the IE point it was the original premise
you know IP is like technology mary said
you know they're not to be watching your
Facebook feed now I think it'll be their
snapchat or Instagram feeds social media
is discouraged but it's also very
amazing ly powerful medium that we have
to
the internet social media so you can't
discount it we so I think putting your
message out there where the most people
can see it is definitely a start to
helping you change public opinion you
change public policy the politicians are
behind the curve the citizens now but
the politicians want votes
so if enough citizens say a as well you
know people are sheep we know we are you
take away their alcohol they get pissed
well it should be may take aware of
cannabis we're going to get this one of
the things I think is also really
interesting and I'm sure that when Karen
is appear so be able to speak to this as
well for a long time as the Marijuana
Policy Project we're used to work with
Karen we were we were funded Mimi by
philanthropists who are just really
generous people who cared about freedom
and wanted to support civil liberties
not so much by the industry as the
industry kept growing and becoming more
and more wealthy there came a point
where a lot of the philanthropists were
starting to look around and say those
things are getting rich and they're not
putting any money in we don't really
want to be the ones supporting this
industry by ourselves anymore we really
want them to
when you start contributing and the
philanthropist started pulling back some
of their money and their contributions
and the more we kept putting pressure on
the industry to give back there was
always an excuse there's like we're not
making it up and I get it where you know
a lot of people really struggle you're
either going to rob through your key
trading or the sacraments taking it all
and there's a lot of different things
that get in the way of getting rich off
the industry but like I said if I could
find a way to contribute when I court
and college I think we can all buy the
way we should find a way but what's
really interesting is the fact that
since X happens we've really built this
industry when I talk to my friends with
all the advocacy groups they tell me
that this donations are not still coming
from industry they're still mostly
coming from philanthropists and with the
same people that were supporting us all
along are still mostly the people still
supporting us and we're seeing more from
the industry but not nearly as much as
you would think so that's what one of
the other things I think we call this
group together because we kind of need
to hold each other accountable and do
better because people think that this is
inevitable veces the laws are going to
change and that legalization is
happening and you don't really have to
do very much but I remember Seventeen's
when we thought it was a member
going to happen and then they were
discriminating across the state Jimmy
Carter was on board and then all of a
sudden we got Reagan and he said
marijuana was the most dangerous drug
known to man
and then we started seeing some of the
worst drug war prohibition that we have
ever seen I mean he escalated it beyond
belief so you can't get complacent and
you can't be someone else is going to do
it and we can't just think it's
automatic you know I remember when
people were trying to come in after you
how to get in the industry
I said volunteer getting all the
movement that's the best way to learn
cuz you can't get a course on where the
college where you can't now but you
couldn't send so you know giving back
this one of the best things you can do
is that still what are the best things
you can do and the best thing to do is
to just get involved really what I'm
saying is this isn't a career this is a
calling for me but it is it became a
career too but once we kind of start
with that
if you come so effective in your soul
that there's nothing else that you can
do you can't even walk away from it even
with the industry and heart it's and
it's been really really hard
a lot of the price or the left or holy
fingers we're getting but a lot easier
road to go down now and we have all
these amazing people to think but don't
get too comfortable because it can
change at any moment we don't know what
Jeff Sessions was going to do even
though he doesn't scare me at all so it
will adjust
whatever happens it stills areas
prospects and people used to say to me I
can't give you the industry commence
illegal now the argument is I can't get
it I can't contribute because it's you
know it's legal now I don't have to do
anything you know so there's obviously
that's not the case on either side so we
don't have a lot of work to do and I
think that says that the key here is
understanding that cannabis is not just
a lifestyle Kansas is not just a
medicine cannabis as much as the culture
cannabis is also regulations and laws
and policies and you can't separate them
if you want to have commercial activity
so and I'm assuming that everybody in
the room is somehow a mold commercial
activity whether you have want to get a
license or you just want to remain an
advocate you're still in that commercial
world so understanding that those two
things really can't live apart if you're
just living in the lifestyle culture
you're in the consumer land nobody care
that you're making any money if you're
just living in policy land that's kind
of boring so it's really it's really the
two together that's what makes the magic
and I think that's what we need to
continue to focus on so I think what I'd
like to do is open it up for some
questions here Robert come around we're
down to two mics so I just want to add
one quick thing you know a lot of
Advocates sure I was mentioning had
passed away in last year too that I've
known for a long time we lost one last
week that some people loved and some
people hate it yeah you know yeah and
maybe you know I take my hat off to the
gentleman because you call the type it
is yes
[Applause]
for our industry in the place in
addition I had a problem yeah yeah and I
just want to say on Facebook there's a
GoFundMe page for his family right now
see a lot of us that have been around
the scene for a while don't have money
when we pass on because we've spent it
in helping others and you know if you
can contribute put it out there go to a
Facebook page go to the GoFundMe page
because you know the kids and the family
are going to need help you know that's
what we find in this industry we're here
to help each other first and foremost my
name is Alana you are discussing I was
curious if you have specific nonprofit
organizations that you can name that can
write down but I should walk out the
door with
I am at a loss
and my favorites like marijuana policy
project and I buy us because they were
to them
full disclosure please our policy
Alliance all organizations but the other
class work locally your community is
much impossible in addition to people in
masks are possible and love them maps
organization which is multidisciplinary
Association yeah
psychedelic studies second everything
married is I like all those
organizations you know I'm in a second
what Mary said to one thing I'm glad
that speak to my heart and Aspen is is
California normal the main normal office
there's a lot of different normal
organizations out there but because my
first detainment was getting petitions
with normal that's always been in my
heart right there yeah yeah yeah I would
have to get I thought some hand as
always see you normally see on earlier
another I held your name use everybody
my name is Morocco thank you for your
time
hey so I get to have a quick question
you know it's on or maybe not so quick
but it's on the question of community
engagement so the first one is you know
one of the things that I know that we're
doing just you know for my visits in
terms of community age with is we're
plugging into all of our local civic
leadership programs most cities in the
Las Vegas area have some type of
leadership program
to either chamber or through some big
office economic development something
like that that gives you kind of like
this fast path to understand the players
you know and understand the policies and
what works there so for I guess the
Canadian carbon took my first part is
what your guys's views were and with
that type of engagement in depending
pointers you guys are talk about how we
craft that engagement once you're
getting so close with the people through
a leadership program like that the
second part to my question and I get a
little bit more so boxy but you know to
be to talk about non industry specific
chairs you know for instance something
that we know all of us whether or not
here in cannabis housing is a really big
problem in LA County
homelessness is one of the biggest
issues are kind of based apparently what
about partnering with groups like
Habitat for Humanity you know kind of
normalizing our charge scheme so that we
aren't just staying within our limbs we
are reaching out we are sowing people
who do care about you and you care about
reducing I'll jump in really quick and
say that that's an excellent idea and I
am glad you brought that up because we
don't just need to give to archanis or
organizations although they need help we
also want to show the whole community
that we could give back and we can help
support them as well so I think
something like how to have to marinate
any of those kinds of things are great
like Diane and her quote earlier we're
talking about or Kristin will talk about
firefighters and you know others as
other organizations and groups that are
involved in directly with cannabis or
not that you could just give back really
it's really there's a rule you can just
give back what you I think what we're
all saying is that you should write if
you're if you're a collective owner or
organizer of a collective I think it's
huge importance Joan and mention alluded
to it earlier work with your local City
Council Luke would work with your city
community and take a proceeds of your
donations and give them back to the
community that builds goodwill all
across the board so every collective
owner in my opinion
party organizer of each collective
should work with their local City
Council to build it will through giving
back
they were always going to be coming and
run into that path of changing but there
have been a community organizations or
they said that they can take our money
so they're scoping work to be done there
and you know I think that every industry
involves with danger
before comfortable thinking it but that
also works
Oh later
yeah 100% on that I agree with you Mary
because we've tried to give money to
certain community leaders and they won't
accept it because it is cannabis what we
found
you know besides taking good donations
when I did have a open dispensary was to
right now buy lunch tickets take a
couple hundred dollars go down to a
middle school and buy lunch tickets and
then say it's a donation and don'ts
maintain the organization you know if
you're if you're only there's donations
work two ways one is you're trying to
make give a donation to get your name
out there the other way is you're making
a donation to make the world a better
place okay
making the world a better place works a
lot better because eventually they find
out where it came from and when they
find out they're like oh they didn't try
to get their name another one is
community cleanups if you live in an
area that has a lot of graffiti a lot of
trash things like that and you have a
business in that area take one day a
month with your employees and maybe some
volunteers and go out and help clean
that community that goes a long way in
the community eyes you know we just had
a fire up in Santa Clarita yesterday one
of the things that a lot of us did was
take water to the firefighters and get
to the front line because we're within a
mile away you know on three and four day
fires it's nice to set up a tent and
cook meals and bring those meals to
people you know there's many ways to do
this where you don't have to be in the
limelight court but it works taking care
of people comes back to you tenfold
you know seeing Mary triggered something
for me mutual friend of ours did a movie
never were close and at yeah Melissa and
there's many activists out there that
need our help from people that are in
here okay like the Richard Eastman's the
Melissa's people like that and if you
see if you know these people reach out
to them
because sometimes just reaching out to
them helps them throughout their day and
I just wanted to put that part out there
thanks
I want to make one follow about Mickey
Mardon he wasn't for everybody he was a
very controversial guy and you know he
was called a bully as all sorts of
things but at the end of the day his
bullshit filter was pretty good and what
he said was usually pretty spot-on
and I'm using supports family alright
with that I want to thank everybody
do you anything else did you say all
right I want to bake my channel we've
got a couple other speakers that are
going to talk to you so let's give them
hands go to your board you want talking
[Applause]
[Music]