[Music]
so we're in the age of surveillance
capitalism and the problem with
surveillance capitalism is what it does
is it tries to harvest behaviors and
data's data that belongs to other people
whether it's their cannabis genetic
sequences or their social behavior on
Facebook and what happens is the
behavioral surplus or data surplus is
harvested by these companies and turned
and monetized so my big problem in the
Philo's affair was my initial and
ongoing concern that Philo's was saying
that they were protecting the craft
cultivators from predatory patents by
creating a database of functions prior
art to protect people from patenting
genetics that weren't theirs
the problem was there was an ulterior
motive the ulterior motive was to
aggregate data use that data to find
markers that could be used to drive a
breeding program and that's
fundamentally dishonest because what
it's saying is we're gonna take all the
data from all your children and use it
to make designer babies that we sell
where they're fundamentally competing
against the people that they were
telling they were there to protect and I
have a real problem with that
so surveillance capitalism was first
popularized relatively recently this
idea by this woman who's a former
professor at Harvard Business School
shosanna Zubov and she wrote this book
called the age of surveillance
capitalism and it's a big thick 800 page
really really bad ass book it's
incredibly well argued it's incredibly
clearly written and it makes this
incredibly damning case that right now
harvesting information is big business
and people don't even know there
being harvested but it's worse than that
when you buy let's say you buy an
internet-connected thermostat for your
house most people don't read the fine
print of the Terms of Service you're
actually agreeing to share your data
about how you move through your house
how you heat your house and basically a
lot of information about your behavior
in your house to a thousand different
companies it's a big difference I mean
when you subscribe to a magazine they
would sell your data to the credit card
company or the credit card company would
sell your data it's like everybody's
gathering other people's data and then
selling it off to other people slicing
dicing and selling it all right and so
the thing is is that it's going to come
to cannabis and you know why it's going
to come to cannabis because
unfortunately the cannabis industry is
the most naive and they're the most easy
to exploit and so whether it's patent
trolling whether it's surveillance
capitalism whether it's lying to people
about the efficacy of compounds produced
by the cannabis plant so they mistakenly
treat themselves with these things it's
really it's it's really kind of a seedy
time in the canvas business and it's
time to clean it up it's time for people
to speak out and protect the innocent
because the truth is there are a lot of
innocents whether they know it or not
perspective well I mean I think the best
example right now without question would
be five most right but I would have
concerns how about if you have an image
how about if you have an
internet-connected app that's
controlling your vaporizer so basically
every time you decide to take a hit at
weed it knows how long you draw how long
a draw you took how much was in the
chamber I mean that that's kind of
actually kind of a little bit more than
you might want to share you certainly
don't that do that with your alcohol
consumption okay and so the thing is is
that you have to control that date the
key is I don't mind data aggregation
what I want is informed exploitation by
the person who's providing the data
about what their data is being used for
and the ability to opt out that's what's
going on and I think there's a lot of
sneaky stuff going on and it will
continue as long as there's an app
connected to anything
whether it's you growing the plant
whether it's you having the plant tested
by an analytical lab a genetic lab
there's an opportunity to gather data
and the best way to suss out whether
somebody's legit or not is are they
gathering data and not shipping a
product follow us is perfect example
viola sells a ship in a product they
were just aggregating data well what we
really gonna use it for and that and so
there are certain kind of tests you can
do I mean right now there's you know I
can I get a lot of crap about my patent
that I wrote and the thing is is that I
would be concerned about my patent if
the people who own the patent were not
shipping a product if they're shipping a
product if they're doing what they said
they were going to do when they applied
for the patent which was bring utility
to the marketplace we got a utility
patent and the key with a utility patent
is you have to show that you're going to
provide utility the only way you can do
that basically is by shipping a product
or a service and if they don't do either
one then their patent trolls so
what's the product or service there
should be well they haven't shipped
anything it's what they're doing is
they're trying to do something very
ambitious and what they're trying to do
is ship homozygous seed so seed that
when they plant it you get the same
plant every time if they start doing
that which I hope they do and was the
intent then they're not patent trolls
they're they're johnny seeds and that's
what they that's what they wanted to be
so let's see if they become that so
basically the idea of if somebody wants
to plant a consistent soybean crop or
400 conventional AG not not necessarily
predatory at right I'm not a fan of
predatory act but I'm a huge fan I mean
Johnny seeds I mean there's they're kind
of an example are Johnny suit says no no
no Johnny seems like that's where you go
to get heirloom apples or heirloom
grapes or whatever I mean they they just
really they're a very very high quality
hippie run egg company in the Northeast
you can get a thousand different plants
right express themselves and they're
gonna say that that's okay oh no it's
like that's normal
fino typical variation know what it is
is Paul and shucking breeding that's not
done like AG doesn't it's done like
underground growers do it I mean there's
a lot of people who are like former
moonshiners who now are telling you
moonshiners know how to run the liquor
business and that wasn't true back then
and it's not true now underground
breeders are not necessarily gonna drive
the future of this and that doesn't have
to be a bad thing it actually could be a
really good thing it's just about intent
and what they do not what they said and
the thing is is that we're now we're
nearing the age where let's stop
listening to the crowd that comes out of
people's mouths about what they're going
to do and how good it's gonna be for us
and start paying attention to what
they're actually shit
because that will define this industry
not what we say
[Music]