and also talking about pathogens on our
cannabis plants there's also the
pathogens of paperwork that we're all
dealing with within this industry and
we're gonna move right into that because
that's just a really important way to
mitigate the pathogens of paperwork so
Hawley licensing and regulations and
solutions and and give us some
unbelievable tidbits and because you
weren't here last night tell us who you
are and and what you're what you're up
to I'm a soil water scientist with
training and the adaptive management of
water sheds which adaptive management
principles rely on the integration of
people that rely on natural resources to
protect those natural resources and
develop sustainability within the
watersheds system I came back to
Humboldt County about seven years ago
after finishing my PhD to start a
consulting firm that focused on
watershed sustainability and at that
time the government was here and the
government in Northern California and
the government was really calling for
people to start registering their water
rights and then it just and so I started
helping my community with their water
rights and within that right on the
heels of that we moved into a tighter
crackdown on medical marijuana that was
being cultivated and then we moved in
very swiftly to proposition 64 which is
the commercial cannabis regulations in
California with that there's a whole
suite of water board regulations that
cannabis farmers need to comply with and
California Department of Fish and
Wildlife regulations and so now for
about the last six and a half years I've
worked very closely with many cannabis
farmers in our community and not only
improving environmental practices but
also in complying with the environmental
regulations so what we see
here among the farms that and a yo of
the farmers that in this room are kind
of a rare practices and so you know
improving environmental conditions is a
gift that we have solutions that we can
really provide to our globe as a whole
I'm guessing the California is not
unique and that the way we produce
commercial agriculture is not
regenerative generally and when we talk
about solutions and these regulations
and regenerative farming practices I
think that really holding up the way
that we are working with our land as a
standard for farming in general in the
world is the best thing that can come
out of one of the best things that can
come out of the regulated industry the
best thing is decriminalization in my
opinion but second to that is to change
the way we produce agricultural products
and the globe now in the first couple of
years I went maybe to let 500 cannabis
farms and I saw a lot of practices that
could be improved upon now I've narrowed
it down I have about 23 core farms that
I support in compliance needs and what
I'm seeing now in terms of solutions for
regulations like I'm physically ill
sitting here thinking about regulations
it's so hard it's it's destroying
families making people sick so what's
the solution I think the solution in
part is knowing the rules and we don't
need to know every detail but what we
have I think the regulations are a
toolkit then if we know the rules then
we can protect ourselves and use them as
tools as we move forward to achieve our
goals and so being able to as a business
owner to assess what part of the
regulation regulatory process
can I grapple with as a business owner
identifying that identifying how much
time and capacity we have as business
owners to deal with regulations and
identifying how much money we have to
spend on compliance understanding those
really helps us and will help business
owners to be compliant in a way that
needs to happen to help y'all move
forward with achieving your goals and if
you choose to work with a professional
make sure it's so much personality like
I focus extremely on environmentalism I
don't touch metric I have I don't care
like I'm wherever this amazing cannabis
goes after it's grown in a way that is
beneficial to the world I don't give a
fuck like that's not my thing but if
someone else if it's really important to
you to have a tight track and trade
system work with professionals that
their expertise serves you or no
professionals that you trust me and call
in like Daniel for example handles his
own compliance but when he has the
waterboard out there to verify his
non-jurisdictional water source he calls
me and we go out and together we like
high-five while the man signs off it is
non jurisdictional water source so
knowing how to plug professionals in
where you need them to alleviate your
burden of regulations I think is really
important it takes a lot of thought I'm
looking at I hope and glow and moon made
who I work with closely and all of you
do a really good job of strategizing
your compliance needs and really being
compliant where you need to be so that
you can operate legally and also
showcase your environmental standards
another solution to the bigger cannabis
production picture is teaching the
government how it's done right and so by
complying by opening your farms
to regulatory inspections you have the
opportunity to teach Sacramento teach
the capital teach the people that are
creating the boxes that need to be chat
teach them show them how we can work
with the land to produce medicine to
produce food to produce fiber to store
carbon in a way that is very ethical and
very kind to the environment because if
you drive down to Sacramento the where
is the capital of South California
you're driving through monoculture
almond orchards that are dripping with
poison they are killing the bees that
they're dependent on for pollination to
produce so we have the opportunity to
change that paradigm every day and
regulations and regulatory compliance is
that's the suit I often consider myself
a wolf in sheep's clothing when I go to
Sacramento and I'm doing my policy work
because we are having to put ourselves
in their boxes so that they can identify
with us and use even ingest the
information that education that we have
to offer them I think that's like a
broad scope on Reggie you know
regulatory compliance but to sum it up
and go back know the rules enough to
allow you to pass the test to operate
legally to allow you to go about doing
your business work with professionals
that you trust when you need them and be
realistic about what part of the
regulatory process you want to take on
within your own business and yeah be be
really honest with yourself about time
and money and capacity and desire think
of a professional as like a lawyer or a
medical doctor or a tax accountant it's
really somebody that you're going to
hire for a very unique job and yeah be
be real about what that job is
talked about seeking professional advice
and Ruby Stein Brecker you've been
helping people you know with this
pathogen of paperwork that we deal with
and and now trying to figure out how we
can better jump the hoops and also how
we can work together there's a lot of
people in this room and a lot of us have
the same issues that come up in the
regulatory system whether it's with
paperwork or if we run against some
troubles and and and and things are
coming up for us a lot of times it's
repeated and we talk about shared
counsel as well so last night Ruby you
were wearing your hat as madrone but
you're also an attorney and you also
helped many cannabis families so I'd
love for you to talk on this yeah so I
think that number one I mean a lot of
what Holly said I wholeheartedly support
and to have an awareness of what you're
prepared to deal with personally what
you have the capacity for and what you
actually have the understanding of and
when you need to call in the
professionals and really and don't be
intimidated because you are you know
have such a wealth of knowledge and our
experts in your area and I know it's
sometimes a lot of times I'll talk to
people and they're very cautious or feel
like they sound dumb or something like
that and I think that if people could
let their guard down and really own
their power and be confident about who
they are and understand that attorneys
and CPAs and consultants are there to
provide you with a service and not to
tell you what to do and if you go in
with that kind of attitude it can
definitely help the dynamic in terms of
them really serving you and serving your
needs and understanding that you know a
lot of times there's folks out there
that will say you know you're going
need my ongoing help and I don't think
that's always the case and you know just
be cautious and take it all with a grain
of salt and take what you need and I
also think that there's no reason that
people cannot join together especially
in a local group of farmers or if you
have similar issues with just a group of
your friends who are farmers getting
problems with contracts are going to
market it's completely acceptable for
you to go to an attorney together and
pay for that time together and ask a
bunch of questions and and it's also
just an opportunity to pitch again this
you know joining this marketing
education consortium as a platform that
everybody can get behind because that
power in so many ways can be leveraged
obviously but especially with seeking
professional counsel getting you know
time with service professionals or
attorneys that you might not be able to
access as individuals I think it's
really important and awesome and so when
you go to see counsel or seek
professional counsel in terms of an
attorney I think that one of the pivotal
times is I mean you all are way far
along you've already got your entities
formed and kind of your business
structure but before making a decision
about anything like that it's really
worth it to go talk to an attorney and
talk to an accountant because so many of
those decisions are really driven by
your finances where you are as a farm
where you're going and that can really
if you go in you know either before or
after but it's really important to do
those in tandem because those decisions
are really tied together about what kind
of entity you're gonna form how you're
gonna do your accounting how much you
really need to put into that and then
it's gonna help you make decisions about
how you're structuring your business
what kind of contracts you're entering
into and all of that
yeah I'm not sure what else I think that
Oh make sure that you attorneys will
often especially when you come in as a
group be very cautious about
representing multiple people and so you
have to waive your right to independent
counsel and that's basically just saying
and they'll have you sign a form that
make sure you understand that you're
getting advice as a whole from this one
attorney and it absolves that counsel of
any conflict of interest that may come
up later consistently having to sign
indemnification in the compliance
process how can they protect themselves
so usually that's you know and with
manufacturers or distributors or anyone
that they're working for everyone wants
indemnification so one thing is that you
make sure it's a mutual indemnification
clause so that you're also protected
honestly like the best way to protect
yourself in that kind of situation is to
run a good business to be operating in
good faith I can't tell you how much it
matters to be able to show that you have
operated in good faith you've done
everything that you can to be in
compliance because if you end up it
before a you know an arbiter or a judge
or something like that in the situation
where you're you know having
indemnification it's coming up as you're
needing to be protected in a lawsuit it
goes a long way to show that you're a
good player that you've done everything
you can you've been an upstanding
participant in that contract and mutual
indemnification and then insurance is a
is a thing now and if you are a licensed
operator you have to have insurance and
sometimes we don't always get the
insurance but it there are certain you
know categories of occurrence that are
not as expensive as you think they are
for some product liability coverage and
things like that and that's really where
the indemnification is coming up right
now is really being afraid of these
lawsuits in the favor
crisis and all that kind of thing yeah
and also I just wanted to say that the
pure collective has several lawyers that
that work specifically with us so that's
something that we have is a resource
within this group already and can help
answer some quick questions and point
you in the right direction and that's a
way that we can collectively work
together