[Music]
we're going to talk about something that
has been very here and dear to me my
entire career which is employee benefit
and you know the benefits arena has
changed dramatically over the last five
years with the ACA and or Obamacare and
you know the employers getting fined for
not having employee benefits just
basically Cory's gonna talk about you
know what what you need to do for your
employees what you can do for your
employees what options you have out
there and I'm really excited because
I've worked with Bolton for many many
many years so Cory if you will enlighten
us I'd appreciate him I have been
working in the cannabis industry for
about two years now but the insurance
industry for about seven years and one
of the biggest things that I see is in
the employment benefits and retention of
employees and especially in the retail
venture to speak to is there's a lot of
turnover and one of those areas is not
offering employee benefits and not
taking care of those employees and they
are your most valuable asset that that
need that taking care of especially here
with the Affordable Care Act it's
something that needs to be offered and
there's a couple handouts going around
that we have described what those
employee benefits are when it comes to
penalties and so on anything under 100
employees in city california's consider
small group so you're basically rated
based off of your age in their zip code
anything above 100 employees to get
composite rating and much better rates
and sometimes much better benefits so
one thing that we have done is partnered
with Oaksterdam University that has an
association called Oaksterdam Business
Association that has created a
composite rating for small group
employers to give them access to large
group health benefits and rates and just
to give you an example is most small
group benefits as its rated based off of
age if you were paying and this is an
example full disclaimer if you're paying
let's say $400 a month for this employee
in a small group and a large group it
may be 189 or $200 which is a big
savings for small businesses out there
so it's definitely important to learn
and understand what the employee
benefits are and what's available to us
and when you're looking at getting
benefits for your staff it is an amazing
retention tool but it is a cost to the
company and so it's really a great idea
to speak with somebody like Cory that
can really help you understand you know
how you can structure it so that maybe
it's not so you know damaging to the
company finances or if you're doing
really really well like I know all of
you are doing and maybe you could be a
little bit more giving you know to your
staff which trust me they appreciate a
lot of people out there even with the
ACA they don't have benefits they can't
afford it
California care it's very expensive if
you're really young and really healthy
you get great rates but the older you
get the more you have to pay it's just
it's an unfortunate truth so talking to
a broker somebody like Cory is so
invaluable even if you're just thinking
about it you know go into your thought
process with with some really good
information behind you and so now we can
talk about sure we can talk about going
into a retail and bringing it all
together right now we're kind of on the
smaller end of not doing that 100
employees but it's still really
important to be thinking like he
mentioned in terms turnover that as
you're bringing people into this
industry what's gonna keep them here
what's gonna keep them growing what's
gonna turn them into tomorrow's leaders
right instead of turning them frustrated
right away we're running out the door
because it's crazy right
but it's some businesses mate might not
feel ready yet for things like health
benefits but there's also some other
creative benefits that you can move
towards to start getting yourself there
as as you budget for
a little bit more stability for
employees we have partnered with an HR
company that offers things like employee
assistance programs so maybe that's not
full on health benefits but if you have
somebody dealing with a specific issue
they can reach out and get some support
so there are benefits like that
mentioned or even things like flex time
with your scheduling or paid time off
that can't show your staff that you do
appreciate that they're here for you and
that you're here for them as well so
even if you feel as though your business
that's maybe not ready to start
investing in things like health
insurance vision dental all that good
stuff there's definitely some creative
solutions that you can make your company
more competitive to bring people to your
place and working their talents for you
and somebody you would touch a little
bit in the last panel about this
transition from the great market if you
will to the new legal market and I think
that this is a really important place to
have some of these conversations because
what we were doing before again I don't
think people were intentionally doing
things wrong they just maybe didn't have
to do things a certain way but now that
you guys are reading through the
regulations we see that labor law
violations are serious violations so
getting to know your labor codes and
doing all that is something that's
really important now that maybe it was
easy to gloss over before so I think as
a retailer manufacturer whoever you are
to stop looking at yourself is a
cannabis business that applies to
cannabis rules and start imagining what
it would be like if you were selling or
manufacturing you're totally normal
products know what what kinds of things
as a retailer would you have to abide by
and instead of going to cannabis
regulations you'd be going to the labor
code to the business and Professions
Code so looking to these places and
pretending like we're any other industry
is a really great place to start what do
you see as far as the day-to-day
challenges in the industry sure so the
challenge is twofold in this transition
right we have employers who have done
things a certain way for a long time who
are maybe afraid to change procedure and
this is a good strategy in some ways
because you know when you're constantly
changing policies that's bad for
employee morale and right now we kind of
have these what's what's the law what's
not in cannabis well the good thing
about HR is there's not a whole lot of
questions about what the law is
California labor laws are easy to find
so figuring out what that is allows you
to to be compliant in that way almost
right away these are things that are not
going to change in another two months
so there's sometimes resistance from
employers in that way well hey I've
always paid people cash at the end of
the day so I just want to stay doing
that before you know things change again
well that's not something that's gonna
change in 2019 we're still gonna have to
abide by the labor laws so I think that
that's really important we do often see
it resistance from employees to certain
people who are coming to the industry
before wanted benefits if you will like
not having a show up to work on time or
being able to be medicated all the time
getting paid cash at the end of the day
so those were some people consider those
things benefits and the transition to
know you're gonna get direct deposit
every two weeks and I'm gonna take out
your taxes and pay my payroll taxes
these are difficult transitions and for
me I keep coming up with transitional
strategies right so for both my
employers and my employees this might
not be what it is forever but this is
what we're gonna try now to get to a
more compliant place so taking those
baby steps is a lot easier for people
than recreating your entire business
model overnight I have
personal knowledge of a cannabis broker
who buries his money in his backyard I
don't know if he does it today but I
know that if he ever moves I know where
I'm gonna start digging because it's a
lot of money but I know that that's how
people were keeping their money because
they couldn't put it in the bank they
couldn't do anything traditional with it
and so now the thought of paying taxes
on that money that's gotta be
mind-blowing because you got that free
and clear but now you you're you're
legal you're in the system so you know
we we have to pay taxes all of us do you
know I I don't like it either but you
know you just have to help everybody
make that transition and I think we can
help you and you know you may have
questions and you may get really really
angry it to babies because it's the way
you've always done it and nobody should
be able to tell you how to run your
business and I gotta say sorry Uncle Sam
he tells us how to run our business I
briefly touched on it so it is as I
mentioned a health insurance platform so
you get employee benefits medical dental
life vision long term disability short
term disability and a few other benefits
that is for the employees of small
businesses and what that does is it
gives small businesses the opportunity
to offer health benefits but they are
large group health benefits so it's like
if you have 2,000 employees you're
getting benefits as if you have 2,000
employees even though you may only have
10 employees so the very broad benefits
and they are affordable as well so right
now what we're working on Patrick back
here he is working with me on this we
would collect information on the
employer and the employees and we will
submit to the healthcare
and look at rates and it should be going
live November first so there's a couple
handouts one is on health care but also
one is on coverages that are very
important for the cannabis industry and
there's a lot of manufacturers
distributors growers etc and how to
protect that product and protect your
assets in some of those handouts my
contact information is on there and it
just kind of gives you some descriptions
on what those coverages are and why
they're important so take a look at
those because I know
LA County in itself is requiring certain
coverages to be able to get the license
so just just look at that and be aware
of that before going in to apply for
those licenses
regulations wire
but as a retailer I've noticed one of
your strongest strengths for good morale
and efficiency is to have very accurate
job descriptions so instead of having
people who fit you know oh hi you're my
employee and you're gonna do all of
these things for me it's actually a
little bit easier to have an
organizational structure that supports
this is your role and your expertise and
and to fit people into that and to grow
out those places now I understand that
not everybody is necessarily ready for
that so I'll move on to you guys first
more maybe legal advice but just in
general I feel like I've seen people
thrive a lot more when they have when
the expectations are very clear about
what they're supposed to be for
multi-state employees and I'm gonna just
address this from a payroll point of
view when you're paying your folks in
different states you have to abide by
those payroll laws within that state so
if cannabis was not legal in another
state I'm not sure how that would work
as far as
I'm sure it would be fine no no no no no
your life in 70 if you're a licensed
entity that you you have a life in the
next state but it's it's fair you could
have a entity that serves another
purpose for your corporate structure and
potentially is not analyzing state so
okay you can have a Salas important
sales rep that lives in I some other
state that's not like George's Georgia
and and so they when you release their
checks you release them based on
Georgia's taxes and you have to fall
under Georgia's legal like employee laws
but even though that they they probably
work in multi states so I don't know if
that would be a huge issue at this point
in time but it's something to remember
and consider Cordia every corporate
strategy you'd like to share with us
perhaps we have a license energy in
Nevada and in California and then we
have a call center in Michigan so the
way we did on the insurance standpoint
on the risk management is we different
state we'd write a different policy from
each state just because crossing state
lines obviously can't do that and a lot
of other things within the insurance
side that's what we would do but keep in
mind
aside from that on the health insurance
side if you have over 50 employees
whether you're local or you're
multi-state you are subject to the
Affordable Care Act and the penalties
that they have as well so I can't tell
you how many cannabis accounts that are
being acquired or all over the place
that may have 100 employees and they
don't offer employee benefits it could
literally the business overnight
if if there was an issue
in the state of California is there a
threshold the never employees that you
would want to have from that perspective
so if you have over full 50 full-time
equivalent employees and there's some
information on that on the handout you
are subject to the Affordable Care Act
and offering you have to offer benefits
if you have 50 full-time equivalent
employees may we all be in that position
Brett you have a question
[Music]
it's called outsourcing and benefit
businesses now our are looking at the
need for having in-house because when
you have somebody in-house and under
your employment then you're paying your
payroll taxes and you're having to give
them sick leave and a you know benefits
so a lot of times like for my services
small companies would absolutely not
need a full-time HR person that would
absolutely not be financially
responsible I don't think because it's
something that you know once I get in
and get you compliant on an ongoing
basis it's a very simple thing so I from
my point of view I'm seeing a lot of
outsourcing out there to touch on the
management company is very common we'll
see most of the distribution companies
manufacturers all of them in separate
entities from the wrist side depending
on the common ownership we can structure
that and that's fine to protect that
business but it still correlates with
the common ownership when it comes to
the ACA Affordable Care Act
here
this is a question about transitioning
in our industry and this is open to all
of our panelists but the question was
about integrating the OD our original
data that would be individuals have been
in the industry for potentially 20-plus
years or longer legacy cultivators for
example and then those individuals who
see the re rush and want to be a part of
this flourishing industry the greatest
fastest growing industry of our day how
do we bring them together to work as a
cohesive group towards the common goal
of the corporation or the entity of
maybe and the team so um I like to refer
to these as start overs instead of
startups because you have to deal with
the legacy and the OGS and that is
probably one of the most difficult
things to deal with because you have the
attitude of it's always been done this
way versus you know somebody coming in
and saying we can make it better so I
what I recommend is that you could
change management a strategy in place
and you really try and respect both
sides it's very easy to say you know
well you've been here for forever and
you just don't know how to change your
way of thinking and they really do some
people you know to be brutally honest
some people won't make the cut they
won't last but if you if you have a
really strong respect for your old
employees and I talked time served
never age and the incoming employees and
you really try to get them to
gather and you put together a strategy
that everyone can agree on and then you
monitor it and you really make it you
you help them understand why it's
necessary and the more you communicate
with them the more apt they are to
change so you just have to pay a little
bit more attention and I guarantee in
the long run they're probably beneficial
I definitely want to touch on this
because I've had some very real
experience with this as a retailer and I
would definitely second what you were
saying about making really clear
expectations and and communicating that
I feel like there's a lot of if first of
all if the new people coming in one in
on the green rush they're definitely
gonna have to understand that its
patrons first because all of us
retailers manufacturers regulators who
do we work for right it's these people
who are trying to come in and get access
the people who fought for medical
cannabis and it voted for adult use
cannabis so we have to make sure that
that first and foremost were this is not
about us as employees this is about
those patrons and and a retailer you are
absolutely dealing with that on the
front line so I think that integrating
those two different ideas is really
important and I would go a step further
and say that diversity within your staff
is is essential because cannabis you
know there's with the exception maybe of
Oaksterdam University there's nowhere
you can go to like get groomed for
canvas right some people are gonna learn
it in the gray market some people are
gonna come in brand new here but the
idea that everybody has a different
experience with this plant and has a
different experience maybe from another
industry that they're gonna bring a lot
of strengths so if you're new people
think they understand what's going on
and they're not going to listen to your
older employees they're gonna miss out
on a lot of valuable knowledge about the
history of how we got here which is
really important but and I also think at
the same time if you've got people who
are like no I'm only gonna work here if
I can get cash at the end of the day and
like Deb well I stand here
yeah they're they're not gonna make it
because I say this all the time are the
biggest misconceptions in the cannabis
industry is that beanie budtender or
customers cisgender whatever your store
calls it is an unskilled position right
these people need to understand body
systems complex regulatory systems and
product life that change Oh what every
two weeks lately but somehow it feels
right so if you're gonna have people
coming in here they're they're gonna
have to be people who are engaged and I
think that you can find these people
from all kinds of walks of life so
coming in as if manager and saying hey
these are my expectations and all of
these people from diverse populations
have to succumb to this I think you're
really gonna see a lot of strengths and
and listen to your staff as well you
know sit down with them and say hey
maybe I'm newer to this and you've been
in this for five years what can we learn
from each other cuz maybe I'll learn
something from somebody who's been in
cannabis for 15 years and they're gonna
learn something from my experience which
comes from an outside industry so I
think that this is a great strength that
we have here when we're building
something you know 10 years from now it
might be oh yeah it's just this guy went
to Canada's college so he's a shoo-in
we're right now we can actually build
some of these relationships that create
a stronger workforce and diversity is
literally written into these regulations
so I think that this is important not
just from OG cannabis people to the
newcomers but all across the board we
have to make sure that everybody's
voices are being heard and we're using
our best ideas if you're hearing it for
the green rush I think you're gonna find
that the community does not support you
in that effort if you're in it to to
bring medicine and help people and to
restore the medical access that we had
prior to Prohibition then you're gonna
find that people come out in big numbers
to help you build something
ya know Peterson Thank You Santa Monica
task force is a holding resolution they
would like your signatures I am a
contributing member they're one of our
industry partners so if you have
information that you'd like to garner
you can assist you with that and you can
also sign up resolution here in Santa
Monica we do have a unique experience
and that we don't have any retailer not
medical not adult use an ordinance was
passed in 2015
authorizing to retailers and as of right
now we've had a holdup with Live Scan
those what I call winners not been yet
announced but stay tuned we will have
access to medical cannabis here in Santa
Monica very soon and potentially the
sama task force will be able to provide
some crucial information regarding
public safety I spoke to the city of
commerce this past week and we talked
about medical cannabis and the audience
really wanted to provide some Q&amp;A
feedback because they wanted more
information about public safety and some
of the questions were you know how is
how is cannabis use affecting the number
of accidents on the road and
unfortunately these are very
controversial questions the answers to
which are debatable according to the
source and we've just been just been
legal for adult use here since January
we just got our regulations so having
that data and be able to report on it
it's quite difficult but potentially we
can put that together and we'll be able
to communicate more succinctly on issues
pertaining to public safety in the
future all right gentleman in the back
follow-up question
we want to work with both mom-and-pop
entities we also want to work with some
the larger corporations we're seeing
that mom-and-pop and a teaser may be
having a difficult time with cash flow
and be able to purchase our emojis or
many orders how do we provide a more
level playing field for both mom and
pops and those larger corporations so as
a buyer with your company among many
other companies is consistent
communication like when I reach out to
you get back to me let me know what you
have in stock right now everybody has
varying amounts of product in stock from
stores to distributors to vendors like
as soon as you know something even if
you're knowing that that week hey I
still don't know where we're at like
communicate that with us like keep your
leaf link up today you know that's a big
issue as many of us use leaf link or
cannily or handshake and all these
different you know platforms to allow us
to order like keep that stuff up to date
me to go place an order on there and
then you call me back or you shoot me a
text which I've asked you to email me so
really everybody is the distributor and
the painter question is this step of
your daily communication we're talking
about HR and staffing right and all of a
sudden we're gonna talk about
distribution think this industry is
really interesting because we have the
choice to make some ethical choices
right so you're sitting here and now you
as a distributor have have choices to
make I have X amount of product you can
determine you know how can I can I
increase maybe for these corporate
clients who have a lot of cash flow and
money to burn and they're like they
don't have as tight of a budget
and can I use that business to literally
sustain maybe something that's a little
bit near and dear to my heart which is
supporting mom-and-pop businesses so
maybe as a distributor that's really
important to you there's different ways
to make this decision you know some
purchasers are saying you know well it's
not only enough to have good product at
a good price point you also need to make
sure that everybody on your staff is
helped these moral and ethical standards
right so there's purchasers all over the
place that are making stamps like that
and so I think distributors can do an
equal thing you know if you know ok well
that person can order tens of thousands
of cartridges at one time so obviously
they're able to get that lower price
point what can you do to make that money
work for these smaller businesses who's
something that you want to see in your
industry somebody that you want to see
on your corner
you know if you guys as distributors
don't only want to see Walmart's of
cannabis well then guess what you know
you're gonna have to build into your
business model how am I gonna be sure to
protect the little guy if you will and
so I think instead of instead of
wondering how small businesses are gonna
be able to compete with large ones think
well what can I do to make my business
more attractive to these to these
smaller companies so maybe you don't
offer net 15 to big corporations offer
it instead to the mom-and-pop who you
trust I am preparing for this event this
evening actually had a similar
conversation with someone and it was
kind of a debate of you know well are
the retailers in LA mom and pop
organizations I mean I got a rose
caregivers for example they got bought I
think maybe six months ago a lot of the
shops are getting purchased by bigger
companies so it kind of made me question
a little are they mom pops and the
answer on the other side of this
conversation was yes many of these
retailers here in LA have been in the
industry
for 15-20 years they are monocots and
it's been difficult to maintain their
storefronts in the face of regulations
in the face of a declining consumer base
in the face of all these these new
things that we have to adapt so they are
now pops and if there is a way to
support those entities that you think
could use a leg up then yes absolutely
let's do it we have a orders but smaller
orders more frequently and looking more
regional hubs where folks largest
distributors can now bring that product
and
did store it somewhere and then purchase
smaller quantities and do like route
that's a great point he just pointed out
that distribution companies are actually
required to store their inventory in
warehouses and potentially they could be
dispatching that in smaller orders
retailers historically have a difficult
time managing inventory or holding
inventory in what is a small retail
space and they typically prefer to have
more of a turnover so they're ordering
smaller smaller orders more frequently I
think that's a great solution thank you
oh right here
all of the above absolutely I think that
I am somebody who's very excited for the
regulated market I love the idea of lab
tests of cannabis and all of these
different things but absolutely throwing
a whole new set of rules on a 20 year
old industry creates an awkward
transition so I think that that's that's
absolutely true and and many people have
talked about the changes in budgets
right so from going from paying people
cash at the end of the day to paying
payroll taxes and all these things
things these are huge hurdles the fact
that and maybe we've got people here
from all over California but I think we
can all talk to your bit about the fact
that the black markets not being
particularly regulated so for me as a
retailer well guess what I'm paying my
state taxes
I'm paying my county and city taxes I'm
here my labour taxes and I can only sell
edibles that are a hundred milligrams
where the guy down the street he's not
paying any of those taxes he's not
playing his employees correctly and he's
got all the good stuff right so these
these are huge hurdles that I think
we're facing in this present moment and
I think that you know and hopefully in
the future we're looking back at like
okay well the regulated market did get a
leg up because we have access to things
like HR companies and health insurance
good thing yeah but right now I think it
is a big struggle in a big risk you know
if you're somebody who's been in this
industry for a while and you're looking
at hey I've made this business from the
ground up and I've made it really
successful and I have to do literally a
180 just to compete and that 180 comes
with with a pretty big price tag so I
think you know I can really only speak
to the retailer so if there's anybody
who wants to speak I maybe if there's
bigger hurdles to manufacturing
cultivation something like that
but I think just a constant transition
is really tricky
not only for employee morale and
turnover but just for operating cost
it's it's difficult to make a
perspective
plant right where do I want to be in a
year from now well what are the rules
gonna be a year from now I don't think
there's anybody in this room who can say
that for sure so that's I think these
are big hurdles and even though we're
excited to move forward into the
regulated market it doesn't mean it's
simple does that answer the question I
don't know I think I need to support
that we can all make an effort to go to
those licensed entities when we do
purchase cannabis products let's make
that effort because it's true that's
been it that's actually been an issue
for retailers here for quite a long time
and they've been reporting them to
authorities there's been no enforcement
and it's continued so I think it's
really up to us as consumers to educate
our fellow consumers and really support
this license movement so that we are
protecting our industry and those
individuals who have put a lot of money
on the line they've and they've hired
attorneys and they've gone through the
application process it's not easy so we
really need to make sure that we're
supporting those individuals also to
touch on that get involved with the
local associations or CCI a really you
could meet some other operators that can
can help out with some of those hurdles
that you're struggling with and and ask
for their help they're more than happy
to help and lend a helping hand
Neal is here with urbe and we'd like to
know if anyone would like to comment on
the closing of the comment period and
how we can actually contribute our
opinions through the comment period I
have a question did anybody attend that
today yeah maybe your friend can jump in
on that as well there was a hearing
today in downtown Los Angeles from the
BCC to discuss these matters she says it
was 90 seconds and he was a joke
you can send an email to the BCC or the
CD pH they are very receptive they will
respond
Dean wants to say something piggyback
off Rico was saying and give it more
concrete
sort of Avenue for you to do that one of
the things I've been really impressed
with over the last 3-4 months with the
CCI a is it has committees that are
dedicated to the different industry
segments and that in the supply chain so
there is a manufacturing committee there
is a retail committee there's a
distribution committee if you are a
retailer and you've got concerns that
you don't think are being heard or you
don't know where to go with them or you
don't know what the what the the
industry is doing for you that's a great
place for you to go and speak with
retailers that are all sitting in a room
figuring out what comments do we want to
provide if you're a manufacturer or a
grower and you can't get product through
a testing lab where it's getting it's
getting bottleneck and you're getting
frustrated or you send it out to test
and it passes and then you send it to a
manufacturing facility then it comes out
as a finished product and then it fails
and you say how the hell is this
possible
get involved in that group there right
now the manufacturing committee the
testing committee the retail committee
they're all sitting around the room
saying what's your fault you're screwing
up my product and the testing bugs are
saying don't kill me I'm just doing what
the law says and then they're saying oh
really and they're starting to listen to
each other and figure out how you put
these regulations to
a way that makes sense so go go find a
group like that and do exactly what we
Co said don't sit here have a couple of
drinks tonight say it's the BCC
is out of control or the regulation sock
and I can't that's that's not gonna make
you successful what's gonna make you
successful is going out and doing
something about it and finding an
organization like that well you can
contribute an idea to a group that's
actually sitting in Sacramento and
trying to make these things work and put
it into action so I'm seeing it happen
firsthand get get in there and make
yourself heard before this this comment
period closes because we don't know when
there will be another opportunity once
these regulations get fully baked find
sort of intended as it was coming out of
my mouth these are monthly events at the
last event last month we actually had a
panel and we talked about the open
comment period it's quite important and
if you can reach out and just put
together a list what you think is
relevant send it over
he doesn't have to be exhaustive it can
be what's most crucial to you and just
be aware that unfortunately some of
these things are built into prop 64 and
we can't change them some of them
require referendum but you can certainly
voice your concerns and potentially
someone on the other line is going to
make a note of it and in the future
those things will change we are here to
affect policy we're not here just to
talk about it we're gonna bring
awareness and a space for you to talk
about these issues so thank you for
being here that's important you've taken
the first step there's more that you can
do will help you do it how many not time
guys
you
[Music]