[Music]
Tony has been everything that we needed
in this industry to speak for us to
people what I say on the other side Tony
has worked for for example for Governor
Brown doing Economic Development uh
impact studies uh just did the
high-speed rail study for uh Governor
Brown uh personal connections throughout
the legislature and the political
establishment in California he's an
economist he was a Rancher at 21,000
acres in King County California I know
none of you know where that is but it's
downway in the south over to the East
and his um uh Tony came on the scene and
and went with us with a tour up in
Humble County with fionaa Fiona you out
there somewhere yeah Fiona Ma's a Board
of Equalization member she'll be uh uh
with us all day today and with George
Runner her colleague from the second
district and we had a roving farm tour
with economic analysis and tax policy
analysis and that day was a catalyst for
a lot of what's been happening across
the state and even in the legislative
process that we saw earlier I can't say
enough about Tony um he's an amazing
voice for us you should all go up and
say hello to Tony afterwards today give
him your cards Tony is accessible
available wants to forward this agenda
the agenda of legalization and ending
prohibition and doing things rationally
and with that I give the microphone over
to Tony Olivera thank
[Applause]
you those of you that might be here for
the state just so you know I'm used to
working up there I've been appointed by
three governors at one time or another I
was a legislative judge for the great
button will lawsuit that lasted the
environmental lawsuit radioactive
lawsuit that lasted seven years I just
spent a year doing the economic impact
study for the highspeed rail I spent a
year and a half doing the agriculture
impact study for the State of California
on value added I work on ESG
environmental and social and governments
projects all over the world I'm in India
right now and in Africa so I really go
all over this is the only grus job that
I'm doing and I I felt cuz somebody got
to pay the bill but I felt this was
important that I be not paid by anybody
try to keep as much bias out of it as
possible so today instead of giving you
answers I hope that I really present
with you the questions that are needed
because what you heard up here was a lot
of effort has been done but there are
some big voids and some big questions
that I think that are natural I was a
County supervisor for 20 years I was a
president of the California uh State
Association of counties so I come from
local government so I understand them
and I served on the kelper board for
seven years I was the appointee by
Schwarz Ander and brown so I understand
the state and I understand local
government and I am a 44 years a farmer
of many products so with that going to
get to the script we'll go all the way
through then if you have we have time
for
questions so I want to sincerely thank
those that have made my visit and
presentation possible today as I truly
do appreciate the opportunity I want to
especially thank all those that have
opened their doors literally businesses
Fields dispensaries homes hearts and
Minds to me this past two and a half
years of research I've been introduced
to every part of the indust industry
spoke with hundreds of people and in
case anyone questions if there's enough
data out there I can honestly tell you
if you want to come and visit my office
there are over 20,000 page of academic
in the industry research out there
available if people are just willing to
look at it
and that comes from academic blogs
emails information that's available
throughout the world I want to
especially thank Susan sories of care
for all the
[Applause]
introductions because without her I've
never been able to meet many of you in
the room and I I literally have been up
and down this state and no one has ever
turned us away to talk to us in a
research in a confidential way and some
of you that listened to the radio talk
show we did a couple weeks ago we were
pretty open about about that discussion
I've attended Humbolt and their work
I've been at Fresno County when they uh
ruled the growing of cannabis outside
that I know those Board of Supervisors
since I was one and I sat in the
audience that day and listening listen
to the lack of
reasoning um and keep in mind that
you're going to hear in this is that
it's without bias if it should be or not
be because that's my job but there are
some built-in biases and I I will Point
those out
as I began my observations today I want
to preface it by stating that I have
read the current iterations of ab 243
266 and 643 SB and yet as a market
Economist I stand by the challenges and
threats that I see that will impede a
free market environment and that will
cause some degree of market failure
going forward my observations are not
just focused on the approach compromises
appeasements Andor interpretation of the
metal marijuana law and administration
thereof but rather an all-encompassing
Marketplace that will exist if and when
recreational Cannabis is approved by the
voters of California because it's all
tied
together I also want to make it clear
that even though I may disagree with
some of the actions taken and or
proposed I do strongly acknowledge the
efforts of so many trying to do what
they think is right for the industry and
the communities of California let us
always acknowledge that the fact and
it's a fact fact I've always reminded
people at the state level
Californians 100% of Californians those
of you living sitting in this audience
at the end of the day live in local
governments no one lives in the state we
live in local governments and therefore
the vested interest by local governments
is the heart and soul of California we
need to recognize that our communities
are
important I also want to confirm I am
not part of the Cannabis industry or I
have I ever been compensated at any time
or in any way by any entity in the last
2 and a half years for my research my
comments today come from a diverse
background of being a farmer a professor
of economics and public policy and is a
25-year veteran of government Service as
a practice an economist and public
policy practitioner I typically do
research in a way to try and limit
bias uh rather and rather report what it
seems to be the facts or strong opinions
about a particular subject by those
within this industry or those of the
oversight of the industry and what you
heard today was just a touch of and
those that of you were part of the
industry more than any other agriculture
crop and we have 450 of them in Fresno
Fresno County alone in the Central
Valley that this is a very complex
industry my research into the California
cannabis and the prospects of full
legalization had taking me on a physical
research trip all across California and
a virtual research journey across the US
around the globe I've exerted the utmost
effort to limit bias in my work but as a
farmer of a number of crops for over 40
years as a past CEO of one of the
world's largest multinational specialty
companies out of London and as a
California local elected government
official for 20 years I have built in
firsthand knowledge of both growing and
governance and as the president of
seesac I can tell you how many times we
did lived with the unintended
consequences of both referendums and
legislation given my background I am
going to present information embedded in
academic Theory and research today but I
will also step out beyond that and give
some personal opinions of unintended
consequences or threats that possibly
are on the path of the journey to a new
and modified medical marijuana Market
Andor for recreational use in
California I also want to point out that
we should never forget that canab
cannabis begins as an agriculture
product and therefore shares all the
risk and challenges of a growing crop
and like all Farmers cannabis Growers
are price takers and therefore subject
to real and artificial changes of supply
and demand in the
market and one of the things that I've
noticed in this legislation there are
some
artificial uh barricades the way it is
right now maybe they'll work that out
and I'll touch a little bit on that in a
free market Society a competitive market
is composed of many buyers and sellers
of goods that a fairly unrestrained to
trade on products and services and
negotiate an ultimate market price that
reaches what we call equilibrium we all
know basic
economics what we as consumers are
willing to pay and what Growers need uh
in order to make a profit or at least
break even
this is where the buyer and seller reach
the satisfactory level of consumers the
buyers considered to be a fair price and
they have the willingness and ability to
pay for what producers Growers need to
cover their cost hopefully that is
profitable the real question here is how
free and competitive can the California
Economist Market truly be given the
possible restraints of Interstate
because right now it's Interstate within
the confines of the State of
California and Poss be no Interstate
consumers across the US even though we
know part of the production currently
goes
Interstate the current proposed
legislation changes will satisfy the
concerns as many at the state and local
levels but a number of changes will
impede any chance to have a fair and
competitive
Marketplace as Government imposes more
and more restrictions in the marketplace
it will cause distortions to what the
ultimate supply and demand equilibrium
might be and is further distorted if the
grower is disallowed to be competitive
by lack of
diversification or use of vertical
efficiencies which we talked about
earlier in my opinion as it is proposed
by some right now the new California
medical marijuana stands to be
restrained by lack of vertical
integration of the grower Market power
may be prevalent by those that have the
power of distribution the market will be
oversupplied by new producers and
potential
offsetting demand diminished by some
Regional opt outs and the right of local
governments to tax I quote the Senate
Bill privilege of
cultivation as a farmer I've never seen
language where it became a privilege to
grow an agriculture
crop the other major threat to a large
over Supply in the inate within the
state Market will be the current
estimated significant amount of state
sales of California cannbis uction that
are forced back into the intrate market
other words we know some estimate heard
it on the radio show that it was on
about 80% of the
Cannabis
sorry 80 started becoming that Professor
80% of uh estimated the Cannabis in
production California could be going out
of state either through
policy or by enforcement just think
about that we don't know what that
number is but let's just take it from
mathema iCal point of view right now if
the production units let's call it a th
thousand units that could be tons
whatever it doesn't matter but if 20% of
that is in in state and 80% leaves if
you reduce the amount of export out of
this state into the rest of the United
States it would be a 50% decrease to
that but it would be a
400% increase to the supply and you
would be totally oversupplied so if
California Growers were going to work
and the reason I bring that up is we
don't know what the fed or other
enforcement agencies might want to do if
we're going to be legally interest rate
interestate is there going to be further
pressure to reduce the amount of
Interstate out of the state of
California this could have a profound
impact on local Supply and ultimately
much lower prices to Growers this of
course might be opposite Trend if in
fact the restrictions and possible
taxation structure forces some Growers
to the alternative Marketplace and I'm
going to talk about that let's say that
fees and
structures uh become too high and since
um
marijuana cannabis and the black black
market are replacement products Growers
put in a devious position or dubious
position of being overt taxed over feed
may decide that their only alternative
is the export
Market as we think about fees fines and
taxes is important to first agree that
even in a free Marketplace some level of
fee and Taxation is acceptable in a
Democratic Society where it is
understood that government participation
of some limited degree is necessary for
services and oversight to prevent market
failures the definition of a market
failure in a free market is when a
market fails due to the inefficient
allocation of
resources this can be from a number of
variables but more typically is from
negative externalities they were talking
about environmental
impacts such as impacts and costs on
third parties such as the environment
other property owners or local
governments or perceived impacts to
local governments or can be where Market
power causes a
failure Market power is one I'm
concerned about Market power is defined
where an individual actor a group of
actors in The Market have substantial
influence on the market
I believe that Research indicates quite
clearly to some degree that in some
regions there has been market failures
due to environmental impacts and that
was talking about
earlier on those environmental impacts I
guess the only thing that I would say as
a grower I would just like to see
cannabis treated like any other crop
that's grown in
California and by that I'm not saying
give it away out I'm saying we got the
airboard that we got the water control
board we got Kell EPA but don't look at
it as a demon crop look at it as any
crop and therefore apply the same kind
of Technologies research and
requirements and I'll talk about that in
a
second uh fines I wanted to touch on
fines just a moment from a civil fine
point of view as as criminal fees of
course are and will be very much
adjudicated in the California court
system as established by current or
future
laws again I raise this point as a way
of making sure that any civil fines
remain in current law with agencies such
as air boards Cal EPA the water board
Etc and that cannabis be treated like
any other agriculture cop crop if in
violation in the growing process any new
civil find structures must be required
by State Statute to ensure no local
agency can be empowered to impose impose
fines outside the state restrictions I'm
I'm concerned about personal bias as a
past County Supervisor no one stands for
local home rule more than I especially
when comes to health and safety but my
concern is where personal bias dictates
public policy beyond the constraints of
Statute we have seen that all over the
United States in things other than
cannabis where personal people in
personal positions have decided not to
go by the law of the
land in
taxes the purpose of a tax on a good or
service is typically accepted in the
realm of good public policy two pay for
necessary specific or general oversight
of the function of society to mitigate
the externalities the impacts negative
impacts of products services and use of
private and public goods and you yes to
raise General and specific funds to
operate local state and federal
governments including education public
policy infrastructure and the many
responsibilities of government in a free
Society with a few exceptions most
Americans understand the need for some
level of Taxation and the dispute
discussions of tax usually comes down to
the equity inquality in the action
actual burden and ultimate distribution
of service and benefits of the tax
revenue you notice I said a burden of
tax because an as an economist there is
no questioning that any degree of
Taxation on a product or service is a
burden to the market
Surplus in this
case economics one 101 what consumers
have left over if they buy their product
or service and what the producers keep
as margin after they sell their products
is the market Surplus you have heard
this before that in many writings out
there that about how taxation causes a
dead weight loss to a free market as a
revenue collected in taxes is taken from
the total Market Surplus anytime
government takes a tax it takes it out
of the marketplace if it's in the
marketplace it's spent on Capital
Improvements it's spent on labor but not
of its taxed even though I say some tax
and we'll get to that is necessary it is
my belief there is a false assumption by
some that California taxpayers see that
a heavy tax on cannabis will generate
positive outcomes either to local and
state government revenue sources and or
to solve other Financial issues within
their jurisdiction and therefore such
tax propos proposals are needed to pass
legalization I don't see it that way
California taxpayers by Nature are not
for excessive taxation or or have they
traditionally felt comfortable to
empower government entities to tax to
solve the
responsibilities or misjudgments of
government Proposition 13 is a great
example where taxpayers rebelled against
somewhat open checkbook on taxing
property values even though some Tout
The unint unintended consequences of
Prop 13 about the effects of the
restraint put on local governments to
tax property in their jurisdiction it is
quite evident that it did curtail The
Runaway valuations of property taxes in
some jurisdictions and push taxation
strategies in a more Market
consumer-driven taxation strategy by
stimulating investment by cities and
counties into Commercial Business and
retail business and generated taxes and
revenues through user
fees there has been a public policy
standard in California that Growers of
agriculture products in general have not
been burdened with tax on their products
at their level other than property tax
tax increases where Capital Improvements
have been made and have in fact
increased the value of their property
this would of course include personal
property tax on equipment supplies Etc
fees of course charged as mentioned
earlier to pay for oversight and
possible mitigation offsets as price
takers the farmers are price takers and
what I believe will be an oversupplied
Market at least in the inter uh short
period first two or three years any
necessary burdens of Taxation will force
Growers out of the market or down
another
path sorry for the reading but I believe
that California Canabis at least in the
near years will be sensitive to price
increases what we call and you guys have
read about inelastic and elastic
something that's inelastic is not price
sensitive uh diabetus medicine like I
take I'll buy it no matter how much it
increases cannabis at this point is what
we call elastic it's very price
sensitive and it will be more price
sensitive because it has a substitute a
substitute to Legal cannabis is the
black market so any price increase will
make it more sensitive and force
choices potential unintended
consequences and threats to the
marketplace in my
opinion depending how the eventual
legislation statute are Ena enacted the
following consequences are possible and
are only a few of many potential impacts
some have been talked about today fees
the allowed fee structures through the
lack of understanding or inent could put
the California Growers processors and
retailers of cannabis in a disadvantage
with other regions other products and
the black market I've not
understood I would asked that question
we didn't have time I will at some time
in the future why we have empowered
local government so much as a compromise
to charge fees and charge taxes somewhat
with an open checkbook I realize that
there are some restrictions but I come
from local governments and fees
typically are defined that we charge
them for the cost only the cost of Mi uh
oversight and the cost of mitigation I'm
concerned about some jurisdictions that
already have a bias against the growing
packaging or cultivation of cannabis if
that fee structure is not in statute by
the state and has limits to it I'm
concerned about where that fee structure
would
go fines fines that have or can have
local bias by administrators law
enforcement or public officials will
distort the marketplace and therefore
the choices of both consumers and
Growers again I'm concerned about the
limits on
fees taxes taxes should be defined and
purposeful with very distinctive
definitions of reason and application
that are set by State Statute and cannot
be altered or set by local
government it's not my belief even
though I come from local government that
local government should be empowered to
set a tax level that they think is
necessary for because it even says in
the current legislation it can be for
general purposes general purposes can be
for a lot of reasons it can solve
infrastructure problems or take care of
large unfunded pension
liabilities you know and so it needs to
be restricted I have no I I am a local
government
Advocate but the fee and tax structure
must be set by the state and local
governments shouldn't and and one of the
questions that we've talked a little bit
about is it even though it's going to
require it doesn't require a vote for a
local Board of Supervisors to charge a
fee it charges a vote it takes a vote to
raise a tax you should be very concerned
about at what tax level that's going to
be set typically when I was a supervisor
if it was for a specific reason it could
pass at
51% if it was for a general reason it
had to be 2/3 and the leg oppos pardon
just the
opposite in general 51% specific 23
no my city
was but think about it because if money
goes into the general coffers of any
local government they can spend it how
they want taxpayers are more concerned
and you can check on that but I think
you'll find it's the opposite
but but but but regardless regardless
regardless it's the question the
question is is that what tax at what
threshold could a local government tax
cannabis and the bill the S the Senate
bill says they can even tax Growers for
the privilege of
growing so you need to be concerned
about it's just a question um we totally
agree I totally agree with that you need
voters to do that but the the T the
threshold of the vote should be
important to
you if the taxation is above what is
considerable Equitable for the defined
purpose it will surely Drive some
consumers and Growers to the substitute
product which is the black market in no
realm can I consider that any tax
structure that puts a privilege tax on
Growers makes any economic or parody
sense as they are truly are the
risk-takers and especially in this area
and they talked a little bit about it if
Growers I'm very much in this industry
because the industries I come from we
survive many times by having co-ops
grower co-ops I think are very necessary
in this industry because you are small I
think the margins are going to be small
but you can't have a co-op if it doesn't
allow vertical integration because
co-ops don't just grow the power of a
co-op is to grow it bring it in package
it together negotiate the price ship it
and then deliver it to your Growers on a
parody basis so I think a Co-op is a
very important part of what's
necessary
um they should be granted the same
reverence uh given to all agrarian
stewards and I talk about All Growers in
California we should not punish an
emerging valid industry due to actions
of some bad players in the past it is a
crop what you guys said up here was
great I think you said that is is
treated because no one no one wants
herbicide and pesticide on cannabis more
than I do that's the power of value
added some of you asked about that if
you want to give value it's kind of like
growing I grow uh uh pomegranates I ship
them all over the world and they're
organic I get value because they know
what I've used and not used we need the
same thing with
cannabis and then the last thing is
Market power unless we are very very
careful about watching who has the power
of distribution
uh and make sure that we close all the
gaps some could become Power Players and
it's not going to be
Growers uh Growers going to be trying to
just survive and barely survive in this
market for the next few years the co-ops
would help you um this could easily
happen if the structure disallows
Growers to have efficiency capabilities
and some degree of vertical integration
if the distribution of retail is is
controlled by a Chosen Few it will
surely cause a degree of Market power
causing damage to the grower consumer
and ultimately to those seeking tax
revenues in the process it actually in a
free market Society what you want is you
want the sellers and buyers to be
creative and and create a lot of Revenue
and that's where you get total tax
revenue is the highest volume we can get
with the lowest tax and we look for that
equilibrium so I'm just concerned about
that I I think they've done fabulous
work the things I'm bringing up today
are just the questions that if you don't
ask over the next several
months and by
2016 it's the questions if you want the
answers we have to ask the questions but
I think there's been a lot of work I've
talked to so many of you I I I think
there's great hope this industry needs
to be legitimized I get asked all the
time after two and a half years how big
it is no one knows no one knows because
we can't measure it you know it's it's
called the of the favorite things in the
economic world we say is uh if we can
measure it we can manage it and what we
should ask our legislators is to allow
us to measure it so we can manage it and
to take the Handcuff off take the
Handcuff off The Growers and
distribution um to allow this to become
a true Marketplace legitimize the
product and let this build into
something that would be
substantial thank you
[Applause]
questions you mentioned how the uh the
states might impose uh punitive fees in
a way that would would not be
advantageous to the industry but isn't
that also part of like a free market
that if some municipalities want to say
look we've got a bias against this then
then the businesses will move to other
municipalities that are very welcoming
we don't do that in the alcohol
industry you know why is can
why is or aspirin or I can name a number
of products why do we Empower local
government I was talking to one of my
students at one of the universities I
teach the other day was from France he
said I don't understand this he was
reading the law he said in France if we
pass something it's good for the whole
country you're going to pass something
in California and few areas say you
don't have to have it here it's that's
not a free market free market is where
uh both sellers and buyers can get
together in an open market because if
not you're going to have a this is going
to be a market that's going to market
failures in certain areas because of
those restrictions now it may just be
something we work through and I think
you guys mentioned great it may be a few
where at first some don't want it and
decide later on as everything comes
along it'll work that way but unless
you're knocking on those doors I if
you're a grower how do you know where
your product's going to go you know how
do you know who's going to opt out and
who's not it's it's just it'd be like
the products that I sell my pomegranates
if I could only sell them in Kings
County it has x value if I can sell them
in 10 counties it has a different value
if I can sell them worldwide it changes
the value of that
product yes do you guys would be uh
would be great to get some of your
Insight on how the taxation is likely to
take place do you foresee happening each
time Canabis moves through the value
chain or just at the end and do you see
it happening on value added each stage
or on the the total value each I've read
all the bills and and watched all your
guys work God bless you and and talk to
a lot of other attorneys about it and I
still can't get that interpretation all
I can see right now is that the only
restriction that I really see a local
government can decide what level of
Taxation it needs the only thing they're
restricted by is the thing that I don't
we don't know the answer to Is at what
threshold will the voters permit that to
be but I didn't see any constraints on
that that that the tax what that tax
would be and or what the fees could be
some counties I I can tell you coming
from
kelper
that I'm I'm for pensions and for all
that but there are some jurisdictions
that are financially struggling pensions
infrastructure and others that need a
bigger percentage of something than
others so is is that a way you know
without that's a reason I most of the
time I I like governance from the bottom
up in this case I would love to see
guidance from the state that puts in law
the maximum amount of tax that can be
charged by local local government and
fees because if not who
decides it seems like there's a basic
contradiction we're calling it
medicine you can't tax medicine yeah
that's the problem and and it's very
simple I'm glad to see the guys that you
have working on this from the
legislature because they understand
medicine the problem is is first of all
you need to recognize it as a true
agricultural crop for what it is number
one two is if if the people have voted
and said that it medical marijuana makes
sense that it's legal in California then
you need to recognize it as a medicine
and treat it that
way then first of all you wouldn't be
taxing a me a medical product and you
certainly wouldn't be taxing the
Growers um Sor well thanks Tony um it's
a round of applause please for Tony
um I uh I hope I hope I hope the
legislators are listening carefully uh
to to an academic who's actually studies
and gets deep into the effects of these
things and we know we do have to do
cleanup