[Music]
today we have grant Van Daan Bush from
fifth-season Chris Higgins from hor
Americas and Matt kobori from calyx King
they'll each be talking about issues
that they see in the market right now
and then how futuristic solutions can
can meet those issues and and needs of
the customer hi so I'm grant van Busche
I spoke earlier just another quick piece
of background on me so I was at General
Mills for a little over five years a
large portion of that time I spent
working on the energy risk management
strategy for General Mills looking at a
lot of distributed energy platforms
looking at a lot of cogeneration systems
as well as how we thought about our both
our diesel natural gas and electricity
risk programs so when I when I joined
fifth-season I think as I mentioned
earlier we had a very tiny farming
technology system and and we knew that
our whole thesis was to try and pull the
labor out of the out of the growing and
we knew that once we did that that
energy would be the largest cost so we
tried to be very thoughtful about how we
built energy solutions into our growing
platform and some of what I'm gonna
share with you today is is actually how
we've done that and how we've set
ourselves up to to optimize energy over
the long term so I certainly want to go
into that I'll try and be brief about it
so so this is our facility this is the
the facility that is coming online right
now as I mentioned earlier we'll have
products on shelves within the next 30
to 45 days this isn't a steel town
called Braddock that is the it's called
us Edgar Thompson steel that's actually
Andrew Carnegie's former manager it's
where he invented the Braddock press
which ultimately made him a little bit
of cash so it's a one point five
megawatt facility with human-free
consistent and controlled by odomes so
what's going on underneath the roof
there is is what you're looking at in
that actually that's a two scale diagram
what we have is a tray loop system where
we've really taken the method
of an automated fulfillment center and
used that as a platform to grow plants
so instead of moving around pallets of
boxes we're moving around pallets of
plants and so as you think about an
automated processing and automated
growing an automated harvesting and an
automated packaging system that's how
that moves around in our full loop and
we have two biodomes that we have
complete control over so what that means
is that we can be a lot more precise so
so from a control standpoint these are
this is an example of one of our panels
we have over a hundred panels inside of
the full system and then on our breaker
we have high resolution information
gathering and what that allows us to do
is feed everything into our system and
so when we talk about smart
manufacturing this is really allows us
to be better about our scheduling so
with the human free grow rooms we don't
have to wait for a day shift or wait for
a night shift in order to move plants
around to the optimal space we don't
have to wait for a day shift or wait for
a night shift in order to kick on
irrigation or kick on fans or even bring
things out that allows us to be very
very smart around how we schedule and
use use our electricity so so it's the
combination of these things and then
also within the system being able to
augment them so so from an energy
optimization standpoint what we're doing
is is we publish grow recipes into our
software system so those grow recipes
each each one of them has an energy
assumption in a buffer window for that
and so as we think about filling up that
biodome with all of these different
individual orders if you will that the
system then takes care of the system is
reoptimize until energy usage is based
on top of that and then our system is
also combining that with our high res
monitoring based on all the smart panels
that we've created to look at and say
okay if we were planning on using this
much energy and our actual energy
consumption was this why is there that
variance and a lot of times because we
have these buffer zones and our grow
recipes what that allows us to do is be
smarter about how we how we use energy
everything's done to a quality standard
so it's not like we are
sacrificing quality on a lot of these
things it's just when we when we think
about blending product together or we
think about creating packages of that
come from multiple trays you might be
able to shave an hour here or an hour
there when you think about this full
full scheduling problem and in one
instance and then finally we have micro
grid so that's really about connecting
this entire energy schedule or this
entire energy portfolio along with
what's happening inside of inside of the
grader inside of your what's happening
locally so this is a micro grid
architecture we work with scale micro
grid they have been fantastic partners
capital is always a struggle when you
are a young startup so you so scale
micro grids innovative platform to to
really reduce that capital requirement
has been very helpful to us the solar
can can really generate about can really
generate a pretty significant amount of
electricity for us it's not you know
sound a hundred percent of our of our
yield or sorry of our requirements and
we also have a standby generator that's
fed by NAT gas that can kick on so the
three days of resiliency is huge for us
in the event that there is a grid outage
our neighbors next door they kind of
pulled out of power and do have a lot of
demand and a lot of say to the utility
but that that capability for us to have
the understanding for how we are
impacting the grid and the flexibility
for how we want to run our operation is
huge when you think about curtailment
and other types of activities so we're
literally just starting this up I wish I
had actual numbers that I could post on
here this is our our projected monthly
load versus available generation I
absolutely cannot wait until we do have
that data and we can share it with you
because to my knowledge we are the first
real manufacturing process that has
dynamic load-balancing that we can do
inside of a human free operation so I
just get really really geeked up about
what that can do sorry yeah so my name
is Chris Higgins I am the general
manager and co-owner of hoard America's
hoard America's there's a texas-based
company Dallas Texas based company and
what we really are is we're a wholesale
supply company
but over the last decade we've really
focused on controlled environment
agriculture and for us that means
anything from a tissue culture facility
to an indoor vertical farm to a
greenhouse we work with those growers
and helping them develop and implement
their ideas as well as providing with
them supplies after they're up and
growing my business partners are from
the Netherlands they are a Dutch grower
cooperative with about 125 years of
experience so in essence my board is
made up of about a thousand Dutch
greenhouse growers so we get a lot of
input from the Netherlands and that's
shaped a lot of what we've done over the
years our vision is to be leading North
American wholesale supply company and
that's kind of shifting right now
because what we've realized over the
years is that many of the growers we're
working with today especially those
looking at growing food crops in unique
environments need more than just a
supply company and they need a partner
they need a partner to talk about what
others are doing that they find
successful what equipment they may be
able to use that they don't have to
completely reinvent and other ways of
helping them manage costs because many
of them are on a very tight budget and
what that causes us to do is link the
grower with manufacturers that we've
vetted and Trust we do have a
demonstration greenhouse in downtown
Dallas it's connected with the State
Fair of Texas so if anybody's ever in
Dallas and wants to visit and see seven
or eight growing systems right now I
don't know what we have it's open 365
days a year it's about a hundred yards
from the old Cotton Bowl and during the
month of October we get about 400,000
visitors right now so it's become kind
of an agritourism spot but in there
you'll see that we will run product
demonstration with new products from
some of our vendor partners like General
Electric grow tin other sensor companies
like 30 megahertz and our goal is to
figure out that this technology can work
not for the most technically
technologically advanced group of people
but that the average grower can make
this equipment work and you'll find
we've had to prove this to ourselves
because our
growing team consists of the landscapers
that run the State Fair that's itself so
we have to teach this to a bunch of
landscapers who have no horticulture
degree would probably be more
comfortable driving a lawn mower than
you know calibrating EC and pH so the
way we look at the business is we try to
simplify it there is a question asked
about you know did they sell weight or
do they sell units in the last panel and
I thought the answer was interesting
because the units are essentially weight
so for a grower of ours that's growing a
head of bib lettuce we know that there
is a certain weight that fills up a
clamshell and we know that there are you
know handful of clam shells that most of
the produce buyers want to receive so
they may be selling a unit but inside
that unit is a weight that we have to
meet so I'm similar to agriculture
throughout the years our growers are
dealing with yield and in order to be
profitable we really have to send
understand those yield economics and our
ability to help those growers be
profitable is what's going to lead to
our longevity so again we're based in
Texas we service all of North America
with customers as far south as Brazil
and as far north as Barrow Alaska and we
do have customers internationally as
well this this slide just really kind of
leads into what I finished up there we
are you know we as a company are focused
on collaboration focus and
open-mindedness one of the things we see
with the industry is that there are a
lot of people that are protecting
themselves with a lot of NDA's if we
look at the history of controlled
environment agriculture and we use the
Dutch model as maybe a case study the
interesting thing about that model is
that they are very open as long as you
speak Dutch but all the greenhouse has
essentially looked the same and what
that means is that those greenhouses
while the systems inside are slightly
different what that means is that their
ability to share helps them share the
cost and it helps them build their
industry not only in the Netherlands but
as they export globally
so that's something that we would like
to see come to the US and come to North
America would be more of an openness of
sharing what are the best practices and
using those best practices to drive our
industry forward not just drive an
individual business forward or an
individual opportunity forward but to
drive the industry forward because with
that we will start to change the
opportunities that we have in the United
States we will start to possibly
manufacture some more stuff here versus
just importing everything from either
Northern Europe art or Asia and again
encouraging everybody to be open and
receptive to new ideas is key for for
our company my name is matthew kobori i
am an owner and operator in the cannabis
industry in several different market
segments primarily through calyx culture
which is a tissue culture and genetic
breeding company and house of cultivar
which is a recreational adult use
cannabis brand headquartered in Seattle
Washington but also with presence in
California and hopefully in 2020 in
Massachusetts as well and in addition my
desire and passion for sustainability
has brought me onto the board of the
resource innovation Institute as well I
started off about over a decade ago in
my basement with one little grow light
as a hobby and has a passion and then
quickly through education and
architecture expanded that out through
one grow light to four grow lights and
then I built out my basement and then a
small garage and then from there a
warehouse and then as the the medical
laws and recreational law is expanded in
Washington State we grew and evolved and
from that first basement to the 50,000
square foot building that were in now in
downtown Seattle there's always been an
issue of power and from from a very
functional standpoint no building that
we ever started off with had enough
power so has always been a process of
trying to reverse engineer what your
outputs are based upon the limitations
of the grid or your local location so
for us it's always been a very
functional requirement to have to be as
sustainable as possible so from that
very early instance about 10 years ago
to now we have been constantly trying to
evolve the
oh jeez I mean I remember building led
getting Cree you know uh diodes and
building LEDs in my basement trying to
think that it was going to be the the
revolution which through you know
companies here today have really taken
it to that next level and it allowed us
to capitalize on those technologies but
what I really want to talk about today
is some of the methodology that goes
beyond what you see in conventional
agriculture and what is specific to to
cannabis and a big part of that is the
product selection so if any of you have
ever been into a retail dispensary or
storefront you've noticed the huge
selection of different strains and
genetics and products that are on the
marketplace and each one of those
genetics has a certain requirement for
it and a lot of it comes down to space
area light water labor and supplies
materials conventionally what we have
done is we've created mother plants and
then from those mother plants that
mother stock we've created clones and
then the clones create the production
plants which then create the products
but for every string for every different
product that you have that means that
you have to keep a mother plant alive to
represent and to hold that genetic to
create that propagation that means that
a lot at least one large plant is going
to be necessary for each one of those
things and that is a light that is water
that goes into that plant and that's
time and labor that those employees
spend dealing with it
so for us what we try to do was how do
we take that and they consolidate that
because that's how you're gonna be the
most efficient and that's how you're
gonna reduce your resource usage so for
us we we have spent a lot of time doing
a lot of research and development and
perfecting the the art and sciences of
tissue culture of micropropagation what
micropropagation has allowed us to do is
essentially take these large mother
plants and the large amount area
resources and consolidate that into in
vitro test tubes and essentially take
all of our mother stock and propagation
stock that took up about eighty five
hundred square feet in our in our
Seattle facility and consolidate that
down to about 1500 square feet of space
it is it has allowed us to reduce our
load quite significantly and it in
addition
a lot of operational benefits as well we
have a lot cleaner plant stock were able
to reduce contamination spread and we're
able to actually have a much more
efficient operational process which
reduces costs and resources in the
downstream processes through different
IPM measures different technology that a
lot of people have to put in place to
mitigate stuff and and contamination and
negative consequences from that that we
can get rid of in the tissue culture
process so not only does it consolidate
the space but it also provides for a
much more streamlined operation
downstream so as I said we we converted
those large mom rooms into the lab space
so this is the example in Seattle of
about eighty five hundred square feet of
original mom in genetic storage space
that was taking up you know had about 15
tons tons HVAC as well supplying it we
we had even gone through a lighting
rebate and had converted all of our
thousand watt metal halide fixtures over
to 315 315 watt surrett male high light
fixtures but we were still using roughly
a little over a hundred thousand watts
whereas in the new tissue culture lab
we're down to about fourteen thousand
watts so as you can see a significant
decrease from eighty five hundred square
feet to fifteen hundred square feet and
from over a hundred thousand watts to
fourteen thousand watts doing the exact
same operational protocol and even
expanding our genetic library and
storage capabilities so you know as a
grower and somebody who's operationally
functionally in the marketplace you know
one thing that I want to try to express
to everybody as we look at the
advancements in the industry it's not
only in the technology that's required
to do this but also in the methodology
and the approaches when you go and you
visit you know grows you're gonna see
there's a million different ways to skin
the cat no to two operations are doing
it the same and I think as we progress
and as we advance we need to start to
create some of those standards as we
discussed earlier and start to share
resources on how we can change
methodologies to then put the proper
equipment in place to really see those
advancements and those reductions in
resource usage thank you and now we'll
take questions a couple of you mentioned
praia teri advancements and NDA's as
part of this work and i wonder how do we
balance those proprietary advancements
and NDA's with opportunities that could
kind of lift all boats
new important ideas for the entire
industry and how do we kind of balance
those two things I'll jump in on this
one and I think it's because we've
experienced this so much I mean
especially in the canvas side of things
people think that they're they're their
trade secrets are really their ultimate
success factor which is in my opinion
with what is slowing down the progress
and even retarding individual growth in
a company's business planning strategy I
really think that through organizations
like the resource innovation Institute
you know bringing like-minded
individuals together to share really is
the best way to transcend that and I
think the way that we do that is to show
value with the information that's coming
out so I think you know through these
standards setting groups getting that
information percolated out to the widest
audience possible in as a cost effective
manner I think is the way in which we
spread it as quickly as possible the
only thing I would add there is is
making sure you as a group we understand
what's worth protecting and what has
been around for a long period of time
I've been in the industry for about 25
years
and I would say about once a month I get
a phone call from somebody who has a
really awesome new idea
and the idea has been around a long time
right so in a lot of ways we want to
protect the easiest one I've always uses
a lot of people want to protect the
irrigation system but all we are doing
is using irrigation systems that have
been around for 30 or 40 years
so so making sure you've done your work
you've done your research and you can
understand okay am I really doing
anything different or am I just slightly
modifying the way I'm moving water that
that's in itself is not worth protecting
but there are things that are right in
understanding what those are and how
those benefit you and your organization
I think are key in helping move
everything forward because if
open yourself up a little bit somebody
may have already made all the mistakes
that you're getting ready to make and
they can save you a lot of money in time
by helping you through those things hi I
had a question about understanding the
incremental cost between what you could
have done and the innovative choice that
you did choose to do and how you were
able to perhaps calculate that yourself
and communicate it to your stakeholders
investors and maybe even the utilities
because oftentimes that's what the
utilities want to know in order to
incentivize some sort of inventive or
cutting-edge technology so finding out
the ROI knowing the incremental cost
between traditional choice versus paving
a new path yeah that's a great question
thank you for asking that Gretchen right
yeah thank you for asking a question so
let me just talk about our switchgear
real quick because when we first looked
at doing the switchgear I think our
project or electrical engineer and the
project said that that was going to cost
us a million dollars more in capital
because our our I'm sorry let me talk
about our micro grid because he said
that you know that we had to upgrade the
switchgear to be the greatest switchgear
that's ever existed before on the planet
of Earth or something like that so so
that was that was a big that was a big
hurdle for us that took some time you
know the local builder on the project
really liked Siemens switch gears and
for our project we had to go with a
Schneider switch gear so it was making
spending a lot of time with that with
that builder getting them very
comfortable with the technology gave
them very comfortable with the install
process getting them very comfortable
with the corresponding effect and making
sure that but I think you asked the
commissioning question earlier getting
that that sequenced into the full
commissioning plan and how that would
fit and how that would fit with the
local utility electrical inspector and
what would what would be that process so
that was something that we we knew that
we we needed to do this and we knew that
it was something that had to happen at
zero incremental capital to us and so
that was an example of where we relied
heavily on external partners to come in
and sit down and take everybody through
the pictures videos everything else to
get the local constructors the local
builders the local people on
with the technology familiar with
everything so that way we could realize
no was not a 1 million dollar
incremental switchgear cost it was
actually you know apples to apples once
you figured it out it was the exact same
switch so that was really big for us we
also looked pretty significantly at a
combined heat and power system that was
a decision we chose not to make for us
at that point in time that was actually
looking the other way looking at some of
the phenomenal advisors that we've had
on the on the HVAC side in terms of how
we were thinking about usage you know
that was just a it was a little bit too
much capital for us at this time and it
was a little bit too much of a slightly
potential risk to the commissioning plan
that we said you know what no there's
there's enough in this facility already
we don't we don't want to take on that
project as well it all comes down to I
think both the math problem and and what
you you feel comfortable doing just to
kind of add to that great comments by
the way um it's really just trying to
look long-term you know I think like
with most technology we advanced or
sustainable solutions there's an
additional upfront cost associated with
it so really looking at that ROI not in
a short-term one or two years but more
in the the five to 10 year realm really
makes things pencil out on paper to make
a lot more sense and also when you're
when you're looking at this from a prog
ative standpoint I don't think any of
these decisions that we're making are
necessarily short-term decisions whether
it be for our business or whether it be
for the planet Earth in general from a
sustainability standpoint for anybody on
the panel can you guys speak a little
bit to your experience and what you're
seeing right now with respect to water
or atmospheric water generation systems
Chris as you remember we had a system
from a Southern California company
called sky well at herbin produce which
was a great system but it was
problematic where we were able to
capture about 140 gallons a day what are
you guys seeing in terms of atmospheric
water generation systems in pure indoor
environments not necessarily greenhouse
but grant for you and other gentlemen
for you so the biggest ones for us an
indoor environment are the condensation
that's coming off
of any reach back components which
nowadays with filter ization that's out
there it's almost a no-brainer to be
able to capture that put that back into
your fertigation and then for most
hydroponic gardeners you know there is
somewhere between a fifteen to
twenty-five percent runoff that's
typically happening through that
flushing process which you know most
people right now are you know mitigating
so that they can put into a sewer system
but there is lots of opportunity to
recapture filter and reuse that water as
well those are the two biggest right now
yeah maybe just to add to that real
briefly so we have it we have a fill-in
drain system we we capture a lot of the
of the water that comes out of that I
don't know the exact percentage you know
for us water is it's really important
but it's not it when when I think about
the hierarchy of cost and strategies for
us it's it's something where it's it's
not the top of the list that's
prohibiting us from either you know
investing immediately in the next
project or or it's not it's not on the
top of our list for for solutions
because we can capture so much of it
it's important to us as a company
because we we think deeply about our
impact to the water cycle and what we're
doing with nutrient-rich water but it's
it's not as important to us as figuring
out the energy usage yeah and I would I
would add to that most of the farms that
we're working with on the indoor side
right it is it should be much lower on
the priority list because their total
water consumption is fairly low
especially on the food producing side
and they're able to recirculate their
irrigation systems so frequently that
they're pretty water efficient when we
look at the you know the bigger
customers we have they're using lots of
water they have they're not implementing
those systems currently in terms of food
producing or flower production they are
more looking at how are they going to
capture rainwater how are they going to
be as efficient as they possibly can
when it comes to managing their
nutrients salts with inside their
irrigation system I think for us with
the majority the customers we have its
it is ok where can I have the biggest
impact today
and probably in figuring out how to make
their nutrient solution go longer by
using you know the right fertilizers and
the right measuring and sensing
equipment is probably a better way for
them to have a bigger impact on water
than it is to capture that in the sphere
of water I'll just add we've done some
research on water and whether they're
worth a whether it's worth incentivizing
from a utility perspective and at least
in the Northeast water is extremely
cheap and plentiful so it's usually not
it does not behoove us to look into
water incentives but that's very
geographically dependent of course if
you were looking at California that's
very very expensive and important water
so that is very Geographic just like
some states may care more about carbon
than other states right now so you'll
see those priorities switch depending on
where you're at I've heard a lot about
water here but it's really not a concern
of any of our customers in Vermont this
is for Matt Matt I'm curious I know you
travel quite a bit around the country
and get a chance to attend a lot of
cannabis conferences what would you say
is a level of lack of better word
cross-pollination between what we know
to be true in cannabis and what more
mature AG sector players are doing today
based on you know multiple years of
experience in greenhouse is there a
bigger need for that kind of cross
sector conversation are you seeing that
happen in other parts of the country
yeah a great great question John you
know I think over the last especially
four or five years as industry has kind
of rapidly grown and evolved you know
we've seen a lot of crossover or I like
the word cross-pollination a lot better
from from major AG over to to the
cannabis industry and vice versa you
know there's been a large amount of
monetary capital to come into the
cannabis industry that has really
invoked a lot of innovation that has
been stagnant in commercial lag for
years however that has also been an
Achilles heel of people trying to evolve
too quickly and forgetting some of the
simple standards
of large-scale agriculture as well so
that that's really where we've seen this
information pass that's been happening
and for the most part you know I think
that the scaling and the the large
industrial practices of Ag are starting
to be more accepted as cannabis gets to
the scale where those things make sense
you know for a long time we're at a
hobbyist or commercial scale where some
of those large-scale methodologies just
weren't applicable but now that that
we're really kind of breaching those
those those size and scale to that that
next level they're really starting to
become applicable and then combining
that with the innovation that starting
to happen we're really seeing this this
hot pot of explosive growth also
I've got to think about what I want how
I want to say this I don't want to
ostracize myself with a group of people
that are looking in you know directly at
cannabis or Tamera cos we have had
cannabis customers for the last decade
prior to that I ran a company called
Grodin which we had a large percentage
of our business was in the cannabis
market what I have watched over the last
five years is that I think they you know
they're there's always been a cannabis
as special and I we heard another
speakers say that earlier today and I
think is is as long as as soon as as an
industry we start to say we're in indoor
crop production or we're in controlled
environment agriculture regardless of
the plant
I think the industry itself will move
faster and find those cross pollinators
much quicker than if we keep setting
that crop aside you know I work the
first decade of my career I focused on
flora culture and in most flora culture
facilities in the United States growers
will grow between five and five hundred
varieties and a thousand varieties and
what we learn is that you know you might
have a bedding plant in the same
greenhouse that later that year you're
gonna have a point setup very different
crops very different ways to grow them
but they're both a plant that responds
to the same variables now how you
program your growing approach or your
cultivation strategy will change but
it's not going to change so drastically
that one plants different than the other
and that segment of the industry there
was no such thing as that point sedia
company or a geranium company there
would be a dream grower who grew other
crops but there wasn't this idea that it
was a crop that was special and then if
you look at big AG especially as we have
making its way in a big AG you know one
one year you're gonna have a strawberry
grower and next year he's gonna be a
hemp grower then if he sold his him at a
reasonable price he may be a hemp Brewer
again but if he didn't guess what he's
probably a blueberry grower the next
year because those crops are extremely
different but to change is just a matter
of changing or managing different
variables but they're the same variables
and and so I think once we get that
there will be growth in the industry
that that helps both sides both the food
or animal ornamental producers as well
as the
miss growers I have one more question
based on that so we're seeing rapid
changes like Matt you talked about how
you changed a girl room into like a lab
space now how do people like utilities
like me or other other groups that are
working with this industry keep up with
that rapid change there's constant
consolidation there's constant new
technologies there's always new
customers being added and you could
argue that the new technologies cost
more and maybe should be rebated but how
do we keep up with what's happening so
quickly and make sure that we're not
let's say investing a bunch of money in
grow lights that may not be used as grow
lights in that space within like a year
well this is my opportunity for another
shameless plug for the resource
innovation Institute I think it's
through organizations like that we're
bringing together really smart
like-minded individuals to figure out
you know the base standards and compare
it in an objective way and I'm a real
big fan of proof is in the pudding you
know - so to actually see it being done
and then to be able to kind of compare
that with others who are doing similar
things to figure out the best way of
doing it I'm like this all I do every
day 24/7 and I still feel like it's hard
for me to keep up on it so I wouldn't
feel bad if you if you have those same
kind of apprehensions and I would just
look for those verified trusted sources
like these nonprofits like the ri-ight
for that validated information