[Music]
industrial agriculture is destroying the
Earth we are killing our living soil
contaminating our water and poisoning
ourselves with chemical
pesticides industrial farming is one of
the highest contributors to climate
change releasing an immense amount of
carbon into the
atmosphere the way we grow a plant has
the power to either harm or heal the
[Music]
planet in our current industrial
extractive model we will continue to
take until there is nothing
[Music]
left but there is another path we can
take
[Music]
one of the most powerful things about
cannabis is it's a
psychoactive medicine and what cannabis
has the ability to do
is connect your mind to connect your
soul back to things that are
real I truly believe that a plant is
made out of the soil the water and the
air that it is surrounded
by it uses the energy of the sun to
create its physical matter out of air
and if we are creating a psychoactive
plant we are what we
smoke we have the experience that is
what those plants have
created and I want to connect people
back to Something Real back to the
source that can make us feel whole again
that can make us feel connected with the
world we live in
[Music]
I came from Back to the land
homesteaders who chose to go and find
career
paths I got this opportunity to come
back to this dilapidated Homestead when
I was about 24 years old and the little
cabin that we lived in when I was a baby
was absorbed into the forest and trees
were grown up everywhere and all the
infrastructure was falling apart and I
set about repairing and and rebuilding
our
Homestead we arrived in each other's
lives in Hawaii ran into each other at a
c
bar it was like 6 months after we
started dating you moved here and we got
goats like couple weeks a couple weeks
after Taylor moved here and decided to
do farmers market the next summer yeah
[Music]
I mean when we started switching our
vegetable production over to no till it
was daunting at first the returns maybe
didn't happen that first year or even
the second year as the soil was left
Freer of disturbance from us and got to
get more into its own true balance
flavor was so much better the ability
for that food to stay fresh like you
would Harvest it and a week later it
looked like you had just harvested it
the most vital healthy vibrant food and
that's what I want to see my myself and
my family eating that's what I want to
see my community
eating each transaction I just feel like
I'm handing them a pack of Life Force
energy when we first started farming you
kind of just see the vegetables as the
goal and the deeper you get into it even
one or two seasons into it you start to
see the reverse
image you know you spend all year
working on making this perfect soil it's
alive and complex cover crop is that
vital way of continuing to
photosynthesize and then it's pulling
energy from the Sun pulling carbon out
of the air to build its
structure so it's just watching the
world make itself out of these elements
and then you put it back in it's just
like it's most beautiful
Circle so when I first got here the soil
I had to work with was 6% organic matter
and fast forward a decade of noil
farming and we're at 24% organic matter
that translates to 14% stable
[Music]
carbon that much of an increase in a
decade means we've sequestered nearly
120 tons of carbon on an acre or
equivalent to driving a car for 27 years
[Music]
we have a 60 Acre Farm here in Round
Valley we have a really Diversified Farm
we grow vegetables and
herbs medicinal
cannabis we have sheep and cows and
chickens I grew up in LA but grew up
camping and like kind of super nature
sciency kid decided to study fashion
design and thought I could change the
world through Tex Styles changing the
textile industry then realized that I
really didn't want to be a part of that
industry ended up on a biodynamic farm
in Hawaii had no idea what biodynamics
was and I think that was like a huge
pivotal moment in my
life like Blair I always kind of
considered myself an environmentalist
but wound up uh working out in the oil
rigs uh in the Gulf of Mexico I did a
couple other endeavors they were very
shortlived and then fin farming
stuck I feel like the sheep have a
special place in my heart it was kind of
like the first animals that Daniel and I
owned
together having animals raised on
pasture is a huge gift to the farm and
to the land the grass is able to grow
really easily all it needs is energy
from the Sun and it's able to sequester
carbon into the
soil the animals then eat that grass
they then poop and pee and give back to
the Earth in that way and then we're
able to use their manure in our garden
to make
compost when they're ready to give us
their gift of their bodies that's I
think some of the most nutritious meat
out
there I think there's endless
opportunities for education for a kid on
the farm
just being able to interact with the
animals and interact with the
land the kind of microorganisms that
he's intaking just by being able to
touch the soil touch the compost touch
the poop we don't shy away from any of
that okay keep it in the
[Music]
bowl can you mix it now
okay squ s
yeah yeah yeah we feel so lucky that
we're able to provide the type of food
that we are and know that he's eating
the best possible food that he can be
eating and that I am too and I'm able to
feed him through breastfeeding really
nutritious milk some I like to say I
have certified biodynamic breast
milk Earth who gives to us this food Sun
who makes it rip
dear Earth dear by you we
liveing thanks to you we give blessings
on the meal okay you going to serve
everybody thank you
once people ask me like well what do you
do and I have to try and come up with
like a few sentences to explain it it's
really hard it's it's my whole
life I was a wildland firefighter from
age 19 to 22 coming from the
firefighting world I was very physical
and I needed like a very physical job to
fulfill that and so I got into farming I
couldn't help but notice that Nicholas
was on like this interesting parallel
path but in this whole other way he did
everything on a bike and uh and I would
see him biking around town like like
with his trailer filled with vegetables
I was bartending at this real hip Cafe
in town and he was hired by the C to
provide food well Elizabeth was so sweet
she'd always hooked me up there oh yeah
so that's how I was like chemistry
started maybe in like getting the
freestyle free breakfast and stuff and I
was always kind of committed to like I
don't want it to look like agriculture
yeah cuz I from the beginning was like I
think the problem is
agriculture one of the core components
of a regenerative mindset is to
understand the source of how things
function and to me that's the
soil I think most people are buying
their potting
soil we've never purchased soils to
start stuff with we've always worked
with soils from the animal
yard like a plant that's grown in a pot
in engineered soil will not express
itself the same way as plants grown in
this medium that is a result of
gathering resources from the place I
think it has a lot to do with why our
plants reach such a full
expression and it's so biologically
mature all our fertility is essentially
a result of the animals manures so there
we have a great source of microbiology
from the rumin of many different species
of animals and this is why we don't just
have one variety of animals but like to
make sure we have several because we
like knowing that there's some donkey
some llama some goat and some sheep and
some chickens and all the different
bacteria that are formed in those guts
play a role in our soil so the more
diverse that is the more resilient I
feel like this is and I think that's
that's
key same with the wood chips it's not
like we try to just get one kind of wood
chip it's like the more different types
of wood chips mixed together is actually
the better wood
ship this is a good way I think to
establish a Rel relationship for the
plants to the place and the source of
the soil so that when it goes out it is
already familiar with what it's going
into this is what our soil looks like up
on the
hill I think terroir is just kind of a
fancy
word I simply feel like it's kind of the
energy of the
place but I think the ter
goes deeper in that I think it includes
the mentality and the connection of the
person and people doing the planting and
the and the
growing it has a lot to do with place
and it has a lot to do also with
practices
[Music]
you know when we first got goats I was
looking forward to the milk and the
cheese but they also add this incredible
layer of security to our Homestead they
do brush clearing and fire safety
clearing they connected me deeply into a
system of interacting with animals and
livestock that's been part of human
history for a long time and to be with
these animals you see that they know
this relationship
too industrial agriculture has viewed
every Agricultural Product whether it's
something we eat or something we wear as
something to extract from the earth
something that's there to be taken and
then you'll take it until it's gone and
regenerative agriculture sees the farmer
as one dot in this interconnected Circle
[Music]
regenerative farming that was the
indigenous way of existing that was the
original way of living on this planet
was to regenerate each cycle each year
you had to go into that year with what
it took to make the cycle happen
again we're working to create a buffer
of healthy thriving Forest around our
Homestead selectively removing trees and
material and then pile burning
it reducing the intensity of potential
fire around our
Homestead it's also a project to
increase the health of the forest around
our Homestead too open up more light
down to the forest floor so we get more
species that our goats can eat
you know when I go through the under
story of the forest around here I try to
see it as the old growth forest it could
become people have been using fire to
tend to their environment for thousands
upon thousands of
years what western colonialists and
settlers thought of as this beautiful
untouched Wilderness was a t
Garden we're hoping to bring some of
that knowledge and some of that balance
of fire back to the landscape
I've recently gotten more involved in
policy work before I felt like I didn't
really have the time we were kind of
just in survival mode on the farm but I
feel really fortunate that I have the
opportunity to be involved in
policy could I sorry can I I just wanted
to ask one other thing about about um
just getting questions to the land use
attorney about our different options
moving forward thank you move to a
journ so far the way that the legal
industry has been structured we're just
like extremely separated from the
consumer the consumer goes into these
dispensaries of really no connection to
what this product is in this tiny little
jar
it's really important for us to remove
all those other steps that happen
between flower in the garden to flower
in the consumer's hand so people
understand like hey maybe I don't want
my flower grown under artificial lights
in fake soil using synthetic fertilizers
by you know some big
Corporation actually I want my flower
grown by people who care who are growing
in the soil with actual sunlight and
really creating medicine that's good for
me and good for the
planet there's some big corporate
interests that are really pushing and
guiding policy and the people are really
have been crying out to say stop do not
let this
happen just because that's happened all
over the state doesn't mean we want it
here in Menino
[Music]
County when corporate businesses come in
their sole focus is profit and so
they're not thinking about how do we do
this in the most environmental way
they're thinking about how do we do this
in the most profitable
way my great grandpa was involved in
Chile with a socialist party and kind of
starting the first labor union at the
place that he worked my grandparents
once they moved to this country helped
people during like the Chilean coup
helped refugees coming over and housing
them and and both of my folks were
really involved in like the anti-vietnam
war
movement it's been really instilled in
me that we have to be advocates for each
other and for our communities because
our governments aren't going to do that
for us we really have to have a strong
voice out there in order to fight for
our rights in this world
I was in Academia I was studying ecology
and really trying to like delve into the
depressing sad reality of our world and
how it's degrading and it was just
killing me it was just my heart was
breaking every day
finding regenerative agriculture gave me
all this
hope at one point in my life I really
believe that humans were bad for the
planet and it does not have to be that
way we are good for the planet we're
important for the
[Music]
planet this has been an unusually dry
spring especially in the early side
usually we get a lot of rain in in in
March and April and this year it was
just kind of scary dry but the actual
Garden space where we've put all the
carbon and been working on the increased
organic matter in the soil is actually
really
Lush one of the beauties of growing in
the style that we do is that you have
abundance just all over the
place we have to clear plants so that we
open up a space for a cannabis
plant there's potatoes and onions and
garlic in the way you're harvesting your
potatoes you're making space for your
plant and you're removing your food and
putting in your your
medicine it's all medicine though food
is medicine as
well we just moved here we meet a
neighbor he's this Gruff old man he's
like well good luck growing anything on
that Serpentine Hillside and we like
those words what does that mean like
prophecy you know like those words just
like
[Music]
echoed when you do have this gift of
being able to work with a piece of land
you should understand its history you
should understand what it's been through
you should understand that you're
dealing with land that's been through
trauma the bonds of its caretakers have
been
severed the humans that lived here that
used to care for this area were
separated and as soon as those Bonds
were broken it's it's never been the
same colonizing mentality came in this
property was completely retared and
mined and and then after they mined it
they logged
it when you really start to understand
and see how the land reacts to your
presence and how the land can regenerate
and become better it is possible for us
to make incredible change and do amazing
feats of restoration and
healing so much of what that truly is is
trying to bring as much life as possible
diversity diversity diversity diversity
heals things
[Music]
there's so much happiness that you can
get by just listening to a swarm of bees
just enjoy the
[Music]
garden the cacophony of their wings just
getting after the pollen and the nectar
is just wonderful you see their little
their little saddle bags all stuffed
with pollen and uh it makes me really
happy
genuinely if we can turn this Hillside
into the Garden of Eden it's really a
testament for the practices that we are
committed to and that's really what we
want to try to promote and inspire
people to understand is that that land
needs to be cared for and to care for
land doesn't mean you go to the store to
buy stuff to take care of it
[Music]
I don't think biodynamics has to be for
everyone but what called to me was this
way of talking about stuff in a in a
totally different
way we are utilizing the animal to every
extent that we can as an offering to the
Earth it really is as simple and complex
as
that by taking the time to do these
simple yet mysterious things you're
providing sustenance for Mother
Earth the cow manur stuffed in the cow
horns is buried in the fall equinox
spends its time Underground during the
winter months and then is dug up around
the Spring
[Music]
Equinox yeah not just any old
Kaka baby you got it you got it got it
try harder
[Music]
good when we dig it up in the spring you
get this really rich beautiful dark
humus material and you're able to take
that stir it in water to enliven the
water and enliven the process
[Music]
by do doing it one way and creating
chaos to go back the other way you are
in a sense organizing all the things
that you've put into
that the vortex is a significant energy
force there's the spiritual side of it
that you're dealing with forces in your
mind but then there's the scientific
side that also says there's oxygen going
in which is feeding the
[Music]
microorganisms if you watch the
meanderings of a river the way it wants
to flow is actually vortexes that are
traveling
Downstream this is kind of really
homeopathic minor small doses micro
dosing over time there really starts to
have a positive
effect we want him to understand that
you know it's not necessarily about
farming it's about
relating knowing where the food is not
having some idea that food is from the
store you know because it's from the the
land hopefully he's eaten peaches and
just exploring this relationship to food
cuz food is really a one of the best
ways to connect to the Earth and to the
land because we can all appreciate good
food and you can't appreciate it more
than when you acquire it without going
to the store to make it happen
[Music]
pull it hard pull it down like
this see beans she's picking berries
see she's eating berries off of a
bush she finds the good ones too she
eats all the good one she does she's
really good at getting
[Music]
them so I grew up in Salt Lake City Utah
couldn't be a more different cultural
setting than humble California and I
love to do this little thought exercise
of whisking my 18-year-old self here and
showing myself that I'm raising children
on a pot farm in the woods and it would
have it would have seemed insane I would
have considered myself endangering the
children and so I try to keep that
perspective in my mind when I imagine
how this looks from the
outside I grew up around cannabis a lot
my stepdad grew and it was a big secret
you'd go to school and they'd be having
the Dare program where the cops would be
trying to talk you into turning your
parents in for for drugs I mean talk
about having the opposite effect uh we I
took the dare you know yeah we grew up
in the prohibition
era I think it's important to normalize
like what a cannabis farmer is or
diversify the idea of what a cannabis
farmer
is it is just a
plant if my kid touches a pot leaf
they're not going to get high and we
don't treat the plant differently than
we treat our other plants and we don't
think that we have
to obviously Edibles are a whole other
you know a whole other thing but when
you're talking about a plant in a garden
it's a completely different thing just
like you're talking about a grape and a
Vineyard and what we're still doing in
this fear around it is like really
unnecessary you know it made us really
nervous because we were growing cannabis
before cannabis was regulated in the
current way that it is and as we started
to have kids was one of the reasons that
it pushed us into going through
compliance and and getting a legal
cannabis farm is that we really didn't
want our kids to grow up with the
secrets we wanted them to understand and
be proud of what their parents do see it
as actual work rather than hearing from
society that their parents are drug
dealers or or whatever and then also not
having to carry the burden of a secret
and the responsibility of if you mess up
it's dangerous for your family
we're just beginning to bring our summer
crops to Market cucumbers tomatoes
zucchini basil green
beans classic summer stuff that people
get really excited
about the now the real Tetris
begins let's
go I'm going fast you're going fast
1450 I this you ate that one yeah nice
is it tasty yeah okay good I eat this
guy you're eating that guy he likes to
call it guys this guy this
guy how about this
guy about this guy about that guy I'm
taking a box of these okay for my little
granddaughters oh nice because uh we
happen to like raspberries oh
good see you later
thank
you day see
[Music]
you in this case what I'm doing is I'm
I'm hunting out the most
tropical fruity candy nose I can come up
with and I'm mashing genetics that both
share that same characteristic into each
other so this is the early stages and it
takes years to really develop lines this
is the hunting phase there's some like
rank kind
of
poopy fruity say it's like it's like
your your baby's been eating too much
[Music]
fruit I love this this feno right here
this is like I'm like it's Perfection I
was like what else do you want Oh and it
stinks
oh ew yes
so sweet gas baby gorgeous gorgeous
gorgeous
gorgeous so we're looking
at these are straw Nana frosting
uh AC cross that we made here with a
cutting of strawberry banana and then
the vanilla frosting it seems to be
capturing both it has the the berry
flavor but then with this like sweet
icing
finish
uh I feeling strong vanilla right here
gas and
grapes um and then it it follows me
around for the rest of the day after
doing
this because it's in the
mustache hey big
guy I'm between two uh rows of fullterm
seed start Cherry Lime
dog they're beautiful they're ready to
[Music]
harvest this is uh the apricot bling
crossed with the eagle scout train wreck
it's tining forward but there's this fuy
fruity musk it's kind of got me at all
angles like the way Thai food has like
that sweet Savory salty sharp everything
the smell version of that where it's
like fruit and pining and Fuel and musk
and all of it kind of coming together at
once when we decided to become a
compliant Farm there was this Vision
that we could finally meet our customers
visions of Farmers Market booth with our
vegetables and our cannabis and just
this lovely idea it made us really
hopeful and excited and then as we
entered the legal Market there were so
many blocks so many walls between us and
the customers in some ways more than
before California has created and many
states that have gone legal have created
kind of like a spider web of traps of
bureaucracy we can't take cannabis to
customers we have to work through a
distributor it has to be packaged it has
to be tested it has to get to retail so
basically you have the system of
multiple places along the way every
place along the way wants to take a cut
of the profit a lot of times you'll see
cannabis on the shelves in California
that's over a year old because it took
eight months just to get from the farmer
to the Shelf through all the hands that
it has to pass through the bud loses
quality it loses tricomes and out of
that was born this idea of Farm Cut Farm
Cut Is minimally processed with just the
sugar leaves we want to share like a
true Farm stack stash and a true Farm
stash is a mason jar full of untrimmed
weed it's because it stays better that
way and you start breaking away your
your leaves to prep it it's
fresh every plant has to be tagged with
a plastic tag with an RFID chip that
becomes garbage after you use it once I
don't enjoy putting them on the plants I
don't enjoy taking them off I don't
enjoy hauling them to the dump I don't
enjoy getting them in the mail it's this
difficult balance to be a
regenerative cannabis Farmer in the
recreational Market we care so deeply
about wanting to provide this ethical
clean product for people and then we
have to wrap it in plastic and separate
it out into grams and leaves and little
plastic containers and you know it's
just awful it's a terrible
trash producing industry right
now and so we have been endeavoring in
compostable packaging and minimally
processed and at an economic price and I
think some of the the real Drive behind
the E ounce is like when we think about
who we want to be accessing our cannabis
it's the people that love
it we want to give them something that
that's really high quality at a
reasonable price and the only way you
could do that is in larger
quantities as a farmer you make a very
very small percentage of what the
customer actually pays for that product
that you
produced 5 to six maybe 7% if you're
lucky
and so that wouldn't make sense for a
small farm large Farms can scale up
enough that profit can work but it means
growing acres and Acres we don't plan to
survive as a farm under that model we
plan to survive long enough until that
model changes and if that model doesn't
change you won't see small Family Farms
growing quality cannabis in the hills of
humble you'll see massive Central
Valley commodity crop farms
[Music]
the largest Marana Greenhouse in
California it can produce enough Pok to
supply the entire United
States this this this is the classic
business problem isn't it how do you get
the cost down and maintain your quality
how are you doing that you know that's a
great question we uh we right now grow
in 500,000 Square ft and we've been
doing it since 2016 so we had to learn
um on the Fly because there was nobody
growing at that scale it was it was new
people were growing in closets not in
huge green houses but the person that's
that built this 6 million or sorry 5
million5 uh sare foot Greenhouse he's
he's helping us with it because he's
grown other um vegetables and things
like that so we're confident that we'll
be able to do it
all right let's go hang this shit let's
go hang it up
f
[Music]
Harvest is always a exciting joyful
stressful time a few years back we had a
series of cold mornings low 20s and lost
significant percentage of the garden to
be out there and to see the plants
covered in ice is not easy it was like
holy shit like is this really happening
again and we do know like through
vegetable production that certain plants
can handle frost more than other plants
some plants can't handle it at all and
luckily cannabis is one of those plants
that can handle a certain
[Music]
degree from looking droopy and sad to
then just perky and ready to greet the
sun they were ready yeah
[Music]
we're in a beautiful place right now
where we can reverse the damage that has
been done there's a movement that has
huge momentum right now and small
farming is the key and resolution to so
much of the problems in the world and
it's important for us to be independent
from Corporation
and to be independent in our food
production and build Connections in
community Through food I think that's a
lot of what is lost in the world now and
away from this digital world and having
our hands in the earth I think would
heal so
much we're a tiny Farm but the practices
we're putting in place the amount of
carbon that you can pull out of the
atmosphere and put into your soil if
this was happening at the industrial
scale you know it would hugely change
the course we're
on and I picture our farm as this tiny
little postage stamp of change and
pulling in this tiny little postage
stamp amount of carbon but then I
picture what that would look like if
every little farm was doing something
like
that I've always thought like if a
person grows a garden it is the most
pure expression of their soul that you
can see you know some people are like
you should write a book like how do you
how how to book and I'm like no it will
be different for every single person and
how cool is that you know like I want to
see everyone's Garden what in Eden if
everybody if every human could have a
couple acres to just grow their Garden
that's the Eden I'd love to see happen
[Music]
our farm name is folk life farm and then
our cannabis brand is radical herbs
that's spelled r a d i CLE e the radical
is the first rout to emerge from a seed
any seed the greater World wants to tell
you that to be radical is to be a fringe
to be you know on the periphery and not
really
grounded but when you look at the root
of the word to be radical is to be
grounded because the radical is the root
and it's the rest of the world that's
crazy if you are grounded and you are
aware of your surroundings and you
listen to your intuition that is what
the world needs right now it needs
radical people and that's what farming
has done for
us farming has kind of allowed me to to
be uh grounded
[Music]
radical because that's what we're trying
to do right now I think is right we're
trying to replace the current Paradigm
of industrial agriculture because it's
not working it's destroying the
environment and we're not looking to
destroy anything we're looking to
replace what is currently happening with
a better system and it it means
everybody has to get involved if you
want to eat vegetables only that's great
but you should find it locally if you
want to eat meat too that's great but
you should find it locally I'm trying to
be like polite and say we're not trying
to destroy anything we're trying to
replace it but we are looking to destroy
the industrial food model I think it
needs to be destroyed and from that is
going to emerge stronger local
communities that are taking this stuff
into their own
hands over the last three billion years
Nature has finally tuned herself to
connect soil air and water in infinite
cycles that support all life on this
planet
[Music]
unlike the industrial model which will
eventually destroy the
Earth a regenerative system works with
nature giving back more than it
takes we are currently using 38% of the
earth's land for
[Music]
agriculture if we start to use
regenerative practices on a fraction of
this land
we can sequester enough carbon to undo
some of the damage we've
done as we experience more extreme
destruction every year due to climate
change there is an urgent need to act
now technology is not going to save us
from Total ecological coll
[Music]
collapse the solutions are right in
front of us and always have
been the future as was the past is
regenerative
[Music]
oh oh
a
[Music]
w