[Music]
No until recently like last couple years
that this was even the thing with Oh our
resumes are huge that's okay cool and
then it's like sometimes I see it in
people who live in our you know a night
but I don't know what all the factors
are if it's just that if it has to do
with the Sun to do with our soil the
soil some sort of combination of things
maybe because the UV intensity because
you know in our Valley area you know
like it's just hard to say I could be a
lot of factors it's pretty intense in
the summer yeah it's like it's but it's
almost desert like in the valley it's
very interesting because like you go out
on the river plane where where I kind of
right on the edge and yeah if you go out
there in the middle of the day in the
summer itself the desert feels like and
you're on these edge of that and we're
on the edge of that and then on the
other side of that is a little more
yeah more on the other on the coastal
side of the mountain is definitely
higher rainfall for sure so we're kind
of in a banana boat well it's
interesting to explore there's so many
there's a lot of variables we'd have to
really really do it me like yeah to know
for sure I I don't think it's cultivar
specific because we have seen the same
cultivars you know they're not
necessarily look that way whether other
people have done the same exact cutting
or seed stock or anything it's so it's
not necessarily that but I think it must
be a combination
it's not one yeah I don't think there's
one reason unless I think a lot of it
you know has to do with with the natural
farming - I think cannabis and likes
being harmed this way you know and I
think it responds - yeah I have I think
you know likes being farm naturally I've
noticed with a lot of the natural
farmers they have their wheat is like an
expression of their place in a different
way you know what I mean like there's a
lot of the weed that are just like oh
this is commercial weed you know what I
mean it's all the same but everybody who
does natural farming there's like a
something special about it because it's
their connection to their land and it's
their own unique creativity and it's
solutrean that's their that's the thing
is there's a lot of style to it it's
like there's a lot of art to it and and
so I mean you're not you're never gonna
see the same thing twice in any
performance and the flowers have their
performance - and we're just
collaborating with them but but
ultimately when you're really letting
the flowers and the biological
intelligence of the soil and of the land
express itself then I mean amazing
things keep happening they're evolving
as they're they're evolving for us to
select from their amazingness you know
so like we're just we're just the people
at the end of the day they get to be
like oh I want come on out one like that
one and they're the ones really
dictating their own evolution and people
are really receiving a lot of amazing
test results coming generator starts you
know like where it's like 30 plus
percent they're like total cannabinoids
you know above 35 total skandhas
cannabinoids a mere 10% other amazing
really interesting terpene profiles and
high numbers and you think well that's
like one thing I noticed like in I don't
have my farm much but I when I go to
different events like I don't like the
commercial events but if I do go to them
the products a lot more similar and what
I think is super cool along the the
wonderful things I learned and the
wonderful conversation I have are great
but something cool is like these like
you guys are saying about likely in the
morning than natural farming community
you have this like oh this is this
random across off my Hill like my
neighbor's dad like worked at now I've
been working with it for a while and
like that's just really cool if somebody
have these really crazy different
experience
the I don't know that that I do that is
too super super cool to like and then
the stories that go with that like some
of the varieties I'm sure you see it in
your local region you know maybe some
older legacy farmers that are like hey
we have like that's where the best
things come from we've worked with this
you know stuff has been handed down it
takes a long time and it's been a lot of
people's hands and work it was it's not
like and even the people who really were
like the keepers of the Lions and the
breeders the elders the holders like
generation that brought a lot of these
seeds out to the hills and started
working with them you know they had tons
of people that were instrumental in
helping them acquire all these things
like none of us did it alone like the
library that we hold today that we're
working with is an extreme privilege an
honor to be working with but you know it
is like it took so many people's hands
along the way to to bring a catalog of
genetics together like that and to take
the time over I need it like a joint
you've got a simulated Randy yeah it's
like a scotch or yeah but it's you know
it's it's very special to the cultural
heritage of all of these different
little regions in the Triangle
especially is all of the stuff that
we've been
keeping as communities you know and then
circles of friends and family and
sharing it and and so now this whole you
know explosion of like everything that's
happening with genetics and with
technology and just in all realms even
aside cannabis but here we are the
keepers of all of this biodiversity you
know there's people like us all over the
world who are cannabis you know with all
seeds with all plants something that
we're gonna lose if we let another
generation go by where we don't try and
keep this information you know what I
mean like we did we didn't grow up no
work you know like doing this our
grandparents did our parents our parents
like remember their grandparents stuff
but like it's it's almost lost you know
yeah and the thing that's really
interesting is you know with biodynamic
farming and so when Rudolf Steiner gave
his lectures they were having these
concerns in in the 20s you know that was
a hundred years ago and so it's
concerning and that was before even
synthetic fertilizers that was they were
how they were providing their fertility
they were start when they first started
outsourcing fertility and changing the
way they were raising animals and not
keeping that system integrated and mono
cropping and separating so in
traditional natural farming methods your
fertility is coming from the land it's
basically you're taking all the manures
and wastes and byproducts of all the
living things on the land and things
that fall and all that goes into the
soil as waste the soil consumes it and
makes it available as nutrition for the
next generation of seeds to grow and
it's a closed system of fertility or an
integrated cycle that all works together
so that you don't have to spend money or
go outside of your immediate locality to
source your fertility it's renewable but
we changed the way we farmed about a
hundred years ago and it was essentially
peasant farming and and it really wasn't
necessarily fair for people and so you
know we've gone through a lot of
different different issues with like
people's rights and stuff flora we've
gone away from peasant farming too but
for the health and how we need to be
feeding ourselves and working with the
land like that kind of farming is in
tune with nature and it's connected
it's it's a part of it it's it's
actually how we evolved from nature you
know and it's our what we're supposed to
be doing with ourselves we're very
machine oriented Daniel from radical
herbs gave a really awesome biodynamic
stalk yesterday and he was talking about
some of the signer concepts about how
it's very mineral oriented and we're so
obsessed with machines and making
machines to do everything we're not
connected with the natural world anymore
and so you know when we do connect with
the natural world amazing things start
to happen that we we see them happening
without science to explain it and then
when we bring science in to explain it
it's like well it only maybe when we
maybe understand a little bit more about
what's happening but we're just reassign
is just there to explain the phenomena
the phenomena is a mystery and when we
participate with the mystery then the
magic happens and science is like oh
let's take some observations on that
magic because like we've we've been
doing this like and we've been finding
like what we didn't know we could grow
weed that tested like that you know what
I mean we weren't really thinking about
the testing but that's amazing or like
we didn't know that when we picked the
trichomes at that ripeness well when you
we had somebody out who takes very very
very macro photos and that are like
every five microns he has a picture in
focus and a trichome is you know like 73
under 90 or so and I mean what they look
like when they're actually right and
it's just like I have no idea and then
you see indoor trichomes and they're
just these clear plain bland little
things you know I don't know we don't
really run into a lot of indoor hydro
doors here honestly but usually we just
I like to smoke like we like to show
people in each other's weed right and
and because people love weed and you
know I don't usually talk shit to people
I'm here I try be I'm nice about it even
though I have my convictions and was
like you know to each their own I don't
really feel like like I'm into my thing
and you can be in your thing but
usually people are in it's I like it
when I talked to a hydro grower and
they're like well your weed and I'm like
yeah this is my full term outdoor and I
made everything I didn't you know like
we still buy animal feed but aside from
that we try to really be conscious about
like everything being crafted to go that
goes into it and making our own composts
all the way to all our own fertilizers
and vinegars and various so what's three
things so the compost making is we kind
of we do buy more by the biodynamic
guidelines with the preps and and so
we've been practicing that and so it's
just refining and getting better at that
than building piles of layers and but
what I've been experimenting with more
lately is our rainwater pond which is
that I can open reservoir and so we had
we did some like water testing and we
found
it has above adequate phosphorus we have
like a high bat population that comes
every night meets the mosquitoes that
that growth you know so we're trying to
create it like an ecosystem with that
they fly over the over the pond and so
we're trying to use we're trying to use
the pond yeah we're like realizing we
can use this it's not necessarily an
aquaponics system but it's kind of like
it's a it's it's like a it's kind of
like aquaponics cuz we have a lot of
frogs we have a lot of you know we're
encouraging it to be habitat although
we're not necessarily supposed to like I
feel like you know the regs according to
the regulations but you know like I
don't care we're doing something good
with it that's well that's a Bobo node
that's me that's a bullfrog management
plan a little bit different but just in
general is that you can make habitats
you can't take it away and that's where
it gets very difficult in terms of using
our water source I assume that this is
like not in any way shape and in stream
ponds that you guys know it's solely so
origin is like the catchment surfaces of
our buildings so but that being said
we're we're trying to create this we're
trying to use this stored water to
create benefits to the whole landscape
right and so we're bringing in bats
we're bringing in yellow-legged frogs
which are to threaten new species and
they might be interested as endangered
soon but there's everywhere all over our
place and that that's beautiful you know
and then we bring in the green hair and
then the
here and he comes sometimes and and so
this year what we want to do is when we
go do willow get our willow for basket
making and we're gonna keep them supple
in the pond and we're basically using
that to make a big willow tea that we're
watering over the whole garden and and
we're using these combining all of these
different things to like make more
fertility and make more abundance not
just for us but for for everybody you
know not so you know other farmers but
also like the plants and animals that
we've live around this home it's been
really cool to see stuff start to really
explode after we've been at it for a few
years yeah