one thing I will say because of my
expense in the CCA that the one thing
where labs and manufacturers come come
together on is is where testing happens
right so in a lot of industries right
especially Pharma right so you don't
test the product in its final package
right you test the product in its final
form right but you can be delivered that
final form in bulk to test its
quarantine until I get the coa and then
everything's hunky-dory and you release
it then they can package it and go right
in our industry we have to receive it in
its final package right which means
childproof packaging blister packaging
oh and great babe cartridges dude it
takes to get enough sample and we're
only talking like two and a half or
three grams total right all right so we
got to go through especially if it's
half gram cartridges well you can only
get two tenths of a gram maybe three
tenths of a gram I'm out of a half-game
cartridge right so if I'm trying to get
three grams right that's how I'm looking
at 10 to 15 cartridges that have to be
opened well that's about 30 minutes of
time so now I charge my customers labor
right for that kind of stuff I have to
all right otherwise I don't make back my
margin on my tests and it's not fair to
them it's not fair to us but it's the
way the regular regulations are written
and it's just one of those things where
manufacturers are pushing for testing at
final at final formulation or final
product but not final package the lab
has been screaming about this for two
frickin years dude because before they
went into the the real rights wanted to
effect this the past year or you know
the year before under the the temporary
you know practice regs was still in
cartridges right and we were still
complaining back then two years ago
right