[Music]
are you oh dial yes it's uh we haven't
actually sat down together with with a
microphone in front of us in almost 25
years probably yeah yeah early nineties
yeah the early name had no idea what
year it was you know I think it was 99
okay so that's 19 years now 19 years ago
I think 20 see more easy well rounded up
to 20 I'm good with that
and I know neither of us were thinking
about legalization back then no and you
remember we had the discussion at that
time in the positronic s-- absolutely
hydro versus biome it became known as
the great hydro versus bio to hold whole
the High Times Magazine issue or even
two or three laughs were about that
whole thing you know yes and I remember
you won the competition with 51% against
49 so we did a blind test so we had like
a hundred blind samples
half of them were hydro and half of them
were biome and then we weren't gonna say
okay the people have to figure out which
one was hydro which one is bio and it
was 51 51 49 that's what Vander was
there he was supposed to bio me yeah so
we set it up but still until now it's
funny we're sitting here I still am
completely bio in hydro so if you look
at my Newton company how is it is it
completely organic
uh-huh and the other half is minerals
which is not completely hydro but uh-huh
and my menus are still half bio organic
and half so you're 50/50 I'm always been
50/50 yeah yeah I have numbers numerous
reasons for that main reason is that
personally I love bio
I think organic is the way to go aha
because on the long run it's very very
good for our planet but there are some
situations where we have to feed a lot
of people
and where it can be also environmentally
friendly when we recycle all the water
and where we can also do a good hydro
job that's very very well put I liked it
I'm from Africa I don't forget that I
know we have serious problems in Africa
with food so where we can feed more
people you're right and then we
technically have to do to maybe some
situation to a hydro system you know I'm
in favor of there to save lives that's
where I come you're very smart like I
love to be able to debate but I can't
that was so well put you know because
water is a pretty is the most precious
resource of all yeah sure it's the most
important thing on our planet sure and
so I I congratulations on the new
organic line by the way yeah you know me
I'm not 5050 no no I go like this I go
no thank you and I usually turn it away
yeah I have a very picky palate yeah I'm
I'm a little bit of a weed snob yeah you
know I don't mean to disrespect anybody
I'm just a very sensitive palate yeah no
listen don't get me wrong now you know I
used to be chef in the old days and it's
all about I have three three three
Michelin star friends so organic food
for me is by far the better food in the
world also when I smoke but you know I
also like to play with hydro in a grow
room you know sure I like to blow up
that plant sure it would nutrients it's
also a hobby so I like to do both when
you come to my factory now in cream or
we have this huge factory with canopy to
wear cream or Toronto Canada so we are
gonna produce next year between 10 and
15 tonnes and half of the factory's
hydro and other half of the factories I
buy oh and even father half of the
factory is HPS and the new half of the
factory's LED you know you make you you
sound you make it sound so harmonious
yeah when you you blend these things
together yeah yeah you don't favor one
over the other and there's been there's
pros and cons in life to pretty much
everything and same thing goes with
cultivation yeah you know me I'm stuck
with just poor old beginnings well it's
a little bit the same with shitty
versioning because you know we had this
debate with so many people uh-huh
all my friends including our friend
Franco past unfortunately away yes
totally
indica indica indica all day long but
I'll be high all day long it was yeah
really yeah he didn't like the sativa
Wow okay she'll ease along with me maybe
to make me feel happy uh-huh
but no no Arianna listen we have red
wine and we have whiskey
I wonder whiskey okay I want the red
wine but also I miss the Teva guy - yeah
I know that I know and you know but a
negative smoke the end again I just yet
but why are you Steve agai because of
celebra high or the taste no because of
that I can work I also like to taste
much more than any cut to be honored to
be honest talk about real sativa 7 15
for 16 weeks and nothing once you get in
America ah come on now you know you have
you ever used smoke my Strawberry Cough
10 weeks yeah but that's 40% indica no
it's 25% now it's more I'm talking about
longer I hear you
yes you're right I don't don't get me
wrong I love that plan but it's a great
I still my favorites that he's not
twenty it's not for it's not it's for
it's it's 40% indigo you think come on
come on yeah come on be fair heights you
cannot have you cannot have 10-week
plant that's 25% indica so let me ask
you you don't watch a lot of television
okay you don't know I don't have time
unfortunately of course I did I recently
did a really interesting episode of
explained on Netflix yeah and I was they
were asking me about the labeling issue
you know about people going into the
shop and wanted to buy indica and being
able to say that this is you know what
it is and it's such an issue yeah
and what I ended up getting into was
talking about how a plant because it's
everything so mixed up nowadays yes that
a plant can have just like almost like
human sexuality you know the range is is
why does as can be so you can have an
indica plan with sativa growth
characteristics yes or a sativa plant
with indica growth characteristics yes
okay so you just agreed with me that I
could have a sativa that has ten
well characters well I can even tell you
even more crazy yeah
yes and no I'm gonna tell you something
that you probably don't know what I just
figured out it's like 10 years ago when
I made my Indian movie so there's a lot
of seats growing us in the mulana and
provocative Valley in India because of
my background you know you know I'm from
Africa remember no 92 I opened the first
coffee shop where you were always guest
and all the hippies came from India with
the Milani and the charros and whatever
you know the same seeds that I grow down
in the valley on let's say a
thousand-meter 1200 meter that were
indica seeds indica plants I grew them
up on 2400 meters that turned out to be
sativas that is interesting that is
completely flabbergasting I was still we
cannot put our finger beyond we did that
test three times and plan just changed
and this is not documented nowhere and
you know sometimes I speak about it so I
know that's why I said yes or no to your
to your story and it's really
interesting yeah there's the crater that
is really crazy yeah this is word for
that in by in by all in plant biology
something more well I can't pay more for
diet or something yeah yeah well I never
went to college probably you also not I
know I haven't so we all like we're
natural-born growers right well I have
to say I did two years with you remember
the clone guy yeah hurry up you know it
was the supplier of winter by the way
lawns okay you remember when when I had
all those clones of course they were all
from butea okay and with him together I
went two years to the hosta hhas that
was the higher agaric school mm-hmm yeah
and there with the tissue culture and
protocol infusion so actually there was
the only two years that I went one day a
week to school how long what will you
resign I was I was thirty years old so
it's 23 years ago Wow it served you well
I want to do yeah
you
[Music]