someone had asked the question about a
kind of like a nursery you know per
square foot how what was the question
that you answered and you just like
broke it down oh yeah they were asking
you know how much how much can I get off
of an operation and it's basically just
takes 60% of the operation and call it
call it functional
this 40% is going to be you know
workable movement you know around stock
if if the conventional problem we have
love the stock and then a 32 square foot
table in terms of grid form can do about
2,000 clones a month and then that one
table roughly you know if we if we have
two thousand we take and refine it to
say sixteen we could put sixteen hundred
clones and every eight square foot of
space so it's eight so it's about 40
square foot for table and for subsequent
rack to hold it over the course of a
month because it takes about two weeks
just strike roots and then it takes
about two weeks for the plants to kind
of come back to carnival form so this is
rhythm that you work with once you dial
in the size of the plants and your
gridding and the 40% space which we've
taken off the top is holding racks it's
work space things that let you do
transition but if you're in if you're in
nursery business I think a lot of people
you know what they do is they produce
stock and then they send you out list to
go look for it and for me my my method
had always been to acquire clients
previous so I had a different approach
to move in plants then a lot of people
did so what it did is as soon as I had
the plant ready it we called you and you
came and picked it up and so what it did
is it allowed me to have a much more
efficient rotation in my racks so that I
didn't have to have so much redundant
holding space right so the main thing is
if you got 10,000 square foot it means
you've got 6,000 square for the work
space and if you take that 6,000 square
foot and you divide about 40 that'll
give you 2,000 clones plus 1600 on a
rack per month with my
stocke kind of what's from your
perspective a healthy mom like how many
clippings you can take per week and then
what were some strategies that you've
used to kind of increase the weekly
yield or whatever your measurement of
number of clippings per time period well
the first part is that with when it
comes to healthy mom it's really about
hormone hormonal dominance in terms of
juvenility what the plan is expressing
itself as a juvenile plant and it's
tissue is extremely herbaceous and it's
cellular growth is really fast because
that's what we want to capture in a
clone and so the bigger older plants use
that on the interior and you only end
getting it on the tips so you end up
having a lot of space devoted to
something that gives you relatively few
clones so I would rather have rotations
of plants constantly weaving through the
mother op so if you if you were to take
plants and put them in three gal and say
we get you know 50 plants per table that
that that table would take me probably
40 days from planting to cuttable form
once I cut it though I'm on 2,000 plants
a month off that table and I'd like to
run it for at least two months so I'd
get four cuts off of it I don't cut it
every week and cut it on a cycle and so
the once we once we build them and the
building part is a part that people
don't catch is that you're gonna come in
and you got to shape them and soft tip
them so you can start to defuse the
hormones and create the skeleton and
then you have to come in and clean out
the skeleton so did you get the real
shape that you want so that it's really
symmetrical and then that plant now
allows you to have a beautiful display
of clonal material on a grid that gives
you an incredible amount of clones per
square foot so and I and I like these
methods because for most people that are
working in their own world having a very
efficient small nursery for themselves
or for their operations is ideal where
every new space is great and don't get
me wrong more square footage is never
bad it's just that for most people they
don't have on
square footage and so you can realize
you don't need a lot of space to be able
to generate a lot of plants and the the
was the question we don't get so happy
about talking about kalam plants where
was the what was the first question we
were talking on that one rotation I was
talking about help so the rotation is if
I could get four cuts for good cuttings
off the plants that means that that
single plant that single tree Guilin
plant gave me a hundred and sixty clones
over a two-month period so that single
square foot was worth $1,600 so eight
hundred bucks a month per square foot in
mother production but that's really
effective money you don't know I mean so
like for me you if you can get four cuts
off that mom and then slide another mom
in that you've already started to build
so once you build a table you can have
another table that you're building with
smaller plants it takes 45 days to build
a plant but part of it is in that early
stage where they're in threes and then
they're saying ones and you're getting
this the frame and the structure shaped
then you can shift it in so four by four
of one is going to be able to transform
into a full four by eight threes so you
don't need as much space to build the
chain but the actual square footage per
yielding amount of mother's stock comes
down to those plants and so say we go to
five gallons of cocoa right then all
we're doing is we're still going into
that same amount per square foot we're
just getting it off of a larger plant
and I like plants that are in the three
gallon range if we're going to do push
and if it's organically built where
you're you're doing full organic bottom
and I almost have to go into like a
seven otherwise I'm having to run too
many T's through it continuously I don't
have enough in the sink to do top
dressing but the problem with seven
gallon pots is that you know you take
the pot right out of the table and you
put it on a spindle so I had these
chairs you sat down and that had
spinner and the plant would sit on the
spinner and you could turn it with your
feet and that way you could sit down and
take all the cuts off the plant and
clean it up and then put it back because
if the workers having to bend over this
shit they're miserable and so if you're
having you know good production from
your cloners you want to make it so that
it's easy on them to do the harvesting
and so plants that are too big
become difficult to physically move and
and spin around and then plants that are
too small require too much of a frequent
irrigation and so it's it's easier if
you're setting stuff up to where in in
in our world in humble County we've had
so many power problems and so many water
problems like we live in the country
even though it's it's got full
infrastructure the weather and some of
the issues here shut down in your world
and so I try to create a system where I
always have a little bit of a buffer on
immediacy of watering it's the same
reason why I came up with putting up
perlite in the bottom of the tray under
the Oasis tray that's not for irrigation
it's the opposite you actually it's
really not the best way to use an oasis
media or rock wall is to put it on a
secondary drain matrix because it
changes the water height column in the
cube itself it's so that when the plants
root they have a secondary matrix to go
into so that you can always lay a layer
of moisture in that right in that
perlite grid that doesn't completely
saturate the upper grid but allows you
to have a hold ability the plan if you
suddenly have in clients that don't show
up for a week or we have temperature
that goes up to 110 and they decide they
want to shut the power lines down
because we're having fires in a region
around us which happens here so I don't
like to have plants that are driven
heavy in smaller pots because ultimately
if I have any issues at all and I wilt
the moms then what I'm doing is I'm
destroying $800 a square foot of
production so like with my own stock and
mother operations once you efficiently
build a grid they're very valuable and
so you have to kind of create a system
that works to fit your tray
fit your Carter's to fit the amount
material you're moving through most
people when they do nursery prop they
always build way more than they need
because they don't have the business and
then they go try to sell this shit and
that's not the way you approach nursery
because nurseries not isn't something
you can put on the shelf and hold and I
see it constantly in the ads that I get
bombarded with where you're trying to
sell me a clone and then you're trying
to sell me a cheaper clone and the
picture it's like nine ten inches tall
now and then you're trying to sell me
something in soil because you
transplanted them then you're trying to
sell me a teen because you transplant it
again and then finally your nursery
doesn't exist anymore because you spent
too much money trying to build an
operation that you couldn't sell the
plans and so all that stuff has to fit
into your density and operational
characteristics of your mother's and so
I know some nurseries that run you know
current culture under current systems
and they get phenomenal root development
in those buckets and the plants that
come out the top a massive and they
they're using tissue culture derived
plants to begin it and that system where
I don't know there's square-foot numbers
but I know the clones coming off
beautifully so you know there's no magic
way to do it it's just that each
situation has to work for you and the
greater the degree of complexity the
greater degree of infrastructure
security you have to put into play or if
it backfires it'll wipe you out good how
long is a mom and the rotation and
you're in your setup like before
essentially she gets retired oh I'd like
to see two months I'd like to see four
cuts come off I'd like to see it take 45
days to build her and then she lives for
another 60 as a form and then I can't
and then I can take her in composter so
we had a big compost so it's a short
short life cycle yeah yeah it has to be
because the problem that you get too is
that you know you've got so many issues
in in cannabis in terms of pathogens and
everyone's experiencing this now we're
like oh they go whoa haven't hold a
couple hundred thousand plants in your
hands it's it
a lot tougher than holding 20 and you
you get spots where you can't see
pathogens move in and then they just go
wild in the operation and so the bigger
older plants because their canopy is so
thick there that's where they hide and
so with smaller plants that you're
cutting two times a month you can take
the plant right out of the table and
then spray it good you can because
you're gonna lay all your beneficial
predation in but the bottom line is when
you're constantly cutting plants at a
nursery you're you're you're delivering
with the clone the beneficial predation
it leaves you don't shake it off when
you cut it you just cut and quagga them
well they're in the tray they're in the
build and then when the clone when that
when the plants leave while your
beneficial predation leaves with it so
you constantly happen to inoculate the
plants within the nursery itself and
using something even simple as like a
Bronner's peppermints so just to knock
stuff down and to make sure that any
soft body insect it's going to get
desiccated using some kind of a good
fogging spray system just makes it
really easy when the plants are whole
double and moveable and you know it just
makes it really really containable so
easy you know this is the longer the
plant lives with you the more more more
more at home it becomes and things start
to live in it and it's that's why you
want to flush him out and I've had moms
that I've kept like for years non-stop I
mean they had to stem on in the size of
a you know like a leader soda bottle and
I mean and it was the but it was it was
like my favorite plan ever because I
grown it for four years at this building
and I just kept bringing it back down in
shape and height so it almost looked
like a sprawling maple tree you know it
had kind of bonsai dup but bottom line
is per square foot it did not deliver
the same amount that you get off a flat
platform right so I I know you your
nursery just has a single client but
have you been following kind of the
nursery market answer the question so
the quite the question is nurseries that
you know obviously there's a
of nurseries in terms of quality and
reputable 'ti but for nurseries that you
respect out there kind of what price
trends have you been seen in terms of
you know if someone wants to buy 5,000
10,000 20,000 50,000 clones kind of what
price trends are you seeing and the per
clone cost you know that's funny I don't
know like I mean to be honest I hear the
range of prices but I don't know the
actual number is being cut because the I
I know whose produces some good work but
because I don't purchase clones from
them and any time anybody sends me any
kind of like clone pricing lists through
on the internet because of my email tied
into through our licenses I just I cut
that shit out so I'm not buying anything
I I don't know I think that you're
probably looking and it depends but I
think that you know and it's something
that would be a teen would be about 20
bucks if you're talking seed stock up to
you know your knee like coming out of
plant Humboldt I think those plants are
closer to like you know 25 to 40 the I
think the goal of some of the new
nurseries on the tissue culture end is
to get them on the $5 range where you're
getting a $5 tissue culture plant that
is flawless you know and so I'm paying
attention to nurseries and operational
stuff but I'm not involved in the sale
so it's funny I mean I'm is deep in
prompt as I could be but not on the sale
end of it because of the way I work with
my contract so I'm kind of out of the
business and nurseries but not the tech
I'm involved with other nurseries and
doing tech and assessment and then
helping establish the libraries of what
you're actually running and why you're
running it because a lot of times with
nurseries people get into it but they
just go buy plants from somebody but
they don't really understand why they're
buying I mean who's smoking it and what
you doing with it and so the issue is
that nurseries end up producing some
really premium products of things that
the market doesn't want to buy so if you
know I mean for real and and so it's
pretty rampant and so for me because
I've had so many years of experience
selling
products in cannabis and and
specifically putting plants that were
prior not heavily pushed into the system
and then pushing them a B because I knew
the market would take it that's where I
get to kind of work with nurseries now
is to say look this is so this is a
really good example of OG if the market
likes OG Kush you can trust that this
variety will satisfy that market from
now until they're done smoking OG
because there's no question that it's
premium and then what it does it lets
the nursery then be able to say okay
that covers our og old-school base and
you have to have a library setup of
things that are staples and then you
have to have a library set up with
things that are burgeoning and so we try
to figure out you know what is hot what
is the trend and is it worth really
catching it is it worth doing the work
to develop the beds the system the
marketing to get that into play or is it
just a fad and if it's just a fad then
what you do is you put a lot of work in
and you send a lot of people into that
road and all of a sudden you know the
system is only meant to take 20 tons in
this 50 tons you got a problem
what nursery is in California do you
think are doing good work you know I
think I think that I like I like
cultivated on a Sacramento I think
Sergio and his team is doing a nice job
and I think that conception nurseries in
Sacramento they just came online I think
they're about to they're going to turn
you upside down with what they're going
to put out on our market like you're
gonna see some shit coming out of there
that's going to be insane in terms of
how vigorous those plants are because
their process of propagation is it is
better you know and so Sergio's team is
doing good work though they they're
putting out beautiful products and you
can get those at dispensaries too which
is killer because the library that he
put together his premium and the quality
of the product he's releasing his
premium so I know they're doing good
work and then in Humble County you know
you got Hendrix on the north end of the
county they always have a curate a good
library I don't really deal with any of
the other nurseries nearby me
because I wearing different different
spheres and so I think if you look at
four seed plants giacomo lot of riceland
with the plant hump you know planning on
bolt he does all the seed plants so that
you're getting something from seed them
work out of different entities that he
chooses from and that's really popular
for people who want to run their six I'm
sure there's some nice nurseries down in
mando that have thrown some good work
out but I don't I don't go to see them
you know it's only it's only larger
operations that hit me up to talk about
you know how do you shape a library how
do you how do you understand market but
I know this and that there's always good
operators you know this yes just go take
a look and see you know who's got the
craft background because the craft
background is going to influence
completely what the selection of plants
available at the nursery are otherwise
you just collect and shit so I see
people with like 80 90 hundred things on
the label and I'm like would you get it
from and it's just random shit so you
know it may be that thing but it doesn't
mean it's the one that people got really
addicted to you know buying and so you
have to end it and no one's run this
shit so I see people all the time and
I'm like did you run the plants like no
we just got the cloner I'm like I don't
even know it's the clone so it has to be
people that have a cultivation
background where they understand that if
you released a plan into the system you
had some idea of what it did so that you
know how to assist the cultivator on
placing it correctly some cultivators
shouldn't grow certain varieties some
regions don't take certain varieties
very well in terms of acceptance in the
market and some varieties are just so
damn valuable that you want to make sure
you don't release too much of it into
the system as a nursery so that you can
maintain that upper shelf where you can
actually if you're smart you can kind of
control the movement of certain products
if you're the one that's putting them
out because you only put out so much of
it and what it does it allows you to
have these hotter items that bring
people into awareness of your farm so if
you're touching something that has great
awareness and people buy it and your
labels connected to it
look at you differently if you are able
to connect to them so I go that shit is
like that's what I dig about nursery's
is that you know propagating trances is
spiritual man because you get into this
rhythm when you propagate student seed
work and doing clonal work you get lost
in propagation and you just you're there
so it's just it's cleansing to me like
this it's so unbelievably focused that
you really do lose track of everything
else except what you're doing so that is
an art I love but the business and
nursery I think is misunderstood by most
because they they don't realize that
you're you're you're really the market
interpreter so where you're having to
look at the stores and the burgeoning
markets and declining markets and create
your libraries to fit that reality not
necessarily things that you'd like to
work with and most of the time the shit
that props great and grows well and is
extremely efficient per square foot is
not what you want to grow you know
you're a breed of Steve on there the
other day right and he was hysterical
but he's like you know the the good shit
never goes big and and the purple shit
that looks better
it's never the strong shit and no he was
so he was so accurate because that's
just one of those things every now and
then all things come together as this
holy grail in terms of plural work the
perk was the Holy Grail because the perk
gave you fantastic clone rates and it
branched really well so when you were
working with purple you knew that every
tray you touched they all plugged they
were all very even in height they didn't
have different hormonal concentrations
throughout the canopy like ogee does so
the trays always look really symmetrical
everything always looked beautiful
it did everything you wanted it to do as
a propagator and the market was
accepting it like a vacuum cleaner so
that's you know that your job in the
nursery end is to find the things that
work well for cultivators just because
you can plug it doesn't mean growers are
going to want to grow it it doesn't mean
buyers are going to want to buy it right
so if you're good at nursery where
you're and to me nurseries are somebody
who's introducing stock into the system
you don't just propagate material
because in cannabis there's no bank
to go to to get the source material
where most nurseries can do that they
get seeds from a common company they put
it out in in massive form they may do
their own in-house
speciality production once they get big
enough but most nurseries are just
really replicating work that they get
from catalogs in cannabis we don't have
these catalogs we don't have these
proven cultivars we don't have the
consistency to do so and so that's where
I think you see a lot of these bigger
operations that light up nurseries
because when I talk to these guys and I
asked them what was the basis of your
build in the library that like well
these are the plants we acquired from
somebody and I'm just like so you're
you're you're investing you know thirty
million dollars in an operation and all
this downstream money that's going to
come from it all the things you have no
idea why anybody chose and so you know
that's the that's the thing without
nursery operators is that if you just
take a look to see who's the owners of
the nursery and how long have they been
doing nursery work they're gonna have a
better idea of what it is that that
should be sold in the place even if
their technology isn't as good I would
rather have a better plant produced
under less than optimal conditions then
the best fucking plant ever cloned that
couldn't sell you don't I mean like I
need the genetics because once you get
something that works for you on your
hill you can go find a lab to scrub it
you can go find a nursery do license
back work with you where they they'll
say you'll say listen can you
I need a grid of this can you produce it
for me what's the numbers and the money
so you don't even have to do in-house
because really if you were able to do
the math on it and both sides worked in
an agreement it would work for you