[Music]
give it out and know that they're not
gonna lose control and get and
never either ones like someone's just
gonna steal it there's really two areas
of intellectual property that that would
relate to and your strongest level of
enforcement would be a patent also
really hard to get but if it could be
granted it would have in a range of
profile for cannabinoids growing style
for the plant it's going to be very
specific to that kind of plant now we
haven't seen any of that enforced yet in
the industry but in theory if someone
stole your genetics that was an exact
one for one if you could have a patent
registered on this prior to putting it
in commerce or prior to the theft you
that would be the strongest enforcement
most people are not going to do that
most people can't afford that the
question of being able to show the
evidence that you actually cultivated in
a specific way that would qualify for
the patent registration most people
can't really provide that evidence the
more accessible way would be through a
trademark and what you would do is you
would concede that the genetics are
going to get out but what you would
focus on is this is so we'll say the
strain is Stardust right that's what you
decided to call it you would focus on I
am great seeds which is the brand
trademark Stardust so if other people
are buying Stardust
from other Creators or other cultivars
cultivators they just they trust your
brand and I think that is one of the
best ways we can do it right now because
if you see other packaging so long as
you record your trademark with the state
of California which as of January 2nd at
9:00 a.m. they started accepting
cannabis trademarks for cannabis goods
and services so long as you're not
trying to trademark the name of the
strain which is not allowed at the
federal level if a plant has ever been
identified by its cultivar rule 12 zero
2.12 I believe of the TM EP states that
any plan identified by its cultivar that
cultivar is not able to be registered as
a trademark if you want to do more
research on this check out what happened
with the Honey Crisp Apple situation
that they filed the patent in the patent
identified Honey Crisp as the cultivar
then University I think it's a Minnesota
went to seek trademark protection at the
federal level for honey Kris to which
for the application the inquiry was well
is this the name the cult of our name of
the plant and on the patent it was
registered as the cultivar name so that
they ended up getting denied they filed
a trademark on Honey Crisp so this law
is already in effect for plants and
actually for doing more research they
use the same law in Canada so there is a
novel issue with trying to protect
strain names as trademarks right now
that I think the industry is going to
have to deal with a lot in the upcoming
years probably in the next two years
we're gonna see a lot more of this but
if you are the farm the seed company any
of these brands and you sell it as farm
trademark
TM this strain for Stardust that is a
way to protect it and you can have
strength in this because if you see
anyone else claiming sure the genetics
might get grown you we're going to
assume it's inferior quality if it's
better than yours that only in certain
ways helps to your legacy if you say I
originally came up with a strain but if
anyone else is claiming that it's
directly
your source you're gonna be able to
fight that which is a new opportunity in
California second night yes of this year
I think the issue now is I want to guard
that right like the Colonel's secret
recipe right which is a trade secret
right would willingly for example give
my clippings to a nursery to them from a
key to that sell to growers would then
flour it out we then get Stardust right
I kind of a cheeky answer it depends on
the range of penetration you want your
genetics to have in the market maybe
you're like you find a sweetheart deal
and you just do a license of I'm gonna
write a contract with this cultivator
and give them just one plant that
they're and this is the one company that
I'm gonna do it with because I really
believe in their ability to propagate
this maybe you would do that especially
if you have some mystique or some
renowned for being a geneticist there I
think that could be viable but if you
want to hold it really tight trying to
establish that chain of control is very
difficult right now because really if
one clipping gets out unless you've
taken steps like filing a patent or
registering a trademark and the genetic
did loose trying to assert ownership
over that is unrealistic it's just not
gonna happen right now so I think you
either have a really structured I mean
if you wanted to try and I don't even
think protecting it as a trade secret
would work
well because as soon as you share it
with someone it's not really a secret so
yeah I think protecting the name of it
as a trademark or trying to get
registration as the patent is best but I
do think there is incentive for people
developing genetics to share this you
just have to create the brand around the
genetics that's the thing that'll be
easiest for you to protect and then it's
just an incentive of I provide quality
clones or quality seeds which I think
there's going to be an increased demand
for that I think there's a really solid
role for nurseries especially supplying
consistent clones to these large-scale
cultivating operations that maybe don't
want to deal with having a constant
clones of pie or dedicating part of
their grow operation to creating mother
plants and doing that upkeep so I think
you could make a name for yourself
definitely as a nursery right to
propagate
genetics right sell them to other people
that flower it's gonna be a lot of
restrictive clauses so focused on how
much plot space do I get how many plants
are you gonna have in production for me
how many clones are do you have to be
accountable for tracking how many clones
you take do I get to try and dictate who
you sell the clones to things like that
so I can try and control the chain of
command the question for a lot of these
would be would they be enforceable terms
I feel like we haven't really tested
that as much in in California this is
going to happen though I think this is
an issue that probably if there's a lot
of agreements being developed around
these terms right now so a lot of
restrictions of just do I have the
ability to inspect your site do I have
because a lot of these are like getting
creative with the amount of control
without saying I actually have an
ownership interest into your business or
and because you're still potentially
running the risk of having them to
someone be like tear up your contract
I'm gonna go do whatever I want so I
think for someone developing genetics
finding the solid relationship first
where hopefully you're never gonna need
to enforce the contract is key or your
inverse that is I just believe in my
genetics I want them out there I have my
trademark attached to this and they get
to use my trademark saying I'm buying
clones from nursery acts or seed
producer acts and I just want everyone
happened like if every of all of
California was growing my genetics I
would love that because my market
penetration is amazing so yeah I think
trying to control these things where if
you find out your employee so I give you
this plan and I find out your employee
brought it home and shared it with their
friends trying to have some form of
legal recourse and then then like
enforcing that is really difficult and
cost prohibitive for a lot of businesses
so theoretically that could work but
then trying to assess what are the
damages you know where is the the value
that was detracted from my part of the
contract
that seems kind of onerous and undefined
right now once again I mean it's going
to depend contract and relationship by
relationship contract by contract but I
think the enforceability for a lot of
these things would be more cost
prohibitive it's a lot easier if its
premise around something like you're
infringing on my trademark you're using
my trademark in a way I don't want or in
the case of if there was a patent
registered in that sense but just hey I
wrote a contract with you I trust you
with my genetics don't dick me over that
is a harder one to afford so especially
for assessing damages majority of my
practices and trademarks and because
California just started this opportunity
to register trademarks for cannabis and
goods and services
there's a little bit of a land grab
going on right now and if you register
first trying to invalidate that
registration if someone else is the
superior right to the trademark is
fairly problematic
it's a litigation there is not a I'm
gonna call up and complain to the state
and invalidate your trademark that
really doesn't happen so trying to
establish what you own right now is huge
talking about agreements and other
issues that are coming up the due
diligence side the wild claims of who
owns what right now are pretty amazing
in some cases and doing the actual due
diligence of saying if I'm gonna
contract with you make sure that I see
documentation substantiating that you
actually own this intellectual property
not a hey I own this because there has
been certain famous strains that have
made the news where there was an
assertion of I own this because I'm
telling everyone I do that doesn't make
it legally bind it and there is some of
that going on right now so I encourage
diligence especially have an
understanding of whatever you're trying
to license and make
that you've taken steps to protect it or
if you're taking your licensing
something from someone make sure it
actually has value there is a very low
understanding I feel like of different
intellectual property issues in the
cannabis space right now and I don't
expect everyone to just know these
things you know but work with someone
who does because I've seen a Lulu
I've seen some agreements that I don't
know if they will they would hold up in
court
I've seen some requests that I don't
think are reasonable and then from the
other side of outside of agreements I've
seen some filings and their core dings
that have been done that are just
completely invalid or should never have
been done and so I think there is an
immense amount of value going forward
for protecting your intellectual
property but having an understanding
what that actually is and if it one is
it protectable - have I taken the steps
to protect it or three if I'm engaging
someone else do they own it like those
are really fundamental questions you
need to be asking
as you said like intellectual property
so like an example that'd be like I
created Peters brand in Colorado and
you're gonna license Peters brand
California right your point that you the
California guy should make sure I can
show you trademarks
yes and in that case you're probably
going to write into part of the
licensing agreement when you license
into California I'm not gonna seek
trademark protection trying to use syrup
your registration and after I start
using your trademark you're going to
register the registration there's a lot
of room for that to go bad also if
you're coming in from out of state if
you the licensee hasn't taken steps to
protect if you're just basing this
purely off estate right and there's no
federal registrations and that isn't
registered to have the license or turn
around and then register some of the
intellectual property that's totally a
possible outcome so taking the steps to
say hey if we're gonna do this you're
gonna forgo XY and Z and allow me to do
it and then we understand that really
that's going to be the sub substance of
this Agreement but I might not have had
the opportunity to even register the
trademark yet Colorado bed because most
so between federal and state trademark
applications at the federal level you
are allowed to do what's called 1b
filing or an intent to use filing a 1a
filing is that I'm actually using the
trademark in commerce and mind you you
can't get a federal trademark on
cannabis or cannabis goods and services
because it's a violation of the
controlled substance act do the schedule
1 status so that's not waffle used in
commerce the best you can do is
ancillary goods and services but at the
state level depending on the state
you're in
you can register on goods and services
for cannabis but the requirement there
is there is no one be filing there's
only I'm actually using it so if you're
coming from Colorado licensing the brand
into California you probably haven't
used the trademark in commerce yet and
you're the licensee will be the first
one to use it so if they use it and then
registered it right away
you've created a very and you haven't
included a term
saying you are not going to do the
registration I'm gonna do the
registration and own it you're creating
a very interesting issue at the contract
because who really owns the trademark
then and did that trademark get entered
into the agreement or so yeah that there
are a lot of problems there is we can't
generally do an A to B solution for
cannabis right now there's usually a few
extra steps and especially at the state
level when it's state to state because
your protection doesn't expand past the
state that you've registered them so
taking those steps to say okay well if
we're gonna license into another state
how do we go about protecting ourselves
either before the agreement is signed or
in conjunction with signing the
agreement
[Music]
I mean you're gonna see some internal
maybe even a term of hey if you're
producing this for me I'm gonna license
you my trademark even if it's just
internally in the same state
I don't maybe I'm not going after
manufacturing license so but I own the
intellectual property so I'm gonna
license you my trademark or my branding
and then have you create the products we
probably have some sort of free
agreement for you to create and do the
manufacturing and then I would maybe
collect a royal royal tea payment for
the use of the trademark maybe with art
so if somebody designs some really cool
art for your packaging or your website
or something and they would license you
write a licensing agreement if you have
limited access to my art or my artistic
works and then that's hopefully
protected by a copyright registration
that that would get bundled into the
licensing agreement for patents you know
maybe I have a method that I have
registered a patent on method of
extraction and I will license you the
use of that technique or if there's a
machine that I don't want to manufacture
because it's gonna be too expensive but
you have a great manufacturing facility
how license you might design that I've
registered as a patent trade secrets
maybe I have an edible company that I'm
we're just known for having amazingly
good cookies and my recipe I've not
shared with anyone and that's my
proprietary blend and I'm gonna license
you that so long as you don't share the
secret with anyone your employees
generally don't know there's probably
some other restriction and agreement
where that extra little secret when I
put nutmeg in it like one or two people
at your company know that and they do it
in the backroom but all those things
could be internally those don't have to
be state to state we're gonna see a lot
more dynamic licensing agreements
between businesses that don't
necessarily do everything or somebody's
stand out and
they don't have the ability to maximise
on production
so let's license it to someone else and
let's collect royalty payments just as
much also so state state to state we're
gonna start seeing international
definitely branding are is moving
international the concept of
international canvass brand is very real
it's not a theoretical like that's going
on and that it gets only more dynamic
because then you have two different
jurisdictions of law trying to figure
out how do you do an enforcement what's
the obligation what's my ability to
police or monitor my contract trademarks
especially Canada and actually I just
learned that they're gonna have an issue
with social media but it sounds like
there will be a way to do agreements
where trademarks get brought up from
California get used in Canada Canada has
restrictive packaging so it's a very
dumb down packaging but if you have a
brand that already has a very flourished
social media presence exactly
so being imposed to building a
grassroots up brand where you have very
limited marketing and your packaging is
nondescript and you have this much space
for a logo in in Canada their massive
packaging just was learning about this
massive packaging restrictions so if you
have an American brand or it doesn't
have to be American you have a brand
that already has a robust following and
brand identity putting that on because
people the natural people use their
phones Oh what is this and if there's
already this developed market I think
for consumers that's fairly persuasive
opposed to what's this other brand that
has maybe 3,000 social media followers
or like is that any good might be good
but it doesn't have as much of a
following and a lot of consumption or
consumers buy based off of the reviews
of other people or have I heard of this
before
so yeah bringing California brands that
are established up to to Canada
is in discussions that is definitely in
discussions from a different
international and I have not worked on
this I spoke with an Israeli attorney
about it but trying to do patent
licensing issues from Israel to the
United States and even doing completion
of research and development in Israel
for aspects of patents that we couldn't
do the research on in the United States
without being at federally illegal so
just doing research for that amount in a
different country and then bringing that
part of the patent back or that part of
the intellectual property back and from
the international side my advice would
just be hire an international attorney
like if you for these deals you
shouldn't be working with someone
domestically who has your own best
interest and they should have a
counterpart in the other country who
also then can say well here's the laws
here's how this is same here's this is
how this is different
opposed to just relying on the other
side your licensing to having their
representation and telling you oh yeah
this is our part of the contract is good
that is not sufficient representation
and so that's why either working I can
see where there's an advantage to maybe
working with more law firms that have a
presence in multiple countries I don't
think that's essential but I think just
finding attorneys and both countries
that have a good knowledge base of
cannabis and how it relates intellectual
property intellectual property relates
to campus
[Music]