[Music]
so sweetie you guys while it's pulling
up I'll tell you this is Dodger
he's a Labrador that works at our
facility he's gentle thank you his job
is to comfort the patients that are
stuck there smoking weed all day so he's
got an important role with our clinical
trials and excited he travels with me
everywhere so okay I think we got this
it's just gonna take a minute to load
the pictures probably but let's see what
we'll just jump right in so um as you
guys know you know our studies are
focused on flower so I know today you're
gonna hear a lot about all the wonderful
derivatives that are coming out of
cannabis flower but our studies try to
focus on actual dry bud material so
we're doing FDA controlled trials trying
to understand the medical benefits of
smoked and vaporize flour and our effort
is to you know to really try to put
flour through the entire FDA drug
development process so we're doing
nonprofit drug development research and
it's really difficult to find partners
that want to do this because you can
imagine you know most these companies
are focused on trying to isolate
cannabinoids things that they can
actually patent and make money from and
we're the opposite you know we're trying
to basically keep flour in the nonprofit
realm because it can't be really
patented easily and and we're doing that
because we believe that flour certainly
is the least expensive because you don't
have to do all the processing after it's
still the most popular if you look at
the data and all these legal states
people still migrate toward natural
flour and we think that it will also if
we can get flour through the FDA process
I think it'll open most doors for other
botanical medicines like you know I work
with maps and many of you know there are
a nonprofit that
spearheads all this psychedelic research
and so for us you know trying to pave
the way for other plant-based medicines
like psilocybin and ayahuasca and all
these important potential medicines so
and then of course the ultimate goal is
to try to to persuade health insurance
companies to pay for flour the same way
they pay for other pharmaceuticals and
that's why getting flour through the FDA
process is so essential in order to
achieve that goal of making insurance
companies add that to their formularies
so um many of you know we're probably
best known for this clinical trial but
we do all sorts of different studies
which I'm going to talk about but but
this study has been really crucial
because first thing it many of you
probably don't know we have not had a
new drug on the market for PTSD in
eighteen years can you believe that the
first and only medicines that were
approved were zoloft and paxil back 18
years ago so nothing else has emerged
and all these other drugs that we use
physicians we we employ all these other
drugs off-label they've never been
tested
officially formally for PTSD but that's
the challenge is when we're when you're
treating PTSD you're trying to attack
this whole constellation of symptoms
right you they come in initially they
might report some insomnia so you put
them on some sleep meds then they report
this depression anxiety you put them on
SSRI or other antidepressants and it you
can see how these guys just keep
snowballing and that's the way modern
medicine is today we have a different
prescription that that that attacks each
different target symptoms so these guys
end up on you know sometimes 10 12
different prescriptions all to treat
PTSD and so that's why we became so
curious about the potential of cannabis
the idea that this complex plant and the
pliat ropey that results from that right
that the opportunity to target multiple
organ systems in the body with
this one intervention is so exciting to
us and that's why we embarked on this
trial but I wanted you to be aware that
this study even though we did finally
complete it this year it took us 10
years to get to the finish line and that
is the sad reality of trying to do
clinical trials in the US and if you
dare say you want to study efficacy of
cannabis how effective is cannabis of
treating a certain illness like this
those studies get in almost into a
permanent review process typically where
they almost never emerge and the only
reason ours did was because we got so
much media coverage along the way that
pressured the government to help us you
know kind of hurdle these obstacles and
you can see oh you know we we ended up
having this crazy saga which many of you
we thank you so much for following us
through this drama because it's insane
but you know we got fired from the
University where we actually had IRB
approval from the University to do the
study we were doing an FDA approved
fully funded study and they rejected us
terminate us but this was a huge gift to
our study because it ultimately we ended
up let me see if I can but yeah we ended
up getting tons of media coverage and
all these celebrities coming out of the
woodwork to defend us like you know many
of you know Andy while he was one of my
attendings at the University he's a he's
a department chair of Integrative
Medicine at the medical school at
University of Arizona and he wrote this
public letter condemning his own
university president for for doing this
and so we're really grateful to have
folks like him and you know John Oliver
all these folks coming out trying to
help us because they realize how what
this was really an attack on scientific
freedom when they tried to suppress this
work and so ultimately we ended up in
our own private Institute and that's
what I wanted to point out to you guys
is that you can do this work totally
independent from any university or
hospital we work through a private IRB
system we have no you know so then we're
not beholden to the politics the ugly
politics in the university it took me
seven years though to get this what they
call the you know the scientists call
this the golden ticket because it allows
you the privilege of purchasing cannabis
from our federal government and so seven
years it finally got the approval
ordered you know move to order eight
kilos of cannabis which was required for
our study and suddenly I'm thinking you
know surely this would come by like
armored truck or something but there's
the FedEx guy shows up at my door with
he has no idea he's even transporting
cannabis he's like why all these cameras
here I was like well this is really
historic day you know he waited so long
for this but I was you know so
disappointed to open up these this
cooler and see you know basically this
was frozen cannabis sitting in the
lockers of the Research Triangle frozen
for years and you open up the sandwich
bags they have no information on them
they don't tell you anything except the
CBD to THC ratio so normally when I do
clinical trials I always get a drug
master file that tells you all the
properties of the study drug no not
there's zero transparency on that you do
not get access to the drug master file
despite us suing before sending FOIA
requests all of that so this is also
another thing that handcuffed scientists
because we have no idea what's really in
it and we also we have our own
analytical s a DEA license to do the
analysis but we decided we wanted to
send it out to an independent lab so
nobody would fault us for this and you
can see this is the material this is
pictures on the top from years ago right
many of you know Ethan Rousseau sent me
these pictures of his study drug when
you can see how depressing this is that
this is the materials basically a
concoction of stems thick seeds leaves
and some flowering you know flowering
tops
this is the most recent batch that we
got on the bottom so you can see what
happened was we started criticizing the
government about this you know all this
extraneous plant material weighing down
because remember when in clinical trials
you issue study drug to patients by
weight right so they may get 2 grams a
day 3 grams a day but if half of the
weight of the study drug is all of this
junk and not the actual flowering part
of the plant then you see how that
already sabotages your study from the
beginning so after all this criticism
they didn't like scientists criticizing
their study drug and they said alright
we're gonna grind it into a powder so
now you can't even discern what's in it
very clever of our government but we
still know you can still see all the
fragments in there that show this is no
better than you know Mexican ditch weed
really but you can see when we sent this
out to these independent labs we ended
up finding excessively high levels of
mold in all the batches and we went to
back to NIDA and and university
Mississippian said you know what was
your mold testing ours was over a
hundred thousand CFU of mold in all the
batches and they said oh we've never
tested for mold and so I was like wow
this is really you know mystifying that
they've never thought I mean they're
growing outdoors in Mississippi it's
like a formula well the humidity there
it's a formula from get growing mold but
they never tested for it and and only
when we brought this to light we shared
the hour summary report you know we
ended up doing three different rounds of
independent testing all showing sky high
levels of mold and sadly this is the
only federally legal supply so think
about that that every single study done
in the US that was looking at flower has
been forced to use this lousy study drug
and I want to just give you some good
news though is that so after ten years
we finally got the seventy this is the
80th veteran through the clinical trial
right so we screened almost 6,000
veterans for the study
finally found that eighty that met all
the correct you can see there's just
pages and pages of inclusion and
exclusion criteria but that's the binder
for the 80th patient we had only four
dropouts in the study which is a real
testament to the you know resilience of
these veterans they just were so
determined they would never resign
unless we forced them to and we did have
a couple patients that had some adverse
events but this is interesting too that
the FDA still requires you know the
binders like a thousand pages and still
we have to do everything on paper spend
hours and hours transferring this to an
electronic databases so you see how
laborious these trials are but
ultimately our I'll just on sadly I
can't share the results of the veterans
study yet because we haven't published
all the data we have unblinded
everything and we're putting we're
pulling this into a manuscript now that
hopefully will be submitted to jam later
this year but I can tell you that the
results are exactly what you would
expect from smoking moldy diluted
cannabis it's it's I'm sad to say that
I'm not sure people are gonna be eager
to read these results so um so you'll
see later but I think that this is what
spurred on I we've been trying to find a
law firm to help us sue the DEA for
years over this monopoly and for those
of you who aren't aware you know
University of Mississippi has enjoyed a
government enforced monopoly for now you
know since 1968 so that's 50 years that
they have had the only scheduled one
license as a bulk manufacturer so every
clinical trial that we or any scientist
do you're all the universities at in
California here CMC are UCSD all these
groups have been forced to buy this
substandard plant material even though
you're surrounded by some of the most
beautiful flower in the world you're
buying that powder that green powder
and so it makes me concerned you know
Pierre just mentioned the National
Academy of Science report and we all
know that that report only showed
efficacy you know really it said that
there was only strong evidence to
support cannabis for pain nausea and
vomiting and and spasticity of MS but
you think about all these other
conditions that patients are reporting
they're getting benefit from you know
everything from epilepsy to inflammatory
bowel disease those study there was not
scientific evidence to support their use
and that doesn't surprise any of us
right because we see what the how these
studies have been undermined by the look
this low quality study drug we see how
studies have been subverted by you know
being forced into fixed dosing that was
one of the things I was most proud of in
this trial that we just finished this
veterans study was the first one I'm
aware of that
oh the FDA allowed us to do patient self
titration right so these PTSD patients
need to be able to adjust their own dose
you can't force them into taking you
know 20 milligrams twice a day whether
they need it or not that would be absurd
and that would that's what happens with
these previous clinical trials we've
forced people and many times take way
more than they need then they get tons
of side effects that you know kind of
eclipsed any therapeutic benefit that
we're able to document so that's where I
think these studies have gone wrong
hopefully all the clinical trials going
forward if any of you out there are
thinking about doing clinical trials I
would really urge you to keep on this
train of patient self titration demand
that your FDA you know the FDA was very
oppositional with this idea initially it
took us months of back-and-forth with
them before they finally embraced it
but believe me their paradigm is
established by Big Pharma right so
that's what they know is fixed dosing
models so we have to push them to to
rethink that paradigm and let us look at
botanical medicine with a different
paradigm
that patient self titration should be
the rule of the day and we've had you
know many of the veterans in the study
didn't even you know they did some days
they you know how the PTSD fluctuates
right some days you are good some days
are bad some days they don't need any
medicine other days they know oh I'm
going to Walmart I got a pre Medicaid I
know this is gonna be brutal so so
that's the idea is we want to give
patients the power to decide when they
want to medicate how much they need some
of these patients you know they were
required to bring back their unused
cannabis each week so I would weigh what
they used each day and I could see that
a lot of these patients only needed a
few inhalations at night to help them
initiate sleep stay asleep all night
suppress their nightmares and flashbacks
they'd wake up in the morning feeling
refreshed they didn't even need often
any study drug in the daytime it was you
know the the nighttime dose was adequate
so that's the whole point is give them
the power to adjust the dose so now I'm
gonna leave I know we're probably sure
Domo I'm okay good okay so um I want to
just explain to you what our next steps
are because of the results of this
veterans study it it spurred us on even
further to demand a change from the DEA
and what many of you probably read in
2016 the DEA announced that they were
going to finally end the monopoly and
license other growers for Research's was
on the federal register so it was a
legit announcement but since that then
three years later they have not moved
forward one inch toward doing this we
they have you know 30 applications
sitting on the desk of the DEA for three
years that have not been processed they
took our application fee $3,000 they
processed my credit card but not my
application so so that's why we were so
lucky to find this law firm that has no
relationship to cannabis by the way
they're people that just heard me speak
at South by Southwest and they were so
outraged by this
oppression of scientific freedom and
they said you know what we'll take this
pro bono they spent months researching
this and submitted the petition so and
it's actually not just against the DEA
but we're also targeting the Attorney
General whose office seems to be the
primary culprit here supposedly the DEA
wanted to move forward but the you know
DOJ and attorney general said no you're
not to process those so this is
essential that this this DEA monopoly is
really the final barrier to doing
legitimate cannabis clinical trials in
the US and it's held us back so much
because you can see the menu here is so
limited in our study we basically got to
look at high THC batch a batch of high
CBD flour a batch of one to one THC the
CBD and placebo and that's it so that's
the menu you've got and and yet here in
the real world patients obviously have
access to thousands of phenotypes we
have a mountain of anecdotal evidence
from patients that this is helping them
but that's the promise this is not
barring out in these clinical trials
because of the you know the the
disappointing study drug and the fixed
dosing model is really harming the
outcomes of these studies so it's a real
conundrum it's like this catch-22 right
because here we're trying to reform
public policy we need data in order to
do that yes there are thousands of
controlled trials that have already been
published in peer-reviewed journals
alluding to the efficacy of cannabis for
certain illnesses but certainly not
close to enough to persuade the medical
community or health departments they're
all we're all so snobbish about you know
we need randomized controlled trials
that is the gold standard and you know
anything short of that is good and
that's the challenge with PTSD right is
that PTSD all the data so far has been
conflicting we have a ton of
observational studies
some have showed cannabis benefits PTSD
have shown it's harmful that it makes
patients aggressive it promotes cannabis
dependence so there's all these reasons
why people were hanging on this trial
hoping that this data would you know
finally the first randomized controlled
trial in the world looking at this
thought finally we'd have a definitive
answer and so this is the challenge for
all of you who are who are in this
movement to try to keep the pressure on
the DEA the DEA has already received
over a dozen letters bipartisan letters
from Congress and they have not even
felt the need to respond it's amazing
that the DEA feels you know I apparently
they're not accountable to anybody
because they don't even respond to two
letters from Congress not even a form
letter so I was pretty amazed by that
and that's why we move forward with the
litigation because we realized we can't
wait on them to to act you know we've
heard references from the new attorney
general bar saying oh we're gonna get on
that now we're gonna do something but we
all know that all these bills are just
stagnating waiting for you know I don't
know what they're waiting for I feel
like nobody's interested in solving the
problem so hopefully we'll find a
sympathetic judge but in the meantime I
wanted to point out this is actually a
two-front war were we're creating here
the one front is this litigation against
the DEA the second front is this
opportunity which is importing cannabis
from a foreign country so our government
seems to have no problem with us
scientists sourcing cannabis from other
countries they just don't want any other
domestic manufacturers so here's what
we're doing is the if we can bring in
flour from Canada as soon as the
Canadian lp's prove that they have GMP
grade flour then I will be a I will have
the green light to to import their flour
and that will finally break this
monopoly because you'll notice many of
you have read how UCSD is importing
flour of sorry they're importing
cannabis oil from tilray for that tremor
study that just
be aware that that oil cannabis oil
there's no monopolies around cannabis
oil that was broken years ago member but
when GW was allowed to bring in Sativex
force for clinical trials so that
monopoly ended years ago the monopoly
that exists is just around flower right
now they have not allowed any flower to
enter the u.s. externally they're not
allowing any other domestic growers so
this is our hope is this trial was
supposed to be I wanted to just point
out something interesting here so we're
looking at late stage cancer patients
right and we're going to evaluate this
is one looking at quality of life the
second study we're doing is looking at
breakthrough pain so we're gonna be
evaluating smoked cannabis flower
compared to fentanyl right because
fentanyl like the nuclear bomb of
opioids we use it so reflexively with
our cancer patients but the fact is that
in a pilot study we did in Montreal we
found that Canton smoked flower
performed way better than fentanyl and
just came on so quickly and patients got
relieved so we're we're going to do the
Strout we have FDA approval the issue
now is that the flower that I was
preparing to import from this LP in
Canada suddenly found the presence of
three mycotoxins so this is something I
want to point out is even these giant
this is a giant LP multi-billion dollars
they have the financial resources to do
the best industrial agriculture in the
world and yet they're not paying
attention to the quality of their
medicine and so this study that was
supposed to start in January and here we
are they still haven't been able to
remediate the flower so I just want to
mention that this is the frustration for
us scientists we are highly dependent on
these groups because we don't want a
non-profit we don't have money to pay
for these studies so we have to wait for
them to do this but I just want to say
that you know some of these corporate
behemoths are just so focused on the
money play and they forgot about the
quality of the medicine and taking care
of sick people and it just makes me sad
that were in this state now where we're
you know we're so dependent on this but
so I want to bring that up and then my
final slide I just want to mention there
are all kinds of interesting things that
come out that are generated through
these trials even though we weren't
studying you know opioid substitution in
our study and we weren't studying
erectile function but the veterans were
reporting to us that both of those
things were happening during the three
months and keep in mind this is even
with this with this really substandard
plant material that they were noticing
that they weren't as relying on their
opioids many of them reported completely
weaning off opioids during the course of
this three months study so that was
exciting phenomena and then this was the
other thing that we had so many young
veterans coming in on viagra because
that was you know that's what the VA
does they pummel you with all these
psych meds that cause you to have no
erectile function and then they throw in
some viagra for a good measure and so
it's you can imagine how demoralizing
for two year old veterans already on
viagra they think their life is over and
and so this was an exciting discovered
to that many of the vets were noticing
that they no longer needed the viagra
during the time where they were using
the smoked flower so I think that was my
final slide we're hoping to do a trial
on this subject as well and we're
looking for partners we have some
interest from a canadian LPS and if
you've heard of zen abyss is one of the
LPS up there that is that is headed up
by a urologist who's already agreed to
fund this trial so we're hoping but the
good thing about them what I was
impressed buying Canada Pier can
probably touch on the is it they're
willing there's like a collaborative
competitiveness we're certainly all the
LPS are fighting you know to dominate
but they're also willing like Zen abyss
was willing to allow us to source flour
from all the different LPS because all
of them have different varieties that
could be valuable and they get that and
so they're willing to fund the study and
not necessarily insist that their flour
has to be the only one so I was really
impressed
by that and I'm hoping someday in the
u.s. we can achieve that kind of
collaborative spirit so now I know we're
short and I know we I don't know if we
do we still have time Oh question do you
think so oh good all right all right
let's see if anybody got a question two
points a lovely talk thank you very much
number one regarding this here's one of
the issues right it may well be the
cannabis it may be a toxin that's doing
this right you just don't know hence the
need for control better control things
and if you'll allow me one anecdote so
you said about having to give fixed dose
you're absolutely right and what I've
been doing of course is titrating up and
I stop when there's some sort of adverse
effect but in one of my patients with
Parkinson's disease who had
osteoarthritis of the hip which is the
hip I was treating we went up to about
one ml of oil twice a day and said
frankly doc it's not working my pain is
the same we said well okay well we'll
just titrate down I got back down to 0.7
twice a day and said stop stop because
you know what my tremors are coming back
now that you're titrating down go back
up because I feel so much better on it
so so we have to keep you know that that
spirit open of openness and looking for
for things and to your point titrating
is so important when using and I think
that's what people are discovering is
that they need often a lot less cannabis
than they thought even though typically
in these studies we're giving them two
or three grams a day just to give them
enough to use what they need but most of
the time these patients are reporting
needing less than a half gram a day and
and that just goes against that attitude
from the prohibitionists that oh if you
give them you know too much that their
gel just abuse it the fact is you know
sick patients just want to feel
functional they're not trying to get
stoned and I think we can you know these
studies hopefully will dispel a lot of
these myths yeah well thank you so much
for the talk this was wonderful
I'm wondering why you all are
investigating smoking as well as
vaporization besides maybe just cost and
like familiarity is there any reason
that
you are looking at both ends of this
it's such a good question I am actually
really frustrated by you know this
veteran study was actually supposed to
randomize people into a smoking arm or
vaporizing arm but we decided we had an
agreement from tilray
to do our vaporizer arm of the study and
that they would fully fund it that was
six years ago they still haven't
finished the trial they have like I
don't know two or four patients and
rolls and it's just been a really anemic
effort and I'm really depressed about
because we would now be able to have
data from both if they had finished but
again this shows you they're happy to
waive the trial in front of their
investors and brag about how they're
doing all this important research but
the fact is when it comes to they had a
chance to be involved in this it really
meant Android can speak to this because
she knows how tough it is these big
corporations are so dependent on
shareholder satisfaction and it's really
hard and they're constantly you know
holding this up and waving it around it
but then when it comes to really
executing they don't do it but I agree
with you the one thing that we heard
from veterans was and many of you in the
audience can probably speak to this and
if you have time after please come talk
to me because I keep hearing from people
that they insist that smoking is just so
much more robust time you know -
typically I'm very anti smoking in my
internal medicine practice I it's what's
really hard for me to embrace this
initially but I recognize this is a
legitimate delivery method the studies
that we had you know 30 years of safety
studies from NIDA still have not
uncovered any long-term harms from
smoking no long malignancy or or
emphysema so I've embraced this but I'm
curious about why you know patients are
talking about how vaporizing is good but
smoking is just a much more robust and
it seems to activate all these molecules
in the plant that aren't you know really
activated by vaporizing which only gets
you to whatever 400 degrees and so
there's something in the combustion that
takes it to another level for patients
and I think that's why it's still
preferred by so many people but not not
optimal when you're dealing with the
medical community
so yeah anybody else out there I know
probably knew hi yes
so we talked we touched on you touched
on actually both these talks touched on
how important titration is and that
often goes hand in hand with the idea
that there may be a bimodal dosing
response curve is that something that
you that this new study is going to be
addressing or has addressed I wish we
don't have but I I know what you're
saying everybody's so curious about this
biphasic response and we're not gonna
get to this is just an FDA phase 2 trial
so it's kind of early phase drug
development stays so but I'm hoping when
we get to phase 3 we'll get into more
the nitty-gritty of that but the really
good point you raise anybody else hi Sue
yeah thank you for your contribution
quick question when you do your trials
do you survey your participants if they
consume other medication other
prescription medication do you suggest
that they don't and only consume
cannabis do you trial want to things
they do have to wash off cannabis for at
least two weeks prior to starting the
study which screens out tons of patients
right off the bat if they're semi
dependent on it they automatically walk
away but it was actually really helpful
even people that were regular users
found the holid the drug holiday you
know the two-week tolerance Brett was
was beneficial because it sort of helped
re sensitize their receptors and so
that's why even with this low quality
cannabis from the government they were
getting some good responses because they
were so sensitive to it even though it
was so diluted so that's one thing so
they're not allowed to use any external
cannabis right once they enter the study
they're done with any and we have ways
of testing for that to make sure that
they're only using ours and then what
happens is oh in terms of other
pharmacology so so the other
pharmaceuticals that patients were on we
asked them to maintain everything the
same right so if they were already on a
cadre of of different psych of you know
as long as it wasn't things like
steroids stuff that would prepare you
would reduce inflammation or chemo
things like that but but basically if
they were on psych meds they were
required to stay on whatever they were
taking if they were in psychotherapy you
know getting cognitive behavioral
therapy they were required to stick with
that throughout the trial not change
anything because that could definitely
confound our results but that was the
best way to do it otherwise imagine if I
was trying to take people off
paxil zola drawl they you know if you
try to take somebody off a fax or
they're there and withdrawal four months
after that and that could really muddy
the waters so we asked people just
remain on exactly what they were taking
right here I know you guys want to go to
one I have a question hi dr. says hi hi
there um in terms of the litigation I'm
a lawyer so I'm gonna ask the litigation
question what's the status of the
litigation and like what phases it in
and then in general not just regarding
the litigation but is there anything
that the folks in this room can do in
terms of advocacy civil disobedience I
don't know that you that you would
recommend to kind of put pressure put
additional pressure on the federal
government yeah I may I'm gonna tell you
what I think and then I make it try to
connect you with my attorneys so this
Texas law firm yet or Coleman they are
they filed the petition about it's a
little over a month ago sometime in June
we submitted and we've not had any
response yet from the court which is
concerns me because I'm worried I don't
know how this works if the case can go
stale over time and so right now what
we're doing the way that I'd say if
there's one call to action I have for
everybody today is if you have
connections with elected officials who
care about this we may be able to submit
some amicus briefs I guess it's called
where they could show their support that
way and maybe we could put pressure on
the courts to acknowledge this because
right now we have a commitment from
jared polin
the governor in Colorado has agreed to
write an amicus and also I a VA the Iraq
Afghanistan veterans so they have agreed
because they already have policy about
this and American Legion is also
evaluating this for amicus support so
I'm hoping that we but we'd love to get
other governors I we're trying to
identify states where taxpayer dollars
are going to fund trials using
Mississippi cannabis and certainly here
you're in danger of that because you
have all new research money coming out
and anybody in in Europe you know
California universities that are buying
that are trying to do control trials
will be forced to buy the cannabis from
Mississippi instead of using your own
you know reg the state license cannabis
so I think you guys have a real your
governor has a real basis to argue that
we need to end this monopoly so that you
don't waste any taxpayer dollars
studying this and getting lousy outcomes
you know so if anybody knows Newsome or
any of the other you know congressmen
certainly I think uh amicus from a
congressman's office could be valuable
so yeah thank you for that question and
I'll connect you with mine we have time
for one more okay thank you so much dr.
justice Lee really appreciate your your
information is very valuable somebody
had mentioned earlier that you have a
registry a patient registry a very large
one yes we what happened was we got
funding from Colorado State University
to build an international registry that
would basically be independent of the
industry so that it could get because
those data could be published later and
if it had IRB approval in advance so
that the data again could be publishable
and what happened was the funding for
the so we had a vendor in Colorado that
was supporting the plot that created the
platform for me and was we were
collecting data
and then our funding ran out and the
platform has now gone dark so I know
this is heartbreaking so what we're
doing is trying to seek out other
partners because this is so important
that we have you know the reason I was
pursuing the registry because I'm so
desperate to get data from people using
real-world flour and even though it's
survey data it's still important because
it helps us look see trends when you get
to the larger date you know once we have
10,000 patients in the registry we'll
see trends that can help us fuel control
trials so so yeah if you know anybody
who's who's interested in providing
funding we're trying to rebuild the
platform and the good thing is we
already know how to do this we have the
you know the structure in place we just
need to reopen it and probably work with
a vendor that's not gonna be so
expensive because that was just too
costly I might actually have somebody
for you a good friend of mine is a chief
clinical officer former chief clinical
officer from Providence Health and Human
Services as you know as a very large
healthcare system had also suggested the
same thing and I might hook you up with
them how would be beautiful okay one
that's great outcome thank you guys so
much
[Applause]