[Music]
you're in the middle breaking your the
gay people is for the regulations that
comes with cost right but so it's like
the lab Martin's just talk about it you
know so laboratories so everybody thinks
that if you own a lab you make a ton of
money no so so you know if you think
about how a lab has to run right and
think about what are our primary product
out people think is a CoA but it's not
right it's customer satisfaction right
so so we like every other business have
to our product is happy customers right
so in order to make a happy customer you
have to be able to meet a reasonable
turnaround time right in order to me at
a reasonable turn amount of time that
means you have to build your lab in a
way that you have capacity you know
unused capacity because the moment you
max out your capacity and something
breaks your customers are now unhappy
because they're not getting turnaround
time right so so this is a vicious cycle
that we go through so if you think about
it from those terms and and what the
margin on your unused capacity has to be
to be able to be able to meet that right
so now you're looking at the start up a
lab you need at least two of everything
and two of everything gets you about 50
samples a day right so that's not a lot
of money all right
so but you know with 50 samples a day
and two of everything
you can keep that many customers happy
however many customers give you 50
samples right whether it's one large
company company or a bunch of small
companies right so if you would like to
get larger than that oh and here's the
important part two of everything will
set you back somewhere between depending
on whether you go at high end or low end
equipment a million and a half to two
and a half million dollars right that's
just the entry fee to play the game
right
that doesn't include building that
doesn't include all the other lab
equipment that needs to be able to help
like the pipetters doesn't include your
salaries or anything like that I suggest
sure yeah I mean you know you don't want
unskilled labour running your machines
that cost $800,000 right that's probably
a bad idea I know so so you know so that
that's just to get started right so now
if you would like to scale and and and
try to be a a larger player in the
industry now you're looking at having to
have well let's use steep hill for
example our berkeley lab right so I have
[Music]
five GL C's another liquid
chromatographs I have another four or
five liquid chromatograph with mass spec
right so you know to be able to do
pesticides
I have 7g CLM and gc/ms is to be able to
do residual solvents some pesticides you
know so you know I see PMS you need a
few of those right because you need at
least two right as I said you need to at
least two of everything right so so you
know so now you know that's what you're
looking at just and then that's that's
just the chemistry that has nothing to
do with microbial stuff and all the
incubators and all the stuff for that
you know you know and then oh wait we
forgot water activity we forgot
microscopes and cameras for visual
inspection and then you have to have a
quality assurance manual you have to
have training programs you have to have
so now yeah so now you have to have
people who have been trained and are
certified in sampling and it can't be
just any sampling you have to have a
statistical sampling plan right it has
to be you know so so you know then you
have to have a vehicle right because by
law or six right or but cuz by law right
you can't lease the vehicle or rent the
vehicle right you have to own vehicle
right so that's the BCC regulation so so
now oh wait storage we forgot storage
right we tried to get storage cut down
to a couple weeks it's 45 frickin
business days so
yeah so now I had to devote part of my
lab to a locked storage facility all
right so these and because none of these
things were actually considered before
the regulations went into play and and
as all these things kept piling up they
kept dumping it like at the same spot
the labs right so and and I'm not saying
that it was then maliciously right but
it kind of was the oh well that's yeah
that's a good spot they have for testing
let's let them keep it there at one
point they they wanted the batches to
actually be held in a facility at the
laboratories we're like whoa dude we
don't even want to keep the XS right so
we should sample twice take the one
sample with us and leave the other
sample lock in quarantine at the
producers because they have its you know
where they were smoking yeah they lost
their license or it was like under
jeopardy any those things could ease it
was a lab there was a testing lab in
Washington and rather than throw the
stuff away
they were cloth you know smoking it and
actually it was a lab chain that was in
California Lucy playing with the rules
Michelle not all labs are you know well
so if the state of California thinks
that wasn't happening in California they
were sadly deluded because there's
nobody so our track and trace system
right our track and trace system is
still only marginally functional I
believe I mean I believe it is
functioning but I believe that the
majority of people are still not on it
and without track and trace you can't
track and trace you know I mean so yes
so you know can they audit after the
fact yeah so what we'd you know so but
now here here's the other problem so
there's this whole other level of stuff
that nobody considered hey how did we
get rid of all this kind of this waste
from the laboratory okay let's call it
local the local trash pickup
what oh hell no we don't take that keep
going
has it's being treated as hazardous
waste and some of the most expensive
right so and we have to pay for for
tonnage
that's not cannabis before they'll take
it it has to be mixed with water or
kitty litter and so we have to pay and
we have to pay the combined weight not
just the way to the cannabis the way to
the water in the kitty litter
wow that's a real unintended consequence
right there so are you seeing unintended
consequences all over the place yes