[Music]
so hi I'm dr. Nadia Saba president and
founder of dr. greenhouse we are an HVAC
well we're a mechanical and agricultural
engineering firm that specializes in
HVAC design for indoor farms and
greenhouses greenhouses is where I got
my start trying to grow mushrooms in a
greenhouse talk about challenging or
trying to grow you know a crop that
likes it damp and cool in a greenhouse
in southern Idaho we had a humidity
control problem but the opposite of what
everyone is normally thinking about we
couldn't keep it wet enough you know
that for me it was my aha moment 22
years ago that I wanted to help farmers
control their environments so fast
forward went to PhD I did my PhD at the
University of Arizona where I studied
greenhouse production of tomatoes and
had a special focus on water use
efficiency so it's not always about
energy
sometimes it's about other resources
that we are also trying to conserve in
our farms enough about me you're gonna
hear plenty from me earlier or later not
earlier later I'm gonna let my panel
here introduce themselves and I think
some of them have some slides to share
with all of you all right thanks so hi
I'm Tim Kenneth on the co-founder and
executive vice president of back little
leaf farms used to be back their farms
literally farms we are five acres of
hydroponic lettuce in Devon's
Massachusetts it's NF T Mobile gutter
system yeah let's do the video do the
video real quick
[Music]
I was always interested in and locally
grown food I have been involved with
greenhouses for most of my life all
called me up said hey listen this
lettuce business possibly figured out
yet I felt strongly that we could do it
a different way grow local and then
deliver a better superior fresher
product we basically have learned from I
think the best practices around the
world and found our own unique way of
operating here at literally farms over
95% of all the lettuce that we consume
is grown in California in Arizona for
3,200 miles away from where they're
growing these products on the west coast
but for us it's it's simpler because we
cut it we deliver it and it's in the
store within 24 hours
we're successfully competing against the
the proven West Coast operations with
close to 10 acres under glass people
didn't know what good lettuce was and
then all of a sudden we reset the
expectation we're all about giving the
plant what the plant needs and taking
away all stresses we're not in charge
the plants are the ones that are in
charge we're just living in their world
hydroponic means grown without soil so
it's way easier for up the plants they
don't have to you know work they just
can take it up and enjoy the song and
just grow
big believer in the Sun it's free the
light we're running from soda fields the
watery collapse from the rooftop and
reuse so we throw nothing away people
ask us what are you doing to the lettuce
it's what we don't do to the lettuce we
never get the lettuce wet we never spray
it with anything
my family's for lettuce all my
colleagues eat the lettuce and so I
don't want to have pesticide residue I
don't want to be herbicide residue we
don't make it travel miles we don't let
it sit around we don't trip we'll wash
it
over the course of moving it through
some chlorinated waters for it to have
kill steps in it because we don't need
to and we're basically feeding people's
families and that's a big responsibility
I really believe this is the right word
Romans I think that it's it's a lot more
sustainable it's a lot more efficient
it's a lot safer and it also comes up
with a better quality product New
England at one time was a huge food
producer we fed ourselves and I love the
fact that we can be part of the catalyst
and being a driver here and as we
succeed in New England we look forward
to going to other regions and doing the
same thing
[Music]
so so that's us Paul so Paul's the
president/ceo he was originally supposed
to be here
got unavoidably detained and asked me to
come in a stud so appreciate the
invitation I've got some slides but I'll
do those later No okay contribute my
slides please so so like Paul said
basically we are a technology taker as
opposed to a technology maker and one of
the things that we do is we take a look
at where the technology comes from and
basically it's the Netherlands Pete our
grower is fourth generation Dutch grower
and we basically you take a look is that
you know there's a country the size of
New York State about 1/10 the size of
California and that the number 2
exporter of food in the world and the
reason that they do that is simple it's
it's greenhouses so I'm not sure how
many people are familiar with with
Holland or the Dutch greenhouse industry
or in particular the Westlands which is
a picture of this they've been at it for
a long time and in terms of continuous
improvement they're they're not just the
greenhouse growing industry but also
glass manufacturers water systems the
growing system that you saw in our in
our video is actually from Finland the
Dutch had not figured out a good what we
felt was a good lettuce growing system
it already figured out tomato industry
cucumber industry pepper industry
obviously the flower industry but
lettuce and leafy greens they hadn't
figured out yet we actually found a
Finnish company that was growing lettuce
for about 5 years in the Arctic Circle
that we took you know we basically took
it in brought it in and then basically
continued to refine and retrofit it the
one thing I would say in all of these
sessions that I've gone to on a listen
to people is that there's not I'm a
produce guy I've got 30 years in the
experience my first job was on
pineapples for doll into the Hunts Point
terminal market in New York City and
I've gone from there um it's about the
product and there's not a lot of
discussion about product in these
sessions and maybe it's because of the
the audience but the one thing I would
say is that we focus in on the product
the variety our product strategy how
we're going to get to market because the
markets being served people that want to
put up greenhouses and feel well I'm
going to have a local product and
everybody's going to beat a path to my
door that is not the case you have to
come in and be able to compete at if not
better than the market that's currently
serving is so that's basically our view
is the Salinas Valley since we have
opened so it's been we've been operating
for three years we actually have the
number one SKU our baby crispy green
lettuce is the number one selling salad
in New England from a single SKU we we
beat organic baby spinach last year
which we're pretty excited about and
were to continue into ground and and
basically it's it's my job is we you
know I came from backyard farms we ran a
42 acre tomato into business out of
Maine and I had proven basically a
relationships with all these customers
so we're in over two thousand grocery
stores in New England and we're not
we're having a tough time keeping up
with demand but you have to get
tractioning with these guys if you're
going to actually sell something our
business is all about scale we are
looking to to basically compete
head-to-head with the salinas valley for
shelf space and share a stomach and and
that's what we've been basically doing
so that's it those are my slides
I'm Dave Nichols director of strategy
for AB harvest we're building a 60 acre
lettuce facility or it's re tomato
facility in Morehead Kentucky I'm
scheduled to open up September of this
year it's kind of our view that there's
a huge opportunity to build greenhouses
at scale in the United States from some
of the support our view here is there's
a high demand for food we need 70
percent more food in the world by 2050
sustainability is a big topic across the
investment community and the economy
boost of acreage really in America we
have between a thousand two thousand
acre as well as Tim said and Netherlands
they have more than twenty thousand
acres
second largest exporter of agricultural
products in the world so it's it's it's
a great model there's a lot of room for
growth in the u.s. AG tech ecosystems
are successful like that Netherlands is
great 20,000 acres Leamington Ontario
these facilities team two seem to
benefit from clustering improving health
care one to 10 Americans eats enough
fruits and vegetables just imagine if we
can get that up to two or three how will
grow the market increasing interest in
farming average age of the farmer in the
US right now is 58 I mean we really
think controlled environment egg is the
opportunity to bring young people into
agriculture really make it cool again
it's a technology it's it's it's a big
opportunity the big challenge and
economic development right now we're
importing four billion pounds of
tomatoes from Mexico we think why not
bring net production home the trends are
in our favor increasing demand for
plant-based foods you see that with
burger king is selling a plant-based
food there's there's got to be a trend
here veganism is increasing and need for
innovation we're not gonna be able to
feed the world on the way we're growing
right now so we need to have some tech
knowledge and I think controlled
environment agriculture is that
technology over the summer of the Uni PC
came out with a really interesting
report on food systems and climate
change it's really the best
advertisement you could see for a
controlled environment agriculture
basically saying climate change is
affecting the way for the breadbasket of
the world where food is grown we're
gonna need more food the only way we're
gonna get there is technology and all
that technology
points to greenhouses and controlled
environment agriculture a UN sustainable
development goals that we use these all
the time there's 17 of them it's a great
it's a great tool for going into the
sustainable investment community but
green it we we chose these six but
really greenhouses can fit into 13 out
of the 17 so it's really it's a
sustainable business when we started at
harvest we knew we just couldn't drop a
greenhouse into the middle of Kentucky
and be successful we had to build a
community around it we really set out to
build an ecosystem we started that from
day one a little bit about why Kentucky
I was gonna get my sales pitch in here
from Kentucky we can reach 70 percent of
the US population the one day's drive
it's a great place for a produce hub and
energy prices are relatively low record
amounts of rainfall the last three years
and easy access to natural gas and and
really the most important kind of the
commission for our company is the labor
force in Kentucky so as we all know that
coal industry is taking a big hit over
the past four or five years lost tens of
thousands of jobs our view is we need a
new industry to come and revive the
region these are some of the the
hardest-working people in America labor
is a huge challenge in all greenhouses
so we figured it's a great spot to kind
of come in and build a greenhouse and
start a sort of new industry in
Appalachia we started a ground game from
the beginning we knew it wasn't gonna be
easy to that's really gonna day one we
got to have 285 employees working in our
greenhouse so we've had a community
outreach effort since day one we've got
MOA use with for the local addiction
recovery care centers
so obviously opioids are a huge issue
around the country even worse than Apple
a just we've got a program where we
transition the clients from recovery
into the workforce into the green house
government and we would think
government's a big issue we work from
with state local federal and even
international governments we had a
meeting with sonny perdue controlled
environment agra is very much on his
radar he's visited facility and in
Georgia in his home state and recently
did a trip to the Netherlands to kind of
to get a kind of a view of the
Netherlands ecosystem we we had the
opportunity to pitch a controlled
environment act to the UN Security
Council
of all people that came to came to
Kentucky and our CEO got an audience
with them sat down talked about the
industry and there I mean obviously it's
really a global opportunity right now
China's adding thousands of acres a year
and a thousands hundreds of acres a year
Russia's adding a lot of acreage there's
a lot of a lot of activity or at least
talked of activity in the Middle East so
it's really it's really a global
opportunity and most importantly
education oh we started we realize we
got a good create an ecosystem we need
farmers we need people to be excited the
kids to be excited about agriculture so
we started last fall a AG tech education
program in Shelby Valley High School
which is in Pikeville Kentucky right in
the middle of coal country the program
was it's been very successful ninety
kids signed up for 33 spots where we
teach basic horticulture and plant
science and then we have harvest put in
a freight farms unit on campus there so
the kids get classroom training and then
some hands-on growing experience in the
container growing leafy greens and at
the college level we're engaged with all
all five local universities University
of Kentucky Berea College
Eastern Kentucky University Morehead
State and University of Pikeville we
just finished a eight day trip to the
Netherlands with ten professors from the
University just kind of Dutch Dutch
government sponsored the trip just
really giving them exposure to what's
possible think if we can make make this
all this ecosystem happen so that was a
that was a great trip so that's it's
kind of a little bit about our company
in our playbook and follow us on social
media leading up to the launch year and
September thank you hi I'm kale Harvick
I work at USDA in a new position
formerly at Cornell but I work for ARS
the research arm at USDA
I just wanted to spend a few minutes
talking about some of our upcoming
research projects first of all virtual
grower is software that's used for
greenhouse growers to be able to plan
lighting systems or
both patterns of their plants or energy
modeling we're going to be coming out
with a new version of that hopefully by
the end of the year there was a hiring
freeze in the federal government for
about three years ended last year so
we're gonna be able to fill some of
those vacancies now and release a new
version of the software but we've got a
lot of big plans for it we're going to
improve the energy modeling capabilities
using a lot of my previous research
improve the lighting system capabilities
to be able to do more sophisticated cost
comparisons and you know specify custom
geometry for your for your buildings we
also want to have a research mode that's
kind of more technical more advanced for
University and government researchers to
be able to use the software to do some
of the research that we've done
previously done a lot of work with
uniformity of lighting systems so if you
look at the system on the left you see
kind of a bull's-eye pattern and that's
that's really what happens every time
you have lights that are in a plane that
are equally spaced you're pretty much
guaranteed to get a bull's-eye pattern
especially on smaller greenhouses and
shells so we've done a lot of work on
how to optimize that to make a more
uniform lighting system either by
changing spacing or changing intensity
of individual lights so we're going to
continue some of that work near field
optimization so this is basically the
issue of if you have short distance
between lights and plants all the other
techniques for measuring light don't
really work because they're meant for
long distances so we're developing
specialized modeling and measurement
techniques to address the unique
uniformity issues of very close light to
canopy systems drones and greenhouses so
there's a lot of big work being done in
the field agriculture space with drones
we're going to bring some of that
technology into the greenhouse starting
with light mapping but then we're going
to expand to machine vision applications
so for example being able to look in
spectra that are outside of the human
vision to look for disease indicators so
you imagine a drone flying around your
crop and it'll spot disease indicators
before you're able to see it as a
with your naked eye so we're excited
about that project and I wanted to close
with some just tips on if you're if
you're thinking about starting a new
greenhouse business leads are some key
things that you know free advice that I
recommend so number one do your due
diligence before you build anything
almost no one does this in my opinion
they have great plans and energy and
that's great but you really got to have
somebody who knows the energy side of
things
HVAC side of things lighting side of
things give you an accurate cost
estimate and see what you're getting
into you don't have to worry about this
if you're in California but in the
Northeast thermal curtain is huge it's
like probably the number one thing you
can do to save on your heating costs
lighting control systems that minimize
your use of supplemental light
unfortunately commercially available
lighting control that's out there right
now is still pretty rudimentary compared
to what we have in the research world so
you know we're working to try to bring
some of that technology into the
commercial space but there's a long way
to go of course looking at your efficacy
of your luminaires
is important making sure you have the
right amount of supplemental light that
you're not under sized and then you know
a big one which nineties can talk more
about this afternoon is install HVAC
systems that are appropriate for your
situation your location your crop the
type of building you have there is no
one-size-fits-all approach to this so
you really need some good engineering
there utility rate schedules I see a lot
of people that kind of get screwed by
their utilities unfortunately because
there's a lot of choice sometimes for
the utility rate schedule that you can
be placed on you might be able to get a
more advantageous one if you look into
it a little bit more because the the
basic schedule that you get put on might
not be the most economically
advantageous for your business and then
finally check with the local utilities
for available incentive programs and
I'll wrap it up there and look forward
your questions at the end
I hello everyone move up here so I can
point to my slides my name is Erika
Matos and I am the director of the
greenhouse lighting in systems
engineering consortium I think while we
just hear from our panelists here it's a
perfect setup for my talk we are we come
to life we are seven-year $5,000,000
project and our goal is to develop to
answer and implement new
energy-efficient technologies to reduce
the energy causes of lighting in
greenhouses and indoor farms
so pretty much we can develop anything
so then people like King literally farms
technology takers don't have to develop
it's ready to go but we do that by
working with the private and a lot of
partners what I want to talk to you
today four quick topics our program is
very comprehensive so I'm just going to
do a quick overview in four quick things
we are talking about futures farms of
the future here so the first one is
models to accelerate technology
development the risk and bring those
technologies to market with glaze we
work with five main pillars here we're
working with manufacturers some lighting
manufacturers sensors and controls
greenhouse growers retailers and policy
makers or energy efficient companies
service service providers we work with
for actually three academic partners
which is Cornell University Rutgers
University and Rensselaer Polytechnic
Institute in New York in New Jersey and
were funded by the state of New York but
we are a public private consortium so
that means we work with several industry
members she really did risk this
technology the development process we're
constantly interacting with them to
understand find the gaps between those
different segments and understand what
we are developing that is a technology
that is ready to go to the market at the
right price and at the right time can
solve a problem and we seen recently
that this model has been more and more
adopted it's becoming more common
because makes a lot of sense here have
three other examples there is this
programming lamp led by University of
Georgia is a five million dollars
program and you have several
collaborators there to minimize costs of
lighting you have optimi I a that's
recently awarded the leading
universities Michigan University really
focus on reducing the causes of
your farm so again they work with
several institutions is sponsored by the
USDA and we have new institutions like
the RI you have too many members I
didn't but that members here but I think
the main goal here is you working in
five different categories so bringing
all these different moving parts
together we have to collaborate that's
how we gonna bring that's how I see the
futures the greenhouses of the future
and indoor farms of the future as well
so I wanna give now one quick example of
integrated technology that's only
possible when we are working together we
call let's see which is light and shade
system implementation that's something
Kay you just mentioned one of the
control systems to optimize lighting
delivery in greenhouses and aspects of
that can be using your farms as well
so what lassie does is it monitors the
ambient so the first aspect here is the
environment is monitoring how much Sun
is being provided throughout the day and
based on that calculates how much
supplemental lighting should be provided
to achieve a certain DLI they light
integral so you can see here we are
measuring from June through July 19 I
know that's a sunny period of the year
but the reason I did that is because we
also control shade some of the DRI
controllers available they will provide
more light but they do not control shade
so here is a true DIY control so the
first aspect is controlling their light
you can see here the green line is the
target DLI and then it has the red and
blue it's an LED lighting systems and an
HPS lighting system so I get really
close to the target every day
second aspect here trying to integrate
the control systems looking at the
plants now so how plants respond to
lighting in co2 if you understand that
one of the examples that I have here
it's Abhiyan it's a strawberry crop and
what we see here is the net assimilation
co2 per meter square per second in
micromoles versus lighting intensity so
we have 500 micro malls a thousand 1,500
and 2,000 under different co2
concentrations I want to want take out
of this graphic which is under different
co2 concentrations you can achieve the
same narrow simulation which we are here
about seven you can get at 500 micro
moles you get a 7-under 675 ppm I think
that silicon here exactly from here but
if you use a higher
to concentration which is now nine
hundred nine hundred and seventy five
you get the same assimilation using
thirty percent less energy so you can
achieve that under 350 micromoles light
intensity throughout giving the same DLI
so there are significant savings if you
can control together lighting and co2
now the last aspect that we I think
really playing a big role into the
future is now looking at the grid the
energy we call day ahead market price so
this graphic here shows how the peaks
vary throughout the year so have all the
hours of the year and the the red line
here is the average price it's about 17
gigawatts and the pig price is about 32
so energy price the average energy price
is 40% lower than the peak time so what
I want you do here we run integrate
these three variables so you're looking
for the environment you're looking for
the crops and you're looking for the
grid how can you make decisions having
all these inputs to provide the same
amount of light every day that you need
for a crop using the minimum amount of
energy so this is carbon reduction what
we do that to show the savings that is
possible here's a quick setup that I did
so we run an integrated model using gem
greenhouse energy model is one of one of
the available models that guy okay you
talk about we pick Ataka in New York as
the location target DL I was 17 moles
per meter squared per day two different
lighting lighting levels at the crop one
at 180 micromoles one at 250 the own
peak electricity cost as we use 0.12
cents off-peak 0.08 cents and then co2
causes at 50 cents per kilogram results
are pretty impressive what happened
using the basic lassi control looking
just the environment would cost in
dollars per meter square per year about
$28 under the 180 micromoles light level
and about $18 under the 250 micro mouse
light level if we use the different
technologies now to talk lassi and then
the second one was lighting environment
plus co2 the third one the day ahead
market price analysis so the grid and
the environment and the last one
combining grid plan physiology which is
the co2
station and lassie we come down to about
nine dollars and about $60 that means
almost 70% less energy than the basic
control and sixty percent less energy
under the second light level so that's
pretty significant now the problem is
how we take these technologies and
implement on the market we have this
available in the research that's why we
have to work with companies we have to
collaborate we're gonna implement these
technologies into commercial greenhouses
in New York which are part of the glaze
consortium wanting named SAF produce in
Berlin New York one with feud gardens in
Buffalo New York and they will be over
the next four years implementing these
technologies so you can create a
baseline right now to show how much
they're spending right now and over the
next three years they're gonna be
implementing environmental part of the
control with less than shochu let's see
then then co2 laser suits that they had
markets youichi let's see now pretty
quick here data analysis going to be
another big part of the greenhouse of
the future here I have two examples
using a similar lighting control tulasi
but we can't we'll just lightly not
shade in this case is a green housing
Georgia you can see on the blue this is
data from November all the way to
February the blue bars represent the
amount of sunlight in radiation we get
the crops and the green lights
supplemental lighting with an
intelligent lighting control there you
can keep modulating the lights we are
trying to get close to the target the
daylight target which is the red line
over here what I want to show the
difference in data analysis don't have
to look at the prices exactly here but I
really want to show here is the
difference between a green housing
Georgia when we have certain environment
and one in New York during the similar
amount of time in New York to achieve
the same deal I the lights basically
needs to be on all the time because the
weather is really different from Georgia
now if you don't have a dynamic lighting
system you're going to be on all the
time or half part of the time
take a look what happen at the last few
days in Georgia in the last few days in
New York we have a bad week in Georgia
and then the intelligent lighting
control system just bring your light
zone as much as it's needed so then you
can ensure the crop quality now in New
York is the other way around you get a
few good days the lighting control
system kicks in and saves energy for you
and you can get you the same deal I
or close as maximum as you can so the
importance of data knowledge is going to
be huge
moving to the future last one very quick
is the lighting low demand response I
think that's the very important one for
us to keep in mind the IES ODEs the
independent electricity systems operator
in Canada put up this big report talking
about the importance of managing the
loads those are Peaks peak electricity
peak time throughout the year so they
are foreseen that they're gonna need to
work with the greenhouse to reduce the
load when necessary through December
through March and then here the hours of
the day when you have this peak hours I
don't want to go too much into the
detail here but I wanna for this crowd
that is horticultural lighting there are
technologies that can reduce the energy
load over the speak times but are not
looking to the crops so have to
understand what's happening with the
crops can they take this amount of load
can we reduce how many times of the year
can I do this how much can we reduce the
light for the crops and that can only be
assessed that if we know what's happened
with the crops in the environment in
real time so I think there would be a
big big part of the greenhouses of the
future and in terms of the future having
them connect to the grid and making
these smart decisions
considering the crops as well that's it
for now we are with glaze so we have a
ton of educational outreach information
if you wanna learn more about you can go
to the website you can sign to the
newsletter and I hope you guys have good
questions for us right now thank you so
much
so yesterday we were shown a slide that
dem that showed a pie chart and on that
pie chart and it showed that greenhouses
use proportionately more heating energy
or at least gas I don't know what it's
used for necessarily than an indoor
facility and I was wondering if any of
you could speak to that trend that we
saw and why gas use might be higher in a
greenhouse and if you would expect the
same trend for a greenhouse where you
guys are located and I realized we don't
have anyone from southern states and the
Sun Belt represented up here but if you
could also maybe speak to if you have
any experience there of if we might see
different energy trends yea the
greenhouse energy profile is definitely
very climate dependent so in the
northern states you have a lot of
natural gas use for some other heating
fuel you also have less sunlight so you
typically need more supplemental light
than you do in the south as you go south
that heating energy goes down but the
lighting energy also goes down cooling
doesn't change too much if you're able
to use evaporative cooling you're
basically just blowing blowing fans the
south east it's a special case and I bet
Nadi will talk more about that this
afternoon but in general energy goes
energy consumption goes down for the
greenhouse as you go south and it's a
dramatic decrease however we can still
you know have profitable greenhouses in
the Northeast you know little leaf farms
is a great great example of that so you
just need the right systems for that
location
anything else for you Tim for little
leaf are you guys enriching with carbon
dioxide yeah we capture basically all
our fluke lab gases off of the boiler
and we pump it into basically we're a
semi closed greenhouse so we have a
pelham wall when we have calm slurps
underneath so there's about 95 fans and
what we're doing is we're circulating
the air through the greenhouse it comes
back in and we're measuring the
temperature in that and we're putting
the co2 in there so the co2 and
the temperature of the greenhouse is
modulated by that back wall so what'll
happen is when it's cool outside
we'll bring cold air in from the outside
mixing with the air that's coming
through the greenhouse put the co2 in
and that's because we are an NFT system
the slurps are underneath the crop so we
got nice airflow that's going through as
well as co2 you know distribution so
yeah we captured all the co2 and then
when we're not running the boiler we
actually buy liquid co2 and bring it in
and supplement co2 levels because it's
interesting I I heard a commercial I
have a friend who's a commercial
greenhouse tomato grower in Canada and
he said that 50% of his energy bill can
actually be running the boilers not just
for heating but for co2 so they used a
flue gas from the boilers even on a hot
sunny day to enrich with carbon dioxide
yeah yes please
we had so team talked about the Dutch
industry at the beginning and we had one
of the webinars it glaze was someone
from there talking about cogeneration
hidden power and that's something that
can really help here so one of the cases
our commercial pilots Whitfield Gardens
they do buy a lot of guests so they run
the boilers and then they just generate
their own electricity all of that and if
a better prices on gas then the literacy
from the grid you can do that in some
cases according to the Dutch guys they
might even sell energy back to the grid
was more profitable than running the
green house in some cases so it's if you
have access to two cheap natural gas
that could be one option as well then
that goes to your site carbon footprint
versus your out-of-sight out-of-mind
carbon footprint - right because you're
generating combustion gases on-site so
thank you for speaking to that my last
question that I want to ask before I
give it to the audience is in your mind
I want to hear from the growers - I mean
we heard a lot from kale and Erica about
your ideas for sort of the future of
green
but I still want to hear from you which
is what what does the green house of the
future look like does it look like what
we see today is it a taller green house
is it a green house with new covers is
it a green house that is highly
automated what does this look like speak
the automation piece I mean the biggest
thing that keeps growers I think Tim
will agree it's a little more automated
in mine but is just labor so we're
looking into all different types of
robotics for tomatoes tomatoes are very
labor intensive so we require a lot of
employees we'll be looking at different
labor enhancing not replacing but labor
enhancing technologies working with a
couple of companies now they're
developing tomato picking robots and
just ways to supplement our labor force
robots can work 24 hours people can so I
think I think robotics will play a big
piece in the green house of the future
yeah I mean we're the labor issue is
huge we're looking at so basically we
have an automated system I mean nobody
touches the lettuce at all I mean the
seedings automated the the gutters come
through the kit through the greenhouse
it's automated comes out you saw it on
the video comes out goes straight
through the cutting station into the way
or the only people that we have working
are the packing people they you know the
next round of infrastructure that we put
in those those jobs can also be replaced
with with further automation I think the
technology piece of the greenhouse
industry it's continuing I mean we
started with two and a half acres you
know it's just sort of like to figure
out you know the new system and
everything like I said where were
technology takers but we improved on
quite a bit are our vendors worked with
us in terms of increasing efficiencies
and tweaking it so we made significant
tweaks from the first greenhouse to the
second greenhouse and then it's even the
further than the next greenhouse that's
gonna be opening up in May there's the
next level on that and that's everything
from you know the glass that we bought
we went to a higher level diffuse glass
to basically our lighting algorithm we
have LEDs as well as high pressure
sodium in terms of our watering system
and our filtration systems
we've redesigned that as well and then
also as we're learning from our vertical
friends it's like okay how do you how do
you maximize the efficiencies of you
know we believe in green houses we
believe in doing things horizontally as
opposed to vertically but there are some
aspects where you can use different
layering techniques in terms of
maximizing space so yeah it's it's on
the the biggest thing is that there's
going to be just a lot more greenhouses
it's just it's coming and and people
that are doing it have been doing it for
a while and they're pretty good at it so
while our green house is on the upward
trend I mean both of you mentioned being
close to market but is that the whole
story
I think Tim said a lot of it's about the
product and just being closer to the
market I mean as US we're competing with
Mexican tomatoes which are picked I'd
put on a truck and spray with a chemical
to to ripen on the way to the US within
10 days drive so we're we can be closer
to the markets worth of one day's Drive
seventy percent of US population and we
can can keep them on the vine longer
they get sweeter they have more
nutrition and they have a longer shelf
life I mean really the product is I
think it's gonna drive this in the long
run here and that's it I mean it's
product quality but it's also
consistency um basically with the
greenhouse you go 52 weeks out of the
year where you're pretty you're not only
delivering a high quality product but
it's a consistently high quality product
as opposed to our friends and field
agriculture that you know basically do a
very very good job but they're dependent
upon the weather so there's gonna be
swings in terms of seasonality there's
always the food safety issue that comes
up I mean you know last this past year
you almost could set your watch to to
the second recalls like you know the
first one was the Thanksgiving and then
almost a year did a date there was
another recall yeah so that's not going
to go and that's not going to go away so
I mean all those things basically have
people running towards like the
greenhouse industries I think the future
even agriculture do you guys sell well
I'm sorry one last question I can't help
myself
do you guys sell your product on a unit
basis or a weight basis unit basis unit
basis so the way that it works basically
to figure out what your unit economics
are the grocery store wants to figure
out what the price point is so price
points are for for packaged lettuce
it's basically anywhere from two ninety
nine to three ninety nine anything over
four dollars is sort of like Death
Valley if you're going to be of scale so
you have to understand what the consumer
preferences and working with the
retailers so if you could get your unit
economics where the retailer can make
their margin at a two ninety nine to
three ninety nine and then realize that
if you have to promote you go down to a
two four five and still make those
margins that's how you that's the
baseline of figuring out what your
business model is I've heard that that
can also be a driver for being close to
market is that if you're selling by
weight and not necessarily by unit and
your and your price is dependent on the
weight where you sell it that being
closer to market the weight of your
lettuce or your tomato or whatever is
going to be higher than if you traveled
3,000 miles for commodity based
businesses yes okay but for the business
that we're in it's more like a CPG a
consumer packaged goods you're selling a
unit got it as opposed to pounds got it
okay all right your turn I promise okay
we got seven or eight minutes good
morning so nice not to be in the hot
seat myself so first a shameless plug
for little leaf because I am a
Massachusetts official and I have to
support also it's delicious they were a
little leaf family questions for you for
the regulator's because there's at least
one in the room if you had a wish list
of anything that could be done
legislatively a regular regulatory to
help promote greenhouses
what would be on that wish list we have
we have one big one it's got a little
bit pie-in-the-sky but we're we're
really trying to go after an investment
tax credit similar to what was given to
wind and solar and we saw that industry
explode over past 10-15 years it was the
number one job creator in the u.s.
during that time and a lot of that can
be pushed back to that 30% investment
tax credit so that's I mean it's a big
lift but that's that's one we're going
after in DC I've just got a simple one
it's like basically have USDA and FDA
looked at greenhouse especially leafy
green industry do a deeper dive to
understand it so we could just do
something as simple as put ready to eat
on our package yeah which believe it or
not is is a huge hurdle for us to climb
I have a question regarding the the way
you're growing inside the greenhouses
are any what's your I guess the panel's
opinion on living soil versus all the
bottled inputs do you see or are you
trying or are you going that way or are
you currently doing that we're going
hydroponically in in Rockville so no
snow living soil yes so are you asking
rock wall versus P versus soil is that
the question or so we started out we
started out with a rock wall system okay
in terms of with the NFT gutter system
that we were doing but we are
transitioning over to Pete when we first
started we figured that we had enough
challenges that we were going to try
things for the first time we want to
make sure that we had seed placement and
to understand sort of like what the
growth cycles are and and root health
etc etc so so the rock wall was a proven
entity but since then we've gotten we've
done a lot of trials with peat so the
third greenhouse will be completely peat
hi my questions for Dave but maybe Tim
you can answer as well the I understand
part of your model was to be in Kentucky
a day's drive but can you talk about
your site selection did you work with
your utility and on hookups or do you
power on site yeah so we got we got
lucky I'm the first site we tried to
grow on top of a reclaimed coal mine in
Pikeville so there's I think in the in
Appalachia there's the land mass the
size of Delaware that's been mountaintop
removal coal mine so there's there's a
lot of reclaimed coal mine it looked
like a spectacular site - had elevation
everything he kind of need for a
greenhouse the issue was differential
settlement we got the geotech report
back it's like there's no way you can
build on the site there's 800 foot of
fill and it's going to settle
differentially and break your greenhouse
into million pieces so that we had a
pivot very quickly we got we just kind
of got lucky on finding a great site in
Morehead Kentucky so through we worked
with everybody anybody and everybody we
could and just found a great site we
spent a lot of time on on site selection
so we have got a development team
looking at future sites pretty much full
time did you want to answer that Tim -
yeah it's yeah no I mean site selection
is huge we worked with so the Masters
Massachusetts Department of Development
um and then the DAC Devin's Enterprise
Commission the town that we were in is
an old army base that the decommission
quite a bit of the property so actually
the that's how we got the site but it
was all working with them in terms of
you know you have to figure out
longitude latitude you know basically
elevations you want to make sure you've
got enough rainfall so you can capture
water you know all all the above so it's
it's a lengthy process
I think my question is to team two you
mentioned about quality of letters is
what customers are buying and when we
talk about hydroponic or greenhouse the
technology has to be repeatable and
scalable for example one day right next
year five acres farm
some rich guy named West Lake and
created 50 acres same technology and
same quality technically he can produce
I don't know 30 50 percent less let us
compare yours so I guess my question is
how do you differentiate from yourself
from the scaling industry and also
sustaining quality on your products well
so appreciate the question so the first
thing is if you set a standard that's
tough to meet
I mean which sounds you know people are
building these greenhouses and they
think that anybody can do it is
difficult and you've got to have I mean
we've we've been you know tacking
Paulson annexed Cornell guy we've been
the first thing you'd have to do is get
growers I mean and in terms of getting
high quality growers I mean Peter our
grower came over from the Netherlands
but since then we've had a pipeline from
Cornell bring and grad students in and
training them up to full-time grower
jobs so that's a huge investment that
we're taking and where you have to grow
your own growers to begin with
second thing is in terms of varietal
selection figuring out what for there's
a lot of varieties out there we were
very fortunate to get a really good
variety that we we've been running with
and we just got basically we've gotten
an exclusive on this we just worked a
deal with the seed company to get an
exclusive on the seed for the rhythm for
the for the area that will be
marketing's in and then the third thing
is it's like bring it on competitions
going to come I mean we're in in terms
of where we are in the Northeast we're
up against Gotham bright farms leaf
farms you know competition is is the
best growers going to rise to the top
so even if you're going to be able to do
it at scale and if the only thing you
have to compete against me is price I
can and I can handle that it's like
we're working on our unit economics to
figure out where we need to be but if we
are in front of the consumer and meeting
that expectation we're going to be you
know the young lady ra says she goes we
get fan mail all the time about our
product so we've got to make sure that
we're constantly constantly hammering
that home so that the barriers of entry
are tough thank thank you to our
panelists and thank you to your
questions
[Applause]
[Music]