give some love to someone who's genetic
Tsar like blowing you away honest it's
been a genetic that was an 11-year hunt
for me I thought it was in seed form
turns out it was a clone only form and
it was from southern Ohio it was a
strain called lemon G a lot of our
breeders are currently using it it's a
strain that's predominantly or I'm sorry
a cut that's predominantly saturated the
market but the terpene profile to me is
timeless and the original formation of
that was totally by chance it was a bag
seed from what I'm told I actually had
contact with the original breeders over
the years the original breeders I can't
necessarily tell you their names just
based on the fact that they're still in
a state where technically they could be
obtained for what they did however I can
tell you this they are some the most
fantastic people I've ever had the
graces of coming into contact with very
very much community type people that was
a seed strain where it was a total
random crack they got everything from a
waxy overtone of the lemon terpene down
where they crossing it was a lemon
genome ir i'm sorry it was a skunk
genome I believe they said somewhere in
there was the original G 13 but to be
totally direct I'm not 100% the
statement I had only heard them actually
referenced the original parent genetics
twice in my lifetime after countless
sit-downs so it's something that I know
they hold very dear and I'm kind of glad
I don't know if that's the case but
ultimately I do know that the skunk
genetic is in there and that's
attributing to the terpene profile from
what they they were gathering that lemon
terpene ended up being everything from
acrylic wax to full-on just straight-up
hind saw and the one that I came into
contact with actually nine years ago
well no it would be 11 now I've had the
strange for two years so that would have
been a nine year hunt that one was the
pine Sophie no that was one that didn't
sell and like Rick was saying earlier
when we were talking about sometimes the
terpenes can be a double-edged sword
because all of a sudden it's a great
after-dinner
strean but not necessarily a every
moment strain and that becomes a very
big issue when you're producing
especially on a commercial scale because
sell ability is always number one on
that based on well I shouldn't say
number one because ideally the health of
the plan and the people consuming it is
the number one let's say that be the
number two so ultimately it's one of
those things where you've got to pay
attention to your market you've got to
adjust which is one of the reasons why
we're seeing the Mac takeover what
worries me about this is yes it's a
great strain and yes the cookies are
great but when the cookies over saturate
the market and the glue over saturates
the market we start to see crossbreeding
reliant on these strains this is where
it becomes a very big danger for us
because now we're starting to
single-channel all of our genetics into
another genetic what this does is it
actually lop sides the market and
creates a dog breeding issue if you will
where all of a sudden inbreeding is
almost a direct result and there's no
around it because of the way that the
prior genetics have been bred and that's
going to destabilize over time and
create issues or genetic mutations which
could be good could be bad I also
believe that that's part possibly why
we've seen such a dramatic THC increase
because in the last twenty years all the
breeding we've been doing has been
crossing these genomes so aggressively
that we see stresses that we never would
have seen in a naturalised environment
these are plants that would have never
met in nature when that happens we're
stretching the genetic rubberband and
creating a lot of genetic variability
that don't necessarily mean everything
we want and a lot of destabilization
comes from these processes which is also
part of the cause of today's multi Fino
generation we'll call it where it's okay
if I have 30 different phenols
come out of a seed pack it's a sellable
seed really in the old market that would
have not have been sellable in fact
that's one of the reasons why the
Amsterdam market was so closed off
because those readers had processes to
maintain quality and we don't see those
practices being transformed today in
very many seed banks they'll be at great
genetics coming out of those seed banks
so as far as quality of genetics that's
not necessarily the equation here what's
the equation is the lawn
the long game of having that genetic or
some traits of that genetic not be
mutated down the line by a incestual
pattern of breeding which is almost in
some cases and in some markets
impossible to escape so imagine the old
days you know when we had a lot more
quarantine going on to our groups and
collectives we maybe had three friends
that we got introduced into the same
thing we were doing and then out of
those three friends maybe we have six
seven genetics that's our breeding pile
that's a very shallow breeding pool and
that's where a lot of these hybridized
things came out of and you know as
America expanded its seed collaborations
and became a seed creating populous
which used to only belong over in you
know Europe at the time and maybe down
south in South America we we literally
skipped some processes you know we
didn't have a teacher so they were
accidents that were made accidentally
which is should be harmless but they're
not to the endgame so you know it's one
of those things where a miss education
and a little bit too much fun too early
is gonna cause us future problems in
this industry if we don't pay attention
to them currently so when I say things
like you know that the max grade or the
cookies are great but what I really mean
by that are they fantastic the people
working with them are working with them
for a very specific reason and that's
awesome and I hope that they get what
they need out of it but if we're over
breeding these strains we're
destabilizing our future availability to
further creation of terpene profiles
chirping mixes the availability to
having a good THC volume with heavy
terpenes or you know just the anomalies
that we're not currently seeing
prevalently on today's market and really
prevalently ever because we've been
continually developing this crop only
aggressively let's say in the last 20
years notably that's really different
when we talk about agriculture we're
talking about things that have been kind
of corn was something that had over 200
years of development
so you know it's a big change in pace
and we still have time to fix these
problems that we're now realizing have
been caused by shallow breed chello gene
pools so you know when we see
destabilizing genetics we see pollen
late-stage like basically week seven
week eight popping out single little
bananas these are all things that say we
shouldn't went further generations or
further genomes out before back breeding
back in and that's really where the
stabilization comes into play and one of
the reasons we're not seeing it in
today's game that takes years because
we're gonna do that maybe three four or
five times but in order to do that
that's four times a set oh then it has
to mix with its parents for generations
back then we go back and do the same
line of sequence over and over again and
that's how you get to the f-16s f-18s F
20s and when you get there you narrow
down your fee nose that way and so what
basically Rick was talking about with
the parents breeding to create those
seeds is once you have that that is your
that's your Mona Lisa
and so what his techniques allow and why
I have such a respect for for Rick and
Brothers Grimm is they do a great deal
of work just safe lining their painting
they don't store their paintings in
direct sunlight they literally sit there
and have them behind covered glass
making sure that they're protected so
when somebody wants to enjoy them they
enjoy what they are expecting they're
enjoying what they remember for instance
and this is not a slam on nirvana I've
gotten great great genetics out of
nirvana back in the early days we worked
with nirvana on a couple of strands ice
we worked with them on mystic blue and
papaya
great strains we all amongst others
Medusa Snow White all kinds of stuff
from them but what I noticed was after
the EU formed and kind of took over and
altered our industry over in Europe we
ended up having genetic issues with
retaining what we remember now some of
the turkeys were still there but the
flower formation was completely
prynt I had a papaya that looked like it
could have been wheat from the way it
grew I mean it would it would have
produced crazy amounts due to that
almost I'd have to say a thousand heads
it had but they were all no bigger than
wheat so you know it was kind of a
really weird flower formation papaya is
known for big chunky flowers had the
smell so somewhere along the line
destabilization of these genetics
occurred because now these are
phenotypes that we never used to see in
the early days these are all obscurities
and they're from the same genetic
profiles that's why were quite rick was
talking about with going back and having
these parents on safeline is a big deal
now over in europe with the EU shifts
and the raids that happen in switzerland
and austria we started to see that
destabilization because by the
government and not necessarily something
these breeders did so to hold it against
them is absolutely asinine because they
were just trying to make sure that they
were staying in line with what they had
now granted they just got crippled by
their own people and pushed back super
far in their genetic lines and had to go
back and crack seats for mothers again
and like Rick was saying if you want to
change your line up and get variants
that's how you do it
if you want to go for consistency you
need your mother and your father to
rebreathe reburied otherwise your seed
batches will vary from time to time and
yes aging can be an issue but that's
where proper usage of boron would during
these processes and phosphates end up
allowing for these seeds to be produced
with all the micro macro minerals and
elements that's needed for the
protection of this genetic now I
reference boron mainly because it's main
thing in a plant system is to create
plasma which is basically the cushion
inside the cell for all the material to
stay from clacking and getting damaged
so that's one of the reasons why boron
is actually very important in the seed
industry as well as phosphates because
that increases vigor to the plant and
generally keeps the root base healthy as
well so there are ways to kind of almost
have better and worse seed batches based
on your chemistry's in your grow room as
well so there's a lot of variables that
we don't necessarily take into account
when looking
whose consistent and who's not and
that's a big deal because we get one
chance to draw an opinion off of most
seed packs very few of us are like
myself and a few other breeders I know
that go out and buy 1015 packs of you
know regular seeds to go phyno hunting
through get a feel for the genetic and
try and pull something that we can make
a market with and that's really where
feminization loses its foothold
because feminization yes we'll give you
what the breeder wants but you're going
to ultimately end up with the same fee
know that the dude 200 miles away has
now in your markets mesh it's gonna
interfere so the whole idea with Renko
seeds or regular seeds as I am sorry for
callin breakouts regular regular seeds
is the idea of actually getting a true
unrepeatable phenotype because like Rick
was saying there's very fine subtleties
that will change along the way and
that's really what your corners stoning
on you want that change in the flavor
you want that change to the actual
physical growth at the plant maybe it's
a denser plant than the others have we
look at the gorilla glue an original
conception of the gorilla glue when it
came out there were two actual gorilla
coup cuts from my knowledge of what it
was in the first one out with a lower
yielding strain that was identical to
the higher yielding strain in almost
every way and now this could be a little
bit of folklore mind you so there's no I
don't have this I haven't spoken with
the breeder and had him say yes this
happened okay so but the idea is this
they sold out on the lower yield and
Aidid that in the public market and from
what I remember they handed it out which
at that point you're thankful to have an
awesome genetic right I mean it's
gorilla glue is freakin great regardless
of how much he deals well later on there
was some issue that ended up happening
and I guess they lost ability to have
access to that strain and there was kind
of the all of a sudden lift in the
volumes we saw from gorilla glue now is
that substantially due to genetic
drifting off of cuttings could be or it
could be that they actually came out
with the two different cuts which is
something that can happen and that's
just kind of an example of genetics
it's literally like looking like your
brother but being two inches taller and
that's exactly kind of the process and
why it's important to have your own is
out of a pack of a thousand we say there
will be a couple of superstars you're
looking at the superstar to really build
your facility with maintaining your
market if you want to go national or
even want to go and take over a state or
even a portion of a state or even a
portion of your city with what you're
doing you've got to have something
nobody else has otherwise the next guy
can come down knock ten bucks off your
price and he's gonna take your market
and walk with it that's where we see
this drastic destabilization of the
pound - and that's where I get worried
because like we were talking earlier
with all the genomes kind of Bible
necking we're starting to see price per
pound drop because everybody's going to
have this or everybody's going to have
that and that's going to eventually
affect the entire market and so not only
are we shooting ourselves in the foot in
the future of having variabilities to
our genomes but we're also creating a
decomposition to our market at a much
faster rate by centering around just a
couple of these genomes and not truly
having that kind of what's next field
and it's one of my favorite parts about
this is not knowing what's around the
corner you get a seed pack from a
regular bag that you had from years and
years ago and you get a sativa that
blows your socks off because it was done
inside not out or it wasn't brought over
in a tire and sprayed with ammonia now
granted that's extremely rare but if
you're not going on looking for these
genomes you're never gonna find the new
genetic crunch the thing that everybody
wants and we all have this essence of
wanting to be the creator of our own art
and that's really what it comes down to
when we want a canvas do we want
something that consistently has a road
painted in it before we get there such
as having a genetic that everybody else
has in that genome and all of a sudden
I'm stuck painting Lansing's what
happens if I want to paint an ocean
scene and have a big wave in an iceberg
I got a a road sitting right in middle
it's like somehow there's a road there
folks but you know and that's kind of
what
doing with the genomes and it's it's
exciting though you know I speak on it
as almost a negative thing but it's the
exciting parts because you never get the
bruises until you fall you never get the
bumps on the nose to tell you not to run
down the hall until you face the wall
okay so you know these are our wake-up
calls these are our moments to see and
and we've hit that point in the creation
of these genetic availabilities to
really start to see the flaws and
follies and also the Grands and the
glories and know what's what now to
produce and proceed with it thankfully
with today's Internet age we have access
to more books than we could speak up
back in the day when we first started it
was a situation where you go to Barnes
and Nobles and have your friend buy your
book and then he'd meet you at a gas
station ten miles from your house I mean
it was absurd but it was what we had to
do to feel safe and nowadays you just
hop on the internet Google up plant the
fish and seeds and you'll find out
what's going wrong in your garden I mean
it's it's one of the greatest
turnarounds this industry I would have
let me say this it's a great turnaround
that I would have never seen coming in
my lifetime especially growing up in
this industry at the ages of 15 16
figuring it out and having the old ways
kind of translate into the new
availability and what I see from that is
a lot of carelessness but from this
carelessness can come a lot of greatness
comes a lot of wake-up calls it also can
cause a lot of problems but just like
anything else anybody who's grown a
business or a grown genetics or grown
anything it all comes with problems so
these problems that I speak of are not
necessarily truly negative in fact
they're absolutely positive to this
industry because without these lessons
we ultimately might find ourselves lost
in the middle of the woods instead of
still in view of the path and that's a
big deal when we're able to create
health in my garden I'm able to do this
I'm able to maintain and care for others
and myself and and really focus on the
health and quality of the material
and that's some we're starting to see
with commercialization with mass
spectrometry and it's creating a safer
product for all of us and ultimately
when you have the genetics the next
thing is what was that genetics grown
with I mean we look at this market we
say old foods food well no it's not are
you gonna feed your kid noodles everyday
and just oatmeal and see him develop
into a great fantastic multi-dimensional
human being no he's gonna lose his
eyesight he may not have brain
development these are the same things
that we don't know we're doing to these
plants yet by not knowing how to feed it
properly we aren't necessarily giving
these plants everything they can to
create their best and we don't know it
and that's what we're realizing in the
hemp industry as well
and a lot of these farmers are
intentionally starving these crops to
not permit to making THC so the
understanding of food in the cannabis
plant is very much in its infancy in
this industry just based on the
understanding of the public it's not in
its infancy as far as its development
and that's where a really interesting
correlation comes in so it's almost like
handing a six-year-old a cellphone they
may not know what they have but they
know they like it and they know that it
does well and that's we're focusing on
all aspects of your grow comes into play
I mean you talk to a gardener about
what's their water source and all of a
sudden oh I do well are you treating
your water no why are you not treating
your water why are you not setting a
zero variability in the biggest variable
area of your room I mean your
chemistry's your genetics
none of that may work right with the
wrong water so it's very important to
start with at the full picture you start
at the base and work your way up but
every single volume of this cultivation
in the state of being is important and
just as important and so it's
interesting because you may say Oh
nutrients are more important or
Lighting's more important or mediums
just as important but the reality is is
it's all important because it's a
symbiotic nature in which they mesh
that's going to create that end product
you can use a nutritional line and see a
pound and a half reduction perlite or
you can use that same nutritional line
properly and
three pounds of light and there's a
variance we don't know as gardeners
because it's it's a misunderstanding
we've been working with GMO crops on the
AG fields for too long and so when we
associate farming we ultimately think a
big AG and then we think of genetic
development and not realizing that those
implementations have not been applied to
this area yet and hopefully never
because that will ultimately narrow down
genetics and lead into the problem we
originated from it's a it's a monster
deal so what I'm excited about is the
massive allowance of education that
we've been able to get from the internet
the availability of clean nutrition the
availability of clean mediums the
availability of good stable genetics
that we've been working on for decades
and breeding the same parents to create
repeatable seed crops so I've been doing
a lot of I've worked with brothers
grints for years I done work with
Nirvana I've done work with green house
Barney's Paradise was a really
interesting kind of run for me because a
15 to 18 percent ice cream plant went
through mass spectrometry from a
greenhouse and hit 30 percent so
somewhere along the lines those genetics
got upgraded but after going over what I
knew of it from the book of buds it sit
every format and profile of the original
genetic and that creamy flavor down to
the rock-hard flowers down to the you
know two and a half ounce maximum per
plant that I was seeing it was
phenomenal so really just about
anybody's good I like the older breeders
because they tend to have a certain
style I've been working aggressively
with ethos lately as well I've been
really excited with a lot of his limited
releases and like I said you know just
because it's limited just because it's a
one-time run doesn't mean that it's
truly a lazy man strain some of us may
call it that but it really is something
special and
maintain its being special some of these
guys will put out limited's that are not
just hey I had this accident and here
you go they're actually limited for
being awesome I mean we look at some of
the old like the reservoir soured the
reservoir Sour Diesel you couldn't
necessarily get that it was a cut only I
mean a lot of these old school strains
that were breeder strains and backbones
for a lot of these new new-school
genetics as well as old school genetics
came from that time period and what's
messed up about it is that bottle
necking because we're sitting in the
middle of that issue right now and we're
seeing that with the saturation of
cookies and glues I mean you look at any
breeders line and if they don't have a
glue or a cookie then they're not in
today's market that says something
because that's been in their shop the
potentiality for issues down the line
are there because that genetic is
everywhere it's one of those things
where it's cool until everybody has it
and that's been the cannabis game that's
kind of been our crowd and it's
important to remember that's where we
come from because that's gonna safeline
not only the future where we can have
things like the cookies in the glue come
out saturate the market but as long as
we recognize not to necessarily take
that as a crutch but to use it as a tool
that's going to be the biggest thing and
right now we're getting a good
equalization of people realizing that
it's more of a crutch than a tool right
now in most Gardens and that we need to
walk away from so as as much as I love
these genetics and have great respect
for the breeders because they did a lot
of hard work to get these phenomenal
things to the market there's a lot of
danger in the excitement that surrounds
them
so it's almost
it's almost dangerous to a certain level
so you know it's kind of been one of my
more focal points of concern in the
industry lately and one of the reasons
I've been focusing on terpenes because
turkeys are a really interesting profile
format that follows through those
genetic lines like the Haze's for
instance you'll smoke a lemonade she'll
smoke a silver haze you'll smoke super
Silver Haze and you will find that exact
terpene profile that's dominant in the
haze genome I have the same thing going
on in our elephant tooth which was a you
know blue ice cream which is blue tooth
from BC seeds before the scandal mixed
with elephant and paradises ice cream
and that one turned into a full-blown
hey it's based on the blue tooth genetic
now what was interesting about that was
the ice cream would have been the main
genetic producer I would have thought or
the dominant replicant based on the fact
that the seeds came from the ice cream
plant which is one of the reasons why I
really wanted it I thought hey that'd be
dominant well it doesn't always work
like that and that's something that
we're starting to also evolve and
recognizes it's not as easy as it seems
and it's it's interesting because if
we're paying attention it will show us
that constantly and we got a lot of
interests in this market as far as
retention but we got a lot of people
wondering how to do that so if they're
wondering how to do that and it's their
end goal to do it currently it's not
being done and we're starting to see
that interfere with
you know I I think we beat that one up a
bit so I'm just gonna leave it there but
it's been a big bothersome reason for me
to be very bold