if Sacramento got their act together the
BCC what do you see could be the future
in the next five to ten years in
Humboldt County and the Emerald triangle
in a perfect world if if things got
better if if somehow they started
getting the regulatory act improved and
making it work for farmers I think that
the and and I and I believe that it will
work over time if I didn't see any
future I wouldn't know what's so hard at
it and just that I didn't see this
little bump but I still have the same
long-term view and I think that what
you're gonna see is a radical change in
in stores just like retail in general so
retail in general is knows no more store
fronts but people love to buy things on
online they love Amazon they love the
simplicity people don't like to deal
people when people tell me that I go
well go tell that to Blockbuster and
explain to me how much they love going
in buying CDs and DVDs to watch their
movies because they don't they would
rather have it delivered right through
the phone cannabis will be the same way
where I think that the delivery model
will be the model of the future by far
and storefronts will only be like
flagships the places that you can come
to for certain things it represents a
company it's in geographic areas that
have huge traffic flow but otherwise
you're done because it mirrors all
retail sales in general right so once we
start to have the distribution and
delivery that is really well organized
through California then what you'd be
able to have is companies that
specialize been working with Humboldt
County products and you started to be
able to go forward you're going to have
very differentiated genetics in terms of
its stamped as its own well then those
companies might have those forms and
they want you to cultivate it I'm sure
the Sunkist doesn't let you just grow
whatever orange you want they give you
the orange they tell you what orange
they want they they control and if
you're in tobacco you're controlled if
you're in one
and champagne you're growing a very for
different type of grape that's it
and so each region to me would produce
things that were distinctive to this
region that were that shined in the
region that let the cultivators produce
common product so that you had the
ability to have enough product from
Humboldt move across the whole state and
then eventually over throughout the US
in a level that gave them the ability to
buy it over and over again and what you
then would have is you have cultivators
that then would have little tiny niche
gardens on their bigger picture farm
that would then let them release a
seasonal kind of like breweries do a
seasonal beer release where they hey we
only brew this lambic once a year
because it's expensive to make we charge
more but we make less and I think that
that will follow suit because it does
with all these other things now the
cannabis is no longer held by us it's
open it'll follow like every other
product and I think that for us is we
just have to understand those changes
are going to occur by think we like it
or not and that what we need to do is is
build the farms build the infrastructure
Humboldt County produces world-class
cannabis period it always will the
climates to good
it just is ideal for really good or a
production you don't get it in the
Central Valley you don't get it in
Southern California you got to run
indoor there you've got to run in during
the desert you got to run indoor in the
Central Valley with it's the
contaminants you have to run into around
the East Coast you got to run indoor in
Florida you got to run into a Texas you
can run outdoor through this all these
regions in this Northern California area
all the way into the Sierras so from the
Sierras north it's some of the best pop
grill and you can imagine till you get
up into like middle Oregon so that
Southern Oregon Northern California
cluster is probably some of the best
cannabis growing on the planet I mean
it's unbelievable all the other
countries you know we talk about these
other countries but they have humidity
issues too and so the things that grow
there are attractive to the customer any
more time wills will switch they'll be
great for biomass but for us for flower
for exquisite smoke these are the
regions where
you gonna get those outdoor products and
so humble just really has to come
together and it is you you're seeing all
these who these groups get together to
learn regenerative farming you're there
everybody is getting together you're
part of it you are putting together
groups to do combined buying for add
products so that's why everybody can get
a cheaper price you're getting people to
come in and say hey this is what I think
would move because I'm looking at the
data this is something that's no longer
moving instead of holding that
information you share it and you share
it with the clusters you're in because
you're all going to compete in a
different little realm and I think that
the positive part of poverty is that it
brings people together and I don't think
I've ever seen Humboldt so United which
is telling me because we've never been
so broke but we are all trying hard to
work together to figure it out and most
of us intend to stay here for the
duration I mean my goal is to die here
and hopefully not tomorrow but you know
when I'm older and I want to see the
farm that I built produce the cannabis
that I used to produce and I want to see
my kids be able to be part of that
industry in the future so that they have
something of value that took a lot of
work to get and I think that I'm no
different than anybody else I mean that
we're on the same exact bone and the
only differences I have is I have
multiple licenses so the multiple
licenses give me a different perspective
than most people because they see it
from either one of the other and I'm
seeing it for many at the same time and
I just know that right now why would you
better be careful financially so beware
all right thanks so much Kevin well
[Music]