[Music]
my name is Michael Masterman Smith I'm a
molecular medical pharmacologist from
UCLA go Bruins
a brain tumor specialist from UCLA go
Bruins
chief scientific officer of CA labs
which is a small company that we're
starting and once again it's the
botanical drug space is one is one way
to explain it Fido phytochemistry is is
another way to explain what are what are
chemicals and pharmaceuticals that come
from nature versus something that might
be synthetically derived in a lab or and
and if any of you who have healthcare or
obviously of healthcare backgrounds but
if you have biology backgrounds we know
most of our drugs come from natural
products and then we will do.a some
tweaks on it and make it synthetic and
that and then that's how drugs develop
so in many ways my talk about medic
medicinal cannabis reverts back to
something that we used to do before we
had the age of synthetic chemistry and
our ability to really modify chemicals
in new in different ways
I'm also a United States congressional
candidate that was something new that
happened this year and I just felt as
though compelled that it was time for me
to step up and and take a serious
responsibility for some of the
healthcare issues that we have in this
country and I'm a founder of the Center
for accessibility center for
accessibility research and education
care it's a new organization that I'm
starting to be able to get healthcare
candidates elected as well as move on
some of these agendas that that that
need to be done at the federal level and
so I'm now a healthcare advocate so from
cancer lab to cannabis farm in 1998 I
became interested in malignant brain
tumors I was researching pediatric brain
tumors and we just didn't have a lot of
options for these patients and these
kids the cause was unknown treatment
options were were and still are very
limited and then in 2003 we discovered
these things called cancer stem cells
and these weren't pediatric brain tumors
and we found that this changed the way
we think about cancer as the cause of
the most malignant cancers and so this
is something where we actually could
dial into these cells go bad and that
causes the problem so we describe these
things as basically stem cells that
break bad and they just go they are
responsible for
create making copies of themselves but
it also creating the tumor tumor bulk
and the malignancy as well as they're
responsible for metastasis and this was
something that I was always very
passionate about I'm still very
passionate about but it's it's a matter
of we haven't we now have a new
understanding of what cells we need to
be looking at now we need to target them
and then 2006 we screened and studied 30
over 30,000 drugs which could kill brain
cancer stem cells this is exhaustive
pharmaceutical research we're really
trying to find what might kill these
things and we couldn't find anything to
kill them the exception of by 2013 that
and if you look at the numbers the
amount of time and effort it takes to be
able to develop something that might
actually be brought through as a as a
treatment for cancers it's a lot of time
so into 2013 we published a study
proving cannabinoid receptor agonists
are a powerful drug class that could
kill these specific cells the issue was
we were dealing with synthetic compounds
we could not get them to clinical trials
we couldn't license them we couldn't do
anything with them because they would
they would they would be considered too
toxic for us to be able to continue
clinical trial that led later on to 2016
I founded a botanical biopharma company
to develop cannabinoid based medicines -
for hard to treat conditions what I'm
gonna talk about today is what is the
endocannabinoid system three important
diseases where cannabis based medicines
may become essential in reducing disease
burden in healthcare costs one is brain
injury and brain health
second one is cancer my specialty and
the third one is pain management and
stemming the opioid crisis I'm gonna
describe what do cannabis medicines
actually look like
what is the national kind of some
medicine policy look like and then we're
gonna go over real quickly challenges
and promise for implementation into the
US healthcare system the takeaway from
all this is how do we make America
healthy again the human endocannabinoid
system so the human endocannabinoid
system is a lock and key for
cannabinoids and cannabis based
compounds there's several different
receptors receptors are antennas they
coat the surface of cells in our bodies
cannabinoid receptor one in red is
receives THC that's tetrahydrocannabinol
that's the that's our that's our domain
thing that everyone focuses on in the
adult use market with regards to to that
market it's mostly in the central and
peripheral nervous system then there's a
kind of annoyed receptor 2 which is
indirectly receives inputs from
cannabidiol which is which is a non
psychoactive CBD and then that's found
in the nervous system and remarkably
it's found in the immune system if you
could see the greens and Red's though
these are this is a receptor system
that's throughout our bodies it is with
regard to difficulty the green area the
immune system well it's for our gut is
it's for a lot of things go down go on
down there and that's where we have a
lot of problems with with autoimmune
diseases and whatnot in our guts and IBD
inflammatory bowel disease it's all it's
all mediated by our immune system and
it's in our gut area now there's also a
third we're still learning this is a you
know basically we we built the car and
we're driving it at the same time we
made there might be a third and
cannabinoid receptor that's still under
study it hasn't been called the CB 3
it's right now called some very
complicated name we're not getting it
into and then there's these
endocannabinoids and these are the drugs
that our body produces just like
endorphins get produced when you when
you run same thing happens in our bodies
we have these endocannabinoids that get
produced for a number of different
reasons and I'm just going to go into a
few of them here today and what they do
so traumatic brain injury traumatic
brain injury is a devastating disease
it's a devastating thing that happens to
a person the and reproduces a cascade of
complex events within 20 minutes and
then there is the reparative in
destructive processes that go on in
those 20 minutes as well as beyond those
20 minutes
there's primary secondary long-term
effects there's no real effective
therapies and the side effects of
traumatic brain injury include painting
memory attention deficits anxiety stroke
effects PTSD affects learning depression
these are risks is a really hardcore
disease that we just really don't
understand a lot about and we're still
trying to figure out the interesting
thing about traumatic brain injury that
however is that we learned that the
about these endocannabinoids from
studying traumatic brain injury
so these endocannabinoids are naturally
occurring contaminoids they protect the
brain from stress during injury and they
were identified by studying the effects
of brain injury on the right side of
this slide is a picture of a presynaptic
post
tactic noron and there was these
chemicals on the left slide is those
those odd-looking chemicals and those
are CBD like compounds and what they
learned was upon brain in a prawn upon a
traumatic brain injury these chemicals
get produced by the body and their
specific purposes to to stop chemical
signaling that can kill neurons and I
thought this is very fascinating that
would happen that we were trying to
figure out traumatic brain injury we
ended up in the same fashion that I was
learning about cancer another lab
studying traumatic brain injury and they
said oh wait a minute this is something
that is something that could protect
brain injury or not and I'm seeing in a
cancer lab and I'm like oh my god this
is something I could kill cancer this is
a lot of the ways scientific communities
starting to look at this look at this
thing and look at cannabinoids in a
different way can I have a kid who knows
in our production our brains are
constantly under stressed through
lifestyle aging if you have a brain
injury you played football or soccer or
any other event that would hit you in
the noggin mood disorders poor sleep
diet these are all things that we all
experience right and it turns out the
cannabinoids may fend off this stress
it's a natural thing that our bodies are
doing in order to in order to protect
itself from from these insults that we
have to our body and of cannabinoids are
produced in response to brain injury may
play a role in recovery from brain
injury and Oquendo binoy to repair and
protect the brain and then the
scientific consensus is now that
cannabinoids can be fir that should be
further developed as potential
preventatives as well as treatments for
brain injury now we're gonna move
switching to cancer the effects of
cancer on our healthcare system are
enormous it takes up to a billion
dollars to bring a drug to the to bring
a new drug to market to satisfy return
on those costs each successful drug must
bring in about five billion to ten
billion dollars so the worldwide sales
of cancer drugs surpassed 100 billion
dollars in 2016 and the market is
expected to reach 147 billions by 2017
or obscurity by 2018 which be this year
mark that bring that into the United
States and and directly affecting your
careers and what we're doing here in the
United States is that we have 1.6
million new cancer cases each year
600,000 cancer deaths and 30% of
patients die within one year so we still
feel own way to go and then we have
these economic issues that we have to
deal with
so the big question can cannabis really
be used to treat cancer absolutely this
is a very the slide of a very what what
goes on in cancer and how we study
cancer cannabinoid receptors get
expressed on cancer cells they act as
antennas to condemn it and then the
cannabinoids can get into the cells
through those receptors and then they
actually just kill the cancer cells but
there's a lot of complications that go
on so if you look at this slide there's
all these different signaling pathways
so the red parts are inhibitors of a
particular function and the green green
arrows are activating functions if you
look at the bottom of the slide most of
those functions that you're seeing are
cancer stem cell things epithelial
mesenchymal transition is how a cell
pops off from a tumor and then goes
somewhere else
that's how metastases get started
there's some things in the middle here
feel it directly in the middle that mTOR
that akt that pi3 kinase or it's called
PA 3k that's a very very powerful
cancer-causing signal the drugs are very
difficult to develop I worked with this
pathway for most of my career and we
every single time we throw a drug at
that that's trying to inhibit that
particular pathway that would kill the
cancer stem cell it didn't work so a lot
of these drugs that are on the market
now they're only there satisfactorily
they're satisfactory they're treated as
block Buster's but we still have a long
way to go because these pathways are
very difficult now that thing in the
middle that pi3k a KTM tor shutting that
pathway down will kill a cancer stem
cell and it turns out that that's what
we found and we were studying
cannabinoids it shut that pathway down
and the cancer can and the cancer stem
cells died and that's really where we're
looking at targeted chemotherapy for
cancer might actually be targeted
cannabinoid therapy for cancer in the
future how does kind of miss kill cancer
cells
some cancers cells Express antenna like
receptors on the cell surface perhaps as
a mutation for growth we're still trying
to understand why I condemn annoyed
receptor would be expressed specifically
on a cancer sent cancer cell a lot of
research still needs to be
dun cannabinoids enter the cancer cells
and act as a Trojan horse can its effect
essential signals that keep cancer cells
alive and then cancer stem cells
particularly are highly dependent on
very specific signals for survival that
cannabinoids shut down and because of
cannabinoid effects on immune function
they may help the body to kill cancer
cells in ways we don't fully understand
at this at this time right now I'm going
to switch into pain management I'm going
to switch into the opioid epidemic one
of the reasons I actually ran for
Congress was because I felt as though
something that we were failing that we
had a drastic failure that went right in
front of our faces and and here as I
hear I'm as a cancer biologist I'm
trying to understand how to treat
complex cancers and all of a sudden
we're seeing deaths from opioids it was
something that we've created it was
something we did and now we're all
panicked by it every doctor I see is
completely panicked by the opioid crisis
so hands rolling I'm going to switch
into hands roll the hands rolling was a
statistician and he looked at basically
development and how finances and art and
and the development of our economies
related to life expectancy and he was
Swedish so he was looking at the Swedish
life expectancy so on the on your y-axis
here though is YX is the life expectancy
on the x-axis is income as our income
and our GDP grows our life expectancy
goes up so as a the state of American
medicine can be seen that in the same
way these are pictures from his family
members who helped him write this book
called fact fulness which I strongly
recommend you to read and check out
because it's a pretty cool book so we
develop in a couple of you know we
develop when we go from walking and then
we get bikes and we start riding bikes
and then we have cars and now we got a
lot of cars so we run into developed and
then we go over developed and I look at
that fourth thing and these are the
patterns of economic development so in
the fourth thing where we have plenty of
cars that's a situation where we were
moving into over development and that's
really where I think our healthcare
system is at right now where we were
good and then we just went over the you
know went overboard a little bit this is
not to scare you we're gonna change
healthcare I think it's going to be
great in the future but we just have to
we have to figure these things out we
Americans make up 5% of the world's
population we consume 75% of the world
we pay the most for them that's not
helping anyone and and our u.s. life
expectancy is dropped because of opioid
deaths males will no longer live to 82
years old we're gonna live to 75 because
of an opioid crisis the number one
killer of people under 50 is opioids
we've got to go do something about this
folks it just turns out that state of
cannabis as medicine is there to start
to help this cannabis relieves a number
of common ailments pain and inflammation
they relieve some costly and difficult
to treat conditions cancer brain injury
autoimmune disorders that work
synergistically with existing existing
medicine so it can be brought right into
our system and not necessarily be this
odd thing that comes in it's just a way
to help other drugs that might work in
particular things such as chemotherapy
and opioids as broad-spectrum effects
and may reduce healthcare costs and in
ways we don't understand yet we have to
research it it can be safely used as a
replacement or with opioids to reduce
opioid overdose and abuse
and healthcare and societal costs are
going down prescription medication use
has gone down and deaths from opioid
crisis has gone down in states that of
medical cannabis programs these are not
is this there was a study in the Journal
of American Medical Association two
weeks ago Journal of internal medicine
as well at the same time Rand just
released a public address released a
study showing the fact that that this is
what's going on what this kind of a
space medicine looked like well Johnson
&amp; Johnson just decided that there now
have a medical cannabis company up in
Canada that they're working with to
create medicines GW pharmaceutical and
in just under the GW Pharmaceuticals is
this on to the left of it is a compact
is a drug called a petiole X on April
18th just next week they're about to
have their FDA review to treat as to
treat seizures from a very rare form of
epilepsy so this is the beginning of
what America is going to be going
through the process we're going to
create these medicines and
and in city labs we learned we started
to work with patients we tried to figure
out like what works what doesn't work
and we started to figure out that there
was ratios that were that were very good
some people who needed pain maybe needed
more THC people but people who didn't
want to get the psychoactive effects
they'd be able to use CBD this is gonna
this is this is gonna be medicine in the
future and as more and more companies
start to move through the pipelines and
and be able to go through our clinical
trials we're gonna have some new tools
in the toolkit and we're gonna get used
to it and we're going to be fine I I
fundamentally believe that we're gonna
be fine we can get ourselves out of
these health care crisis and cannabis
medicine is going to be a part of that
the way to do it
for true cannabis based medicine and in
order for medicine to be accepted and
doctors to be able to say yes I believe
in this it has to be precise it has to
be accurate it has to be for specific
indications we have to report on the
side-effects we have to understand the
proper use for the condition and then be
able to explain to physicians and
patients how they should be using it
because if you don't use it right it
might not work well and it might also
get you really really high and that
might not be good either and then when
we're dealing with the severe diseases a
physicians care should be there this
isn't something that people should go
off and do that I'll do on their own if
you're sick you know doctors would I'm a
PhD I know a lot of things doctors know
a lot of things they need to be able to
be able to work with the patient so we
don't really have that in this in
America right now and we need to get to
that point and then it should be
insurable once we can make an insurable
we'll probably be able to really be able
to reduce our healthcare costs as well
as improve our care and you know America
will get healthy again components of an
effective national medical cannabis
policy this is something that I came out
for years and years and years and
looking and looking and looking and when
I ran for United States Congress I said
what would I want to do if I had the
power what is exactly the steps that I
would take in order to introduce
cannabis into this healthcare into the
healthcare system first accurate
scheduling of cannabis and cannabinoid
derivatives such as CBD and THC THC
psychoactive CBD is a little less
psychoactive to non psychoactive and yet
being treated like the exact same
compound with the exact same as a drug
of abuse that has little or no medical
value and yet we're seeing that there is
medical value and they're not
necessarily drug drugs of abuse either
we need to have a federal recognition to
cat cannabinoids are a safe alternative
for pain relief because that's where it
started we got the opioid crisis because
we were focusing on opioids for pain
relief and we weren't looking at
anything else and we need to start
thinking out we need to start thinking a
little bit differently about how things
go we need to fund research initiatives
we have to study the endocannabinoid
system when I was in training they
didn't teach us anything about the
endocannabinoid system that's just it's
not something that you learn when you're
going through an American medical school
we have to research and develop and
deploy new therapies and we're going to
start to have to do this very very
quickly we have to understand the
healthcare economics so if healthcare
cows go down with cannabis and they're
researching it cannabis is an out of pot
out-of-pocket expense so we have to
understand how this is going to actually
favorably improve healthcare and and
favorably improve our ability to insure
for it and actually make it possibly
easier to sell insurance if you're
dealing with things at work and and have
the right cost metrics this could help
this is going to help you help your
industry and over the long term and then
we have to study Panama's use disorders
scientists and doctors do not call this
an addictive substance they'll call it a
cannabis use disorder they won't call it
an addiction there's something going on
there that this is not an addictive
substance as we've been led to believe
throughout generations we have to create
specifications for medical education and
continuing medical education training
doctors nurses and you in the healthcare
system they want to learn about this
they want to do the right thing they
know the drugs that they're that they're
prescribing in many cases are not what
they are not optimal they just want
other options but they need to be
trained and so see me is gonna be a part
of that as well as continuing education
for our health care insurers you guys
should really get up to speed on this
this is why I'm here we're gonna have
these conversations we're gonna learn a
lot it's going to help us and then we
need to improve the regulatory process
for cannabis medicine across our federal
the DEA the FDA the Veterans
Administration the National and suits
our drug abuse these are agencies that
need to be working together in concert
to be able to introduce cannabis
medicines into our society and then
Six's insurance coverage for medical
cannabis and cannabis medicine it's a
medicine it should be it should it
should fall under the same exact
guidelines that we deal with other
medicines and that's where we're getting
to and this is one of the reasons why
I'm speaking here today the challenge is
to implement a cannabis medicine pretty
simple we have an adult use thing we all
have something some relationship to
cannabis in some way we have to separate
out that yes there's a director a tional
use and the adult use and the fact that
we use this to treat very deadly
diseases and we use it as a mechanism to
improve our healthcare system and these
are two different things and the stigma
that gets applied through things like
this don't help doesn't help my job it's
not going to help your job so if you're
gonna walk away from here I'm gonna ask
you for this the promise and implemented
cannabis based medicine it's grown-up
pants when somebody's at the dinner
table and you're at cocktail hour or
you're in the office and you're talking
about cannabis and cannabis medicine
we're the grown-up pants and say hey
listen I talked to somebody who really
knows what he's talking about he says we
can cure cancer with this I talked to
somebody who really knows what they're
talking about and they they they're
there's a there's a way to go about
doing this yes I snicker I laugh it's
funny but I'm also working on very
difficult diseases and so my goal is
really recruit everybody in this room to
think like that because we're all gonna
get sick we're all gonna have to we're
all gonna have to deal with this in the
future do we want to do it we do do we
want the medicines we already have yes
some of them are great some of them
aren't that great some of them may be
too much some of them it's not enough
that you know circumstance ours that
we're there and we need to integrate
cannabis medicine to our healthcare
system because while we don't the rest
of the world is going to so this is
something that that grown-up pants are
pretty important and it is okay for you
to laugh but then say yeah but it's also
used for some really important things
and those medicines are going to come
along and we're going to
the insurance codes for specific ratios
and specific dosages and and specific
products are going to be on the market
and I have a feeling that they're going
to be a lot cheaper than some of the
drugs that we have to do that we have
today and we can make America healthy
again I'd like to thank everybody like
thank you for listening to me
[Applause]
[Music]