so it sounds like you use cover crops
yeah oh yeah oh you have other life
growing it's not just a lone soldier
standing out there by themselves oh yeah
I have
okay I'm gonna lay it on you my system
you're gonna love this it's it's a a
scaleable high production no-till micro
remediated subterranean full-spectrum
light depth bio retention pit technique
yes that's what we've been missing
that's like that's beautiful I know what
that mean you know what that means you
know you know that knew the layers upon
layers of life took a while to realize
even realize that's what I was doing
because I've always been doing that
technique honestly since the beginning
when I learned some science after living
it for 15 years I'm like oh my god
that's what that's called I didn't even
know I was doing no-till for 12 years
but I'm doing it