[Music]
this show used to be so small that we
didn't need a large room outside of you
know obviously so what are we 10 times
where we've been in terms of the size of
this like three years ago started with
like 700 then it was 2000 then it was
7000 and then we went to 20 last year
which was unheard of and now it's 40,000
people coming to see cannabis I'm an
emerging markets guy and and and I've
been investing around the world my
career and I've also been investing in
new asset classes and and to me this
kind of stuff gets scary when I see this
relative to - you know I was here two
years ago it wasn't here last year two
years ago as my first I've been
investing in the sector for about 3
years and and this gets me a little
concerned when we also know what's going
on in public markets and how some
companies that launch - you know two
weeks ago at a 3 billion dollar market
cap were cut in half we won't name names
Nick the floor is yours
it's never as long as I don't have any
well you know I got it I got into
cannabis 2006 after the military and
when I saw and like from Colorado
standpoint medical markets evolving than
pre adult use transferring to other
states other countries it's growing but
when I think even this conference and
doubling in size of the companies that
were here last year
two-thirds of them aren't here and now
there's like all these new companies so
that's happening where there's all these
new states new markets new opportunities
ancillary hands-on hands-off and it's
hard for cannabis companies without
liquidity or without an institutional
cap to really get the capital they need
but then how do investors choose
individual portfolio opportunities do
the due diligence on them the team the
license their revenue even understand is
this a profitable business model because
normal investing is one thing cannabis
is another so the being able to bridge
cannabis knowledge capital knowledge
those are the teams are like either
private funds or some of the public
offerings have a lot of potential but
for most of these organizations of the
thirty thousand here twenty thousand
won't be here next year but then they'll
be enough
40,000 new ones ramping up at the gate
let's talk to the man who's running a
big business right now and and you know
how you see the world because bottom
line you're in a position to be
consolidating a lot of different markets
that you're in you're growing your
markets right now you're you're you know
you're I believe you've been referred to
as the Beast of the East or you would
certainly like to be so talk to me about
that Bob I think Nick Nick said it right
I read this this industry is first of
all it's been legalized state to stay so
so all the normal things of businesses
didn't exist in the cannabis world we
don't have banking we can't cross state
lines
we have unusual taxes with 280e we've
got a federal government that is lurking
in the shadows and we're trying to get
state governments to try to figure out
how the industry works but I think some
of the states have done a good job and
and in it and it's been the private
sector it's been the entrepreneur that
took the risk with private money rich
guys that took a risk and helped build
these incubate these companies state to
state different licenses not-for-profit
for-profit the other I think now that
the Canadian public market got involved
and all these capitals being invested up
in base trade they see a way of
aggregating multi-state operators like
ourselves I mean my company Merriman mr
MD on the oTCQB 16 consecutive growth
quarters but I mean I think that what my
company was based on was operations I
mean we believed in strong management we
best practices best of class and
cultivation production distillation and
merchandising and we always thought that
earnings and revenue and assets would
make everything work we're a little
scared of the capital markets and the
multiples of projected revenue
and we worry about the entrepreneur
state the state that might be getting
killed by these category killers well
that's interesting cuz and I'll then
toss this to Nick because it sounds to
me like though that the capital markets
have been your friend let's face it
you've built an incredibly strong
company you have the position with your
your stock also potentially to be a
vehicle for making acquisitions or cash
you have sophisticated investors that
have been drawn to your company and
actually are investors because they kick
the tires they looked under the hood and
they they really see a good operator so
then the question is Nick he's building
a company that's in the public markets
and he continues to grow you know at an
aggressive pace and yet a lot of these
companies that we see trading on in
Toronto or OTC here shouldn't ever have
gone public and and you know so why are
people rewarding some of these other
companies when in fact we've all seen
this before at other times in asset
cycles dare I call them bubbles I would
say the current bubble is actually three
times worse than even the dot-com bubble
and it's gonna really be felt in Canada
I mean from what we saw in Colorado to
multiple states we've worked in 30
states our consulting company having
done licenses and most of those
understanding the underhood operational
companies were actually this is
agriculture this is manufacturing this
is retail brand licensing triple net
leasing property management companies
it's not master growers that's when you
have major failures seeing how that
worked on a multiple state level to then
all the licenses internationally we
started to work we saw that
international opportunity obviously
we've worked in Canada like five six
years done licenses have lp's genetics
companies use them even to help win our
German licenses in the beginning but now
with all of our partners internationally
in twelve licenses that are all
privately held with exclusive rights to
capital for us when you're fighting
against tilray with one license and I
have the other and there were thirteen
billion market cap and I have exclusive
capital rights operational control
that's where there's like major
opportunity but the international side
you think Colorado four years ago zero
dollars in revenue of adult use now it's
like six seven billion plus the velocity
of capital which is almost 7x
of a normal industry so you have almost
a fifty billion dollar economy created
in Colorado of like jobs workforce taxes
that people say there wasn't even a
billion in sales internationally last
year so it's too early but Canada by
being nationally legal on a medical
basis initially allowed those public
markets to happen the problem is they
also didn't realize by legalizing adult
use they're violating international law
and that's not necessarily off I'm
following state law but I don't like to
ever break international law you got to
know the rules to play the game and many
people don't focus on that I'm not a
lawyer or accountant we hire lots of
those I've worked with worked with
hundreds of them in hundreds and
hundreds I best in a lot of these
companies and and I'm also a guy that by
the way look I lived in Russia for a few
years so if there's a guy that's gonna
be scared travelling across borders
right it's gonna be me but we'll those
were the things like Homeland Security
all those initial fears I mean we
probably lost 50 million of investor
confidence based on some of those now
they've kind of lifted those provisions
but in the industry this is an emerging
opportunity the cannabis industry was
the gutter for so many years illicit so
then it didn't really bring the best
people and then the first people willing
to take these high-risk markets you know
that's like maybe not the most seasoned
normal triple-a type of investors so now
that we're seeing institutional capital
being interested we do have banks we do
have finance been internationally I'm
legal medical legal for the ancillary
side 1962 Single Convention on
psychotropic substances World Health
Organization doctrines we look at these
and tax treaties where we can do this
what countries based on standards can
actually do it they say not just a
Cyprus not just in Malta I don't do
things just for a press release to be
worth 50 million dollars more in a
market cap the next day we make online
i'm confused it sounds to me like you're
telling me that that canada is not only
violating standards that are established
in the 66 treaty etc but that there's a
complete disregard for something that
first of all are other countries doing
this differently because it seems to me
if you listen to the canadians the
germans are welcome welcoming them with
opening arms to help them build out
their fledgling cannabis
etc so when you think about
international Germany was a major there
were ten initial licenses issued from
the bee farm and it was literally the
smallest girl I'd had to model in I'm
almost ten years like 200 kilos of
annual production but that market of 83
million people that also taught us about
the bee farm how the government's paying
for cannabis in health care standard
like socialized medicine so as long as I
meet the high quality standard at the
lowest cost to production
I'm the generic in every pharmacy so
unless adopter rates bedre can read in
an API for recommending pharmaceutical
drugs which it's considered there i'm
the generic i'm the lowest price highest
quality i take the whole market so
canada thought they're gonna take over
the world
i'm from northern Wisconsin but Canada
is not where you do giant greenhouses to
grow pineapples for the world so
low-class places like Colombia for oil
production one standardized where these
other markets will be so much more
advantageous I mean it sounds like
though there's an argument an easy
argument I think I agree with you that I
don't know why the Canadians are
necessarily I'm taking over the world
well it's wider than their capital
markets and was to take the whorl of my
Canadian friends but the the
international diamond dynamics you're
talking about I think are interesting so
you know Bob I'd be how do you weigh in
here I mean obviously you've been
extremely cautious about building your
business state-by-state
not breaking federal law that's you know
compliance to me is taken as a given any
any company that's been served that
survived this long started you know with
compliance as the first thing that they
had so I mean does this concern you
I think the Canadians opened the door or
the Trudeau effect national federal
freedom but you know I think there's
only thirty four million people in
Canada I think the cannabis business in
California will probably make that small
I think that everybody is running
watching the US and as the biggest
consumer market in the world will
ultimately take our place in the leader
in innovation and science and I think
the what's happening in Germany is good
Spain Portugal I mean it's happening
everywhere and and initiative is it
being driven by money are we looking for
jurisdictions where we can go down and
get cheap labor and
is is capital the reason that cannabis
is making this emerging industry and I
think it strives it like everything else
but I think there's a bigger thing that
we try to do in merrimette is to care
about people
I mean care about building products and
interfacing with physician outreach
where we actually help people with with
it whether it's MS or anxiety or nausea
or PTSD and some of the things with
epilepsy in Rhode Island we run a clinic
with 48 families with mothers with
epileptic children to come to help see
their kids stop talk as shaking and I
think I saw you last week in Maryland
where we ran the Maryland medical
cannabis forum we had five of the
foremost doctors in the world talking
about using cannabis to take people off
of opiates and to create interface with
the with the physicians and the
pharmaceutical industry so it seems to
be happening all over the world we have
40,000 people here want to be to learn
but I think money drives something
regulation drives something and I think
it's all good ultimately hopefully we'll
have an emerging industry that's as
validated medical principles that that
is helping people and where people
aren't hiding in fret of afraid of the
federal US law there's a big difference
between a medical in the United States
and medical internationally like our
clinical trials research is so lacking
in the United States that when we're
looking for those drug placements or
drug discovery in these other markets
international markets that's where if
five companies are doing MS research and
that they're projected to take 10% of
the MS market by 2020 730 billion whew
and Israel whew and some other locations
but when you're getting early mover
positions on that let's say with a hedge
getting into all five when they're going
towards approvals doubling down on the
ones moving more towards approvals
having the shares to lend to short the
ones that won't get approvals that anti
fragile mentality but in cannabis like
pharmaceutical international is one
thing but everything in the United
States medical adult use will kind of
merge into one thing it's just medical
is that quasi legality and the federal
protection but anyone can disabled that
that's how I got into this but anyone
can take somebody with epilepsy prop up
these things to get more
it's legalized we know that or how
medical transitions to adult use very
different from a tax basis but even
medical is less safe in Colorado than
adult use based on testing standards so
when we're looking at these
international markets
you know Canada violating international
law of that convention for for
legalizing something for an adult use
purpose that's on these controlled
substance lists that could hurt so many
other sectors of markets of Canadian
pharmaceutical companies non cannabis
related from B be able to exports other
markets so when we see like this
velocity effect of how those things
happen the wise Canadian companies are
taking that liquidity investing
internationally into these other markets
sometimes for press release value other
times for revenue share of these new
markets but they're doing it in a way
that they they no capital they know how
to manipulate these public markets you
know tilray a few of those have done a
very good job with press releases even
though you look at the revenues to
earnings it's a little different but
they're actually buying a lot of these
toxic assets that when you buy the good
you're buying the bad where if you buy
this US extraction company that has fake
science and has lawsuits pending for all
these other issues you're buying all of
that with you so then like I won't push
those lawsuits until right before a sale
right before a listing right before an
offering and right now that's why
investors choosing individual deals or
individual stocks it's way too hard
you're not gonna choose the Unicorn but
like private funds that have exclusive
deal flow track record in cannabis and
capital that's where investors should be
looking for the longer-term impacts like
hundred ex VC funds p/e models like our
p/e models will come in and cannibalize
Canadian assets of like their
intellectual property and staff I'm
getting really confused and I feel like
I'm I feel like our conversation is
happening we're having four different
conversations at once which are all
incredibly important conversations so in
summary what I think we're talking about
first of all we're mixed brought up the
fact that not only is is Canada
operating internationally potentially in
an illegal fashion you believe they are
but that also this is then perpetuating
some of these Canadian companies to
around the world go out and consolidate
by the way good for them from a capital
markets perspective taking their stock
which is arguably an overpriced stock
and going out and buying companies in
the US or higher growth markets which
will be a creative
to their shareholders because they've
they've they arguably don't have a very
large markets we've talked about the
size of the Canadian market the
limitations of it and that possibly that
the Canadians aren't the right people to
be following around the globe if you're
an investor unless of course you think
that a company in Canada is buying a
very good asset in the US with an
overpriced currency the other thing
we're talking about though is the you
know the social good of what's going on
here and I think you know we're all here
for that I think a lot of people are
here for that and and as someone that
again you know the the the allegory to
to this in I could be in in Rio or Sao
Paulo in 2002 investing in Brazilian
resource companies at a time when
there'd be a room this full of people
also of us investors has said oh my god
we've got own commodities oh my god the
bricks and all these emerging market
companies oh and these Brazilian
companies are really trustworthy guys
and we're going to give all our money to
them we've seen this before and it
doesn't always go well but I I think the
conversation that everybody can agree
upon is that there is not only a social
good of what's going on here but that
there's a massive benefit and I think
Nick you even talked about how it sounds
to me like you think if the if the
Canadians just stuck to to to medical
and didn't go adult we would have stayed
away from they would have had less
exposure but then you always have to
have a Netscape to have a Google kind of
emerge so I love to learn from others
failures there's plenty of successes in
Canada and like I said as a disabled
veteran that's how I got into this and
push this but I also know that many of
the companies that are using that social
good component are either not doing it
as profitably or correctly as they
should be because they haven't had the
same standards so international G a PGM
PGA CP GDP all of the different
standards that in the u.s. at
state-by-state but all you had to do in
the US was just follow the federal
guidelines and standards and then you
would have always been compliant but
this is the first time I feel like in
the history of business and capitalism
that actually doing the right thing is
the most profitable and like I love
putting in door out of business giant
greenhouses like 22 pounds of coal to
make
one gram of indoor cannabis and you love
the earth and it's saving like people in
cancer but you destroy like killing your
grandchildren to feed your children
mentality but like large things that are
making super cash flow companies that
are better than a B Corp I'm all about
our investors but through revolutionary
profitable businesses but the right mark
at the right time in the right capital
for it that's the challenge where
institutional capital is not there but
even private will still do 18.8%
interest on real estate backed by real
estate but even that a hundred million
of that to make eighteen million over
five years as a waste of money I mean I
would have taken that hundred and made a
billion in five so it's like knowing
when where and how and how how investors
need to look at this in classes
ancillary medical adult use you have
different risk profiles for each
dichotomy of that most of them just see
the cannabis industry instead of
property management company brand
licensing companies all of the different
verticals profitable party business
what's the part you're most excited
about I mean you're you're straddling
the integration between first of all
adult and medical you're you're involved
in infrastructure build out your company
also helps other companies get to the
places they want to go because of your
presence so what are you most excited
about a lot of people think that if the
u.s. if the states had just stayed to
medical we might have gotten the federal
law passed a long time ago it's a good
point I'm most excited about branding
and distribution creating new lines of
products that cross state lines and puts
America back at the forefront of what it
does best I think we just made a we just
made right well it's the yeah well I
think I think the new farm bill
unleashing CBD from him is going to
create a whole new industry that will
get there will parallel track cannabis
till they integrate in five six years
we're excited about that opportunity
we're excited about more and more people
getting the benefit of feeling more
familiar I think we've made major head
roads and getting physicians to come out
from under the hospitals and take a more
vocal stance about
how this thing can really help people at
a fraction of the cost I love when we
help kids and I love when we help senior
citizens that are taking narcotics
because they're difficult when they
could have a bite of a cookie I watch a
movie and go to sleep and not bother
anybody so I think the industry is doing
instead of Netflix and chill that's what
we need to do I won't tell you what my
mother used to do it's alright yeah so
by the way I can't seem to get rid of
this guy because that we were together
on a panel a week ago and I do want to
bring up and I'm curious your view on
this it was a medical it was a medical
cannabis panel it was in conjunction
with the medical cannabis commission of
Maryland so we had regulators there and
we had three of the four most doctors
Juanes last PhD who are spending and
devoting their life to science and what
was so impressive about this event was
the not only you know the the social
kind of reverberation your your feeling
from the doctors who see the impact
they're having in the community but also
the other powerful thing was the
frustration that exists right now when
there's so much good that can be done
with medical cannabis and yet it's we're
still so far away from properly
educating the medical community
educating the dispensaries I mean let's
face it you know
I hope no one here I hope you guys don't
know I mean you know Bob you owned
dispensaries yes so how are you guys
well what's next next turn to talk but I
want you to help us understand how the
dispensaries are gonna try to better
educate and or to do what we hear from
the doctors is is overcoming an issue
where patients are going into facilities
and not coming away with either the the
prescribed product and and and and
medical cannabis that they came in there
for well that's the problem you use the
word prescribe so that means you're
talking about international markets
because in the United States it's doctor
recommendations because they're not able
to actually prescribe medical cannabis
medical is a term that we use in the
United States for one classification I
see it from the tax rate and the access
like what are the qualifying conditions
of that mark
it normally back in the day if it didn't
have pain or PTSD
we wouldn't investor go into it it's a
short squeeze market doctor education is
important but like in Germany doctors
when they go to make a prescription for
cannabis they're going onto a database
of an API network that has all of the
prescription drugs and it's there in the
United States we have those but cannabis
is not listed even though it's been a
part of our pharmacopoeia for 150 plus
years so medical cannabis in the United
States is very different than medical
cannabis internationally or
pharmaceutical FDA clinical trial like
efficacy BMI so we can never get those
confused doctor education is lacking but
I think a lot of them just realize if
the market allows it where it's this
could help potentially help my client
with X you know ailments
those like a California law Guam some of
those others the really restrictive
states and markets without doctor
education we have no patients patients
or clients clients revenue revenue
business it's not about bud tenders but
some states like Pennsylvania you had to
have medical doctors pharmacists like
having dealt with like controlled
substances in the past so each state's
different but most dispensaries you're
not tell the false claims this cures
this has been shown to like following
normal FDA guidance and having budtender
retail sales associate patient advocate
education so I like the good groups like
the great nonprofits like Americans for
safe access patient focused
certification like when they're actually
educating how to talk about medical
cannabis not falsely make medical claims
even though we know like how efficacious
is is you mean you think CBD side here
I mean ninety-five percent of those
products in the u.s. don't even have CBD
and it's like heroin based on legality
right now so you you know we've dealt
with hemp we've dealt with cannabis and
all the cannabinoids but it's just that
misinformation which has really hurt our
markets it's hurting investor confidence
it's why the right investors like
trusting those right sources just
because of public companies public
doesn't mean they're actually disclosing
everything about the market because many
of them don't even know where you're
seeing how they're operating and it's
just press release press release market
cap market cap versus revenue versus
long-term ownership and control those
quick returns to be made here but the
real investments into the long-term
multi trillion-dollar industry right
here coming we only have a few more
years to get all those really positions
otherwise
you're just gonna like be trading Apple
that's like hey apples got some room to
grow or like you want to shirt the Hong
Kong dollar with me everyone does that
this is now urgent and now the big
players are seeing it to get up those
mas
like one federal legalization happens
here big emanates internationally and
then like reverse IPOs and those true
bonafide IPOs go public when ready 95
plus percent of those companies have not
and it'll hurt investors some will make
a little bit now but not like the
Cargill's that we're creating privately
well it just seems to me look there was
obviously a run to market and there was
a again we've talked at some length of
why the capital markets we know why
they're necessary but but we we also
know why Canada fed a bit of an asset
bubble but it seems to me that this is a
market that's incredibly more
discriminating than it was a year ago
not only because people have gotten
smarter and realized there's a lot of
companies that that you know even you
know it's nice again I use my emerging
markets metaphor it's nice to talk about
the potential and the consumption growth
patterns that are going to change and
the demographics but the reality is at
some point a company needs to be worth
something that's relative to something
else
and it needs to be fair so we know why
people just gotten smarter also there's
just more things to invest in so before
you just had this this you know
effectively a proxy play where someone
would own you know one or two of the big
Canadian LPS we know who they are it
doesn't make them bad guys it just
doesn't mean that they were terribly
cheap or a good investment beyond the
first you know 50% move higher the other
dynamic that I think is as a capital
markets guy that's maybe the most
important one right now on a in terms of
the investor part of the conversation
we're having one of the six
conversations we're having in one
tonight is that you you you ultimately
have a I think a dynamic where a lot of
these companies will need more capital
in the future are going to have to go to
markets and actually prove proof of
concept and and you know Bob's been
doing this from day one and obviously
the capital markets have continued to
reward him that may be about to happen
in a market place where capitals not
free so I am talking about mister market
now and what
we've gone through in the last two
months of volatility for global markets
the the the real genesis of the cannabis
capital markets happened in a world
where capital was free and and
volatility was zero and and that's also
an under talked about dynamic for
investing today because I won't get into
a wonky conversation on global central
banks and investment dynamics and that
kind of one-on-one stuff this is a
cannabis show but it's critical to the
path for investments and the growth of
capital markets I mean Bob you get do
you get worried about the change in
capital markets environment from a
market perspective that we could have in
the first quarter of 2019 in other words
it could get really nasty out there the
Fed could overstep their bounds as they
do every time volatility if you follow
the VIX is at 25 right now in averaged
11 for the preceding 12 months or eleven
and a half so does that even enter your
your sphere of reference as you think
about your capital market strategy you
always cognizant of all those
sophisticated things and what happens in
other industry or historically in the
market I think cannabis has broken a lot
of the rules and I think two things are
happening one everybody in the states no
prohibition is coming and it's going to
end and when it comes the big companies
the pharmaceutical the alcohol are going
to come in and whoever had the courage
to make the investments whether on the
private side or even on the public side
are going to make out reward at big time
but I think the it still starts day to
day of earnings and revenue and helping
people and and I think it will sort its
way out the multiples in Canada there'll
be winners and losers I mean whoever
doesn't make their numbers next year
based on what they value today are gonna
have to answer to their stockholders in
the marketplace
merrimette we have consistent growth we
try not to get our head of ourselves
some people think we're value too high
compared to other realities and other
people this other company
that look just like us that are five
times more valuable than us so are they
to hire me to love
I think only time will tell and I think
the next 2019 is going to be a major
year for the cannabis industry kind of
like you said about volatile volatility
where there's some volatility now
there's opportunity but the other thing
about cannabis is we are recession proof
we literally grow money on trees and I
was like alcohol tabacco recessions I
mean we're in a Claddagh gory there
where it's not just the adult use like
side but from a medical standpoint ahem
standpoint everything that we're doing
the verticals are so much larger than
other markets that if you're in those
public markets you're exposed to that
volatility even of other unrelated
markets private companies that are cash
flowing themselves based on this much
more insulated from some of those
changes now I can't just do a press
release and have a hundred million
dollars the next day like that takes you
know maybe a quarter to raise at a time
like when private capital now but
whether there's these major volatile
markets and people are going in and
buying these toxic assets or creating
like new positive asset classes it's
that moment that where you know where to
put the capital when to hold when to
sell or now even with our hedge fund
strategy how to actually do market
regulation and profit from it from the
market volatility from the wrong players
who got into the wrong boat for how they
were going to raise their capital but
going public for like initial liquidity
for investors great I love that play but
right now all of the companies listing
reverse mergers splits off from the US
they're see easy access to capital but
they're exposed and they're all part of
that same part so when that sector goes
down you saw a couple weeks ago like
that 20% that was not a fun few days for
a lot of those public companies we
didn't feel any of that
and actually I had days there that new
Purchase Agreements happening based on
lower prices so vertical integration
owning the means of production like
seeing that hands on side the biotech
the drug discovery what these things
will be worth these are times that you
could never get these positions again so
even though it's volatile opportunities
are vast if you know where to put those
or if you've worked in this for a decade
go and make those individual investments
either stocks or private but if not I'm
not just pushing etf's here or certain
REITs or ancillary or hands-on but some
of the private funds now are great but
and even some of them look at a courage
then like by going public and then some
of these lawsuits that are happening
things were done early and just because
you have a great advisor and great
pedigree does not mean you know Capital
in cannabis you know one point that I've
failed to make is the the black market
of cannabis is is around us the 80 to
100 billion dollars that already exists
in the cannabis market but I'm in for
the shadows all the legal market is
doing is it's bringing that out of the
shadows and into reality and into taxes
and into health so I think it's a good
summary I think the industry is and a
good foothold and I think as all markets
do they all shake out to some sort of
reality yeah I think that's right and
and the the point that I would be hoping
to make is not to dispute that this is
gonna be a counter-cyclical high-growth
industry for a long time the nature of
the product the nature of the usage is
not necessarily attached to a boom bust
economy but and I would it's it's
impossible dispute to me as someone that
invests in public and private companies
that private companies are less volatile
on a day to day basis of course they are
there's nope there's no mark to market
by the way a lot of companies suddenly
become worthless overnight in a market
where capital markets fall apart and
businesses they're too starved for
capital so I would just simply say that
we all believe in what we're doing here
we all believe that this is a market
that's going to continue to attract
bright minds and deep pocketed investors
whether they be institutions whether
they be strategic partners whether they
be family offices the rich guys that
that that Bob's talking about that that
actually were brave guys coming out here
laying you know reaching into their wall
and investing in something that most
people said they were crazy on but we
I've seen it time and time again that
and if you've I kind of feel like I know
with when my dad used to talk to me
about my grandfather who lived through
the depression and and how he was
changed by that I mean look I I managed
money through the crisis I lost half my
financial wealth from the crisis anyone
who went through that says markets can
do almost anything and by the way for a
fledgling
industry that is capital starved okay as
much as there's money floating around
here everybody here needs money okay and
so if you cut off the spicket to that in
a shocked fashion all I'm saying is
first of all good healthy companies will
go out of business because they weren't
planned for that and investors will be
on the wrong side of investments with
great companies and great management
teams and wonder what happened so I
don't want to scare anybody I think
we're all cognizant of that but but it's
it's important to understand you know I
spoke out of the conference on the west
coast a few months ago when everything
was at its peak everything and I gave my
Japan in the 1980 speech and by the way
I'm not neural roubini man III think
he's doom and gloom and this and that so
I want to make this really clear sorry
Ariel but I mean really you know but I
do think that Japan is still getting
through the excesses of cash-rich
without a plan is not a way to invest
where they're building golf courses to
nowhere and I you know that is one of
the first things I I was thinking about
when I was given a you know a you know
whatever a keynote pitch so sorry for
being Timmy downer here but you know Bob
just sum up for me I don't know what
your expectations were for MJ biz 2018
but I mean it's been insane so you know
talk about that 2018 has been great more
people were deals more more education
were new systems more technology more
doctors and I think the the atmosphere
and the health of our industry is strong
so thankful for events like this not
just for like the business generation
but like you're seeing this movement and
really taking traction every one of
these people that comes to it is really
an advocate for us and then like through
education driving business it's great
but we need more foot soldiers out there
that are educated and that's what we've
lacked in the United States forever from
a business standpoint I mean the new
clients are great the new referral
partners the new vendors the new access
to different technologies is always
spectacular right I like walking around
thinking which companies I want to buy
which ones I want to short but from our
standpoint I think we had seven new
countries you know with engagements here
from a consulting standpoint you know
probably 50 plus million a prime
capital commitments based on meetings
that have happened here amazing what
these things do for the industry and
long term we're creating something that
pass on to future generation so we we
have to remember that like you said with
the responsibility of our companies to
our shareholders but also knowing
there's a lot of opportunity here a lot
of ways to make money a lot of ways to
lose money if you don't know how
diversifying that risk putting things
together like which cede to sales work
which ones don't choose one company it's
probably not going to be a unicorn but
like diversifying across the sector's a
lot more insulation when it's backed
with real estate assets intellectual
property a little bit more insulated
than the public market volatility you
got to be in both but public when ready
and established I think long term
they'll write about how this happened
compared to dot-com bubble and then
Luxembourg Exchange Tel Aviv exchange
but then you look at revenue on those
companies too or have a limitation on a
market not allowing export will change a
multi trillion-dollar industry
trajectory within a few years so without
without these events we would literally
be still in the basement so really
honored for MGB is what they do end up
for your companies and major news like
covering this we really appreciate it I
mean I think we're obviously not in the
basement here but the good news for
everybody here is we're barely on the
first floor I mean we're we're barely
we're building a foundation right here
[Music]