[Music]
hello hello hello everybody and welcome
to another episode of the Dank hour
We're super excited to have you with you
sorry about the the slow start
today it's it's been an interesting one
because uh we we've had to bounce around
a little bit so we're streaming this
from Zoom onto streamyard into YouTube
so it's like we're multiplatform but
we're only going one spot but anyways I
hope you're excited as as usual I'm
London your dictator of dialogue your
your master of moderation all around
weird guy that likes to talk to about
cannabis with some wacky weirdos um I
shouldn't call you all weirdo you're
fantastic human beings I really
shouldn't be saying that but we have an
amazing really star in the Cannabis
space that is that is written I don't
know how many papers this year Alone um
so and we're a bit behind schedule so
we're going to roll right into it and
get the conversation go and welcome to
uh welcome to the show do
Daniel is that was that what you prefer
to go by or would you prefer something
else so so my name is Daniel I'm a
distinguished professor of Neuroscience
uh in at the school the University of
California irine school of medicine I'm
a neuroscientist a pharmacologist I uh
have a PhD from Columbia University I
did my postdoctoral work at the roeller
University and worked basically on the
endoc canaban System since the early
1990s uh for about 10 15
years 100% of my activity was on the
endocab signaling system then as it
became clear that cannabis was becoming
more and more legalized in the state of
California happens in 96 the first time
and in 2016 the second time uh it became
clear to me that there was a topic that
had to be tackled and so my lab started
also working on on phyto canav know so
cannabi notes that are derived from the
cannabis plant um and I am the editor-in
chief of a journal called cannabis and
canabo research that whose mission is
really to to publish solid peer-reviewed
work in everything cannabis and
cannaboid we had a little bit of an
issue on our last episode where we had
some problems with recording and all the
other business and and whatnot and so on
so we we got cut off on the first
question unfortunately we missed Kyle's
very first awesome question but we did
uh kind of start the recording of the
video in Zoom uh with uh Dr Mark's
question um and and really was quite
phenomenal so we sorry we've missed that
part of the recording but we're going to
get right back into it right now and you
can watch it watch it all from there
it's a fantastic episode so don't miss
out on any of it and we'll see you all
next week on The Dan cower
Med entirely by CB1 cannabinoid
receptors maybe there is a small CB2
component but CB1 drives most of the
pharmacology and the CB1 receptor gets
involved because am44 which does not
bind to CB1 receptors stops the
degradation of an enamide an enamide
levels increase so now an enamide
activates CB1 receptors and produces
analgesia and of course if you block the
CB1 receptor you block the effect of am
for for because you block the effect of
an anine so that's the that's the
context uh so we published that it was a
science paper in 1997 where we
identified that the the animate
transporter and a few years later I
think was the group of bankat but I
don't
remember precisely made an interesting
observation that if they gave tanol
which actually the structure of Talen is
very simple is contained in the
structure of am404 if they gave Talen to
well no no no you have to remove the the
acetate there's an acetal group acetate
yes yeah once you remove the acetate
group then you're right you can it has
yes it I was simplifying things Mark
that's that's precisely right you're
precisely correct
so they found that it gets this this
portion of of of Talon gets
condensed with with arachidonic acid and
that is a reaction ction that almost
certainly is carried out by the enzyme
fatty acid amm hydas which can work in
Reverse so now you have this structure
which is actually am404 and the the
because has been known for actually
quite a few years at the least in animal
models if you block CB1 receptor stanol
effects decrease or disappear people
draw drew the conclusion which I think
is not unreasonable that in Vivo
whenever we take
tylenol at least part of it and tyon is
taken a fairly high doses so the the
brain levels are probably micromolar so
they're probably rather substantial so
the reaction is not impossible of course
no one is seen it in the human brain so
it's still speculative but it could
happen and it is seen in the rat and the
mouse brain so melan brains can carry
out their reaction and if the reaction
takes place yes it's entirely possible
the INF for participates in the effects
of Tylenol because another important
background is that Tylenol although is
categorized often erroneously as an nade
so a non-steroidal anti-inflammatory
drug actually is not in that it does not
really really very effectively block the
major Target of all an AES like aspirin
or omein which is
cyol probably and it's been for many
years a mystery so this has been is one
of the possible uh solution of this
mystery again we would need to know
there is a simple experiment to be done
in humans if one could do this
experiments or one one had the you know
the you know the all the approvals to do
or the funding to do such an experiment
it just to give Tylenol to someone to
people measure the analgesic effect and
with or without a canabo receptor
antagonist so if the effect is is is
abrogated by the canab receptor
antagonist then then you have your
answer no one has done these experiments
I don't think everyone will ever do it
but it's an interesting question it's an
interesting question well and we should
remind our our our viewers that the Cy
oxygenase pathway is one of the
penultimate um Pathways in the
arachadonic acid pathway right isn't
that
correct so so it it it shows how these
two sets of um Pathways if you will that
um uh making these um uh compounds that
have neurological activity as well as
anti an oxidant uh activity as well as
the prostaglandins which enjoy a variety
of different biological activities these
are not trivial molecules but they're
molecules that are have their origins in
the lipid themselves which I find just
absolutely fascinating again going back
toomy so do the endoc canabo it's both
an but they do in a different way and
that's what's fascinating about them and
after this I think we should move on to
other question questions but the
basically what we what we showed over
the years is that anite andg the two
main andoc cannabinoids are preformed
and they're present preformed in the
fat-like membrane that surrounds cells
the lipid membrane that surround cells
they're preformed they're not active
because they are not liberated they are
liberated upon demand so there is a
stimulus that comes by activates the
cell the cell releases the active
endocannabinoid with it you know with
the endocannabinoid structure so the
arconic acid the ethanolamine aric acid
and glycerol and then the compound
activates the canabo receptor and then
he's destroyed now this is very
different from the e conoids which you
mentioned like cylo lioo product because
they in the the case you release an
arconic acid and then arconic acid is
metabolized but the concept is the same
the cell is not just a membrane is not
just a protection but it's a source of
signaling molecules and it's actually
really what fascinated me 35 years ago
and I I still am fascinated by it you
know obviously I don't have a lot of
fantasy or better things to do but
that's that's what I that's what I work
on thank you really much enjoy your
literature and enjoy reading every paper
you've published thank you thank you
Mark that's very very kind of you I'm
just gonna jump into just real quick
before we have Tess go ahead I'm sorry
I'm on like the dark screen on this side
of the internet that doesn't want me
visible anymore uh but I did want to
throw out that you know we we have a
very passionate group of epic epic nerds
on our Channel and that like to follow
and do these things we we try and keep
it as high brow as possible so don't be
afraid if you want to go on a long
tangent about like you know whatever
we're we're we're here to listen we
always appreciate that um but anyways
I'm going to give the floor to Tess to
ask the next question thanks
again
I think that's a great uh segue London I
was about to comment on the level of
nerd Dum that was going on right now and
how much I was loving it so it's such a
pleasure to have you on Dr pelli I um am
a microbiologist by training but there
was a very uh couple years when I was a
um an undergrad and early grad student
where I worked in a neuroimmune
pharmacology lab and I was studying
neurogenesis and I thought it was
fascinating all of the things going on
in your brain all the different I always
thought of it as like a like a soap
opera of characters in your brain like
uh communicating with each other
sometimes liking each other sometimes
stabbing each other in the back and you
know and all the crazy networks of
signaling that goes on where there's
arrows and there's Arrows with a blunt
end and and all the crazy shenanigans
that goes on so like bringing it down a
couple nerd levels to just like what it
looks like when you're trying to
understand it from a Sy systematic point
of view and since you got started in you
know understanding and trying to study
lipid derive Messengers I was wondering
besides cannabis what's your favorite
lipid derived man or sorry endoc canabo
or other canabo related compounds
besides them because that's we talk
about that all the time um what are some
of your other favorite players
especially the lipids out there and why
oh that's a good question again you know
I was not expecting a nerd a nerd panel
being you know you know attacking me
from all from all angles I'm loving it
it's great it's more fun than I was
expecting so um my other favorite uh
lipid lipid derived molecules at this
point in my career are two actually and
we've been also working on them for
quite a while they are called the okay
I'm not going to say how they're called
right away I'm going to say first of all
they look like an
animite but they don't qu like an
animite and they don't walk like an
anide so they're not an endo they're not
endoc canabo but they have some basic
similarities with an anomid so an anite
is arachidonic acid which is this long
fatty acid with four double bonds or
unsaturations and one polar head made
made of ethanolamine so that's an anide
right and there is an bond between
ethanolamine and the fatty acid and
that's very very important the Amite
Bond okay these compounds are have the
same general structure so there is
ethanolamine there is an amine Bond but
instead of having arachidonic acid so a
very long chain fatty acid with multiple
unsaturations they have either no
unsaturation at all and 16 carbon atoms
that's called palmo ethanolamide or
paa and Olay um 18 carbon atoms of one
double bond OIC acid and that that's
called oan olamide or OA so OA and paa
are my second second best lipids I call
them we call them parac canabo and let
me explain why we call them parac canabo
para in Greek means
around and uh so these are compounds
that are around our main
endocannabinoids anandamide and 2 a
because they resemble there are many
things they do in common with bomide in
particular they have as I said similar
structure but most importantly they have
a similar set of membrane precursors not
not identical but similar they are
produced by the very same enzyme there
is an enzyme which by the way Mark
contains a zinc atom so is one of your
favorite molecules uh this zinc
containing enzymes called nape
phospholipase D or AP plld and releases
an enamide and releases also these other
guys now the the the key difference
however is functional because OA and
paa um do not bind or activate in any
shape or form canabo receptors neither
the CB1 nor the CB2 they activate a
different set of receptors in
particularly they are uh High Affinity
Agonist lians so high Affinity
activators of the So-Cal peroxisome it's
a mouthful peroxisome proliferator
activated receptor type Alpha P Alpha
for short P Alpha for short and P Alpha
is a nuclear receptor so this compounds
going to the cell buy to this nuclear
receptor the nuclear receptor moves to
the Moon nucleus does all sort of
interesting things oea we proved this
you know already 20 years ago and we've
been studying it it very systematically
over the last two decades oea is a very
important regulator of of feeding and
liquid metabolism by activating P Alpha
for example it curbs food intake very
markedly is a very effective anorexiant
as they say technically but also it
stimulates the consumption utilization
of energy throughout the body in in the
white OS tisue in the brown OS tisue in
the liver etc etc and it's just a
fascinating molecule just from from that
perspective um PA if if if anything is
possible is even more fascinating it
also works on people Alpha but in
different cells than OA does and Pa is
particularly important immune cells and
it's particularly important in
regulating inflammatory responses and
pain so H PA now in fact is in the
market after you know we we discovered
its receptor many years ago and we you
know we characterized it you know it's
now been sold throughout the world
mostly in Europe but also here in United
States as a supplement to a to reduce
mild forms of pain and it is actually
quite effective in that regard not very
effective because it's rapidly destroyed
by the body but it's rather rather
effective so to answer your question I
love these parac canabo because they
encapsulate a very important principle
that in nature just as you said before
things don't work they're never that
simple so an animite is produced and
these other guys are produced they work
work together sometimes synergistically
so they they add onto the activity of
each other sometimes antagonistically
for example PA and an enamide both
inhibit pain and they do so in a way
that if you add one an animite and one
PA you have five the effect of five
molecules not a two molecules so there's
a sort of synergistic effect right so
they work together on pain but an
animite know work opposite on food
intake because an animite stimulates
food intake OA inhibits it and because
these are my favorite lipids in the
whole wide world I could talk about them
for hours but even the Nerds that are
listening to us I see it's not very many
of them but so I assume they're really
the you know those who are interested I
I think would would start shooting
themselves in the in you know in the
temple so I I I think I rather stop
here that's awesome I love that you have
other
favorite um signaling molecules and it's
cool to that they can be so similar but
also so different and it doesn't take
that much of a little tweak of a
molecule to completely change how it
behaves and I think that that Segways
really well into a question that Evian
had I kind of feel like hi Dr h f so I
actually feel like you were answering
the question as uh as we're going I was
like wait a minute I think he's actually
answering my question because my
question was around the um the feeding
in the body weight uh part of some of
your research was really fascinating to
me and how that implies you know what
the therapeutic applications for some of
that more recent research with the the
paa uh that was kind of where I wanted
to go with it which sounds like
basically what you just answered I was
curious about the signaling and the
responses and also like what the
implications are for
therapeutic uh you know how we're going
to apply these cannabinoid kind of
research that you've been working
towards for therapeutic application I'm
really fascinated by that and then also
um you know I know you've done a lot of
work around the molecular um signaling
also so I just wanted to see if maybe
you could break it down for people in a
way that is uh maybe like doesn't have
to totally be layman's terms but you
know just bringing how that research is
going to impact people and I was was
also very curious like where it's headed
for you on the therapeutic um element
like what what's your goals or what are
you most excited about researching into
the future with these things so well
thank you those
are couple of different questions so let
me start with the first one um the issue
of food intake and Body Body Energy
regulation so that is actually really
really critical when um when we started
the 30 years ago working on on the endoc
canaban system the last thing the last
thing we would have imagined is that the
endoc canaban system is more important
outside the brain than it is inside the
brain and uh the reason why it's more
important outside the brain than inside
the brain is because it regulates energy
metabolism at every level from the
tongue
to the gut to the arpus organ to the
liver to the pancreas the entire
body has cannabinoid receptors
particularly CB1 cannabinoid receptors
that are linked somehow to something
that has to do with energy intake and
energy storage and the overarching logic
here is actually very very simple
regardless of how specifically they act
in different parts of the body CB1
cannabinoid receptors and the
endocannabinoids that activate them are
involved in keeping in getting as much
energy as possible from the environment
particularly fat energy because that's
the best energy that we can get and keep
it in our fat stores our adal stores as
much as possible and this is simply
because as I'm sure all of you know for
250,000 years we did not have uh
refrigerators and it was pretty hard for
us to find fat as you know we had to
hunt it and once we found it most of the
time animals are not fat most of the
times they lean because they you know
you know run around so you had we had to
break their bones and suck the marrow or
eat the brain this was the main way of
getting fat so really really hard and
the evolution of the endoc canab system
I believe is based on this on the idea
that just like insulin it helps us main
achieve as get as much fat as possible
from the environment and store it as
much as possible now now that you know
plenty has put us in a situation where
we have the opposite problem not finding
fat but getting rid of fat so that's
where canabo receptors also can become a
target from a therapeutic perspective a
molecular Target in that one by blocking
these receptors one could block all
these actions that I just told you so so
basically you would block reduce
appetite you can reduce the absorption
of lipids in the gut you would res you
would reduce the ability of fat to be
incorporated into adipose cells and so
on and so forth now and that was done
was tested not just in the animals but
actually was shown to be quite effective
in humans uh now quite a few years ago
2003 2004
so 20 years ago or
so um the only problem the only problem
the small detail that the pharmaceutical
company that developed these agents are
called canabo receptor antagonist so
they block CB1 receptors quite
selectively and they have exactly the
opposite effect of what endocannabinoid
would have so they will block appetite
blah blah blah whatever I told it in in
Reverse whatever I said in Reverse okay
so these are very effective in humans
and in fact there were clinical trials
showing that one of them called remona
band that was developed by a company
called sopi and remona band uh really
worked for obese people the only small
problem as I said was that they did not
consider the pharmaceutical company
developed did not consider that the main
uh effect of the endoc canaban system in
the brain as we by the way had
discovered in those very same
years in 2001 to 2003 and the five is to
regulate mood so and to improve mood and
that's the other thing that the
cannabinoids do they they make her life
a little bit better
um and what happens if you block the
canab receptor in the bra in the brain
you can imagine now your life becomes
sensibly less good so now you develop
anxiety you develop depression you
develop even suicidal ideation and so
this all set of those dependent side
effects of the
cannabinoid the CB1 receptor antagonist
remona band emerged pretty quickly and
the Food and Drug Administration of the
United States never gave um the
authorization to use remona band in
patients um in Europe it was briefly
briefly approved but then withdrawn when
they saw the same s effects that have
been seen in in in the clinical trials
in the United States in the clinical
trials in the United States so now what
there people are doing um and this is
something that initially had hard time
in gain interaction but now has become
rather increasingly more popular they're
developing a CB1 CB1 receptor antagonist
that don't enter the CNS say they don't
enter the brain why why is that useful
well because the anxiety effect the pro
anxiety Pro depression effect occurs in
the central nervous system system but
the as I said before the effects on on
metabolism occur outside the central
nervous system and so you can take
advantage of this just by developing
agents that fail to cross the so-call
bloodb brain barrier which is this big
wall that you know prevents the entrance
of many substances from the circulation
into the into the brain parena and you
just you know if you play chemical
tricks and I'm sure mark would would
know about them if you play chemical
tricks you can prevent that from
happening it's a lot harder to do than
it is to say but it can be done and it
has been done and now there are some of
this peripherally restricted as they
said they're called canabo receptor
antagonist which um seem very very
promising in animals they seem to be
very very promising and they believe the
clinical trials are either ongoing or
about to start so that's one possible
therapeutic application of of using now
negatively using B blocking the canabo
receptor I personally think that there
is a lot more I mean not a lot more but
certainly a lot of a lot of value and
promise also in activating the canabo
receptor in ways that are that are
therapeutically relevant the simplest
way is of course by using
cannabis cannabis contains THC THC
mimics the endocannabinoids in many ways
and produces many any of the effects of
the endocannabinoids the problem in
using cannabis as we all know is that
you know it's very difficult to separate
one effect from the other because you
know once you have THC in circulation
you have THC in circulation it gets to
the brain and every you know basically
every canabo receptor in the brain is
activated right pretty pretty much so um
depending on the dose then you can have
I don't know a relatively mild effect
which could be for example analgesic in
some cas cases but it's very hard now
not to not not to impinge upon the next
effect which is now you know maybe a
little bit of sedation maybe a little
bit of euphoria giddiness and stuff like
that so it's hard to separate the
therapeutic effect which could be I
don't know analgesic or appetite
stimulating from a more uh a more into
intoxicating action which some people
just don't want you know if you of
course if you use cannabis for
nonmedical purposes you are seeking the
intoxication and if it's done you know
properly it's a very safe way of of
getting out of our own of our our
thoughts and and and and relax a little
bit so that's a separate problem
medically if you need to go to work and
you know you just want to you know
stimulate your appetite or block your or
block a pain or have an allistic effect
it's harder to separate the you know
this is called the therapeutic window by
the way and and the therapeutic window
of THC of cannabis is really not very
not very uh not very large so there is a
very small separation between the
effects you want from an effect you may
not want okay so that's that's the main
problem we have with activating the
canabo system the endocab system
directly so I have spent you know
literally 20 years trying to activate it
indirectly and by by that what I mean is
that we have the
endocannabinoids we have enzymes that
destroy the endoc avoids or you know
protean systems like the transporter I
mentioned before they destroy the
endocannabinoids so if we block these
enzymes or we block these you know
protein systems what what happens well
the endocab levels will rise right so
and if they rise because you stop the
degradation if they rise they will
activate canabo receptors so you could
say well well then you know you it's the
same effect as given THC no it isn't and
the reason why it is not is that endoc
canabo let's not forget are not are
produced upon demand so they're not
normally there all the time they're
there when we need them when they are
needed and and where and when they are
needed so let's say in a particular area
of the brain there is a need for the
production of an animite an anite
production increases and at that point
if on board we have a drug a chemical
that blocks the degradation of an anite
in that specific region at that specific
spefic time there will be an increase in
an emite not elsewhere just in that
specific region and that increase in an
emite will presumably also be limited
just because there is only so much an
endite the body can produce right
whereas you know there is an unlimited
amount of THC one can take so in fact
this concept is not theoretical anymore
it's been demonstrated in in thousands
of animal studies since we launched the
idea uh with the first inhibitor of the
intracellular degradation of an anite
was published in
2002 uh since then we showed that you
know an anide blocking an anide
degradation is anxiolytic produces
reduces
anxiety and and that's one reason why
blocking canabo receptor causes anxiety
because you know an anide typically is a
kind of a body owned anxiolytic or
anti-anxiety
molecule right uh and so F Inhibitors
this this is the enzyme that Cleaves an
an is called fa faah fan and hydes and F
Inhibitors now 20 years after this
discovery 20 plus years after the
discovery are being tested in the clinic
for the treatment of social anxiety
which is something that of course you
know I'm following very closely it makes
me very very proud because they would be
uh after 20 years working on this a very
nice indication of our work um you know
if it doesn't work it doesn't work as
but our job is at least to give it a
try so I I could go on you know honestly
uh if Yan I could go on uh on on on the
topic of therapeutic applications for a
while I just don't want to digress too
much and so maybe we could go back to
the questions I appreciate I will just
say I really appreciate your answer
because I and it did every time you go
it gives me like five more questions so
I know that there's a bunch of other
questions in there but I
I'm curious about the like a couple
things later just to put in the mind is
that I'm curious about the implications
you mentioned also with the other
cannaboid like thcv kept coming up in my
mind when you were speaking about that
and then also the um I feel like there's
something uh well I'll pass it on but I
feel like there's a couple things like
the inflammatory piece you did drop a
couple things about the inflammatory
potential so I'm also curious about that
but I'm just going to put it out there
and pass it on to I think Damon is next
or now lon's here if you wna no Damon's
up next perfect thank you Dr pelli um no
we're gonna talk more about therapeutic
cannabis this is an amazing
conversation uh so originally I wanted
to ask like why does cannabis work for
chronic pain management and uh you had a
really good discussion with Dr scalon
there and you touched on that um I like
what you said about the therapeutic
window of cannabis um that's something
that patients always have to keep in
mind what how would you ensure or like
what would you suggest that a medical
patient could do to stay within that
therapeutic window and what would you
suggest for dosage safety yeah so that's
a that's another very very very good
question so when it comes to canabus and
pain I am extremely frustrated but and
the reason for that is that uh um there
is uh what is called substantial
evidence that cannabis is effect and
cannabinoids are effective in
alleviating pain in adults substantial
evidence unfortunately is not conclusive
evidence all right and for this reason
um the medical
profession are very recalcitrant very
hesitant to recommend uh to recommend
cannabis although they they do more and
more un fortunately what they do um
because they don't understand the system
very well is that they will suggest that
people start with CBD as if CBD was the
dumb cousin of THC CBD and THC are
completely different molecules me not
completely different chemically but
they're functionally completely
different and they do very very
different things so unfortunately we
have a very very long uh route before
before we we educate the medical
profession on this but back to to your
your
question given the fact that uh
Physicians especially in the United
States do not understand the problem a
lot of patients uh ask around go online
ask me you know they send me emails Etc
and that it puts me always in a very
difficult position the reason for that
is because if we had one cannabis I go
into a store and say give me give me
cannabis and they give you cannabis that
would be Rel easy to answer
unfortunately the choice that consumers
have these days especially in states
where I mean in states where it's legal
obviously is is gigantic and there are
so many small differences you know
they're not big differences at the end
of the day you go into a a dispensary
and you look around it's pretty much all
kush but it's still it's still you know
there are still different varieties and
different levels of potency Etc so what
do I recommend I have to recommend you
know I mean I can recommend easily to a
nerd but it's difficult to recommend to
a person lay person who does not know
about this so I say look start a five
milligram THC I wish that you know they
could go into a store pull out a little
thing like this and say oh 5 milligram
of THC is this much unfortunately as you
well know doesn't work that way it's not
that simple but anyway start a five
milligram THC if you are a
Man start at 2.5 if you're a woman
and the reason for that is that women uh
tend to respond more uh profoundly to
cannabis mostly I I think because they
metabolize it more quickly to something
else called 11 hydroxy THC which is even
more poent than THC is so 2.5 as a woman
five milligram as a man and and by that
I mean of course a man you know between
say 70 and 90 kilograms of weight if you
have an obese person is different if you
have a child I do not recommend using
cannabis period that's a different story
maybe for for a separate question so now
we are between 2.5 and five and you do
that for a couple of weeks you cannot do
it just for a day you and by the way you
don't need to have a high it does not
necess you don't necessarily need to be
to feel the high you will feel certainly
something if you're completely naive you
feel imulation but not it's not going to
be a real intoxication in a normal
person and uh but if you don't feel any
s sign any relief from pain I would go I
would increase the dose maybe to 10
milligram and five milligram five in a
woman 10 in a man and or maybe 7.5
depending on how risk averse you one is
the risk there again is to uh is to be
unable to drive a car for example being
you know having having you know an
intoxicating intoxication intoxicating
response and being unable to drive a
operate Machinery drive a car but you
could also offset that by using it at
night and that depends again on your
pain condition and a lot of people
especially people in my age group who
now start using cannabis because they
have pains and aches and don't sleep
well they use it at night that's the
ideal scenario it's an ideal scenar
scario because if you if you dose if you
take a relatively low dose of cannabis
at night 5 10 milligrams 15 milligram 20
milligram tops 10 milligram 20 milligram
tops then you are very unlikely to have
any side effects and you will wake up in
the morning with very little hangover if
any the only thing that will undoubtedly
happen is that your REM sleep so the
Sleep associated with with with dreams
will be pushed toward the end of the
night so you will wake up remember every
single dream you made but aside from
that you know you may make up a little
hungry maybe but not necessarily so
that's my suggestion if you can use it
at night use it a fairly low doses
tiated yourself don't you know and often
if you ask the the Physicians they won't
know what to say in some cases actually
and this is scandalous in my opinion but
I've heard of situations where the where
Physicians have been ordered by their
bosses not to advise on cannabis because
they you know some some people are just
so paranoid about
it in some fields of
medicine thank you very much Dr pelly um
that's a wonderful response I Now
understand why I remember all of my
dreams absolutely like I'm anecdotal
evidence to that one so London who you
got up next Kyle I I got I get to ask my
question because I I mean other than
your intro which I'm gonna have to like
steal from you quick again at the end of
the show but one thing I I really want
to dig into and and well actually it's
it's it's really a little bit more open
question that I mean you're really if
you look at we have a shared document
that we put up of of links to all the
papers that you've released over over
the years and then I mean just in 2023
alone I don't know how many there were
there I think there were seven or eight
papers um that were released that you
know are coming forward what is
something that maybe not is common
knowledge I mean of course we have a lot
of people that are very invested in
cannabis that people don't know or that
every person should know about cannabis
that isn't being spoken about right now
what's something that um you know the
average person on in the world should
know about cannabis that isn't that
isn't common knowledge at this point in
time well
uh I I I I feel that there are so many
things that uh as you said the LA person
who is not an expert in cannbis will not
know and the main problem is that we're
are facing just a barrage of this
information and misinformation that
comes from uh you know from the from the
media and um and that disinformation
comes into two basic buckets one is
those who love cannabis and think is you
know the best things in slic bread and
those who hate cannabis and they think
is it's going to kill you if you even
sniff it and so unfortunately this is we
are Lally between a rock and a hard
place and both position are obviously
wrong uh but um and you know one picks
you know people pick one or the other
maybe based on political inclinations or
personal experience what not but not
really Based on data so what I if there
was one thing about Canabis that I I
would tell sort of the average person
who you know
doesn't know much about it is don't be
afraid of it as long as you're not a
teenager if you are a
teenager um and you really want to test
you really want to try it fine but just
don't do it that often do it maybe once
a week don't make sure you don't do it
daily but if you are an adult don't be
too afraid of it don't think it's going
to kill you because it's not going to
kill you uh but on the other hand
consider that there is a finite chance
in that you could become um it could
become habitual that you could just want
to do it regardless of what you know you
know you rather stay home excuse me and
smoke pop than say go to the the movies
with your
girlfriend excuse
me so and um sorry my my throat is
giving
me a little bit of a problem
I don't know something in the
air anyway so I guess what I'm trying to
say
is don't uh don't be paranoid about
cannabis a lot of people are
and and that's wrong but don't be too
laical about it either fit it with
respect that it deserves if it's
something you want to add to your life
just be careful with it and if you're if
you have kids and they're they want to
experience with
it direct them to an experimentation
that is free of harm so small you know
in a in a controlled
environment and most importantly not too
frequent because we are discovering
about long-term effects of cannabis that
are very very very
surprising let me give you an
example
people get really freaked out about
cannabis and schizophrenia right
I think that that's overblown I think
that is completely overblown I think
that is uh yes there is evidence of an
increased risk with heavy Canabis use in
in adolescence but I think by and large
that evidence
is difficult to interpret but for
example use of cannabis during
adolescent will likely
cause permanent changes in your ad organ
you know your your ability to store fat
in Aros tissue white and
brown will probably change for life if
you use regularly during adolescence and
we have evidence from animal studies but
also evidence from Human large number of
human studies so that could be something
you want to think about because before
you enter you adopt a behavior that you
know for a fact is going to change you
forever and
without with consequences that are not
clear and cannot be fully be predicted a
priority I think one should be really
careful and I think that's the way I
would talk to my daughter I mean I my
daughter asked me about it and that's
what I told her look look sweetie this
is what it is if you really have to do
it because your friends are pushing you
because you're curious just try not to
do it frequently do it every once a week
or something like that and and and don't
exaggerate it's just a just a basic rule
so this is what I would tell people
would not be like something very very
technal would just be a way of assuaging
fears but also at the same time of not
making look like okay cannabis just a
glass of water you drink a glass of
water you get you can smoke a a whole
joint especially these days at 24% 25%
30% THC the whole joint is a lot of THC
so I would be I would be careful there
awesome well I think there's I I I've
always kind of landed in the middle spot
I like to think myself is although I've
been a very passionate cannabis advocate
for me it's always there's no matter
what there's danger to everything like
you know like 150 people die a year in
the states alone from Tylenol right
everything has its risk and everything
has its safety so and we're still
learning so much and I think you know as
a parent as well I look at my kids and
go I look at my kids and go you know if
if what what my parents said to me was
this terrible you're going to make
yourself stupid and all that and when I
spoke I'm like oh well this isn't true
where now I can have a more realistic
Viewpoint of going to my children and
going hey well you know like if you're
going to do it which I'm probably not
going to stop be able to stop you
because you're my kids um at least like
you can do it in moderation this is why
you should and I think it's a really
important and valuable insight to have I
want to give give the floor for one more
question from from Kyle as I we we got
his question cut off earlier um and then
if I can just get you a little bit of an
intro just after that so before we run
and finish off the show I want to be
respectful for your time we said we
would be till about I believe 6:30 PST
so I don't don't want to take too much
of your time I'm sure you have a dinner
to get to go
ahead so so now that we've got the
explanation of the pericin avonoids uh I
have some questions about pae and OA as
a as a supplement so I've and this
question comes from uh Jason I guess
inspired by Jason Wilson who uh I
believe you've been on his show before
um as well curious about cannabis but
essentially he uses cannabis for his
chronic pain and he has told me that
when he uses pea as a supplement as an
adjunct his his pain score goes way down
like markedly and it's it's very
noticeable um and so given what you know
about PA and oea and its functions is
that something that people you know
people can be doing regularly is that
something that people should be
concerned learned about uh I know You'
mentioned it targets uh par Alpha so is
there such a thing as the potential for
par Alpha down regulation with overuse
is there is there any potential
downsides that you see to using these
things as adjunct either for pain and
inflammation or in the case of oea for
something like weight loss and
dieting well that that's very very very
thoughtful question so first of all your
friend the person who uses THC cannabis
THC containing cannabis and then when
they add PA they find this much more
pronounced effect uh this is an anecdote
of course but actually fits extremely
well with a very very important body of
preclinical data data in animals showing
that co-activation of the CB1 canabo
receptors by an endide or by THC and the
P Offa receptor by paa co-activation of
these two receptors is synergistic which
means that if one one produces two and
the other produces two in isolation when
you put it together you actually have
more like 20 and this is something that
is very very very striking in animal in
animal models the reason for that is
because um it's quite interesting P
Alpha and CB1 each
independently is capable of reducing
pain but through different mechanisms so
when you add the two of them together
the two mechanisms don't overlap so
because they don't overlap you they
don't block one another and but in fact
they potential they potentiate one
another so the the end result is I said
is is sort of what we call formally a
synergism a pharmacological
synergism uh this said pa alone is used
and is sold in you know in Europe and in
the United States uh in Europe is
actually prescribed and found in
pharmacies in the United States is
mostly on Amazon or or we sites like
that and paa alone has some analgesic
effect it's a it's a very safe compound
uh it's considered Gras or grass
generally recognized as
safe uh I don't know if any even even
squeezing my brain I can't remember of
any single you know negative effect with
PA that one should be concerned
about but of course we're all different
right and so if one person decides to
use PA for their pain for example
moderate pain I wouldn't use it for
anything too serious because for
instance I'll explain in a minute if you
if they decide to use it just monitor
yourself just like with THC not like
with everything else monitor yourself
you know don't let yourself in you know
do an experiment on yourself you know
you tried for a week for two weeks if
something strange happens for example
you get a pain somewhere that you don't
that is new to you stop wait and if the
the new pain disappears likely it was
caused by paa but some weird reaction to
PA we all are weird you know in a sense
we all are different animals right we're
not mice or rats we're not congenic so
we need to we need to be cognizant of
that so that's for PA I think you
mentioned oea as well oea it's
interesting is um a little bit more
complicated than PA is is not quite as
clearly as safe OA is is probably quite
safe but um we don't have as much data
on OA as we do on paa and Pa the main
the effect of PA if you take it by mouth
the main effect is actually to reduce
food intake so it will reduce your
appetite will use your hunger and it
does so in a weird way it does so in an
interesting way it does not really make
you eat less in a meal but it prolongs
the time between one meal and the next
meal so I you know even if you have a
relatively small meal now you're not
going to be hungry two hours later you
would probably be H hungry four hours
later if you had a nice dose of oea this
has been shown in animal models but also
in humans actually OA is quite effective
as an anti-obesity drug has been shown
in clinical trials as an anti-obesity
agent it's not a drug it's a natural
component natural
compound uh it's a for OA and Pa the
same rule applies they are natural
compounds and that is their that there
is their their strong their for their
strength but also their weakness what is
their strength the strength is that
because they are natural our body uh so
they recognize the receptors they do
their thing and then our body disposes
of them very quickly okay and that is
important because if you overactivate
the P Alpha receptor as you pointed out
you can risk to downregulate the
receptor in fact you have all sort of
effects not just the receptor down
regulation all sort of nasty things you
don't want to happen these are very
delicate receptor systems right but
instead you give OA pea you know they're
destroyed they activate the receptor
they go away they're destroyed no no no
no no no harm no
foul this is a strength but it's also a
weakness because of course you know if
you want for example oea to go to a
specific tissue I don't know the brain
good luck with that because you know it
has to go through the intestinal mucose
and through the intestinal mucosa where
fats are absorbed then he has to pass
the liver where oea finds an enzyme that
destroys the whole role of that enzyme
is to destroy OA and paa it's called fa
again it's very abundant in the liver
it's the same enzyme and so by the time
you know you the blood exit the liver to
go toward the brain the cerebral
circulation oea is virtually old gone
there is only the OA that is produced by
the body so is is not a very good drug
neither OA nor PA are good drugs because
of this reason uh but the little the few
things that they do they do well and
they're safe the approach that I have
taken as a lab is again as I did for the
endocannabinoids to try and block the
degradation particularly of paa and
there is one enzyme that is not far is
called NLEA n it destroy PA and that
enzyme is amazing is one is right now is
my favorite enzyme right now I mean I I
go by by years and so for for this year
next year it's probably going to be my
favorite enzyme and we develop
inhibitors for these enzyme with call
colleagues in Italy who are medicinal
chemists we develop inhibitors for this
enzyme and these Inhibitors are killer
analgesics they're just so good at
blocking pain in animals and they're
also very good anti-inflammatory
agents so my hope is that um yes it's
good to use oea and Pa mostly PA OA we
don't have as much data in terms of
safety and some efficacy But ultimately
what we want to do is to really use
utilize make use of this system of this
endogenous signaling system to achieve
more efficacy for serious disorders like
you know arthritis or chronic
neuropathic pain Etc that was
beautifully answered and the Tak homes
that I got from that at least um are
right pharmacological interventions and
ways that we're trying to approach this
Maybe by working on some of these
enzymes or other things might be a good
way but in terms of product formulators
this is really great news like like you
were saying the THC and Pa completely
hitting different angles and kind of
synergizing so it sounds like a lot of
product formulators may want to consider
using paracin abono a bit more in their
formulations what I got I hope I hope
something there hope activity will
develop in in that direction the FDA the
Food and Drug Administration does not
like combining things they get all
freaked out when you combine things and
you know and you know they care about
well they seem to care about safety
sometimes they do sometimes they don't
depends on who on the situation but
let's not go there it's politics
is you know it it's fascinating to a
chemist like me that a single double
bond that's in the middle of that fatty
chain has anything to do with anything
you know right I mean it's like
right so it's uncanny not it's uncanny
it is
uncanny the the the the polyunsaturate
analoges like L linolenic and linolic do
those ethanolamides
have CB1 they do primarily CB1 as you
start adding double bonds it goes toward
the CB1 if you remove the double bonds
as you remove them it goes towards the
peer
Alpha and ER and uh in know people have
done including on my lab we have done
you know structureal activity
relationship studies showing exactly
that and so and from an evolutionary
perspective I think it's interesting
because canab receptors are relatively
new in evolution they're not present in
insects they're probably present in
cordada but they they're not present in
bacteria or unicellular organisms but or
implants but the these implants for
example have something similar to PA
right that is also a signal in molecule
I think that in order
to the during Evolution the addition of
double bonds help uh sort of diversify
this General class of molecules of fatty
acid ethanolamides that had all sort of
signaling functions already Diversified
them in a specific direction away from P
Alpha toward GPR cap receptors like P
CB1 and
CB2
I mean it's total speculation but I I
mean and no one will ever know but you
know it's it's a nice just so story I
like to tell that to myself at
night by the way here is a suggestion to
your viewers if you you mention my
papers before than you so much for that
if you have problems with cannabis and
still want to sleep read my papers that
way you'll your right to sleep no
problem and no risk of
intoxication that's awesome you
mentioned Italy and you know I didn't
know if i' I've mentioned it before but
I actually I'm I get to go back to
Florence on the on the 23rd to go visit
my family and I I'm currently living in
Croatia so it's like 2 am here or 3:30
at this point in time so but uh I have a
friend sativa Creations is his brand but
he Mel Moda maaari always M pronounce
his last name but he works with some of
the uh Italian Italian experts in the
area so I bet you there's maybe one or
two apart here so do you get over to
Italy very often or are you you want a
here I was there um I mean not during
covid I went there because my mother
passed away and I had some business to
do there but um then I I missed a year I
was there in in October
actually to for work mainly but I did
stop in my hometown to to see my my old
friends but Croatia is a beautiful
beautiful country you are very well set
I I'm very lucky you know it's no it's
no Italy you know don't tell the
Croatian that because they'll kill me
and they're all 18 feet tall so you know
I'm just this little like half Italian
guy so they're they're all a lot bigger
than me um but I I have the the South
like my my family is from the south and
and we have a farm down there and it's
just just something about it you know
between the cheese and the bread and the
people it's it's magical to me so we're
we're actually I'm getting my C
citizenship and moving there full-time
and by should be by Summer we we all
have my passport but I wanted to just do
one last thing and ask you how can we
support what's going on with you with
all the research you're doing where can
we check out more where can our our our
I mean we we will of course share the
link in our description of of where we
found the grouping of your papers but
where else can can people find out more
and and get more involved if they would
like
to but you know I I don't do a lot of
social media
and that's a that's a weakness but you
know my my journal does cannabis and
canab research has you know some social
media
activity if your viewers are interested
in uh in exploring and understanding and
mostly if they're interesting interested
in solid information about cannabis and
a cannabinoids really cannabis and
cannabinoid research is a good is a good
source of information uh is very
scholarly of course very technical but
at least everything is double double
checked is vetted through the peer
review system and we also as a journal
try to uh to explore everything Canabis
so we go from the plant uh we publish
papers in mody for example all the way
to the clinic and to not just that we
even go into the into policy so and we
have editors for policy editors for boty
editors for this and that so it's a
place where I think um
people will be able to find Reliable
information there are unfortunately a
bunch of sites out there to make money
that and we don't make money at least I
don't make money out of that I don't
know someone must you know good for them
but I don't uh NE do any of the of the
editors and whatnot but the um there are
uh sites out there like this American
Journal of endoc canaby as if it was
even a discipline that I really I really
just to you know just to sell stuff and
I I I think people should be very aware
about that because of course you know
the in the case incentives are different
and uh while everyone has got incentives
incentive to sell is probably the
strongest incentive to fool people and
so I would be very careful in into using
you
know those quote unquote journals is a
source of of reliable
information
[Music]
know keeping with
the