many of these guys have already heard my
rant about the use of an Oxford comma in
the regulations which is in the
regulations it says cannabis
concentrates you know suppositories
capsules whatever vape cartridges comma
inhalable products a parenthetical
shattered a blacks and when they put it
in that second part in the regs they
didn't put three cartridges comma
inhalable products shattered a blacks
they just put inhalable products
shattered a blacks and so the argument
happening now is that might be what you
mean but Department of Public Health
that is not what you said and we're
trying so hard to read and understand in
the English language in the use of
commas and all of these things I guess
so Julie's get the comma woman and I
love it because I use that argument in
our letter and then my argument is that
there is a difference between a product
and a container of that product I cannot
use the oil that is in the pen without
the vape cart I cannot and the BCC tells
me I cannot bulk oil test the oil before
it goes in to the vape cart I must test
what the final form of the product so
unless the product is bulk oil and then
the container is the vape pen cart which
is not at all the way that it is set up
in the regulations then there is no way
that that vape pen cart is deemed to be
a container and if I'm gonna get out my
crystal ball I'm just gonna tell you
guys yeah that's where it's going yes
we're gonna have to put universal
symbols on cartridges I have no doubt
they're gonna bring back the little
stamp maker is gonna lobby to put the
stamps back on the edibles so you know
the difference between a cannabis
chocolate and another chocolate we're
gonna go all the way down the rabbit
hole because especially since if people
in Laguna Beach are getting Cu pees to
open a CBD store and they're gonna sell
vapes guess what your law enforcement is
gonna want to know on visual perception
is that a CBD vapor is that a THC vape
because now we're starting to fork into
CBD good ta
she bad this is what's happening