the event's been good
i think this is my favorite secret cup
that we've done out of all of them
secret cup it's one of those special
events you know it's a secret you really
can't
can't tell people too much about it you
know just can't say none
this has been a dream of mine to be able
to do these events it's super super
great to be able to
dream up something like this and then
sit back and and see it
come to fruition
like it has
all right smile i'm taking videos
[Applause]
it was taking some scary ass risks it
really was but the reward was great
because it felt like we carved out a
little piece of the world and made it
exactly how we wanted to
for a little while
[Music]
you put the flower in the grinder and
you crank it in bed with mary you can
find her in my blanket you got fire i'm
a blazer call it rise to the occasion
fat shatter patties butter drying in the
base and i don't need no provocation to
smoke my occupation's the toe even
though it's also making me broke come on
barack obama gotta lend some change with
a stroke of a pen quit persecuting all
of those you're supposed to defend how
to be taking talks of the sourdy hourly
gone like a falcon on the balcony i'm
dripping when i'm out of weed i need a
buddha sack that pre-98 bubba headband
the super jack rolling never get far
opening the fresh jar little skywalker
choking on the death star spoiled
bragger email coil rapper royal shadow
rapper spitting hotter than my oil
[Music]
the seeker cup is a cannabis judging
contest that puts the voting power in
the hands of the people who know
cannabis best the growers and
concentrate makers themselves
[Music]
most people already know that cannabis
grows from a seed but the part of the
plant we use for medicine comes
primarily from the oil in the trichomes
which are formed on the outside of the
flowers and leaves hashish is simply oil
extracted from the flowers and leaves
trichomes can be separated many ways the
oldest is to use a sifting technique to
separate the resin heads and make what
is commonly called keith one of the most
popular extraction techniques is to use
low heat and pressure to simply squish
the oil out of the buds keep or water
hash and make rosin
water hash is made using a system of
bags filled with ice water and cannabis
the contents are carefully stirred to
separate out the plant material from the
trichomes
once properly dried and cured water hash
results in a quality product
hash oils have become one of the most
desired cannabis extracts to true
connoisseurs
usually made with common solvents and
involves a closed-looped extraction
process
often called oil shatter wax or butter
these products have proven both the
safety and effectivity of cannabis as a
universal medicine
while the recipe is simple the results
are amazing
the secret cup is the only competition
where the extract makers are the judges
coming together as a community and
sharing techniques with their peers to
advance their craft before ultimately
deciding whose entry is the
international champion i guess for me
the secret cup is many things
it has become a way that i get to
celebrate with my friends and so we have
a family
yeah so i started making hash um
i'm actually a grower been in the
industry for
since solidly 1998.
[Music]
i get like a lime taste
it's good but it's just kind of low in
taste i got this inspiration by coming
to the cup to the secret cup in 2012 and
i took last place man and it
it uh burned inside of me like no other
and i met i was around a bunch of guys
that were from my area
that were probably like the best
hashmakers on the planet you know like
and it just was super inspiring being
around them and um haven't really looked
back
i have been making hash since i was a
kid we would grow outdoor and because of
the climate uh and where we were at we
weren't getting very dense nugs and so
what we would end up doing is hashing it
because that was the way we could make
any money off of what we grew
so that's how it kind of started and
then it just progressed from there i
ended up preferring hash to uh to
flowers
just because it really lets me know
where the terpene profile stands and and
where the grower was at when he when he
made his when he made his product you
know it lets me know everything about
the grower you know just from the taste
flavor and so you know that's that's why
i prefer hash that and and it's a health
thing you know less is more you know
when it comes to hash and you don't end
up smoking flowers all day long every
day stinking and wasting your time you
know take a dab and it's done my
favorite thing about the secret cup is
the friends and the people that have
and they're all from different areas in
the country but we can all keep in touch
on the internet or whatever and
we all share an unhealthy obsession with
dabbing
the culture that surrounds it this is a
real organic
community experience this is done with a
lot of effort a lot of love there's
something here that you won't find in
the corporate element of other events it
doesn't really have that feel of people
trying to make money it more or less has
the feel of a community trying to
really become more tight-knit
and
a group of purists trying to really find
the best product and more most
healthiest product out there
my name is doug drake up and i own
hitman glass and i also throw chalice
festival big round of applause for uh
hitman glass and chalice
[Applause]
[Music]
supporting daniel and jeremy and uh
this whole elaborate thing they've
created uh i've definitely been there
from the earlier stages you know
attending a lot of their events events
like this progress the movement because
really nobody else is doing anything
like this we strive for
perfection in our work but at the secret
cups there's a little bit more of a i
don't know like a brotherhood where we
can talk about things and share our tech
rather than try to um hoard it or keep
it as like a secret society or something
that
to me the the secret cup is my family
not just my friends
um wherever we are if you
catch the vision and you're a part of it
then
you're part of the family
and hydro just as an artist supporting
the seeker cup with the secret cup
anthem it's awesome i know everybody
loves it so thank you for the anthem as
well
welcome to the cup i'm so glad that you
made it from l.a to m
for me it's really family you know
having all the people come together from
all the different cities every cup it's
something bigger it's something better
it's uh it's people helping each other
out to get the stuff on another level
you know people aren't holding back the
tricks really much and
and that's what's cool about it well
like i said family family family oh
you're on film dude you're not posing
[Music]
we get to celebrate the things that we
love the culture of cannabis
concentrates
and
all the good things that we want to see
go further in the community it was like
summer camp for hashmakers
it was like the the best symposium we
could come up with
it's cool that the event kind of grew
with
the movement you know and it grew at the
times it's really developed into its own
beast um i go to all types of wheat
events all over the world
all these guys are my friends and family
really
i've been attending almost every secret
cup since the inception and i've also
performed at several of them or hosted
others so i've been involved in one
capacity another for a lot of the shows
but i can't take credit for any of it
it's all definitely jeremy and daniel's
i'm really really happy that we were
able to do the event here in such an
amazing venue we were really really
lucky to have the people that helped us
last year kind of line it up that's
fields and ole and the whole staff here
ron
everybody's been awesome so
i would love to come back and do a lot
more here
there's a certain joy that comes from
experiencing superior work
so it's for the kind of sewers and it's
for the patients
so
i'm really happy to give this award to
we actually took first place last year
so that was out of control for us and i
love this man like i said just to be
around all my brothers and sisters i
work a lot right now so
to get to enjoy this and be around
family and like it's awesome it's it's
the best bringing everybody together
you know it's somebody's cool house and
we're hanging out and you're just
chilling like you're with your friends
at home you know i like being able to
meet people on a one-on-one basis
sometimes when you meet someone in their
booth they're so riddled with other
people and stress and everything that
they got going on it's hard to get on a
personal basis with someone and really
talk to them about their tech or what
they're doing or or how where they stand
in the oil industry or even in the
cannabis industry period when it's a
much more personal level like this and
you have a lot more time to hang out
with everyone and hear where they come
from and hear their story you meet a lot
of great people from all around the
world that you never would have had the
chance to meet and you know that's
that's probably one of the better things
about
the nationals is that here in vegas you
know you have the top three from every
region around the world essentially the
20 best hash makers in the united states
and you know to have them all sit down
at the same table and compare each
other's stuff in and of itself is is
just making history in the cannabis
movement fuck yeah i think we're the
best you know maybe not me but the group
of people are probably hands down the
best you know
i'm a very lucky person i get to travel
all over the country and now the world
doing these competitions bringing
like-minded people together it's such a
joy to be able to experience all these
different places and all these different
people
we don't make a lot of money
but the the experiences we get in being
able to go to the event ourselves that
we want to go to even though we had to
create it uh it's priceless
it's the thing i'm most proud of
in life
i don't want to thank haggard for just
djing for like two days straight
[Applause]
i think jeremy has a few things too we
wanted to throw out there before we
start announcing the winners myself and
daniel met at a
dispensary it was called kind meds
they were the premier
dispensary for concentrates in the
valley at the time when i was growing up
the there was a definite stigma against
cannabis my mother she was a smoker and
was actually smoking until she was about
five months pregnant but my grandmother
was definitely against it even though
she owned a bar when i moved from
arizona to california to live with her
she broke it down for me to like see
that bench right there in blythe me and
your stepdad smoked a joint there and at
first it was completely shocking to me
the fact that she my mother smoked pot
you know but for the next five years i
was living with her and you know got
very exposed to it and
yeah i never really
had a stigma after i was nine years old
i mean it was just a part of regular
life
so there were no brand names or
companies known for cannabis there were
strains that you'd heard about like maui
wowie was this famous hawaiian strain or
thai stick when you're going to buy
cannabis in the old days it was like
good bud or bad
cheap or expensive
there were not a lot of choices and it
wasn't the same every time you went back
to the same person even
sometimes they would have this sometimes
they would have that
you got a little bit of variety but they
were limited in what they grew or who
they were able to get from too
so we didn't have any of the brands here
in the united states when you went
overseas though they had seed companies
and coffee shops so certain genetics
started to come from people who had
established themselves in amsterdam and
other places at sea companies
and the strains they came out with
would generate recognition and those
would become sought after as well but
even then from grower to grower the
plants can be very different
even though it's the same genetics and
even from seed to seed of the same
strain they can be very different your
experience with cannabis was very
limited and very unique
if you were even able to get some of
this stuff so as cannabis grew and
became more of a mainstream thing
now you saw it was easier to establish
and popularize a brand
then the change went away from the
emphasis being really the genetics and
now it's more the brands with certain
genetics being associated with those
brands it's really fascinating
it was all uh in college for me
see when i was 16 years old i was living
in a foster home i joined a christian
fundamentalist church
and was in there until i was 19 years
old
and then uh when i was 19 years old
i decided that you know i met a girl and
i decided i wanted to be with her not
with the church so
i uh i left it there was this weird kid
who was an obvious stoner um
i was about to cross the street and he
was crossing the street too and he was
and we ran into each other he was like
hey can you try to buy us some beer at
the store we're both 19. and i'm like
sure i'll give it a shot i walk right in
there i get his 240s and come out and
he's like hey i i want to roll up this
blunt you know do you want to smoke and
i'm like yeah so we go back to his
apartment um he got one of those giant
cigars and announced a swag and he broke
it all up pulled the seeds and stems out
and rolled the fattest blunt i smoked
half of it slept on his couch like for
two days and i just woke up and i think
i've smoked every weed every single day
since
look at that guy go lugs of steels
after his philosopher's stones and
everything
cannabis helped me socially tremendously
i wasn't one of the popular kids growing
up and all i ever wanted was to just be
one of the cool kids for the longest
time i did not embrace being different
i saw it as a negative thing growing up
not being part of the in crowd knowing
that i was different from everybody else
it was a struggle as i smoked cannabis i
started to realize that being different
could be something really cool and
really special
and i was able to have this life that i
dreamed about growing up and travel all
over the world do all these crazy things
that was all because of cannabis i think
for me um it was the entire lifestyle of
it
i
sold weed because you know i was a
foster kid that went straight into a
university
and lived on financial aid
and i wanted to smoke and have fun and
you know live like the other college
kids so this afforded me the opportunity
to do it what i liked about it the most
is how it just brought so many different
people together
like you know when you're 18 19 years
old you have these sessions where
you know you have black people white
people people from korea that are
exchange students people from europe
that are exchange students you know
all together smoking weed and it was
really cool and it was really fun and it
was really nice and i felt like i was on
the path to some sort of
like some sort of thing something was
coming
[Applause]
almost shattered kids it doesn't like to
stick to a fucking dabber
so if you get shattered in your eyes
please do not sue me i don't have that
much money
the idea for the secret cup came from a
trip that i took to california right
after i won
first place the denver high times
medical cannabis cup for concentrate it
gave me a little bit of notoriety and i
was doing well financially so i took a
trip all up down the coast when i went
to san jose i was hanging out with a
bunch of people that
were part of this group online called
extract artists you know we were talking
about cups and we wanted to make the
best event possible so one thing that we
decided was you know we really had to
have qualified people judging it and
then we decided that
the most qualified people of all would
be
um actual
extract artist the first seeker cup
daniel was throwing it
when i went to cover the
event at his house i realized he was
overwhelmed and i started helping out
right away
being the person that i am in the
industry i've been on a lot of different
teams and i can recognize something
as
truly wonderful
and truly special when i see it
and i immediately recognized that the
seeker cup was going to be something
very special that the people who were
entering were different they weren't the
typical people that enter
a lot of these other events
the idea came sort of evolved into you
know the actual you know competitors
would be judging
the people they were competing against
because the fact is i wanted to make it
educational i want everyone who competes
to learn i want them to see what's
possible i want them to see what they're
competing against and uh you know if
they need to just change what they're
doing to be better the whole
sentiment of the competition was not the
same there was almost a level of sharing
and and camaraderie that was part of
this competition
versus like
a typical competition was very like
segregated and tribal you know
i'm versus you were enemies
but at the secret cup people were
sharing ideas they were talking about
these concepts in a different way
it was
kind of to raise the bar for everyone
it's kind of my legacy it's kind of like
what i'm trying to do i won a lot of
prizes and uh
contests
previously and i find that i like giving
out the prizes even better than i liked
winning them just because
it's fun to be able to find new talent
in something and
a lot of the hashmakers that are doing
really well today and making great
products
um were
not discovered by the secret cup but you
know that was the first contest they
ever won
when i saw that in colorado at the first
seeker cup
i told daniel i said i want to do this
in los angeles our community was
potentially deeper and
doing better work than the work they
were doing in colorado and i wanted to
showcase that right away you know i had
been to the amsterdam cannabis cups many
times and a common sentiment when you're
going there from california
is that you're not very impressed with
the quality of cannabis or the quality
of hash or you know the quality of a lot
of the products that are being entered
some of it is definitely very impressive
if you're lucky enough to get
uh introduced to that
and so i i came to daniel and i said i
wanted to do it and then when he gave me
the green light
to go ahead and do it i took that ball
and i ran with it
the big event in cannabis when i was
growing up was high times cannabis cup
and they would do that every year in
amsterdam
there was a part of the whole business
side that was really odd to me as a
consumer at the time
when you're meeting these cannabis
celebrities and people you looked up to
there was all this beef that was going
on in the cannabis industry
adam from th seeds i heard refer to it
as politics
seems so ridiculous from the outside
looking in
these people were openly working in
cannabis they were growing weed for a
living
isn't this the most wonderful dream job
that anybody could have
but somehow they all had these little
chips on their shoulders to a certain
degree and it was kind of this whole
shady side of the business
if you win a cannabis cup you get to be
a judge so i got to see behind the doors
and see that whole process
and the coolest part of the whole
experience was getting a whole bunch of
different weed of course
and being actually being chilling in
what was called the judge house at the
time
um
felt really exclusive you know uh
hanging out with like method man and red
men smoking weed with like famous people
was kind of cool
but you know it kind of occurred to me
like coming from the perspective of a
competitor
that these people were just not
qualified
like it was
a few of us winners and then
like everybody else was just like
buddies and stuff that had known certain
staff members for a long time there's a
lot of events right now and
they
are a new thing for a lot of people
the high times event is the one that's
been around for the longest time and
we're all just figuring it out as we go
along and different people have
different core ideals involved with when
they're doing the shows you know
different people do it for furthering
their companies or for some vision that
they might have but i think we have a
really special place that we come from
where we're doing it because we've
attended and done all the other shows
and we know what it is that we're
missing and we're trying to fill that
gap for people
and
show everyone how great it can really be
like yeah like you have people like our
boy brett and maine uh he was the
coordinator over in maine and he started
doing his own event out there at the
same venue that he found this like cool
little farm area and they had like a big
barn where you can throw stuff in and
like the owner smokes so it's cool
yeah he started doing a community
bonfire like two or three times a year
and that's awesome you know
i'm very happy to inspire something like
that and then you have the people that
we inspired that only saw
the expo part of it thinking like
that was the thing
right when
our events like were about like a week
or two weeks leading up to
the the actual public expo the public
expo was the award show
that we also had booths at
but that wasn't the thing
you know that was the end of the thing
but they saw they saw that and they were
like okay we give if we find a venue and
make a swap meet people will come
and that's good too you know that is
good too
but this is like you know the
the lowest aspect of it all the the the
buying and the selling not the hanging
out not the community you might have a
dj or comedian making some jokes but
there's nowhere for you to sit you walk
around in a circle you buy what you want
you go home
and that's cool too that's cool too
actually it started when high time
started coming around i think it was
like 2010 2011 um high time started
coming to the u.s
the medical scene in california and in
denver and washington had had progressed
to a state to where they could hold
competitions there high times is a
different thing i i love it i think it's
cool but it's just its own giant in
itself you know and like i think this is
more like
like the best of the best type of deal
you know like yeah a lot of people
compete in that but this is where we
like really get to go like this you know
[Music]
i
started going to the competitions um and
i had friends that owned different
companies and i had helped them with
different entries and or entered my own
stuff and just kind of progressed from
there i started to make a name for
myself when people started to see what i
provided you know it's kind of funny you
know what you
find to be
you know everywhere like for instance
southern california if you go to ola
everyone has og or grows og and then you
go to somewhere like denver or even the
east coast and
there's a lot of people have never even
tried it and so you know you start to
really open your eyes to
a lot of
people out there and where they're at
and where they stand and then cbds
started to happen and i you know i
started to try to progress into cbds and
help as many people as possible and you
know when i started seeing
when i was i would go to a cup and have
a booth and people would come up to me
and say hey man you know that last drop
he made here at so and so you know that
really helps me with whatever ailment i
have and it was that right there was my
motivation to continue with what i was
doing and to go even harder and try to
help as many people as i could make
money doing it and and feel good about
myself there's a lot of people that work
every day and they make a lot of money
but they might not feel too good about
what they do for a living you know like
i don't have those issues i feel great
about what i do there's a lot of people
i help everything about their life and
the people that love them is better
that's what pushes me forward that's
that right there is what makes me want
to help as many people as i can and try
to make sure that you know everyone
understands that you know a lot of
things have been purported a lot of way
you know there's a lot of pharmaceutical
drugs that really increase problems
instead of alleviate them and cbd's is a
way for people to really
change
what's wrong with them change issues
that they're having and alleviate
symptoms and live a much better
lifestyle because of it and you know
it's it's just new it's just now coming
forward we just now have the science
behind it we just now have everything we
need to progress forward and um and show
people you know the science is there the
more people that are helped the more
people that lives are improved and the
more people that see that
is the change that we can make in the
world you know we got to start with
ourselves and hope that other people
follow suit you know
definitely not my first secret cup uh i
heard about the secret cup a while ago
and then finally they came to the east
coast did the secret cup beast coast
when i entered in as dabber hashery
extracts and
got to meet all the good boys at the cup
the competition element of it is sort of
like it's like an american idol
of hash making
and now
the award for highest terps
surprisingly goes to a high cbd entry as
well
number 17 gilded extracts for remedy sap
for the highest terps award to compete
in this event each contestant only needs
to provide 20 grams of concentrate or 60
grams of flour evening the playing field
for smaller producers
their submission is broken down into
judges packs at intake and distributed
just a few hours later
the competitors will have a week to
sample all the entries before the award
ceremony
are you excited to judge it oh yeah
definitely they will score the entries 1
to 10 in various categories some places
have more competitors than others but
who will win is always a mystery all
that is known for sure is that the
competition will be stiff between these
masters of the cannabis craft everybody
in this in this competition was
like
everybody knocked it out of the park
they're all there for a reason it's all
good
so it's
you know they call it extract art for a
reason because it's people's art and you
know it's it's hard to say which one is
better you know i i was an attendee
always at the original and the cannabis
cup in amsterdam was the only event you
wait one year and you fly across the
seas and you got to go to one event a
year in amsterdam and
now now we're here there's all kinds of
events and it's all changing and i think
it's really really great
when high time started doing their
events in the united states they were
now allowing the boost to sell cannabis
actually a few other events did this too
on a smaller scale
but i times did it really big and i
remember going to that event and
thinking oh my god this is really new
and different from even the amsterdam
events
it still wasn't as cool as that
experience really but it was the best we
got so far for the us i'm one of very
few people that got my love for events
by going to events
and being inspired and building these
friendships
i think that's really unique
and most of the people that are involved
in them now never spent a dollar to just
go to enjoy the event without promoting
some business or something entirely
business related growing up not being
part of anybody's tribe
feeling like you're an outcast and very
different then you go to this event
and there's all these different kinds of
people
but
they're somehow like you
and you start to feel like
it's okay to be the way that i am like
these things that i like
and in fact maybe i'm gonna get more
into it start enjoying these things in a
more celebratory way not just in the
shadows
and that shouldn't be something that you
get only once a year in amsterdam
when events started to happen in
california i was all for it and i wanted
to support all of those events and see
where they went
but for high times
there was a stigma that followed their
competition
over in amsterdam
people had started to say that the
competitions were fixed
i can say the winners were not the
authentic best in the competition so how
were they winning
these big companies obviously people
thought they were paying or cheating in
some sort of way
and i have enough experience now that i
could say that's not true
may have happened
but it was marketing that was mostly
winning the events because it's much
easier to convince people that you have
the best than to authentically produce
the best
and high times got a bunch of bad press
just because of the way their
competitions worked it was all about
building your brand there so these
people would like some of the a lot of
the attendees were fans of these
hashmakers so they'd go out and they'd
actually be able to meet them and dab
their personal stuff and like form
personal connections with these brands
that you know sometimes they had they'd
already been supporting
sometimes that they had just seen and
really wanted to try
[Music]
this event i'm all about having each
event have their
have its own unique you know terms or
you know judging rules or whatever you
know like every event i like that it's
its own thing
um and this clearly wasn't just like
regurgitation of uh high times or
anything like that it was its own unique
thing from the get-go and like knowing
jeremy and dan i know they just really
care about hash and um you know like
they're very caring people jeremy helps
me with chalice
you know the chalice festival and he
does it for the community and he does it
because he cares you know
and uh
that's what i love about these two guys
you know and they really uh they're fr
it's from the heart
we have a really good mix of people who
compete and
everyone kind of works together to make
the secret cup happen
wasted to taste it
it's about the taste
and people bring all these great things
to the table they they
for free you know they'll give
their product or something from
themselves
and and just to make it better for their
city or the other people that are
attending and so
that's probably the thing that's the
same and it's amazing that we are able
to find these really unique and
helpful people in every city that make
it possible i think it's the bond with
like the brothers that we have here with
all the hashmakers and
the knowledge that actually is being
spread amongst uh amongst us now and
well like i said 2012 was a lot
different where people were i think
scared to give their technique out and
all these things because of business you
know and now everyone i think is getting
it like there's a lot of business and
man we can all teach each other and
maybe grow from this and at least that's
where my mindset is i can't really speak
for everyone else but i feel like if you
want change right then that has to be
within yourself so if i really want
something to be different then i need to
change it from right here
and that's what we're doing i saw it as
a networking event a lot of people saw
it as a party uh but this was like
high-level networking that was like
causing lanes to open up all over the
country
when we developed the event we
tried to think about the things that we
didn't like
that
weren't just personal opinion uh things
that we didn't like about the other
events
we tried to think fundamentally what was
wrong with them
if we could improve the fairness
we wanted to make them more accurate
representations of what our culture is
really about i've entered a lot of high
times cups i've entered a lot of
different competitions what always ends
up happening is nine times out of ten
they hire someone like wiz khalifa or
snoop dogg the judge and he doesn't know
a thing about growing he may know what
weed he likes and what wedi doesn't like
but he doesn't know anything about
growing and so you get a lot of things
and like for instance it's a lot harder
to take a wee a 16-week sativa full all
the way cure it properly and have it be
dense hard resonance that's a lot harder
to do than it is to grow cookies at
eight weeks which frosts up for everyone
so you know there's a lot of things that
aren't taken into consideration because
the people judging aren't hands on when
it comes to the secret cup everyone
judging is also entering so they do this
on a daily basis they understand what to
look for they understand what not to
look for what they like what they don't
like and it reflects in the judging you
know nine times out of ten you know when
you look at the people that win first
second or third place they deserve to be
there and that's that says something
about the competition in and of itself
so when we were first doing the events
we had
really a lot of support from everyone in
the industry so the well-known brands
were entering the well-known hashmakers
all the biggest companies wanted to be a
part of it
and then as we started doing the events
and they couldn't even place in the top
three
you started to realize these big brands
had a lot to lose by entering these
competitions with these smaller
more
passionate growers and hashmakers and
they were universally defeating these
big companies at every event in every
part of the country even internationally
when we did our events
in spain and in amsterdam both times
people from the uk
traveled there and won the events and
there's no medical cannabis in the uk
there's no legal cannabis of any kind in
the uk so
these people are risking their lives
and when they would show up at the event
they reminded me of all of our people in
california they were at that level and
you're going to start to see that as
cannabis becomes more open without you
guys in the community we would not be
able to throw an event anywhere so give
yourselves a big round of applause for
being part of the 17th community
remember when we first started throwing
them we would put really really really
long tables with like power outlets
underneath the tables and set them up
and like throw out like candy and waters
and stuff for people just to go at it
like we could have made so much more
money they wouldn't have remembered it
the rest of their lives and the people
that got to go remember it this is why i
wanted a secret cup here in dc i have
been traveling forever outside of dc uh
going to
cannabis cups going to events going to
the west coast where it's really
you know three times ahead of where
we're at because you have the
temperature you have the ability for
people to flex that experience and um i
wanted to see how that would have
happened over here
and just as i you know kind of saw it in
my head
um you know first out of dc you know
most of the things that you saw were
just fairly
okay and homegrown um i wanted people to
understand that there's more out there
um there's gold oils there are you know
trees that look like christmas you know
uh you know a christmas tree dusted in
snow the secret cup was like
a party that made you feel exclusive
just because you were there
i got it
oh
[Music]
i mean it was something different you
know than the high times events which
i'd been to and i'm a fan of i i enjoyed
it but this was another level you had a
lot of the people that came out that
were smokers that
they just wanted to you know they just
wanted to smoke weed and they weren't
really about
the higher end of things and that's
where the secret cup came into places
and that's where it gave a place for
people that weren't into that kind of
stuff so i asked dan if i could you know
put together a song for him i wanted to
do a top shelf song
for appreciation and he said no i got
this secret cup mixtape that i wanted to
put out
so you should do a song about the secret
cup because we're about to start doing
them in other cities and expanding so
so i ended up putting together the
secret cup anthem i came out to denver
for the finals and i had two verses done
in the hook and i wrapped it for dan and
jeremy and they're like oh this shit is
amazing all right i'll put together the
third verse
after the event from the experiences and
that's really what it is it's just the
songs are all like a story of my life
so this was what that was it was just
documenting my times at the secret cup
and especially that third verse was just
like soaking up that finals event
mortimer out there rocking her belt that
energy of everybody in the place just uh
having a great time it's always peaceful
there's never problems at the events
just being around so many like-minded
people so many people that are into the
same thing you are that appreciate the
same things you do
and it's not just it's not just the hash
i mean it's uh it's everything else too
it's all the trappings of the culture
um
intense love of glass art
that everybody shares a chance to meet
people that are actually making medicine
the chance to meet people that are
actually making the glass art
[Music]
[Applause]
so when we were doing the secret cup one
of the things that i wanted to
incorporate into it were some of the
stereotypical
things about cannabis that go along with
the whole culture i myself i believe
really strongly that
cannabis and art are
really closely connected you've all
heard stories of this musician talking
about cannabis influencing their art so
we wanted to incorporate some of that
into the seeker cup
we had live glassblowing at almost all
of the events and glassblowing for me is
a really important part of the culture
for a long long time head shops
were the main meeting point for
stoners when you
got in trouble
a lot of times that was your only
opportunity to still be in the cannabis
industry in some sort of way you could
work at a head shop and that was okay
the glass
aspects of cannabis has been one of the
things that pushed the culture forward
so so glass was very simple in the very
beginning and as it has innovated and
become more intricate and more diverse
in the colors and all the different
things it's pushed the whole culture
forward in a classy and really
respectable way the first secret cup i
did was the first one they did in
california
and
i mean that's one of my favorite
memories blowing glass live because i've
done it before but for head shop owners
and they appreciate it but this was the
crowd of
like
virgin eyes for that kind of thing so
you had a whole bunch of people just
staring at you and i mean
i remember the event
the crowd was at the glass demo i mean
that was where the most of the people
that attended the event they had music
going on and the the vendor booths with
the different hashes and flowers and
things to buy and people were buying for
sure i'm sure it was a lucrative event
for them but i just remember seeing
this
like really big crowd of people that
were all focused on us taking pictures
and videos and
um
i see the pictures from that event and i
mean it just looks cool we were blowing
glass in front of this huge
graffiti murals on these train tracks
that were defunct um but i mean we were
literally set up on the train tracks and
the pictures are just really cool it
wasn't
a huge area so the crowd looks tight you
know it looks like there's a lot more
people there that may have been there
but it was still a really large crowd
super huge fan of glassblowing
i grew up
around some really amazing glassblowers
that i'm like
in a way baffled that they're not taking
advantage of all this like what's going
on around them you know and some of them
have money and some of them were growing
whatever else but i just
i felt like they're like missing out on
this like huge
opportunity in the glass world right now
and growing up like even before i was
really deep into the scene like you
would buy glass pipe that you liked at a
head shop or somewhere it would have a
special meaning to you because you would
take it around throughout your life and
you would have all these special moments
that you shared with this piece and with
other people and
it became kind of part of your whole
journey and then when you would break it
it was like a loss it was a real tragic
loss
you would maybe buy a new piece or
something like that and it would start a
new journey
it was something that
um you know became really special
and and as i learn more and more about
glass
you know i think that that is something
that's under appreciated
people kind of don't even realize that
they have this relationship with their
glass pipe or their glass bong or
whatever it is
i mean i think that concentrates had a
big role on how
glass manufacturing has been changed
you've watched
you know
pieces go from being the four foot bong
to being the four inch rig
that you you it's very hard to walk into
a head shop and find a piece that has a
down stem for a flower bowl now
everything's got a male ground joint for
a dome or a domeless nail
so it's it's been interesting to watch
it evolve and obviously the internet's
had its role in that by
giving everybody the immediate access to
information
where it would normally take word of
mouth
a long time to spread
geographically the internet allows it to
just spread like overnight
i think this is what's putting us uh the
whole the hashmakers and all that kind
of in the forefront and it's vice it's
like we're piggybacking off each other
because they go hand in hand and this
revolution is like it's amazing
glass had to change when the kind of
hash that we smoked
started to turn into a liquid and so the
tools that were being used originally
became much more diverse
and
when we entered the cannabis cup we were
entering with one of the very first
dabbing tools that were
out there
and as time progressed those tools have
become so innovative that that original
tool is basically obsolete nobody uses
it anymore just hitting it purely off
the the titanium device
all you were getting was that oil
and it was getting vaporized super quick
it wasn't smoke it's not setting it on
fire you're just getting it so hot that
it changes from a plasma to a gas and
you inhale it and it bypasses your
the the what is it the blood brain
barrier and just instantly
high
and the thing is it's really easy to
you know sort of regulate your dosage
too
oh you smoked on my dab
you smoke all of my dab
when dabbing came onto the scene it
really uh
it changed everything it gave
us artists a new outlet to make things
because now we're coming up with
entirely new accessories that haven't
been thought up before
all right so
this right here kind of
changed everything for
the glass industry this is dabbing
what this is is
um concentrated
thc oil or hash oil
and
so we're heating up this nail
which is made of quartz on one of our
glass rigs
let me get this nail nice and hot
there's no combustion you're not burning
any
any plant material at all the first time
i saw someone take a dab
i was at uh
at mers house and he's since passed away
but he was a well-known glassblower in
our industry and um
i showed up at his house and i see this
torch in this rig just like that except
we had titanium at the time and it was a
swing
and they're heating it up and taking
dabs and i'm like oh my gosh are you
guys doing drugs here you know that's
what i was thinking because you know i
never associate cannabis with that kind
of thought but yeah i didn't know what's
going on
they explained to me the process and
i mean it's like a whole different way
to consume cannabis
and now we have a whole different
line of things we need to make we made
these like swings um it was basically a
funnel that was bent and you'd
sell these swings like this to other
companies and they would wrap them with
metal in fact um
this is one
that
was one of the first companies that kind
of marketed the swings they asked me
to make and i did pattern work ones and
then i did these
sculpted ones and looking back i mean
these are really
rough um but what they were doing was
wrapping this titanium pad
around the swing
around the glass and calling it a swing
because it swings back and forth so
you'd heat this up
and once it was glowing you'd swing it
back down and get your dab ready and you
just drop it and that's what this little
opening was for so you could get your
dab tool in there and vaporize it and
you don't see
very many people use using the swings
anymore um
you know every now and then i probably
make one a year
someone will hit me up and they want
like a classic rig so we started making
the swings and then nails came out and
domes and uh
that's a whole thing that's like
come and gone like that that time that
time it's weird because it's still so
new
um but there's
trends that have come and gone
and now everyone uses some form of a
banger
and even those are becoming a little
different and taking on different shapes
and cannabis in general is just a very
fast-moving innovative business
the thing that is popular this year
might be completely obsolete by the end
of the next year so
you have to stay on top of it really
really
all the time and having these events and
all the different cities that helped us
to constantly be on the pulse of where
cannabis was going
now we're thinking
[Music]
you know the rigs and the dab
scene is big so a lot of the more higher
end pieces are going to be
uh styled and engineered to do dabs
whereas a lot of the flower pieces are
made differently they have a different
way the diffusers go in and things like
that it's because you know without the
dabbing rigs like i said in 1999 we were
making oil there wasn't no dab rigs then
though like we're pouring that shit on
on buds and like killing our throat and
lungs and it was a horrible way to do
oil and some people tried to hot knife
it and stuff but
um i just think that that's
like i said it's piggybacking off each
other so it's like a
it's a beautiful dynamic you know like
it's
it's future it's what it is you know
i think vaporizing the oil and stuff is
the future like no more smoking the
flower and i love flowers of death but i
just really feel like vaporizing even
vaporizing flower i guess is better than
not you know
i think dabbing is still the future dude
there's all these youngsters that want
to be a part of it still like haven't
got to experience all this you know and
now these certain states are becoming 21
years of age to partake these kids are
like wow i can't wait to be 21.
people need to see the the stuff if it's
made properly
it's not dangerous and in fact can
really approach like connoisseur grade
levels
um i want people to know what's possible
like the magic that you can get out of
this plant
i want people to
know how to smoke it know how to judge
the quality of it um have better access
to meds wherever they're from um i want
all that stuff to happen
so when you attended a secret cup a lot
of times you're being exposed to the
next new trend in cannabis people would
show up to the secret cup
and
sometimes they would have worked on
something for like
you know maybe a year long and they'd
have this wonderful story of the plant
that they grew or where their
concentrate came from sometimes it was
like a new technique
and
i've even
had
you know my eyes opened on things that i
didn't think were possible like i've had
a alcohol
extraction oil that was phenomenal
tasting
and
you know there's just been
numerous things that
um
even
me as somebody who had experienced quite
a lot in cannabis
i
constantly am having my eyes open to new
things and i love that about the secret
cup the innovation the real innovation
because people that were into that whole
part of the events
the the seeker cup was the kind of event
that attracted a true cannabis
connoisseur somebody that had really
learned the history
and
a lot of people that were doing really
really cutting edge innovation that's
what i love about these two guys you
know and they really uh they're it's
from the heart you know and uh
that's
i feel a little more rare
you know in in
industry events or whatever that it's
from someone from the movement from the
industry it's from you know the soul
and i think everybody notices that
um and and the energy the event has now
and like it means something to win the
event if i don't win first second or
third or any anything um at least i got
to present myself and my side of the
story and show people
maybe something that they haven't had
the opportunity to try and you know
that's a win to me but you know winning
actually winning that would be a large
statement to where the cannabis industry
is progressing and how
much extract artists care about quality
clean meds because when you enter a
solvent-less entry it's zero ppm zero
it's zero you know solvent is there's no
nothing that can harm you and so when
you have something as loud as my entry
and as flavorful as my entry you know
and and and to have them recognize that
recognize what it is as a medicine and
vote for me to win that would be
probably one of the highlights of my
life i'd be really stoked not just for
myself but for the cannabis industry and
where we stand as extract artists
i don't want it to get big
a lot of the other events their goal is
to get bigger and make more money and
that's never been my goal
my goal has been to provide the best
experience for the people
that attend the event
and as we've done the events i know
where we're lacking
and i know where we're strong
and i just want to focus on those kinds
of things and bring
to the people some more of the
experiences that they're looking for
that's one of the hardest things
is uh
the budget that we're facing but i
believe that people see what we're
trying to do now
and that's going to open the doors to a
much greater experience for all the
people involved
i'm really excited that you know i think
the face of the secret cup's changing a
little bit and the more knowledge the
more things are like this we get to
express it to each other you know i
really want to break new ground so
uh i like to do different things with
the events if i keep getting caught up
in the same pattern
a lot of times that can be not so fun
you know
the other thing is i want to see
everybody uh happy and i want to push
the education so
this message that we've got i want to
get to everyone and
it's difficult you know we don't have
the platform to speak just yet
and
we're slowly building you know
i would recommend it to anybody who's a
connoisseur or someone who strives to
know what
real
medicine in the cannabis community is
there's a lot of people that try to pass
off
you know nugrum or these other terms of
what
high quality things should be when
they're really not anywhere close to it
and the competitors are a good example
of what
the perfect concentrates or what we
strive to have should be like and what
real medicine should be for people that
need it you know
and uh yeah i think that's pretty much
it
[Music]
the goal was to make it a part of
regular life and we were successful and
it is now
but what was special
was
the fact that we were on the fringes on
the front lines making something happen
for the first time um and that there was
risk involved and that was exciting
how's it going everyone uh i just
started uh fresh off the butt
extractions a little while ago uh first
i want to foremost thank uh dan and
nicotine for hosting this event
there have been a number of times in my
career
in the cannabis industry
where i
almost had to pinch myself where i i'm
like
think about what you're doing think
about where you are
thanks
i mean the only way i could compare it
is it's like having like a rock star
lifestyle you're like
traveling to these
strange
unknown places
people are like bringing you into like
these
grows or these
you know farms that
they don't bring people into and i'm
gonna bring them attention this is some
sort of
value a new value to their company that
wasn't something that existed before
and here i am thankfully i am an
authentic
cannabis fan
so they could talk to me and know
that i'm truly passionate about
everything and
they felt a lot more comfortable
bringing me into these places but it was
strange you know you could feel
the
danger and some of the situations you
know and i'm in oakland
going to this
different place or that different place
and
you know here i am
you know little me
and uh some of these people are heavily
armed
going to other countries like
spain dealing with the military police
in spain
like
they have cannabis over there but they
they don't necessarily have like legal
cannabis the way that we have so
it's
constantly an evolving process and
you know it's it's stressful and
a lot of times you're hating it a lot of
times you're thinking i should have done
a regular job that these risks that i'm
taking are not worth it
that i'm not getting financially
something that's going to get me set up
for life out of this
this is just some sort of like
passionate thing that i've got myself
into because of how much i believe in
this you know for some reason a lot of
credit comes my way but the fact of the
matter is the the secret cup wouldn't
exist the uh i wouldn't have been able
to accomplish any of this without jeremy
i mean he has a he has a mind for events
and he puts in
all the tough work and anytime he needs
uh someone needs to be an asshole like
this guy is the one who does it
you know you question well i think it's
pretty normal to have those moments
but it's also pretty awesome to have
those triumphs when
you've won or you you've done something
especially the events like we've thrown
an event in some sort of
unique place and
people have like
won awards it's been this really
wonderful thing for
a lot of people and
a really amazing adventure you feel a
triumph that's not really
explainable i mean i've vacationed to
amsterdam many times
when i threw an event in amsterdam
i felt
like a totally different feeling
and
those kind of things are really special
i'm glad to have been a part of it and i
think
even just for the people that attend the
events
that they've had some of those really
special moments too
[Music]
local laws are what determines what
we're able to do as far as an event goes
because we don't want to run a foul of
them so that determines how you know
like any kind of distribution if
possible happens that determines whether
we have a
big
expo that's public or we have a small
private event like this one
vegas laws right now until they go fully
recreational
means that you know we can totally rent
a house and have a private event but we
can't you know like just invite the
public to it because uh they had an
event here recently and uh totally had
cops show up to it shut down the
medicating area they weren't quite done
with it yet yeah that was that was a
message you know one of the things also
at the secret cup was because we were
experts at all this stuff
you know we might be consuming these
large amounts but the idea was not to be
like trashy about it it was to be classy
about it and to show that cannabis
didn't have to be this like
get fucked up and
be a mess you know like this
stereotypical negative thing that a lot
of people look at it as that you could
enjoy it and still be like a functioning
adult and do all kinds of things i mean
there's a lot of things you can do to
like leave a good impression on the city
that you're working with um
one thing that we did in rhode island
that worked really well is we went to
the city government we told them exactly
what we were going to do we broke it
down for them they were completely on
board we got all the permits we needed
and we were able to
on top of all that um
raise a whole bunch of stuff for the
homeless so we had people bringing food
and clothes and we had two truckloads
full of stuff that we dropped off to the
local
homeless shelter
even with the secret cup i will say like
as as bad as the situation was with the
law enforcement my interactions with
them were all fine you know nobody did
anything to me that was inappropriate
they definitely put a lot of attention
on events
simply because we were smoking cannabis
there and that was the entire reason
they had a problem with our event we
could have done almost
the exact same events
minus the actual cannabis part of them
and they would have had no problem with
the event the problem was the smoking
cannabis part
not even the sales the sales obviously i
could see
sometimes those being problems you know
or issues
uh
that was not the issue the issue was
smoking cannabis
and that to me is staggering i can't
believe that that's still a problem
uh people don't see all the wrestling
that we have to do with regulations and
laws when we throw one of these events
we have to contract a lawyer and make
sure this is even possible to do it
first of all
then it comes to actually putting the
event together
that means that we have to like raise a
lot of money and we have to have the
trust of the community in order to do so
primarily what pays for these events is
people that pay for the enhanced
experience of like you know the the
chance to come to the vip event the
chance gift bag that kind of thing the
chance to try the entries you know
they're all paying extra for that stuff
and we use that money that we raised
from them to like throw this event we
don't have major sponsors we're a
grassroots event
and so as far as manpower goes
we have a lot of volunteers a lot of
people that really believe in this they
might not be able to shell out the 300
necessary to get a ticket but you know
they are definitely willing to put their
heart and you know their their efforts
into making sure the event goes well
like we have people doing like web work
photography
people that are cooking people that are
serving people that are cleaning up
people that are running errands and
putting out any fire that pops up
so
it's a it's a 100 a group effort it's
like you know the family comes together
and then we get it done
the very first secret cup was targeted
to just kind of be one event
and then as i wanted to do my own event
in los angeles
other people that had gone to the first
one wanted to do their own in their own
cities too
but they were having trouble so dan
contacted me
brought me on
so from that point on
i became involved with throwing all of
the events all over the world
and ultimately i'm the only person
that was at every secret cup in every
city and every state and every country
and that's
actually a very proud accomplishment
and
one of the best adventures of my life
everywhere we went
people would just you know jump in and
help out like when we had the beast
coast thing um we ordered hundreds of
lobsters and it just turned out that we
had a chef there he's now one of my good
friends ben
had a chef there with his knives and
stuff and he started cooking them for
everybody you know it was that it was
that level of pitching in all the time
everybody was just
everywhere we went like we had people
just step up and help out give us places
to stay drive around work for free
i mean there's so many people
like uh
yeah everyone we did it was the
community and like we really
what we did was facilitate you know
everybody coming together that's what we
did you know we we created a lane and
everybody else had to pitch into work
so eventually there were little events
that just focused on money
vending aspects of the event scene
and they started popping up every day
basically
and there were huge concert-based events
every month or so
when we were first doing the events
and this is also true for chalice
we had the community all coming together
it was really a special thing
it was a whole movement it was
incredible
and we were powerful
but as these things happen and people
would go to all these other events all
the time
we lost that feeling that what we were
doing was something special
and now most of the other events are
gone
in fact there's only a handful of events
all over the world that i really think
are worth going to
uh it seemed that as time went on there
was less of an interest from the
community um to help and we had always
relied on the community's help it's one
thing to find a venue that is making no
money and you're going to give them
thousands of dollars to like use their
event space for a big ass event like
that's a little easier it seemed like
over time than finding an intimate space
for 100 friends to hang out
you know like airbnb was up on the whole
party thing
um
it just got harder and harder to do the
vip stuff to like put out the money
ahead of time you know i've been to a
lot of these things since the first one
in seattle that
uh i was able to go to
and there was kinks then too you know
what i mean but it's just
you know you learn to expect it and it's
you know it's a bunch of stoners putting
together a party you know what i mean so
as we were doing the secret cup we ran
into all these problems
all these different ways and
one that was common was legal problems
with the police from the first event in
los angeles we had police called in who
showed up in riot gear
that same year we had issues with them
in san francisco involving our venue and
we had to switch that last minute that
happened often the worst time was
probably colorado where it happened
twice in a week and we had to switch
cities because at one venue i had to
talk to detectives who had a file on us
the second event in arizona was the only
event they forced us to cancel
but in humboldt they showed up to the
second event with k-9 units and wanted
to arrest everyone they could
in spain they met me as i was exiting
the plane with my picture and wanted to
look through my luggage because all the
trophies and prizes made them suspicious
of me the last event we even did had a
local cannabis advocacy group take a
public sand against the event
simply for coming to their town
there were so many times we had to deal
with problems like these
all of it made it really difficult to
continue with the events
and it also led us to having to do
refunds and cover losses from dropouts
and
deal with all the negativity surrounding
all those kinds of things
caught a few people trying to cheat and
the support from the community just
became much less
we weren't making a bunch of money we're
doing these events for the love of
cannabis and recognizing the really true
achievement and innovations in the
cannabis industry when we started to run
into so many problems especially
financially
and people just not appreciating what we
were trying to do
we decided to stop doing it
to sum it up there's there's two aspects
of how we inspired people we inspired
people with the spirit of the secret cup
and we inspired them with the business
of the secret cup spirit of the secret
cup was
for me
um it was
freedom it was like it was almost like
being a kid again
you know it was like a summer camp like
a getaway um like a convention
for a very niche society of people that
were making hash for
um for the community
that had built fans that were like
celebrity chefs that were
you know he had some notoriety so we
were able to just
bring all these people together and it
was great you know and that that that
was the best part of it for me they you
know
you do stuff you do at other events
listen to music like
uh eat food like all that stuff but you
know the the love of the cannabis was
like why everybody was there and that
was great
that was great does that live on
it sure does live on but in
but not like it was
now that it's been a couple years since
we've done an event
right around the time we did the
campouts there is a group of people who
start talking about doing another secret
cup when i run into people at other
events
it's very common for them to tell me
about how their company owes some of
their success to the secret hub in some
way
they got their first booth there
they made some important connection
and the love for the positive
experiences is still strong and that
makes me super happy for all those
people who are still doing it
and big d
you made it all possible for me so thank
you very very much i really appreciate
it yeah
but yeah the you know there were more
events after this we inspired a lot of
people to do this on their own in fact
like one thing that i said every one of
the cups we had was like look
we did this we're just like you do this
too you know they give
your people a place to
buy
better medicine cheaper you know
directly from the people that are making
it build these relationships that will
carry over after legalization after the
chads come in and steal it from you you
know
i really did my best to like spread
those seeds everywhere i went
and like we didn't even like ask for
credit from anybody
a lot of times people get
really upset
and they start to see into things that
aren't there and
then they start to believe these stories
that they've kind of
created for themselves
like we had people that entered our
event lots of different times and they
never won
you know they get really frustrated
and uh
you know
it's it's hard to accept that you just
aren't doing the best work that's out
there
it's a lot easier to say
that there's some sort of conspiracy
against you and that's why you're not
winning
any time that you do something that
somebody else isn't doing
even if it's a failure it's still a
progression because in that failure
you're going to learn from it and you're
going to learn something that you would
have never learned had you not taken the
step anyway so
so anything that's a progression towards
what something hasn't been done before
in my mind is is an advancement towards
uh towards something better even if it's
not something that you initially
recognize is better
we were operating in a great area
between medical and recreational
they passed these laws and they were not
very specific so you kind of had blanket
protection in order to put one of these
on like a lot of times like the local
authorities didn't even want to
bother with us you know we put this
together with our friends
you know we made a movement that
attracted people from all over the
country and all over the world that
built up the mythos of this subculture
to the point where it entered popular
culture
um
but at the the end of the day
we didn't have the resources to go on
anymore so we had to stop
you know the the movement still goes on
there are still other events that are
kind of doing similar things to what we
were doing and and some of the people
that used to attend our events are
headlining those
uh other events in other places but
it's not the same
i think this is one of the
best events out there
i really think that you know
we would love to to
to have more people that are purists and
and people like us like-minded people
get involved all over as as we're
opening up the doors of the united
states from our
legal marijuana i think it's also going
to open up the doors for more people to
become family in the secret cup so yeah
i would recommend it i would uh love to
see this family grow
the best part about the secret cup is
how it brings all the like-minded
individuals together uh kind of in a
form of unity and it's not so much about
the commercialization
it's more about the art it's more about
the product
it's more about
the sense of community
you know everybody's going to have a
good time no matter what because
we're all here together you know
so all that's
all that small stuff doesn't really
matter we all we all made it here we all
we're all having a good time
you know it could be stressful because
of the logistics side of things but
in the end it
it always comes together i just i love
everybody gathering
and really man this this shit's like
it's like being in some magical
wonderland that people just don't i mean
when my friends and my folks hear about
how what we're how we're getting down
out here they just can't believe it you
know it's nuts they see the videos it's
it's really cool it's a blessing to be a
part of all of this and i can only
relate it to when i was younger i
thought man if we could only
live in the times of when the hippies
were doing you know the 60s the 70s the
woodstock days how crazy that must have
been like where are we i think we're in
that like blip of of our 60s 70s and
it's just cool to be a part of this have
so many of the homies get down that we
do get down with and uh you already know
it's just it's just the beginning it's
gonna keep going secret cup to infinity
and beyond
yeah i mean dude it just it erupted into
its own thing
the cannabis scene from place to place
is unique and wonderful they have their
own genetics they have their own heroes
their own
soldiers
they have their activists
there are really wonderful things going
on
all over the country all over the world
and when you go to these other places
and you start to learn these stories and
part of the story is the culture of the
place that you're in and part of the
story is the cannabis history that
is from this location and surrounding
all of these kind of
genetics and these different growers and
um hashmakers
all of that stuff is
so rich
and for me as a cannabis enthusiast a
true person that loved cannabis like
going to these places and hearing these
stories and meeting these people
it was awesome for me and
just as cool as it was for them to be a
part of our event it was cool for me to
be a part of their history and their
culture one thing i want to communicate
is like the best thing about it all for
me
um wasn't the the cannabis it was the
freedom it was like traveling to a
different city
and people there you know greeting us
warmly and giving us gifts and feeding
us and taking to their us to their
favorite spots and showing us their
zones like only a local could
local people that would hear that you're
coming out and they would want to take
us to their grow or they would want to
take us to some really local special
food spot and
sometimes it had nothing to do with
cannabis they just wanted to show us the
history of the town and i loved it it
was so wonderful i
enjoyed that probably the best out of
all the things that we did
i loved that shit i loved it
that was my favorite part
i'm glad to see you all out here and
supporting uh this is what we wanted to
do we want to spread the movement you
guys all get it this is this is a
medical event too so i i really want to
thank all you guys that are patients i i
really believe in uh the medical value
to what we do here it's uh pretty
commonly known that having friends and
having a good social life is healing for
people and uh they're constantly trying
to keep us away from each other they
don't want us to be friends i don't know
what it's about but we're all here
together
and we're forming a family and they're
not gonna be able to keep us apart
so thank you guys all for being out here
and uh i hope you had a great time when
we first did the events
you know people were very skeptical
about
our ability to do them and and the whole
thing and they would have a lot to say
and then as we were doing them and
people were having these amazing
wonderful times and there were these
colossal successes
people wanted to get on board and become
supporters and so we had
some people kind of just had play on our
name you know they started their own
event and it had
a similar name to our event
but that ultimately
resulted in people just straight up
stealing our name there were multiple
events in other countries
that were just called the secret cup
that we had no affiliation with at all
i guess that's flattering and kind of
now where i'm standing i'm ready to give
the the title of seeker cup to the
to the world and everyone can go throw
their own secret cups and
you know
i wish everyone
all the success and all the happy times
that we had
okay let's get to it
like we were really lucky that we got to
do it in the right time and we did it in
the right time and
we
a lot of people made a lot of
connections and we all made a lot of
memories and we all made a lot of
friendships
but the thing we did could only happen
in the time period that it happened
and i'm glad we made it happen
welcome to the cup i'm so glad that you
made it from l.a to ny we all getting
faded all across the nation tell me who
got the best the top shelf extracts i
won't settle for the rest gotta be that
proper give me highest helicopters chest
dumping like a chopper coffin like i
need a doctor talking slow like a
mobster leaning low in my chair thinking
what should i hit next
[Music]
where's my number have you seen it
that's the game of the event and most
will never find them either
now grab a torch
everyone's faded
fuck jeremy
nobody tell them about this
this is what you don't see at the secret
house
you