[Music]
so my family's in conventional
agriculture and I spent and spent some
time in cannabis my family gave an
opportunity to treat the alfalfa fields
essentially so I found myself looking
for dragonfly Earth medicine products at
forever flowering and I talked to Eric
and and he just bluntly told me very
clearly he's like you should find this
Elaine lady and just go listen to what
she says and just go find that
information he said this lady speaks but
nobody really understands the depth of
what she's talking about it's like if
you really want a brew tea's don't
follow recipes on the internet go find
out how to use this microscope as a tool
he says if your family farms on the line
and this is serious do this one thing
and that was pretty fantastic advice you
know as far as opportunities even to
create a business now my wife and I do
it and so just that phone calls turned
into work no not as a job a career no I
was just trying to help out the family
farm and the family had kind of seen the
end of the chemical road and it was
getting more expensive and less prospero
land so I was familiar with teas and I
had determined that there was something
beneficial going on with dragonfly and
Rocky Mountain worm company and Eric
seemed to know both of them so I called
Erik trying to find some of the products
so I could just copy what I was seeing
what seemed to be working and I was
really overwhelmed with the process of a
productive recipe because now we're not
talking about fooling around the garden
we're talking about like a family farm
it's something you know is much deeper
going on there and so I just wanted to
find a concrete answer that I could feel
comfortable in rely on and so Eric said
if that's what you're looking for you
need to just go find this woman
so that's been a pretty dramatic career
change I just functionally wanted to
learn how to use the microscope as a
tool and and how to how to actually
create this thing this woman said this
disease pressures reduction you know all
these things how do you quantify that so
that I could repeat that and at that
time it was really difficult to get in
touch with that information and get in
connection with that information she
would do three and five day workshops
but that's like like that's like a
trifold brochure I mean this woman's
been doing this for 40 years and so you
know in the beginning it was like a
10-week online you could chat with her
on Sunday and watch some videos and I
like introduced it and then she came out
with the like 16 week module that was a
mind-blower
and back when I went through you had to
find her to learn the microscope you had
to do a 2 day 2 day intensive and so it
was really difficult to even learn the
skill to quantify that this lady was
even telling the truth you know it's
hard to get to where you could sit down
and learn how to use the microscope so
when I went through it I had to take a 2
day workshop and then find somebody that
knew how to use the microscope and so I
had to befriend somebody else that was
doing this microscope thing so we could
sit down for eight hours on a Sunday and
say this is what this organism is this
is what this organ is amazing and so now
now you can do an online class and you
learn to a deeper depth than I learned
two years ago and so I've had to
continually engage to increase my my
tolerances and to stay statistically
relevant with my math and so we do that
periodically and we all check each
other's math we all count the same
sample so we stay up on that but now
people are taking these videos and
working through what took me a year and
a half to be comfortable to say my math
is correct you know it took about a year
and a half of fooling with the
microscope to say my math is
statistically correct
and now you can take a 16-week class you
can take the microscope class and I'm
seeing these younger guys they're really
intelligent finding it in six months and
being good at it and so you know the
thing is evolving faster than I can even
watch and I'm just trying to be positive
and be proactive and be a part of that
movement and you know try to help people
become self-sufficient cuz that's what
this is all about and that's why this is
so fuck I mean this information has been
around for 40 years the basis of what I
built my program on is is a paper the
lane wrote in 1987 and the organism to
organism interactions and how those
affect plant growth on a biomass level
like the quantified
[Music]