[Music]
good evening everybody thank you for
having me um I don't have a lot of time
so I'll just give you my background real
quick raised in New Jersey went to
Rucker undergraduate and then went to
Rucker medical school ated the weather
and came out here for internship and
residency and I haven't left been out
here since 1990 I did 3 years of
internship and residency at Children's
Hospital Los Angeles and stayed for a
year to be chief resident I went into
Critical Care transport and emergency
medicine after that and I did that for
about 12 13 years completely burned out
after having a child of my own trying to
be mommy during the day and doctor at
night lasts only a few years before your
endoc canabo system falls apart and you
need a mental break and during the time
that I took a leave of absence a friend
of mine developed breast cancer and her
husband called me and said we want to we
think we want to go get medical cannabis
she's really suffering with the
treatment and this was in 2ou late 2007
early 2008 and I was ashamed to say that
I knew nothing other than what I
experienced back in college which was
not MediCal at all so I decided and
since I had time and I'm I'm a science
geek I decided to do my research and
sure enough I was astounded once you
start reading and looking you will find
some incredible things it's criminal
that that I'm one of the few doctors
that knows this it's sad that all you
guys are here and there's are there any
doctors in the audience I mean come on
where are we you know so um I decided to
go into practice I joined a very nice
professional practice in Long Beach and
then ended up um buying Cana centers
which is um my practice I also do some
medical Consulting for a group called
ghost group and um they've been very
supportive so that I can keep my prices
down so that I can see patients for one
fee and then take care of them for a
whole year they do a lot they subsidize
and they don't ask me for very much at
all so it's a pretty uh they're kind of
a behind the-scenes group so we're going
to talk about the endocannabinoid system
I'm going to go fast if you have
questions at the end feel free to
approach me or um email me I have some
cards too if you have questions so
basically you have to remember that
people used cannabis for thousands and
thousands of years as a medicine they
saw it as a medicine and then what
happened in the late 1930s early 1940s
is that for political and economic
reasons mostly uh there was uh
propaganda against cannabis and it
basically got taken off of kind of the
medical uh formulary and was made
illegal and then fast forward to 1970
controlled substance act but in the
meanwhile in Israel in 1964 as you can
see uh Dr Rafael mulam who's still
around today doing cannabis research
he's really a tremendous uh contributor
to all of this he was trying to figure
out what compound in the plant made
people feel the psychoactive effects and
so he isolated in his very crude 1964
lab THC from CBD and from some of the
other compounds and he gave isolated THC
to young healthy men and sure they felt
the psychoactive effects he gave CBD to
young healthy men and they didn't feel
anything and some of the other compounds
as well and nobody felt psychoactivity
so he achieved his goal which was to
find out what caused psychoactivity but
remember that that was in 1964 you know
just a few years later controlled
substance act shuts down a lot of
research and we really didn't know how
THC worked for another 24 years and in
1988 scientists discovered this little
guy right here called
um uh the endoc canabo receptor or uh
cannabinoid receptor and initially that
was actually a a known receptor remember
a receptor acts like a lock and the
chemical key has to come along and
unlock it okay so scientists had
actually seen this receptor and they had
tried different compounds different keys
and they couldn't figure out what it was
so they called it an orphan receptor
because it didn't have a key and then in
another research lab elsewhere someone
decided to take synthetic THC and
radioactive dbel it and follow it in a
rat's brain and lo and behold THC went
every time to that orphan receptor so
they changed the name from Orphan
receptor to cannabinoid receptor what
scientists knew at the time very smart
scientists is that we do not have
receptors in our body for something that
exists outside our body we must have a
chemical key inside our body that works
at that receptor so it was in the
looking for how THC worked we found
basically the endoc canabo system now it
took four years you could see I write it
right here
1992 there was the discovery of the
first Endo canabo Endo from within like
endorphins okay and it took them four
years to discover it because it's a
fat-based molecule and they were looking
for a water-based molecule so it took
them a little while but they did find it
and lo and behold in 1992 they found the
first endoc canabo called anandamide and
then subsequently five endoc canabo have
been found in humans next
slide what is the role of the
endocannabinoid
system from
1988 1992 when all of this research was
taking place if you looked at how much
research there was on THC and CBD you
know there was just a few little studies
here and there since then it is hundreds
of thousands of papers have been looked
at because this was a receptor that once
it was mapped out they realized it's the
most widespread receptor in your body
and most doctors don't even know that it
exists most people don't know that it
exists in this research they discovered
and a tremendous amount of research has
been done just in the last 20 25 years
that the role of the endoc canabo system
is to maintain balance within the cell
of your brain and your body and balance
is called
homeostasis and so what the cannabinoid
system does is it sends signals between
cells to balance the neurotransmitters
so you can see in the brain it controls
and helps to balance cognition motor
control emotional response and motivated
behavior and in the body mostly immune
function but also gastrointestinal
microcirculation and the autonomic
nervous
system okay in this slide please don't
be uh over dazzled by it it's very
simple here's a neuron and it's talking
to this neuron by sending
neurotransmitters so dopamine
norepinephrine um serotonin and so on
and notice they have their own receptors
if it's an over me uh too much message
it's usually too much sometimes not
enough but usually it's an excitatory
message your brain is firing think about
anxiety epilepsy ADHD autism right too
much message actually disrupts the cell
and makes the calcium go up when the
calcium goes up this is a plus sign
turns on the factory that makes your
body's natural marijuana like substance
which then spins up here key in the lock
to send the message to turn it down turn
it down if anybody's used cannabis you
know for many people it turns down
anxiety it turns off pain now there are
other ways that it works it can turn on
things too like hunger
but but basically remember what it's
doing is it's trying to say hey cell
turn it down it's like me knocking on my
15-year-old's door and saying turn your
music down that's basically what your
endoc canabo system is doing and
remember that the receptor itself does
not know the difference between
your uh endocan canabo the one you make
within or the cannabinoids from the
plant and that is why many people can
achieve um medical use of cannabis
without feeling over psycho Ive and so
on which I I'm not against but many
people do find a nice balance because
they figure out the dose that just kind
of puts them right back in so really the
way I like to think about the endoc
canabo system is that you're a boat in
the ocean and you start to tip and your
endoc canabo system kicks in and
balances you that's really what the job
is this is one of my favorite quotes
it's by an Italian researcher who's has
done tremendous work Vincenzo demarzo
and it says the endoc canabo system is
essential to life and it relates
messages that affect how we relax eat
sleep forget and
protect so receptor location those
receptors are not on every cell they're
only on certain cells and if you look at
the slide and this is pretty well laid
out on the internet if you want to do
more research you can see pain memory
stress learning appetite higher
cognitive function movement and over
there I think that's nauseum vomiting
remember in the brain stem right here is
where you control heart rate and
respirations there are no receptors in
that area of the brain there are opiate
receptors but no cannabinoid receptors
and that's why nobody turns off their
breathing or their heart rate with even
the hugest overdose of cannabis it may
be trippy but you won't
die there's also cannabinoid receptors
from the neck down and actually they've
also found these second type in certain
areas of the brain and what's
interesting is this slide shows you the
density so red and yellow is the highest
density you can see they're everywhere
right um highest concentration in the
immune system so spleen tonsils your
thymus your white blood cells and
basically they Med mediate the way your
body responds to its environment so cyto
kindes can cause inflammation and that
is why we know cannabis to be a very
potent
anti-inflammatory they're also found on
certain cells in the brain the micro of
the brain just think of those as like
the pacmen that clean up inside your
brain they're not the neurons but they
are the cells that help clean up and
they also have cannabinoid receptors in
the gut um cannabinoid receptors
modulate inflammation and also uh they
mediate uh pain response in the
peripheral nervous system next
slide now in uh 2003 Dr Ethan rouso
who's a very well-known very
proliferative can uh medical cannabis
specialist he's a neurologist by trade
he floated this idea of people possibly
having a clinical endoc aboid deficiency
what if the same way diabetics type 1
diabetics don't make
insulin people with hypothyroidism don't
make thyroid hormone what if you don't
make your natural endoc can abinoid how
does that manifest and it turns out that
research just in the last 10 years has
shown that all of these diseases listed
here there is scientific evidence to
show that there's an endoc canabo
deficiency or
dysfunction that is May causing these I
will tell you that I have migraine
patient after migraine patient coming
into my office finding incredible
results fibromyalgia hands down I have
patients getting off hardcore opiates
and all kinds of pain medications
irritable bowel syndrome and I just want
to tell everybody that migraine
fibromyalgia and irritable bowel are
three um conditions where and I'm sorry
to the men in the room but male doctors
say oh you know she's one of those women
it's in her head well it is in your head
it's your end cannabinoid system ask
them if they've ever heard of that
it's so other conditions as well um
chronic motion anorexia ftt is failure
to thrive in in babies you have to have
a um normal functioning endoc canabo
system for a baby to suckle um anxiety
depression Parkinson's Huntington's
schizophrenia and the list goes on and
on and this is a big area of research of
course you know pharmaceutical companies
want to come up with a pharmaceutical
that's going to work at that receptor
but you know I say why recreate the
wheel Mother Nature has what we
need all right so I'm going to talk just
very briefly about receptors um the
number of receptors that you have can
change in response to the environment so
people who are sick seizures Crohn's
disease nerve pain sleep deprived rats
have been shown that in these types of U
medical conditions or Environmental
stress is your body makes more receptors
it's like your body saying Feed me more
cannaboid so I can get the boat Back in
Balance okay uh very interesting study
since someone brought up autism I think
this was uh 2013 they drew white blood
cells a regular blood test from children
with autism and children without autism
and across the board children with
autism in their white blood cells part
of their immune system they had
increased number of canabo receptors and
I'm seeing tremendous results for a
number of my patients with
autism so again the increase in
receptors is thought to be protective
it's like the cells are just saying
please send more
canabo downregulation of receptors is
the opposite if you overstimulate the
receptor what basically happens is the
receptor remember I showed you it's
sitting on the cell wall it can get
pulled into the cell if it's being
inundated usually with THC and so that's
how tolerance builds up because your
receptors basically hide inside the
cells waiting for the all clear and
that's why when people take a break from
Cannabis and then they come back to it
say oh my gosh it's so strong well
that's because all your receptors popped
out most people don't realize this but
there was a study done where they took
chronic heavy users and they mapped out
their receptors and they had very few
receptors compared to somebody who I
call cannabis naive who's never used
cannabis before and they took those uh
people volunteers and locked them in a
lab where they made them abstain and get
a scan every seven days and by day 28
they had the same amount of receptors as
a cannabis naive so I have patients that
say oh I took a 5-month break if you
need to psychologically that's fine but
physiologically based on your um cells
28 days 30 days usually does the trick
for you um establish your uh receptor
count to normal most many of my patients
with severe medical conditions can't go
that long so we tell them even 2 or 3
days a break in between will take uh
will help your receptors um let's see if
there's anything else oh um what I
wanted to say here otherwise is oh The
receptors can be uh you can develop
tolerance at different parts of your
brain so some people come and say well I
don't feel I still get high but it's not
helping my pain well so the part of the
brain that's feeling the psychoactive
effect is still working but the
receptors in the part that are receiving
pain may actually be developing
tolerance it's not tolerance all around
the same it's different parts can
develop tolerance nobody's really
explained why that happens
yet and then um down regulation so
receptors hiding in the cells can be
advantageous for those that require high
doses so if you don't mind me talking
about Sophie uh little Sophie who has a
brain tumor she's on high doses of THC
that's good she it's good that she
developed tolerance cuz now the the
Cannabis can work to fight the cancer
but not like wipe her out all day where
she's sleeping the whole day so she
actually has tolerance to that but for
most people like I said if you're not
getting the pain response that you want
because you're overdoing that's a
disadvantage um I recommend to people
you know it's very individual what are
we treating uh where are we going what's
the goal and so um for me I recommend
patients to um uh maintain sensitive
receptors and then I joke around that
I'm going to make a t-shirt that says
respect your your receptors um so it's
been shown that low Doses and acute
doses what acute doses mean is just not
all the time um actually enhances the
way your endoc canabo system works if
you feed the system and are nice to it
it works better and so it's been shown
that low doses acute doses of THC
increase production of your natural
endoc canabo so you may be deficient but
your body may actually run a little bit
better once you start using low doses of
C of THC it also increases the number of
The receptors it increases the way the
receptors bind to the THC so that
they're actually a little bit more
sensitive to it and then in rats it's
been shown that just low doses compared
with medium doses or high doses actually
enhanced the pain relief because when
they measured the endoc canabo in those
animals compared to the start of the
study in the end they had extra canabo
that they made on their own um so by
just feeding the system you can widen
the own uh the system actually widen
widens its own therapeutic window um if
cannabis use is below a certain
threshold you get this response if it's
over that then sometimes you know you
get into that tolerance
issue thank
you now um I always joke around about
this but the difference between THC and
CBD is very important THC likes the
receptor it's monogamous to to the
receptor okay CBD is a promiscuous
molecule I didn't make that up I stole
it from a a researcher but I love it it
works at lots of different places it has
some effect on the receptor but it
really has non-abo receptor effects that
really explain why it is such a
profound um medical molecule and so I've
listed here and I don't want to I know
we don't have that much time but there's
not a lot of affinity for The receptors
but it it modulates how other compounds
bind to the receptor specifically THC it
blocks certain nononono receptors it
activates certain nononono receptors one
of which is the Gaba receptor if you
know anything about Gaba Gaba promotes
calmness anti-anxiety and CBD binds to
that receptor it inhibits the uptake of
some neurotransmitters so your natural
neurotransmitters may hang around a
little bit longer it modulates the flow
of ions like sodium and calcium through
the cells um it inhibits the
enzyme um and this is wrong I wrote the
right the wrong thing here it inhibits
the enzyme that breaks down your natural
cannabinoids so when your body releases
that canabo and it binds to the receptor
an enzyme comes along and comes along
and breaks it down right away CBD blocks
that enzyme so your natural endoc canabo
can work a little bit longer at that
receptor and give a longer response um
very very important because I hear a lot
of people not understanding this you can
develop tolerance to THC why why because
it works at that receptor and the
receptor pulls into the cell there is no
evidence scientifically of tolerance to
CBD and I have lots of patients that
once they find their dose of CBD they
can stay there for a very long
time so I wanted to just include the
slide because this is a big area of
Interest right now what about the
endocannabinoid system in different age
groups right so we know a normal
functioning endoc canabo system is
critical for fetal development actually
implanting into the uterus you have to
have a normal endoc canabo system and
there's some evidence to show in animals
that if you if animals Mis carry they
may have an endoc canabo deficiency so
by giving them canabo they actually can
carry um pups to uh term but if you have
a normal endocannabinoid system and you
use cannabis you actually might get the
opposite effect so it's always the state
of the person or the animal that's using
cannabis you know we're not all the same
we all start from a different Baseline
um normal functioning endoc canabo
system is critical for Advanced Brain
development in adolescence you know
everybody I I've been interviewed how
can you promote this there's teenagers
you know I have a teenager in my house
he can tell you the difference between
THC and CBD what the indications are and
he's already told me I'm curious mom but
I'm going to wait because you know what
my brain's good and I've said to him if
you get sick you know we're going to use
this medicine but you're not sick so
just wait and he keep keeps asking me
what age again mom what age so but he's
15 and so far we're good I told him that
I have like um a drug dog's nose so I
can sniff it out
so um so now one interesting thing is
that in children there's some evidence
to show that their canono receptors are
not fully uh developed so they may
actually be fairly insensitive to the
psychoactivity of THC and I will tell
you that my adult cancer patients have
way more trouble tolerating highd does
th than my pediatric cancer patients and
so there's no question that that's that
happens and then in aging and this is
very interesting remember as the brain
ages there's accumulation of free
radicals and damaged molecules and neur
what we call neuroinflammation and we
start to lose cell function we all know
elderly people who struggle a little bit
and what's interesting is that um some
initial research uh Recent research is
showing that um activity at the endoc
canabo system feeding that system
actually helps protect the Aging brain
and slows down some of the aging
process all right so how do you take
care of your own endoc canabo system and
encourage people around you to take care
of it obviously chronic stress impairs
your cannabinoid system by decreasing
your body's natural endoc canabo levels
so what I call mindful stress reduction
meditation yoga deep breathing there's
some evidence to show that that is
helpful obviously exercise with some of
us are programmed to do and some of us
are not moderate to high-intensity
voluntary exercise increases your endoc
canabo levels and there's some evidence
that show that actually the runner High
may be endoc canabo and not
endorphins dietary omega-3 fatty acids
so of course in the United States our
diet is high in the Omega 6 fatty acids
which you have to have but you don't
want it at a very high ratio you want
your Omega 6 and omega3 to be um to be
like a 3:1 or a 2:1 but most people are
like a 10 to one so supplementing I have
all of my patients that have severe
illness I get them on uh a dietary
supplement of Omega-3 and that's one of
I I don't tell people to get a huge
amount of supplements because it gets
very difficult to take a lot of things
when you're sick but that is definitely
something that will help the endoc
canabo system function better there's
evidence in animals that social
interaction increases your endoc canabo
system and then um there's a number of
intervention so probiotic acupuncture
osteopathic manipulation and uh kumin
which is in turmeric which is
anti-inflammatory have all been shown to
enhance endoc canabo activity and
obviously chronic alcohol use in binge
drinking decreases the endoc canabo
system and can actually affect it
negatively that's not a glass of wine a
night we're talking about people who are
overdoing all right and then the last
slide I just want to show you this I was
um honored to be able to participate
I'm not selling anything because I get
no money from this but I was asked to be
part of the faculty uh Dr Deborah Mala
up in um Santa Cruz who's part of a
group that I belong to called The
Society of cannabis clinicians developed
a 12 module CME credit and I believe
nurses can get credit as well to for
this um program and you just go online
and it's an online program and you sign
up it's a little pricey but I will tell
you it's worth every dime it's 12
modules plus a few extra modules and you
can go back through them it's
interactive um uh the uh faculty speaks
and you can you know hit play and hit
pause and do whatever and then there's
uh credits at the end and you can print
out a certification uh at the end
basically you know every um cannabis
expert that's standing out now um
including Dr Abrams Dr um Dustin sulak
in Maine um Dr Mala have all part
participated and it's a fantastic thing
and I'm going to tell you just in in
summary here that in my experience and
to answer one of the questions that you
brought up to what what's one of the
biggest barriers is that people who are
sick and people who have loved ones are
open-minded I cannot figure out why my
colleagues in the medical field are so
close-minded it is drives me insane and
I'll say what's an endoc canabo do you
know about the endoc canabo system and
when it's oneon-one
it's with me they're very open but as
you all well know there's a lot of ego
in the medical community and it's very
hard to break through so you know if you
have a doctor that is questioning and
saying well yeah sure you can use
cannabis and then they don't know
anything about it give them this website
say there's this wonderful you can get
CME credit which you need to have for
your medical licensing and they can use
this so that they have some basic
knowledge I find that most of my
patients know more than any doctor I
come across and it it's kind of getting
depressing and so we really have to push
uh the Physicians um by saying we need
you in this fight this is when I was in
medical school I was taught cannabis is
a drug of abuse it is not a drug of
abuse it is a very therapeutic drug and
we have to undo some of that
brainwashing so I encourage all of you
to take this website and to share it
with whoever you can share it with so um
and so that's
[Applause]
my limited understanding even though I
was Premed 40 years
ago um is that I mean I did not know
that we had an actual cannaboid system
in our body until tonight okay um it's
different than the Endorphin is what
you're saying right it is it is but it
interacts acts with the uh endorphin
system so it's here to produce when it's
properly working to produce a s a state
of homeostasis for us cor it is and what
it does and which I you know I couldn't
include everything but what I'll tell
you is that your endoc canabo system
sits a little dormant until there's a
trigger which is imbalance and then it
brings it back up so you make those
endorphins in response to a trigger
inflammation injury illness and that
kind of thing okay and so that from a
medicinal standpoint um when it gets
into a severe state of deficiency or the
presence of disease is when you need to
introduce external cannabis to to get
the system Back in Balance again yes I
wouldn't say extreme deficiency I mean I
see people who are coming yeah
sufficient deficiency right and some
people come in and say I have migraines
fibromyalgia irritable bow I know they
have an endoc canabo deficiency they've
taken 15 different medicines that don't
work and they say oh my friend gave me a
cannabis edible I've had the best in my
life well I mean you know where does it
work it's not magic fairy dust it worked
at the endoc can avonoid system so they
did their own test to figure out what
their deficiency
is El over there which
one hi I um my name is deay by the way
SP um I was I've read some research
where they've done um just research
where they've given people just THC or
just CBD and to see how it works and
they found that just TBD on its own
doesn't work unless there's some THC and
vice versa and I was wondering if you
might be able to speak a little bit
about the Synergy between both sure and
that's a great question because that's
what's holding up the pharmaceutical
companies from reproducing this is
they're interested in single molecule
the cannabinoid plant the cannabis plant
has 400 different compounds and Dr mulam
Who has been studying this for you know
as long as I've been alive he basically
discovered that each compound has its
own medicinal properties but when added
together it is very much much enhanced
and what he named that is called the
Entourage effect you need all of those
compounds to get the benefits so right
now we're seeing some pharmaceutical CBD
on the market uh it's from a company
called GW Pharmaceuticals in Great
Britain they're producing um a drug
called epidex for Pediatric epilepsy
they've removed all the THC now for some
patients it does work but not the same
we don't we're not seeing the same uh
success as what we're seeing with what
is called whole plant extract you want
the whole plant you wouldn't take an
apple and pull out one little vitamin
out of it you eat the whole apple right
this is Mother Nature it doesn't fit the
business model for pharmaceutical
companies and so that is why we
shouldn't treat it like a pharmaceutical
it should be treated as its own special
category so with that with that in
effect I've been
I've had um some friends who've had
people back East who are very very sick
and they're being you know whether it's
cancer or Crohns or liver whatever the
the the gist is is that they're being
given synthetic
marijuana Marisol or something Marinol
Marinol what Marinol is is just isolated
synthetic THC and they're not getting
the same results no and what happens
with with isolated uh THC is you either
get really stoned and it's uncomfortable
what we call
dysphoria or you don't get any result at
all I mean I had a patient tell me it's
like eating M&amp;M's he didn't feel it at
all the fact that they were saying that
they didn't even they were hoping they'd
feel something and some patients that
they got it some patients do get the
nausea reduction and the appetite
Improvement which is what it's indicated
for but if you compare and there is a uh
very elderly psychiatrist at Harvard by
the name of Lester grinspoon if you ever
get a chance you should Google him he
says anybody given a choice between the
two who's tried between the two will
always 100% pick the whole plant extract
over an isolated
synthetic so in your position then you
would you would not ever condone the
synthetic verision because you don't see
the results as POS I live in California
so I don't have to use synthetic
canas and I have patients who live live
I mean I do see sometimes see out of
state patients who are very desperate I
cannot tell you how frustrating it is
when somebody gets a CBD only product
because they have these stupid CBD only
laws I understand it may be a foot in
the door but politicians want to stop
there they there's millions of people
that can benefit from Cannabis and CBD
only cuts that down and that is not how
it should be and so those patients say
well CBD didn't work what would you do
well I'd add THC and try to find the
balance between the two compounds I
understand we may not want big psycho
activity especially in a child but at
the same time we can find a balance
between how much CBD and how much THC
that will work for that particular
person there's there's no reason to
discard THC it is medicinal it makes me
crazy when people say it's recreational
it is medicinal it can be recreational
but so can B it in and alcohol and all
these other
things thank you all right I think we
got time for one more here you want do
it take
it so I I'm sorry I have a cold um I've
done a lot of research and my
understanding is hemp versus marijuana
hemp has more CBD less
THC and cannabis has THC more THC less
cannabis so I was told that if I wanted
to not get high I should look at hemp
and hemp oil as opposed to cannabis okay
great question lot of confusion about
what is hemp and what is cannabis and
basically it boils down to the genetics
of the plant which nobody talks about
you don't hear about that in a
collective or in a doctor's office but
basically Cannabis sativa is actually a
hemp fibrous and cannabis indicia is
really programmed to make more THC
however everybody thinks it's the other
way around and so and there's a lot of
confusion what you have to remember is
go back to the Entourage effect you want
every part of the plant that you can
have and I didn't even get into What's
called the terpenoids cuz there isn't
time but you wouldn't want to take just
a piece of the cannabis plant hemp is a
very good nutritional source of Omega
fatty acids I encourage people it's it's
like a bonus nutrition product and
everybody should incorporate it hemp oil
hemp Parts whatever but I do not see it
as quote medicine it can enhance your
end cannabinoid system but if you are a
sick person you should be using the
cannabis plant that makes both THC and
CBD what you have to remember is that
freedom to grow cannabis in California
now we're going on 20 years of medical
legalization right and what's happened
is that with that freedom to grow people
have been Crossing strains and so on in
that um growing of cannabis what has
happened is everybody wants to max out
the high THC you know everybody like my
car has more torque than your car if
that even makes sense but it's more THC
at the sacrifice of CBD so if you go and
look at any uh test results of cannabis
99% of the plants in California are 20%
THC
0.02% CBD but what's happened over the
last few years because of kind of the
media attention to CBD and the and the
scientific knowledge that is come out is
that we now recognize that we need to
have some CBD as balance in these plans
and I find that my patients look I have
lots of patients that do really well on
THC but if they come in and say well my
pain you know I kind of distracted from
and it's not really helping and I ask
them what they're using invariably
they're using all THC with no CBD and if
we add in CBD they're going to get
better results because it's kind of been
bred down and now we're talking about
bringing it back so we've kind of come
Circle back to what Mother Nature may
have meant with some CBD one other thing
about hemp it's very important is hemp
is considered is a plant um that's
considered a bioaccumulator which means
that it sucks up a lot from the ground
and it can suck up heavy metals I've
actually had patients come in who have
gotten cannabis tested and there's some
nasty stuff in there the FDA if you go
to the FDA which is not my favorite
group but um if you go to their website
they actually have a list list of
products that are supposedly hemp CBD
products and most of them don't even
have any CBD in them because there
really isn't any regulation of what's
going on the the hemp that you would buy
at you know a grocery store usually is
is somebody's bothering to make it right
the hemp right now unregulated that's
available in some collectives is not
regulated you're better off just going
and buying and adding that if you want
medicine I recommend a medical cannabis
plant with some tested ratio of THC to
CBD what's the ratio it depends on what
illness you have so a lot of my epilepsy
patients use high CBD low THC a recent
study of patients with um neuropathic
pain nerve pain and chronic pain they
found four to one CBD is always first
okay so four parts CBD to one part THC
seem to work across the board for many
chronic pain patients some patients may
find that still a little psychoactive so
you could bump up on the CBD a little
bit I have a lot of patients that use
high CBD during the day so that they're
not feeling under the influence they can
still drive their car go to work take
care of their kids and then at night
they use a higher THC product so that
they can get sleep and relax and get a
little bit more pain
relief oh one more sure all right one
more you want to ask yeah yeah sorry I
can talk to you
after um yes my question is then is
followup to that uh when making your
whole whole plant extract how critical
is it that it's all in the same plant or
can you mix extracts from different
plants like say you have a a high CBD
strain and then a higher THC strain
would that still be the same effect or
would it be beneficial if you just have
a single plant extract so that's a great
question so the amount of THC is going
to be the amount of THC in that plant if
you add more to it you just add it up
the big difference is the other oils
that are in the plant called the
terpenoids which you may have heard of
when you're looking at terpenoids
remember so I'll just share one one
example a turpenoid is essential oil
found in the plant and it's cross
species with other plants meaning you
can find a turpenoid called linol in
lavender we all know Lavender is kind of
common linol is also found in certain
strains of cannabis many of them have a
name that hints towards lavender like
purple purple princess granddaddy purple
purple haze so sometimes the names
aren't just stupid they actually refer
to what the plant is so if you mix
though you know something with linol was
something with mirene you may not know
exactly unless you measure it you may
not know exactly what end result you're
going to get okay and so you know I'm
all for the regulation so that people
can walk into a collective and see how
much THC how much CBD solvents
pesticides and the turpenoid profile cuz
if I know I need linol I don't want to
buy a plant that doesn't have any linol
in it right so that is just just the
same way food food is labeled and my
doctor says you know eat more calcium
eat more fiber you want to look at
labels you want to be able to know you
know does Artic chokes how what do they
have I look on the internet and I can
see so it's the same thing with these
plants and this is completely doable
it's just California kind of got it
backwards we legalized first and then
didn't really regulate the way we should
have thank you
[Applause]
oh
[Music]