yeah we're running a european-wide say
research called the 4/20 poll we are
collecting a consumer data and these
data are we gonna use to to convince
governments to make better regulations
better laws which suits the needs of the
cannabis consumer nice and how you are
planning to do that like what is your
strategy strategy well we used to do
this in in the Netherlands we had a
research done with 9000 people and that
data has been used to convince the Dutch
government to finally regulate the
growing in the Netherlands so I should
probably know where for 40 years we have
the coffee shops in the Netherlands you
can bike you can buy weeds but it was
not allowed to grow and now legislation
is coming through which makes also the
growing possible basis with partly
thanks to the data that we have provided
and well there's a lot of things going
on in Europe on the regulation side and
so we are also collecting now as
throughout Europe the same data to use
that to convince European governments to
to regulate the recreational cannabis
you can fill out the questionnaire at
420 poles calm