[Music]
this is what should be a very lively
discussion on who's winning and who's
losing in the cannabis economic climate
of California so my name is Andre Burke
and I was born at age zero and have
successfully survived as a living
organism long enough to become a Forbes
contributor and connector in the
industry my name is Tim Schafer I'm a
deputy state treasurer and the office of
treasurer at John Chiang I was the
primary staff to the treasurer's 17
member cannabis banking working group
which produced the material that
Hezekiah referred to obliquely in the
last panel and I'll have a couple of
things to say about that
at an appropriate moment my name is Matt
human I'm an attorney I've been involved
in cannabis since the mid 90s in San
Francisco I have been involved in a lot
of fights including the most recent one
which we'll be discussing today about
how the CHP grabbed my client and took
$230,000 and gave it to someone from the
Immigration and Citizenship Services
we'll talk about what that is about and
I'm a senior partner in Allen cumin and
associates which is a political
consulting firm and forecasting firm on
cannabis issues and I'm also the
director of a think tank called
California cannabis educational voice
Foundation which was responsible for
some of the work you saw up in Humboldt
County and its passage of its ordinance
and I'm very pleased to be here and
thank you susan Soares for inviting me
and for him doing such a wonderful job
on this event thank you
hi everyone my name is Mac young I'm
with a pop media we put TVs and iPads
and dispensaries all over California
once again Thank You Susan wherever she
went
this is beautiful glad to be here
I also am on the border directors of
glocca which is the Greater Los Angeles
collective Association which represents
about thirty five of the legal
dispensaries in Los Angeles as well as
the UC ba and the SCC hi my name is bo
Whitney I'm vice president and senior
economists for new frontier data new
frontier data is the global leader and
big data analytics specifically focused
in the cannabis space we've been
referenced in 68 countries five billion
page views and our goal is to provide
data that's well vetted actionable
nonpartisan non advocacy for policy
makers operators and investors hello
everyone my name is Fran Turner I'm the
Senior Managing Partner of seven past
global we are a hybrid hedge fund and
private equity fund focused particularly
in the non plant touching but
additionally we do investments on the
plant side our first fund is actually a
dual fund second fund is non plant
touching and we're also launching the
world's first security token that's
focused on a tokenized to fund I'd like
to mention before we get started we
originally had two women prepared for
this panel they were unfortunately
unable to make it but I know that's
important in this industry and so we'll
have an all-male panel this time so last
month I part of the reason I was
selected for this panel as I sent a
social media post and I was asking to
speak relating to an article about with
companies who were thriving under the
medical marijuana model and who are now
struggling under legalization I posted
it to Instagram Facebook and Twitter and
I received 50 responses within the day
45 Facebook shares and it was to the
point where I had to set up a Google
Form and a survey to collect all the
information one of the things we'll be
doing here today is I'll be sharing some
of those stories as
we get into each topic one of the
replies I got was it shouldn't have to
be a fight to stay out of jail and keep
my own property and business but that's
how it is now I guess is the second time
offender within the span of two years
after legalization I'm looking at one
year in jail and I need to forfeit my
business in my property so at the same
time I'm getting it's on my email and
I'm listening on the radio and there's a
commercial selling register they say for
our online course find out everything
you need to know to make money in the
cannabis industry now I'm not going to
identify who actually put out that
commercial but they're on this boat and
they're on the next floor so that's the
dichotomy we have with what the promises
are around this industry and what the
reality is like to begin with Matt young
of a pod is the California cannabis
industry really a get rich scheme
anymore unfortunately not I'm in the
position to where I talked to
dispensaries every day brands every day
and sorry businesses every day and
unfortunately it gets harder and harder
to even survive let alone make money
raising capital is one issue but on top
of that with the dispensaries
is that is that better
okay sorry guys on the dispensary side
the regulations on the distribution side
there's testing issues packaging issues
on if you're a cultivator a manufacturer
you're moving into new buildings you're
buying new equipment you're moving into
new cities because unfortunately a lot
of the cities where they were located
before they are not issuing licenses and
they're having to upend their whole
business and even companies that are ten
years old that are very well-established
large companies are you know
experiencing growing beans to where
they're a 10 year old startup and no one
is getting rich right now but that's
okay you know the the cream will rise to
the top and everyone buckles down and
works hard and you know this is just the
very beginning of a very long journey
I think if I can add that if we look at
just American statistics in general so
eighty percent of companies survive
their first year fifty percent of
companies are business within five years
and if you apply that tax you're
regulated businesses it's more twenty
percent actually survive so again it's
lack of capital collectively and
obviously this is intensified by limited
bank lending again a scarce both venture
prime an empty market is this today but
also just operations in regards to
regulated businesses so on top of if we
talked about California specifically
because of legislation moving at a bit
more slowly what's happening is that
other companies from other states or
other countries are also moving in and
they are also well capitalized so
therefore they're actually cannibalizing
somewhat because of see market so again
it's an evolution it's a large market
but it's definitely a longer play than a
shorter play but the 80/20 rule will
still be lickable most folks who are in
what they call the legacy market i guess
it's been referred to haven't really and
even the large capital coming in don't
understand the market trends and how
everything's moving towards biomass and
the incredible amount of fragmentation
and slices of the market
whether it's distilling winterizing all
the you know extraction all designed to
address this massive increase in
extracted products is what I call it
someone have may have a different
nomenclature so what I think and I've
seen this even with you know wealthy
capital folks coming in and even with my
cannabis guys you know Hezekiah and I
went you know go back to the humble
growers they don't really understand
that and haven't caught up yet
to that real reality of where the
markets going and the individuals you
know I can segment out just in the
extraction industry probably seven or
eight different sub markets and people
aren't seeing that yet and I think
that's gonna make a huge difference in
the statistic which I agree with that
it's you know something like two-thirds
or three-quarters of folks are gonna go
out of business even if they had been in
business before so in North America
between the 2015 and 2017 roughly six
billion dollars was invested in the
cannabis area a lot of the money that I
see being made is not necessarily in the
plant touching sphere it's the picks and
shovels and so the greenhouse providers
the soil the nutrients those folks that
don't necessarily depend upon the plant
touching side of the of the industry and
aren't subject to 280e taxation etc and
depending upon the risk profiles of the
investors there's there's been a large
amount of inflows on cultivation and
retail but there's also been a lot of
inflows on real estate and software and
so depending upon where the investors
minds are at the risk tolerance they're
going to either go with the plant
touching and go all-in or they're gonna
invest in the ancillary businesses
conversation we didn't really complete
is one on banking and that's that's why
it's a pleasure here to have tim schafer
with us the california deputy treasurer
public finance i want to share with
everyone what one company wrote me so
this is bloom box and
these these folks provide b2b software
as product as a service and they said
legalization didn't help us with
investment capital because there's no
way to safely bank or insure these
investment funds smaller investors
cannot incur risk and larger v-type VC
type investors are still bound by
so-called vice clauses commonly embedded
in their partnership agreements that
prohibit even indirect investments in
federally scheduled substances is this
really instruct Lee a Schedule one issue
a complex question with an equally
complex answer let me start let me start
start here banking banking many
businesses is a question of a banker
being able to engage in reasonable risk
management let me give you an example
that has nothing to do with cannabis
many banks will refuse to open accounts
for check cashing services for horse
racing tracks for payday auto lenders
for cardrooms why because often these
organizations can mask occult activities
which will create regulatory risk for
the bank so they avoid it now notice
that it's perfectly legal to be in the
cardroom business or to run a horse
racing track assuming you've got
licenses from your locality to do that
introduced the notion of cannabis a
federally scheduled truck and then the
problem begins to metastasize the
problem metastasizes in this way in my
view bankers are risk averse
and if this is a risk management
business the default position can easily
become risk avoidance rather than risk
management if there is no clear pathway
to economics that would work that
introduces the next facet of the risk
and that is because there is this
growing wave in our nation to discuss
Canopus the fact that it may be d
scheduled scares the bank's why well
because they can set up an apparatus
that will require a great deal of
investment only to look up and discover
that we're now off scheduled one and
we're back in the same category as a
card room or a racetrack and so forth
and therein is I think one of the
Rubik's cubes that need to be solved one
of the things that I would encourage you
all to become familiar with hezekiah
mentioned this in the last panel is this
document right here I'm not going to
read it to you it's available in the
state treasurer's website the title of
it is banking access strategies for
cannabis related businesses and give you
just a few seconds of what the four
primary recommendations are first at
least for the here and now develop a
system that will accommodate the cash
industry rather than trying to force it
into the business figure out a way to
accommodate the cash industry a little
bit better than we're doing we call that
inside the office the armored car bus
route strategy number 38 bus run by
Brinks that makes a scheduled stop
everywhere and picks up currency to pay
taxes and fees to the state to the local
agencies number to develop a data portal
those of you who are familiar with the
Washington system
know that the cannabis control mechanism
in that state ar-ar-ar figuratively
speaking kind of bolted on the framework
that was used for liquor control number
three investigate the feasibility of
establishing a state backed financial
institution that would cater to or
accommodate the industry I hope I get
questions on that later and then finally
in this to me is the big one develop a
consortium of bankers regulators
cannabis industry folks the stakeholders
that were discussed in the last panel
that our medical customers put them
together in a group that will devote
some energy and time to lobbying federal
legislators and federal regulators about
the evolving nature of it those are the
four things you'll see in the report and
we're underway with each of those for
now and I agree with Tim I think if I
can add a little perspective from the
bank side about a year and a half ago I
ran America's fastest growing bank for a
beer two three years we grew from not
1.9 billion over 13 billion that period
of time aggregating to pause is the most
difficult thing that's possible if you
take a look at it you've got to if you
have a perspective a asking for deposits
or giving a loan obviously asking for
deposits more challenging so we need to
take higher risk strategies that bald
eb-5 broker-dealer cash businesses the
regulators are spent approximately half
of the year
so about 150 business days in our
offices and again measuring and
analyzing our high-risk businesses banks
themselves can hold 25 percent typically
if it's well-run
of their collective deposit base in
high-risk and what that means is it's a
fight for what high risk deposits can
actually sit on that balance sheet so
with that comes in here and risk the Tim
mention so and again if you take a look
at the smaller banks that are
participating they're about 300 banks
across us right now that
actually actively engaging cannabis
business to actually have a kyc an ml
program and BSA program that facilitates
it actually costs tens of thousands of
dollars if not hundreds and on top of
that if you look at these smaller banks
they don't have the technology some of
the core processing solutions to
actually interpret and understand
exactly where that money is coming from
so that entire process on an ongoing
basis ends up costing hundreds of
thousands of dollars because you need
personnel and staff to actually manage
that as well so that's the main
challenge that they're having in to
Tim's point it is very challenging and
the natural mentality the banker can be
risk averse the other side's challenge
is the actual payment side so if we
think about Visa MasterCard AB in
basically is where all the transactions
pass through if you think of every
hundred dollars it passes through AB in
only one dollar can actually be high
risk related and so by definition
cannabis is high risk so we also need to
come up with additional payment
mechanisms that will help evolve
industry so it's not only just a cash
business lately I've been saying that
we're we have two policies at play one
is to allow cannabis and the other is
prohibited and the it's impossible to
move forward unless one is gonna win and
so we're back to you have to organize
you you have to go to the legislature
the courts aren't gonna help you have to
actually force this issue and the
absurdity of the contradictions between
what is really happening and what the
population in this country wants and
ultimately Congress has to do something
about it that's my perspective I've gone
back and forth with Fiona and other
folks in the state government about a
bank and well it's a really wonderful
idea and I support it there's just too
many I think too many barriers because
of federal prohibition to allow it so
until we get Congress to do something
and this is just an old song I feel kind
of stupid keep bringing it up but until
we you know get our Congress people to
actually do something about it and
organize effectively rather than the old
left-wing firing squad you know that
joke how does the left-wing firing squad
line up in a circle and so you know
everyone's gonna have to
how to organize and work together put
the egos aside and then we got to go to
Congress because that's where ultimately
I think this has to get fixed from
personal experience our companies we've
lost to bank accounts just this month
one of the reasons was we deposited more
than five thousand dollars per month
into the account which as a business
owner having five thousand dollars
deposited in cash it's not a lot of
money especially in a cash business and
the other was because even though we ran
on plant touching business we accept
money from plant touching businesses and
that account was subsequently shut down
and right now I'm gonna have to talk to
and find one of those three hundred
banks because I have tried to open new
bank accounts and we have to put our
website down our website mentions
cannabis and we have been unable so far
we've only tried this week but we've
been unable to open a new bank account
which is very discouraging especially
for someone who has to run a business so
we'll see you know what changes we can
man I've been have to read that report
too but hopefully these rules can change
quickly because it's it's that's one
more deterrent to running a cannabis
business on top of all of everything
else thanking is also a huge challenge
so I don't know if the banks and I hate
to put a wet blanket over everybody but
I don't think the banks have an
incentive in order to enter into this
space okay so sorry about that I don't
think that banks have an incentive to
enter into this space because they the
the way that they grow their revenues
through acquisitions of other banks and
so they don't want to jeopardize those
acquisitions by entering into cannabis
space so they're deferring and staying
away from that and now I'm from Portland
Oregon
so in Oregon we have two main credit
unions that provide banking services
checking and savings five hundred
dollars a month for a checking and
savings account and that's to cover the
costs but they only have 600 accounts
total and there's over
4,400 businesses in Oregon right now
that aren't cannabis related so that's
the that kind of draws a picture of or
paints a picture of just the extent of
how little banking is offered to the
cannabis industry right now let's talk
about taxes and costs so one of the
replies that was shared with me fella
says I was on the board of Silicon
Valley Americans for safe access
San Jose imposed a tax which was a point
of contention but the real bad part was
not just a tax it was no licenses for
years and then an act an actual
crackdown and monopolies on 16
businesses just like BCC is doing now
how they evolved and how does that
monopoly come about the way that I look
at that taxation is is that taxation
really influences the amount of legal
participation in the system and if taxes
are too high then it dissuades people
from participating either from an
operator's perspective or a consumers
perspective and for example and I think
in Nevada City they had a $10 a square
foot tax on their operations so if
you're a twenty thousand and regardless
of if it's can appear or whatever so in
that sense if you're a 20,000 square
foot operation already you're paying two
hundred thousand dollars in taxes just
at the local level before you generate
any revenue before any and so that's
just it's basically and there was a
phrase that I heard here in California
it's called prohibition through
legalization and so and I that really
resonated with me because they say hey
yeah come on in
we want your tax money we're gonna tax
you until you can't operate and then
what good is it right so but consumers
and businesses are extremely price
sensitive and we've at new frontier data
we've developed models that showed just
how price sensitive consumers are and
what level of legal participation would
occur
at various tax levels we provided
testimony at the state legislature in
Sacramento on a tax reduction bill that
looked at a reduction from 15% to 11% so
fairly nominal reduction but it was
going to generate 168 million dollars in
additional retail sales 64,000 new
entrants consumers from the Elissa
market into legal market and
unfortunately that proposal was voted
down so not sure what solution I can
provide but it's very very compelling
that as consumers are price sensitive
policy makers need to adjust and develop
their tax policies accordingly you know
I mean that's a really good point and
and I think it goes back to what I
always see is that there are
contradictory policies at play and if
the government does not want consumption
for example mark Kleiman and some other
prominent policy makers are basically
you know that can Oregon how they want
it to limit you know the the amount
grown and so forth they don't want it so
they put a syntax on it and that's
really what we're seeing we're seeing
the government contradicting itself with
saying we want legalization but we
really don't and I think until that is
addressed and until there's really
policy goals that are clarified you're
going to see this I had a conversation
with Lori Ajax a few months ago and I
asked her you know where who's on your
staff doing policy like the Board of
Equalization for example has policy
people and she said well we do policy
ourselves we don't have a professional
policy maker and so to me that was a red
flag that that we're not really thinking
about policy were really you know
sweeping it under the carpet
but everything's driven by policy
everything and so unless you have that
resolve which it's not it's a
contradiction then we're going to be in
this mess so another side of the tax
issue is
leveling the playing field where legal
licensed businesses are forced to pay
all these licensing fees all of these
taxes and you have the the gray in the
black market that aren't contributing
anything to the taxes which is you know
another struggle to keep your legal
business alive and that's where
enforcement really has to come into play
- hopefully shut down the illegal
operations so it's easier for those
licensed businesses to stay open and
have a little play in field because
right now it's it's really unfair and
hard for the dispensaries and hard for
the license brands to be able to compete
with companies that aren't paying
payroll taxes but you know it's 40
percent of your business plus you've got
to e2 EU which no one's brought up yet
which is totally unfair which the
government governor just rejected that
bill so there's a lot of things we got
to work on some of you know me you've
heard me speak before I'm by no means an
apologist for banks but the the banter
you just heard is really critical to the
banking discussion as well
bankers are creatures of analysis
without clear sightlines into financial
data they don't get comfortable with
risk one of the principal sightlines
into financial data for small businesses
are tax returns 280e
essentially shoves deductible expenses
into the background for federal purposes
making it more difficult for the banker
to assess his or her risk that remains a
problem that i think it is - this
observer is a bit nonsensical if what
you're trying to do is to achieve tax
compliance that's the second thing the
second thing is that remember that to a
bank and again know of none I'm not an
apologist for banks here I'm just trying
to keep myself centered on this - a bank
taking a deposit
that deposit is your asset it is the
bank's liability the bank's liability
has to be offset with an asset that will
earn more than what the deposit is
costing it if we insist on this bizarre
mechanism of forfeiture of asset
forfeiture on federally insured
institutions what have you forced the
bank to do you've forced the bank to
take deposits from the industry but not
lend to the industry not lending to the
industry is a lower yield prospect so
you've now put the squeeze on the bank
again I'm not an apologist here I'm just
trying to report the balls and strikes
okay you've put the squeeze on the bank
at the very same time that some of our
tax policies have put the squeeze on the
industry that's struggling how to get to
the finish struggling to get to the
finish line Thanks just to size the
extent of 280e new frontier data
presented in the White House an analysis
of the 280e
looking at the entire US market over a
seven-year period cannabis businesses
pay approximately fourteen point six
billion dollars in additional taxes than
they would normally pay if they were
treated as a normal business the a
health policy adviser for a president
Trump said why would I give up fourteen
point six billion dollars in revenue and
the response to that of course is well
look at all those jobs look at all the
conversion from the illicit market look
at all of the social issues that you
address by through this legalization and
so there's obviously a net benefit to
you know the 280 tax reform but it's
going to take a lot of Education and and
a lot of additional data in order for
them to be
instead of this just a quick point if I
start talking about 280e I'll go crazy
because I was the architect and the
first guy who put the legal team
together to litigate the champ case in
the u.s. Tax Court so that's a whole
other issue that's going it hasn't even
begun to rear its ugly head yet but what
I wanted to say was that I'm talking to
people and in seeing some stirrings of
trying to get local cities or counties
to actually have citizens advocate to
have no taxes in those cities or
counties and I think that's going to
catch on if everyone can start to talk
in their communities about not imposing
taxes because you've already got the
retail sales tax in California anywhere
from seven and a half to nine and a half
percent plus the 15% state excise tax
that's 22 to 25 percent right there so
you don't need any more taxes at the
local level and you can always impose
them later if things start crack
cranking up so I think from an
organizing point of view and that's
often how I look at this as a political
organizing matter I think you have to go
to your small the City Council's and the
county boards of Supervisors and say
look and you'd be surprised how many
people don't go to these meetings or
don't meet with legislators but if you
go and say look you're gonna kill this
industry and you're gonna port your goal
of ending the black market so why don't
you look at the data the kind of data
that you're you're talking about so I
would encourage everyone to think about
finding a community maybe like Berkeley
like Dale details Berkeley that's
actually did just reduce their taxes
from was it ten to five percent or
something like that so and and and
continue to sort of push on that issue
so that would be my my two cents on that
moving on to licensing so here was a
comment that came to me I started down a
path to getting a distributor license in
San Francisco and I found insurmountable
obstacles at every turn when I was
unable to find a location suitable in
the minut areas available within San
Francisco where my activity was zoned
correctly the city asked me nicely to
shut my business down I did it was hard
I let my five employees go
and I cried a bunch eight of ten brands
I was representing last year no longer
exists in the legal market the people
behind those brands are like family to
me and they lost their livelihoods over
these new laws how far off course that
we become I think we're seeing it in
some of our portfolio activity it almost
becomes a competitive advantage to have
teams that specialize in getting
licenses so you're basically putting
together consultants bankers
professionals that specialize in those
various licenses so it's almost an
unfair competitive and regards to how
we're going about it and then it goes
back to what I originally mentioned
we're doing is leveraging companies from
other states other countries to actually
import their businesses in the state
they've got proven business models which
is part of the credibility that you need
and then they have the existing capital
so unfortunately the lack of speed at
this moment or the tardiness assemble
this licensing Negley affects the
California businesses specifically but
creates advantages for some of the out
save competition and the other part here
is where we were going after multiple
international licenses and what we are
seeing is it is an educational process
but the period appears to be somewhat
shorter than what we're seeing in
California at this point in time so from
a policy perspective it's really
difficult to balance the market versus
the free market in Oregon for example
there's one cultivation license for
every five hundred thousand dollars of
the total addressable market the total
revenue in the entire market whereas in
Florida that in an area where they have
limited licensure that's one license for
every hundred twenty-five million
dollars and so the concept here is it's
difficult for policy makers to balance
what's the sweet spot there's data out
there they just haven't asked for it
they haven't it hasn't resonated with
them because you know in such states as
Oregon and Washington you have super
saturation of supply
you have declining values declining
revenues and then people go out of
business and compounded with 280e
compounded with the lack of banking then
that's a tough nut to crack
because you know people are that's real
wealth that because friends and families
are the people that need to invest in
this so if you don't set it up correctly
then you have a chance to wipe out
individuals wealth you know to a to a
massive extent so that that's the tough
nut to crack right now and nobody's
really dialed it in quite yet so that's
another thing to talk about is wiping
out your wealth which I've experienced a
couple times and I can abyss career and
that's why I had to start a pop and not
touch this plant anymore but starting
over at zero is tough and when you look
at like the social equity programs that
they're trying to start this business
takes millions of dollars to do if you
don't have millions of dollars you've
got a team up with people that have
millions of dollars and there's
companies I've talked to on the social
equity side and it seems like they're
kind of taking advantage you know these
people have already been beat down
they've already lost everything and now
companies are going to use their you
know experience and and their arrests
and their financial ruin for their own
personal gains so that's another thing
that this the licensing it's just
another turrent for you know the regular
guy everyone wants to be a part of this
industry and that regular person who has
all this experience who loves the plant
loves the industry you know he's got an
uphill battle to to try and really
participate and succeed so hopefully you
know events like this can get people
educated get people to meet other people
you know that can help them raising
capital help them get licensed all those
kind of things and you know hopefully it
grows from there you know this industry
in essence is 9 and 9 months old so
we're at the start of something great
and hopefully it gets better and better
in nascent markets like this it's
natural to have a lot of actors
come in at the beginning everybody's
excited there is a passion but just
naturally these markets consolidate and
so my advice to you as small businesses
now policy makers want to protect small
business while also allowing for growth
and development and consolidation in the
market but my advice to operators here
is be sure to do your due diligence be
sure to have an exit strategy talk to
people and if you want to compete with
the big guys then develop some type of
consortiums or business you know
affiliations or groups collaborations
with others so that you can compete or
realize just where your cost structure
is and and plan accordingly so that you
develop and carve out your own niche
because if you don't you'll just be
consumed and wiped out just like a lot
of the small businesses out there right
now I'm going to whine for one second
that both the industry and the
government and the consumers are not
doing enough to make the changes that
need to happen because everybody's
retreating to their corner and trying to
scrap it up themselves and so unless you
know what did Franklin say you know if
we don't all hang together we're gonna
hang separately and I can't keep
emphasizing that enough and that
actually means that you have to talk to
people and communicate and organize
because otherwise you're just gonna back
back right into this legal concept that
I keep explaining to everybody called
clusterfuck and that's that's
essentially what what's going to keep
happening unless you guys do something
about it there's leadership in this
movement I'd like to refer to myself as
a general the rebel forces and the war
on drugs but it's you need a lot more
you need the people to actually stand up
you got to do more and that's always
going to be my message
I'm not going to be an apologist for the
banks I keep repeating that because I'm
really not many of our small banks let's
let's focus on some numbers because I
think what Matt is just described is a
sliver and the door that you can stick
your foot in as we sit here today there
are roughly a hundred and sixty five
banks in California that's down from
about 225 just nine years ago
consolidation is an inevitable part of
the banking business as well so let's
think about how little banks start
little banks start with an
entrepreneurial instinct and I'll bet
that sounds familiar to most of you that
entrepreneurial instinct brings together
local business people who say hey I've
got a great idea why don't we start a
bank then their journey begins also
where they're subject to regulation this
is not a request for your sympathy
instead I'm asking for empathy if we
understand where the other folks are
coming from it makes our problem easier
to solve because we can we can engage in
more productive dialogue so the small
business people come together and they
form a bank what's the first thing the
regulator says to them you can't grow
too fast you can't make certain kinds of
loans you can't engage in certain types
of business that regulator keeps that
group of business people on a very short
leash until it can be satisfied that
that new little bank doesn't represent a
contagion point for the larger banking
system if in fact a regulator shows up
says uh it looks to me like you may be
banking a marijuana business who are the
people who are directly impacted by that
the original shareholders guess who the
directors of that little bank are the
original shareholders so you can see how
the problem becomes cyclical here's what
I would offer up for your just to ponder
when we conducted one of our public
hearings up in Santa Rosa I heard from a
very passionate member of the industry
the cannabis industry say I can't even
go into my local community bank and sit
with a senior executive of the local
community bank and have a conversation
about my business class what's wrong
with that picture
okay that entrepreneur wasn't asking for
a loan wasn't asking for a deposit
relationship that entrepreneur was
asking for the expertise of that local
banker so I've had this same
conversation that have just had with you
with local bankers okay because if we
stop retreating to our corners as
matters describe and understand that
small business flourishes in the banking
sector the same way small business will
flourish in your sector and it's only by
talking to one another effectively that
we're gonna make some progress Tim would
you like to explain the set of visual
aids you've brought here I'm sure others
are curious do I I flashed this one
around this is available on the state
treasurer's website I would encourage
you to review it I will tell you having
worked for John Chun as his employee for
the last five plus five years and as his
consultant for seven years before that
this is not somebody who writes reports
and files them away this is our
blueprint I brought a fresh copy the one
on my desk I promise you as dog-eared
who's got lots of little yellow stickies
on it this is an important road map for
the hard work that will have to be done
I'm not going to make any apologies it
is hard work sure the second thing that
you boy that doesn't last that one went
fast didn't it the second thing I would
want to encourage you all to pay
attention to is there are a number of
jurisdiction
in the united states that have examined
the feasibility of creating a public
bank that for the moment that has
nothing to do with your business but
stay with me for a few seconds and i'll
bring them together this is has been
resurrected as a result of the Occupy
movement after the financial crisis in
2008 2009 people in small businesses and
and and many communities in California
felt that big Wall Street had abandoned
them and so the call went out to have
the state or in some cases a locality
get into the business of owning a bank
the model typically held up as a paragon
of success is the Bank of North Dakota
I might ant which is owned by the state
of North Dakota I might add to temper
your enthusiasm the Bank of North Dakota
is the only publicly owned bank in the
United States and it was formed ninety
nine years ago okay so that's not to say
you should be discouraged now inevitably
inevitably after we legalized cannabis
two and a half years ago two years ago
the the public bank movement merged for
a little while with the cannabis banking
route that just made things worse in
some jurisdictions but that doesn't mean
it's going to be worse forever so if you
are from various parts of the state
Santa Rosa or you are in Richmond
Berkeley Albany Oakland and Alameda
County each of those areas is looking
into this public bank idea the City and
County of San Francisco is looking on it
I service the treasurer's delegate to
the task force to the San Francisco
supervisors on this the state itself is
looking into it
although ours here's the merger ours is
focus
on standing up a bank that would engage
in the cannabis business now that
doesn't necessarily mean they bank the
way you and I know a bank it may be a
payment system maybe a credit union it's
still it's still being studied SB 930
I Sen etre Hertzberg at the request of
candidate for treasurer Fiona mah full
disclosure I'm not campaigning here was
introduced into the Senate last year was
passed out of the Senate by not a mature
not a unanimously but very close and got
to the second house and died in its
Appropriations Committee I expect that
we will see that back again the
difference is that we will have
completed the study that's recommended
in here about how to do that that may
inform the legislature in the next
legislative session beginning in January
with all the respect to my esteemed
colleague the private banks in the state
will allow a public bank over there dead
banking bodies okay that's my
perspective on it thank you all for a
great panel I have a fun tax question if
that can even happen but so Mac you mean
you represent a new client that was a
licensed transporter that I had $230,000
seized by the Department of Homeland
Security this is the first seized by the
CHP and turned over to the Department of
Homeland Security since this technically
is the first shot across the bow against
the license industry by the federal
government I am curious does that
licensed operator owed taxes on that
money or are we gonna wait until a
settlement is reached before that's
determined hell if I know
you know first of all that should i take
two minutes to tell the story or do you
want to hear about what's going on this
this is a great case that we're going to
use to smash open the contradiction so
keep following it support us the chp did
stop my clients first for a mud flap
violation on their pickup truck then let
him go and then they followed him up the
road stopped him again because it turned
out that the chp had it in for my
clients who had both been in the CHP and
had left the CHP one of the clients had
been fired from the CHP he got
reinstated and then he resigned the
other one was accused of stealing from a
locker room at the CHP he was actually
charged criminally and the jury did not
find him guilty and he is therefore
innocent but the CHP terminated him for
insubordination because he wouldn't tell
them what happened upon his advice of
his lawyer during that criminal
proceeding so he was fired for
insubordination those are my guys so
when you hear all the press stuff about
how dirty my guys are just remember that
these were guys who were just doing
their job and neither of them you know
were I mean there was a real story
behind who they were what happened was
once they were stopped on the second
stop they were treated like animals by
the CHP officers they were taken to the
Merced CHP station
the CHP called the Fresno office of the
United States Citizenship and
Immigration Services had an officer from
that office in Fresno come up to Merced
and take the two hundred thirty thousand
dollars into custody
this was a clear workaround to the
robber core bloom and our amendment for
those who don't know federal law that
prohibits the Department of Justice from
spending money on cannabis interdiction
in medical cannabis states that
Department the Department of Homeland
Security has a separate budget so isn't
that tricky the federal government has
shown us what they're doing now when the
when we challenge and I just will be
filing forfeiture administrative claims
and so forth and we're gonna be
challenging that in federal court in the
Eastern District when the Eastern
District forfeiture attorney for the
United States attorney walks in the
courtroom guess when I'm gonna tell the
judge he can't be here because your
budget his budget doesn't allow him to
be here so I've spoken to a couple of
other attorneys notably Eric Shevin I
haven't gotten a lot of details from him
but we know this is a trend they're
gonna take the money and give it to DHS
as a workaround around Roy Parker blue
man our that should really really make
everybody stand up and shout and I hope
everybody will do that and that's the
basic story we're gonna be filing all
sorts of actions I'm already talking to
you know clients around the state we're
gonna mark Wasserman and his brother
Craig where are you guys raise your
hands my co-counsel we're going to be
creating a huge stir about this we're
gonna be getting attorneys I want to get
an attorney from every county in the
state to be on the pleadings we're gonna
get a class-action injunction against
the CHP and then oh yeah
and then when we're then when this thing
is revealed for its absurdity then the
legislature will hopefully fix this
because this is all about a legislative
fix the courts are gonna just follow the
law call balls and strikes you know and
so forth they're not going to give us
anything they really haven't and they
they don't plan on it that's not where
you go it's in the legislative arena so
that's what's gonna happen
keep-keep wallet follow us there's gonna
be lots of stories about this don't
believe a goddamn word the CHP is saying
my name is Etienne font and I'm with
Berkeley patient's group we turn 19 next
month
we've unfortunately been kicked out of
over 30 different banks and we've heard
this discussion of banks coming along
and it's actually gonna happen is it can
unfortunately take a worst-case scenario
where a distributor or owner is murdered
before there is actual action taken
place at the state / federal level I
would hate to think that but
unfortunately these are the realities we
face every day when we're having to move
large sums of cash Berkeley patients
group has been a stalwart member of the
community and particularly of the reform
community and my hats off to you I had a
client that was bringing cannabis to a
cannabis retail operation was there was
so incriminate out the operation
followed him and then beat the crap out
of him so it's lucky that he wasn't
murdered but I think these sorts of
things are going on but people are
afraid to report them and so that's part
of why we don't get more action because
people don't realize the severity of the
problem so prior to joining new frontier
data
I was the chief operations officer at
golden leaf holdings in Oregon some of
my co-workers didn't show up one day
because their best friend was murdered
he had his head blown off for $40,000
and so to me on a personal basis I don't
people are already being murdered for
and so it's and I agree with you people
don't necessarily talk about it so I
don't know if that's gonna be what puts
the whole banking issue over the top
it's gonna be something else probably
just the scale on economics rather than
the humanity I'm Dale derringer I
represent California normal national
organization for reform of marijuana
laws we are
a non-profit 501 C 4 I've never been in
the business of course at Worrell also
probably the oldest marijuana
organization in the state going back and
we've had a bank account with no
problems I must say since 1974 but we
started we did encounter a glitch about
ten years ago when we started listing
dispensaries and we tried to get a
PayPal account so people could pay
dispensaries who walk or collectives
actually they were patient collectives
who wanted to get listed online could
pay by PayPal and PayPal said hey we're
terminating your account because you're
dealing with these things that are
federally illegal so we said oh well you
know you do have a point there they are
illegal we'll stop doing business with
those people ah but we continued to list
doctors now doctors are legal and
there's a federal court decision even
saying so they got wind of that and they
terminated our services altogether then
more recently we've started to hear a
spate of nonprofits like other normal
chapters like doctors organizations like
the Alameda County Democrats a brownie
Mary Democrats who have not been able to
get banking services five-o again all
nonprofits this is new is there
something happening there amongst the
regulators and wash it is there some new
rule or something why has this started
to happen after all of these years Dale
I think this working committee out of
the the prohibitionists and the White
House and the Office of National Drug
Control Policy have a multi-faceted
targeted campaign going on right now
one is the transferring assets to DHS or
other agencies that can take the asset
it's it's it's obviously a stupid play
because we're going to beat them in
federal court when the US attorneys come
in but there's that's a part
it as well I think you also you see this
massive tax auditing that's going on in
Colorado if you haven't you know wait
you know with all the problems we have
here in California wait of the IRS
starts auditing your businesses there's
gonna get the licenses from the state
and they're gonna start auditing at a
much higher rate than they do for small
businesses generally like we saw like we
see and my colleague Rachel Jillette
some you know or in Colorado I talk to
her frequently about this
there's multi multiple strategies that
they're engaging in to continue to
attack us and continue to try to cripple
this industry and those people are not
going to stop unless we you know unless
we shout and scream basically the review
that I did on that bill it seemed that
the focus the scope of 9:30 was becoming
more and more narrow only for direct
services provided to these businesses as
we know businesses have lots of related
services is it gonna get expanded is it
gonna remain so small and it has no
support from banking community as far as
I know this is not a policy of the state
treasurer it is an opinion from his
policy adviser so just to be clear on
that because there's media in the room
he has not taken a position on SB 9:30
or did not take a position
it was my view which I expressed to the
author and to the sponsor that the bill
had some infirmities simply because of
the economics of the banking business
and the manner in which new banks are
set up now having said that I was
reminded of a story that I was told by
former state senator Arcturus who back
in the thinking now middle 1980s some of
you are old enough to remember PSA
Airlines and air cow and gasoline prices
went up and air fares from Southern
California went up with them and Senator
Torres in a politically brilliant move
said
I've got a great idea we can get these
guys to the table if I introduce a bill
suggesting that we have a state airline
and suddenly everybody from the airline
started to show up in Sacramento to
discuss fair regulation and it was my
view to Senator Hertzberg because I'm
not a political expert by any means but
it was my view to Senator Hertzberg and
to the sponsor of the bill that SB 930
will have accomplished an awful lot if
you simply get the conversation started
anything you can do to get the
conversation started and even if it's
grunting and sweating to make that ball
move forward just a couple of inches is
probably a good fight they have so yes I
think you can expect to see
[Music]
[Applause]