I had a coach and he was in his 40s and
he would be sparring and training with
us for hours and I was like how do you
do that how you doing that in your 40s
and he's like smoke weed you know that I
smoked weed up
he's like I'm able to keep up with you
guys I'm relaxed I'm not using as much
energy and I tell you what he was one of
the best guys in the gym training and
sparring even in his 40s and he moved
amazingly well and he could train for a
long period of time and there's a few su
fighters and I will definitely not say
their names some of them are very vocal
about their use but some of the guys
that do triathlons and they were
explaining to me they're saying you know
when I get tired you know I'll be in the
middle and I'll start my run he's like I
take my pen out and I just hit the pen
and I'm gone I just get focused and it
was just blow it was blowing my mind
because I never used and trained I I did
after I stopped fighting and I shoot
benefits to it I got it I understood
what they were saying but yeah I almost
in a weird way I almost feel like it's
cheating in some ways because I'm so not
in my head I'm just in the moment and
I'm training and I'm creative and it's
almost not fair when I'm training with
someone because I don't know that's the
other reason why I wish I was using a
little bit more when I was fighting
because I never used and trained so in
that regard I definitely found benefits
after I was done fighting when I retired
but a lot of guys you know use and are
very active and are performing even
better so it it is a performance
enhancer in a lot of ways