[Music]
sure yeah a history lesson okay well let
me just let me the reason why I'm
talking about it is because I've written
a book not for you and not for most of
the people that listen to this podcast
but for your mother or your aunt and
uncle because I'm convinced that
autoflowering cannabis is the next
tomato once or twice in a lifetime as a
garden writer because that's what I
that's what I do in a different life as
a garden writer I can tell you that once
or twice in a lifetime a new plant is
introduced last time it happened that
you might remember that I certainly
remember is the snap pea when the sugar
snap peas came out oh my god people went
nuts it was a brand new plant nobody had
ever I've ever seen and so people went
nuts I'm convinced that autoflowering
cannabis is the next tomato it's a snap
pea in terms of a new introduction and
the reason why I say that is is is it
there are a couple of reasons the first
is that these plants which most people
have never heard of these plants are a
normal-size plan unlike sativa and
indica which could be you know anywhere
from 8 to 15 feet tall these plants are
anywhere from 18 inches to maybe 4 feet
they're shrubs at the best but they're
but they're smaller they grow in pots as
well as outdoors in the soil you can
grow indoors or outdoors the reason why
they're called odo flower is because
they don't have a photo period which
makes all the difference in the world
they are a cross between a sativa or
indica or sativa and indica and
a Rudi Alice these were plants that were
discovered in the early 1900's in Russia
they were escaped from plantations where
they were growing hemp and evolution
created a situation where they went from
seed to flower without a photo period
only based on genetics and so yeah there
any number of you know grass
I mean lawns there are any number of
plants that are auto flowering plants
now the key thing about this is that is
that if you live in the northern
hemisphere even if you live on the
equator that 12-hour darkness plus is a
problem we get 12 hours in Anchorage
Alaska right when the frost hits so
we're never gonna get a planted flowers
the plants that we are are all using
today have Afghani as a basis somebody
went over there and got this plant not
knowing really what it was what was for
it turns out these things take six seven
eight months from seed to harvest what
we have in OTO flowers is the ability to
grow a plant from seed to harvest in
seven to nine weeks now when they were
first commercialized in 2000 two or
three with a low rider
they were crappy plants they were small
the yield was terrible the the strength
wasn't all that good the early often and
so as a consequence if you started to
look at them and breed them and fool
around with them people laughed at you
if you were on one of the you know one
of the internet websites you know they
threw you off basically
so somebody started Auto flower and net
which people want to go take a look at
today the science because these things
can be bred so quickly advanced
exponentially and around two thousand
eight nine ten the streets started to
get better the quality was phenomenal
the size of the plants changed
and I would say today we are at the
point where they need to be so what are
some of the improvements well depending
on what your perspective is you can
either Breeden's you know CBD and cetera
et cetera THC the lack of powdery mildew
has been you know that stuff has been
bred out and bred in to make these a
plant which your mother would grow in
her house or honor condo deck it is such
an easy plant to grow that if you add
fertilizer to it
you're probably causing a problem these
are plants that grow so quickly that
when an insect hits it very often what
happens is is the the life phase of the
plant is gone that the insect requires
holy crow so so the whole idea of
growing these plants has gone from
complicated you know you had to have a
degree in chemistry yet you know I don't
know but hydroponics lab lab left to the
most simple easy you go buy a bag that
soil you're sticking in a five-gallon
pot you put the seed in the pot you
don't even transplant it because they
don't like to be transplanted and bingo
seven to nine weeks later you have a
usable and I mean a usable cannabis crop
well these plants can be anywhere from
this big you know to about four feet
four and a half feet well I saw yield
the other day eighty grams on a cola and
there were about eight colors on the
plant so the yield is phenomenal if you
just pop on the Instagram and look up
autoflowering cannabis you will be
phenomenally surprised this is the next
tomato now from a commercial growers
perspective in places like Oregon
they're beginning to use these because
the the advantages are phenomenal first
of all you get a uniform size plant very
important
second of all you can you you don't have
to worry about the photoperiod
what that means is that that if you are
growing photo period
you can put these plants in between your
photo period plants whether you're in a
veg stage or a flower stage and still
get results absolutely spectacular the
the ability to breed these things is
wonderful because they are so quick and
you know the the fact that you can turn
over any number of crops means that if
you're growing outdoors you can put one
in the ground you know now and and
probably get two more crops in before a
frost hits sometime in October
just beat Acula the plants really are
there any specific breeders that you've
talked to and kind of yeah well you know
I would say on a general and the general
level for the home grower the tomato
grower I would I would take a look at
mephesto seeds mephesto genetics
phenomenal in Oregon there's a company
called new breed seeds which is a sister
company to territorial seeds which sell
already sells tomato plants so we're
really in a great spot you know it's
it's it's worth looking around now yes
and they're able to work on the genetics
so that we can back back trace to some
of the land races this is really an
exciting tool that we've developed so
it's not necessarily no absolutely not
it's a tool it's a tool because you can
breed these with regular cannabis take
some of the advantages of these and in
the advantages of regular cannabis the
bigger cousins does I'd like to save it
transitioning from my mom sure to the
hardcore
commercial cultivator selling flour into
the California market or yeah market the
Washington State market
what are those growers like when you you
meet people all the time what are their
thoughts on adding autoflowering into
their mix of light depth can I add
hunter not sure what about the
cultivator who says appellation is a
really impart of part of my future
survive sure well let's let's work with
the the the Appalachian part first I
mean I said you know Appalachian you
know it has to do with it what I call
the three-legged stool genetics light
what's the light in your area and the
soil the microbes in the soil obviously
I would be a microbe guy and what gives
what gives the planter or I think are
the microbes in the soil and the light
because the light has such an incredible
impact on the microbes in the soil which
make available all of the 18 nutrients
that the plant needs to have now we can
put all the other crap we want in a
plant that's not what the plant uses it
uses those 1718 nutrients and that's it
and and the ability to be able to have
specialized microbes in your area to
create that order so works with these
plants just like any other plant so it's
no different than a regular cannabis
plant and because you can grow these in
pots very easily and move them around
very easily you can create your own tour
or to a certain degree you can bring in
soil is my questions they can go into
the ground oh absolutely and or they
going absolutely because you know
oscillation purists go if you're in a
pot if you're not in the ground here
yeah well if you're really if you're in
a pot but you have the soil that you
take I know but then then they go well
then you can grow humble appellation in
anywhere in the world and that's true I
hate to say it but but these are these
are really spectacular plants the colors
the varieties oh my god it's
unbelievable and you know the fact that
you can grow a plant in a little teeny
area and get a usable harvest Wow so I I
think the future of cannabis is going to
be auto flower I think we're gonna end
up in a situation once it's fully
legalized where you're gonna be able to
walk into your you know your best buy at
Christmastime and they're gonna be a
little Christmas trees Auto flower
cannabis at Easter it's gonna you know
it's gonna have same tree but it'll have
that you know it's a little agreeing on
stuff well you know I said the same
thing about legalization and it took a
while but but I think we're there you
know I I predicted I a pretty well the
microbe wave this is not a great book
it's it's just that it hit the wave at
the right time I think I predicted
pretty well the mycorrhizal wave this is
so when you go to a dispensary very
often they sell the seeds the seeds do
not contain THC in them obviously so you
should be able to buy them in the mail
you know unless you live in a place like
Alaska where they've made seeds part of
the place you don't need to be but you
can pick these seats up there very very
available but but for homegrown
flowering sounds like it's going to
that's right you're gonna be able to go
to a seed rack and when you buy your
tomato plant and your celery or your
carrots there's gonna be four or five
different kinds of wonderful is it open
source Science and Technology yes yes no
secrets
Rudi Alice plants are available people
can breed their own you know so far it
looks like a very clean entry into the
industry I think it's gonna be really
helpful for everybody but we have
improved everything we've done you know
I mean and we've we've introduced CBD or
brought it back we've introduced you
know all sorts of things and this is
just another tool
in the chest and really an important
[Music]