all right morning
good morning so i'm sol alba from
beneficial insectary
michael arsenault maven we're here to
talk about some
natural enemy releases and some tips on
how to do it
um we're starting with you know the
general soil predators um that can be
used together we're talking about
delosha corey aria uh the roe field
predatory rope beetle
targets drips pre-pupa and fungus gnat
it's formerly known as a theta choriaria
but the entomologists
that the taxonomist and the
insect taxonomist changed that recently
along with that we're going to release
uh stradiolaelips symmetus which is
the predatory soil might also target
serps and fungus gnat
um this one was known but as a
hypo aspis most people still know it as
hypo aspis but
we just call them strats so anyway
um first thing you want to do
basically uh when you uh show up and are
prepping for a release
is to acclimate the bugs um
you know they come in in ice packed in
ice
so you want to warm it up you know it's
a i guess would be the equivalent of
you waking up somebody waking you up
with like a bucket full of ice water
right you kind of want to acclimate it
to the grow conditions so
as you can see right here we we have
both containers
this is a this is the soil predator mite
and this is
the predatory rove beetle
and we have these acclimating here to
get to the ground temperature
basically we're going to show you how we
do it
so after this acclimation um what you
want to do
is you want to inspect
them for viability so
just tap them out and you'll see them
there
they're called rove beetles because they
just
move everywhere they're just constantly
like mini search
yeah kind of like that right they flip
their tails up like all road beetles do
oops so anyway those all look pretty
viable
um bro fields do fly
they're not great fighters but they do
fly so
that's a huge advantage strats are a
little bit more difficult to
see but often you can see them crawling
on the
there's none there
[Music]
but yeah you want to carefully inspect
for the viability
[Music]
it may require a loop so you may not be
able to see them
really and then they also could still be
sluggish we didn't quite wait
you know the 30 to 45 minutes and that
we should have so
for purposes of moving this video along
we'll uh we'll take a closer video to
show you what they look like when
they're crawling around
um although you know that pretty much
shows you and
they're just mites so i think i did say
the
white carrying you know the little foam
top for the
refrigerated box yeah
so um this is
probably these are probably enough mites
for
several um i think i remember
calculating somewhere like 600 square
feet
something like that so we're going to
overload them here but
there's a living soil so mike really
wanted to try to establish them
and that's one of the beauties of the of
this
these predators here in particular is um
both of these are some of the easiest
to get to establish in your growth in
fact um that
uh that was the case
um the farm i work with where we need
very few releases to actually get them
to establish
they like them they like your
environment they will uh
they'll establish readily so if you
don't have like
heavy fungus that pressure or heavy
thrust pressure
um and there's not an abundant food
source
in the soil with those two uh pests what
other
things can these guys you know that's
that's a good question
um some mites will eat uh fungus i'm not
sure if hypoaspis
eats or strats eat fungus um about like
springtails right
tails is yeah springtails are great in
fact i'm working on a rearing system for
delosha um which requires rearing
springtails first and then feeding that
to them
and just for fun there's some
springtails buried in this bed
are they well they'll help you with
those it's an extra food source for them
um
i don't know which is their preference
but these are frequently used
as um an adjunct to
nematodes for fungus not control
but the nematodes are obviously your
best choice but
two more weapons right
speaking about speaking of rearing
springtails um
lot of growers don't know this it's been
done for
for a while now other greenhouse
operations of other crops
you can build what are called delosha
breeder boxes
basically that is you know a box where
you have a food source and salt the soil
and you release some of your delosia in
that
and it's covered you allow them to
reproduce and colonies form
because you've given them food and so
you have all sorts of
life stages you have eggs you have
nymphs or larva and you have the adults
and then you can open the box
and adults will leave the box but you
have this generation in the box it's
essentially constantly producing um row
beetles
and you just very simple to maintain you
know every once in a while you add some
food
keep them moist and and
you know this has been done for a while
i've done it um it's really cool it's
like a little
mini insectary or you could call it like
a giant delosha sachets you know if you
know what a sachet is
anyway um so yeah um
it's really pretty simple to release
these um and like we said we want them
warmed up so they're moving
and um it's just that really you can
either tap them
you know tap them in you know but
they're uh
they're probably like these are also
you know pretty pretty tough beetles
what's the carrier like cocoa and
vermiculite yeah it's a it's a cocoa and
vermiculite carrier pretty much i'm
sorry pete and vermiculite carrier
let's see them right there so we're
gonna go ahead and
empty this container
these guys will
um you can actually
do flats like this but they're wet so
the carrier will stick obviously to the
leaf but if you've got them
where they're if you have them where
they're um
you know with without the dome and
they're fairly dry then
you can just shake the uh you can just
shake the
extra carrier off the leaves once once
the beetles have
moved down into into the soil
or fake soil or whatever whatever it is
i'm gonna hand this over to
mike here nice and you pop out in the
back there
whoa
a little bit left
all right
so
now for the strats you know the same
idea
you can sprinkle them or in this case a
lot better to
just stand out are there feeder mites in
the lotion as well
in the strats you mean or in the um
i'm not sure that we it was a real
beetle
um i'm not sure what's in the carrier
um if anything they might have put some
some eggs
of feeder feeding eggs like zamoth
um that lays eggs that we can use
for for feeding certain predators i'm
not sure
i know delosha eats those i've seen them
do it
with the mites i don't think so
that's why we do overnight shipping just
to get them to you
you know get them out you go
thanks sir oh it's important too
i don't know mike it might remember to
do it over there but what's that you
kind of want to leave these
caps and the open bottles out in the
grill for a while
nice in case you know it's just a good
practice
it's a
it's as simple as that probably the
easiest
release there is out there it's a
no-brainer
and like we said it's both of these have
the ability whoops the ability to
establish
readily in your growth
um i've even seen them actually at
mike's operation
um these actually haven't has them
established
in a rockwool media and
another grower i know in l.a downtown
l.a
had a natural a native
native population of delosha that is
established
oh yeah along with strategies they never
released but they were there
they're everywhere delosha was the
gateway
uh benny for our facility so they didn't
like to invest into venues because they
didn't think they would persist
and then one day uh during a cut down
i'm seeing some delosha rolling through
the rockwool cubes this is probably
i'm guessing six months post you know
last introduction into the field and
when i showed that to my cultivation
manager he was like
okay well we'll you can get back to
ordering those since those do seem to
persist and that with the nematodes
really seem to
[Music]
not so much for us because you know our
business is selling
family and beneficials and you're
essentially getting one that tends to
establish
but uh that's fine we just want bio
control to work for you
that's pretty much it um
easy right definitely it's my
insurance policy thank you