so we're talking tissue culture and you
said you've recently been dabbling in it
yeah yeah we hired a stem-cell
researcher three years ago we started
with by the way it was a stem-cell
researcher in human stem cells so he had
to quickly learn the tissue culture for
plants but it was the right person to do
it they spent about six months
developing tech and we went from just
quickly did he say anything that he
learned that was different doing plant
stem cell versus human I mean yeah
there's a lot of differences to it but a
lot of the protocols for clean run were
very important so having someone real
familiar protocols when in terms of yeah
the technology itself it's a lot
different but it started as just reading
papers on the
and then trying to replicate the studies
and then after that it was okay let's do
some real hardly anything there's a
couple of famously bad paper job yeah
and there's a we started but after about
a strangle this auto scientist I mean it
was like doing from scratch learn it and
then you know the conclusion that we
came to in our here in Apple is that
it's great for certain things
or general propagation you know mom's
and cutting still seem to be the way to
go yeah yeah we started way before he
goes tot talk about what what was it
good for in your scenario so well we
were just starting to get into the
research on cleaning up plant material
and this is right about the time where
we've started to hear better you know it
is about this these mutations energies
being actual virus or viroid but we even
had the information and then it came out
you know about a year and half later you
guys did some research right only think
that Layton and please how blatant
poverty I think there's probably others
okay yeah definitely pop wait
yes really Wow as a cultivator you know
I've been growing for 20 years now
started to see those like real oh geez
and like any kind of old you later Brian
is it seem like at first and anything
that we but yeah it's an interesting
kind so there's there's been a lot of
like crazy research in the tissue
culture but it's good to hear that some
of the top guys found the same thing we
didn't put in tons of money in tissue
culture for propagation IV yeah I know I
mean like we were in the space like
probably like 2004 14 or so we started
it and it is funny because I was
thinking back on this for us it was a
big thing was like we were out there
commands let's check out a tissue
culture because yeah tissue culture
we're like wow you do the math you'd be
like a million plants and read 10 square
feet and so we started exploring it you
know we built our lab
and same thing did you look at the
papers and never accomplished what the
papers promised but we actually did
launch a commercial line of plants
through tissue injuries scallop collapse
pretty aggressively we have this lab
that line of powder so we did but you
know at the end of the day you do the
math and you're like Jesus or our tissue
culture plants cause there's just it
just didn't and then you know we would
do trials as well as question like our
tissue culture plants higher quality are
they more productive you know they
branch Warren every time we did a trial
in life good yeah no it was pretty damn
close either way it's pretty dang
closest note there's no clear there was
no clear advantage position culture so
yeah but like you said I think what did
become really a bug to us was especially
around
sanitation yeah and you know we saw in
Frank League like going back all the way
you know for my whole Tigers in the
industry people have always talked about
genetic drift right so genetic drift
don't you notice that plants do worse
over time and I'm like you know like as
like you know my life energy net assists
tell me that that's not a thing yep
right but what could be happening is
we've got those disease pressures right
and we didn't know what they were
frankly we haven't eaten in symptoms at
the time but we said like let's start
figuring out like play-doh sanitation
like mariculture techniques and like
other like treatments of arafat to
eliminate viruses thyroids and other
pathogens and but it took like four more
years before we were really able to you
know we really had that we had we had
the phyto sanitation stuff but then we
had to do the sequencing diagnostic one
actually
was over the culprits right now and the
hot lady I would was just that's all you
need to get a thing
yeah that was the biggest one I mean
that's that we're confident we should
like causality we really want you know
Jeremy warren is now director of plant
health was really able to go all the way
to identifying that causes the tutting
symptoms that we see but we you know
since we published that we've had people
come to us with other symptoms hey
what's this what's this and we're now
seeing other symptoms that are hp/lb but
we think they're probably something else
so we're going through a second a second
set of sequencing see what are some of
the symptoms you're seeing and yeah I
mean it's like all across the board
Jeremy's really the best to explore this
but you know frequently we'll see like
bearing leaf deformities or like really
common especially when they're like you
know this is like kind of my like and a
farmer hat you know my farmer
descriptions like you'll see Leafs where
they have like asymmetric deformities
though like curved like various forms of
modeling mosaic II type symptoms kind of
looks like variation but it's yeah yeah
we have I've seen that a lot structural
issues on the lead
it's not different than ago right right
you have it various forms of like even
like various terms of leap curving read
like leave talking and stuff like that
sometimes that's just nutrient but other
times it seems to be something else is
going on there so yeah whole plethora
even like you know weird like Fox
sailing on flowers and stuff like that
it's funny because h blvd we have found
is very widespread yeah like you know
now that we've got that and this is
really the key for us and what we've
done with tissue culture is turn the lab
into what we call a clean plant program
so we marry this tissue culture with the
mariculture various pre treatments to
get clean plants but also really
importantly we have the diagnostic lab
right so we have to after we go through
the process we have to like run it
through the lab to confirm whether is in
fact it's a plant and then frankly like
in what we call our elite mom repository
routinely test to make sure that those
plants have not become reinfected right
because i mean you really have to get
rid of the viral all the way throughout
the plant okay you can hide it
where you have a lower branch that has
yeah
that's one of the really surprising
things is that this is like you know
it's been described to me as like you
know it's like you would be looking for
one person on the planet Mars right it's
like potentially the scale you're
dealing with and even like with really
precise pcr Diagnostics like for us we
don't really consider anything clean
until tests clean three times
consecutively that's great news
because you get a lot of false negatives
one thing that's interesting we were
able to reduce the Dunning just by mom
select she's not even doing teaching
poultry just really aggressive mom
selection you know you take your
thousand cuttings from your mom's and
then you take you know the top thirty
and those become long
do that generations and generations and
eventually you just kind of selecting
towards mm and you could reduce
it and we've seen that help along the
statistical yeah 100 percent like even
the first thing we ever saw published on
studying because Rick Prum presented
like the Emerald Conference years ago
and that was like really best practice
you know even before anyone knew that
Wow yes it's just why he's doing it a
select select select select call call
bad stuff select select and it's funny
we still have known enough about the
thyroid to like know exactly how that
works but yeah they do call it late
reasonably if it can exist a
symptomatically and frequently does so
you know presumably you just get the
pressure below a certain point or
something like that
you can yeah he can manage but that's a
really good point yeah I mean we've
noticed also it seems I mean this is
just kind of observation that the
environment and you know the way they
grow the plant can also influence how
the symptoms
so baby you know your your environment
is on point everything's perfect
Lighting's perfect planets super happy
and the viroid does it effectively to
something it's dress yeah I know like so
my version of that is like we we get
receive many more symptomatic clients
with inner growers but like green house
and especially outdoor growers seem to
have far fewer symptoms and so like we
don't know exactly what that is but
probably something environmental as well
yeah yeah hot and cold or maybe it's the
light or something the epigenetics I
mean I guess it's the the plants ability
to trigger certain certain genes and
I've heard that with like outdoors rust
wherever you put something that's indoor
it seems to be real weak out and within
you know our season you could bring it
back in its strong and maybe it's UV
light or yeah yeah it's really a
jeremy's field of study on our team but
I do know like the plants do have a
immune response system yeah so you know
in an environment where that system can
work better it's going to be better at
it so yeah I mean I think just in
general indoor barak indoor environment
is much more stable yeah
although you can control it but the
stability itself is a lot different it
can be hard yeah well and it's just
unnatural right there's stuff that
doesn't doesn't always work the way to
find expects it to her
right one
I just want to get back to the port cozy
when we were over there before we came
over here it was for us here just
specifically like the three things
tissue culture is good like remember we
talked about like keeping your library
right so can you just get into like like
what if why do we use tissue culture for
as a functioning grow operation and
where is it not really relevant because
then you got it to like it's easy to
take a thousand clippings a week right
right yeah so for like proper
propagation Methodist general production
at a facility
seems like mom clone is still the way to
go for cannabis at least right now when
we did research on tissue culture the
one yeah the one benefit we thought and
we didn't really get to test it as much
as we wanted to but it was if you are
doing breeding and phenotype selection
storing those varieties you know it's a
lot less space and you can store for
quite a bit of time if you have the
right thing
but that's you know I still think
there's a lot of research it needs to be
done you can probably speak of that more
terms of storage 300 percent that's
basically so that's for us we have to
clean by a program and we have the
genetic library that's you know it helps
us it you know it's the two combined for
us was what's really important right we
can take a new genetics clean them up
add them to the library got something
like 100 varietals now at the lab you
know which allows us to offer more
interesting genetics more frequently and
also to know that they're clean
have you guys done any long-term stores
with cryo freezing or is it just kind of
life
wheezing about zero degrees
we haven't done any cryopreservation
stuff yeah yeah we have done a variety
of life long-term storage protocols
which have been mostly successful for us
but never like the liquid nitrogen bath