with the clones and tissue culture you
have some phenomenal stuff and I not
even just stateside I think you're kind
of tapped in globally as far as landrace
and some of these other things when it
comes to true genetics right in projects
I am you know like I mean things stay
within the borders of the country but
for sure being being and being involved
in cannabis for a long time and sharing
genetics for a long time
I never really I never understood the
real impact of it over the course of
decades so I always moved material to
people and I was shared material people
because I believe fundamentally people
need good quality material to work with
and that and that being being generous
with that one aspect allows people to
have a much higher level of success and
I don't I never still don't I don't see
my fellow cultivators or nursery
operators really as competitors because
it's a big industry and and really what
you're is you're all in the same
situation working kind of
collaboratively so I've always moved the
material that way and what it did is it
allowed me to get a global amount of
people that I've dealt with over the
course of my life yeah so it lets me see
like what's going on in all these
different places it's nuts man last of
its pangs of Weeden in Iran Iran has got
fields of grass and so it's amazing to
see all of the Europe it's amazing to
see what's taking place all through the
Americas Australia New Zealand that
they've been hitting up and it's so to
me it's amazing because it lets us
really take a look at the picture of
genetics and then you know for us what
we did is we shift it into a full tissue
culture build-out so we tried to figure
out for years like how do you run an
operation using as the most I know what
I did is I look for whatever was the
stringent the most difficult standards
to try to follow with amount of inputs
so I would find out could you actually
succeed following a regulated system in
Ag because no other AG is regulated like
that and then it was hard and
and everybody's finding out how hard it
is right now because you don't have the
tools and so you can't suddenly have a
mistaken guard ever use the tool there's
no tool to use you're the problem and
it's it's it's difficult so we tried to
figure it out for years and we knew the
tissue culture was the only way to go
around it and I work with TC labs for a
while playing around but it just wasn't
dialed in enough to make it efficient
and so the price point was too high so
you could plug the cut but you couldn't
get the price point down so we were able
to work with the lab out of Petaluma
node and get it to the point where our
new facility is designed to just receive
the material from them in like in micro
plant look for them and then we just
grow it out into a clonal form so that
we can end wholesale it so it kind of
puts us in a job or level of a wholesale
so that it lets us put material into
nurseries or the nurseries that's been
virally stamped and third-party so this
way you you have the ability to start
with material that has been certified by
somebody other than us that's coming
from TC so it's not carrying any
inherent viruses any kind of pathogenic
problems that you lose areum is what you
see so much of and it's in the materials
in the material you're not gonna get rid
of it so scrubbing it gets rid of it
then it lets you grow and then work off
of getting your protocols straight so
then you can run the same variety a
couple times in a row and actually have
a predicate of concept what are you
gonna make no and without this
stabilization it's tough and so you see
in TC blow up everywhere but a lot of it
is they're just trying to figure it out
and we're ready to do the full rollout
right now so I'm excited because man
it's it's a nightmare to run nursery
operations in regulated conditions
because morally you don't want to use
any of this crap and then on a business
level you're not allowed to on
regulations and so far you have no tools
and cannabis is constantly being exposed
any pathogens all the time and so your
technology comes in and so strawberries
bananas fruit trees they all use this to
get around this problem and so that's
what we're gonna have to go with it and
in a lot of ways using the technology is
expensive but I would rather have the
tech and the expense and I would rather
have toxic anibus all right you know I
just don't agree with it man and I've
been I've been
a child people fears maybe people could
talk smack but come over in tests it's
never been any pesticides and fungicides
or regulators any of these plants ever
because that's an artificial reality and
and sometimes man you know you got to
look stupid to figure it out and
sometimes it's amazing how time changes
who looks bad who doesn't yeah but all
in all if we can do this correctly than
what it does it allows us to start
taking old varieties that are basically
they want to get rid of them and scrub
them on a cellular level and get the get
the pathogenic weight off of it
so that you can then have material
that's beautiful again and then hold it
in banks because so much of the source
material is being diminished because as
you remove the population of cultivators
that used to cultivate you can't afford
to hold a library if you can only sell
OG so why do you hold the other twenty
six varieties you're gonna get rid of
them and pretty soon you have nothing
and everyone goes here big guys I'll
have it no they don't when the big guys
come in when we call any of these large
lp's when they buy a grow company they
buy the company and they buy their there
their genetic collection and so it's the
genetic collection that seems to have
the value so I have an extensive genetic
collection that we laugh that goes back
in time right and I always laugh and I'm
just like it's the toolbox because I can
go into this collection and I can pull
out a lot of material and then it's
what's neat and I was some of the newer
collections because a lot of the newer
cannabis it's not that it's it's worse
or better than older cannabis it's just
marketed to different groups and so now
that you have a bigger demographic to
sell to because you can actually target
them we can start to have specific stuff
and for me you know I'm excited about
stuff that's meant for like 50 to 70
year olds that want to go back to like
just to smoke a good weed I love it
because you're already aware guys in the
industry besides that's like I have a
friend who's got a hundred thirty-five
acres down in Santa Barbara County and
I'm like if you want to do something
different it's like I'm trying to figure
out trying to chase all these trendy
strange I'm like I'll tell you one thing
to do now the largest group that's
consuming cannabis is 39 and under okay
but the fastest-growing segment is
is over 40 yeah so I said you know do
something different and I know you have
a lot of dispenser will say they won't
buy it they won't buy it but if you get
the marketing on point I'm like I'm
Tania get some of those strains get the
strain that you and I grew up it hit the
strain that your dad grew up and and and
and and make sure that you're letting
the individuals that you really want to
have experience that know it's there yes
so that's the problem because they're
not they're not looking at numbers they
don't care about numbers any care by
numbers in the past no they don't care
about Instagram what they what they care
about is I want smokes something that
makes me happy or calm or euphoric or
contemplative or relaxed but I want the
experience to be quality in any one of
those directions and a lot of the new
candidates because the potency levels
are so high they can't titrate it so
they can't get the dose right so they go
burn to join the two and they're just so
austere I'm worried about people who
maybe like this is why I stopped doing
the for any of my mom she was like I
don't like how it feels is this and that
I'm like mom that's like me I used to go
down to Mexico during spring break you
know kid growing up and I'm like that'd
be me going down there for spring break
getting drunk off tequila saying I'm
never drinking again exactly it's not
the right mentality when I think it's
BDS analytics have pointed out that the
potency of cannabis specifically as it
relates to THC has been a multiplier
it's been 4x in the last 7 years needs
it though because if you're not pulling
over 20 you know you're not making any
money on the extract is you have to yeah
and so it's just really trying to
stratify if we goes like nobody smokes
flour anymore but it is market across
the board for everything oh yeah it's
just you have to target it correctly and
there are people that smoke flour a lot
of them want experience over sheer
knockout and that's where you can get
into the extracts because we can make
anything stronger and then add a trip
package to direct it but for the the
people that want to be able to consume
cannabis in an enjoyable manner where
they can burn five six joints and hang
out and laugh and now that we know that
the lung ailments don't exist with
cannabis really so this way someone says
smoking weeds bad for you I got you know
my lungs pretty good
and so that that allows you to really
get rid of that argument and go back
into this is how I prefer to smoke and
what I want is I want cannabis it makes
me feel good in the direction I want and
I don't need a celebrity endorser on it
I don't need a special box on it I used
to get it in a baggie out the back of a
car from a dude named Shiloh ya know we
can and it's all good so that's really
what the truth of it is is and then just
give it to him in a in a clean form safe
form reliable form and then have it so
they can go get it through the course of
the year I'll make a pre buy or be able
to get because people would buy a couple
ounces or you couldn't get them in one
shot but you could buy a quarter pound
over a week put it in your house throw
up throw a liter pack in it they'll keep
it moist and you have yourself some rich
cannabis for a long time so you know
that group would do that I mean we were
just we did a little field trip down to
mercy lovely guys down the road yeah
great products weren't cute and the guy
in front of me is like all I know is I
found the one I like and I keep coming
back say have it yeah and I'm like and
do you know which farm it not just a
strain do you know which farm are
getting it from you so I do I'm oh
that's what matters yep yeah there's a
genotype there's a phenotype it's in a
production in a production type yeah so
the same varietal in the hands of two
different people's radically different
animal yeah and so when you find a good
farm reward the farmer buy rebuy his
product and then you'd also contact the
farm and ask them what else do you do
that's like this and who else might I
want a smoked weed from yeah because we
always advertise each other now it's so
like competitive but it doesn't need to
be what needs to be competitive is
getting the education to the public so
that they have enough tools to make
smart decisions so that they're
satisfied with what they buy and they
rebuy it and you got it you got to be of
service to these people that they they
do not know and they haven't been
exposed and in the dispensary is shield
the truth in a lot of cases
and the grower needs to be able to make
these direct connections and when people
find that they love a flower from a farm
and they can contact the farm and have a
communication of in and it may not be
able to sell to him directly but they
can sure as hell help them understand
why they are who they are which then
lets word-of-mouth Drive your business
and they can also say these are other
farms that have nice products you should
check them out because that's what
you're doing is now you being a cannabis
human being that's true and that's yeah
again we we were just having dinner last
night downtown here in Santa Rosa and
there were I would venture to say there
were some growers sitting at the table
next to us that's one of them brought
that up they're like screw it I want to
go straight to the dispensary I want to
be able to tell my story I want to be
able to share what makes this different
I thought was really interesting how
that exactly your point they're like if
we could cut out the distributor we
would and you know they want to
communicate we want to do it what we'll
do with those though at the dispensary I
have the one log we'll set it up to
where we have the grower events where we
can get all the growers that want to
come down from the hills and meet the
public that we can advertise for bring
them because we have a beautiful
facility to do his that and then we can
then sell their product through the
store legally for them but we don't have
to be the person that interprets who you
are and then explains it to another you
can do that directly and then they can
confer with us so we can we can
substantiate via that yeah they are
those people
they said they do a really good job and
you're like they do they do a great job
and what it does now you have
confirmation of a hypothesis a belief
that you've confirmed becomes a purchase
and if it's good they buy a toy so
unless you buy it twice it's on stuff
checked out the dispensary up there with
you guys that's why I suppressed by
because you're right you go into some of
these especially the higher bar I'm not
knock you know business to business in
the disconnect and I know we're trying
to be more PC we're starting to call
them cannabis consultants versus bud
tenders but a lot of its office a new
term it's a cannabis that's hella funny
C squared C squared
cannabis consultants is like somewhere
we segue from rec to adult use of
terminology yeah
for a tional use yes inspirational use
I'm not a secret shop but not to claim
went out just to experience it and this
young lady I'm like well you know what's
your favorite psyche well I was just
lazy not at lunch and I just ripped that
and I'm like she was full on high when
she is talking to me make a
recommendation she is recommending based
on someone who their idea of hitting the
pinnacle is true noble yes for what her
favorite terpene was she'd be like yeah
it doesn't matter where and it the the
farmer the farmer needs to be able to
get in there because ultimately there is
well there's a lot of weight the
cannabis consultant names killing me
there's a lot of weight I always I'm
always aggressive on the budtender
but it's not because I have any
disrespect for them it's the opposite
it's that they're having a lot of
responsibility put on their back very
true for not a lot of money and the the
education just needs to be put in place
so that they're understanding more on
how to market and satisfy the desire of
the farm and the buyer that either user
and it's a lot of weight on them and so
they always get a ration ship and not
being educated enough but I'm like if it
was a tree like a career do that oh yeah
no that's a--that's like a real barista
in Italy yes yeah that's a different job
go to Italy
they're not regular coffee baker you get
their passion yeah everything conductors
they can they conduct a business man
they run a tight ship and I saw that
when we were really quick that's there
was a gal she is kneeling there doing a
fender day at a jetty and packs air
which was nice there was an older woman
I'd venture to guess about 68 69 sitting
on the couch and you had cannabis
consult and I was talking to her and I
was eavesdropping because being in the
industry law I just want to hear
people's story that's it the way that
this woman was explaining it and
speaking at her level it's almost like
okay obviously she went to college and
took speech one day right yet she knew
her audience she knew how to speak to
this woman and she is being very
specific on the dosage and before you go
to bed one puff see how if you wake up
with obviously sleep deprivation what
yes 64% of people who consume cannabis
according to BDS is because of sleep
issues yeah this woman was born about if
you wake up 3 4 in the morning one more
puff that should carry you through I
love the fact that she she has taken the
time
I mean there's there is a cute this was
Friday 50 people in line this was all
about the dance and that kind of stuff
you can't fake like everybody has these
policies where we do all these things
but really the people that serve
cannabis the tenders when they're when
they're real they they're so crucial
because they interface all these people
that are undereducated and how to use
the product and then they alleviate
their fear that they're gonna make a
mistake and so they give them confidence
to try things and they they give them
information and they can direct them and
steer them and it's a beautiful
relationship and I mean at first
somebody's been running dispensaries for
a long time but senders get their own
it's almost like bartenders oh yeah our
cannabis consultants are you illiquid
consulted the liquor consultant gets a
unbelievable following because of how
they serve that drink to the person and
make them feel that it's worth their
time to be there in the interaction yeah
yeah yeah no it's it's it's it's it's a
pure yeah and with with cannabis its
brand new in that respect and you've got
to be able to put it together and then
you have to be able to have tenders that
understand what the products are and
then you have to have the ability that
farms have reps that are human and
patient that are able to say listen take
the time and you repeat yourself a lot
because each person is going to ask the
same questions but bottom line is that's
your responsibility yeah and when you
really look at it like that it allows
you to really get lost in what you're
doing and then people who listen to it
the people who listen to you explain to
someone else are the ones that really
are affected because they go you know
what just like you saw that girl or that
woman serve that other woman you will
always look at the woman who did the
serving differently because you realize
not only were you effective with your
speech but you were effective as a human
being
that you took the time to slow down and
help someone who was unaware of how to
use the tools and it wasn't to push up
cell you weren't trying to sell him a
product you were just trying to get him
something that worked and and the effort
was there and you know that's why I
located me so bad so it's the cool
[Music]
you