[Music]
my name is Julie crocodile G I'm the
director of compliance and I am here to
moderate this panel discussion on track
and trace metric track and trace I will
say upfront that I'm sure I'm near
confident we're gonna come out of this
panel with more questions than answers
about track and trace just so you know
because it is a giant question mark for
the entire industry right now when is it
gonna start what's happening the these
are all big questions but for any
operator looking to the horizon and
seeing this coming it the most important
thing I think right now to emphasize is
that the the regulations currently
stipulate that all of these
record-keeping requirements that are
outlined you're obligated to be doing it
right now on a minimum of paper or some
sort of you know records so that
record-keeping onus is already here and
really looking at those regulations and
when you look at these these track and
trace elements and the things that are
going to have to be measured and the
points of this of the supply chain that
are going to be tracked that's kind of
the critical information that you need
to see and be incorporating into your
compliance programs and your operations
right now for anybody that hasn't taken
a gander at it here's a quick list of
some of the things you're gonna have to
enter into track and trace things like
the packaging of cannabis Goods the sale
of cannabis Goods the transportation of
cannabis Goods the receipt of cannabis
Goods the return of cannabis Goods the
destruction of disposal of cannabis
Goods lab testing and results any other
activity that they may choose to require
by any licensing
thirty at anytime you may have to put in
there you have to put information for
every activity for each of those
activities you have to put in the name
and type the you IDs the amount of the
Cannabis goods by waiter count the date
and time the activity happened the name
of the license number of whoever is
involved in it at any level of the
supply chain whether they're being
transported and so on and so forth the
date and time the arrival date the
estimated arrival time and when it
actually arrived and the driver's
license number of who's doing it so
those are some of the ones from the BCC
the I'm not done either there's more
thing just keep going you know if if
waste is disposed who disposed it what
was the employee's name what's their
employee number what was the reason that
it was destroyed or disposed and how
who's being collected it did you haul it
did somebody else haul it did you drop
it off how a manage did away
how much did away when it was there and
how much did away when you dropped it
off and any do any adjustments that have
to be made spoilage or following any
event any other information they might
need and all of these transactions have
to be put in to track and trace within
24 hours of them happening there were
efforts I guess where and that's just
the BCC
so that's just one agencies requirement
that doesn't go into the cultivation
side of the cultivation requirements for
track and trace which is that I mean
luckily cultivators you guys get three
days to put it in the system so you got
a little more time but there's every
event or change in disposition of your
plant material flowering destruction
disposal harvest processing storage
packaging all of those have to be
entered in at many different points and
ended back to the comments because we
can't stop talking about it they just
threw in another point of having to
weigh and enter the wet weight not just
the dry harvest weigh so this is why
these things are important in other
states people regularly bring on two to
three new employees whose sole job is to
monitor track and trace and to keep your
cyst
synched and to keep your physical
inventory synced you know that exactly
two to three employees so my company is
gonna have multiple distribution cross
docking locations around the state and
I'm gonna have to hire two the company's
gonna have to hire two to three people
just to run the track and trade system
and I'm get into this more but all those
requirements you listed are really fall
on the distributor because we're
alternately before this product goes to
retail we're supposed to make sure all
of that was put into the track and trade
system properly and we have to do that
however when we've done the training for
track and trace it's all about
cultivation right now there's not a
distribution track and trace training
per metric we have asked I have asked on
behalf of my clients it does not exist
California being very unique in that our
distribution model and our distributors
have a significantly more responsibility
including taxes than any other state
that metric is currently working in so
to Tim's point I had tell my clients
this is a line item in your budget when
you are thinking about who you're hiring
when you were thinking about how you're
going to forecast financials if you're
talking about how you're going to get
investment this is the biggest piece of
that it falls into compliance the
uncomfortable number that I generally
tell clients is it's 20 to 30% of your
operating budget currently moving
forward that should be designated to
specifically compliance when I say that
I do not mean legal
I mean track and trace compliance I like
to chime in that from like the
dispensary point of view because we're
the outlet that actually moves all the
product and I know that a lot of people
are freaking out I mean I you said it so
comically but it was scary as shit like
the stuff that we're gonna have to do
but I'm actually excited about this I
feel like here in California we're
building the national platform for how
we are gonna move this entire movement
that every single one of us is
volved and that we've been wanting this
to be national and international and we
are the pioneers in this industry so if
this kind of shit scares you good
however if it's gonna prevent you from
doing it right get out of the industry
because we have no choice now comment
when we have laws and regulations that
we don't want to see that are not guided
by people that work in the industry or
understand the industry but there's a
lot of this stuff that's really
important and that you know having a
system that's gonna be integrated having
good software that's gonna assist you
along the way and setting up good SOPs
right now last week last year to get you
prepared for what you're gonna do and if
this is the kind of stuff that like I
have seen when they kept when I got at
this industry four years ago we were
preparing for this and this is what we
have continued to do and we know that we
are going to have to continue to fight
if you're gonna be alive like over 90
percent of the companies that were on
the market two years ago are by E like
you're not here anymore
and they're not on my shelves and we're
having to find new product and right now
with what we just went through with July
first like my stores were actually in
really good condition content and
considering how the other ones were
because we had foresight and
understanding that breaths going on
vacation the end of June and we're gonna
get this shit taken care of beforehand
and that really what drove me to get it
done but honestly like we were sitting
so much better than a lot of stores
because they just didn't understand how
the regulations directly affected them
because they don't take a stance and
understand that they need to to read
these regulations and that's why we're
hiring people on also to just hire just
to handle compliance because as a
director of operations as the buyer for
the store I can't do it all I wear too
many hats and I didn't want to sound
pessimistic about track and trace
because I'm very excited the principle
is very exciting to me when I worked at
the Board of Equalization we talked
about tracking trace we talked about
what agencies were gonna be implemented
what type of data was gonna be
incorporated into a track and trace
system I believe track and trace is a
good thing I just want to know exactly
from my angle what is what I'm
responsible for and you know some
timelines when
gonna be in place when you know there's
been some promises by the state that
haven't come to fruition so here we are
so I'm very excited for track and trace
I think it's good for all the the legal
compliant actors and it reinforces our
place in the marketplace it also
provides you just from a economic
standpoint if you are prepared
you're not going to suffer I think this
is one of those great examples in time
where if you are an early adopter you
are going to reap those benefits it's
difficult I know from both the operators
on either of my side will tell you it is
a heavy lift but it is one that
ultimately will position them in the
marketplace to succeed they'll be
responsible they'll be known as
responsible operators along the supply
chain and from the retail perspective
they'll be trusted by the public to go
and secure the type of medication or
recreational product that they want so
as long as you are taking an active a
proactive stance about imposing what you
believe to be what the state wants is
we're starting to get that to be
crystallized if you have processes in
place SOPs if you're using them if
you're sending your shipping manifests
if you're using the tools that the
agencies have given you thus far
correcting them won't be such a painful
lift as what you hear from others who
are like this is going to take out my
business well if you weren't planning
for that unfortunately that's the
reality of what will happen and that's a
great point I mean at River that's what
we've been doing you know we've been
sending our shipping our invoices and
our Manifest into the BCC daily all the
test results on products and you know
January 1st all have gone to the bureau
and we are gearing ourselves up for this
we were gearing ourselves up for the for
the transfer the July 1st deadline even
though there was a lot of information
like oh they're gonna extend it they're
gonna extend it I never ever once
thought that they were gonna extend the
July 1st deadline I just
you know I know everybody in industry
was like it's gonna happen they're gonna
extend it I just being a regulator and
being on that side I knew that would
never happen
so you know being ready for this stuff
conditioning yourselves it's like you
know jogging in the morning you're
running trying to build that for a race
this is what this is so I would
recommend you do and that was a great
point and what I'd like to add on to
that is that as a buyer I had so many
companies that I have talked to since
January 1st and February when we got our
license that you're gonna be ready for
July you're gonna be you know your
packaging is gonna be there your lab
testing is gonna be there and I've had
all of these companies swear to me up
and down that they were gonna have their
shit together in a basket ready to go
and it was not anywhere close to the
basket like nothing was together we had
where my entire one of my departments
would be down to from 15 different
brands or different you know varieties
down to one item and I had several
companies that had their stuff together
like I'm gonna give props to heavy
hitters and dosis they were huge and
that some of these companies like up
north and Island that were able to give
me a range of products to have on my
shelf when no other store really had it
you know that's something that we did
not have the foresight these companies
did not and that's gonna stick on me as
a buyer remembering that you swore to me
that you would have it together and you
did not and right now I'm taking a lot
of companies without the maybe the
background that I'm searching for and
when I have that time where we can sit
down and have a dialogue but that time
will be over soon where it's like you
know right now any product but here in
the next few months things will be very
different as companies move forward and
I do think I just like to sit as painful
as it is for operators to be the guinea
pigs during this period it is an
incredible opportunity that we've gotten
to actually operate under emergency
regulations and have the opportunity to
truly experience the issues and problems
and hiccups so that we can in this
comment period before the regulations
are permanent have the opportunity to
actually test it out a little bit and
then suggest it but there's no it's not
to understate at all the impact that it
has been on operators and how difficult
it is for them to try to remain
compliant through the process because
something that might be is easy for a
regulatory agency is changing some
language has tens if not hundreds of
thousands dollars worth of impact on an
actual operating business that has to
redesign their packaging or pivot or
bring on all this extra labor or any
just the time that it takes where
they're like you can put a sticker on it
and just the cost of the labor to have a
bunch of people put a sticker on
something yeah exactly that those
aspects are are you know incredibly
difficult for the companies to be nimble
but it is important to keep your eyes
far forward on the horizon of those
regulations to see what's coming the
Department of Public Health said that in
the first five months of the new
regulations post January first they got
almost zero questions about packaging
and labeling in the transition period it
was only in that last few weeks before
it kicked in that suddenly everybody was
like oh shit you're serious like this is
happening and it was very difficult for
the companies that were not prepared to
do that pivot the universal symbol in
case anybody is unclear at this point
it shall be black if your packaging is
black then it can be well not on flour
we're talking about manufactured goods
it's very important manufactured goods
it must be black on flour wherever you
want to put it but I manufactured goods
at my speed black you can splash some
white on the back of it and still put it
on black packaging like if we spent less
time being upset about that concept
there were many solutions so if you
again if you stay ahead of it if you're
talking to your other operators if
you're going to your trade associations
there are so many solutions and
an industry I am always constantly
amazed at the ability to pivot and the
creativity that comes from the cannabis
space if you were willing to just engage
in a conversation and it should not go
unsaid all of you that are here you're
doing the first step in ensuring the
success of your business so you should
feel very accomplished and proud of
yourselves for showing up that is
basically what the cannabis industry as
a whole does it shows up industry I mean
just going through this whole process
and being a compliance director for a
distribution company so I mean
constantly on the phone with brands that
we represent and with the retailers we
saw and we're talking about regulations
we're talking about where that damn
universal symbol is supposed to be and
what color it's supposed to be and I'd
like those conversations I think that's
healthy I think you know we may disagree
and you know and maybe we have a
different reading of the regs but I
think that's great we're all trying to
get to this place this compliant place
wherever the state wants us to go and I
know the final rigs have different
packaging requirements now so pay
attention to that you know child
resistant packaging according to the
proposed final regs is on the retailer
now so we'll see if that actually
actually happens yeah but what we do
know what we do know about track and
trace if you have a temporary license
you're not required to be on it
depending on your locality I would like
to say because there are some local
there are some localities and up in
Humboldt that have their own local track
and trace that you have to be
functioning on already but as far as the
state is concerned and metric is
concerned it will be with the issuance
of your annual license
a clock starts ticking and you get your
annual license and you have so much time
to onboard to get your designated
Account Manager for metric track and
trace to be trained and it's a five day
window I believe in the regs right now
from if we
five days from getting your license to
have that person do the training as soon
as they've done that training you have
30 days to input every product you have
at whatever stage that it's in into your
track and trace everything has to be
input in that 30 days and after that
period of time its seed to sale nothing
can enter the system that isn't existing
in your system already at that point and
this is where I would actually really
like to see us making comment all of us
in the industry because as it comes to
the operator side like again we're the
ones moving your stuff and getting it
into patients hands and getting it to
customers hands is that it would be
wonderful and I'm not anticipating this
is that we really spend this fall and
this descend this early winter and to
focus on what the hell metric is and all
of us learning about it olives going
into multiple training modules so that
we can really master this so we have a
smooth transition because I don't know
about y'all but none of this has been
very smooth like this has been just
combated with questions constantly so I
would really love for the state to say
hey guys everybody's gonna work on this
this fall we're gonna get everybody's
licensing because you know they've
missed a lot of marks the state has
totally missed deadlines has left us in
just waiting the plane the waiting game
just hurry up and wait and what I would
love is for them to say hey everybody on
January 1st 2019
that's when metric starts because I'm
even confused as an operator that when
my stores are some of the first stores
here in LA there were licensed is I'm
gonna be placed in a situation where am
I only gonna be able to buy product from
distributors that are metric tracking
trays well then there I go again with
February where I couldn't buy product or
in July first when I don't have any
product on my shelves that every time we
do this this is a huge expense however
we've been in this game long enough that
we should have kind of had some
foresight on this and some money in the
bank but it is the situation great
comment point
Brett excellent metric is a it's
supposed to start from zero I think what
we've seen in other states that have had
an easier time is it has
beginning point unfortunately as clunky
as it was that didn't start on January 1
here in California so for commenting
that we have this opportunity to start
and that even temporary licensees
everybody January 1 2019 we do metric if
that's a universal comment we could be
so powerful as an industry to ask for
that just looking at what has happened
in other states we know I think there
was a great article and MJ Business
Daily over the weekend about Maryland
and the API that was part of metric was
trying to help consumers which was a
great thing right you as a consumer we
would want to know how much you've
purchased and how much you can purchase
within your purchasing limits not
everybody is a mathematician I know I am
a lawyer my math skills probably not the
best I would love if there was a
software that told me how much I still
could buy as a consumer what that did
unfortunately was overload the system
and therefore even other states outside
of Maryland had an impact because metric
wasn't able to keep up with the volume
what does that say to me California is
the highest volume of users from an
operational standpoint than the
teeny-tiny state of Maryland so we
probably have more operators than they
had both operators and consumers working
so if we take that into consideration
and that's sort of the basis of your
comment then maybe we can be effective
to really use that time as Brett said to
be prepared for metric so as a
distributor this is what I want to see
from metric so we have very clear
responsibilities according to state law
and the regs we collect the cultivation
tax we collect the excise tax we are
responsible for facilitating state
certified testing producing a CoA on the
product we also wondered at the current
metric system we have to check and make
sure that everything's entered
incorrectly and right now from the
training that my company
has has received from from metric and
I'm not trying to I don't want to like
sound like I'm knocking metric or and
maybe also something we need to consider
too is maybe the states kind of slow
rolling this as well maybe it's not
metric maybe you know there's there's
issues going on and stay with
implementation so you have to remember
that but these are important issues that
I need to see where I can as a
distributor where I can track these
issues where especially like taxes like
cultivation tax is a prime example right
now I'm supposed to collect cultivation
taxes on product that was manufactured
into a candy bar and how am I supposed
to know as a distributor how much
product how much flour or how much trim
was actually put into that product and
therefore remitting it to see DTF a
California Department tax and fee
Administration sorry for that acronyms I
need to see I need to see that
information as a distributor you know
all that information for the retailers
when I send an invoice to a retailer you
know the excise tax I need to make sure
that that's in the track and trade
system I need to make sure that all this
data that's put in is entered in there
so as a distributor I can properly track
this and make sure that one I get it to
a retailer that it's you know compliant
and everything and also it needs to be
expeditious we don't need to be slowing
down it's already slow right now you
hinted at a lot of the brands not being
on board and we were we were there too a
lot of our brands just didn't believe us
and so they're catching up so you know
making this process is expeditious as
possible it's already slow with that and
testing and everything so you know
that's that's what I want to see as a
distributor and I want to get this
product out to the retailers as quick as
possible and so they can sell it and put
it in a consumers hands so you know my
company makes money the retailer makes
money and the consumer gets the product
that they ultimately want so you know
that's that's kind of my view of it and
I haven't had a lot of those questions
answered from about metrics and you know
one of the other thing that's important
is and we're missing in these
conversations is the local jurisdiction
the more confused they are the less
likely they are to adopt an ordinance
we're still at what 30 percent of the
the states 482 cities and 58 counties
that are regulating when I go out part
of what I do for clients is open up
cities I served as the special city
attorney for the city of Hollister
drafting their regulatory ordinance one
of the biggest questions they asked was
what was going on with track and trace
because it was important for them to
know that their operators were going to
be adopting into that similar to what
Julian was talking about with humble and
CIPA some people are carrying two tags
because it was so important for that
County or that city that jurisdiction to
have some assemblance of track and trace
when the state wasn't able to answer
those critical questions so it's also
understanding that so you can engage
with your municipalities for those of
you that are going through the planning
and building process that haven't opened
yet these are real critical questions
they'll also come back to how you pay
your local taxes because they're gonna
want to look at your track and trace to
make sure that you're paying the
appropriate amount so this is really a
systemic issue it's a bedrock issue for
me and one that everybody needs to be
able to speak eloquently on because
you're gonna have questions from your
retailer from your distributor from your
cultivator from your city from the state
investing in this and really starting to
understand it even though it's
complicated and difficult is going to be
how you are successful so we're all
spending a lot of money on point-of-sale
systems and he our PC our peas and we
have no idea how those are going to tie
into the track and trace system so I
would and this is very this is huge
because this is if they do not tie in
properly you're gonna be doing a lot of
manual entry which is going to increase
your operations cost so it's gonna hit
your it's going to hit your pocketbook I
believe you will see the marketing
points for POS systems radically
transform with the launch of track and
trace where it's going to
go from it's beautiful and iPad
interface to does it talk to track and
trace and does it talk to it in an
automated way or a manual way which I
would say when you are talking to your
POS companies is a number one question
to ask because a lot of them will be
like sure it interfaces with track and
trace but what they mean is it at the
end of the day you can download a CSV
file that you're gonna spend hours
formatting the columns and then you're
gonna try to upload it to track and
trace and 98% of the time it's gonna
fail and you're gonna rip all your hair
out and it's not actually updating track
and trace in an automated way and that's
the point as I work I have a client
who's a very well-known POS provider
track and trace provider and one of our
biggest issues right now is that it's
not the API with metric doesn't work so
it's not that they can tell you that
they can do something it's that it
doesn't compute so you do at the end of
the day with several of these almost all
of the POS systems will have to do some
manual data entry and those are
important questions to ask and I don't
think there is that widget or that fix
that's been made yet to make that API
work so I just want to like kind of jump
on that one too about POS systems
obviously at any retail business that is
a cornerstone of how you stay compliant
and able to be successful in getting
people in and out of your store and so
we we formerly had bio track and we were
ready to try something that was gonna be
a little bit more modern and there was
gonna have some better abilities for us
and so we had tried out we had talked
with several companies and we made a
decision to go with the company trees
I've heard multiple different things
from multiple different companies one of
the companies that I highly recommend as
well is green bits every time I've
worked with them they've been amazing
like their team is and from everything
that being told as well that they are
metric compliant
and and integrated and they will be
fully working with that because at the
end of the night I'm going to be paying
all this extra payroll and be going
through managers quite rapidly when
they're gonna have to be staying there
late uploading and making sure that when
that distributor dropped off that
product at my store that we entered in
that 24 digit PIN or if not it's gonna
kick back the entire damn report and
that is gonna be bad staff morale and
that's honestly one of my most important
things that I look for in my store is
making sure that my staff is happy
because if a staff is happy they're
productive and that metric is really
gonna slow things down and that's why we
need to streamline this stuff as much as
possible so that's why you're very much
you urge you to please comment and and
speak about how we need to postpone
maybe metrics so that we all jump on at
the same time so that we're all on the
same page and on that is please if
you're in the industry and we get that
allowance do not take it for granted I
actually do like do your homework and I
think there's a gentleman over here that
actually had a question just summarizing
the question it was this gentleman has
multiple license types he's gonna get
hit from cultivation retail distribution
and manufacturing and track and trace
requirements therein and has been
approached by many different
out-of-state operator
consultants saying you know we can help
you with training in advance of this
system and how useful that may or may
not be and what do you do to prepare now
for that system it's important to
remember that California is unique I
think this is a tried-and-true issue
sometimes our state consultants are
great right am I gonna knock that but
when you're in California you've got
resources all around you we are all
going through this together I don't know
if any of you are on band watch but
Jackie McGowan site is great it will
Network you with others who are going
through and suffering through some of
the same trials and tribulations that
you are going through and together like
I said before California is very
resilient and as an industry we tend and
now need to lean on each other more
because we have different license types
problem with outside consultants is they
come in and they
you oh so you're a myth no you're not
you're a manufacturer and you're a type
6 type you're a type 7 type 6 type n
type P right you're different and now
you're not just different in semantics
you're different in what you're allowed
to do and how the product moves through
the supply chain so you're a vertically
integrated business there are other
vertically integrated businesses go to
your community your cannabis community
and ask what those problems are as we go
through it together
I know CCIA will wind up doing a lot of
metric training and there will be a
committee on that go to your trade
associations that are local and pull
from your local community because it is
true I've seen outside consultants come
in and do an application and don't
realize that a local application is the
equivalent of another state's
state level application and all the
sudden enough to clean up a mess for a
client that maybe got ousted from a
jurisdiction that they should have been
in so it's it's a tagline of be cautious
beware beat your best advocate if
somebody tells you that they can tell
you how metric is gonna work in
California ask them to show you first
the proof is in the pudding who else
have you done this for I also think that
the like I was reading the list before
where this is where you're practicing
your internal programs and building them
around the stated regulatory of
requirements for record-keeping is the
best thing that you can look at is what
is it saying in the regs are these
checkpoints of when do I have to weigh
it when do I have to report it when do I
have to write it down when do it you
know all of these transfer points the
shipping manifest is already something
it's a document that's gonna be in track
and trace that's already been released
by the agency that people are supposed
to be using now I don't know how many of
you guys are actually using a shipping
manifest to move product from one
location good for you BCC C a govt send
it to the basic BCC website do it every
day that's great and and it's the good
thing about this period before track and
trace is kicked in is that it's practice
it's paper practice because you do not
want to be trying to figure this out
when the 30-day clock is ticking to
actually enter it all in there for real
you want to be able to troubleshoot and
test drive these systems and have your
staff be confident and know what they're
doing and informed about the check
points and not have it all be this
incredible load that's dumped on them in
this very short window and in working I
mean it's the big catch phrase that
everybody talks about culture of
compliance and a culture of compliance
but it's hugely important because it's
very important from every level of your
employees to understand why they have to
do this and not think that it's just
some ridiculous rigmarole that you're
making up to make their lives difficult
that it is a regulatory legal
requirement that could result in
tremendous amounts of fines in the loss
of your license if somebody doesn't fill
out the form and I know Julie does this
we do this at my um in my companies we
can come out and audit you there are
compliance services that will come out
and we will work through that with you
and we'll say oh you know what
hey your seller's permits not out you
know that nifty little temporary license
that you got that's sitting in the back
office that has to go out in a
conspicuous place for everybody to see
and we'll go through and look at your
shipping manifest in and see that you're
doing it correctly
now that is a great expense that has a
huge ROI for your company so hire an
outside person before BC CDFA or DPH
come out and do an on-site audit so
there are companies out there that do
that you just need to look for them and
I know this gentleman has been so
patient
what I'm gonna say about that all 10
mental states and DC although uh Pamela
right
yes and was 100% correct California is a
lot more complex we are passing at a
country with our laws and everything I
would interject themselves and what can
I forget see you guys here asking from
out-of-state how they did things we have
resources and what questions give my
card afterwards if plenty of FLD with
people have deviled metric the three
biggest things that I would say about
metric it's gonna stuff
it's not to be a punchline or anything
like that bad data in if bad data out
yep never smartest people on that system
we're gonna be fuck I agree with that
couldn't have said that better something
that I've been blessed with is
colleagues and friends in this industry
that have helped me along the way and I
do kind of want to give a shout out to
one of my closest colleagues and I
consider our true friend is Cassie
Walker in the back and she is the SOP
queen she is the one that comes through
and makes sure that every all the I's
are dotted the T's are crossed and has
gotten our inventory on point with our
stores because that is something in our
industry as people just took no
responsibility for where there was their
inventory was the only time you counted
it is if you needed to order the product
and then I was like yeah it's a little
off like that's not gonna be acceptable
like everything has to be on point and
that was what I was really excited this
mornings when I was in the store over at
Green Cross and Cassie comes through and
like all the flowers on point and I'm
like that's amazing because that is what
we have to work to you like metrics not
gonna be that bad if your inventories
are on point and your SOPs are on point
and you actually have protocols and this
is what's forcing us to professionalize
our industry I come from emergency
veterinary medicine where we have
controlled drugs like shit that actually
kills people and you know unlike
cannabis you know and so it's like we
have to count our fentanyl every month
we have to count our morphine and our
hydromorphone and ketamine and we have
to actually count this stuff and
actually provide this to this day and to
the federal government on where this is
going and so when I got into cannabis I
was so shocked because we had no
accountability whatsoever people would
just show up with a trash bag full of
weed and then you know sell it to the
store and it's now we're in this system
where it's like you have to take
responsibility for where you're at and a
lot of people that are griping about it
they just don't want to change the way
that they're doing things but this is
going to make us better and you'll have
somebody on your team that know
how to write SOPs and knows how to adapt
to when we get a new regulation instead
of sitting there and wasting all this
energy bitching and moaning about it I
actually put that energy into it and I
have been blessed with the people around
me in this industry that share the same
level of integrity and the philosophy of
the movement of cannabis and want to see
this to be successful and that's why I'm
very thankful for and to echo what the
gentleman from Baker was saying one of
the most tremendous resources that I've
had for really getting a glimpse into
how metric and track and trace works and
what it looks like is doing demos with
POS companies in other states because
you can go look at look at the other
states that have track and trace the
other states that have metric who are
the top what are the POS companies
working there and call them up and they
have been the most helpful people and I
have done walkthroughs and demos and
they've showed me what the forms look
like and how it looks like to enter it
and how it interfaces with that and
they're they're a tremendous resource
and then what's great is you can ask
them for references of what companies
are they working with there and then
have those companies help you understand
how is that process what's it like and
that that community is available that
we're not the first well there are
distinctions and complications to
California we're not the first ones
going into this track and trace system
so there are other people who have
experience to share and that's a
difference between a consultant and a
company so a company that's gonna walk
you through a POS system or if you call
a cultivator or a manufacturer or you
meet somebody at upcoming and CIA who is
in another metric state and you ask them
those questions that is very different
than a consultant so I just want to make
sure that that was said because I think
that was a great point and thank you for
raising it the other thing I will say is
start reconciling your inventory every
14 days you got to do it when you come
online it should be something that as
soon as you get the temperament before
you do because now everybody that's
getting temperaments is starting day one
right day one you do your inventory 14
days later you reconcile that inventory
make it a pattern in a practice it'll be
a happy
that you will just automatically you and
your staff will know how to do and the
14 days is a requirement and in BCC reg
so that's just not just the number she
was making up that's actually like a
requirement so we were practicing that
too and if you're you know you have to
be within 2% so it's kind of a fine kind
of a fine line so you know practice that
my only we mentioned about other states
now others a lot of other states don't
have a distribution model so so this is
where track and trace kind of worries me
and I can't really look to another state
on what I need is a distributor from
metric and what what I can expect I mean
we'll figure it out whatever it is but
it's a little tough for us but I am glad
that you know for retailers that you
know they have some examples my name is
Rico sorry for you anybody didn't hear
me we work with a ton of POS systems
across the across the nation ton of
track and trace systems and bottom line
is California's more complex there's
more volume than everywhere else we have
different channels and everywhere else
it's going to suck is a platform chosen
by the state whether it's bio track with
this metric there's other systems as
well they don't know what they're doing
they get chosen by the state they get a
contract and it's gonna crash a bunch of
times whether it's metric whether it is
your POS you're using so this is why I
was saying I wasn't trying to joke or
anything get your smartest people on the
system because your business is on the
line number one you need a backup person
as well you need a great great SOPs for
backups as well you need truth in data
as well our company we try to connect
all your systems so everybody has the
same data work with were three companies
that work with other platforms as well
because you're going to need those
backups you're gonna need that integrity
from your backup system and then your
backup to your backup system I know it
sounds like a lot and it is a lot but
these are the things you need to do to
operate in this business all right so
when you go out and you have a lot of
POS system saying the Oh your POS
compliant we're a metric compliant in
California nobody's compliant so that's
a lie
they've applied and they've passed the
tests but they're not compliant nobody
is using the system yet so what you
should do there's some systems that are
working there's some pluses that are
working out of state they're compliant
with metric ask them questions it
doesn't mean they're gonna have all the
answers cuz nobody is doing it in
California if you have a POS that is
that is approved by metric ask them a
ton of questions ask their clients a ton
of questions don't jump in because it's
a new shiny object and it looks good
make sure that it works and then you
always keep the other guy's phone number
handy because something will fail and if
they're not giving the service you need
move that's all I say all right I want
to leave a little time for questions
does anybody have any questions
working with companies that are willing
to interface together if you're not
compliant in what respect you could lose
your license your license could be
revoked and then you could be precluded
from then going into another
jurisdiction we can look no further than
our neighbor Colorado who lives to try
to come into California sweetleaf is a
good example right looping that was an
issue that and this that's a great
example actually sweetleaf because let's
let's think about it break it down the
issue was looping right and they were
asking whether or not you could buy more
than one ounce in one day so you just
went to the back of the line is that a
good SOP practice in general if you were
a retail operator and somebody told you
oh yeah you could do that don't worry
the regs think they say that they're
just ambiguous in that area does that
seem like you would be diverting product
is there a reason that one person would
need to purchase an entire pound of
marijuana in one day for themselves and
wasn't going to spread it around to
other people if it sounds like a bad
idea it probably is because now that
company
we'll have to because in both local
jurisdictions in California and the
state if you have any violation same or
similar within a marijuana industry you
have to disclose it and if you think
that with the high level of competition
in this state a local jurisdiction is
going to select an operator who had
twenty nine twenty six licenses revoked
in the city of Denver because they were
providing too much product without
tracking and tracing and ensuring that
there wasn't diversion then that is it
that will never happen
so compliance today is we are livelihood
tomorrow because this happened what four
or five years later they don't care once
these agencies set the dust settles and
they have nothing better to do they have
five years to audit you here in
California what you do today will harm
you tomorrow
I think that that goes like back to what
Pamela was saying here is that your SOPs
in place so staying compliant should be
how you make sure that every day you're
going through that but also having
integrity on how you run your business
so it's not just about staying compliant
like there's always gonna be loopholes
to every single one of these regulations
like I don't know like having mobile
billboards that run around with med men
on them and they sit on in your back
parking lot of your business so that
whenever you're low on product it's a
mobile billboard for their company
that's the kind of stuff that does not
gain you respect in this industry so
maybe you're finding a loophole to be
compliant but you are not gaining the
respect of your brothers and sisters
that have fought their asses off to
pioneer this industry and that does not
gain our respect I don't care about
competition competition drives us to do
better but when you are going to find
loopholes to stay compliant but you're
just bullshit with it that upsets me
because we're in this I'm in this for
the medicine I care that adult you
should be totally legal for people and
we need to stay compliant to make sure
that happens but I am fighting for the
medicine that has saved my life and then
it saved so many others so notice they
will come back and get you yeah the
cannabis industry is a community so
every time there is an issue where
license is revoked because of
non-compliance that hurts us all that
just doesn't it doesn't hurt just the
business that got their license revoked
hurts us all because when I'm trying to
go into another city and they're like
well I read this article about this
company that did this you're probably
going to do the same right you're prade
they lump you all in together they lump
us all in together and so this is a
community kind of effort too we all need
to be compliant because we're just
hurting everybody else we're keeping
another another locality from opening up
do you know how many cities there are in
the state of California there's about
fourth
482 cities and 58 counties and special
jurisdictions on top of that this is
this is a nation and when we have a bad
actor and one part of the state it could
be in the smallest little city it could
affect us all and this it's important to
think of track and trace is not just
some horrible record-keeping onus that
was came out of thin air like it's an
antidote to fear it's an antidote to
demonstrating a comprehensive system of
accountability and transparency that it
does something unprecedented in industry
there is no other industry that has ever
had to have this level of rigor from
seed to sale and the thing that gets me
excited is if we can do this then we get
to turn around in ask it of other
industries to say I don't want to know
Campbell Soup whether this tomato come
from I want to know as a consumer I want
to see this chain I want to see where
everybody else is doing tomfoolery
because they don't have to do this so
that we are pioneering this incredible
system of consumer protection of market
protection of transparency of
information that everybody on the chain
who is a compliant operator who cares
about patience who cares about what
people put in their body we want to know
where did it come from we want to know
the legacy of this product we want to
know what it contains we want to know
what the test results are and so it's
not just some horrible thing that's
happening to us it's an amazing and
comprehensive system and it also
provides federal protection because what
we're demonstrating is that there is not
diversion in our system that these
operators are compliant that they are
operating compliantly under the state
regulations so thank you very much feds
you can stay over there because we are
willing to expose this information yeah
this gentleman asked how are we
submitting our reports to the BC secret
you're in an industry that's never been
before yeah so so we submit invoices
every day to the BCC before they go out
for delivery and then we also submit any
testing results that we have from
product in fact any state certified
tests that come from a lab are submitted
to the BCC so they'll if it passes is no
problem if there's a fail for like a
label claim THC CBD or pesticides which
doesn't happen very often they will
inform us what your remediation method
will state a remediation method if it's
just a label claim fell distributors in
the state of California can real able
those those and that's pretty easy as
long as they're not over the limits so
yeah we simply paper records we have we
just we just scan them and and and email
them to the BOE RC the BCC sorry now BOE
so yeah just PDFs yeah just yeah what
type what percentage of retailers pay
river distributing the taxes that's a
hundred percent because we collected Co
D because we are responsible for
emitting that tax and we have 90 days
from whenever that transaction takes
place so we're not gonna float the
excise tax there's just no way any
distributor in the right mind shouldn't
be doing that you know I'm sure there's
a lot of honest you know retailers that
would pay those taxes and pay that but
honestly in the position we're in now we
collect that Co D okay not and you
actually can't do full consignment
anymore you actually have to take the
excise tax at the time of delivery so
that there's no there is no consignment
on excise tax and I think that that's
also something that we need to let
patients and customers know now it's
like this whole I go to the events all
the time they keep talking about this
15% I'm like what 15% are you talking
about because this is on like on the
fair market value this is a 24% tax that
patients these are actual patients so I
deal with mothers that spend $1500 a
month before all of this happened to
provide seizure medication for their
children and now they are getting hit
not just with excise tax but also with
sales tax and then 5% medical tax and
they can't go get a medical card because
the city is so fucked with the way that
they hand these things out that it takes
them months to be able to get their
actual card the way that they're
supposed to because they're getting
denied every time they go to the office
or the appointments aren't available to
removal the sales and use tax which to
Julie's point earlier how is that not a
lawsuit you are imposing taxes adult use
taxes for medicine yeah but the but I
mean and sorry you know to bust
everybody's bubble but cannabis is not
considered a medicine by the state of
California you can't get a
recommendation you you can't get a
prescription you can get a
recommendation you you we had this issue
come up at BOE all the time in fact we
you know there was legislation to
basically for medical cannabis before
prop 64 to have a sales tax exemption
from those products considering it
medicine but it's considered a
recommendation not a prescription it's
not considered a medicine and it's not
you're not relieved of any sales tax
liability other than if you're a
qualified medical patient with a card
from your County
the news mm use tax tax tax excise tax
collected by the distributor or paid
elected
it depends on the business arrangement
so he's asked he's asking if the
distributors required to collect the
excise tax no and yes
so yes in the sense if it's an arm's
length transaction and when I say arm's
length transaction that means that I'm a
distributor and I have no absolutely no
relationship ownership in the retail arm
of that company now there's a lot of
micro businesses out there where they
have distribution retail manufacturing
or cultivation whatever they can have
three of those license so if I do have
that relationship then the excise tax is
collected at the point of sell on
whatever that product sold for
that's a it's an arm's-length
transaction sotae for simple layman's
point of view yes that I wouldn't if I
didn't own any part of that retailer
yes it's an arm's length transaction I
applied the state the markup the sixty
percent markup which that you get to
your twenty four percent you get to
twenty four percent number and then I
charged the excise tax and it's on the
invoice the dispensary remits it to the
distributor and then we take it and then
we remit it to California Department tax
and fee Administration
we made up our own invoices that are
compliant we ran them by BCC so he's
asking there are some kind of sample
invoices out there sample manifest I
just want to be sure we have time to get
to all because I will go deep in the
weeds on tax questions that is a tangled
mess of hell so the gentleman in the
back has a question so the question was
can you set up a sandbox to enter the
metric system and kind of play around
with it we have entered a sandbox River
has but there's really not much on
distribution it's all about cultivation
so even though we're in the sandbox
there's really nothing for us to see
yeah I mean Fran well the company that
created metrics my understanding was
made to track blueberries in Florida I
mean that was what this software was
created for it it was never intended to
be a cannabis tracking software and it
certainly never envisioned the maturity
and complexity in on Genuity of a
California cannabis marketplace so
there's so many aspects of this software
being pushed to do things that it was
not necessary I mean it definitely was
not designed to do and it has not been
contemplated yet it's amazing when the
regulatory agencies were first releasing
some of their application materials but
they had no idea how complex just the
product outputs were I think the first
thing they had it was like concentrates
shatter vapes that was it there was this
like they're like what else do you do
with it
and so it's just the learning curve that
we're in and I have a lot of empathy for
the agencies as well they thought they
had a three year period of time to roll
out a medical plan and then prop 64
happened and it was like oh by the way
January you need to do this so it's been
a rush job on all levels in in the
active people who are the operators
having to navigate
system with them are the ones who are
the guinea pigs and suffer the
consequences of all of these changes
that's a really good point you know when
when prop 64 came along I was working
for the BOE and I was thinking hey we
just worked on these medical laws we got
them passed we're gonna let these roll
out we're gonna get right regulations
we're gonna see how they work and then
all of a sudden you know prop 64 and
then we're like oh shit it's gonna pass
it so we're gonna have two separate
systems we're gonna have a medical and
we're gonna have a W system which we did
for a while until they merged them all
together and the Senate bill 94 and some
other trailer bills so and that's where
I would like to see us stop focusing on
the competition that we've that's been
the business game for so many years and
really rely on each other right now to
really move forward there is gonna be
enough business for all of you I promise
as an operator like there's enough for
all of you and we need to work together
to make this happen thank you
because it truly is art as the big issue
right now beating each other up
I work in Sacramento and I see these
freakin wars we have with one another
but joy and like I mean it's just
ridiculous come on like let's get over
it and work together this gentleman over
here don't be this guy I don't know if
anybody recognizes the guy in the front
of the shirt yeah who is that what's
this guy's name yeah don't be that guy
trying to push all your competition off
the cliff while everybody is in this
very perilous situation I mean med men
is going around there handing out cards
in front of every other they're going on
to weed maps and Leafly and basically
seeing which competition is low on
products and they're sending street
teams to basically swarm those
dispensaries and hand fliers out drive
their Med men distribution trucks around
to basically take their business while
they're at their weakest point that is a
fuckin shitty practice
and I'm calling it out and don't any of
you do what they do compete fight but do
it in the right way so the question was
can we provide clarity as to sampling
along all of the supply chain I can give
you an example what we do at River as
far as sampling so and we've ran this by
the regulator's by the taxation
officials and I say taxation officials
because there's tax implications to
samples so what we do is we sell samples
not for resale to retailers for a very
discounted price and we've gotten
clarification from California Department
tax and fee Administration that those
products are not under the excise tax
regime so they're under the sales and
use tax regime so we charge themselves
in use tax whatever that is whatever
locality they're in so that's how we
handle samples essentially at River no
but in that situation because we're
making the sell to the retailer as the
distributor were we're responsible for
collecting that sales and use tax and
remitting it to the state so that was a
very that was one of the issues that
came up right away if it's like cave we
provided samples to retailers like hey
this is our new latest brand you know we
want to promote then well you can't give
away cannabis goods for free anymore so
you know I think we kind of divide I'm
not gonna say it was you know the we
were the first people thought of it we
thought of this idea of discounted
sample products not for resale with a
clear sticker and you know getting on
track and trace that we're gonna be able
to do that I don't know is there gonna
be a queue for not not for resale and
that's the situation for us as as a
buyer for stores as how the days of
samples like we're not there anymore
which is also great though because we
also have I know what your lab testing
is you I know what your pesticide
testing all of these things that before
you know I I knew a guy that knew a guy
you know and so it's a lot more
respectful as far as how they're coming
at it in the industry yes everything is
coming in to me in sample form but it's
coming in to me and an invoice because
everything has to be tracking traced if
not then these companies would just be
like it's diversion and itself like oh
we're gonna make all this product and
call it samples and we're still gonna
enter into our metric track and trace
that's not gonna float because how are
you gonna take all this product and
eventually move it down here and then
some of its gonna have to be moved into
samples you're not gonna know what that
is from the beginning so it needs to
come in to me with an invoice and so
that I can I just go ahead and enter it
into my system right now as sample you
know floor Cal this you know when I get
it from River so that I'm able to just
go ahead and allocate that that out it
moves through my cut track and trace and
bam it is now sold and out of my system
and it has been paid its taxes the whole
way through and so that's how we you
have to move forward with samples in
it's not a bad system it's a way for us
to track and trace everything it's just
not the old days where they could just
throw down some eighths and some joints
and and a vapor cartridge and edibles
and I mean I mean that's what cannabis
is for sir no and that's the whole
purpose we want the we want the buyers
and we want the bud tenders we want them
to use that product so they can convey
that experience with but back to our
original theme I would say that this is
an excellent area begging of your
comments during this comment period the
agencies have admitted they had a
tremendous blind spot in oversight in
terms of any comprehension of the back
end actual sales process of what happens
and how products get to the shelf the no
free samples was intended as a consumer
facing issue they never considered well
how does anybody know what they want to
buy especially in a system where a
retailer cannot get their money back for
a product that they buy and doesn't sell
well they even cannot if the retailer
sells a vape cart to a consumer and then
they find out it doesn't work the
retailer is supposed to destroy it they
can't send it back to the manufacturer
distributor
them to say well I don't know let's find
out what was wrong with it and let's do
some more research and wire our
cartridges failing as it's written right
now in the regs the retailer would
destroy a defective product not be able
to get return it for a replacement to
the distributor so there's a lot of
holes in that area to look at in terms
of how should the sales process work
because you would think in a track and
trace system it's not that hard to have
a product category that's listed not for
resale these are samples these are for
education these are for R&amp;D like those
things but they but you have to
articulate the need for those solutions
as an operator from the back end and one
of the issues on samples is so right now
every sample I give you has to be state
certified tested so it has to go through
the whole process of state certified
testing you know I mean it's like this
is one of the on the comment period this
is a huge issue and thanks for bringing
that up I mean that's that's a huge
issue we need to deal with how are we
going to promote these products we have
to we can't just like I can't just like
drop off a bunch of product at your
dispensary and say here sell a it
doesn't work that way we want to know
what the products like the experience
you know the quality what does it look
like what does the flower look like yeah
and you're you're absolutely right
there's only a certain amount of
products that can be given back to a
distributor return and that's
manufacturer products that are defective
that's it you can't return flower you
can't do anything I mean it's very very
limited
I believe that's almost all the time we
have do we have any more burning
questions from summer oh yes hello I see
you up front
I'm just shielding myself from this
bright
the biggest issue that I found that the
question was from the manufacturers
perspective is there an amount that
you're required to charge the biggest
issue is the taxes they don't care if
you sell it for a penny it all depends
on how the taxes are brought through the
process and it might be depending on who
you talk to it the CDC of a you know
there's been different versions of this
so for a full sized sample that's
exactly the same thing as a retail
sample they may want to see the full
excise tax carry through for that
product so it's it's really important to
clarify with the tax agency what they
are gonna want to see and to and to run
that by them to make sure that you're
doing that in a compliant way because
the agencies will be like sure penny
programs go for it but but it's the tax
piece because if you're doing that wrong
the CDT FA has stated they're gonna
consider that tax fraud CD T FA is also
implementing their own regulations as
well so you gotta watch those we're
talking about BCC and all these other
three the three main regulating agencies
well CD T a CD T FA at this time is also
working through the regulatory process
because they are under an emergency
regulations process right now and
they're adopting their final regulations
on cannabis so pay attention to that as
well be forewarned I had a client that
had CD t fa show up for an audit so they
are doing that as well the other
agencies you always want to be thinking
about if you're a cultivator the water
boards and the California Department of
Fish &amp; Wildlife are chomping at the bit
they have been waiting impatiently to
regulate this industry so they're
they're off to the races
if you're a cultivator make them your
friend
[Music]