topic that I spent some time discussing
with folks is what happens to a market
that was medical only and when adult use
rolls out right and so what we've seen
which I find very very interesting is
when all of a sudden anxiety or chronic
pain or lack of appetite doesn't become
a qualifying condition and you actually
have to prove a need for for a medical
card that the product landscape changes
you know completely yeah right me
because all them all the taxes are being
made on the adult use side and so that's
where you see all the super high potency
flour go through a lot of the edibles
and then when you find in a medical side
is a lot more topical applications is a
lot more maybe inhalers things like that
is that something you seen as well
California I think it's a good example
on how that switched and it switched
from the the medical wherever it is like
medical medical medical and now it's
recreational and that's like well now I
don't have to right now I can go back to
just you know recreational right
wouldn't without having a medical excuse
my only concern what something like that
is taxation yep
taxation will actually drive people yep
either back to the medical or back to
the black market was even worse yeah I
know and we've we've totally seen
exactly that happen I mean you know
everyone the taxation in Colorado we saw
that the gap between what taxes are
being paid for medical and what taxes
are being paid for adult use we're
actually pretty good because what
happened was you're finding people who
don't need that card willing to pay the
taxes to go into a adult you shop and
find a product they need and the state
is incentivized to make sure they do so
because they make more tax revenue on
those individuals but those who really
need help are able to go into their
medical provider and you know honestly
see a product line that's much more
tailored for them and what they need so
I know we talked about like the CBD
being the entry point yep for non
cannabis consumers yeah I see the
medical market being the same as CBD at
the state level I completely agree
yeah medical is a way for a state to
start and like very indirectly get into
the market absolutely then transition
over to record
yeah and it's basically it's it's proof
to the public that the sky is not gonna
fall true the minute we legalize right
that we're gonna go to do this you're
gonna wake up tomorrow and everything's
gonna be fine your neighbors aren't
gonna be like all walking around stoned
all the time yeah I mean look we've all
had those friends yeah where you go out
doesn't matter have a good time maybe
you have a drink or two but there's
always that one friend that potentially
has one too many yeah absolutely
yeah and it becomes hell at the other
night so for those people that think
like Oh cannabis cannabis it's a simple
question like at the end of the night
and we take two segments one friend that
drinks too much yeah and one friend that
consumes too much cannabis which one do
you want to deal with it the end oh my
god I'd much rather deal with a guy who
was too high right he's gonna raid your
fridge
yeah eat your Twinkies maybe to you know
ask you for you to take him a
jack-in-the-box or even better maybe
he's just gonna order through door -
zaps and get his food and then pass out
in your couch pass out of your couch
it's gonna be good absolutely he's gonna
wake up feeling good the next day right
unlike the other friend who's gonna be
in health yeah absolutely and and that's
I think that's that's a big thing to
understand from a consumption
perspective that now people
misunderstand about cannabis ya know
it's and I think you know I think a lot
of it is you mentioned this earlier that
the average individual will not fess up
to being a consumer they won't when when
confronted with a stranger asking them
right and so for me I've always tried to
do everything I can to be very forward
and open about my consumption true with
my family with my friends with other
professionals and the stores because I
think we're guys like us who have been
professionals for a very long time we're
the first ones through the wall right
were the first ones to be in this
industry and say hey guys this really
isn't a big deal no it's not it really
isn't a big deal you know we've consumed
together at events and it's like hey
well we can still function again we're
consume responsibly right it's no
different than having a drink at the end
of a day of a conference or whatever it
might be
and the more people see and I see this
with my parents as well right I love to
use my parents as an example you know
immigrants from Costa Rica very wary of
legal guidelines you know don't want to
be on the wrong side of the law for
anything that was a fun conversation to
tell them when I first got into the
industry right but then again I've
always been the problem child so they
figured I was gonna be the one hand
doing that sort of thing anyway
yeah same here yeah but then it started
with me and they were like well yeah
that he would try anything
so whatever but then my sister started
asking me for advice on on what to do
and I started giving her some
recommendations and it helped her with
some conditions that she had and I think
between my sister and myself both openly
consuming and my parents seeing this and
just being around it more and realizing
hey this really isn't a big deal at all
right it's it's it's like it allows
people to get to let their guard down a
little bit and if they see somebody who
they trust consuming and then realizing
oh you know he's not going crazy right
now maybe this is something there's
something to this I think that's you
know that's a step in the right
direction and that's how we'll get more
and more people to be on on the right
side of this topic yeah I I don't I
don't disagree with you there
[Music]