[Music]
tell us about the alliance
okay well Trinity County has its first
official trade association non-profit
member-driven agriculture Alliance and
basically we've been a really tight-knit
community always and we've been doing
all of our work as licensed participants
in the cannabis world especially as
farmers all just grassroots from the
beginning you know it has Trinity County
better enjoy to deal with no no I mean
not a right the regulations the policy
the politics the backlash from
conservative side of the county which
borders the Central Valley and has a
very different cultural mindset than
humble yeah we're in the southern we're
in West where were eight miles from the
whole county line in Grandpa Valley it's
over big mountains but they're already
know they're over there over a mountain
from us there's been a lot of crops when
Western Trinity has been really that's
the thing I was going to say is it's
been really painful in a lot of ways to
have to go out and deal with politics
but also it's democracy in action and
we're taking it into our own hands and
we had to because we were we were
looking at a van we were looking in 2016
at Trinity County part of the Emerald
triangle having a hard ban on commercial
licensed cannabis and we had to all buck
up and get out there and go start
participating in our local government
and it was high time that our generation
did that because we've been so
disconnected because we don't trust it
we don't believe in it and I mean it
will say it's proven to me that it is
exactly what I thought it was going to
be but at the same time our community
was really brought together and forced
to forced to like bring these issues out
into the open because in for so long in
Trinity it was just like nobody talked
about it in public everybody knew what
they had going on in their backyard but
everybody had a cover story it wasn't
like it was a very still secret behind
the green curtain in society even within
our own communities which are really
remote and really tighten it and people
really look out for each other it's a
really sparsely populated County it's
fourteen thousand people and if you were
to iron out flatten out all the
mountains and if you flattened out the
acreage because it's very steep you'd be
the size of Texas so there's 14,000
people nestled in these little valleys
and lots of crannies with these huge
mountains between us and you know we
know the people in our communities
really well we all rely on each other
because we're it's how it is out there
but but then we as a county had to all
really come together and as you know
people coming from kind of different
walks of life have to acknowledge that
cannabis is really important
agricultural products to our economy to
our local economy and that we do need to
diversify from it but we also need to
accept it and figure out how to take
care of our environment and bring in
this industry in a way where we can
actually have a say in how how we care
for our watershed and you know it was it
was important to us in our future that I
I wish we could I wish we could fish in
the Southfork you know I wish there were
more than 11 chinook salmon left in the
river behind my house for my children my
children's children so there were a lot
of reasons to do it to come out of the
woods and have to deal with regulation
and the freaking government but also to
demand our rights as human we're
supposed to be the ones telling them
what to do that's the way it's supposed
to work so let's hold them up to it and
it's just an endless job but we finally
after four years of working as just a
tight-knit grassroots community came
together and officially formed an
organization the Trinity County
Agricultural ioan sand it's totally
member-driven not-for-profit and we were
founded this year and so now we have
this official United voice and there are
a lot of us and we have legal license
successful businesses now and and we're
paying taxes what we're doing a lot so
we're at the table and it's mostly to
focus where it started we were building
the Trinity brand yeah the idea is
really is that we all have to work
together to be we all are Trinity
together there's not that many of us
even all together we're one day we all
are together
you need to like resources exactly I
mean a lot of it a lot of different
things that we can work person out who
knows about metric that we can all talk
to and we all pay them for there's a lot
of it is education and enablement not I
mean they're ourselves in each other
just for like navigating and being like
okay what do we need to do we're all
figuring this out no so that the metric
person comes and we you know like it's
like because with Trinity worse well
we're we're so remote you know what I
mean we need a place where cuz we can
all get together but it's hard to get
other people to come see us at each of
our spots because we're all so far away
from each other like out you know in the
mountains so it's really great when we
can come together and we can say what we
all need this and we can have one person
or like not necessarily one person but
like somebody the person we need to give
us the information about the regulations
that we're all dealing with collectively
or the problems we're having with really
remote we have a high demand for our
product but it's inefficient with the
regulations with the transport
regulations with everything to really to
reach all these reach everybody as
individual farms so one of the big
concepts of working together is a trade
organization is to help get our product
to market and to find partners we can
work with collectively and who can reach
to out to us collectively and have a way
to kind of vet people also that are good
to work with because there is a high
demand for Trinity product and
it's hard to know who you have to know
somebody so this is a way for us to be
able to also outwardly reach out and
also I mean we joke a lot in Trinity
that we're like you know Humboldt
best-kept secret or whatever this or
that because there's so few of us and
most people it's most people unless
you're a real like connoisseur and
really into the whole story of lead you
you've maybe never heard of Trinity
County and even if you're into Eve
you've heard of Humboldt probably but
you tell me you might not have a people
don't like to go up drive that far
depending on where they are but that's
the way it is all over the state you
know what I mean like if you're just
somebody like I do the Bay Area I do you
know it's so the way they've structured
it doesn't really work you know what I
mean because it'd be easy if I could
just do my own sales I could be like
yeah I can bring it to you I can bring
in whatever but with the with the rigs
how they are it's like well we're you
know you've got to find the distributor
that service your clients there it's
just you know there's a lot
no they're still arguing about
storefront retail or they are they set
up an ad hoc nothing's happening we have
none we have non storefront retail we
have delivery and we finally got it it's
all like pulling teeth
Trinity because we do have a really
conservative affluent demographic part
of our population and so it's hard to
push the ordinances through and in
storefront retail like everybody was
like oh we'll never have a dispensary in
downtown or either go but now I think
actually the momentum has shifted a lot
and they are working on storefront
retail but it doesn't exist at this
point in time it's not actually there
right now I can't go work with them and
so even if there were there's definitely
always there's any way more cultivation
than then there is going to be retail
for you know the amount of tourism and
population that we compared to how much
definitely for export I mean I think
initially I think essentially it's you
know like we're all waiting for federal
laws to change and things to move on
with all the rest of that and then we'll
see what happens because ultimately I
mean I think Trinity's Trinity has our
our you know pool of buyers this shrunk
way down to like California and even
then being like inefficient throughout
more than beyond Northern California is
just inefficient so it's easier as a
farm to just work with brands and
distributors who will deal with all of
the rest of that you know
you have to make choices about a lot of
things like at the end of the day is it
worth it to worry about every store
you're in or is it easier to just let
someone else worry about how many jars
are coming off the shelf and spend more
time with your family you know like
whoever pays me the money like like that
it's pretty simple you know and that's
been insane with the regulations it's
just figuring out how to conduct all my
business to that point I mean you guys
have such a unique story that you do
sell most your product already in jars
or is there something but that's white
label well it's it's usually copra but
there's no one way that it's worked and
it's very difficult as a independent
farm unless you're vertically integrated
with all the licenses all the way up to
really get your costs as fact that you
put into being your own brand because
it's very expensive to be a brand I see
that financially speaking I make more
money white label in my progress it's a
lot easier to just concentrate on the
farming and I mean we're fortunate that
people do co-brand with us and give us
credit but I'm looking for somebody
who's fair and just an ethical business
partner and like I I appreciate I think
I think it's important that people get
credit for the work but I also have to
live in reality and it's a lot easier I
mean we never have trouble with finding
like the idea behind growing good
quality is that it's good to have a
demand either way and that we've always
been able to tell that we were
completely anonymous people before when
we
to pretend we were just musicians and
whatever I'll seen him like we all had
our cover stories and it wasn't part of
our story it wasn't about that
and we've kind of decided to become let
it be part of our story and just beat
speak the truth and be ourselves because
part of the whole point of this is that
we shouldn't have to hide it but as far
as like branding our farm it's like yeah
I'd love to just be an independent farm
label like an independent wine label I'd
love to be able to just sell it at the
farmers market and people could come way
out there mount they want to put so much
weed that way we could just be a normal
brand label like small brand label the
thing is that I I see the reason you
guys cultivate the way you do is because
it's right but it is a branding
technique I guarantee you the
distributor's see that your style of
growing is a branding technique but that
being said it resonates with the
consumers mochas as a branding I think
because it feels right so I think that's
the cool part of getting your story out
in the jarring perhaps as an easy way to
do that because there's that recognition
but the the key is that like that it's
the distributor the retail that are
seeing the financial in that it's the
retailer that's seeing the same thing
you're seeing in why you're growing that
way is why they're consuming that and so
that's still a pendulum its it still it
benefits us a lot but it also we're
still battling the whole oh this is full
season outdoor oh the price is this like
commodification of the product and total
disregard for the quality but they will
take it and they will put it in a jar
and pretend it's indoor and baby put it
on the top shelf and just know and and
perpetuate that man so you know like we
appreciate having partners who
you recognize recognize like you're
saying and passed that on to the
consumer and I'm creating access to that
I think it is why it's so important to
be honest of on all fronts not that we
weren't B but being frank that we know
in the past brokers and whatever word
playing those games and maybe I saw less
of an issue with in the past than I do
now I was kind of whatever that's their
trip but now I'm like really seeing
though it's like it's it's it's messing
with the consumer to such a you know
level when you are start making that
false association which sometimes is
true but we've know so much it's not and
it's a disservice to us maybe in a
financial realm but it's a disservice to
the consumer also like and we need to
get over the like you can grow beautiful
beautiful weed in the Sun right you know
like naturally and like it's just why is
that so crazy the way nothing else well
I had this at recently I was talking
with a greenhouse producer and I was
explaining to him the verbage of indoor
and that in his world like greenhouses
are indoor because there is no indoor in
agriculture so the fact that we don't
even like you know greenhouse be that it
has to be this thing the Sun and the air
aren't allowed to touch it in order to
be the highest yeah and it was almost
like my mind to this this guy who it's
his whole world too but not cannabis
that that would even be a thing yeah
that greenhouses wouldn't be good enough
as a structure that we'd have to have
this this other thing that started off
as a way to hide the product and yeah
people developed a lot of skill and got
that a lot better and better obviously
to where they are with indoor that's
where it started from and I think I've
you know maybe even talking to you guys
about that in the past and that that's
translate
from being a necessity thing to be in
this sales point I think a big part of
it comes from this whole like our modern
technological view of ourselves as
humans controlling and being superior to
other like biology the natural things in
general that sterilization of things
being better than like having probiotic
like biodiversity things like that you
know that we have and and just
technology like people want to become
machines so that they can live forever
and this kind of stuff like I think that
mindset people like to play God with
their grow and if you can control all
factors like you're not in collaboration
with nature you're not you're you're not
like at the mercy of the elements
anymore you're in control of everything
about you created this little world in
this room and it's not the earth it's
like you know what I'm saying and I
think people get really into being like
mad scientist in their laboratory and it
comes from it just a very different
philosophy and it cos it seems
unconscionable to be like in a
closed-off
to garden recently do our job because we
want to be outside you can be in awe of
nature yeah so but I mean maybe they're
not all trying to play God I'm being
real no but no totally because it is
like that because it's like we're gonna
make sure that there's it's sterile you
know what I mean yeah and then like just
then people are like ooh bugs you know
what I mean that's like like our we have
it our egg Commissioner did our
inspection and it was awesome because
he's very Pro pesticide he's like very
old-fashioned but he came out and he was
like oh look at that carpenter bee and
look at that bug and look at this and
that I'm like because he's a bug guy and
he loves bugs and yeah I plant these I
plant these plants and these bugs come
and they eat my other bugs that you
would spray pesticides on and
everybody's happy you know what I mean
like and there's no chemicals involved
and he was so like this his whole career
and all things and changing our
agriculture is the biggest way we're
gonna change
you know stop climate change or if we
can you know and I mean like we people
need to get in the dirt and and doing
these things you know like whatever
you're gonna do like just get in the
dirt and do a little bit like that makes
a difference in plants and flowers and
more pollinators because like the way
they work as they go from flower to
flower to flower to flower so if
everybody just has a few you know it
makes a big difference and like my bees
go to my neighbor's flower gardens and
the flower gardens after them and like
them that farm down the road and it's
it's cause them for miss us bees
yeah it's great they go like two miles
or something so or you or maybe even
more I don't quote they go far I don't
have a beat would be cool technology is
cool too you know but just the idea that
like we can there's there's just a very
different way of thinking that went off
it started as like we have to put the
plants inside to hide them but it turned
into this like whole thing of like I can
create a universe in this room and the
thing that people forget is that you can
still be a mad scientist in the soil and
on the farm that's what that is like
it's way more fun to have other things
it's like a video game you want a video
game we're like no things jump at you
ever nothing surprises you like how how
boring is that it's the same every year
like when it's outside and every and
were you really doing this season full
season cycle every year is different in
so many ways it affects the flavor you
know it's creamier this year it's it's
more tart this year
to me that's marketable that's that's
that that's
are gonna be great exactly that's we're
just waiting for the awareness to the
consumer and for everybody to catch up
because wine has been wine didn't start
out that way either when you look back
at how Prohibition and did with that and
how it how the wine industry evolved and
small winemakers couldn't sell direct
retail the way they can now they had to
push for that it took them a long time
to be strong enough force to get there
and we're just you know we're seeing a
lot of similar things where we're just
waiting for it all to catch up because
it is marketable it is special it is
good for the world yeah I think getting
that exposure of of your type of flowers
into the hands of more people that may
be in their own rights I've seen there's
some some hydro growers where like I
disagree like I don't like a lot of to
keep the key lights in their products
and I don't like a lot of the
methodology but what they're seen in
some of these systems is more complete
nutrition than in a failed attempt at
organics or whatever and because that
biology wasn't present the a lot of the
nutrition was not available to the plant
they got a subpar product and rather
than maybe correlating that saying how
could I make these systems in play they
went with this bottle Dormouse you know
raw salt nutrition program that has all
these detrimental effects that we see
but at least in their controlled
environment where they're able to
mitigate some of the problems they're
getting a certain complete nutrition
that they weren't getting what they're
incomplete non living soil organics and
to turn around full circle like see like
some of the herb that you guys produce
that's getting that full nutrition it's
I think for me it's easier to say like
yes full Sun regenerative organics work
because it's true
it truly is nothing versus someone
that's like six months yeah Green
that's kind of why I see it all like in
your garden of nice and green source
gardens and Moon user farms and all the
ridge
you know radical herbs and like there's
so much beautiful I mean then there's
people I'm not even saying because
there's so many people you know we're
getting to know so many amazing people
who put their own take on this and it
adds an individual thing yeah we know
that but as long as we get cut in we're
happy about it you know what I mean I
think it's fair as long as but if you
want to be like no this is the outdoor
commodity price and then sell it for
five times what you bought it for as
endure that doesn't feel fair to me or
the person who's buying it on the other
end you know
you build upon that's all in the service
of a brand enterprise that's not all
that's like that's your future like
whatever you need to do to survive yeah
building on those things is all building
on branding and especially yeah that are
pork that's great
which which you you will be successful
to beauty
we've been doing those things and it's
been growing for sure yeah yeah I mean
none of us had farm brands also one of
the things that we find is interesting
in in branding ourselves and marketing
ourselves as we appeal to you know
connoisseurs and most of the
connoisseurs in Northern California work
in the cannabis industry forms that you
guys put off and even other people I
think the similary I see there though is
is the care for the environment the kiss
stewardship of the lamp also care for
the plant and for producing really
quality herb having that be a big part
of the equation and like I feel like
getting out I don't think we're gonna be
like as a society that's just like
humans were not gonna go anywhere unless
we start focusing on quality in general
just and that's and the thing that's
scary and is that the majority of people
will always trade
minions for quality and so how do we
change that you know because at the
retail level what happens is they have
lots of people that come in for the
cheapest thing and very few people that
come in for a more expensive thing so if
they pay the farmer a fair price to do a
small batch quality product and then
they add all the middleman cost of all
the crazy taxes regulation all the stuff
not just normal middleman costs and then
it's finally in the packaging too
because it has to be this ridiculous it
has to be a childproof there's only like
so many suppliers and all stuff so you
get to the final like it's ready for the
shelf and then they're selling by the
jar and these retail stores are not
mostly not that large like what we're
looking at and their model is like if
you were to compare to something else
it'd be more like a Walgreens or CVS
then it would be like a fine wine shop
and so it's it's about yeah but it's
it's just just still happening it's just
still being creative yeah Jesus
difficult because there's so many
players
I know for a fact because I've been here
for the last five years talking to all
these people and marketing people to
mainstream people coming in is that
there are entities out there big time
marking entities that have more money
than we can ever dream of that will that
will be working
these large commercial grows and they
will be out there marketing the language
in the narrative organic simple and fall
down these buds were it sustainable
which you'll already see Clark
commercials
oh yeah well so yeah doesn't mean that
you can't regain the meaning of that to
me you know give up that fight at all
but that's the truth
like there's a small forest there's
nothing you can do about that I know
this
they're called flower up in Canada FL
OWR massive hydroponics
and I've been told that the guy who runs
it is a hydroponics and what they plan
to do is to put very high-end top and
microphonic flour of lots of it
now what I think is any top dollar is
nothing on the planet no exactly that's
where well the thing in that that I
always think of is like when you're
doing indoor you can do it anywhere it's
not California weed anymore you know
what I mean and like now that we're
getting into this legalization that's a
reality that like you're cowley
California indoor is is just indoor and
now your indoor has to be better than
somebody from Canada or like the small
growers who are going to come out of the
Midwest to like
yeah thank you no well like people care
about weed and the thing about weed is
it reflects that you know what I mean
they're not going to be able like
whatever they think is top-shelf isn't
actually gonna meet the like somebody
who really cares about weed there's more
in it than that it's a special
mysterious plant you know they mean the
side of what I believe is that cannabis
fur
so so for your cannabis people they do
care about quality and it's an
aspiration yeah and most families
a person who thinks they're a
connoisseur who thinks that what they're
there that they like the best
whether they do or not it's but then
there's they also the because I used to
be this person to where I was like I
love wheat I will smoke any wheat you
give me
I love wheat you know what I mean but in
smoking all the different kinds of weed
I got to know what was like what do I
like you know what I mean what am i
stoked on when I get that because
because I and I know I'm not gonna make
me get that next time you know what I
mean because it because it was the black
market and you get what you get right so
you know I think it'll it'll get figured
out because it does get figured out yeah
I just I just think
I know totally and we have relationships
with retailers who care about our
product and we care about their store
and and you know and that's I just
that's a good working with so soulful
and we have a good relationship with
them and we've you know we've had
different we've had a lot of different
distributors we've gone through and so
just depending on the distributor they
let you cultivate those relationships or
not but some of them don't and so that's
a big challenge to or it's like how do i
cultivate these relationships when I
can't be the person distributing it or
like even giving them samples you know I
mean it's and that those are those are
really difficult complications and so
you have to find somebody who's really
support it supportive of your stuff and
it's like you know and so it's good too
right now I feel like I mean for
everybody it seems good it's good to
team up with people and so we can all
raise awareness for each other because
we're all small come like we're not even
companies some of us and like we're out
just all small farms and small small
producers in the Emerald triangle who
you know like do a good job but we get
word or not allowed to to do the
outreach that we otherwise would like
for to have a booth at the Emerald cup
we were like we had an opportunity to
get a booth but the the amount of
investment that would go have to go into
just getting the booth because of the
regulatory you know burdens was like
it's it's just not even feasible you
know what I mean because you have to
like well we could have one strain you
know baby but like you have to have you
either are gonna have to like put in
what you think you're gonna sell and
have those all tested which is like all
those varieties have to have this or you
have to have it all finished by then to
have it all tested and all and then it
all has to go to one place you can't
really move from that up place very
easily supply people up here and they
want it it's all stuck over there like
that kind of stuff happens so it's
constantly with every batch every
strange so every and it's not even
anybody's fault it's even when they're
trying to get it to them and doing the
best they can yeah they were and they
they were made specifically by certain
people to get a certain outcome and part
of that outcome is for us not to be able
to control our supplies they are not
serving the interest
I mean it's making it very difficult if
it's there
for you to get a smile
you know poor farmers life - coming down
yeah but the Emerald cup isn't
prohibitive it's not necessarily it's
not the cup you know it's like they
actually are helpful with the contest
and expense sending deadlines and all
these things you know what I mean they
definitely are like
supportive of the farmers but like yeah
it's crazy that the res inventory no I
mean it commodifies the supply and it
allows us no control over our product as
it moves up the supply chain and it
doesn't allow us to retain its true
value and allows other people to
capitalize on our value and so you know
as a small independent producer with not
a 200 million dollar investment capital
or marketing budget or whatever and you
know reach to like all these you know
with like processing and all these
things you have to have know is like
most small producers in the mo triangle
can't process on their farm anymore
without getting
and circle moving because they're not in
the right zoning for that India that we
can do at least do our own trim trimming
well like it's not necessarily
processing but we can do trimming and
packaging and you dry see if you don't
actually have to hire a bunch of
employees they are letting you do some
processing on small farms and Trinity
and in Mendocino they're not there even
their small farmers aren't being allowed
to even do their you know like what a
small home business scale would should
be allowed to do they're not they've
taken that away from us they've they're
treating us like it doesn't matter how
small you are you're like this
industrial like huge impact and you
could be doing it that way so I
recognize why those things are there but
there's no differentiation between us
and them and what we have to do to
operate and so just our ability to
really be a true small craft producer
and keep our own value and make our own
value-added products like I used to make
medicines of all kinds that were
handcrafted from start to finish in tiny
batches with wild crafted other plants
and like really medicinal products that
I can't make without a commercial
kitchen and separate license it's a
separate manufacturing thing than the
hash so we couldn't even even if we did
all that they'd have really it'd be
insane you know and so there's already a
lot of stuff we used to do that
consumers have no access to now yeah and
there might be medical stuff where it's
like we could still provide medicine but
I don't know it's very it's been very
frustrating for for every I think
everybody on every side you know and
even the consumer like oh yeah with the
supply
and even to just help support be like
somebody's like I know weed I'm gonna go
get the job that helps would good we'd
get on out there you know like for
people you know anymore that was the
first thing I learned I was editing a
magazine a different business magazine
covers from all aspects for the last
five years
we in short order island
I was talking to a legislator a CEO a
cultivator everything was was about edge
yeah that's right so that's kind of why
we even applied for the regenerative
farm award and even showed up at them
World Cup and like do all this stuff was
because we're like this is really this
is something I could actually really get
behind and the more platforms there are
to reach people the better and I mean
you just have to be authentic about it
and hope that I do get I do get a lot of
feedback from people who who say they
can tell the difference between just
like other corporate kind of marketing
greenwashing and stuff and us and our
reef art that we're you know they really
see the reef the real authenticity
behind what I'll let just us but all
over all of us and so I think consumers
are starting to seek that out and try
and and you know it's just it's kind of
that game of time that
but we can we can keep educating a lot
of people haven't ever gotten to try
really amazing cannabis they have no
idea what it would be like it's true and
in parts of a lot of parts of the
country it's still really difficult
really uncommon you know very suited how
much like the eye
you know
you're reading
right okay flower for the not only in
this country
yeah yeah we are that's really really
where we're really like our sites are
really set like on a few humps over you
know I there's a few more hills still in
between but like you're looking over
there and that's really where we all
should be focused for sure and and
direct-to-consumer for sure be we used
to talk about this all the time it's
like we need hundreds dedicated stoners
or whatever you know like like it's not
gonna be in every it's not gonna be safe
way wine it's not gonna be everywhere
and so part of it is finding the people
the niche the people who really care you
know there's a little market down
well we just moved but a little market
it's in LA nonnamous market on the
corner
and I go they have it is a mostly
pointer but they have a special bro
inception before fear and likely using
InDesign bottles now for those bottles
in yeah I think there's gonna be more
and more of that the best champagnes and
France are grown on a quarter acre we'll
get there