[Music]
I was driving in my car yesterday and I
heard on NPR I was just randomly on NPR
there's a whole story about this
conference happening and uh I hear Susan
come on and say you know there's a lot
of business conferences out there but
this one isn't business conference this
is about the the politics and and uh and
the and the and the cause and and all
that's that's happening uh out here is
what comes on and I
went I'm supposed to give a keynote
about about the top seven investment
Trends what am I going to do um and uh
and so but so on the way in and I'm
thinking to myself you know usually when
I speak at business conferences when I
speak at investment conferences I tend
to put on my activist and inspiration
hat and try and like really rally people
to get behind the
cause um whereas everybody else is
talking about really kind of hard
business type stuff and uh and so I
decided to kind of switch it up a little
bit for this since this is maybe less of
a business audience and maybe more of a
of a policy audience um which is to
actually go a little bit more into the
uh kind of hard sort of business uh uh
kind of topics in in this uh and so I'll
you know it's really hard for me to not
talk inspirationally about this
important cause but I'm going to try and
hold back as much as I can to be able to
download as much kind of business stuff
that I can in the short period of time
uh that we have top five cannabis
investment Trends um and before I get
into into these let me just say that
when I say top five cannabis investment
Trends these aren't necessarily the top
five places where money is going um I'm
talking about kind of the top five most
sort of unique or uh interesting trends
that I've seen uh come around that I
think have a lot of big implications
about where the Cannabis industry uh
could be going uh in the coming years uh
and also
you know we hear from about 20 to 30
companies every week that want to
present to our investors and we Whittle
that down to two or three a week that we
put on a webinar and then there's this
whole online platform where investors
get to kind of look at deals and share
due diligence and all of this kind of
stuff so we've now seen thousands and
thousands of pitches and so this is kind
of gleaned from some of the things that
I'm seeing uh that are kind of I think
interesting from a investment standpoint
um and I'll also just say on some of
these like don't shoot the messenger um
this is just kind of what's
Happening um so let's let's let's hit
let's hit the first one um which is
limited investment into limited
licensing particularly in Canada um but
really limited licensing anywhere people
are very very excited about and it's
because of uh High barriers to entry uh
creates a uh really concentrated benefit
and so as people are starting to give
these licenses out uh the more
concentrated the benefit the more people
want to fight hard and will spend a lot
of money and do whatever they can to get
those very very few licenses uh that are
available and there's a trend in
particularly the Northeast um but also
in in markets in Canada where you've got
these really huge facilities uh that are
that are occurring and so investors are
very excited I mean when people you know
ask well what's the what's the biggest
investment opportunity right now it's
like well if you can get a uh if you can
get a license in a really limited
licensing environment that is probably
the the biggest opportunity and it's one
that will disappear uh very shortly as
soon as more places uh come on board um
thankfully in California it looks like
that it's going to be a lot more open
than that I mean it's still limited but
it's not it's um it's not so limited
that there's such a highly concentrated
benefit in one place and so uh I think
that's going to be the one of the big
questions that we have going forward
when there's limited licensing then the
real investment opportunity tends to be
in either cultivation or dispensing
depending on um you you know what the
relationship the ratio is between those
two and then in states that are more
open uh where there's a lot of
cultivation licenses a lot of dispensary
licenses then the opportunity tends to
be uh in the product manufacturer uh
angle of it that that's where the real
opportunity is and uh it's one of the
reasons why we're seeing so much
investment I think in California into
Brands uh because I think the real a
really big opportunity will be
in in that area um so let's go to the
next one so genetics biofarma and
testing you know we've got this really
interesting thing happening right now
where people who've been working with
this plant underground um or in the in
the gray area for many many decades are
finally able to be uh working with uh
you know the top engineers and top uh
scientists in the in the world to really
be able to take this plant in different
directions um and this is the part where
hey you know Don't Kill the Messenger
but there's like a lot of really
interesting things happening uh when it
comes to you know even companies that
are creating canabo with yeast there's
there's investment happening um in in
these types of uh applications where
there isn't even a plant that creating
the the compound um you have a lot of
advancement in testing technology uh and
this is an area where I think cannabis
may be able to lead the entire testing
industry because you have um in some
ways less regulation and more demand and
it's more easy for this industry to be
willing to uh accept new ideas because
there's nothing there's not as much
there to start with in the first place
and there's so much growth
and so particularly miniatur
miniaturization of testing uh as well as
getting more testing around genetics and
things like that so that we know that
you know this this strain is really
means this strain and all of this stuff
around that there's a lot of ancillary
businesses all related um to testing
biofarma and
genetics next one
um feeling ings and lowd do um and and
when I say feelings I don't mean like I
mean like uh like you know happy or
creative or
um uh you know relaxed these sorts of
feelings right so um there was I think
probably the first company to really
kind of swing at this uh was a company
called Ebu but now there's a number of
companies that are really trying to look
at how to create a r
repeatable uh experience for the wide
range of of consumers out there who have
really chosen not to consume cannabis
because one time you know maybe eight
eight time eight times out of 10 they
enjoy it but the two times are enough to
make them not want to do it again uh and
and and also people just wanting to dial
in their experience more and for the
average consumer like figuring out the
differences between all the different
strains and how they relate to their own
experience is mindboggling I mean I
include myself in that category um which
is and I'm as exposed to all of this as
as anybody and I'm sorry I just I can't
I can't nerd out on the strain names and
the and the and the way that they impact
me like I kind of like how do I want to
feel right now okay give me that right
and I don't and I and I'm luckily I'm
surrounded by people who are like really
into into the plant and all the new
nuances and so I can say I want to feel
like this and they can go okay here take
this but we got to cut the middleman out
and um and that is one area that I think
is getting a get get a lot of investment
um uh over the over the coming years uh
in terms of developing brands that are
able to to do that and that's both a
branding question and a product
development question um certainly The
Branding plays a big role in being able
to deliver that but there's
also uh the actual formulation to be
able to give someone that experience and
when you've got a plant that you know
where the experience is so
subjective um I question whether or not
it's even going to be possible to create
that repeatable experience um but
certainly there's a lot to be gained if
somebody can really crack that
nut uh next one um automated trimming um
again don't shoot the messenger
um uh but automated trimming is you know
is one of those areas where it's this
absolutely huge huge labor expense and
as we move into sort of oia standards
and we move into uh situations where
carpal dealing with carpal tunnel and
all of this kind of stuff um coming up
with different solutions uh that are
going to keep the plants in intact um at
the same time as uh being able to
quickly move through the trimming
process um I think is an area where
we're going to start seeing a lot more
uh investment and I think there's a lot
of reluctance among current um
cultivators um who have been in this for
a long time to really try out these
sorts of things but I think newer people
that are that are coming in are like
totally they totally want to figure out
a different solution here and uh and so
I think that's going to be interesting
and remember that this is this doesn't
happen our industry doesn't happen in a
vacuum there's this whole robotics
industry that's just totally taking off
uh where we're able to the prices are
reducing and people can start building
like robots doing interesting things
like in their home in their basements uh
and so there's a lot of opportunity uh
with those things intersecting uh that
could um also continually drive down the
price of cannabis which is also another
topic that I'm not going to get into
here because I know other people have
but as we think about the future and how
to adjust to it uh this is one of the
things that is going to continue to
drive prices down uh next next slide um
and then brand IP
licensing the race is on for
Brands
and we are seeing so so much uh energy
and investment going into companies that
are building Brands and then licensing
those Brands out to the licensed
producers uh in given States um part of
this is driven by the challenge of laws
because you have a situation where you
know you can't send your product across
state lines and so what can you send
across state lines right so you can uh
the the the whole you know kind of
branding experience can be shared across
uh state lines and then also you have a
lot of processors and producers who in a
brand new market want to be able to like
start out ahead of the game and so they
want to look to brands that already have
a certain feel and a A vibe and a
certain following and so it becomes a a
natural uh
pairing there and I think that what
you're seeing
with branding is you know it's very
similar to you know it's kind of what
Coca-Cola does um and others do in in in
other sectors that don't even have these
same kind of barriers that we have uh in
this sector and I think there are some
really interesting examples Around The
Branding and figuring out what's really
going to connect with both today's
consumers and um the Futures consumers
of cannabis um and more importantly I
think the one the the audience that's
missed um when they look at today's
cannabis consumers and then they look at
tomorrow's cannabis consumers they're
missing and they're missing this a lot
in The Branding um is today's current
consumers that are just in the illicit
Market they're just not going to the
stores right they're missing that
audience and so I think that's what
we're going everyone's trying to make
like the the the the top end everyone's
trying to make the Rolex and if you
really look at what people make and what
their disposable income is and the kind
of brands that they actually buy um then
when they're when they're not paying a
bunch of money to be in a specialized
store play paying an in inflated price
um I think that's really particularly as
the as the price of cannabis goes down
hitting that market is going to be uh a
really huge uh opportunity and then
there's the question um when we talk
about sort of you know corporatization
or like what kind of brands are really
going to resonate with people this is
where I think consumer Choice can is
really going to make a a huge difference
like I notice I see Swami uh over here
in the in the corner right I mean like
you know um a brand like Swami right you
it's like it's like you've got a
situation where like I think for a lot
of people that's really going to
resonate um and so we're going to get a
chance to see a lot of interesting
different brands you see the Marley
Naturals you see uh open Vapes you see
these different people kind of taking
different angles and it's going to be
very interesting to see what's happening
but I know for a lot of investors they
really believe that the power is going
to be in the brands and here's one of
the beautiful things about the brand
play is that it it it allows investors
to be involved in an ancillary business
uh because often in most cases these IP
comp these companies that are holding
The Branding um aren't actually touching
the they're licensing uh their formula
and their um and their their creative
out to uh others and so I think that's
an interesting uh area where I think
we're going to see uh a lot more
investment and then also the other thing
there's so many rules there's so many
laws around investing in directly into a
company and so this also it's not just
because it's ancillary it's even within
within various state laws wanting to
invest in ancillary businesses become
comes even more interesting because uh
there's so many regulations uh in so
many states California included um and
then um and then there's actually a
sixth Trend and I almost didn't include
it let's go actually um one more
cool I almost didn't put this uh which
was the sixth trend is that businesses
are starting to really donate to the
Cannabis industry is really starting to
donate to the politics of this issue uh
um and I didn't I didn't put it in
because I I think I've been sort of the
pi Piper of the industry isn't doing
enough to support the
movement and you know we get up at each
one of our events and we're like donate
donate donate if you're not donating and
you're in this industry then you're
shering your responsibility you're a
freeloader you know I mean there's this
whole thing going on and it's been
really hard it's been really really hard
to get a lot of the people involved in
the in contributing to the cause and it
it's particularly frustrating for me
because the whole reason I started
arkview in the first place the whole
reason I left the the the sort of
movement World full-time and moved into
the business side full-time was because
I believed that business is a powerful
platform for political change and as
soon as we could really Inspire that
that end
that it would become a no-brainer for
businesses and entrepreneurs to be
donating to change the laws this is what
we learned in the renewable energy
industry right you could you could write
letters to members of Congress all day
long but until you had profitable
businesses that and business models
associated with renewable energy it was
only going to go so far and I I thought
that was true about cannabis and about
uh uh changing these laws and that was
the whole reason that Steve D'Angelo and
I started arkview in the first place was
based on that belief and here we are six
years later we started arkview in
2010 and really hoping we would have
been further down the line in people
coming into this industry and investing
into this industry and simultaneously
donating to the
cause um but I'm happy to say that in
the last month or so this storyline is
actually starting to change I mean of
course it'll never be enough it'll never
I'm like I admit that I'm like I'm an
I'm I'm an activist and and a fundraiser
by by heart and you're never satisfied
if you're an activist or you're a
fundraiser but I will say that it's
starting they're starting to crack it's
starting to happen that people are
recognizing that the future of the
market for their uh businesses is really
dependent upon being able to support the
cause not just because it opens up more
markets but because it's cause marketing
because it's hard to be in this industry
which was started by by
activists and to actually conduct
business when you're not one of the top
people out there contributing to the
cause um and so I'm just so grateful
that this is an industry birthed out of
a movement because it's what's going to
make it a new kind of industry and I
hope that we continue to hold businesses
feet to the fire to pay for
reform um it's it's bizarre that there's
all these people that are going to
benefit and the people who are for the
most part paying to pass these
initiatives are the people who aren't
even going to benefit um and so that's
got to change over time and uh I can I'm
just looking out in the audience I see
James slat I see others who a lot of
people who've really put a lot on the
line um for this for this industry and
while we're sitting here thinking about
what's the best policy or how to make
the most money there are tens of
thousands of people sitting in prison
who wake up every day living in fear and
they wake up living in fear and they're
counting on us they're counting on us to
get this right they're counting on us to
not let our petty disagreements get in
the way of getting them out of jail
and so I put this list up of companies
that I know of that are donating at
least
$100,000 to uh legalization efforts in
the last year or so uh and uh if you
know of another company that should be
on that list that is not please let me
know um and then um we would love to add
them to it but we want to be shouting
from the rooftops the companies that are
really standing up but I also want you
to look at that
list and notice who isn't on there um um
no no I'm I'm talking specific these are
um uh just to be clear I'm talking about
cannabis businesses in the Cannabis
industry uh that are uh contributing at
least $100,000 to all of the uh uh
either either contributing or raising
$100,000 to the efforts so um there's
also a lot of companies that aren't on
this list right and so um how do we how
do we make sure that we are able to grow
that in the future um and so I thank you
for all that you're doing um to help
bring this issue and this industry
forward and um I look forward to working
with you to keep it moving thank you
[Applause]
[Music]