[Music]
nicer than Yuri different is an EC than
200 parts per million of potassium
because they have a different electro
conductivity when you're reading parts
per million on a meter it's a
combination of all the salts together
that you're reading iso as nitrogen
assault everything that yeah almost all
fertilizers are salts okay assault is a
metal and a nonmetal technically a metal
and a nonmetal that have combined so
nitrogen which calcium nitrate calcium
is the metal potassium is the metal
nitrate is the nonmetal potassium
sulfate is a salt sodium chloride sodium
is the metal chloride the nonmetal and
so most all nutrients are a type of salt
and it's worried where people will get
into difficulty if they use something
like urea or ammonia because you can mix
urea in water and not get a reading
because it's not assault there's no
electric electric conductivity in the
urea it's simply a double ammonia
molecule right and ammonia is the same
way it doesn't read if you if you're
using nose elements you have to be
careful that you're understanding how
much you have but the other end of it is
is that if you're growing in a situation
where it's cold the bacteria that break
down urea work at a lower temperature
than the bacteria that break down
ammonia and so what you can end up with
urea being broke down into ammonia and
just sitting there and then you get
ammonia toxicity and if the temperature
is warm enough it just naturally
converts into
nitrogen from the ammonia and if
someone's using their EC reader they
won't even know that this is an issue
yes that's right yeah EC or
parts-per-million because they are the
same yeah you're reading the same type
of information when you're sort of
mixing together your nutrients and
you're measuring ppm which is which is a
derivative of you see what are what are
you looking for and like what are you
different levels tell you yeah if when
you're looking at EC it's basically just
telling you a level of nutrients that
are there when it when you're when
you're feeding more nutrients there that
are present generally the easier the
plant has finding them and using them
this is up to a point of course because
everybody knows it's too high you start
burning roots because these salts will
then start pulling water out on the root
and the roots die and I say it's it's
it's kind of true because what's more
important actually than the level of
nutrients is actually the balance of
nutrients how much nitrogen there is to
potassium
compared to phosphorus compared to
calcium compared to iron magnesium
manganese all the different nutrients
that are there the more balanced it is
it's like eating a balanced diet
yourself the more balanced it is the
healthier you are the better you feel
the more you can do what you're supposed
to do if you're overloaded in in fats
you might you might grow but carry too
much weight and which will not allow you
to do many things that you that you want
to do if you don't have enough fats of
course then you don't have enough energy
because pretty much you need fat in your
diet to get enough energy if you're
exercising strenuously or just working
hard so it works that way with plants
too the more balanced what you have
nutrient for your plants the better off
you are that's part of why I don't like
parts-per-million because everybody
thinks yeah parts-per-million is telling
you what you have for nutrients and it
doesn't it just tells you what the level
of salts are and if it were all sea salt
you would have almost nothing that was
good for the plant in there but it would
still read parts per million they'll say
1200 right so the readers give you a
rough estimate of the EC of all the
elements in aggregate not like here's
the EC of this element or that element
yeah and that's a good point
EC is no better for reading whether
they're good or not it simply is a
measurement of a relative level of
nutrient or salt in your solution so
then it comes to a having a level of
trust that the nutrient supplier is
telling you exactly what he's giving
right because if you can trust that then
you can sort of at you can work
backwards to figure out what's going on
right yes you have to remember also that
in your nutrient solutions mostly what
they talk about is n P and K nitrogen
phosphorus potassium but as important of
all is in all of those someone will tell
you calcium and that's terribly
important but iron copper boron all
seldom are mentioned in there but more
than likely they have those elements in
the feed so then if you do trust what
they say on the packaging then what are
you looking for because we talked about
having like too hot a solution too weak
like what do you sort of want to
fine-tune at and why a lot of it depends
on how you as a grower are growing
temperature how big a root area you have
if you've got a twenty five gallon pot
or if you've got a three gallon pot it
all kind of depends then on how much
you're watering
if if you're one of water very regular
you can get by with a smaller pot like a
three gallon pot you may win good hot
weather you may want it won't be
watering you know six eight ten times a
day
smaller doses but more often he gives
you a fresh shot of water also a fresh
shot of nutrients so you keep a relative
balance of nutrients throughout the
whole day whereas if you are watering
say once a day or every other day you
may start in the morning very high and
you just gradually get slower through
the day and the plants gonna suck up
different nutrients and different
proportions based on what it needs and
wants yes and you could actually
potentially from one day to another run
short on one of the nutrients and that's
why completely you know reintroducing a
complete shot or complete balance is is
quite important now I think we missed
out I missed I went on a tangent there
from where you see yeah off of BC it's
kind of like what do you want to feed at
and and if you're watering quite regular
you can feed at a higher EC because
between the first the one water to the
next you don't lose so much of the
moisture the water I and II see is an
electrical conductivity which is a
measure of the concentration of salts so
in your growing media if you've got just
four for a number to pick we've got 500
grams of fertilizer in there and it's
completely saturated the EC is going to
be at a certain level I don't know
exactly what it is but at a certain
level as that pot dries out the bat
plant is using water taking water out of
there or water is evaporating out the
top the EC is just going to climb
because it's a concentration of the
salts in your media and is as the weight
of the media gets lighter because it's
losing water the EC is gonna ramp up but
what would bring the EC what would maybe
not in the same
scope but when the plans suck the plants
sucking up nutrients also lower you see
a little bit but not as quickly as the
drawings raising it yeah it tends to use
more water and also you do lose some
water from evaporation in the from the
media so you tend to the plant tends to
use more water you also never have the
the nutrients in exact balance so
there's certain elements that are gonna
gradually be climbing depending on the
stage of growth or the time of day or
what's going on with the way the client
is growing so you'll gradually always be
building some nutrients maybe
diminishing some others but in general
as the time from water to water goes the
EC within your your growing media is
gonna go up because there is less
moisture in there so the other thing
this thing reads is pH levels so what
what are we what's the relevance of pH
levels to healthy happy plant growth
specifically cannabis yeah okay cuz
different plants have different pH needs
lichens yeah I mean it's a you familiar
with a lot of citrus fruits and
camellias in that really like a low pH
around four or three five or something
most plants like a pH say five five five
six to six something six four and then
there's some some plants that like it
higher than that most of the time it's a
result of war the plant origin ated from
originated from because the the plant is
developed to survive in a certain
environment and so it's genetics gives
it a certain pH range that it likes
mostly related to how nutrients are
available to it pH oftentimes if you've
got a high pH calcium becomes more
available if you have a low pH you start
to get low availability of calcium iron
and well she herself faded
micronutrients all the time say 20 years
ago they used to push an EC of our pH of
say 65 to 72 or something like that it
is because a lot of the sulfated
micronutrients are more available at
those PHS as we've gotten into more
chelated micronutrients the we have
gradually been working with a bit lower
and bit lower so now we start to get
below 6 to mid 5 to mid 6s a pH were
many of the pH or the micronutrients are
available to the plant so keeping your
pH in in a certain level is oftentimes
important to the availability of the
nutrients around it but so a specific pH
level allows nutrients to sort of make
themselves bioavailable and different
yeah rates yeah you can look in the
online encyclopedia or something like
that they'll have a chart that shows
which nutrients are available most at
what what PHS and if you take somewhere
down the middle where almost everything
is available pretty close to the most
there's one or two I'm not actually for
kind of outside of that line but there's
a couple of them that if you could run a
lower pH now actually be better for that
nutrient but it isn't for any of the
others so when I'm working backwards
when a nutrient supplier creates
nutrients they need you to live within a
certain pH range because they're
formulating yes to a specific range so
that they know oh we need more of this
because that isn't as bioavailable at
that range yeah yeah and we as growers
just gradually a climate to the climate
eyes to that because we notice their
plants are growing better at this pH and
so we just kind of gradually push
ourselves to the pH of the nutrient that
we're behind because it seems to work
better and so you know here lots of
growers talk about this I like a pH of
around 6:00 a little above 6 or below 6
but really most of the time you're gonna
find them in that 5 5 to 65 somewhere in
between there and they they found a spot
and it may have to do with their water
because the water that you're using is
going to affect the pH what kind of what
kind of an acid you're using for pH P I
which down up and down because they will
react quicker or slower changing the pH
of what you have
[Music]