foreign
[Music]
thank you
welcome to Future cannabis project
everybody and tonight we have fireside
chats I have been posting about this for
a little while now and I hope you're
excited to join in in the conversation
because we have one hell of a set of
speakers coming up to us today
um and and and just some of the best
conversations I have ever happened to be
a part of
um this lineup is a rock star we have I
think around over 10 of the top people
in the North American industry some of
the most authentic true human beings to
true people of the plant humus beings
and and let's just talk a little bit
I'll let you know who's coming in in on
this show Kevin jodry will be there
career Hustler Josh and Kelly from
dragonfly Earth medicine huge speakers
in this Shayla Blanc is in and out he's
a little bit busy because he's running
the whole event here at the Unicorn cup
in the Fireside Chats Shannon rossio
antidote brilliant brilliant human being
Noel lease founder and of nectar
Collective head of extracts at Terra and
antidote don't forget about Michael West
coordinator at Rubicon Organics Marcus
BC Bubble Man Richardson chief trichome
officer at Whistler Technologies one
hell of a character and one a hell of a
human being he dropped some major bombs
um Pam West is in in their cross train
cannabis goat earthwolf farms we've got
uh who else do we have in there Jameson
Wellborn from the Banyan Tree we've got
some amazing human beings that have
stopped by enjoying Christian Clapton
director of sales and marketing at
Rosebud cannabis farms and custom
cannabis we got Ron Harrington was in
the house from gold houses and Willow
Wood
Consulting no Elise I mean like the the
lineup was just fun is just phenomenal
and I can't wait to let you all get in
on this conversation
um and I hope you all enjoy it because
fuck man it was awesome recording it and
it was even awesome it was even more
awesome being a part of it and I can't
wait to show every little bit of it to
you now so without any further Ado let
this show begin
all right cool uh welcome to the Unicorn
cup
we're here for the fireside chat and a
question was asked about perspective I
think so I'm not the only uh Californian
here
two two like like currently like
operating though in terms of like
operational right and so the question
was what's my view on the Canadian
cannabis industry as I sit here in
person
and
it's interesting because to me I mean I
I'm familiar with the industry right in
in Canada and the evolution of it became
almost identity-less where your package
looks like I have no idea what's in the
package they don't even have an identity
on the pack except a a stick on label so
I I look at it and I'm like you're
taking the identity away from the
cultivators and so Canada
it over corporatized it to the point
where it's almost impossible for a small
person to gain traction without some
collaborative effort and it's odd
because to me you know Canada had such a
thriving craft Community for so long
and
the the lack of ability to be seen in
any way that lets you highlight your
differences that lets you showcase what
you do
um some kind of identity on a package
you know like I like looked at the walls
and I knew some of the companies so we I
decided somebody take me to a store so I
was able to kind of understand how do
you purchase at a store here
and it was just very hard to identify
with the product and understand what you
wanted to get and then expectations of
what the quality was in the bag
and so hopefully you know just like us
in California we go through an evolution
here
I just think that really we're early and
we are we're early in the new world of
industry and there's teething pains and
the truth of it is that the people who
regulate and control have very little
understanding and the truth that I
learned is that
they regulate us so hard because they
believe we're so sneaky and the only way
you could believe that is if you were
sneaky yourself
and so what I learned was that you guys
are really dirty and you think we'd
screw you this hard and this is why
you're doing it to us so it's really
inside I nailed it with the uh stealing
of the identity I I don't know how to
buy in a cannabis store in Canada when I
walk into it everything looks the same
all the packaging looks the same I'm
often like where's the hash like where's
the extract and sometimes they'll have a
little sort of spot I mean down to the
covering of the windows you see all of
that is done under the guise of
protecting children that's how that's
how they do it you can't have the
windows open you have to make it very
safe for people to come in and Rob you
so they don't get caught and so you
cover all the front windows because God
forbid if a child walked by that store
and saw through the window it's okay if
they see the you know massive amounts of
alcohol that kill millions of people
annually right next door at the liquor
store but if they see cannabis products
through the window you've now broken a
federal law in Canada and so and also
the packaging you can't you can't have
fun fonts you can't have anything that
looks like it was a cartoon or any type
of unique cool packaging because of
course that as well is with their
marketing to children that's what
they're doing so they they allowed us to
have Federal legalization in Canada but
under the guise that it's a dangerous
thing that children need to be protected
from and that's what's led us to where
we are right now
I think a lot of the laws were copy and
pasted directly from alcohol and tobacco
and and we're forced to to shoulder our
way out of them so in Canada I think
it's it's the issue becomes when you
can't
when when the two goals of legalization
are protecting children from Cannabis
and converting the black market but the
regulations are written in such a way
that the only way
somebody can move quickly in this market
is to raise an egregious amount of money
legally and then deploy that Capital it
turns to Bay Street which is Canada's
Wall Street to raise all this Capital
quickly and then completely misallocate
it and that's what's happening in Canada
where we had an incredible opportunity
to become a world leader in cannabis and
what happened was
greet greet White Collar businessman and
stock Brokers and analysts who took the
square footage of your property and not
the square footage of the building on
that property and appraised the value of
your company and how many buildable
square feet there were on your acreage
versus your 10 000 square foot building
and then raise Capital based on that are
the the the the problem in this industry
and if we were too able if we were able
to properly allocate half of the capital
that was raised in Canada we would be in
a much better position than we are today
and we've lost all trust in retail
investorship and so there's a lot of uh
jaded individuals who listen to a lot of
people who promised that they were here
to build this industry in here for the
Long Haul and they're no longer here
anymore and it's three years later
um they're they're literally some of
them are raising money to go fucking
mine asteroids so you know we we have an
issue here where the people who actually
care are left pick up the pieces of a
system that doesn't cater to the people
who got it to where it is today
there is the First Nations part of
Canada too which does have a lot more
open
availability to do different things so
if you go into a dispensary on a First
Nations like land you can't have a
different experience so yeah American
average individual go there yeah yeah
you know and when you when you link up
with uh you know the First Nations who
want to do something different you know
it really does help
and they have the ability to create
their own laws and their own abilities
uh through packaging and working with
farms and stuff so there there is
um
a way to affect federal laws through
that to show them you know with maybe
different Taxation and different uh
brackets and different ways of working
at farms direct sales
um that you know that that can make a
change
well and just to touch on that the the
the first nations are actually not
working with the feds at all they've
totally decided that they're not going
to have anything to do with the feds and
then when you ask the feds which we've
had plenty of meetings with the Fed so
like hey what are you guys going to do
about this what do you plan on doing
like
anybody want to answer that question you
know they're all looking at each other
on the panel so really there's an
incredible power in Canada with the
First Nations to be able to do it better
and to be able to step out and really
check out how badly that we did it and
be able to step in with some better
protocols some better action forward and
better education to the community I just
think that you know they have gold in
their hands to maybe save this industry
honestly
oh there's definitely space this this
space to go forward it's just you know I
was I was in Berlin a number of years
ago and I was on a uh I was speaker at
an event and I get on this tour bus with
the with maybe 40 or 50 other people to
go to this club and everybody's asking
each other what they do
and everyone was some kind of investment
broker and I was the only grower on the
entire bus
and when people found out I was a girl
on the bus have you ever seen the EF
Hutton commercial where when EF Hutton
speaks everyone listens when when when
it you could see the murmur through the
whole bus and you could see everyone
turn around and go wow that's a grower
because they had never met one and so I
was like this is fascinating and I'm
like what are you guys doing here and
they said oh our world is really hard
and cannabis to us is really easy and I
said so you're gonna come in here and
they go yeah we're like locusts we go
and take everything we can and then we
move to the next industry
and it was such a a relatory
statement because it it helped you
understand the mindset of the Investment
Group that was coming in and so what I
knew at that moment was that we were
about to get into Carnage because the
people that were coming in were here not
to stay they were here to take as much
as they could and then go on to the next
industry they didn't have an emotional
connection to people or cannabis so
there was they were not they would it
was just herb it was it was a
sociopathic tendencies
and I was it was such a
an eye-opening moment because these were
the groups that were about to demolish
the world and they did
and I got to see it firsthand and so in
the U.S same issues Canada same issues
but I'm in I'm in a lot of countries
working this doesn't matter where you go
the craft Community is just getting
buried and the people that are trying to
bury us aren't doing a very good job
they're failing and that's the irony is
that it's almost I hate to see people
fail but I kind of don't hate to see you
fail it kind of makes me feel kind of
good because your intent was to destroy
everyone around you and that wasn't our
intent we we just wanted to exist as
producers and have a cannabis
relationship
and everyone else had this intent to
where we're going to take over and not
just get market share but we're going to
take your share
and that's not
unique to Canada or or California you
know that every country I'm in it's the
same story and the only way any of these
groups succeed is to actually work
collaboratively in some capacity
well when you said they want to bury us
you know it's an accurate metaphor and
the reason they didn't do a good job is
because they didn't realize that we were
seeds
and when you bury a seed
it grows
I mean I think it comes down to you know
when you come from that Community
you care how that Community views you
and and and and and and and sees and and
judges you whereas when you're not
connected to that Community you're
playing by a completely different set of
rules than somebody who has a deep
connection to this plan and and I think
that we all make our decisions you know
not based on financial enrichment but
you know what is best for the community
what's best for the plant and and
ultimately what's best for us and our
families but I think that you know
multiple considerations are taking place
whereas we're competing against people
who have very limited considerations the
consideration is listen am I going to be
financially enriched from this scenario
yes or no yes okay let's fucking do it
so
um you know I think that when you're
dealing with these these people you're
you're dealing with individuals who are
playing with a much thinner rule book
than you're playing with
you know but I also think that
we're kind of moving on to the next one
I also think that we're kind of moving
on to the next phase where the
corporations came
the big guys came they tried to make a
bunch of money some of them did some
didn't and now it's where does it sit
and it was the the concept of can you
actually do it can you actually grow
good cannabis at a scale
and now I think that we're looking at
how since I've been to Canada I realized
this is a craft built Community it's a
local built community and I hope that we
see us move into more micros which is
we're about to do and really uh be able
to see the craft uh people get a chance
at this
um because
the the corporations did fail they're
they're they're making it some are
making it but it's not so great out
there for them and it's a and it's a
Time Cannabis has the ability to build a
completely new paradigm of corporate
structure
so you know do you see a future in the
micro cultivation license in cannabis
with the current 2150 square foot canopy
cap
I I don't think that works I think it's
set up for failure
it has to be it has to be adjusted
if they got a couple people that knew
what the heck they were talking about
and what it takes to make a buck in this
industry and still cover the coas the
employees that you need the record
keeping the the vaults that everything
has to be done in the infrastructure
that they require there's no way that
you can make money with a micro that
they just set it up for failure so until
Canada decides that you know what if if
if we're a flea and we got to eat on the
dog the dog's got to be alive or there's
going to be no blood there and so until
they figure out a way to make it
profitable people can't keep losing
money because the money's bleeding out
of investors into cannabis I see it
that's what it is rich people got money
and it just goes right down the tubes
and it's gone so I I hate to be negative
about it you know people say oh you know
it's bad saying you're like a bunch of
crabs in a pot you know and everybody's
climbing over each other and a guy
underneath but it's it's kind of like
that
well they're they're structuring it like
that like where we live
I can give you some ideas of like the
the compression so Humboldt County when
they when they flew us with the
satellite to really figure out how many
active grows there were they figured you
know they were able to easily pick out
about 35 000. and I figured there was
probably another ten thousand they
didn't pick up so we're talking about 45
000 grows that were present so
Humboldt's the size of the state of
Connecticut we only have 120 000 people
we would generate in about 8 billion a
year wholesale and that comes out to
every single human being in Humboldt
County was getting 70 grand a year so if
you had five people in your house you're
making 350 000 every house everybody the
money in Humboldt was Supernatural and
so you got to see what happened when
regular people get paid
and so we had 35 000 I think if there
was 45 000 how many active licenses that
occurred so they went from that 40 down
to 1100 how many active of this year 250
and I'm one of them
so and I I have two cultivation licenses
three that I'm tied into so I'm I'm
three of that 250.
and so how about Trinity County the
whole County Trinity was big so humble
as as an entity did 8 billion the
Emerald Triangle did 14 billion so I did
the economic essay for Humboldt County
meaning that the university came to me
for assistance years ago saying we want
to do the first economic index of the of
the impact of Black Market cannabis on
the economy and they couldn't get any
data and so they came to me and said
could you help us because and I knew we
needed that number to quantify our value
as cultivators and Humboldt and I was
able to come up with half a billion
dollars of quantifiable data that the
that the university could use to create
the first economic index for cannabis
well I didn't know that I was going to
get credit for the study I just helped
the university out my name got put on
the study as the source of the
information it brought an ocean of
politicians and tax Specialists to my
office from that moment forward because
they said you have a unique
Vision into the game because no one else
is coming up with these numbers that we
can quantify so we want to let you know
the real numbers because we know how
much money is coming out of here because
we measure the cash coming out of the
trucks where the go where the government
they go you're doing 8 billion wholesale
and the whole triangle is doing 14. so
Mendo and Trinity were doing six so we'd
say Mendo is four Trinity is two how
many active licenses exist in Trinity
today
seven
seven active licenses right and so the
problem is is that everyone's like we're
all going to die off but what's really
taking place is we as the people are
dying off the licenses are being sold
and Acquired and held so that as the
evolution goes on those real estate
valuations can re-rise and the value of
the crop can re-rise and New farmers
will emerge and I don't think that
they're bad people that are coming in
for the craft licenses it's just it
kills me to see every one of my
neighbors sell their farm and run for
their fucking lives there's also the
hard work variable oh yeah yeah you'll
love it you know what I mean you're
gonna love it you gotta fucking love
this and also you know there were a
number of individuals that got into the
cultivation of cannabis especially in
Northern California but all over the
world globally to
um be able to execute on a certain
lifestyle that they wanted to
um
that they wanted to employ whether that
be like you know snowboarding or or or
surfing or whatever that was and and
maybe the Cannabis wasn't you know the
front and center thing in their lives
and and maybe
being dedicated and and
you know honing in on a hard work ethic
wasn't something that they were doing
over the years they were enjoying life
and doing other things and I think that
now in this legal industry where your
margins are slim and measurable
um there's a lot of individuals that
maybe don't want to do the leg lifting
required to to operate in the space and
and we're hearing a lot of complaints
around that and
some of that we just have to understand
is you know there was a lot of margin
for a long time
and so the paid guy most people most
people I met I mean really honestly
there's there's there's two cultivators
ones that own cultivation and ones who
cultivate
ones that own cultivation have
infrastructure and employees and they
get paid but they're not the ones who
physically are on the job
they're the ones that are leaving as
rapidly as possible trying to go find
new money but the problem is there's no
money to find so I'm watching them run
from state to state to state to state to
state and I'm just like holy shit you do
better just to stay home and then
there's real cultivators that really
love the craft the cultivation
and they're still sticking with it
they're just trying to figure out what
scale they can operate and then like if
you ask in my opinion on stuff I'm
trying to tell you how to like diversify
and and don't whatever you do don't lose
your land don't lose your license don't
lose your farm
figure out what you got to do to keep it
alive and allow this Evolution to occur
because it will and then you're back
into the world you were supposed to be
and it's just that the transition is
painful
well and I think just to say to what you
were saying Jameson and also to sort of
touch on what you were talking about
Kevin is that I think that we were
cultivators and in that our community
members we are Hustlers we were talking
to each other and also our Equity was
seasonal
having seasonal Equity means that you
have Equity at a certain time of year
but that doesn't mean that all of the
licensing and all of the people and all
of the banks and everybody that wants
your money is working on that same
seasonal you know Equity that you have
so that right there is one of the most
difficult things because I know for sure
in California as well as here everybody
comes for you in the spring
well I mean you know if if you've been
cultivating for a long time you know
your funds are low in the springtime so
it really isn't just people not wanting
to work hard it's people not
understanding what the work is now it's
like we were speaking one language and
we were doing it really well and we were
all speaking the same language and now
sort of this whole other thing came in
and said now we're forcing you to speak
another language well a lot of us have
been so busy continuing to work we
didn't have time to open up the books
and learn and speak the other language
as well as the seasonal Equity wasn't
there so it's just it's really important
to look at like all aspects as to why
you know the cultivators aren't the ones
who are holding the majority of licenses
or the or the Legacy Market you know a
lot of us are still holding on but you
know it's challenging because you know
basically they're asking a fish to be a
tiger
and we've all been working really hard
at being fishes and we're great at it
so you know there's a lot of different
things in here oh yeah and it's not it's
definitely not just the cultivator but
like like where we are you know you're
different your government does distro so
government handles distro for you so
it's distro the the issue though is that
they're definitely not handling that
product gently and so you're having
distro that's destroying the quality of
your consumption and that's not the
cultivator's fault but no one knows how
to blame anybody but the cultivator but
what we are it's the distribution
straight up steals your money I'm
talking straight up steals your money
and Falls up and leaves and you have
zero the only company that I can trust
is is a giant one and everyone trips on
dealing with giant companies they're the
only ones to pay every one of these
other distros screws you and all they
have to do is make a single error they
make a single era and they lose a
license for 24 48 72 hours they have to
unload their entire business and then
get so you make any errors in lab or you
make any errors in distro
you destroy I mean we're talking tiny
errors you're destroyed and the amount
of oversight is heavy my storefront
we've had eight inspections now eight
with I mean I'm talking they come
through and dump out the garbage they go
through all the stuff and I go what are
you looking for they go tobacco residue
and and consumption of alcohol evidence
and I'm like who the fuck's smoking
cigarettes and drinking booze in the
dispensary I'm looking at him I'm like
this is crazy but that's what we got
[Music]
um
I I think I'm a bit stubborn where I
refuse to fail
and uh and I think part of that is
because
um I care so much about our community
and all of the Legacy Growers and the
plant and I can see all the negative
aspects of legalization and how things
have unfolded and and quite honestly I
knew it was going to go down like that
because I knew the moment that
legalization happened and all these
large corporations got into power that
they wouldn't want to you know pay their
labor to prune and they would scale up
so you know large that they would have
to use pesticides and they would fail
and I saw like I predicted all of that
and I knew that Mama cannabis is
actually in charge and we're all as
Growers infused with her and
greed is never going to win and the only
thing that's going to win is
um you know people coming together as a
community and as a collective and that's
part of legalization too it's forcing us
to evolve it's forcing us to come out of
our own individual lives and come
together and work hard together and
that's something that we've been doing
here in the Kootenays as well and you
know I understand the regulations suck
and that it's hard and difficult to
understand and I understand that the
government did this in a way to destroy
our culture but we still like I just
refuse to give up and I and it's like we
need to come together as a collective we
need to work we need to find the
administrative people and you know do it
as a giant team and as a community
because the world needs us
and the world needs cannabis Growers and
the Cannabis Community to help us evolve
and shift into a new Direction
I think that the faster the craft
community
can understand that they're no longer
just selling a a
biomass but they're they're also selling
their story they're creating their brand
and they're telling telling us a a tale
of days gone by I mean we have to
understand that you know Seagrams was
once some of the most badass gangsters
around and and not with with not a
pristine reputation and a hundred years
later they're one of the most respected
uh families in Canada and so we have to
apply that same understanding to our
culture that is slowly going to be
eroded and and destroyed over this next
hundred years where we have to Champion
it and we have to tell those stories So
the faster that these small craft
producers understand that they're not
just selling
hash rosin or they're not just selling
cured flour but they're selling a brand
and a story behind that and they're
selling you know their their Equity
partners and and the way that they take
care of the flower and what
differentiates them and and where they
came from I think the faster that
those individuals are going to be able
to really short lure out that Niche that
they need in the market and identify
their consumers because realistically we
know the consumers are out there we just
got to fucking identify them and get
them into the stores
I think there there's an evolution
happening too with just plant medicine
in general
so there's a lot with Legacy and craft
Growers that they can do in the new
paradigm of new plant medicines and so
maybe it's not just Mama ganja which we
love so much and that's led the way into
these new laws coming in so it's really
important for us to continue to advocate
for this new plant medicine laws and I
think as we also recognize part of
building regenerative Farms or having
you know the Dem peer certified Farms or
whatever was to build a sanctuary
because it was like oh it makes the
gardens healthier and it makes the
trichomes more alively and stuff but
then you also realize wow it makes me
feel so good in here and everyone that
comes by is like wow you have this Oasis
and all this food I didn't know that
food looked like that little lilocois or
kiwis whatever it is male and female you
know some plants won't bloom and then
all of a sudden you realize wow I
couldn't start a nursery of just super
foods and just bringing people in and
then even just now the whole new
wave of Tourism you know and bringing
people in and camping setups and having
people just breathe the air and being
able to walk the gardens and we talked
about like it'd be fun to like have like
you pick where someone comes and they
camp and they like I'll buy that plant
at the end of the year that would be
amazing you know but just the idea of
you know bringing the micros up to a the
research I mean uh the farm gate sales
you know where we can
we need to be able to give the medicine
which created the whole thing you know
so if if we are having a hard time
selling the weed which you know I'm
saying the lifestyle that's creating the
weed now is like becoming valuable as
a retreat center or something that's
giving people New Life on energetic
levels you know because people need to
be healed not just with medicine but
with healing other healing modalities
and I also think that you know
cannabis has always been deemed the
gateway drug
and so cannabis and we've been working
really hard to give her a place
in the world and a lot of us all of us
here have been incredibly already
successful at that so now we really need
to discuss you know are we saving
ourselves or are we saving cannabis
because if you ask me I believe that
cannabis is
is well on her way
I think that she has taken Leaps and
Bounds through the education that we've
been put forth already I'm not saying
hello because I'm going to be the last
one holding on for sure but I also think
that it's important for us to recognize
and not have so much ego that it's not
about us
it's about the plan it's about the
medicine going forward and she has
different modalities that she needs to
walk through and different doors that
she needs to be and maybe the Legacy
Market is not one that's going to get
her to the next stage that she wants to
be either not saying that the Legacy
Market is going to be done and we're
going to stop growing or anything like
that but just like Josh said if cannabis
is the gateway drug then that's the
gateway to ayahuasca ceremony that's the
gateway to MDMA that's the gateway to
LSD therapy mushrooms psychedelics all
of it
which we do now have the ability to jump
onto and say oh maybe it's not just
about the cannabis plant like Josh was
saying but it's about all of the plants
that change our lives and that we now
have this ability in Canada 2.5 grams of
any
psychedelic plant
like holy
we can really and a lot of the Legacy
Market people are the people who have
been doing plant medicine ceremony for
30 40 years already and we already have
been sitting with our friends in
psychedelic therapy for so long and a
lot of the doctors that are taking it on
much like the corporate cannabis
industry that came in in the beginning
are going to also bastardize the message
that that plant medicine has so I think
that we need to pull up our overalls and
get out there and start ushering in all
of the rest of the plants that need to
follow after cannabis
yeah I think I think you know I'm I'm
lucky enough because I most my family
comes from a state that will probably be
the last state to legalize or medicalize
cannabis it's about five kilometers that
way and if I go try and drive across the
state with what I brought to the
Festival this week and they'll throw me
in jail for 10-year minimum but that led
me to becoming a cannabis Refugee moving
to many of the early states that passed
medical and recreational laws and
allowed me to see kind of the laws pass
first in the U.S and then now here in
Canada a lot of the states when they
pass those early laws they passed fairly
restrictive laws and since then they've
actually come out with kind of fixer
bills that eased some of those early
regulations and they did that because
they didn't want to have a proliferation
of black market sales Etc so they rather
than making the industry a little bit
too lenient they started to too tight
and now that there's been kind of a wave
of legalization or medicalization kind
of grow across the U.S now you're
starting to see States actually trying
to compete in order to be a competitive
market for cannabis Canada did the same
thing you hit on it earlier the state
the federal government the provincial
governments creating a government-driven
monopoly on distribution has essentially
crushed the market it was a sent DOA
before the industry came out because the
government officials did not even
understand the cold chain associated
with a perishable product the minute the
cannabinoids are harvested the minute
the plants are harvested you're starting
a decomposition that we as processors
are going to try and minimize but it
just like grapes and wine it's a
perishable product that needs to be
maintained and
even though I can produce a kilo of
isolate for less than the kilo craft
flower in the CBD hemp Realm
we're not going to see the world you
know get flooded by poor low-grade
isolate the isolate is going to be just
like distillate a bull commodity into
the manufactured product but ultimately
like alcohol you know I can go buy I can
make a gallon ethanol at home for less
than a dollar a gallon I can go to the
store and buy go to the gas station and
buy it for less than two or three or
five here in Canada But ultimately if
I'm gonna go buy a bottle of wine at
liqueur I'm going to be spending
whatever 20 50 up to 100 because of the
story that's behind it because of the
terpenes that are present in it and
because I know it's supporting kind of a
craft Market of quality produced
products and I think while the big
producers were able to get to Market a
little bit faster due to the capital
expenditures ultimately the companies
that are going to be able to operate on
Lower margins with better profitability
are going to be the ones that kind of
focus on the higher end quality products
within the market I definitely agree
with that statement but the previous
statement to just play Devil's Advocate
I from a North American standpoint I see
it a little bit differently when we look
at State legalization when we look at
215 in California when we look at
Washington when we look at Colorado we
see the first wave of legalization and
regulation being very
I would more so argue towards loose
where you can have uh products being
manufactured in less than commercial
settings being put into a medical
and or recreational system dependent on
the state and those products with very
little oversight being delivered to end
consumers and I think this creates
tremendously positive effects because
even if this is a short window before in
future regulation I think that it allows
the new consumers who are entering the
market now that cannabis has been
legalized to be exposed to a myriad of
different products and and learn and
explore what products work for them we
did not have that opportunity in Canada
whatsoever we have to jump through so
many regulatory hoops and create such
large skus as Marcus can talk to to be
able to get a product to Market
um that there was no window of
innovation where we had a quick
opportunity to draw in a number of New
Market entrants by offering them a bunch
of different products and so we really
suffered where the current consumers
frequenting uh retail stores in Canada
are primarily new consumers and the the
consumers that have been consuming prior
to October 17 2017.
um are you know more than likely
sourcing from
different channels you know the thing
about it though right is that
I mean I've been I've been a nerd like a
long time but 15 years now of of like
public front public operational license
kind of stuff or allowed to be licensed
um and what you got is you had such an
incredible time period during prop 215
the diversity was Supernatural we had I
want to say we had like 30 000 stores or
something in Cali right with down 1100.
um so you had tremendous uh access you
had the ability for small batches to be
moved so you had many many cultivators
feeding us operation so what you got was
you got really fresh flour
diverse flower and flower from people
who were about producing flour and then
you had excellent extract makers and you
had there was it was the beginning of
the hash Revolution but this was still
really the like the butane was moving
forward
and when we went into this full legal
what you have is this radical
disappointment and
it's
it's so odd because it's almost
impossible to get anybody happy with the
circumstances because you're really not
in control of them you don't have
control of all the variables we used to
have control all the variables from from
inception to set from to consumption
and now you don't control everything and
I'm a vertical so like in some
operations I actually do control
everything from genetic development to
sale of the product out the store so
every license all the way through the
chain except lab I'm holding
so it lets me see what happens when you
have control of everything but that's
pretty rare and so most people are in
this situation where they have zero
control
and they have an expectation of a
product at a store so for most people
that go legal they only had
they went from street corner to
storefront California had 20 20 21 since
that came out in like 96 so prop to 15
come out 96 so yeah 25 years of
storefront sales
so the people are just furious that they
can't get what they used to get they
can't get that same treatment they don't
get the same prices they get worse
quality flour and so there's this anger
and resentment which then allows the
traditional to fill it but the problem
is the people with licenses are dumping
so hard into the system that they
collapse the traditional so right now
you can get indoor
in La for 800 bucks a pound indoor you
you there's there's I want to say
outdoor units are like a buck 50 200
fresh depth just went from four to six
at the storefront right so four to six
if you're moving it through the chain
if it's in the traditional that shits at
250 right if you can sell it and so
we're seeing an 80 reduction in the
economy we're seeing 80 reduction in in
in all aspects of anything peripherally
touching cannabis
and and all that'll it'll move forward
but our problem is that you know we had
so many years of this system that was
actually pretty cool too like for me I'm
from traditional prior so I never use
the storefronts in that way we just sold
product to them I didn't need to access
product that way so I was never a
consumer of the of the product through a
store I didn't really go into a
dispensary until I took one over
and then it allowed me to understand
who's coming in what they need and how
they need it and what their expectations
are and when you fulfill it you have
loyal customer
um relationships
but even now if we try as hard as we
want we still can't satisfy the people
because the way the system is set up
and it's just this
it's tumultuous and but you have to just
kind of like I I key on it I look at it
identify it and then I just push it the
fuck aside and I keep going
because I know that there is a future
and it's just really having to be able
to move through it and the issue for us
is smaller operators I mean so I have to
go grab investment for projects too but
I'm for the majority of my life I built
everything
and most people did and the problem is
that they can't sustain that Capital
bleed
and you're not big enough and when you
run your projections the the monies
aren't great enough to Warrant
investment from a larger entity and so
it's always a scale up everybody wants
to scale up but for craft you can't
scale up there's a limit you can't keep
getting bigger and still call it craft
and and that's really the issue you know
is that we have a limit to what we can
do we can't gather the funds and so like
my the way I operate is I try to be
collaborative with the people in my
community so that what it does it allows
us to kind of Share info and I can say
look this is moving and this is not
moving these things are happening and
these things are not happening and it
just lets you see let you get facts that
this is what's going down this what's
not and that way people who aren't in my
position can benefit from that
information so what it does it lets you
know that's a bad route but that's a
safe route and that's a great route
and and that's what we have always tried
to do as as community members is be cool
amongst each other and and it's really I
think more crucial than ever to behave
that way right now
because you don't have anybody but your
neighbor it's really you look across
that's this is your allies
not not anybody else
I just think it's hard that you guys
keep talking about you know Legacy
markets in different states and it's yet
to be mentioned um you know we keep
using consumer but nobody's used patient
really and I think that is a huge gap uh
in this transition and I just spent
the first four months of this year in
New York and have been working in uh
tri-state area in work in licensing down
in the states or have traditionally
um and
it's really interesting to see
um you know this Scramble for the
definition of legacy in New York and New
Jersey which are obviously huge cannabis
consumer markets they dictate a ton I
mean you have a lot to say on that
that's like brilliant and so it dictates
the trends everywhere but that being
said like I was going to mention it was
interesting I whispered to Kelly I was
like you're a fantastic grower and you
have all this clout for that but then
your
your take on the Canadian Market was as
a consumer you know and that's that's
the point that there is and so I think
you know the the term Legacy which is so
hard to Define like really involves
medicinal it's the connection with
cannabis as a medicine and
that is very real yeah
[Laughter]
all right
which is the thing the thing is no keep
going because that's valid yeah well and
it's even just as Kel mentioned like um
you know with with different seasonal
Equity a lot of that too you were
growing plants for patients and a lot of
it had to do with establishing that
community and those inroads and those
channels and you knew that this person
needed that plant but you could also use
that margin to help somebody else out
that couldn't pay you anything and so I
think it's just really valid to keep in
mind the patient and you know in that
transition of what is plant medicine and
what does that mean to the standard
person I mean look at this festival and
across the lake I mean here you have
this fireside chat but those are the
people that are going to be buying the
things at the end of the day and
determining the market and that's where
you know the investors look at BDS
analytics down in the state or what's
moving and you know people say well now
I should start a gummy company because
look gummies are great or beverages are
great and it's just chasing that thing
instead of remembering like you guys are
the ones that start the trends
we should go back just a little bit and
dimension on New York I have many
friends in New York and what their goal
currently it's wild west is what they
say is to build Brands and package
that's something we learned as Legacy
people we need to package and put it on
and make it look nice something that we
don't have here which is very disturbing
to hit a point before was raw Garden put
out 1 316 products different strains in
one year cultivars in one year how many
can you do in Canada
four
maybe six as an LP it is one basically
every six months let's say
and so that really truly cuts down the
variety and honestly I don't even know
if Canadians want it because I've been
studying the Canadian market and they
they they they're not we're not to that
educational level yet because the
consumer and we are not those people and
we are not to judge what they want to
buy off of what we like because that
doesn't work
they want to buy pre-rolls
they want to buy vape pens and they want
to buy flowers and we can the rest of
those percentages drop way down and it's
all coming and it's all growing fast
those other categories are growing fast
100 but when you talk to the Canadian
consumer
I would like a reasonable price
and I want to be cheap you guys sells
pre-rolls by the 140 pack yeah I was
like what the fuck is that I mean the
cultivator is saying that they're
getting more money
pieces now than they are actually
getting for the fires that they try and
the bottom line too is we're out of the
tobacco area so nobody nobody knows how
to roll weed anymore no they think so
it's weird
convenience where our pen our pen Mark
is re-blowing back up you know we're
running like 30 we're in the mid 30s on
flower sales I'll say as a connoisseur
of great hash and great cannabis that
entering the legal Market in Canada
really kind of crushed my soul when I
made my first batch of bubble and my
qa's there and we're making it I'm like
this is fucking awesome whipping up you
know five six dried kilos at a time
we're gonna make a kilo of bubs get it
in the freeze dryers and I'm kind of
like uh I only did this once I was like
okay let's separate all the grades yeah
we're gonna keep all the microns
separate and yeah these are real nice
ones here 90 73 120 oh yeah that's nice
get it all get it all at the end of my
qa's like okay so how many are you gonna
mix all this together I'm like well no
no you got it we gotta keep them
separate she's like okay so instead of
1200 I'll just multiply that by eight
twelve hundred for each COA times eight
so now and then the next thing to crush
me was when Ontario was like oh yeah we
want your bubble but uh we're gonna need
like four kilos of it or and then if we
sell it really fast you gotta have
another four kilos right away and I'm
thinking how the fuck am I gonna get
eight kilos of 90 Micron bubble how the
how am I gonna fucking I'm like and then
my whole team is like you're not dude
you're not gonna do that we need you to
mix them all together and I'm like
I'm all together I'm the kind of
creative
I want them separate I don't want them
together
but surely these things just crushed me
and I was like okay like I'll keep going
and then and then what you were saying
no like very accurate like
I want to release six star 90 Micron
bubble but it's like those aren't my
customers the customers in the Canadian
Market is like they want something
inexpensive they want something they
want pre-roll so I'm like well I'm a
hash guy what am I going to do to bring
those those people have only one piece
of paraphernalia it's a big lighter they
don't have rolling papers they don't
have anything no grinder they buy
pre-roll joints they're about 85 percent
of the Canadian market so now I'm like
what can I make for them where they can
only use a lighter and then I had to
come out with this product called hash
hits that's like really to me it's
certainly not a six star hash it would
be a mediocre hash but that's what's
supposed to go with that but man you
know it's five it's a gram you get five
paper tubes with a little stainless
steel bowl there's point two of a gram
of hash they're killing it like we sell
so many of them in every Province like
people love them because now the joint
smoker can like bridge over to but that
was hard for me not like I had to go
against my own ego and my own like what
I thought like holy shit like all I've
been about is the best quality ever but
now I'm in an industry that if I try to
make six star 90 Micron bubble that like
people like Jameson be like yeah dude
that's fire I will go bankrupt no you
enter those in the comments and take
pictures of it I'll be bankrupt company
will be out of business so now it's like
we got to figure out something that's
like that you can get to the that
Marketplace you know that group of
people that are they're certainly not us
well I think it's a separation of skus
right we as as processors have to take
our products bring it in do it do what
we do and pick it out and be like okay
well this is going to go into infused
joints because now that is actually the
number one seller because people they
just want to get high let's just be
honest get out of work and you want to
get high so if you can do it in one
joint that joint is a 40 THC or go out
40 THC
I don't necessarily think you care what
star it is no right at all so we're
always going to cream that at the very
top and hopefully sell that well here's
the other thing because I want to do
that so yeah
say you do make the six star the minute
it leaves your facility I got it at like
minus 30 degrees Celsius the minute it
leaves my facility it's now like Mike
was talking it's just like these people
are shipping warm like warm spinach
without any like it's produce you have
to keep it cool so it just gets degraded
on the weight of the place every single
dispensary do you know what they keep in
their cool fridges the few that they
have fucking beverages with 10
milligrams of distilling Nano emulsified
that doesn't need to stay in the fridge
like let people use ice put the hash and
the oil and all the weed you have in the
building in those fucking fridges and
freezers because there's volatile
compounds Beyond terpenes and terpenoids
into thile calls and bio weights and
Esters that are that are so volatile
they are just degrading if they're not
like cold
that's what we're fighting
yeah
I think I think the key is just
understanding like those those zippering
market segments right that in 50 years
would I go by at a bodega in New York
City is going to be different than what
I buy at a high-end canaguar Lounge in
New York City right and you know the
people the more educated consumers are
probably going to be keeping up with the
Trends on what genetics are being
developed Trends on new types of hash
and they'll be more likely to buy it pay
for a premium But ultimately in the
early and draggingly slow rollout that
is federally regulated products we have
to be able to produce products that we
could we can sell to you know in an
entire Province for now eventually
entire countries because Canada allows
export of products to other continents
but we need to be able to sell products
that can easily be replicatable
consumable and in the early part of that
market it's going to be something that
follows kind of a uniform standard
operating procedure your whereas as as
the industry evolves you're not going to
have your 20 bottle of wine or whatever
forty dollar fifty dollar bottle extract
you're going to start to have that
diverse diversification of that of the
market you'll have your 40 gram of
extract or 100 Grand magic you'll have
your you'll have your 40 eighth or a
forty dollar ounce and I'm not gonna buy
the 40
ounce unless if I'm gonna roll up a
bunch of joints to give away to a bunch
of tourists but I am going to be going
to the market and buying those 40 AIDS
so genetics I haven't grown yet because
I want to see if that genetic fits with
my patient profile my bio essay
so in California in Canada in Washington
in Colorado we have very very accurate
Market data and understanding of
consumers that are walking into the
doors of these retail
consumption areas and and we even have
polls and other questionnaires that are
proposed by high foluting corporations
like Deloitte and BDS and and places
like that quantifying the market
opportunity and telling us how much
money we could make and how many
consumers there really are it's fucking
bullshit like there's no fucking way
that these individuals crunching numbers
are able to ascertain the culture or the
undercurrent that has carried this
industry for the last however many
whatever number you want to pick between
five thousand and a hundred and so like
my my my understanding is like okay fine
cool we all at the whole Market
including the suits understands the
purchasing parodies and and trends of
the individuals walking in the door what
we're here to talk about and the value
we're here to add is how we expose those
new groups to get those groups in the
doors and get markets to those
individuals that will transition those
individuals because I'll tell you
somebody like me is worth a lot more
than somebody walking in and buying a
pack of pre-rolls at the end of every
week and so if you're able to convert a
heavy use consumer who's been using for
decades Decades of heavy use and it's
not uncommon you're going to unlock
a a tremendous amount of of Revenue of
revenue for your company and so you know
we have the road map of how to okay
let's create pre-rolls okay fine put
distillate in them call them rocket
rolls and fucking fine cool we're not I
don't want to I don't want to talk about
that I want to talk about how we create
unique products that we can get
uh existing community members to change
where they're accessing their medicine
from so we can we can change this trend
in the right way like that's what I
think we should be talking about not you
know okay pre-rolls are growing and so
are vape pens
[Music]
because what we're assuming is that your
snapshot is correct and what it's
showing is this is what happens in a
market that is inadequately developed
and controlled and so you've lost the
diversity and you've lost the ability to
capture you you're not the people when I
when I was when I was actively in this
shop in the in the Heyday of of before
legalization
people would come in and buy six or
seven hundred dollars worth of oil at a
time because that's what they consumed
and they had the income for it but they
would come and buy it that doesn't exist
anymore
and we've lost that group because you've
dissatisfied them with what's taken
place and you're using headset data so
everybody's using the same data set to
build their operation and I'm just like
whatever you want to do just don't do
that
foreign
what's that
oh yeah oh yeah yeah this was and it was
constant I mean it was it was for years
and years and years we had these type of
sales because that's where people who
wanted products they couldn't because
what they knew was that they knew
friends who blasted but what I had done
is I had gone to all the friends that
were good blasters and said would you
guys start filling our stores and all I
need to do is have our own Labs test
your product
and then will will if you want will even
brand it for you if you don't want to
put your name on it so you don't get
revealed but what we had was this
ungodly collection of products and it
allowed us to catch the people who
really consumed the product they don't
they don't exist in the dispensaries
right now
and it's a travesty
[Music]
it is the Fireside chatting amongst
ourselves
nobody was you were saying it is
important because what you're saying is
that's us in BC we're all in the same
situation in in the in the fact that
legalization created a barrier that that
only allows specific people to come in
and they come in and they're risk
adverse so when when people say to me
you know what do you want to do I said
do anything that goes over 68 days
because nobody's run anything over 65.
it's real simple like go in the store
and say there's 72 choices don't do
those
anything that says ice cream don't do it
I don't care people love it there's too
many competitors it's okay just
understand that you can't follow the map
they're giving you because they don't
know where the fuck they're going either
so you have to look at data and
statistics in a manner that is relevant
to the situation it's not like I call it
biblical and I'm not really even
religious but it's not real it's a
snapshot of a moment in time in a
situation that is not open to change so
as we disrupt it we have change but I
want to recapture those people I want to
recapture the people and and to me
it's almost like it's the micro groups
everywhere that are really the new heart
and soul of cannabis where you're too
light for light regen tent grower
because it's all you have to that's your
infrastructure you don't have the
ability to put a farm in and when I meet
these people I'm seeing some of the
nicest product I've seen because it's
the return to craft production and I've
always dreamed of Home production for
everyone I don't as a dispensary owner I
still advocate for it continuously
because for all my medical years nobody
could afford it and that's why we did
all that subsidy shit I mean I gave away
fucking millions and millions of dollars
for years and sometimes as I struggle
now I'm like whoa what did I do and then
I asked myself would I do it again I go
yeah because ultimately it was a
beautiful moment in time where you got
to have a relationship with people that
were really needy and cannabis was that
food is what they had to eat and and for
me all the years in the hustle
I realized that I had never understood
medical cannabis and I didn't have any
clue about medical people
and
it caught me you know it caught me
emotionally and so
to me home growing is medical there but
all use of cannabis is medical spiritual
inspirational how do we want to define
it it's just that the medical has the
most need and usually the least on a
cash
you know and I think that uh education
Falls right behind that where you have
pushed you know I personally have pushed
a lot of Education about terpenes let's
just say and
that doesn't pay you and so to speak to
your point I want to talk about the the
things that are good and coming up and
everything but the other side of it is
the balance of the books and with the
money the truth is in the numbers and we
have to make money they're not making it
easy for any of us to do in any country
I believe no you know we each have our
own issues with it all so
to drive that it requires like Shannon
said in the past a large team of people
to really truly Drive the education
Drive the concept of your story because
I think that
all you know in this world of
consumerism uh we're looking for Unique
Individuals and unique story lines that
add a
flavor to your product that you can't
buy and you can't make it's because you
did it you lived it right and so we need
to capture that as a group of small
craft individuals and boutique Growers
and truly represent us as a whole
because that's the only way we can have
the amount of pull we need to
necessarily compete with a larger group
out there without selling pieces of our
soul to get the money to do it
because we know that that's what it
comes down to if you go out and try to
do it yourself you are going to have to
give up something of yourself to do it
there's always a price to pay you know I
mean like if you're talking about
cannabis culture it's free exit and
entry but when it comes down to cannabis
business under regulated rules it's you
either play it or you don't and if you
don't want to do it don't and if you do
do I mean it's that simple and and so
you have to really really really want to
be here if you want to be here
and that's that's the difficult part is
just desire doesn't get you far enough
you know and and when it comes to
education it doesn't pay but I don't
look at it as payment like I I did an
ungodly amount of pro bono education
because I wanted to share information
that I was receiving currently and I
knew I was getting stuff that was flying
out of the pipe straight and I was just
regurgitating it into the public so that
we would have a more educated consumer
group and cultivation group and I I I
didn't want to monopolize the
information so that I was the only one
with it because what I always knew is
you're not going to survive alone
you know
yeah it's the love of it but it's the
love of the people too like I
I spent my whole life in weed and so
herb herb took care of me my whole life
right and so what I know is that I don't
have to know you or benefit from you if
you benefit from the information because
what I know is that if if when I was
needy and I got information that was
valuable it was extremely important and
I said well I'm catching shit that most
people aren't catching I'm in a lot of
rooms that people aren't in and I'm not
signing ndas that say I can't talk about
it and so I was I mean I've been spewing
for years
so that people would get some insight
about what was taking place so that
other peoples could survive
and that way we got more of us in the
room
he's right there uh yeah yeah before I
get into this I Marcus I didn't know
you're so funny man like awesome that's
great that's awesome
yeah
um just pulling it back to what Kelly
was referring to in the different
languages between the Legacy and and the
commercial market and it it is
interesting I will say right my my
perspective is one from a pure business
um I I've come to the Cannabis industry
I came out of high tech high tech was a
blast right I was there before I was in
in the world of Google when AdWords
weren't a thing and I watched AdWords
come on and it was absolutely
astronomical I mean we were earning
every dollar we would spend on Google
AdWords in those days shit we were
earning 10 bucks in Revenue it was
ridiculous it was like shooting fish in
a barrel and it and that dried up like
it just it just dried up right and then
you know as the as technology evolved I
got into product development and really
understood how organizations should
operate and after 20 years and you know
getting kicked so many damn times and
learning during the lumps of of what it
takes to run a corporation right that's
that's our opportunity here
right in Canada right I hear about the
US and and and it's different mentality
from a business perspective there is a
lot of Regulation here in Canada and and
I'll tell you every company in the
Canadian market today is a startup and
what further compounds that is that
we're in a startup industry
right it's a cluster
daily it's a cluster large LPS small LPS
micros it's a cluster and yet that's our
opportunity
right that's our opportunity
to get organized
to understand the processes and learn
the language Kelly it's beautiful I will
say right I've heard this word called
this combination a phrase of creative
compliance
right if you start to read the
regulations you can drive a Mac Truck
somewhere through some of these as long
as and I'll look at Marcus and we'll go
as long as your QA you know is drinking
the same Kool-Aid that you're drinking
right so there are ways to do it
and we talk about the different you know
it's US versus them
but we we forget about this layer right
in the middle and it's people
right it's not it's not US versus them
like no no sorry no no no no no no no
I'm just saying the language the
language there's individuals in our
industry who are motivated only by
Financial enrichment 100 that's them
yeah and then there's the others and
that's us yeah and there is a fucking
line and it is US versus them it's very
very fucking much is us first so let me
tell you this I'm not I'm not gonna
debate that I'm talking about there's
when we as as as commercial corporate
corporate LPS we want to sell our
product into Ontario there's this layer
of of people in there and they just want
to help us
regardless of shape size form they just
want to help us
right so having somebody there to help
interpret that and understand that and
again I'll go back to the startup within
a startup every province is still trying
to organize themselves BC just
reorganize the way that they buy again
we got to relearn that we got we we have
to have build new relationships with new
people again so it's it can be done and
the beauty of that is we're small we're
Nimble and we actually have a brand
we've got a storyline you guys are so
damn authentic it's it's so beautifully
Rich right yeah
yeah that's what I've seen it I've seen
the big you know publicly traded I've
worked in those sterile walls and now
down to smaller guys like like Che and
stuff like that's our opportunity they
can't pivot like we can and then that
middle layer they want to help us right
a prime example is Ontario right now
they've created a flow through model
right so whether you've got you know
three kilos for sale or 10 kilos for
sale right they want your product right
you want to talk about supporting a
small you know your community again like
there is an ideal opportunity and it's
evolving right I imagine soon enough
this this flow through model will be
across the country right Alberta's
trying to figure it out but that's our
opportunity is to figure out how we can
become Nimble use creative compliance
and just be agile right and get smart
with products
data's interesting it really is you're
right about the you're right about the
agility because when we talk about it
was we had a question the other day
about like genetics and it was you know
everybody's gonna knock each other out
and you're like no in order to do
stabilized seed lines you got a couple
year development process if you're
looking for a one-off uh hunts then
that's instantaneous if you're doing TC
work it can be up to 9 to 12 months if
depending on how infected the cultivar
is and how many times you've got to
stress it to pull the pathogen out so
you can expose it and clean it regular
propagation is two weeks so what you
have is you have
the the scientific push and then you
have the craft push and they're
different and so if it takes me 12
months to propagate something and get it
in and I can do it in two weeks
then that means that I I'm faster than
you it doesn't mean that I can compete
with you but it means I have a niche
because I can get a product that's
trending into Market quicker same thing
with seed work where we we see there's a
trend in tripping change we see
volatiles that people want they go
They're heavy volatile sulfurs are
coming back into Vogue well we know that
we can run into those populations
quickly and then hunt out a cultivar
versus try to develop a stabilized seed
line which is going to take us a couple
years so stabilize seed work which comes
from large businesses is a radically
different view than people that are
hunting from a smaller level and so
they're not really competing and TC
nurseries aren't really competing with
conventional nurseries because
propagation is pretty simple and TC is
extremely expensive to create the
operation but pathogenically you need
the scrubbing services but the people
that were doing small nurseries were
like TC who's going to get them right
away and I'm like no they they can't get
the market the product to Market quick
enough and so as long as you stay hyper
Nimble it's just the problem is staying
hyper Nimble requires a commitment to
the craft that's phenomenal and for a
lot of people in cannabis prior the
reason why they got into cannabis was
because it allowed you I always tell
people I said the beauty cannabis was it
let me work x amount days a month and
make make attorney money like doctor
money and what did I get out of that an
unfucking believable good life I had
time to be with my kids I got to travel
with my children I got to do a lot of
shit regular people don't get to do
because I had the money and the time and
someone said you should have been making
more money every day and I said no I
made enough money now I had time
and that's the problem is that for most
of us at a career we kind of understood
the value of time and so the having to
shift in and so like for me at 56 I I
still I'm willing to go but it's hard to
get a lot of people from the world we
were in to commit to that level of speed
and so the pace is what's killing them
too and but you're totally right that
there's there's these blinks you can get
in but you have to be totally cognizant
of the blink and you need to move today
yeah that and you know the word
consistency always comes to mind in our
shop right consistency every Harvest
needs to be consistent right that's
really a big part of it and in that yeah
agility is a big a big move and yet here
in Canada it's the agility there's a
structured system and I think it's the
if we understand that structured system
who we need to sell to at the different
levels right sure you've got your
internal team you've got to sell two
then you got to get out and then now you
got to sell to the provincial buyers
then you got to sell to The Dispensary
buyer then you're gonna sell to the bud
tender and ultimately you got the last
mile which is the consumer so we've got
five levels and that's all buried in
beautiful red tape
right it really is it's it's looking at
that and understanding the way that we
can navigate through that we'll provide
I think opportunities for brands that
are craft to truly come to the Forefront
and we're seeing the crumble of the
mid-tier groups right they just can't do
it they cannot earn and keep the doors
open for the dollar and the wholesale
market today it's it's an interesting
Market it really is here in Canada it's
super competitive extremely competitive
you guys over built like your your
expectations of of moving product
globally
unfortunately just didn't come to
fruition well with US Dollars though
yeah yeah right U.S cash yeah yeah
because we couldn't we couldn't use the
stock market in the US and so but the
thing is it like you know some of the
California Ops you know that we're going
to see a lot of these major ones fold up
and nobody's talking about it but I'm
like I know you're not turning to profit
and your investors at this point aren't
going to give you any more money and so
we're going to see this cleansing we
figured that you should see in the next
year and a half so next year should be a
blood bath again and then we'll start to
come out of it and you get into 2024
in 2025 and you start to have normality
because we've cleaned out both big and
small
and you got to get rid of these bigger
groups because really what they're doing
is they're dumping and in California I'd
say 40 50 of the total products sold in
stores the other half of the product
grown is going out the back door
and so it's it's sustaining groups that
shouldn't be sustained
because ultimately what you're doing is
you're using your tools to to be able to
work your infrastructure allows you
enough product to sell at a low price to
make enough to continue but for small
farms that's not true
and so it's this it's this odd situation
where you understand how to manipulate
the rules
and you're big enough to be able to
sustain movement and if you can even
register a nickel on the profit the
investors will continue to feed but
anybody below that level is dying but
it's it's going to suddenly flop in a
minute it's I can't sustain forever and
so we're about to see the collapse come
and we need it we you need to get rid of
all these large operations that are not
meant to be there I call them aphid
factories because I tore them right
they're aphid factories that's what
they're growing is they're aphid
factories
and I've never seen anything like in my
life if you stop moving the plants are
moving so they literally moving on the
table so then like you know there's only
six companies that make dishwashers
there's only one or two companies that
make eyeglass frames
are we heading to that sort of Cold War
era in California that is leading the
evolution of the Cannabis sort of yes
without a question there is no question
that that's what's coming and you know
I'm looking at two million three million
square foot Greenhouse operations you
just got one that come online that's
going to be running seven they're
looking I think their their goal is a
risk right now about a million million
pounds per year the goal is to get a 80
ounce into the store and of of decent
weed right decent and the problem is
though is that their marketing and his
craft and so what it does is it confuses
the customer right and so we had we had
this we had this debate about this
concept called crafted scale right and
so the largest operation has this and I
said to them I said isn't that a fucking
oxymoron can they it's like saying
you're tall and short at the same time
they they don't go together and and I'm
laughing but they weren't but
it's the part is that my thing is take
the lane you belong in and so what you
need is you need inexpensive cannabis
for the majority because ultimately it's
an agricultural crop and so if we could
grow inexpensive cannabis cleanly in a
sustainable fashion then please let that
happen because people really need to buy
45 ounces because I don't have the money
for a 95 eighth and my store is selling
85 dollar AIDS so like I'm touching the
highest end of the the periphery of
cannabis and I'm a craft operator at the
same time so I'm kind of anomaly because
I'm a craft farmer but I'm I'm playing
with monstrous companies
and so it kind of lets you see the the
picture in totality
but you have to have economies scale to
create these agricultural products and
once we have that now we have a clear
division on what is craft and and what
we do like like what we've been working
on is we we've developed the gone GA
program
and
we we fought hard to get it into
Humboldt County so that what I was able
to do was get all these people that were
buyers for these 140 store operations to
come in and get an education but what I
do is I bring them in with craft Farmers
so I have Farmers meet them in the
parking lot just to smoke weed with them
and to throw a bag to them and I have
Farmers come to the class to talk about
it we bring in herb that's two years old
to let them know this is what
two-year-old herb looks like done right
and what it does it's recalibrating
everybody so it's allowing us to start
getting bigger companies to start
creating
relationships with Craft Farms because
the lead buyer of someone who's moving
two billion dollars worth of weed
realizes that's better pot
and so we're working on this education
but educating the customer it's
effective but you better educate the
people who are buying the grass for the
distro and who's who's buying the weed
for the store because they're the ones
that put the product in the window and
then the data is based off of that
so the the gatekeeper is the one who's
really controlling the data and people
are trying to educate the customer
constantly and all I'm trying to educate
the customer on is how do you buy weed
in the new system it's the people who
are going to sell the weed that you need
to educate on how do you Market it how
do you showcase it how do you gradient
on price and how do we determine quality
that's not branding because right now
branding controls price quality is
quality branding is branding and we want
to clearly start to Define it so we
spend all this time developing the
system so that what we could do and my
goal wasn't to educate the consumer it
was to educate the people who are
gatekeeping our money so that they have
an ability to understand wow craft
product is better if there's an Echelon
and there's an upper echelon then that's
craft
and that way we are able to get lifted
up because craft has to be more valuable
than commercial or we can't do it and
and and it's not about
because we we're there because I know a
lot of Craft Farms that grow shitty pot
like I'm just going to say what it is
they've been growing wheat for a long
time and they were able to get sub-grade
herb into the system because the system
had a fucking need well there's no more
need and now it better be good and what
you're seeing is pretty good isn't good
enough and most people were pretty good
and you have to really be clear about
like what's good and what's not and and
developing these grading standards and
getting the ability to be able to say I
got you this is better blending your
hash shouldn't have to be the case
because the bottom line the irony when
you say in that I'm the guy that
invented that was fell out of my fucking
chair because it's so true you're like
I'm the wrong person to blend I'm the
guy that separated it you can't make me
go back
and they have to because otherwise you
can't exist
and and it's it's in that it's in that
reality and it's it's the communication
to the people who are selling and buying
and getting them to actually sit down
and experience the different products
and be able to say look I'm not trying
to convince you with words I'm going to
let you chill the product and and you'll
experience it
that's what's what's not taken place
because we don't have that open
environment with cannabis anymore the
way that the shops used to work was it
was radically more freely moving and so
you could bring product in talk to the
buyer show the product consume the
product give them some product let them
think about the product then they would
take your product now it's through a
buyer that is disconnected from anything
else and and they're and I'm saying
Canada they are radically undereducated
holy Christ like you guys have a problem
you have a problem you have government
officials buying you weed holy shit when
I realized like when I got to look at
this yeah because he said I looked at it
like a customer because that's the only
person I really care about in the
business because everyone's bought a
weed right so I said what's it like to
go to a store take me to a store and so
Dennis and Mark took me to a store and I
was like looking around and I'm like 140
pre-rolls in a container and then it was
140 and 60 and 20. I'm like people
buying that shit
wow like that's a purchase
and it was and I realized wow Canada
whoa your your legacy Market must be
doing the majority of the good work
because there's nothing in the store
that was good well the people who bought
cannabis in the past in Canada were not
in those channels to get those jobs the
people who got those jobs were in liquor
distribution and tobacco distribution
and they just moved right into those
jobs I thought the same thing and I
think the same thing but I will say
there is a silver lining there's
cannabis people now buyers that have
been buyers over the years that are now
going into those jobs and I met a guy in
Manitoba this guy Dan he called me up
he's like oh I'm one of the buyers for
Manitoba and I'm like oh my God what's
this gonna be like I brought my pot
smoking Uncle over to his house we go to
this guy's house and I'm telling you I
was like I teared up a little bit I was
like every single room in his house was
overflowing with like he had rosin
presses and he had grow tents and he was
he was 3D printing tags for all of
plants in one room like everything in
the house was for weed and I just
thought fuck if we get more guys like
this being the buyers for the provinces
I mean that's legitimately what you need
you really need that we don't have it
yet no you have to have the regulatory
support and and the thing is that
cannabis has become a cannabis is always
cool but it's become it's become allowed
so that people who previously had to
hide their their stuff can open it up
and I was with all the state regulators
and I have this this uh uh what do you
call it an auditor and he comes walking
up to me and he whispers in my ear I
Know Who You Are
and that the fucking hair my back stood
up because when you have the when you
have the government Auditors saying I
know who you are and he's like bro I
follow all your shit I got a tent in my
house right now man I'm gonna send you a
photo can you give me your number and I
was like holy shit I think it's gonna be
all right
because it's the truth you're having a a
change it's just the problem is
it doesn't happen quick enough when your
capital is bleeding and so the issue
here is a bleed rate
can you control the bleed rate
and for a lot of the farmers I talked to
I said listen just follow your farm and
go get a job for a year I mean I I
Lawrence Ringo's son I bumped in him the
other day Lawrence Ringo is one of the
pioneers of CBD right so like we're
talking Pioneer and and he was a
sweetheart too man I love Lawrence and I
bump into his son and I've known his
kids for years too and he's like man I
followed by farm and he goes and I went
and got an AG permit he goes it cost me
35 and I said how much can I grow they
said as much as you want anywhere you
want he goes I put up a farm buildings
for everybody whatever you want and he's
like
he's like bro farming is easy
and when is the last time you had
someone say Farm is easy well yeah
compared to cannabis farming it is
um I had a question and maybe Kevin you
can answer this but Marcus you made me
think of it when you said like
pharmaceutical reps come over and
it's awesome to educate the buyers but
what happens when there's these large
companies that are investor-backed that
have retailers that have to hit certain
numbers so what they do is what
pharmaceutical companies did where they
go in and they send sales rep with a
bunch of perks for the bud tenders who
are then expected to sell a certain
amount of that product and so it's
basically you know you you have these
companies that are coming from more
traditional sales backgrounds rather
than this is the best we have ever seen
you have to put this on the shelf and
more like okay the bud tenders know this
they all have the t-shirts they're gonna
do a demo you know and how does that
impact that in your that's a good
question and the problem the problem
with that mentality and sales is that
people get really pissed off if they
even push them Herb that doesn't do the
job
and so as the person at the counter when
someone buys weed from you and comes
back the next day and throws it at you
and says the shit sucked and you told me
it was good all of a sudden you don't
want to push that product anymore
and that's a problem with all stores so
anytime the the the employees lose favor
of a thing you got to sit down and say
are you just tired of selling it because
we sell a lot of it or are you having
bad feedback that's causing problems and
we maybe we shouldn't sell it
and they're two different things so so
selling flour that you need to sell but
trying to sell sub pot flour and push it
to the customer that bites you in the
ass and it comes back because ultimately
what you do is you lose the customer and
so the more they try to force the desire
upon the individual what they don't
catch fundamentally to me is that it's
like they don't have to smoke weed in
their life wheat is the drug that when
you consume it it lets you see bullshit
it's the drug when you consume it that
you do not conspire to fuck others over
so you're selling a drug that pond
consumption gives a lens of clarity
about what just occurred and so you
consume and go I just got fucked by you
and you don't go back and so I think
that's the issue it's just what's taken
places you got
not enough storefronts and so you have
Limited store for instance so the stores
control the flow of the product too well
and then the people that can then make
the relationships with the store as a
control in it but the thing is they're
having such dissatisfaction that you're
driving customers right out of the
stores so it's backfiring on them as
well because they're losing customers
from that strategy
you can give them all the t-shirts and
hats and all the shit you want you get
four customers come in and swear at them
which they do I like I've even been
behind the counter oh it's an
interesting experience
especially one that's moving a lot of
people and a lot of money you see rage
and that shit doesn't work so for me the
more you try to drive subpop product by
those methodologies because cannabis as
a consumption when you consume it it's
not fucking ice cream it has a radically
different effect on you and I I talk to
people all the time and I'm like does
anybody that building even smoke like
you don't have to be a smoker to do the
business but you better have somebody
who's a consumer in your fucking Circle
who's clearly telling you this shit is
garbage and if you don't have that and
you're making the Assumption even the
scientists I work with in labs they go
we're doing all analysis by by COA and
I'm laughing and I'm like I got any
fucking mind
it's not a lab that's going to consume
it it's a human being so you have to get
a human in the room to sample it because
this paper does not give you any
information about that
and that's just what it is and so
I get to fuck with some Giants and when
I see them stumbling around the dock it
makes me feel a little more confident
well I think the the keeping us all
isolated not allowing vapor lounges you
know having vapor lounges would allow so
many people to learn so much if we had a
place to consume together and you know
because right now there's really the
market we talk about right now in Canada
is not actually the market you think
you're talking about because that market
the the Legacy Market
most of those people still grow their
own weed make their own hash trade
amongst their friends buy with their
friends they're not really a part of the
Canadian Market the Canadian Market is
all these people that are like oh they
legalize marijuana like I'm gonna give
it a shot I got a gummy and I got like a
little a drink it tastes like beer and I
got this other thing this little vape
pen thing and so it's this whole other
group of people that are currently like
if you want to pay your burn every month
like they're they're how you're gonna do
it it's not through all of these but at
the same time I'm with you I want to
recapture those people I want to sell
six star and full Mount dry sift and I
want to like have Podium products that
are like small batch and incredible and
you know powered by regenerative Farms
like Rosebud and done and all these
different groups in Canada that's what I
want to see but it's like until we can
actually sit around and consume cannabis
in public
We're Not Gonna you know the world
changed when people just started
drinking beers and pubs the
conversations that occurred from those
experiences with that drug created the
future world and then they did then they
started doing tea houses and those
conversations were different from the
ones that were being done by the
laborers who were drinking the beer
these were different people who were
Scholars and they were drinking tea and
that created conversations that created
a new future and then people started
drinking coffee and coffee was super
productive and that created a whole
different reality this is going to as
well but we need to be able to hang out
in public just like you can go to a
store right into a vapor lounge and have
these conversations and bump into one
another and that's why we all loved
Amsterdam in the 80s and the 90s because
it was that it was the only place in the
world you could go to and just bump into
people from other places yeah I like
weed too I'm from Denmark oh I'm from
Canada let's talk
I think that's what's important about
what we're doing right here right now
this is it this is one of the few places
I've seen in Canada events that allows
us to do that and all get together
and hang out and Converse with each
other because the community really is
small in the end and uh to be able to
sit with each other and break bread
let's say is a huge
um
that impact on how we all walk away and
think about it and who we talk to and
how we go out and socially describe what
we do now and how we think of it is all
influenced by each other's conversations
here we need more events that are
properly done to be able to do so
and more than events we need normalized
lounges that are in every city that you
can just be skateboarding and be like Oh
weird like I see pod stores all the time
I have zero interest in going in I'm
like oh I should go into this generic
shop that looks like an Apple store that
has like all the products look exactly
the same and I and I'm like a cannabis
consumer of 30 plus years and I can't
fucking recognize any of them is that a
payroll joint oh it's a vape cartridge
okay that's weird I just can't recognize
any of it but if I went by and saw a
vapor lounge that I could just go into
and here's the other thing about
cannabis you'd be welcome at every table
in that vapor lounge if there was only
one chair at a 12 person table and you
walked in of course come and sit down
man we'll smoke with you like let's find
out who this person is and let's those
conversations that are yet to happen are
going to create our future world I go we
have we have a a consumption license at
our spot but kovid made it a pain in the
ass was an outside one and because we
have acreage there we just let the
acreage be the lounge but I love lounges
and I go to the ones in the city when
I'm in town check them out well my
favorite one was this uh the Northwest
Social Club in Oregon
and it was so eclectic and diverse and
who was there and how they ran it and
the cost that it made it really cool and
and what I tripped out on was that the
clusters of people who were in their 70s
and 80s that were bringing in ounces of
oil to blaze I was like whoa you're the
concentrate consumers of bulk and
quality though you know like but I
couldn't all tie-dyed out and I mean my
grandmother's age and I was just like oh
this is awesome
and it let me see that diversity and
then there was groups of women so I
always look for groups of women because
what I know is that if you see women
coming into places or you see women
walking in areas and you see them
without men they feel safe so they must
be low crime rate and there's no
pressure to go into the club and so what
I saw is very
different demographics than bars and
radically friendlier with if you could
sit down there was always a space and we
would go me and Pedro would go and hang
out in the Northwest and I'd be in there
for like nine hours and everybody that
we were supposed to meet on business I'd
have them come to the club and meet so
we could just hang out and get high
and and they had such an incredible
setup where they had underneath on the
the basement they had all the pool
tables and old school games and ping
pong and shuffleboard and on the on the
top floor they had all these uh TVs but
it only had four different kinds of
movie cannabis movies comedies Kung Fu
and like old school 80s action right so
you had interesting stuff and they had
music in an outside area and when you
went in the food was really cheap so you
could you know you could get a drink for
a dollar fifty so what it did is it
allowed you not to be victimized while
you were in and so you bought a yearly
membership and then you'd show up and
drop a couple bucks to get in
but it was like my single favorite place
in the world
because when I was hanging out there's
always somebody sitting next to you and
everybody starts to have a conversation
and you don't have that in in bars the
same way because once people get
liquored up they're a different person
and
not everybody transforms but most
transform but with cannabis the
transformation is usually man this is so
hot you want to smoke some
and and it's it's to me it's the way the
community has to be built so I fully in
agreement that the fact that we're
allowed to buy the product but we can't
consume it anywhere except in in our we
want you to take it directly home and
consume it in your house when the
windows closed I can't smoke anywhere in
public I mean it was like that Vancouver
originally and that was what was really
cool about Vancouver was going to
Vancouver wow you can do that here in
North America and buy seeds in the
basement whatever it was you know that
was the blunt Brothers Cafe exactly Ice
come up and blazing the blunt brothers
because I was like yeah
and um you know and also just that that
kind of was the patient care side of
things too it's when you talk about make
groups of women sometimes that's like
their
Therapy Group where they're going
through cancer together or something and
and I think for us always cannabis was
like becoming more intelligent Rising
above like what was left what was given
to you like medically uh or whether it's
athletes you know there's so many
athletes in the world that are you know
they're getting broken or they're
getting compromised and there's no real
guidance in the medical industry for
True health and well-being so I like the
idea of lounges as well when they're
mixed with like elixir bars and you know
herbal uh you know exploration hydrosols
aromatherapy and stuff so you're like
getting high and then all of a sudden
you're like whoa like experiencing
plants in a whole different way a better
food a better way of existing at home
and um that's uh part of the magic of
the ganja and bringing the community
together and I do think that's missing
and I think that the medical industry
and getting the people that are left out
you know when the medical industry can't
do anything that's her men I have you
know cannabis really shines and in the
you know the the regulated system I just
don't feel that medicine is really for
those people so it's almost more just
blast out like consumer medicine where I
just really resonate with the craft
aspect of it and creating Avenues and
lounges and places where we can get
together so we can communicate what's
working about the medicine and it's not
just a product that's going out and it
fits a data set and a you know a a graph
you know you're actually learning how
your medicine is reacting with people
and then people needing it and I just I
I just will I think all of us would
always stand you know for that that
light and moving forward I hope that we
can still do that with things that are
happening you know locally local
processors being able to support local
micro producers and these events uh
moving forward I wanted to actually you
were almost describing my Vapor Bar in
in like 2001 my my the melting point so
I had my first my first Lounge I opened
up the melting point 2001 on Commercial
Drive I was in Jamaica on the beach and
my buddy called me and said I found your
your place 11 I and I and I and I 11 11
Commercial Drive I was like I rented it
didn't even know what I was doing
started a gallery did the whole glass
show with Slinger and all the glass
blowers back in the day like we did the
regenerate and the degenerate art shows
I opened a raw food living Source Cafe
that was a hundred percent organic vegan
and macrobiotic everything was grown
within 100 miles of the cafe and it was
just the most magical place I had the
inhalation station of vaporization with
12 different vaporizers on my table and
I was vaporizing people with like all
sorts of like different herbs all
different sorts of terpene profiles and
then if you were the reason I opened it
I wasn't selling any weed but at that
point Canada had a medical you know
cannabis you could get a license
medically to to have cannabis and I
thought well
you can't ask people about their health
that's illegal like it's not my job so
people wanted to come in and use the
vaporizers and put their Herb in and I
just I'd also want to give a shout out
to Hillary black who prior to that in 97
opened up you know through inspiration
of California the Corrals Todd McCormick
all these people that she had spent time
with down there she came up uh she came
back to Vancouver in 97 and she opened
the BC Compassion Club and it's wild to
think that that was really the one of
the major catalysts that led us to our
conversations tonight which are just so
like
so different from the birth of what was
created and it was you know it wasn't
just Hillary it was like just like in
California it was the gay community who
brought this forward you know they they
backed cannabis in a way that no other
person who lived in the sort of Joe
stratey mainstream world would do and so
these two dudes kind of hooked up with
Hillary she started the BC Compassion
Club and who she was helping were the
most vulnerable the most ill terminally
ill mentally ill like every type of
illness you can have homeless living on
the street really the most vulnerable
people that was that was who cannabis
chose to help first
because really there was so much
propaganda against it it was still very
much like ooh like this is drugs so it
was like well let's just help the you
know the people who literally had the
least and who had the most to lose in a
sense because they just already had
nothing and to watch how the be how
cannabis for me it was very profound
because I was a broker in the city at
the time selling a ton of cannabis you
know in a penthouse apartment just
flipping mad pounds to everyone and with
the Compassion Club I was like ooh I
can't make any profit off of this I have
to actually lose money and just give the
Cannabis Compassion Club cannabis and
just be like here's some pounds like I
don't want to make money off this and it
was the first time in my life I was ever
exposed to like making friends with
people who would then die like weeks
later or a month later or a day later
like there was if you were around in
those days and I'm sure it was no
different in California
they were dying every day so this Core
group of people that were helping people
were also dealing with this super heavy
emotion of of death and that was the
birth of what has led us now to talk
about data points and marketing and
compliance and qas and making me mix my
bubble hash and it is just so
so trippy you know I'm not necessarily
against it but it is a very strange
pathway that that would lead us to to
here you know the irony of how it began
like I I I knew the story of San
Francisco cannabis but before Dennis
perone died and I I met Dennis and knew
him but before he died
he has his get-together as a house and
you had to have 30 years in the hustle
right so only 30-year Hustlers could go
to the event and so me and a couple of
my partners go down and hang with Dennis
before he dies and and my buddies got to
hang out with the other architects of
prop 215.
and it was really about
this honesty of we noticed that our
friends who were dying of AIDS could eat
if they smoked and so we started the
first Compassion Club
and it turned into a five-story monster
and if you poor and needy you got free
weed
and so when I got into medical cannabis
and and Dennis was a giant Dope Dealer
like people I don't people have any idea
that fucking Dennis Barone was a giant
Dope Dealer he was out of control for
years I mean they shot him and tried to
kill him they really really didn't like
Dennis perone but but inside that little
motherfucker was the heart of a tiger
and he just would not break and he was
surrounded by brilliant people as well
and as a group they drove it forward and
so when I really got into medical
cannabis
it was it was the inspiration for those
people that I was like wow man if Dennis
perone can do this that means it can be
done
like he proved it that you can be cool
you can you can take care of people who
are ill and you just have to make sure
that you are making enough money
successfully to sustain it and you have
you have the ability to do this and
that's what we did and so you know we we
did we did an ungodly amount of if it
was a CBD product for years you didn't
pay for it so anything to do with with
with we were the ones that were
releasing all the CBD genes into the
system but anything to do with medical
cannabis if you came to me and you had
your wife was dying you would die and
you were sick we subsidized you
and we tried to like hold your hand till
you died and it was so emotionally
intense because we realized the met I
had never been ill so I hadn't been
through the hospital yet I didn't know
what it was like to be in the medical
system
I didn't understand that for us to reach
out and be friendly and and kind and
supportive was that emotionally heavy
and you're watching people break down
and you don't realize they're breaking
down because they haven't been treated
nicely
and it was and and it was Heavy because
I didn't come from a compassionate
background and I come right out of the
street and so for me to run the program
was insane because I wasn't trying to
make money I I was already I already had
made money I didn't get into medical
cannabis to make cash I got in because I
wanted a different direction and so for
me it was odd to see everybody trying to
like beat the captive audience to death
and I was just like holy shit
wow I said I'm the most moral person in
the room and I'm by far the most
Criminal and it tripped me out it was
something I just it was so eye-opening
that we were more moral
in that regard and I was just like whoa
I've broken every rule but this one I'm
not and so I'm about you on that when
the the gay community AIDS created a
problem that was not dealt with
correctly and internally they discovered
a product that would help
and how many times has that occurred
through history but we just lost the
history
so what other Myriad of problems have
been solved by this that we just don't
know
yeah Josh was just mentioning that yeah
Wham the Legends Legends Legends of
compassion
I think that we're really hitting the
nail on the head it's starting to get
laid too but I'm really hitting the nail
on the head that I think what has
happened is that we've taken the
compassion out of the Legacy Market by
forcing the Legacy Market into a
non-compassionate industry which I like
to call an outdistry so we are we we're
in it because of compassion
and now if it's not going to be
compassionate then I'm not in I'm not
interested like it's not interesting
anymore me anymore I'm moving to
psychedelics because at least I can find
a place of compassion there because I've
always grown my plants I've always grown
my community I've helped out in my
community I've brought medicine we were
the medicine makers before you know
anybody understood it and they're still
catching up to us in the pharmaceutical
Market
so
we did it because and we still do it
because of the compassion but if they're
going to force us and take the
compassion out of it it's just not as
interesting anymore so yeah if we bring
it back to the compassion I mean that's
really what we're all talking about here
and I loved it that it's basically like
where we came back to is like oh it's
just compassion versus the industry it's
the outestry versus the freaking Legacy
Market but what it is is the heart and
soul versus the money man
and there's just simply gonna always be
people that are more interested in the
heart and soul of the beginning of any
industry and that's the reason why it
becomes an industry is because it
started with heart and soul and that's
the reason why it was successful
so you know hey cannabis is one of the
most adaptogen plants adaptogenic plants
in the world that we know of on this
planet and us as cultivators of it
know that if we are to survive and if we
are to continue to bring plant medicine
forward then we need to follow her
guidance of be adaptable
very well put Kelly
the only thing I think about in all that
is like yes like I was there for a lot
of that in the 90s and it was so
powerful and it was like you know how
could you make How Could You profit off
of those people like how could you
profit off patients that are so hurting
it's just but yet how can you sustain it
well I sustained it through flipping mad
pounds and then donating the excess like
I go by 100 pounds and every pound would
be like 500 grams and I'd be like take
out make those 454s add it all up and
then go give that to The Compassion Club
but it was like I needed both systems to
to philanthropize to the other side and
then the other thing I think about is
yes like some people are going to stay
there my what's driving me isn't like
profit margins and all of this I know
how important it is to make these
products available to everyone because
otherwise they're drinking alcohol and
they're they're they're literally
consuming things that are bringing down
their vibrations which is it's really
making the world a worse place and if we
can just slowly make like psychedelics
available to people and can't like with
cannabis
he's leading the way you know
psychedelics are going to be in stores
soon enough you know Dana Larson what
he's got a the Peyote store or the the
coca leaf store in Vancouver he's
selling psilocybin capsules he's just
like yeah I did whatever like I'm doing
it again I did it with weed I'll do it
with this and once they you know allow
this there's people that always need to
push that envelope because Civil
Disobedience no matter what you think is
what led us here I always remind the
corporate kind of people like listen
like it's if we stop pushing the
envelope now we'll be complacent and
we'll deteriorate we'll collapse we have
to always push the envelope and the
envelope is pushing the rules they're
putting the boundaries that they're
setting for us we need to keep pushing
them right where we are right now
because we have moved forward the bottom
line is
you know my buddy Ron who I just visited
my mentor my dear friend Ron you know
took me under his wing when I was 17
taught me how to grow weed showed me
more weed than I'd ever seen in my life
he served 11 years in the Stony Mountain
Penitentiary for being a habitual
florist 11 years with child murders and
rapists and like the most dangerous
people that you could imagine and that's
really at least here in Canada for now
not happening anymore you know we don't
get guns put in our faces anymore
because we have a backyard full of
plants like so that to me it's it's it's
getting better and I want to see how
much better we can make it by pushing
the boundaries within this within the
system I don't care if we collapse it
and push the boundaries to the point we
need to get back to some Civil
Disobedience though
word and continuing with the uh being
able to make products like it's fun to
make products and it's it's compounding
products that that really is what we
need right now so like being able to to
compound products I think is a beautiful
future coming that way I got a shout out
to my mom uh we're at a pot conference
and they're they're down on alcohol
how's that Mom
I I my mom threw me out of the house
when I was 16. I was next door doing a
bong hit with my next door neighbor and
I looked out the window it was dusk
about you know night and I saw my mom's
face in the window I'll never forget it
and after that I I said quick I got to
go home when I went home my stuff was
right on the porch man I was out well at
that time how old are you
so you so you were I'm 56 but you were
you're from that you're from the
absolute peak of this shit's heroin when
my my family was organized crime right
I was considered the worst criminal in
the house and I got relatives doing 200
years in prison and I was the criminal
because it because oh my God drugs weed
because weed was worse than heroin and
and I trip out that uh because the
propaganda was so unbelievable
and now here we are now and so I agree
with you Marcus that I we we're making
these changes and we still you know in
the U.S they're still stuck in people in
The Joint left and right so we're not
we're not doing the job we're supposed
to it's a lot of rhetoric but what
you're seeing is people becoming
cannabis
aficionados cannabis um just not just
consumers but also
culturally aware and the more the the
the public becomes sensitized the harder
it is to screw people
because they're your jury
and so you have to be able to allow this
to take place but you know I mean
I've just been waiting my whole life and
so I just figure well I'm not gonna
someone said like they go what are you
gonna do next and I said there is no
next this is what I do
and I'm gonna do this till I'm dead and
so because of that I know that the
timeline is forever and so I just need
to make sure that I make good good
movement and that I see long term and
then I try to build value and I try to
drag as many people forward with me as I
can because it's hard to party alone and
have a good time
uh in Canada the laws are like still
transforming you know like everywhere
and um it's important for us to continue
to learn it's cool to hear about New
York and all the vaping lounges it's
like you can smoke anywhere in New York
City now like that's crazy that's so fun
so what we're all talking about is
happening over there Maine you know
there's some really amazing patient care
uh available in Maine and a lot of our
Farmers that we work with in Maine have
a really amazing system
a lot of good stuff in Michigan you know
incredible Farmers incredible genetics
going on uh you know the compost camps
they're definitely feeling like the
floods uh and all that but you know just
big love to those families uh you know
trying to make it go in Oklahoma that
whole scene they're going down next yeah
yeah Michigan just hit the ground yeah
Oklahoma's hitting the ground next right
yeah yeah my buddy my buddy's telling me
we're in the next humble then he hits me
up the next day and he goes man Hale
took my whole crop and I said you're not
the next humble
it's going to be all right
how did Oklahoma go from giving Will
Foster 96 years in prison for growing
some plants in his basement to just
literally letting everyone grow weed
cash grab 2500 2500 for the license it's
a cash grab and it's mind-bending
well you got people in prison watching
this occur and you you're and I'm I'm
I'm expunged but I'm a multi-time felon
I collected a whole slew of the fucking
charges over the years right and so they
only come up when the federal database
pulls me and so I so I have to I had to
write this letter of Contrition for my
license and I had to say
I apologize for the crime I committed so
that I can commit the crime legally
today and that's what I wrote as my
statement I said this work and they were
like well I guess it's contrite but I
was just like this is great
yes and so you know I have all the
expungement so I come up as a clean
individual but the bottom line is
what allowed that to happen was was the
money I made in the hustle because most
most the people didn't have that lawyer
power where I had a lawyer Entertainer
for like 25 years
so like when you're hanging out with
your tourney all the time you have a
different life
and most people don't have that ability
and so for me I'm like I I
I feel fortunate not smart
and the number of my friends at the time
in the joint and then like my family did
time all of a weed I'm like we're still
not done but we're moving forward but
this shit that shit I can handle you
slowing my business down I can't handle
you fucking people and put them in the
joint like if there was a choice between
the two you can you can you can make my
business life harder versus put someone
in prison because once you in prison
you're in a different fucking world
and the average individual growing weed
does not belong in prison
time you if you're not a certain type of
dude you have a bad time well I was
facing 25 years and I remember the judge
asking my lawyer how would be November
22nd be for the next uh date and John
conradly he's like oh no your honor that
that date won't work for me leans over
to my ear and he goes cause I'll be at
the Cannabis Cup in Amsterdam with my
clients like in court he says this and
I'm like holy fuck I'm just like this is
my first time getting busted I'm kind of
like okay like yeah that's true we are
going to the Cannabis Cup together
fuck so it's it is important to be good
friends with you Laura and have the
right lawyer and have the right lawyer
and yeah well you do have to have a
couple but you have to have one key
lawyer and and then what happens is he
becomes kind of like you consularity and
through him he finds your other lawyers
you don't look for lawyers your lawyer
looks for lawyers and you say look I got
a problem let's put a team together your
lawyer puts the team together because
the one thing you know is that attorney
you've chosen who's worked with you is
about you and you know that when they
get in court they're fucking ferocious
so like I may have lost that case but
the ass beating they were given the drug
task force in front of me where he the
judge said I don't understand the line
of questioning my attorney said oh it's
easy I don't think this cop's smart
enough to actually fucking hold a job as
a cop so we're going to go at that first
and I was like oh this is great I was
watching him just smack the shit out of
these guys and I said if I lose it was
worth it holy Christ this is what it's
like to have some murder attorneys on
the screen holy shit well how about my
attorney who worked with my prosecutor
for 25 years and then they prosecutor
came to my attorney in the middle of my
case that I'm facing 25 years for and
it's the one of the first Compassion
Club cases in Canada so Hillary black
and the whole Compassion Club crew
they're in the court case uh in the room
the prosecutor in the hallway asks he
says hey did you hear about our good
buddy he's a judge they've worked with
him for 25 years as well he's got
prostate cancer he's in uh he's in the
hospital do you think your client could
get him a bag of weed so now my
prosecutor is trafficking in cannabis in
the hallway while Prosecuting me for
cannabis
I was just like holy shit
I did get him a bag of weed
oh yeah we're holding them but hold on
awake but no that's it's a funny shit
but it's true it's the and but the issue
is you know that the the legal system I
don't care what country you're in is
expensive and the average individual
can't really fight a case they have to
they have to take a public defender and
cop a plea
and they don't people don't understand
that you know your provided attorney the
attorney's job isn't to defend you it's
to come and play and so you end up
having to settle these pieces and so
most people just don't have the legal
power and I mean I just seen it when I
was like that's why I left Rhode Island
really was that I was visiting my cousin
in the joint he's doing 200 years in
prison all my friends about to about
spend their lives in prison and I'm
sitting there going man there's no
future we're all going to we're going to
the Joint you're carrying a bag of grass
in your pocket you go into prison at the
time right and we're all we're all in
crime pot so like we're definitely going
down for time and I was like
this is this isn't this isn't there's
nothing here and it had become it was 83
so the drug law was in full effect and
they were just sweeping people up so me
and Dale garringer from normal were
hanging out and we were talking about
timelines he said Woo 83 was aggressive
and I said everywhere and he goes oh
yeah that was the year where they went
off and that's where I got smashed
but
you you
can't live a life where every moment the
penalty is is death
it's too it's just too much and and so I
said look I'm gonna get out of here for
a minute and then as when I was gone I
spent I spent an afternoon with a global
level drug trafficker and he he helped
me understand that cannabis was my life
and was my future and I said wow that's
that's heavy and I got when I got out of
the military I went right back into the
game and never left
because he helped me understand that
that was a time period and that the
evolution of cannabis was about to begin
he said that we're about to go through
his radical Global change and I was like
wow I'm gonna I'm gonna ride that change
because being a nurb is where I had my
my best time it was where I felt uh most
comfortable you know consuming cannabis
being around cannabis people cannabis
cultivation like that was me and when I
put it down you put down a piece of
yourself but I just I everyone around me
was going to prison and I already been
incarcerated so I was just like this
isn't fucking life no but what it did
here in Canada was it made cannabis very
valuable because we would get caught
with it and really you'd have to have
hundreds of pounds to go to prison so it
was suddenly like pounds were like so
and I don't know about 83 what pounds
we're selling for but like by 93 it's
like 5500 to 7 000 US dollars in
Manhattan for a pound of good weed and
you could buy it you could buy it in in
in well but like by the 100 pack you
could buy it by uh um in Vancouver for
like 2400 Canadian to like on a high-end
3200 Canadian which at the time was like
1.48 exchange so it was like you're
paying like with your American dollars
you're like I think I just paid like
1300 US dollars for this pound and now
this pound is worth like six or seven
thousand US Dollars and I'm moving 200
at a time or a thousand at a time like
it just became such a crazy place where
it was like the wild wild west but you
also had all these amazing people coming
up who you'd become friends with but
then you'd never see them again because
they got pulled over in Spokane or they
went down to Alabama or they like went
somewhere where it was like 10 20 30
years like
was just a crazy thing that you're
killing us you guys were killing us in
California oh I'm sure all the guys that
were flying in all the guys that were
flying in to grab herb from us we had we
had become entitled and and and the the
BC group was putting out better products
and for cheaper prices so I think at the
time you know you could get a unit for
like 2600 and in Humble you know it was
like 4 400. yeah so because I can't
whenever somebody came to Canada as soon
as I spoke they knew I wasn't Canadian
and the first words out of the cab
driver's mouth were you looking for
units like a Pax and I was like wow I
said I'm California they got fuck you
got weed and then and then we would just
hang out oh yeah but the
that that that quality that was moving
out of Canada was pretty good and the
price point was phenomenal and if it
wasn't for 9 11 and perp California
would have got buried that it saved Our
Lives you were killing us and you were
actually nicer and more friendly to deal
with so all the guys I knew that did big
big plane work but they had their own
planes
they were just like and we all got along
but they were like God dealing with you
fuckers out there sucks he goes the
Canadians are so nice
and and the herb is cheaper
waging yeah you're rivers of it
I can see the mountains here
I'm looking here and I'm like wow you
you could have went off plenty of water
no enforcement holy shit yeah you don't
have the helicopter see we had the
helicopters but the same thing I didn't
mind them because even when I got busted
and they they took me for 900 pounds one
year
um
that 900 pounds I lost means someone
else made 900 pounds more money and the
years that you got fucked I got paid
it's it's a game so I never tripped on
the helicopters you need you need the
difficulty to make the mission correct
if there's no difficulty Everybody Plays
well and and the people who play in the
game so like that world required a
certain type of person
and at that time that's what I was into
well I'll tell you the beasters because
you mentioned it I'll say you know that
was uh that was not created by a
Canadian the original beasters were
American buyers that would come up buy
massive amounts of weed and then sifted
they'd sift all the sift off the weed
and then they'd send the weed to these
different North Carolina like down in
Kentucky like all these different places
and you know it wasn't the only part
there was also really breeder Steve
turning on the Vietnamese to growing
cannabis giving them grapefruit cultivar
that was on and don't get me wrong when
they first start I'll never forget it
because I met these guys they were like
hardcore gangster dudes and they they
were just like man this is so good we
don't need to have guns I don't need to
have bodyguards this is amazing business
you know but what happened was
they pumped out amazing products for
about two years and then it was like
yeah we don't need to go eight weeks or
nine weeks uh we don't need to really
dry it properly yeah and it just went
downhill because people were coming up
to buy it you didn't have to do that
anymore and they just they were more
like in the business of just like
pumping Out product but the first
product those guys pumped out I was
beyond impressed I was like wow like
how could you it was a cultural thing
because it was like Caucasian people
were just fucking each other over and
fucking it up and the way he put it to
me my buddy was like Vietnam's small bro
like if I have to go back there and I
fuck someone here in Canada like I am
bumping into them you know so they were
able to work together in a way that like
put out really once they got the
cultivars and Steve definitely hooked
them up with the cultivars they were
able to put out really nice cannabis and
it just it must have seemed like a
miracle to them from coming from like a
really gangsterism selling heroin
selling cocaine to just leaving that
behind and getting into this herb game
because there was that much money in the
Arab game you guys are still violent
though I had a buddy that got killed by
the Canadians oh yeah like you guys
still had you had the the it was biker
gang shit doing the trafficking and they
owed my pot in the money and instead of
paying my buddy they just they came down
to Santa Rosa and they fucking murdered
them at his house over the debt right
and and I was like college in Upstate
New York during that time yeah
a lot of weed it was really cheap when
it was four thousand dollars for
anything anything you give anything and
you could get it for 1300 us that drove
a pretty big market for a long time that
was coming over uh Native lands it was
all over the borders yeah they're just
uh thousands of pounds a day that whole
Mohawk thing that happened if you
remember the Mohawk thing that was like
uh hey look over here right they had the
guns and the masks and they were
supposedly protecting a field that field
was nothing it was all like it was like
giving a crop up to move ten thousand
crops over the Border you know every
single day they were moving thousands of
pounds and you could never feed enough
into America
there was just really even just New York
just New York and so what happens now
when New York the Northeast the largest
market in the world let's say actually
gets out of its Cowboy stage and
produces enough cannabis legally
that they'll never have to have imported
cannabis ever again oh well I I will say
one thing about that and I think he will
as well terroir
right that's it terroir that's a cracked
thing you can't get Jamaican you can't
know but you can't
there were grapes when when the Vikings
landed in the new world and I don't hear
I I've never had a wine from Pei but I
could tell you there are some fantastic
wine regions in BC there's some
fantastic wine regions in France so I
think you're going to end up seeing is
cultivars being developed for
locally adapted for this environment
that can fit within that climactic
standards and you know here here in the
Kootenays that's probably going to be
shorter season plants but there's going
to be some you know the high variety of
pine terpenoids within within the
environment and likely within the
compost is probably going to contribute
to uh Pine and other similar terpenoids
being slightly higher within the
cultivars and so we can compare it to
micro breweries let's say 100 there's a
lot of people that drink Budweiser
same thing with cannabis there's going
there's going to be those people don't
drink microbrews also yeah and I think
but you're gonna have to have both 100 I
don't think you can rest in business on
just one or the other quite yet having
both of them I mean my goal was always
to put out the best all the time and say
at the highest level possible but I
realized at one point that it wasn't
just the highest level of The
Connoisseur it was the highest level of
every grade that you can go after so if
you have to put out a lower grade
because it is what it is
match the price point and put out the
highest possible grade you can faster
that price point I just know I've
traveled all over the world and made
hash all over the world and probably 26
27 countries and I have my favorites and
there are different profiles that are
created in those different countries
that I've never tasted or experienced
and I can't even put it into language
really that just the overall feeling
that you can get from Cannabis that's
been expressed from a different terroir
you know and so that like to me where I
really want to see this go is like I'd
love to be able to see all of these
different Terror I mean of course the
old you know Afghanistan and Lebanon and
all these different house producing
countries but for all we know there's
house producing countries that we've
never heard of that will you know like
in Jamaica a perfect example is oh in
the Westmoreland they grow the best weed
it's like no they don't that's just
where it was the furthest away from the
fucking Army in the police force of
Kingston it's the furthest point of the
island that's that's why they went there
not for the soil or for whatever else so
but what happens when we really start
going to places for the terroir to find
these different Expressions that aren't
necessarily based on uh how much can I
get and how fast can I get it so when I
went to Barcelona when we did you know
if you've ever been to span Abyss that's
kind of like the New Amsterdam and we
were getting
um
hash from Morocco you know and they were
saying oh this is how they get it here
they like ski do it over and we're
smoking hashimaka it's called Blue Dream
and it's called OG Kush and it's called
and I'm like wait a second so we can't
get the original uh genetics or the land
race you guys have been growing for
centuries anymore because all of the
people the children have gotten hip to
the game and they've come and gotten
genetics from Amsterdam or Barcelona
America and are growing them there and
we're losing that traditional hash that
truly is Afghanistan
and maybe there'll be a difference in
how you know we can see it grown
differently and the different
expressions from this cultivars that
we're using today but I think it's a
tragedy that we're going to lose in
Jamaica they didn't have Lamb's problem
right there none of the Ross's had last
breath they had Sour Diesel and because
it's such a small island or they don't
pull their males
that was the the end up talk was that we
don't have that anymore we don't have it
in a pure form it doesn't exist because
we ruined that because of our geography
and we tried to take what we saw in the
world and bring it to our world and now
you know the chase is uh land races but
we're losing we are losing stuff but
like I just got brought into this
project in Morocco
and it's it's to develop appellations of
origin for the farm so they can start to
identify you know the impacts of the
region and it's also to sequence the
genetics and get the fucking Dutch and
American genes out of the pool because
it's killing the farmers because none of
that shit is developed for drought and
so when the agronomists come over from
these countries they're telling them you
need more water to use it they'll be
great and they're trying to tell them we
don't have any more water we only have
this much water and it's like nobody's
kind of cognizant of this limitation and
they're trying to say well then you're
not going to be able to produce cannabis
and they said we've been producing it
for 3 000 fucking years so I don't think
we need the advice and what they
realized is that what they need is
people to come in and so the Moroccan
government got a hold of an Israeli
group that's connected the DD Mary so
they have someone who's a brilliant
cannabinoid scientist to be able to
really do deep dives into profiles and
then we have the sequence in groups and
I got brought in to help them kind of
work with the farmers and start to
develop these this project
but the it's the irony of it is is that
they got infiltrated with American and
Dutch genes and then they're failing
because plants that were produced in
rockwool don't really give you water
conservation
you know what I mean like you're you're
not starving the plant off and so you're
giving it optimal conditions and you're
dialing in your dry vacs and all your
fucking Squirts and the problem is it
got optimal moisture the entire time and
it is not possible and what we see too
is that the European market is far more
driven towards what we would call
traditional Moroccan hash to go along
with tobacco and that the desire for the
American Products isn't there the
Europeans aren't Desiring our products
as much as they want the traditional
products but they want them standardized
stabilized and delivered freely like you
know frequently able to be accessed
easily like it's been for centuries in
Europe
and so you're kind of seeing the change
and it's it's like when I was in I was
in Columbia same thing I went there to
work on a project and they people knew I
was coming into Colombia and so all
these Old Farmers out of Cali had come
down and picked me up and we went and
hung out in Bogota and they were the
preservationists of the old Colombian
lines and they said our families have
held this for hundreds of years so we
have like 50 different varieties that
we've held in form for a long time and
what we're trying to do is bring these
forward in breeding projects and and
further them into the normal world
because they understand that the the
historical value so it's the same thing
you you go to you go to a I was telling
somebody I said you go to you go to
Thailand and I said you get a bag of
fucking runs you're going to be upset
and and they're like no no I said trust
me on this one a tourist doesn't want
runts in Thailand they want runts in
fucking Florida because that's an indoor
flower you know you make it anyway
but with with what we're talking about
is very specific stuff and so
New York blowing up everyone's going to
have their own internal Market but you
would still want to import some killer
seasonal from Humboldt County you would
still want to import some killer
seasonal from you'd still want to import
some phenomenal herb from Colombia you'd
still want to touch Jamaica you still
want to touch all these countries that
produce phenomenal herb
and maybe not replace your crop it's not
a competitor but there's no way New York
can produce those products and there's
no fucking way they're going to do it
indoor you're not going to do equatorial
shooting how long is that how long does
that take for us to get to that point
what's happening right now do you think
it's oh my guarant fucking see it we're
trying to negot like in in
I just know that all these countries
that are opening up I'm brought into the
conversations about sourcing product and
so legal countries to Legal countries
it's happening so for the U.S we're
fucked for a minute because we're not
doing we're not opening the borders at
all and the problem with the U.S so I
said two years ago I figured five years
so I figured five years because I
figured that the administration that I
was in in America didn't give a fuck
about us and I figured the Dems probably
don't give a fuck about us either but
maybe at the next election they'd be so
desperate that they'll have to legalize
and so legalization is just a tool it's
it's not about fairness or parody it's
straight up a political tool to use to
get votes
and so until they have the need there's
no need to do so and so for us in the
U.S we're just hoping that we can go
state to state which is difficult
because if you if you if it's contiguous
we can do a compact but if we have to
fly through the air over a state that is
not part of the compact that goes on the
federal so it creates this situation
that's that's tough but globally we're
not the only producers so I don't I
don't see cannabis from a U.S
perspective only because I'm touching
cannabis in other countries and so what
I know is any country that's legal can
import so when we couldn't get enough
Urban Israel from the production we've
got it imported from Portugal
so people in Portugal are selling herb I
just think I think this is a really
interesting conversation too and while
it's like my favorite part of it I'm
gonna cut it short because we've been
here for a while and feeling a little
bit hungry I've been going going for a
while
um but what I but what I did want to say
is that what we do is we continue to
talk about culture we're talking about
the Cannabis culture and now we're
expanding the word culture to different
areas which we call terroir and when we
talk about secondary metabolites and we
talk about terpene profiles we talk
about different cannabinoid profiles
we're talking about the culture of the
plant and that culture of the plant can
only come from different areas in
different zones and I just think it's
really interesting that that term
culture continues to come back we are
always honoring the culture of us in the
industry and Us in different cultures
but how awesome for us to be able to
honor all of the different cultures that
cannabis comes from as well because
that's the true you know culture and
when we talk about cannabis culture
that's really what we're talking about
not just our association as human beings
with it
and I just wanted to thank you all so
much it's been a really wonderful
evening so I'm just gonna kick out this
has been just so stimulating and I
wanted to thank the Unicorn cup it's
been so amazing and uh London thank you
so much for having
me
okay awesome thanks so much
Justin Kelly from dragonfly love you
guys have a good night pick up unicorn
come
uh hi I'm Bubba what was the route last
part no no I'm joking
I need more mushrooms I'm Marcus aka the
bubble man and uh yeah thank you so much
for uh future cannabis project and
London and the che and the whole Rosebud
crew and the Unicorn cup and uh all of
the people that are sitting here and
just uh what a lovely evening fireside
chat
foreign
yeah thanks
uh I'm Pamela West uh also very much
thank you for the culture that's being
created this weekend that's what we need
more than anything else it's been sucked
out from like from the uh
thank you
I'm Jamison Wellborn from the Banyan
Tree thank you so much Ted London future
Canada's project the Unicorn cop
everyone here this was awesome and uh we
need more of this so if you're watching
this go out and and set something up
like this and you're a community we need
more
my name is Noel Lisi and I'm with
nectar's Collective I'd like to say so
much thanks to the Unicorn cup for
putting an event together that we can
all sit and uh be with one another and
have a fireside chat
Uh Kevin jodry Korea Hustler
I just want to say thank you so much for
for allowing me to be part of the event
it's it's it's a pretty special one here
and
FCP and London covering us salute so
thank you so much
uh Mike on
um
check check got Christian Clapton uh
from Rosebud and custom cannabis yeah
thanks uh thanks to Che and crew they've
done a hell of a job again here this
year and super proud of everything
they've done they're uh they're a good
group and it's pleasure to meet all you
here today thank you
I'm Shannon Ross with antidote here in
the Kootenays and uh just thank you
everybody for being here it's nice to
see everybody and and share stories and
uh
and
yeah thanks
Ron Harrington Wildwood cannabis
Consulting it's thanks to everybody it's
good meeting some new people here and
it's great to see all the smiling faces
and and what uh kind and honest human
beings are are in this group I
some good people
[Music]
Liz Blaze thank you unicorn cup gonna go
eat and get high
your name
I just wanted to say um shout out to all
the people in Northern California and
Southern Oregon with the fires dealing
with fires right now talking about their
you know protecting their homes and
everything big protection to all those
ganja farmers down there
[Music]
what's up everybody
foreign
[Music]