we talk a lot about you know sun-grown
versus indoor in terms of different
types of policies but I think we also
need to start talking about rural versus
urban and there's a whole set of
barriers for rural cannabis businesses
that urban cannabis businesses do not
have to deal with but yeah we are put up
against the same processes so things
like having things affixed to the ground
or having a DEA accessibility if you
have employees or having separate areas
for everything or having you know a
paved road to and from your facility if
you have employees there's a day every
day of the week exactly so I think we
can start thinking about that and maybe
next legislative session we need to come
with a bill that is specifically
addressing issues for rural cannabis
businesses and not just farmers just you
know manufacturers and retail and
anybody that has to exist in a rural
area where you don't have good internet
right and you and your micro businesses
can't all be on the same premise and no
one else does it that way and the
wineries grow grapes here and make wine
here and have a tasting room here and so
why are we being subject to a very urban
centered policy structure it's just not
fair to the people that are the legacy
producers in this industry was there any
kind of shift in the requirement for the
micro business and everything needed to
be at the same no there wasn't a shift
in that there was a shift in the number
of pricing tiers for almost all of the
licenses within the BCC everything from
testing labs to self distribution micro
businesses and also cannabis event
organizers I thought that was pretty
fascinating but a couple of things that
I thought like speaking of rural farmers
I think about seasonal farmers right
we're in an urban area you are more
likely to have electricity or resources
available right that flat area that
allows you to maybe cultivate year-round
or develop in that manner row farmers
often have it
in that manner and so they're not those
kind of cultivators we still don't have
the ability to utilize light deprivation
in the outdoor tier and it seems like
that didn't happen either and it seems
like there's some concern about whether
or not if you're in a structure say like
a hoop house or a green house but you
don't use DEP tarps and you don't use
lighting it looks like you might get
forced into the ml1 tier in that
structure but then I also there was a
series of recent inspections and what
we've been told is if you are licensed
under the mix light one tear and you
have say I don't know nine thousand
square feet in white def hoops but a
thousand square feet of it is open air
for your 10,000 square feet of canopy
but those need to be two separate
licenses you can't cultivate your full
term outdoor crop under your ml1 license
and bundle those together I think that's
going to have exponential impact for
separate premises and separate
operations and separate license fees and
separate surety bonds scuffling that
came up and we were talking to the Board
of Supervisors in Mendocino and they
were not aware at all that you could not
be outdoor and have one license if you
for pulling a tarp or having a hoop
house people thought that they can have
10,000 square feet as long as you said
if you were mixed light that included
outdoor or mix light and you can
there one license right yeah challenging
what are we gonna do guess where you
have to go smoke pot
[Music]