[Music]
always an honor and a privilege to be
here with congressman Dana Rohrabacher
all right Dana why don't you tell us a
little bit about what you've been doing
to support the industry over the years
and what your outlook is for the future
I am an optimist because we started just
10 years ago remember we didn't have the
Rohrabacher Farr amendment and now it's
Rohrbacher bloom an hour we didn't have
that and our government was able to run
roughshod over anything what local
people wanted to do when it came to
cannabis well now with robach afar and
we've managed to get a majority vote on
this twice now through the United States
Congress and it is currently law you
can't have the DEA coming in when it
comes to medical marijuana and
superseding the state law so that people
are dealing with medical marijuana at
least that part of it is are safe from
being arrested by the federal
authorities and having all of their
property confiscated now at least we
have that kind of protection and in the
future I think in the next election
cycle I think we're going to come to a
tipping point this is this is a turning
point on this issue and we will see that
not just the Department of Justice but
all the departments and agencies of the
federal government we'll leave it up to
the states because President Trump has
made that promise love him or hate him
he keeps his promises and that's to
legalize
medical marijuana and personal use by
leaving that up to the states as our
biggest champion on the Republican
caucus just looking at worst-case
scenario if you don't win your
re-election in November what are the
prospects for the for the Rohrbacher
protections well the first thing that
will happen if I lose the election is
I'm going to go surfing and drink
tequila for at least three or four
months anyway so however I I'm in a
really tough race I do believe I'll be
on top when it comes because I'm I
believe in freedom and I think my
constituents believe in freedom and
however if I do lose
there'll be it'll be a lot tougher in
Congress because they have grown used to
someone who's acceptable to the
conservative Republicans mobilizing
those votes and we need those votes to
accomplish our goal which is to get the
federal government out of this issue and
leave it to the states and local
government so it'll be a lot harder if
I'm not around but I am predicting that
I will win and I'm predicting that once
that happens
president Trump will then he will keep
his word he will support legislation
that leaves this issue up to the states
they did he made that pledge during the
campaign love him or hate him he keeps
his word about trying to initiate what
what he promised he'd do so I'm
optimistic that should I be elected and
I think I can be and will be that we
will be able to have some great steps
forward and there'll be no cup of going
back after this next congressional
all right and what about you know this
is an America first administration and I
think that you know I think that we both
agree that that part of the America
first policy should also be putting
America's cannabis industry first and
you know we we recently just just
acquired cannabis for research from
Canada of course Canada legalized
marijuana last week and III you know
have some concerns that you know we're
falling behind in the global market what
do you think that this administration is
going to do to help you know make the
make America's cannabis industry great
again how about making how about making
America's farmers great again by letting
them grow cannabis that's exactly right
the fact is that cannabis will be not it
will will affect American agriculture in
so many ways that people don't even know
now first of all cannabis isn't just for
smoking cannabis is also for paper for
cloth cannabis can be used for so many
things and our farmers which now we end
up having to pay not to grow certain
crops they will be able to grow cannabis
for rope why should we buy hemp for rope
from anybody else in the world we've
been giving over a billion and a half
dollars to Canada every year so we can
buy hemp from them how ridiculous is
that our farmers should be getting that
money and also there's something else
that will happen and I believe the
cannabis industry will be
revolutionising agriculture in the sense
that they are now turning old buildings
into into manufacturing facilities for
food and they we could see cannabis they
put all of the scientific knowledge and
engineering to grow cannabis plants
inside these old warehouses what they're
learning from that will be put to use
across the board to help me grow
vegetables and other
so the cannabis industry is not only
going to be revolutionized in what it
can do and when just cannabis but also
for the other crops that they are
teaching they are now revolutionizing
the production of other crops in America
that's absolutely right it's a little
personal question here is I know you've
been you're back to surfing which is
excellent and I think I think that you
also the only member of Congress who has
come out as a consumer of cannabis or
through topical non psychoactive topical
applications is there any connection
there well I will have to tell you I had
both of these shoulders replaced because
thirty years of heavy surfing and I
surfed all the Cartledge away and I
couldn't even move these arms and so it
was so painful and I was speaking to
work somebody had cannabis they said
well what you need to do is rub some of
this cannabis salve on it well it was in
fact I can't tell you whether or not the
cannabis was what it was but I can tell
you right now after shoulder
replacements there it is I can both arms
now these are all metal now and if I'm
going to be a surfer again I'm going to
keep these arms operating and I bet
you're not the only member of Congress
that uses medical cannabis or cannabis
Oh have you heard have you heard
anything down there in the gym or in the
the Congressional locker room about
other members of Congress I know that
there are people who have had suffering
just like anyplace else
older people have things that they
suffer under and I know there are some
people everywhere who are utilizing
cannabis to take care of their maladies
I have put cannabis salve on my arms
when I had horrible pain because all the
cartilage had been worn away because I'm
a surfer and I was suffering with this
horrible pain
yeah I put cannabis salve on it I
actually admitted that before a group of
people and it sort of made national news
but but again what's wrong with that
what is wrong with anybody putting a
salve with it's based on cannabis on
their arm to alleviate their pain I got
no problems with it many men
it's absolutely legal here in California
yes now that Canada has legalized
cannabis nationally in your view has the
federal government or Congress are they
taking any lessons from that that might
be applied toward legalizing here in the
United States well it's important of
course for our farmers to be able to
compete with these farmers up in Canada
who are now producing what is a cash
crop and hey I want those billions of
dollars to come here I love the
Canadians but I want that money here to
our own farmers but however there's
another lesson when it come when you
come to other countries by outline
cannabis here we have financed the drug
cartels in Mexico the people who are
growing cannabis in Mexico are not like
the folks up in Canada these are people
who are gangsters just like we had to
deal with gangsters when we had
prohibition of alcohol we need to make
sure that we legalize cannabis here and
make sure honest businesspeople and
honest farmers are engaged in this new
enterprise rather than depending on the
what the drug cartels of Mexico and
we're financing those drug cartels we
could correct that it'll help Mexico
it'll help us I think that the industry
is not
mobilizing people to go see their
personal congressman instead they've
made a much broader effort to try to if
that Congress as a whole and by going
and doing the work necessary to find out
whose constituents who are the
constituents of those people standing in
the way I think we could have been a lot
more effective on that who are the
veterans from so-and-so's district who
are the people who who have children our
seniors our senior citizens groups from
a person from one specific congressman's
district who is a no vote now so we need
to do that and I would hope that the
industry is gonna be much more
grassroots I don't that's the word
grassroots when it comes to getting this
job done yeah I couldn't agree more I
mean I I told people in the industry
that every day that just having the
conversations with elected officials at
all levels not not just Congress even at
the City Council and state state state
house makes such a difference and it's
so important that the industry to also
understand that we haven't won this yet
you know we're still it's not time to
sit back and rest on our laurels there's
still a lot of work to do and you gotta
win it one elected official at a time
not as a whole there you go
[Music]