[Music]
we're going to invite Kevin de Leon up
to join us yes and we work his campaign
alright give it up for Kevin de Leon you
guys well very quickly let me introduce
myself to each and every one of you for
those who don't know me now I thank you
very much for allowing me to share a few
words with all of you here today an
incredible night here in Bennett's
California my name is Kevin de Leon and
I'm running to become your next US
Senator for the great state of
California and I believe strongly that
these are very dangerous consequential
times in our nation's history that we're
in fact engaged in the battle for the
soul for this nation against a president
without one now the issue of cannabis
and why this is so important and why we
should have a voice in Washington DC is
because the current incumbent that I'm
running it against doesn't even support
the use of cannabis for medicinal uses
now think about this wherever your
perspective may be on the issue of
cannabis and I know where all of your
perspectives are on cannabis but society
as a whole now if you don't support at
minimum the use of cannabis for
medicinal purposes when we have
scientific empirical evidence with
regards to people who have AIDS people
who have Alzheimers a Parkinson's some
form of cancer breast cancer ovarian
cancer whatever type of cancer whatever
variation to help alleviate pain
suffering if you don't support that with
scientific evidence then I don't believe
you should be a voice of a state like
California that is diverse like no other
state in the entire world
so I am a supporter of the medicinal use
of cannabis as well as the recreational
use of cannabis and we have an
incredible opportunity to make sure that
cannabis industry becomes a strong green
pillar of our economy today we're the
fifth largest economy in the world and
to put this in context there are only
four economies larger than that of ours
the United States of America as a whole
China Japan Germany then your great
state our great state the state of
California and if you're remotely
interested in rounding up the top ten
that number six is United Kingdom seven
it is France then we have Italy India
and that number 10 it is Vladimir
Putin's Russia so to put this in context
California's GDP is larger than that of
Vladimir Putin's Russia and I am a
strong proponent of clean energy I am
the author of the most far-reaching
climate change policy in the United
States America 100% clean energy
California is the largest economy in the
world to legally mandate 100% clean
energy by the year 2045 I'm a strong
supporter of clean energy because we
have an incredible opportunity to
convert these environmental challenges
into real economic opportunities
especially giving those at the lowest
economic strata those men and women of
color real opportunities to succeed in a
clean energy space energy efficiency
renewable energy wind solar another
clean energy technologies Huell that
will be invented in the future
transportation electrification Zeb's
zero emissions vehicles so a green
economy is our future but a green
economy what cannabis is our future -
and these are two twin pillars that can
really drive California's economy well
into the future that's why having a
voice in Washington DC and being a
leader nationwide for cannabis is
absolutely important now when we pass
medicinal use of cannabis we thought
that that would open up the doors but it
really didn't because of all the
litigation because local governments
because of cultural prejudices with
regards to cannabis but that's why we
have a Department of Justice that's hast
to the legal establishment of cannabis
not just in California but throughout
the country that's why we need a voice
in Washington DC that's gonna dese
Ketchel D scheduled cannabis because to
put cannabis on the same level of heroin
and cocaine is ludicrous and we have
seen the consequences of so many men and
women but particularly men and men of
color that have been incarcerated
because of this scheduling and we've
seen the devastation we've seen our
taxpayer dollars blow up budgets to
incarcerate so many individuals and
that's why we need a strong voice in
Washington DC that will fight the
Department of Justice the will fight the
prejudices that exist in the Congress
today we export 75% of cannabis to other
parts of the country so California will
be and can be and should be and will be
that economy for the entire nation
that's why I just want to thank you very
much for giving me an opportunity to
share a few words with with all of you
here today I want to say that we have a
real opportunity to grow this industry
but you need champions we're going to be
there with you
so can I thank you for being a champion
for our cause and and you know you
definitely have our votes I voted for
you I'm so excited that you're here
right now you know and we are we're in
the midst of a tsunami of regulations
that just changed on us at the moment
and we've been witnessing extinction
events with our our licensed operators
since January 1st we've been watching
extinction events with legacy operators
that were not able to get permits still
haven't been able to get permits and now
with the regulations continuing to cause
whiplash we're and we're in a we're in
an awkward state right now where we're
not sure which way we're going and and
even my the smartest people in the
industry can't figure it we can't come
to a consensus on what just changed
therefore we can't come to a consensus
on what solutions we need to employ what
to do yeah right and so really where
we're at is we're having a tremendously
challenging time regulating an
unregulated market and competing with an
unregulated market and what it seems
like California did was they took models
from other states and tried to you know
copy/paste this section over here and
we'll do it like Colorado did it over
there recall Rob they did not take it to
account that we had a thriving black
market that produced 12 and a half
million pounds of cannabis prior to
legalization going into effect and so I
mean really like the number one issue
that we're discovering right now that is
blowing all of my smartest friends away
is that we have an inversion problem
everyone was so worried about a
diversion problem we have a significant
inversion problem because there's so
many legacy operators that can't get
oppor they get get permits and then you
know we wanted to be able to talk to you
about you know these challenges that
we're facing at the moment we have we
have eleven days right now left of a 15
day public comment period there were we
can't get consensus with the smartest
people on you know so take over Pamela
the consensus is difficult because the
issues of fact operators at different a
pivot points right there's different
pressure points if you are a retailer
and you have multiple operations or if
you're vertically integrated or if
you're a tech platform what does a non
cannabis plant touching business look
like I think that those are the the real
quintessential issues and what does it
mean to be an owner what does it mean to
be a financial interest holder and as we
chart through these issues that we'll
talk about I think knowing as somebody
who is hopefully going to be
representing California's interest at
the federal level a lot of these issues
splinter down into how do we get access
to banking how do we go about forging a
path of uncertainty
through these regulations and I know
that if 280 for example weren't an issue
some of these other licensing white
labeling structuring issues would also
then evaporate so I think it's
interesting for us to start that
dialogue is what is the federal effect
of the state let me just add one thing
because you said something that was
really critical with the issue of
banking and how many folks put their
live set at a risk you know with so much
cash and we had the banking system here
that won't is prohibited legally
obviously from accepting legally gotten
gains by our retailers just this Monday
I did a press conference with the
president of the City Council Los
Angeles Herb Wesson with regards to the
establishment of a public bank and what
it reasons is because the federal
regulations won't allow cannabis to be
part of officially the banking system
that's why at the federal level I want
to be your voice to push this and I
think that there's a lot of cultural
prejudices obviously that primi eight
Washington DC on the issue of cannabis
we're so innovative we're so creative
we're disruptive of a state we just
don't push the envelope we in fact we
tear the animals apart and that's why
California is always so ahead of the
curve in many ways and that's why in
Washington DC it's always been archaic
it's just been behind the times and
that's why we have to have a voice in
Washington DC because what premie Eights
Washington you see all these cultural
prejudices that
remember the movie the old movie reefer
madness you know people truly think that
in Washington DC with regards to reefer
madness you know and that's so behind
the times and compares to what it's
happening bless you but that's what
makes California such an incredible
place and on the banking issue is what I
want to work on as well too because that
will help legitimize if you will you
know and
cash flow price points with regards to
getting access to capital which right
now is very very complex if not almost
impossible right now so that's just a
little you know with regards to the
banking issue so something that I love
seen and individuals lives because I'm
all about self enrichment is seeing
people that have a full circle moment
I've actually had a very much a full
circle moment tonight as about two and a
half three years ago I was in Washington
DC at our capital lobbying for cannabis
rights and I actually spoke with our
California senators office at the time
that you're running against and the
chief of staff and the assistant chief
of staff were very non-responsive or or
combative with the group from Americans
for safe access and at the end of it I
told the chief of staff I look forward
to the day that I get to vote for the
person that will be replacing you
because this is California and we
support cannabis here and if our
representatives don't stand behind what
we believe in then it is time for you to
go so I am personally very honored
tonight to be sitting next to you this
is someone have a guitar for me right
now
exile will play you saw impose gives me
guitar right now yeah what they were job
no no Joe no Joe Rogan's moments right
now you know for yeah we saw what
happened long that stock went down real
fast you know I thought it'd go up
actually you know but let me say this
again thank you very much for BA to my
heart for forgiving me a few moments and
I'm sorry that if I disrupted a little
bit but my campaign is a disruptive
campaign and listen if I would never
have been a state senator know what I
have ever been the leader the president
of our California State Senate if I had
listened to folks say no when it is your
time and know your place in many ways
we're all disruptive and that's who we
are because that's that creative spirit
that's restless and precisely what you
said is it this is about values and it's
our values and that's why it's time that
we export California values to
Washington not the other way round and
we don't have to accept the status quo
the naysayers it's always we can't do
this we can't do that well we can't deal
with the issue banking because it
doesn't a lot the law doesn't allow you
know for banking for the cannabis
industry well why not let's change that
and let's disrupt the status quo that's
how you make laws and that's how you
make change in this country and that's
why we're the fifth largest economy in
the world and that's why we need to deal
with the issue of this cannabis industry
and make it a very legitimate industry
like clean energy like any other
industry you guys are on the cusp you
are in the vanguard you are the
progressive wing of this new industry
that is a legitimate industry and will
be sooner or later recognized by the
federal authorities but in order for
that to happen you have to be involved
in politics because if you're not
involved in politics politics is gonna
get involved with you whether you like
it or not in this case politics is
getting a ball with you and you're not
liking it so what you're gonna do you're
gonna cross your arms
and say well that's the way it is well
no you're gonna fight for what you
believe is right that's who we are as
Californians and that's why I'm asking
you come November 6 less than two weeks
from now don't forget to vote tell your
friends your neighbors your loved ones
your co-workers your workers for the
next 2 minutes I want you to listen to
the 3 other people on stage with you
and I want each of you to give Kevin one
thing cannabis-related that if he wins
you would like him to think about as he
settles into Washington if you choose
banking I'm choosing law enforcement
which one you going I only get one I
want I want retraining for law
enforcement they don't know what they
don't know the difference between a
licensed operator and an unlicensed one
and we're having a really hard time even
calling them for support when a licensed
operator is getting robbed for them to
care and then I care about our licensed
weed they're not going to go find it
this is happening in a lot of
jurisdictions at the moment so that's
sort of you know but if we had banking
the that that's my number one thing but
I'm pretty sure that Pamela was gonna go
with that one yeah we banking retraining
for law enforcement and and to that note
though as a person who fights for people
dealing with disabilities as I was an
individual on disability myself for
several years while I went back to
college due to my epilepsy is police
force it's not just cannabis it's every
area that you're an outlier that if
you're outside of the norm they need
training but I'm not gonna take that one
what I'm going to take is maybe a little
bit grander is that I would love to see
cannabis part of a universal health care
system and not owned primarily or only
by the pharmaceutical industry hi wait a
second
I had debilitating migraines so much so
that they wanted to put me out on
disability and I'm an attorney you don't
hire an attorney who has a cognitive
deficit for migraines and I was able to
get a standing prescription of 60 to 90
opioids in a month and then I had to
leave California to go to my family in
Arizona and luckily cannabis was there
for me and that's why I have a career
they started advocating for you know the
single most important person in your
life is you right you are irreplaceable
to yourself and so I had to start
advocating for myself and through the
advocacy of myself I was advocating for
those that were providing clean medicine
so to echo Brett's statement we need to
see reform for cannabis such that it's
not thirty two thousand dollars a year
to be a patient to get epidemics that's
just it's unfathomable and you don't get
insurance you don't get medical reform
without insurance reform and we haven't
seen that and cannabis can be such a
good conduit I like to think of it as
the mirror that we can look at how we
deal with so many other issues and treat
so many other drugs that could be if
used and dispelled with this nefarious
brush better than their opioid
counterparts that are only there because
the pharmaceutical companies are pushing
them don't take away the small business
that California is built on in cannabis
and replace it with the pharmaceutical
companies by blanketing reform that
allows for them to de schedule instead
of the schedule without a plan so thank
you very much this is wonderful employed
I appreciate very much the input that
I've received it's important that all
elected officials all policymakers
listen to all the perspectives you know
I'd be remiss if I don't also introduce
quickly a California State Legislature
as well Assemblywoman Wendy Carillo
who's always been a strong supporter of
cannabis industry and and Wendy can you
show your face so folks can see you
that's Wendy cutter you everybody newly
elected assembly woman she's a strong
strong fierce independent woman a strong
support of the cannabis industry she has
an incredible future she's in the
beginning stages of being your
Assemblywoman representing parts of East
LA and El Sereno an eco-park and Silver
Lake and look a lot you know to her for
leadership not just on this issue but on
many other issues of getting it's windy
country over there today with us and
thanks a lot for coming out to to Venice
today at the last second and then let's
get out there let's let's win let's show
the rest of the country and show the
rest of the world how it's done great
state but that thing about you I thank
you
[Applause]
[Music]