[Music]
you have a history in vape cartridges
yes from your days slinging nicotine so
now you're slinging weeds so that's true
so talk about kind of the evolution and
what you've seen and then maybe some of
the toxicity issues we were hearing
about now yeah so I mean as far as
toxicity goes with a lot of the vape
hardware that's available in the THC
space what a lot of the consumers don't
understand is that each of the products
aren't made equally so it ultimately
comes down to the original source of the
raw material so the same with steel the
brass the ceramic there's a you know
there's there's a good and bad for
everything you know you can buy cheap
metal where you can buy expensive metal
the biggest thing is you know all flour
and extraction processes are different
across the board you know you have guys
using butane you have you guys using dry
ice
you guys have using co2 and that all
reacts differently with different metals
so the biggest thing is when you do send
a cartridge to get tested for have heavy
metals and it comes back as a fail what
ends up happening is the oil is etching
away at the metal inside it's yeah it's
pretty much leaching into the oil and
this is when it comes bus or even when
it's just sitting there even when it's
just sitting there there you know the
whole combustion process isn't as
important there is there is a metal
there is metal wire in there and
you know that most folks don't look into
that but you know we can either be a
source of Kanthal stainless steel
there's nickel so they all serve its
purpose you know and that's just a
heating element of it the ceramic itself
most people have this thought of oh the
ceramic heats up well there needs to be
two wires that run into that ceramic to
give you a positive and a negative to
get an actual electric current in there
but back to the heavy metals you know
like I was saying even when the oil sits
there it will etch away and leach from
that metal so if you are using a lower
quality metal or you're sourcing lower
quality cartridge you can't always trust
that there's a you know that that
product is going to be heavy metal
passing so it really comes down to the
raw materials used and also to the
quality control at the factory level so
a lot of our products are thoroughly
washed rinsed and there's a whole
cleansing process for the raw material
that we use before they actually get
sent to the assembly line and broken
down into the appropriate pieces for
assembly
so I mean the thing is a lot of this
technology stems from the Electronic
Cigarette world and a lot of where the
industry may move forward will kind of
follow suit of how things were in that
industry you know five ten cartridges
are a technology of the past in the
electronic cigarette industry world but
they've been repurposed for a reason you
know better ceramics are used for
thicker distillate and thinner CBD
so when it comes down to ceramic you can
also purchase a cheaper ceramic so you
can have a really coarse compacted
ceramic where if you were to break a
cartridge apart and open the coil you
can actually run your fingers through
that ceramic and it will kind of break
apart like sand then you have a solid
ceramic ware ceramic clarified yeah that
first scenario isn't good but it does
it's not what you're looking for but it
can work
you know if ever if all the other
material source is of quality it will
work extremely well but if you are using
more traditional well traditional in the
sense of this industry would be a more
ceramic core solid ceramic or you know
ceramic is porous in itself so that's
what actually pulls in the actual dis
lit or oil and then in turn the positive
and negative wire that's running through
that ceramic is what's vaporizing the
THC other than that I mean you know that
I crusher we really emphasize on quality
control I mean we are working with some
of the top industry leaders in this
space when it comes to pod systems or
cartridges that I can't exactly give you
know
our customers are industry leaders and
while our clients are industry leaders
and they've kind of set a precedence of
what it is to move forward in the
industry you know they're they're making
sure their chain supply is up to par
that we can get them product and quality
product at the same time you know it's I
can tell you that in the Southern
California region we probably have a
good ninety percent of what is out there
available to the general consumer right
now we are providing that hardware
specifically to those brands that you
know the general question let me ask
this we're being secretive about who
they are but I mean your stuffs pretty
apparent so like if I went into a
dispensary you could pick out your whoa
not necessarily because I mean in China
everyone we know the Chinese
manufacturing side of things you know
when it comes to shoes or purses there's
a bunch of factories that make the same
thing so it's hard to make something
that isn't going to get copied okay so
you you've innovated on the design but
then a month later or six months later
you see a bunch of identical looking you
know cheaper quality material yep yeah
and I mean it ultimately comes down to
the brands you know if they want to work
with a cheaper supplier that's fully up
to them just the general consumer
doesn't realize that they're not getting
the products not getting tested you know
you don't know if it's pesticide free
and you don't know if it's heavy metal
passing so that's the biggest thing is
for us you can we publicly we publicly
have everything on our website that lab
tested for every single one of our
products for our heavy metals you know
we are the provider of hardware
and you know what everyone else provides
is what they put into that and sell it
off to the rest of the market well so
let let's talk about kind of concentrate
and obviously there's been lots of
innovative new types of concentrates on
the market so in terms of like can you
talk about different concentrates and
maybe like their characteristics like
maybe they have different viscosities
and like how that affects and interplays
with you know which types of what type
of hardware technology is required of
course
so the general consumer right now has
this perception of clear is better
clearer is cleaner and that's not the
truth and that is honestly not the truth
you know if you were to leave a cup of
water outside during the day that air is
gonna bring so much stuff into that
water it's not going to be clear the
entire time it will turn yellow
it will turn Maui general consumers
don't realize that that once air and
heat is introduced into oil it will
oxidize that oil will oxidize and it's
not necessarily a bad thing think of it
as a tea bag when you get a fresh tea
bag and you put it into a cup of water a
cup of hot water it's pretty clear and
you see the color change but if you
leave that tea bag in that hot cup of
water that tea bag starts to kind of
deteriorate the flowers deteriorate a
little bit more your tea starts to get
darker it's the same thing with oil
sometimes time gives it a little bit
better flavor so the general consumer
doesn't realize that when it comes to
viscosity and finding the correct device
for our clients that's all that's
totally up to them you know distillate
usually comes out extremely thick live
resin is you know extremely extremely
thick you you know it's almost a solid
at that
and that's where terpenes come into play
you know terpenes will break that down a
little bit give you a little bit more
flavor and you know that will change
there's gossiped e of the oil itself so
not all oil is made in tools not all oil
is meant to be clear and that's
something that most folks need to
realize is if you are using a lot of
terpenes to create a flavor profile for
your biomass you might have a looser
liquid than a looser oil I'm sorry a
looser oil rather than a thicker oil me
personally
I personally enjoy the two-two-one CBD
THC ratio just a little bit more mellow
bhai rather than something that's gonna
really get me you know couch-potato
mode and then is there a specific like
is it live resin two to one is it's it's
mainly distillate two to one two to one
with CBD you know anything with a twenty
five anything with a 60% CBD to you know
like a twenty percent thirty percent THC
is personally what I like I can say I do
enjoy this dizzy mango quite a bit I do
enjoy that quiter
and all your products showcased out here
which one would you smoke that out of
well unfortunately Susie doesn't provide
that in a syringe maybe that's an idea
for them to give to you know
dispensaries that might buy hardware for
the general consumers to fill their own
but me personally right now I am using
the Zen which is our newest device great
thing is it utilizes USB see charging
rather than the old micro USB that
everyone still uses so you know you're
not going to go having to look for
another wire because most folks have
either Apple or Android phone charger
and that plugs straight into this a
great thing is you have three settings
for it so you have a low medium and high
so if you are running a thicker oil in
the pod you know you can warm that up a
little bit more it's in the pod right
now right now this is a CBD this is just
plain CBD isolate with are you filling
it yourself is I filled this one up
myself yes okay but but is that let like
because I'm looking at that it's like a
fax looking platform but is is this a
disposable cartridge difficult
cartridges are usually one time usage so
you have your own proprietary platforms
that is standard know so it's all
proprietary you know each of our pods
are made to a certain spec there are a
few brands that we work with that you
know have really taken over that space
in a couple of states right now I know
Florida Michigan and Southern California
have the V fire and there's couple
brands that have really made that
specific device their own not this
specific device this one's the Zen B
fire is a little bit bigger of a device
yes this is I pressure the V fire is the
I crusher model and then there's a
couple there's a couple brands that
rebrand you know we don't I can't
disclose that information unfortunately
yeah wait we're talking I guess my
confusion is I'm seeing devices that
look like this that look well maybe not
this one but that that one specifically
looks like a brand would let me see the
pot itself so brands are ordering
thousands of these filling them you're
putting them in dispensaries on shelves
and it only works with your device yes
okay but the brands are also purchasing
the device and rebranding the pot is
there okay yes but point being they're
standardizing on your proprietary
technology platform which I find
interesting so because I know
so basically packs does that them guys
do that busy does that because what
historically I'm getting at is you know
common thread sizes right like what five
ten right so that that is thanks to the
electronic cigarette industry that
thread has become the standard and
that's because the electronic cigarette
industry there are a lot of smokers in
that industry there's a lot of people
that medicate and use recreational so a
lot of those guys can walk into any
dispensary and buy a 5-10 cartridge and
not be persuaded to buy a stick battery
you know they have ten lying around the
house yeah they have ten lying around
the house they got one of those really
big ones I'd blow clouds you know and
the thing is they can turn the power
down on those to work correctly four or
five ten cartridge okay so as a supplier
would you guys rather not like is this
kind of like an old technology
no it's been it's been repurposed and
it's been reworked to work better with
cannabis viscosity is the viscosity is
much thicker and the thing is you can't
pump more power into the cartridge if
you do that you end up in turn burning
the THC molecules and completely whoa at
that point what is the purpose of it you
know I mean so you know for this is my
one advice that most consumers is you've
seen guys with electronic cigarettes
blown clouds clouds does not make the
cartridge any better it doesn't make
your distillate any better you know at
the end of the day the general consumer
knows that there's one reason why
they're doing this they're trying to get
their high they're trying to lower their
anxiety you know or even for metal
report medical purposes that are trying
to prevent a seizure you know but cloud
production is not a huge factor I think
perception wise so what you're saying is
if you blow and you don't see anything
you're still getting you're still
getting something now because I was
dealing with that actually with the
ghost babe where I kept sucking and
blowing and being like I don't see any
vapor but then I was like but I'm super
high yeah exactly
everyone's different everyone's lung
capacity is different do I mean I mean I
can get a pretty big cloud from this if
I really drew on it you know so
right that that's you know what I mean
but um I'm sitting there and I really
have to toke that in you know I mean
that's not the case for everyone so
getting back to kind of the proprietary
pod and battery kind of compatibility
right because like your pod won't work
with a packs battery and vice versa
what are you kind of seeing in that game
I mean do you find it interesting that
there are all these companies coming out
with proprietary connections yeah it's
you know it's uh it's their one way of
cornering a certain market you know in
the packs don't get me wrong works well
but the fact that not every consumer can
pay $60 for a battery not every consumer
can pay $60 for a pod half gram at that
point not every consumer can do that
we're working with some companies that
yes they're using one of our designs as
a proprietary system and you know
they're able to sell to consumers at $40
for a full gram and the battery will
last them for two days you know and
that's a big thing that's a big thing
you know tax has a market focus that
they're targeting they have an idea
they're executing it extremely well she
is doing the exact same thing so you
know we're just offering that solution
for brands like them or anyone that
aspires to be someone like that can
brands go on both platforms where do you
do is there like you got a sign with us
or with them
I don't know the specific details of
that but from what I understand you know
there are a few brands that do have two
different devices for two different
purposes from different manufacturers
okay so you talked about how this is
still relevant technology wise but like
what's the improvement that this has
over kind of the traditional legacy so I
mean with this one are five ten
cartridges specifically you know with
five ten cartridges they're great but
most consumers aren't very careful with
a lot of their things you know with the
traditional pens you know sometimes you
put it in your back pocket you will sit
on it and it will snap you know we've
all seen it happen you drop it the glass
will break you lose your pressure you
lose your precious biomass you know with
the batteries and the pods you know the
pods are made out of PT EGC plastic so
it is a medical grade plastic so you
know if you are dropping this on the
floor the battery is gonna protect their
pot and in all reality if you drop your
pod it's not going to break on you and
shatter on you but but from a smoking
standpoint like is this one capable of
handling more variability in viscosity
than yeah minor like it definitely is
I've had clients of mine send videos of
them putting live resin into some of our
pods you know they're still working on
their aged it is not encouraged it is
not encouraged do experiment at your own
risk that's what I tell my clients but
you know that's where we see a lot of
the trend moving toward right now is
live resin but they're cutting the live
resin right now there are you know with
a lot of terpenes to get different
flavors and then you have your consumers
that want that true taste
some live resin right in front of you I
would definitely have to say the guy
that I'm using right now this has been
holding up pretty well but every mix
will be different one of our clients has
put live resin in this specific pod and
he has mixed it with different you know
liquidiser so either MCT Hunnicutt or
even terpenes i would assume if you're
doing live resin the last thing you want
to do is make sure that see sometimes
just a little bit goes a long way you
know I mean and everyone experiments on
a different level I mean how did we get
live resin it was out of a crazy idea
that he had to put it in dry ice right
and now look at where we're at with it
you know it's I mean how did electronic
cigarettes come to be you know
traditional analog cigarettes have been
around for so long and it's the same
thing with hand rolling it's been around
for so long it's been a standard for so
long it took one person to say hey I
want to play Breaking Bad and I want to
try something crazy and now we have
distillate now we have live resin you
know it just takes one crazy experiment
to do and that one person can lead the
entire industry space into a completely
different direction yeah I mean who
would have thought 10 15 years ago that
we're gonna be at an event where we can
openly smoke and not be looked at in a
certain manner