we're gonna head bring the hearing to
order
welcome to the joint legislative hearing
of the assembly committees on government
organization business and professions
and health to provide an overview of
vaping tobacco and cannabis products
health effects and deficiencies in
regulation and current law I'd like to
begin by welcoming the committee members
and thanking them for being here our
witnesses and certainly the general
public for your attendance today I'd
like to thank the staff from the
respective committees for putting
together an in-depth agenda on this
important and timely topic this joint
informational hearing will be the first
of two hearings on the subject of e
cigarettes and vaping today's hearing
will provide an overview of the issues
related to vaping including the health
effects and regulatory landscape with
testimony provided by medical
professionals tobacco and vaping experts
and state government regulators the
hearing will also look into the growing
popularity of e-cigarettes and vaping
examine the overall impact on youth and
general consumers ecig arete sand vaping
devices with seven billion dollars in
annual sales have become part of a daily
life for millions of Americans vaping
has risen dramatically in popularity
around the world from 7 million users in
2011 to over 35 million users today as
this happens traditional tobacco smoking
rates continue to decline however recent
studies have found that more than half
of American adult East cigarette users
are under 35 years of age fueling
concern about the popularity of vaping
among young people youth access and uses
skyrocketed with the preparation of
flavors attractive to the teenager such
as Bazooka Joe bubblegum cotton candy
and gummy bears federal statistics show
a significant increase in vaping among
teens between 2017 and 2018 more than
one in four high school students
reported vaping in the past month up
from one in five students in 2018 Issa
Viet use among middle students has also
middle-school students has also
increased federal health officials are
calling this troubling trend an epidemic
and fear that teenagers who vape
we'll eventually start smoking but now
as a legislature we're not only faced
with the issues of rapid rise and teen
the e-cigarette use but a national
outbreak of mysterious lung injury cases
associated with the use of vaping
products the CDC now reports seven
thirteen hundred vaping illnesses in at
least 26 nationwide linked to the use of
e-cigarettes and vaping there were no
more than 200 new cases reported just
last week and the CDC told Congress this
morning that these statistics are
unfortunately expected to increase
considerably in the near future
the median age of deceased patients was
49 years old the range was from 17 to 75
years old according to recent findings
by the CDC most of the patients impacted
by these illnesses reported using THC
containing products suggesting THC
products are playing a role in these
illnesses that said some patients have
reported using both THC products and
nicotine products as well as a smaller
number reported using only nicotine
products similar testing on the samples
collected or received by the FDA shows a
variety of products or product
components with different ingredients or
delivery systems making this
investigation especially challenging
authorities are still gathering
information but according to recent
reports patients with the conditions
seem to be overwhelmingly male around
70% with 80% of patients under age 35
according to the CDC their investigation
is ongoing and no single brand product
substance or additive has been linked to
all cases while the cause of the
outbreak remains unknown
the CDC warns against the use of any
e-cigarette or any vaping product aside
from the recently illnesses outbreak the
long-term health effects of continued
East cigarette and vaping use remain
unknown as the scientific community
continues to study the health hazards
posed by these technology bottom-line we
still do not have all the answers but as
a legislature we must get a grasp on the
multiple cases surrounding e cigarettes
and vaping we must consider the health
and safety concerns impacts on youth
black market enforcement issues in areas
of an adequate state
regulation and oversight we need to
identify where existing efforts have
failed and discuss expert
recommendations to reverse the deeply
concerning epidemic abuse e-cigarette
use and vaping news impacting children's
and families across California today
will serve as an opportunity to
establish consistent set of facts so
that we're all operating off the same
set of facts and highlight the best
available information we currently have
I would now ask chairman lo for his
opening remarks mr. chair and again
thank you very much to the collective
work of our respective committees and
forming this and putting this together I
know that this is just the beginning of
the conversation that we have to be as
responsive to consumer protection and
the constituencies that we represent
similarly within the respect of business
and professions you hit it on the head
mr. chair but in regards to the state of
California in cannabis and I'm part of
the crisis on vaping is with respect to
the failure of the regulatory system to
which the legal access to quality
regulated cannabis products throughout
the state is relatively limited in fact
as we well know roughly 3/4 of cities
and counties have been licensed cannabis
retailers seating those areas to
unlicensed unregulated untaxed and
untested illicit market operators
similarly we also know that the
identifying root causes and impacts of
these illness will have an impact on
those responsible actors within the
legal and the illicit market and we need
to hold them respectfully to account
that being said we are looking at what
to do to protect individuals in the
marketplace and average Californians it
may also be of consideration that we
explore a moratorium on additives which
appears to reflect industry's best
practices we as a state or a port of
entry for a lot of vaping supplies of
the United States and I know that we
have a particular important role with
respect to the industry as a large state
and the nation's supply chain of the
illicit marketplace in both cannabis and
nicotine vaping products so
I very much look forward to the
testimony from our public
representatives and and look forward to
the continued conversation thank you
very much to the chairs here and I think
chairman gray actually framed this
discussion very very well as a start as
a starting point so I just want to hear
from our experts this afternoon but you
have some comments I think the explosion
in popularity of e-cigarettes here at
ISA current use has been a problem for
some time with staggering numbers of
youth becoming addicted to nicotine in
the last several weeks it's become all
too clear that we have a much bigger
problem on our hands with the outbreak
of lung illness and injuries and death
and the questions around exactly what's
causing this my colleagues and I are
committed to working on all aspects of
this issue as you've heard this hearing
is just a first step
I break this into two different in my
mind the way I look at this and and
there are many aspects of this I am
concerned about one the number of young
people that are starting today period
whether it's nicotine or THC
number two the illness that we're facing
the public health crisis that we're
facing there and so I think as we start
hearing about this I think those are
separate issues in many ways there is
some crossover but that's how my my
weird compartmentalised mind works so
with that I'm happy to introduce our
first panel so I'd ask them to please
come up dr. Eliza Tong and Kimberly Vega
Dorie who will give us an overview of
the vaping and East cigarette industry
and discuss the prevalence of products
use thank you in advance
thank you dear Assembly members my name
is Eliza Tong and I'm speaking today as
a practicing physician and tobacco
research expert for identification
purposes I worked at University of
California Davis today miss Homer vaca
Dori from the California Youth Advocacy
network and I will share some brief
background information about
understanding the new vaping epidemic
for California the word epidemic has
been used for years to describe how
tobacco is the leading preventable cause
of death
now the word epidemic is being used for
vaping with the sharp rise in youth
rates the massive proliferation of
products and shocking new cases of
vaping associated pulmonary injury and
deaths first I'll highlight some key
points for the regulatory and health
landscape next miss homer of agador ii
will highlight the impact on youth and
young adults this is what I call my
greatest hits slides but looking back
lessons from the past about marketing
and science are important for
understanding what is going on today so
in the 50s and 60s when scientific
studies that first started linking
smoking cigarettes to lung cancer
emerged the tobacco company started
running these historic advertorials
called a frank statement to cigarette
smokers to create doubt by disputing the
study findings saying experiments with
mice were not regarded as conclusive for
lung cancer they also ran ads showing
doctors here promoting products they
also say that they believe their
products were not injurious to health
and that they would cooperate for public
health and then growing over time all
the scientific evidence 10 years later
it took the first landmark surgeon
general's report in 1964 to synthesize
all that biological and epidemiological
evidence concluding that smoking does
indeed cause lung cancer subsequently
the US Congress adopted laws for health
warnings on cigarette packages and
advertising bans in the broadcast media
however tobacco control work continues
today as the Centers for Disease Control
States due to the quote the addictive
nature of tobacco and powerful economic
forces promoting its use now in the 70s
80s the next couple decades the industry
started trying to develop and market new
products as less harmful to smokers but
it was actually the evidence that
non-smokers could also be harmed that
had the most impact
some folks in the room may not have been
alive during this time but that
advertisement on the left-hand side with
the disco lady shows that the industry
sold low tar cigarettes mild light ultra
light cigarettes has less harmful
because we knew that tar caused cancer
when it was painted on the backs of mice
maybe this was a way to get less cancer
however these cigarettes were also
machine tested for lower levels of tar
but that's not really what happened when
people actually use these products so it
did not actually reduce the health risks
of smoking and it took us years to
figure that out so in real life smokers
could change the way they smoke because
they were trying to get a lot more
nicotine and they could actually get the
same amount of chemicals or even more
than the machine-based numbers suggested
so as time went on in the mid 1980s the
Surgeon General came out with a report
on the growing again the growing
scientific evidence that secondhand
smoke exposure caused harm to
non-smokers and in fact cause lung
cancer this evidence helped stimulate a
broad array of change from if some of
you in the room may remember no smoking
sections which people jokingly say is
like having a no peeing section in a
pool because it doesn't really work -
now what we have for smoke-free policies
that protect non-smokers so in
California we are very fortunate at 1999
with our first tobacco taxed that we
created a comprehensive tobacco control
program to change social norms around
smoking reduce product availability and
protect public health instead of only
focusing on treating individual smokers
this approach has been widely recognized
internationally as one of the greatest
public health successes to this day now
the 90s to the 2000s were marked by
lawsuits whistleblowers helped bring
internal tobacco industry documents to
light that were previously protected
through attorney-client privilege
these internal document documents were
in stark contrast to the picture in the
upper right where the tobacco industry
CEOs at the time testified in front of
Congress I believe nicotine is not
addictive subsequently the state
attorney general's sued for Medicaid
costs for tobacco related disease
leading to what is called as the master
cell
agreement at the federal level in 2006
the US Department of Justice ruled that
the industry violated the racketeering
and corrupt influence organizations law
concluding that the industry quote
continues to engage in and execute a
50-year scheme to defraud the public on
health effects and marketing to children
and then four years afterwards the
industry argued against federal
penalties and it took over a decade
later in 2017 for them to finally air
quote corrective court-ordered
statements which some of which are seen
on the lower right and so these ran kind
of in late-night TV
black and white there's you can still
see some of them on YouTube however
studies showed that only forty percent
of US adults were actually aware of
these corrective statements but the
range of what they had the state
included acknowledgment that nicotine
was indeed addictive low tar light ultra
light mild and natural cigarettes
actually lacked health benefits and were
deceptively marketed as less harmful
cigarettes for a minute related to
maximize nicotine delivery and that
there is no safe level of exposure to
secondhand smoke so now we come to the
Food and Drug Administration in 2009
they were given authority to regulate
tobacco products and this included the
manufacturer distribution and marketing
of tobacco products so FDA is supposed
to approve that new products are not
worse than cigarettes before they go to
market they're also supposed to approve
any marked products making cessation or
reduced harm claims or go through their
office as well and products like Jill
have not done for example flavors and
cigarettes have already been banned
through this regulation except for
menthol cigarettes due to industry
pressure however this led to the rise of
new products that were not quote
cigarettes some you can see on the far
upper right that did not have to follow
rules made for cigarettes with a brown
paper wrapping you could suddenly have a
cigarette or little cigar and you don't
have to follow the flavor or packaging
rules that were made for cigarettes
electronic cigarettes were on the rise
as well but it took years for the FDA to
finalize what's called the
deeming rule to begin regulation that
was in 2016 and the FDA delayed
implementation of that for until 2022
for manufacturers to submit information
and improve their products but now with
public pressure as you all may well know
this has been moved up to next year this
one's a little bit complicated but let
me walk you through this so throughout
the years California's success story is
that cigarette smoking prevalence rates
have declined faster than the rest of
the country but the news now is that
vaping and marijuana use rates are
rising especially in young adults so
this data focuses on the general adult
population as the summer of agador he's
going to describe youth and young adults
since California has a tobacco 21 law
not to sell to persons under 21 so the
bar chart shows on the far right that in
2017 our California prevalence for any
tobacco use was almost 15% on the far
left you'll see cigarettes that's 10%
and only 3% for vaping that little bar
the second bar from the left
however younger people who are aged 21
to 29 years old they've ate that much
higher rates with 11% in 2017 and 13% in
2018 and users may use or switch across
multiple tobacco products and in the US
over half of e cigarette users are
current smokers marijuana use on the
right in adults especially young people
is also rising with over 1 and for young
adults over 21
similarly Co use of marijuana and
tobacco is rising now with 1 in 8 young
adults over 21
so with this low federal regulatory
landscape for vaping it's difficult to
know what's actually in these cigarette
products and their aerosol at despite
what they're labeled as this is a
graphic from the CDC where they note
that products that are marketed as even
having no nicotine have been found to
contain nicotine so studies to date show
that this aerosol is not water vapor
which is what many people think in the
public instead this aerosol as a
chemical mixture that can contain
propylene glycol volatile organic
compounds carcinogens heavy metals
flavors and ultrafine particles
ultrafine particles for example can are
just some of the substances that can
have immediate harmful effects so all of
us who've experienced the California
smoky fires for example or freeway air
pollution they're those things are the
ultrafine particles are known to cause
inflammation that's important for heart
and lung function in particular even if
some products contain less of these
harmful ingredients the CDC has
underscored this does not mean it is a
safe product there isn't in fact no safe
tobacco product we've already learned
that low tar cigarettes as defined by a
machine doesn't mean it's a safer
product we are still learning how
heating and inhaling chemicals in these
products that affect the human body so
despite having been banned in cigarettes
flavors and their marketing of flavored
tobacco products are concerning for the
rise and use and their harmful health
effects so just a couple examples here
some menthol has been most notably been
targeted towards the african-american
community contributing to tobacco
related health disparities beyond being
just a flavor preference the growing
evidence about menthol is that it's
numbing properties make it easier easier
to initiate and inhale its chemical
properties make it harder to quit
because it's actually working on the
nicotine receptors and and there's an
Associated carcinogen with these oils
and called polygons and there there's a
recent JAMA article that says there are
levels that are higher way higher and
ecig a' Rhett's then actually what's in
regular cigarettes or also fda levels
for food and it's been banned as a food
additive as a synthetic chemical other
flavors that are appealing to children
include fruit candy or sweet flavors
that has been noted but these have
safety standards that are meant for
eating not for inhaling growing evidence
shows that these flavors by themselves
and in combination can harm health such
as with lung function blood vessel cells
and white blood cells which is important
for your immunity diacetyl which is
found in three quarters of liquids is
associated with bronchiolitis obliterans
and irreversible lung disease described
in workers from buttered popcorn factory
factories
so the high potency of nicotine levels
and in marijuana's psychoactive
component THC and these vaping products
is really alarming in fact the Surgeon
General has released warnings to young
adults for both of these components
because the developing brain is
especially vulnerable through age 25
nicotine itself is not harmless with
potential for cardiovascular effects
seizures and even poisonings it's used
in pesticides with vaping new nicotine
salts and liquids have high
bioavailability and are more easily
absorbed with less aerosol than regular
cigarettes and regular cigarettes the
industry had used ammonia to basically
freebase on higher levels of nicotine to
be absorbed in your body
in fact with that diagram on the right
it is from the CDC and it shows one
small jewel pod of ejuice contains at
least as much nicotine as one pack of
cigarettes but again as noted it may be
even higher depending on how you use it
newer products that you have even higher
eliquid concentrations of nicotine maybe
from refillables and as more people vape
marijuana the Surgeon General has put
out a warning that THC concentrations
have increased threefold over the past
couple decades so these health effects
of vaping these high potency nicotine
and marijuana products including in
combination and how heating might be
different than burning this is all
learning for everyone including the
medical profession and this is an
ongoing natural experiment in humans so
as mentioned now this past summer with
the vaping associated pulmonary injury
all this combination of the rise in
vaping nicotine and marijuana has
brought us to this stage so every week
the CDC is reporting more cases so as
mentioned earlier 1,300 cases over a
hundred cases in California 26 deaths
including three in California King
County Tulare County in LA County and
this isn't just a youth problem because
the median age of death is 49 years old
and the range is 17 to 75 and again the
CDC states no single product or
substance has been linked to all cases
although most reported they
teach see it's only about a third
exclusively and well over half reported
vaping nicotine so the CDC has come out
to say to the public people should not
use vaping products with THC consider
that as well for nicotine products also
other recommendations are not to buy
vaping products off the street or modify
or add substances however many people
get their products socially from others
so it's hard to tell
regardless of the investigation the CDC
emphasizes that young people pregnant
women and never should not vape there is
no safe tobacco product use and THC is
associated with a wide range of health
effects especially the users and we're
still learning about that to this day
it's worth noting also that secondhand
smoke exposure and non-smokers has
become an increasingly important issue
so the CDC image on the Left describes
how the Surgeon General has concluded
that aerosol from vaping can contain
harmful substances and use in public
places undermines existing protections
for non users back in 2006 there was a
certain generals report that concluded
there is no risk-free level of exposure
to secondhand smoke and non-users this
is especially important for heart and
lung health and on the right hand side
is an image from California's tobacco
control programs new secondhand dangers
campaign and where they describe over
the past two years secondhand marijuana
exposures increased by 86% secondhand
vape exposures increased by 67% and it's
worth noting also that 30 percent of
California youth in 2018 also report
exposure to secondhand smoke vapor and
marijuana so these smoked in
tobacco-free policies that protect
public health now need to consider
vaping including marijuana so wrapping
up smoking cessation has a strong
evidence base that it works counseling
support and medications can help people
quit for good however it's because of
the highly addictive nature of nicotine
it can take at least eight to twelve
really good attempts for someone to quit
for good and providers are told they
should ask about tobacco use and
exposure advised to quit and advise
about health harms and refer to
counseling support and offer medications
we are still trying to learn what to do
about vaping
it's not even a requirement for us to
ask about vaping but our state quit line
now the California smokers helpline at
UC San Diego they have now stepped up as
our free statewide resource to help not
only help people quit smoking but also
with vaping and this includes for teens
there are seven fda-approved tobacco
cessation aids to assist with nicotine
withdrawal symptoms over two to three
months and most people are familiar with
the nicotine patch lozenge or gum but
there are also other faster-acting
modalities like the nasal spray and
inhaler none of which are meant to go
into your lungs this is like the back of
your throat and cheek absorption and
none of these are meant to be for
long-term either so when the u.s. ecig
arrests are not approved as a smoking
cessation aid as concluded by the US
Preventive Services Task Force which
reviews all the scientific evidence but
now our health systems and providers are
now challenged with figuring out how to
ask advise and treat people who vape and
to help people quit vaping for good so
with that I'll transition to misnomer
Baga Dori thank you so much for the
opportunity to speak today my name is
Kim home Rebecca Dori and I'm with an
organization that works statewide on
tobacco control issues with youth and
young adults and we also work with all
of our colleges and universities in the
state on smoking tobacco-free policy
initiatives today I'm going to highlight
and summarize for you the national and
state data we have on youth and young
adult use I do want to note that this is
tobacco heavy because that's my area of
expertise but it's also what we have a
lot of research on so looking at current
use we know at the national level that
we saw our peak in youth vaping in 2015
and we started to go down in 2016 with a
slight uptick in 2017 much of this is
due to the types of devices that were
available on the market prior to the new
devices that we have we like to say
there were three types of products we
sig likes are the first they look just
like little cigarettes the second are
the vape pens which now we're hearing
from young people are really only being
used as wax pens to be THC solutions and
then the third were the mods and the
tanks and part of the challenges with
these products were they were not very
good at delivering nicotine solution and
so
individuals were not getting satiated
when using them and trying to use them
other than other tobacco products in
2018 that all changed with the
introduction of the new pod based
products there are two things that
change with these products the first was
the size of the device which is very
problematic for young people because
they're easy to hide and because they're
also smaller the batteries are smaller
there's less aerosol that is emitted
from them and so they're very very
difficult to detect the second was the
type of solutions that's in these
products so it's a nicotine salt
solution it's easier to consume and it's
significantly higher and nicotine
solutions than the other products before
these these are the products that young
people have been using and these are the
products that are responsible for this
epidemic that we are now recognizing at
the national level so within a one year
period we saw an increase of one and a
half million students youth students who
increase their use of these products
with vaping and the greatest increase
was seen among high school students
looking at the recent data that was
released from the national government
this is preliminary data and more will
be coming soon but it's showing that we
are continuing to see an increase in
youth vaping of tobacco products and so
in 2018 when the alarms went off we saw
an increase up to almost 21 percent that
has jumped again to nearly twenty eight
percent and this is past 30-day use so
this is not ever used this as regular
30-day use what's also troubling is the
types of products that young people are
using so we know in 2016 there were over
15,000 unique flavors of vaping devices
on the market and we know that young
people were most likely to use candy
flavored or fruit flavored but in 2019
we've seen a jump of young people using
mints and insulated products so we have
a lot to celebrate with our cigarette
smoking we've done some phenomenal work
to get us down to 2% it's a historic low
but that is not the same with all
tobacco products and so specifically
looking in California the data in 2018
which we saw as much as we're dealing
with right now data a year ago can be
archaic when we're dealing with this
problem but what we have is nearly 11
percent of teens reported past
they use vaping devices and you can see
with the yellow in this chart the
majority of the products that are being
used regardless of its vaping or another
tobacco product is a flavor product data
from the California student tobacco
survey also shows that youth use of
marijuana is high so there was not any
significant changes from 2016 to 2018 in
use but it's important to note that
marijuana use among teens is still
higher than tobacco use and also higher
than a cigarette use the survey the
questions that were asked on the survey
asked students who reported vaping what
types of products they vape tin they did
ask if they've eight THC solutions and
21% close to 22 percent of teens did
report vaping THC products in California
now looking at young adults we see a
similar trend and that cigarette smoking
is going down these cigarette use is
going up and marijuana use has gone up
significantly we again have been
successful in trying to reduce
combustible products but the same can't
be said for vaping devices what's
interesting and I've been working with
colleges and universities for over
eighteen years is that for a long time
we've been seeing the use of tobacco use
rates go down with college students so
we can predict that if somebody does not
go to college that their likelihood of
smoking cigarette is higher than
somebody who is in college now that has
been completely reversed by this trend
in vaping and so college students now
have significantly higher rates of
vaping nicotine solutions and vaping
marijuana products than individuals who
do not go to college one challenge with
this specifically too is that our
colleges and universities many in
California which are now smoking
tobacco-free have an influx of students
who are addicted to these products who
are now going to their campuses and our
need of support to help them quit and
they're going to smoke in tobacco-free
campuses but our K through 12 campuses
are smoking tobacco-free and young
people are still using these products so
when we look at literature specific to
why young people use tobacco products
and specifically vape we have evidence
that shows that young people of eight
because it's their norm
so if their friends are using these
products or they have family members who
use them they're more likely to use them
what's interesting is if you talk to a
young person if you talk to college
students to youth their perception of
what the use is is significantly higher
than what it actually is and so that
makes them believe that it's completely
normalized to use these products with
interesting many of the young people
that we work with have not been exposed
to secondhand smoke indoors they've
grown up in a smoke-free California so
the norm of cigarette smoking is not
there but we've completely reversed that
with vaping because young people are
seeing it and they think everybody does
it if you ever talked to a teen and you
ask them do you know people that they
say yes everybody is vaping also with
flavors so flavors was a high indicator
of why people are using these products
to experiment with flavors and when we
asked we do focus groups with young
people and we asked them about the
products that they use and all of the
young people we talked to say they use
products because of the flavors they
taste good and flavors in the vaping
devices but also in combustible products
it masks the harshness of the smoke and
it makes them believe that it's not as
bad we've had unflavored cigarette
products since 2009 with the exception
of mentholated products and so there's a
lot of misperceptions around the harms
of many of these products and a
cigarette czar also included in that
it's important to note as well that when
we did our focus groups with youth while
we talk primarily about tobacco every
conversation we have with the young
person wraps back into marijuana and
while young people have mixed feelings
on the safety of e-cigarettes the
majority of young people we talk to
believe that marijuana was completely
safe so another reason for this is the
access to tobacco products so when jool
started to become popular in 2017-2018
the truth initiative dead national study
specific to individuals who had reported
dual use to find out where they were
getting these products and as you can
see the majority of young people
reported that they were getting them in
the retail environment and getting them
locally and so when we look here in
California our biggest offenders
retailers are selling tobacco products
are actually the tobacco and vape shops
where young people are not allowed in
and yet they are selling at rates higher
than levels of any other retailer so
some of the concerns that we have from
an organization that works with young
people the first is we have extensive
data to show that young people who
experiment with vaping or young people
who do vape are significantly more
likely to become tobacco users use the
combustible products that they have not
been using but will start using or use
marijuana products we also know that the
young people who are vaping today would
not have considered smoking a cigarette
they would not have been at high risk
for tobacco use and now they are because
of their vaping behavior we also know
that a cigarette rates are continuing to
grow and use of combustible cigarettes
is decreasing or staying the same in
some populations it's also important to
know as dr. Tong had said that the the
products that young people are using
today have significantly higher levels
of nicotine than the products of the
past what's hard about these products we
don't know what young people are using
so unlike a cigarette that you would buy
you would smoke it and then it would be
extinguished and would be done these
products are used and students are
sharing them when we talk to teens about
their use and we ask them if they own
the products they say no what happens is
they leave class their friend does a
puff puff and then passes the product to
them and then they puff puff and pass it
back and so they are sharing devices and
sharing different solutions and often
times they have no idea what they're
actually vaping what's also interesting
is in 1998 after the master settlement
agreement was signed we saw a change in
tobacco use behavior among young people
where young people would experiment with
tobacco before the age of 18 and if they
became addicted they would do so in
their young adult years and that has
shifted in my time in tobacco control
this is the first time that we have
young adults or youth that are actually
self identifying as being addicted to
tobacco and seeking help in quitting and
we're trying desperately to figure out
how to get them that help oftentimes
they may not be ready to quit but at
least motivating them for those quit
attempts is critically important because
they are
addicted levels of addiction are very
different as well and again we don't
fully understand how much nicotine
individuals are getting it's based on
the products are using the
bioavailability of those products the
frequency of use and that is still not a
perfect science to understand that so
California communities are responding
this data is already outdated as another
ordinance is passed earlier this week
but as of Friday there were 44 local
jurisdictions that had ordinances that
specifically related to flavored
products it's important to know that
much of this work was started early on
in response to FDA not including menthol
in the ban on cigarettes so much of this
work started to try to eliminate
mentholated products from the market and
has since expanded to include all vaping
products other products such as hookah
the majority of hookah bars in our state
are actually within a mile of a college
and university campus so it's not
surprising that colleges college
students have the highest rates of
hookah use in our state so when we look
at this more and more communities are
starting to amend their tobacco retail
license or adopt ordinances specifically
banning the sale of all flavored tobacco
products although some do have
exemptions we do have now it's four
ordinances but previously three
ordinances that ban the sale of
electronic smoking devices San Francisco
and Richmond have limitations on theirs
if FDA were to approve these products
Livermore's ban as a complete man with
no end date and then of course Beverly
Hills passed an ordinance that bans the
sale of all tobacco products in their
community with the exception of three
cigar bars that were left as an
exemption to allow use and sale within
those bars so in summary we do have an
epidemic we know that we have a history
of working with an industry that has
utilized tactics to try to dissuade the
conversation on Public Health the new
cigarette companies have employed many
of these same strategies and they're
under federal and Gatien into federal
litigation for that right now
there are numerous health concerns with
all of these products as dr. Tong had
mentioned the high potency of these new
pod based products both with nicotine
but also THC is very
worming we see some of the products we
had our team's been doing focus groups
for years and annually we ask them about
the products that they see what products
they use the pens the second-generation
pens that were previously used for
vaping nicotine solutions are now Prima
primarily used by young people as wax
pens and they know exactly where to get
the cartridges and how to get them we
know that youth and young adult vaping
has continued to increase and as new
data from the federal government shows
it is continuing and we know that the
burden of this problem is currently
existing under K through 12 schools in
our colleges and universities where
young people are using these products
and the health systems are also trying
to identify how do we help these people
quit using them but there is a response
from our local communities in California
to respond and there are a number of
individuals throughout the state that
are working to try to reduce these rates
and the support it's a backhoe free
California thank you thank you very much
for your presentation it's both very
informative and pretty alarming quite
frankly I'd like to open this up to the
pen to the members for questions
questions
mr. gray yeah thank you for your
presentation I'm curious about the
attention you went over the local
ordinances at the city and county level
throughout California I noticed every
one of them deals with flavored tobacco
any Secours right yet during your
presentation unless I read that wrong it
occurred to me that the highest use
seems to be marijuana products and we're
vaping amongst teenagers which seems
consistent since the outbreak of this
public health crisis at least with the
illnesses and the reported deaths I've
had numerous conversations with school
officials in my district every one of
them has suggested that the great
majority of products that they
confiscate from young people at the high
schools have marijuana in them and it's
curious that the public policy response
starting with the president all the way
down to the local level is wrong your
presentation is exclusively focused on
e6 when that's not apparently the number
one driver certainly a significant
contributor which also was not in your
presentation why do you think that is so
in California we have our tobacco tax
dollars are used to fund a comprehensive
tobacco control program to address
tobacco control ordinances a similar
program for marijuana does not exist in
the state so you think if a program did
exist that might drive more of these
local ordinances and efforts maybe calls
for the banning of flavored marijuana
for example I can't comment on that
specifically but I can note that
California does have one of the most
successful tobacco control programs in
the world and it's been extraordinarily
successful in reducing tobacco use in
our state as well as changing norms
around tobacco use in the state here say
it seems concerning I ran into several
people vaping in my district over the
past 30 days and took the time to cut
shot with them about what they were
doing and what product they were using
and one of things I found kind of
shocking and and maybe something we
could come to expect given the the
publicity and the press reporting and
some of the information out there is
that they were all under the impression
that marijuana vaping was safe and the
tobacco vaping could kill you I assume
they got that impression from the news
reports and some of the information put
out there by advocacy groups and others
kind of exclusively focused on tobacco
but it seems like a danger when clear
that we don't quite know what's causing
it and and the public health warnings to
not VAE period until we have a better
idea or perhaps you know perhaps we
don't get a better idea people shouldn't
be vaping at all and it's absolutely an
unsafe or critically unsafe product but
it strikes me that that's a dangerous
public health outcome when you have
young people not informed about the real
dangers would you agree correct yes and
and again I'm I'm not in charge of
funding decisions in the state of
California but do you want to note we
have an incredible tobacco control
program who has obviously when we talk
to young people I want to note that even
though we have seen increases in vaping
among young people in California it's
lower than the national level so the
work that's being done to address
tobacco control in this state is done
well and we are our making good
successes but I can't speak to the
marijuana prevention and public health
aspect of that mr. Cooper yes for this
McAdory
hopefully I pronounced your name right
um it's your nonprofit right so you guys
get money and really the big issue is I
agree with what mr. gray said over two
billion dollars in tobacco tax revenue
is bought in by the state and yet less
than 3% is used for enforcement so while
you pat yourself on the back for what
you guys are done it's a different model
now things have changed with the vaping
so a lot of that money not in reading
the information here
some paperwork where most of that money
that goes to the cities and counties
goes for education or training but not
for enforcement and that's really the
big issue with that and this legislature
what do you want to do to deal with this
issue because the black-market they're
in there to make money and make profits
off of their people and that's we'll
talk about later on but we've got to
change that model with this we know
something we're saying this but yet 3%
is insufficient I know the AG allowed
allocated 38 million this year for CD pH
and DLJ but once again you know as far
as its operation shoulder tap operations
that law enforcement does that's not
getting done that much so there are a
whole host of issues with this but I put
the blame on the state for a lot of
these issues that have come up for a
long time for a myriad of issues but but
how do you
I guess rectify that do you think more
money should be given towards
enforcement you're saying the rates are
low but now obviously it's in keeping
with vaping so it might be in on the
enforcement in Morse to be allocated
because obviously this education part is
working like so much and the trainings
are working so much because you can go
to a pot shop without pot shop but a
head shop whatever you want to call it
but the black market is out there so
these kids can go anywhere in the black
market and get it they're gonna sell so
do you favor our support more funding
for the enforcement end so I can't speak
to that and I can't take a position on
it but I can't say that I know the
Department of Justice is here and that
they'll share the work that they've been
doing with the grants that they've been
given out the good thing that's
happening with the funding from Prop 56
with the combination of funding for
Department of Justice Department of
Education Department of Public Health
there's a lot of new partnerships to try
to bring allies and enforcement from the
schools and then also from the
Department of Public Health and
community together to identify how to
come about that but I'm not an expert on
the enforcement side nor can I speak to
that what the end of the day the
enforcement still happens at a local
level loved ulj I've worked them for a
long time dlj passes the money's host
your local sheriffs and police
departments that do all these operations
so I guess
the footing is inadequate and hasn't
been for quite some time thank you I
just add also it depends on the social
norm of the whole society so we know
that kids are not always just going to
the stores to buy it they're getting it
maybe from their parents for at least
some of the confiscated products have
been even amongst friends or family so
we have to address the whole society and
not just target and punish people but
think about the whole of society and
also the health the public health good
that we're trying to do well my backrest
been thirty years in law enforcement and
there are thousands of shops in LA that
are black market shops so it's really
easy for a young person to go to black
market shop and buy it like these
cartridges are produced in China but
they're filled up here in California be
a cannabis or the nicotine so it happens
here in the good old USA so like I said
at issue is you can't just bring your
head in the ground to those illicit
shops that are out there in the
thousands
yes mr. McCarney ah Thank You mr.
Sheriff
you know this is so overwhelming I don't
even know where to start there's so many
pieces and and I appreciate well first
of all thank you to the three chairs for
bringing this together when came up I
think it was late August early September
before we saw a lot of this movement so
certainly it's very timely and the
issues and frankly the questions that
are arising come by the by the day if
not by the hour I do think that it's the
overarching topic is important as you
said dr. what I think that's kind of how
I said it be you articulated very wisely
that this the Youth epidemic and we see
the romanticism with the flavours which
I'll get to in a second for this other
question that that mr. gray talked about
is this whole issue of the all the
vaping is is it safe in the first place
should we be permitting it so there's I
know that there's legal elements of it
and some say it's the illegal pieces but
how do you differentiate and I think
that that is a real question we have to
to offer ask ourselves so I want to
start with first as far as the the
product as a whole we saw that your
great PowerPoint and the in the decline
in smoking rates across our country here
in California and one of the the pushes
of the industry this is an alternative
and and they they have said that it's a
safe alternative and the FDA of course
came at them and said you can't say that
now am i understanding I just saw this
advertisement came up on someone's email
yesterday and they said to me and it
says it's a satisfying alternative so I
guess they're changing their language
it's not a safe alternative but it's a
satisfying I guess that's not necessary
illegal so as far as the alternative
what does the public health world say
about that as far as alternate or -
standard
tobacco smoking use alright so I think
that's by underscoring what the CDC has
emphasized there's no safe tobacco
product and we're learning about the
wide range of health effects of THC as
well what I tell my patients is your
blends are meant to breathe clean air
and so my goal as a provider will be to
help you quit for good so it as an
alternative I would probably say let's
try to get you to zero and have clean
lungs
yes it's somewhat similar two years ago
they came out with filters and they said
to filtered cigarettes are safer and
potentially marginally safer but but are
they safe so a minder saying when they
first came out with the patches and the
gum there were there were prescriptions
to get them you couldn't buy them over
the counter mm-hmm has I never been
talked about as having if there if there
is an alternative to having it utilized
by people and medicine like like you
right so pharmacy as opposed to these
these little shops that we see around
town right so how to quit
especially when nicotine is so addictive
these medications those five nicotine
replacement medications are meant to
help people with withdrawal symptoms as
which are especially worse in the first
couple weeks anxiety irritability you
know I've seen people want to leave the
hospital against medical advice because
they can't go out for a cigarette but it
can really lead to a lot of agitation so
those medications are meant over two to
three months to help you help your brain
unlearn the nicotine addiction and to
learn new behaviors to replace the
product that you are using so you know
I've heard in the news media like well
maybe people trying to quit vaping
should go back to cigarettes no we have
medications that are time tested but
what we're facing here is a new high
potency nicotine that even as a provider
I don't even know quite how to dose
people I can only just hope to try to
titrate up to what their needs are until
their own symptoms are abated okay and
then to the youth piece I know you
talked about this Kimberly so it's
advertising is a big bit and literally
last night I was driving through my
district and we see these shops all over
there and we know that they there's the
youth element with the flavor and we've
seen reports that LGBT community is is
is have hired numbers for this literally
I saw a shop with the with the pride
colors I'm sure you can see it it's a
blueberry vape shop blueberry vape and
smoke on what Avenue and just
unbelievable that's exactly what we're
talking about the population and it's
targeting the community come to come
right in knowing that there's this
romanticism I know that I have eleven
year old girls and they were selling
girl-scout cookies right over here at
Safeway and one of my daughters saw
somebody coming out vaping the cinnamon
just like Daddy that that it smells
really good it smells like it tastes
really good too 11 year old yeah so you
know these kids have everything around
them if they see it's cool that they
have the advertising and so this is a
crazy crazy epidemic and it's coming
from all different angles and you know
it's part of its up coming up on us to
to really act and I know there's no one
solution I get that there's not one bill
one thing I know talking about last
year's a package of things on the menu
to do to tackle this and I think that
we're we're doing this today the
conversation we're hopefully going to be
pushing some policy in the near future
cities are stepping up and doing it too
but I don't think that one flavor ban or
policy is going to end you know even if
you go after the shops and mr. gray and
I had some amazing presentations this
past year talking about the shops that
are getting the stings it's not the
grocery stores it's the little montage
shops and they're the ones are having
the huge huge numbers and so having more
enforcement there like mr. Cooper say I
think is part of the solution but even
if we shut down that you know kids are
smart they figure out mom's password to
Amazon and buy stuff online and so it's
going to take a multitude of ways
to go after this so the last topic I
wanted to discuss his I understand that
it's it's it's a nuanced issue with the
with the non tobacco vaping and first of
all I even know how many if there is is
it prevalent for the cannabis vaping and
flavors do we know that so I get data on
the vaping specifically of THC and
flavor THC and I do not believe that
that exists okay so as mr. Gray's
suggestion if we did have
across-the-board no flavor for tobacco
and cannabis we don't really know how
much that would impact the cannabis
vaping products potentially it's it
correct my my expertise is not in THC
sites so I'm not aware of what percent
of vaping devices are sold in flavors
and what percent of young people are
vaping flavored wax pens okay or THC
devices and then the last issue and this
the question which I think is the
question we're asking about the
illnesses and it's it's mainly from the
THC products and the industry is saying
hey that's not our product that's the
illegal black market product that's
coming over and they're not having the
same metals in there that we haven't
tested and so forth I don't know the
sciences I may be messing that up but I
would assume that people who are who use
this product they use it all right they
don't they're not pure they don't just
do one or the other so it's hard to tell
which one was the culprit and so is
there a way to to have a safe nuanced
way for the cannabis product and go
after the the devices that are really
causing harm can we understand that you
know what I was getting at yes but I
think that's why the CDC has come out
saying out of all the 500 and so things
they could get from the cases that were
sick and they couldn't find one
substance or one product
to call it upon that's why they're still
making that very strong statement
everyone please just stop thinking until
we try to figure this out I don't think
we really know and I and so far there's
no suggestion that say there is a safe
device or way of vaping or what chemical
so the medical community is with the CDC
and saying with all the questions and
not enough answers we should just do a
time-out on all the stuff I think that
would be the safest thing for Public
Health mm-hmm and and is there ongoing
research that enables you to see if they
their devices that are legally sold do
have some safety requirements in them
that so this is where the FDA regulation
is supposed to come into play where the
manufacturers are supposed to submit
information about their products and the
effect on health so that's why that
deadline that moratorium is now being up
to next year okay thank you and I know
our later panel has our Department of
Public Health so that potentially these
issues will be addressed there as well
thank you
Thank You mr. chair thank you um so we
have miss lon
mr. Lowe and then mr. Cooper again great
thank you I appreciate the conversation
I think this for me I first started
thinking about this in 2011-12 when I
was on a school board and we did not
know if our tobacco policy for Student
Conduct actually covered vaping it was
very confusing then we didn't know if
the law allowed for that and I think
since then the school districts have
evolved into thinking and I know some of
my colleagues have touched upon issues
of enforcement or impact health impact
but one of the things that I heard in
this presentation repeated was the lack
of understanding and education which I
find to be one of the harder things to
do to educate the public and so I just
wondered if you could speak to what
you're seeing in terms of best practice
as educating the youth or public about
this certainly there have been articles
clearly the articles have not had an
impact on you know mass number of minors
decreasing their use at least not
with the data that you presented so what
are the best practices what what is
California doing well to try to educate
minors and adults about the impact
that's a great question
so again to refer back to the tobacco
control program we have here in
California so the the focus of that
program is to denormalize the use of
tobacco control and part of that is by
engaging communities to change the norms
of the access to tobacco the exposure to
tobacco the advertising and marketing to
various tobacco products and retail
environments also there's a lot of work
happening at the local level to change
the number the density of retailers and
communities the location of those
retailers and moving them away from
schools so that's one part of it the
second side is to do the media campaign
and to try to engage parents and adults
and young adults around not just the
dangers of the products but what's
happening within communities and tobacco
industry tactics and so that work is
continuing so that's just the side that
the Department of Public Health has the
Department of Education who is also
partner in this work then does the
school work specifically and so they're
funding through their tobacco use
prevention education program then goes
to try to train teachers and educate
parents and administrators on the
problem of these products what hadas off
guard was how quickly these products
grew and as Assemblymember gray noted
that oftentimes when we go into schools
and we ask what product seeing people
are using we I I remember I was actually
in Madera County and talked to some law
enforcement who were working with high
school students and learned that all of
the products they confiscated were wax
pens and I was surprised by that but
when we talked to students we find out
that they are constantly trying to be
ahead of the game so when we focus just
on jool parents know what joules are so
they're looking for joules and so then
kids go to sauron or they go to novo or
any of the other new products and so
it's trying to get the bigger picture
and not just focus on a product but
trying to create healthier communities
by removing the products and then by
having media campaigns to make people
aware of them and as was also noted a
lot of the comprehensive policies that
local jurisdictions are creating not so
much on the sales but on the use of
these products I know that the majority
of our colleges and universities in the
states have comprehensive policies that
cover the inhalation or use of any
combustible or vaporized product on
their campus and the idea is that if we
can remove the use from being visible
that will change the norm and then that
will then change people's use because
it's not normalized to use it so it's a
really comprehensive program that
communities are working on community
coalition's across the state the
Department of Public Health has a really
robust and very successful media
campaign and then the Department of
Education is working within the schools
to try to address it from all approaches
and really trying to engage all
community members including parents to
make them aware of these and then really
helping to equip them and to equip
trusted adults to be able to ask the
question about use to advise and
encourage quit attempts and then to
refer them to services that can help
them quit thank you clearly sounds that
there's no doubt that it's comprehensive
I think my concern is that despite how
comprehensive it is the problem is
outpacing the potential solution and so
I'm just wondering if our definition or
understanding of comprehensive is going
to have to adapt to a problem that's
evolved I'm at a very fast and deep way
and I think I'm trying to grapple with
that so I appreciate the feedback may I
add that the doctors need to be educated
as well we we don't know how to ask and
treat these things and they what the
kids are doing we don't even know that
they're the same parents who are the
providers who are trying to keep up or
may not know that you know this problem
is out there that's true
thank you very much and thank you right
doctor Tong and Kimberly for your
presentation I will admit to that your
presentation scared the crap out of me
because we have done such hard work in
trying to address this public health
crisis now seems to be coming right back
again and so the sense of urgency is
very real but I wanted to call your
attention to this slide that you
provided to us with respect to one-third
of tobacco shops and vape shops sold to
minors in 2018 your graphic here about
34 percent of usage comes from tobacco
and vaping vape shops specifically so
that of one-third going to that of
minors we heard earlier about that of
locals and school districts and the
challenges of local municipalities
trying to tackle this issues of bans
outright and oftentimes at the state
level we battle on that of local control
versus the state coming in but it's
clear to me that the locals are not
necessarily in control and as I've had
an opportunity to meet when we're now
out of session with local school
district and board members this is the
number one issue that they are hearing
and seeing about that they are not able
to tackle this and they're asking
specifically for additional help from
the state to try to tackle this do you
have any guidance or insights with
respect to that of locals and the role
of state versus local and again seeing
that the lack of enforcement
specifically going to selling to minors
of one-third going to tobacco stores do
you have any sense on the observations
or mechanisms that you're hearing as you
are engaged in talking to those most
impacted I knew a number of
jurisdictions are adopting stronger
tobacco retail licenses many don't have
retail licenses right now and are
looking at adopting them with stronger
fees associated stronger penalties and
then also the inclusion of flavor bans
the the focus on the flavor ban is
because we know that young people are
initiating tobacco use because the
products are flavored and they seem less
harmful as a result and so by
eliminating those products it's
eliminating products that are attracting
youth to purchase them but as we have
sort of seen the trends are given your
presentation there are that's a
relatively small segment of local
municipalities that have actually taken
action and yet the impacted populations
since you've also shown the percentage
continues to rise but again I think
maybe you have any insights with respect
to do you believe that local
jurisdictions are actually doing what
they can and should be doing to sort of
tackle this issues given the rates and
then also given the statistics of that
of enforcement going to miners because
again local seeds we hear all the time
local control but they're clearly not in
control if the miners are being sold
these products I think that some
jurisdictions in the state have a
stronger history of adopting strong
tobacco control ordinances and we see
that with those jurisdictions having
policies in place now I know that
there's a lot of work being done
throughout this state but I know that
there are regions where it may not be
happening
sure did you off the top of your head
you just referenced a number of
jurisdictions that have comprehensive
policies that may be doing better with
respect to that of enforcement and some
of these policies are any jurisdictions
I can't speak to the enforcement piece
but I know that we know specifically the
bay area has been the champion for
flavored ordinance we know that Los
Angeles has recently the county has
recently had an ordinance the city is
looking at an ordinance the city of
Sacramento's which just went into effect
so definitely more of the urban
communities to have ordinances that are
already adopted or are closer to
adoption thank you very much mr. Cooper
follow-up to miss Mills question all
those ordinances they have them in place
but you walk around downtown outside
people are still a vape in be in
Sacramento LA or San Francisco but I'll
go back to the doctor
CDC's that take a break from vaping and
that's just unrealistic I think when
people are involved in addiction be it
tobacco alcohol or illicit drugs it is
just tough to kick no matter what FDA is
saying hey vaping is better than smoking
tobacco so we've got a whole group of
people
out there and I think it's unrealistic
to do that maybe 10 years from now or
whatever we find out we more information
on this I don't know there's no timeline
really and I'm sure it's not gonna
happen anytime soon so being realistic
they're not taking a break so I guess
that's the doctor vaping if it's I guess
it's just not from the black market it's
still safer than smoking tobacco then so
I think this is where the FDA regulation
is of e-cigarettes is still not there
and this is for the manufacturers to
submit information about health so I
don't think we can even make that
statement that it's a safe end it right
now the CDs saying there's no safe
tobacco product and but we know that
they're inhaling these chemicals with
vaping can have immediate health effects
so as the Surgeon General has noted you
know even for non users secondhand
aerosol has harmful constituents so I
think what we're seeing right now is
maybe what you're referring to is does
maybe having less carcinogens in some of
these products maybe does that mean less
harm and I think that's why I'm trying
to also show this is maybe what was
thought for low tar before but it takes
years for the scientific evidence to
keep coming out and every day there's a
lot of evidence about immediate
biological effects and it'll take a few
years to get at the Dini ology data so I
think that's where a lot of the public
confusion is where they think these are
newer safer cleaner products they don't
make you smell it Mike but must be
better but I think we are now finding
out there is still a lot of learning to
do with the science and so far the
science is showing this is not a safe
product so for some of the previous
vaping pens from nicotine part that went
through FDA they were approved to the
FDA and tested they never what did the
manufacturers submit to the FDA right so
I think in 2016 the deeming rule by the
FDA is that it has authority to regulate
e-cigarettes
but right now whatever is on the label
it's not regulated that hasn't been
implemented yet so that's why
they've started trying to move up that
moratorium to say start submitting
what's actually in these things the FDA
does fund what's called T cores these
tobacco centers of regulatory science
that have been producing some of this
scientific evidence and it needs to be
compiled and they're also informing the
FDA about these products as well so it's
still early stages to say that these
that we even know what's in these
products and the effects on human health
so the media has been all over this and
they've submitted a lot of test samples
for testing and from what I've seen in
the media all their test samples that
came back we're from the illicit market
be it tobacco or cannabis and not
legitimate manufacturers so I think when
you look at this I mean a lot of it
comes from earlier you guys talked about
the brick and motar
it's like seventy four percent a lot of
it comes from the illicit market so it
seemed to me just as a layman that that
is a big issue with it where a lot of
these products do come from no doubt
that's something that needs to be
regulated and you know as you were
mentioning you know we need Department
of Justice to also help with this but
you know I think it's very challenging
because the the products that the CDC
investigation has then it's not even all
of the cases that they've been able to
get the products and tests so what they
don't know and that's what they conclude
is right now there is no single product
or substance but at the same time
they're saying please ask some of these
questions about where are people getting
it how are they using it what are they
filling it up with and they're asking
doctors to ask these questions to help
it out
we don't know thank you anyone else
go ahead and local bastards
so my colleagues have inspired some
additional questions for you one things
you know the the the debate of the
discussion the dialogue in the state
legislature in California this year was
predominantly on one hand folks that
wanted to focus on the moratorium or the
banning of flavored Ystad products and
the other less of effort we had was to
focus more on the oversight regulation
taxation of e-cigs as we do into
traditional tobacco I was involved as
one of the authors on the oversight
regulatory approach and the inspiration
for that was frankly traditional tracker
right we've seen in traditional
education oversight regulation taxation
has been a successful recipe to reduce
consumption with youth and the general
public right and sometimes we don't need
to be smarter than ourselves up here but
rather look at effective practices and
then replicate those and so you know at
one point we had a bill before
legislature that of the 15,000 reported
tobacco flavors he said flavors that
were out there would have restricted the
sale of 14 thousand nine hundred and
ninety seven of them consistent with
traditional tobacco where you have
menthol and traditional tobacco flavors
available but not some of these flavors
that we discussed earlier and the
committee that I serve on in regulates
language NACO of alcohol as well and I
would point to prohibition in the early
part of the last century as an example
of where more turns bands aren't
necessarily always effective in fact
sometimes they serve to exasperate the
black market and now as we're faced with
real health concerns that all evidence
thus far seems to point to black market
products I haven't seen I haven't read a
lot that suggests
the legal THC and/or tobacco products
were costly they may be in others lot
yet to learn but we certainly know that
some of these black market products have
caused some damage so do you agree or do
you not agree based on your work that
regulatory oversight education taxation
wouldn't be a good direction to go for
ecigs just as we've done with
traditional tobacco or do you share the
view that we ought to do something
entirely different and do more of a
prohibition style ban on products well I
think this is personally and I'm just
speaking for myself I mean I think this
is something I mean vaping is so new all
these health effects and health harms
are just growing we have to look at
every single option I mean for sure to
control whatever we can is most
important I think we're learning even to
in you know as a provider the opiate
epidemic is very much
on all of our minds and this is
something we are tasked very heavily to
do and that was under a medical model
and not a market model so even that you
know we know that there are addictions
is a very challenging thing that people
get it from many different sources and a
comprehensive approach is very much
needed and I would say the same in
regards to the type of work that's being
done we know and we look back to 2009 we
know that when we remove flavors from
cigarettes here in California every
population had a decrease in cigarette
consumption with the exception of
African Americans who have the highest
rates of methylated use so we know that
there was a positive impact by removing
those flavored products and so it could
only be assumed that when we look at the
two different issues and I agree with
dr. wood that we have an issue
you thing and that increasing and then
we have the issue of the illnesses but
looking specifically at the youth vaping
side that removing youth friendly
products and flavored products from the
market would have an impact on youth use
of the products and eventually their
transition to other tobacco products
down the road which is what the research
is showing us I tend to agree with that
comment which is why we designed the
bill that we were working on to reflect
tobacco exactly which is banning flavors
outside of traditional tobacco flavors
menthol and and traditional tobacco so
that did work and seems like could work
again the other efforts on flavors are
different than what you just described
the other question I had is the
availability and popularity of nicorette
and the reason asked the question is
what when I first learned about the
e-cigarette vaping abduch I went and
wanted to see all of these crazy flavors
right like Captain Crunch and bubblegum
this and I screamed that and so I went
to the jewel website and started looking
they didn't find any of them I had been
told all there's always crazy you know
fifteen thousand flavors and so I'm on
the website and found fruit mint and
several others and then I looked at a
couple other company websites and found
similar similar results what struck me
about that is I was familiar through
some friends and family of folks who had
used Nicorette in the past and it struck
me they were similar to Nicorette
flavors so I went looked and I was right
there same type of fruit mint same types
of flavors that were offered in these
products why have we not seen an
epidemic of nicorette use amongst teens
if in fact just being logically
consistent that flavors drive
consumption and teens then I would
assume we should have a Nicorette
epidemic
and I don't believe we have one any
thoughts on that doctor sure
so usually nicotine gum or lozenge is
usually two milligrams of nicotine we're
talking these dual pods that the
manufacturer says has like 56 milligrams
and that's supposed to be the equivalent
of at least one pack of cigarettes so
when you're having flavors flavors is
just one part it's the marketing and
it's also the taste that masks maybe
whatever bitterness even in Nick
nicotine gum or lozenge you know
patients say there's some peppery taste
that bothers them and the mint numbs it
and it masks that so I think we're talk
that's why we're talking about the high
potency nicotine plus the flavor the
appeal of flavors and that combination I
think is something that's way different
from these vaping products than with the
medication that the FDA oversees for
quitting tobacco and if I can just add
to that so a couple of other points so
in the newest data that we have it's
still preliminary data but from the
National Youth tobacco survey we've seen
an increase a significant increase in
youth use of mentholated vaping devices
and meant vaping devices and a decrease
in fruit and candy is significantly
lower so we are getting to a point where
young people are switching to mint or
starting with mint products on the
Nicorette industry procs you talked
about vaping products not not gun
correct so on the on the gum side so it
is there is no standard for use of
nicotine replacement therapy products
for use with minors those products are
not marketed to minors and so when we
look at Jul who I think we can call them
out for and they're currently again
under investigation for the practices of
the marketing that they did due to youth
specifically and so that's a huge
difference
is that access to these products they're
a lot more attractive to youth and gum
that's being promoted by providers and
then also the invasive marketing of
these new devices on social
media sites and specifically to youth
and young adults so that might point us
back in the direction of restrictions on
marketing education taxation increased
oversight and penalties all those things
that might dial in on accessing those
products make it more similar to a
Nicorette product that's more
restrictive in its availability but also
just to follow up on your thought doctor
brings up and we did not discuss this at
least not that I'm aware of and perhaps
some other chairs or members did discuss
it was the focusing on the nicotine
content which I think you bring up this
kind of excessive nicotine content maybe
maybe we need to focus taxation
moratorium prohibition provisions on
example on the amount of nicotine
contained in a product that's something
we haven't looked at but do you think
that might be an effective Avenue to go
down worth exploring
on the e-liquids and trying to
understand what's in them and also you
know we know people are price responsive
so that is I mean the closest we got to
that I know the bill that I was working
on some of my colleagues we were we were
looking at a taxation approach that
would have been based off of the
nicotine content in the product so I'm
gonna go back and take another look at
that based on your comments here today I
think also just to note just like with
the tar you know whatever's registering
in the Machine we still need to learn
what's actually going on with the humans
as well
and my final my final question I wasn't
sure I heard your answers on prohibition
you're for a prohibition or a ban versus
regular regulation oversight taxes I
kind of laid that out there and I didn't
hear you guys answer that as a provider
I'm not sure that's usually my realm
like and I'm here to educate about that
question I just curious on your
you know opinion given your involvement
oh well I think time is telling that
these products are not safe and so it's
worth looking at every angle that we're
understanding these with the vaping
associated pulmonary injury we still
have a lot to learn that you know if the
CDC is saying to stop vaping you know
what are our options so I don't know
that that's called prohibition but I
think it's called how do we act for
public health thank you for your time
thank you what thank you very much
a few questions follow up
[Music]
I'll just one comment to comment and mr.
green I agree and disagree on things and
so I may or may not be obvious people
but that's okay but but but he pointed
out that you know we talked about
banning the 14,000 997 flavors and still
leaving others out there but my
understanding from tobacco free kids is
that when you leave mint and menthol on
the table you still got 50 percent
that's the preference for 50 percent of
users so so that's to me is a is kind of
a problem and so and that's that's data
that was fairly recent that came out in
August I believe so
so I mean my numbers may not be exact
but I think mint was somewhere around 32
percent and then you add menthol in
there and the numbers still high so in
other words that's why rule that's why
mr. McCarty and I particularly looking
at a ban on all flavors but so but what
we're talking about the FDA and safety
and you mentioned tea corpse or tea
course tea course it seems kind of
counter intuitive productive it seems
wrong that we would ask the industry to
provide us with its safety data
considering the history of the industry
and how they've been deceptive on
tobacco throughout the time tobacco has
been out there so I failed to see why
you know yes the FDA is pushing that up
but how do we get other data out there
that isn't potentially bias it feels a
little like the fox guarding the hen
house quite frankly and it just it feels
backwards
especially in this arena with a history
of not being truthful on on issues why
would we then take the same people and
have them have them you know conduct the
research and then say oh yeah
this is this is safe yes well there are
a lot of contradictions in the history
of tobacco control and I think where
this whole vaping epidemic is making us
try to examine everything from a from
what we know and what we're seeing now I
just want to point out that some of
these tea cores are very can serve as in
terms of independent review so I've had
colleagues at UC San Francisco where
there's a new product that called IKOS
that is a heat not burn product it's not
vaping it's heating and they just got
FDA they submitted through the FDA
approval to market and the folks at
these centers looked at the data
independently and came to some different
conclusions so for example this product
that heats not burns tobacco versus
regular cigarettes when they looked at
the industry data they showed there was
actually two hundred to a thousand
percent higher of over 50 constituents
out of a hundred chemical constituents
in this heat not burn product compared
to regular cigarettes and even higher
liver function tests liver inflammation
from blood tests than regular cigarettes
so I think these tea cores that are help
to that are helping the FDA understand
what is important data for regulatory
science play very critical roles but
they are not industry they're typically
universities that are providing data and
also can help with independent review of
data as well
in the interest of time I do have some
other comments and I'm gonna hit on them
but but I know we've got a lot of big
agenda ahead of us here I think you know
with regards to mr. Lowe's you talked
about the really small number of cities
and that have actually taken action I
think in a short amount of time the fact
that almost 10% of California cities
have taken some action on flavors I
think is significant and I think you're
gonna see that number grow if there is
an action from either the federal
government or the state so I think part
of that is is just people saying whoa we
got a problem here we need to do
something and maybe it's not the right
thing to do but it's better than doing
nothing at all and so I think that that
you're gonna see more and more of that I
to hear that is like the number one
issue in school vaping and it isn't
distinguish being vaping tobacco and
vaping cannabis it's vaping it's all
lumped together it is then it is the
number one issue I hear from from people
we have done a marvelous job on
education related tobacco I think it
shows by the number of the percentage
and how that actual traditional tobacco
use had continued to go down but the the
stark change between 2017 and 18 and
then now into nineteen I gotta wonder if
it isn't just because of the trendy
little device those original devices
were pretty clunky and big and hard to
hide and mom and see that what the heck
is this thing but it's hard it's a much
easier conceal something like like the
Joule devices and so that makes it cool
and I wonder how much of that is an
issue I think now we're also we are
hearing now that that in the public
health emergency I'll call it right now
with the illnesses that are happening
kids are taking a more cautious approach
about that some kids anyway
females more than males because I think
guys thing to think they're invincible
period and so I think that there are
there at least from new New Starts and
those that are currently are
quote-unquote addicted continue to do
that because it's an addiction it's it's
a it's almost impossible to walk away
from I think one of the challenges that
we face in the education certainly in
the cannabis space is the promise of
prot 64 was revenue
or that and we have a time lag now and
the revenue isn't what we expected from
the taxes and so we're kind of a little
bit behind the scenes on that from my
perspective and we do have programs
either so maybe we piggyback off of the
successful programs that you've been
talking about but the resources to move
that haven't haven't been as available
yet it is interesting I have a son who's
now 23 he said in in throughout middle
school and high school that cannabis was
much more accessible and much more
consumed than tobacco once and so the
numbers that you're talking about usage
doesn't surprise me too much based on
that and what I hear from from other
from other people so in as far as
taxation whether we were taxing nicotine
products or cannabis products maybe even
you know labeling you know different
labels and you know maybe we go at some
point - I think there's isn't there some
sort of a there's like a sticker or
something on tobacco products it's decks
maybe we go that way with cannabis at
some point but that doesn't help us with
the illicit market and so that I think
is that that will continue to be that
will help distinguish between the two
markets but I don't know that that helps
us with the illicit market until there's
better enforcement so it's more so if
you want to comment I threw a lot out
there I'm sorry yeah most it wasn't a
question so well thank you for your
comments I do have to follow comments so
one is on the cool factor of these
devices certainly it's very cool we work
with young people who are engaged in
working on these ordinances in their
local communities and they have come and
shared with us that they shy away from
telling their peers what they're working
on because it's not cool to be an anti
tobacco person right now because vaping
has become the norm so that's an issue
but the issue is that even if it was
just a cool trend for a little bit it's
a cool trend with a highly addictive
solution so now young people are
addicted so even if they don't want to
use it anymore as you had mentioned this
is an
addiction not a habit and so now we're
dealing with something that was cool who
has created a new generation of nicotine
addicts so that's a big issue the other
thing we've been talking a lot about
vaping as that's the intent of this
hearing but also just to note that the
flavors that we saw cigarette smoking
going down over the last many years and
much of that can be attributed to FDA
and removing the flavors it can be
attributed to the amazing work that's
happened here in California but it's
important to note that tobacco use of
other products was not changing or was
increasing with you thinking adults and
that's the other flavor tobacco products
and oftentimes young people will smoke
their marijuana with a flavored cigar
wrapper and so the connection there is
all of the flavored tobacco it's not
simply flavored nicotine solutions it's
an issue with young people it's the
flavoring in all of the products so it
seems our comments have drawn up more
questions so yeah mr. McCarty and then
mr. Rivas yeah well the first thing
about the cities I just wanted to
mention dr. what is is there's 10% right
now but I would say the population wise
it's probably close to 25 30 with la San
Francisco LA County the city of LA on
the verge and other big cities and so
some of the rules are different so
that's one thing like we saw with
plastic bags and menu labeling if we
have all these jurisdictions with
slightly different laws it's mass
confusion for consumers and I with the
industry is probably enough let's have
one statewide policy I think that's
important but on the tax can regulation
I get what you're what you're saying
chairman gray but there's some products
that you know when there's moderate use
taxing regulation oversight makes sense
like alcohol moderate use we don't tax
it regulate and have a policy for
cocaine heroin and methamphetamine
because we know it's unsafe for any set
subset of humans kids especially I think
the safety thing is the question here
and one thing we never talked about you
don't ask you last question here is is
that the tobacco miner setting is very
different than this
the nicotine the high dosage have a huge
impact on young people on their
development there's still there the
depression anxiety and behavioral issues
and there was one young man that's suing
Jul talking about what it led to his
lifestyle change and that's a public
health issue that has cost upon society
and healthcare costs and so you know
that piece we haven't really talked
about yet is that the impact it has just
on the actual young people so you
mentioned talked about that for say oh
yes so I think when the Surgeon General
is talking about the developing brain is
also addressing mental health issues and
I thank you for bringing that up
and it's nicotine and marijuana's and
it's not to say that it does it's not
important for older people it's just
that this is especially important for
the next generation so I think those are
very excellent points you bring up that
it's not just physical health and you
know these pulmonary injury cases are
alarming but there's you know it's the
whole person that we need to look at
thank you yeah so I appreciate the
information you know I come from prior
to my time in the assembly I was a
school discipline manager so I saw this
epidemic right before my eyes I saw
anything and everything you know and so
obviously this is a very complex issue
in a discussion we probably make it
worse by all the dialogue you've heard
up here quite made more complex but
certainly seems like we're racing
against the clock it seems like this
epidemic is getting worse day by day and
based on all this conversation up here
it's you know very easy to get lost in
the weeds of this complex issue and
there's obviously a lot that we do not
know but based on what we do know we do
know that there is a public health
problem that there's a crisis right that
we have was it more than a thousand
cases of lung illness that have been
reported in people under 35 years of age
60% of those patients are under 18 years
old 21% are between 18 and 20 years of
age and as of this morning 29 deaths
related to this and in in you know
obviously as I mention it's easy to get
in the weeds based on this conversation
we talk about enforcement we could talk
about flavors and on flavors we could
talk about THC we talked about you know
the nicotine we talked about taxation
but the only thing we can that we really
do know the one thing we can point to is
that the relate the the the the the one
thing we could point to relate to the
cause of all these illnesses and the
deaths is vaping that all reported
patients have a history of using vapor
products right and so to me standing up
here we've got all the information we
look at what other states are doing we
know it you know our governor did
through executive action but it seems to
me an absent a complete van of all
vaping products the flavor not flavor
all vaping products nothing is going to
be in unless we have that nothing is
going to be enough to prevent future
illnesses until we absolutely know what
is causing these illnesses and so you
know until you know in the meantime that
we're rolling out all these public
awareness campaigns that we are adopting
regulations and build a policy framework
you know regulatory framework to address
this crisis you know and find the most
effective a solution however many you
know ideas it's gonna take unless we
have an absolute ban it seems to me that
we're gonna keep reading about more
illnesses we're gonna keep reading about
more deaths aside from the public health
cost impact the treatment of some of
these people is going to be astronomical
and I represent a rural area where we
are you know we lack health care
services and so understanding
availability of treatment let alone the
cost is a problem so absent so I guess
my question is absent a complete ban you
know this is only gonna get worse is
that true or not true or I you know I
don't know
I think I'll comment that every week my
slides are outdated because these cases
are rising and this is these are young
people who can some of them as you're
noting hospitalized in the ICU very
expensive cost of care they're lucky
they're young because they can walk out
the people who are dying are middle-aged
you know how do we stop this I think
this is this is why we're coming
together today but to anticipate the
health professions are going to be able
to take care of this it has to be more
upstream and as I think everyone's noted
today a very comprehensive approach you
know I think it's the cats out of the
bag already and you know what can we all
do together to help control the epidemic
thank you thank you both very much for
kicking this off much very much
appreciate the information and go ahead
chairman Lowe will introduce our second
panel thank you very much and Ennis we
then clear the table for the next panel
the next panel is how vaping in
electronic cigarettes are regulated in
California and what more needs to be
done our panelists
Susan Vannelli acting director of the
Department of Public Health
Laurie Ajax chief of the Bureau of
cannabis control nicolas maduro
director for the California Department
of tax and fee Administration Karen lief
senior assistant attorney general for
tobacco litigation and enforcement
section and then finally herder kaput
for senior assistant attorney general
for the canvas control section and
members and colleagues just as a point
of notification that it's been an hour
and 45 minutes in our first panel
discussion and I know that we have this
panel and add additional panel after
that followed by public comments so I
know that we'll try to be very direct
with some of our comments in the
interest of time to be able to get as
much information as possible so having
said that might we first begin then in
order here and we begin with Susan
Fanelli please
good afternoon chairs chairs and members
I'm Susan finale acting director for the
California Department of Public Health
I've been asked today to speak about the
role of the Department of Public Health
in tobacco and vaping regulation first I
want to start with as you're aware
governor Newsom did issue the executive
order and gave specifically asked the
Department of Public Health to launch a
20 million dollar statewide digital and
social media public awareness campaign
to educate youth young adults and
parents about the health risks of vaping
developing recommendations to reduce the
availability of vaping devices to
persons under 21 years of age including
the establishment of warning signs about
the health risks of vaping both in
advertising and that retail of retailers
increased enforcement regarding illegal
sales of vaping products and
specifically eliquid flavors to youth in
addition CD pH was charged to make
recommendations regarding the
establishment of standards for nicotine
content and uniform packaging for
purposes of including nicotine content
in the calculation of taxes for today no
recommend he no recommendations have
been finalized at this time and we
continue to explore all comprehensive
off set of options as we look to address
this issue we will release an
advertising campaign dissuading young
people from vaping raising awareness of
the new outbreak associated with vaping
and denormalizing all tobacco use in
california and that campaign is set to
start next week as you heard this this
afternoon from the first panel the
numbers around youth vaping are very
concerning in 2018 the high school
smoking prevalence in California was 2%
compared to 8% nationally but we're
afraid that progress is going to go the
other way at the same time we are seeing
this alarming rise in the number of
school-age children using electronic
cigarettes e-cigarettes were the most
commonly used tobacco product among
California high school students eighty
six point four percent of high schools
tobacco users reported using a flavored
tobacco product the cost of smoking in
California is estimated at 18 1 point 1
billion or four hundred and four
thousand six hundred and three dollars
per smoker all Californians are paying
these
not just the smokers most recently this
vaping outbreak raises greater concerns
for youth as well as adults in the next
panel dr. charity dean from our acting
State Health Officer will share
information about the outbreak and the
health impacts so next I want to turn to
our role in regulating both tobacco and
cannabis first off I want to start by
emphasizing that much of the regulatory
control as you heard in the first panel
is resides with the federal Food and
Drug Administration for tobacco products
CD pH programs focus on education
prevention and use reduction in addition
to enforcement and limiting access to
youth CD pH submitters administers to
tobacco related programs the California
tobacco control program and the Stop
tobacco access to kids Enforcement Act
or stake the tobacco control program is
comprehensive statewide tobacco use
prevention and reduction program it
conducts health education interventions
and behavior change programs at the
state level in the community and in
other non school settings with a focus
on changing the role the community norms
influencing behavioral change regarding
tobacco use this program consists of a
statewide media campaign statewide and
community tobacco use prevention and
reduction programs conducted by local
health departments and nonprofit
agencies and statewide tobacco related
surveillance and out and evaluation
activities through this program CD pH
provides money for conducting smoking
cessation programs and approximately
fourteen point three million annually to
local jurisdictions and grant projects
the single largest provider smoking
cessation assistance in California is
the smokers helpline that operates with
a budget of nine million annually from
CDP age and receives another 1.4 million
from first five California the
California smokers helpline provides
cessation counseling and support in
seven languages and for the hearing
impaired
it offers support via the telephone chat
text messaging an app and apps it also
provides counseling tailored to
e-cigarette and smokeless tobacco users
and it provides assistance to teens and
pregnant women
pursuant to the executive order our
tobacco control permit program will
increase surveillance activities to
monitor awareness and perceptions of
vaping of the outbreak the stop tobacco
access to kids Enforcement Act is the
state program is a law enforcement
program focused on decreasing illegal
tobacco sales to persons under 21 years
of age by conducting inspections at
tobacco retail facilities awarding
grants to local law enforcement agencies
for tobacco retail inspections and
training and conducting tobacco related
retail inspections for the US Food and
Drug Administration we will be
increasing the compliance checks through
the stake act and read with the aim of
reducing illegal sales to youth prop 56
provides an additional six million
dollars to increase our enforcement
activities under stake in 2016 the
minimum legal tobacco sale age was moved
to age 21 yet in 2018 the statewide rate
of illegal tobacco sales to underage
adults was 19% the rate of illegal
tobacco sales for higher was higher for
e-cigarettes at 22% now I'm going to
turn to the a very different role that
we have in man you're manufacturing
cannabis on the manufactured cannabis
safety branch is very different in
contrast in contrast to tobacco control
where the majority of regulatory control
rusts with the federal FDA California
regulates nearly every every aspect of
the state's cannabis industry CDP H
houses the manufactured cannabis safety
branch which enforces a strict
regulatory framework established through
prop 64 medicinal and adult use canvas
regulatory safety act mal curse' and
regulations for cannabis products this
authority includes general cannabis
manufacturing oversight packaging and
labeling advertising and marketing
manufacturing and regulations read
regarding prohibited products and
emergency orders CDP H and other state
departments and agencies to continue to
work to bring cannabis businesses into
the legal marketplace but as we
acknowledged in the first panel that's
still a problem
just so you know Marcia has built-in
provisions that reduce youth access and
prevent products with harmful
contaminants from being sold to
consumers these include age restricted
rate retailers cannabis retail stores
are only available for adult 21 years of
age and older testing requirements for
pesticides heavy metals microbials and
residual solvents under the BCC
government warning statements outlines a
government warning statement that must
be on every cannabis product and alerts
consumers to potential effects
advertising restrictions and in in
regulations we further clarified those
statutory protections to require good
manufacturing practices by cannabis
manufacturers requirement to disclose
all of the ingredients prohibitions that
labels and products cannot be attractive
to youth manufacturers cannot add
nicotine or caffeine product to their
products requiring the universal symbol
on vape cartridges and a prohibition
against health claims on those products
in closing we continue to work through
the Health and Human Services Agency and
the governor's office to address the
outbreak and to reduce youth use of
tobacco and cannabis products we look
forward to continuing our work with the
legislature with stakeholders to address
the public health concerns thank you
very much for the opportunity to present
today thank you very much
the members thank you for inviting me to
participate in this important discussion
my name is Laurie Ajax and I'm the chief
of the Bureau of cannabis control as one
of the state agencies responsible for
regulating commercial cannabis licenses
including distribution micro businesses
retailers and testing labs the Bureau of
cannabis control has been closely
following the outbreak outbreak of
health illnesses being reported across
the country that have been linked to
vaping the bureau supports governor
newsome's executive order in september
taking direct action to address this
public health crisis all cannabis and
cannabis products legally sold in
California must come through a supply
chain of only licensed cannabis
businesses starting at cultivation and
inning with the sale to consumer this is
important because all licensees must
comply with requirements that put public
safety first the most crucial public
health related step in the legal supply
chain is mandatory regulatory compliance
testing before any cannabis or cannabis
product can be sold by licensed
retailers in California and must go
through rigorous testing for
contaminants such as pesticide mold
heavy metals processing chemicals
residual solvents and other harmful
ingredients for example cannabis and
cannabis products are tested for 66
pesticides and 20 residual solvents and
processing chemicals in conjunction with
the Department of pesticide regulation
the bureau has set levels for these
contaminants that cannot be exceeded in
cannabis or cannabis products these
levels are set based on what are
considered a safe amount for human
consumption
only after a testing laboratory has
confirmed that the cannabis or cannabis
product does not exceed any of these
limits can it be distributed to
retailers for sale to consumers cannabis
and cannabis products that cannot meet
testing standards must be destroyed
while no single substance or product has
yet been linked to the cases involving
vaping related illnesses it has been
reported that many of the cases involve
the use of THC containing products
particularly from the unlicensed market
therefore to assist with a drape
addressing the vaping health issues the
bureau in cooperation with other state
Adan 8 entities is focused on unlicensed
activity tracing sources of vaping
illnesses and public education the
bureau the cannabis Enforcement Unit
within the Department of Consumer
Affairs the California Department of
Public Health California Department of
tax and fee Administration and local law
enforcement agencies are currently
working together to identify and shut
down unlicensed retailers distributors
and manufacturers the cannabis
Enforcement Unit provides sworn peace
officer service to investigate
unlicensed activity complaints received
by the bureau
the Bureau and the cannabis enforcement
unit are working together to prioritize
complain
involving illegal cannabis vaping
products in the last six weeks the
cannabis Enforcement Unit served 12
search warrants and involved illegally
manufactured vaping products the search
warrant was served on unlicensed
cannabis retailers distributors and
manufacturers in conjunction with local
law enforcement agencies during these
operations 21,000 pounds of cannabis
Goods were seized with a retail value of
51 million this include the seizure of
20,000 vape pens and vape pen cartridges
the most recent case you may have heard
in the media is about the seizure of
cushy punch products I can assure you
that the situation is being actively
investigated however I'm not able to
provide any further details about this
during my testimony today as this
investigation is ongoing in addition to
stopping unlicensed retailers and
counterfeit cannabis products it is
critical to educate consumers about how
to identify a licensed retailer their
bureau is overseeing a statewide public
information campaign called hashtag get
weed wise the campaign includes
extensive outreach educating consumers
about the risks associated with cannabis
purchase from unlicensed businesses and
ensuring they understand that only
cannabis and cannabis products purchased
from licensed retailers have passed
state regulatory testing the bureau is
highlighting how a consumer can use the
see a pot check calm website to verify
the business's license before making a
purchase the campaign also is making it
clear to unlicensed businesses that they
will be prosecuted for that activities
unless they cease operations or get
licensed the bureau supports the
governor's efforts to confront the youth
of AP and academic and address this
ongoing public health crisis the bureau
will continue to work with the
legislature to ensure these products are
safe for consumers thank you again for
having me here today thank you very much
now Nicolas maduro's from the california
department of tax and fee
Administration's thank you chairman and
members of the committee's my name is
nick murderess i'm the director of the
california department of tax and fee
administration CD TFA
it's a mouthful to say the California
Department of tax and fee administration
so CTFA administers about 37 tax
programs for the state of California our
largest is the sales and use tax program
but we also administer the tobacco taxes
for the state as well as the cannabis
taxes today I'll focus on those two
programs I'd like to first start out by
discussing how those tax programs work
then briefly outline our enforcement
methods and lastly I'll highlight some
of the challenges we face as we crack
down on untaxed and illegal vape
products both in the tobacco and
cannabis realms so the tobacco tax
programs we have three basic categories
of tax programs we administers cigarette
taxes tobacco product taxes and
cigarette and tobacco products licensing
fees last year the department brought in
and administered about seventy four
point four billion dollars in tax
revenue of that two point 1 billion
dollars is related to these tobacco tax
and fee programs other tobacco products
which are the non cigarette taxes
accounted for about 13% of that revenue
or 281 million dollars in FY 1819 those
are taxes derived from historically it
was cigars smoking tobacco chewing
tobacco and snuff with prop 56 and 2016
electronic cigarettes and baked products
were added to that definition of tobacco
products and so it is only since then
that we've been taxing those vaping
products as OTP or other tobacco
products we estimate that last year the
tax revenue from those programs from oat
from vaping products amounted to about
56 million dollars starting next year we
will have exact numbers as we're
changing our returns to require that
vaping products be separately listed on
the tax returns the rate on
OTP including vaping products is set
based on the tobacco the cigarette tax
rate so cigarettes are taxed at two
dollars and 87 cents per pack in the
state of California now started out as
three cents back in the 50s and we're up
to 287 what we do annually is we take
that 287 and we add 50 cents to it so
you're at 3 dollars and 37 cents per
pack we divide that by 20 which is the
number of cigarettes in a single pack
you get 16 point eight five cents and
then we divide that number each year by
the average weighted cost of a single
cigarette this year that means that OTP
including all of these tobacco baked
products are taxed at a rate of fifty
nine point two seven percent now one
curious thing about the way the
California taxes are set up is that that
average wholesale cost which is the
denominator in the equation Rises each
year because of inflation which means
that the tax rate on other tobacco
products actually goes down each year it
is to me a strange outcome but we have
anyway in addition to that tax we also
have the cigarette in tobacco products
licensing program which licenses
annually about 31,000 retailers 300
wholesalers and 800 distributors now on
the tobacco side of the equation we
administer the sales and use tax program
which applies to these tobacco sales as
well as the excise tax and the
cultivation tax last fiscal year that
all of those programs together brought
in about four hundred and eighty million
dollars into date since adult legal
cannabis they've have brought in about
six hundred and thirty seven million
dollars the excise tax is again a very
complicated one at the moment it's 15%
based on the wholesale cost plus and
markup rate that CDT fa determines each
year which is currently set at 60% so
it's not a 15% on the actual price paid
by the consumer it could be much less
than 15% it could be much higher because
obviously markup the actual markup
varies in transactions and that anyway
so those are the tax programs we
administer how we enforce them we have
three basic methods inspections
investigations and audits we have ten
inspection teams dedicated to tobacco
enforcement and now through a BCP last
year to cannabis enforcement as well
around the state their job day in and
day out is to do inspections of
retailers to make sure that all of the
products in those stores is tax paid in
the case of cigarettes as was mentioned
earlier all of the tax paid materials
have stamps every pack of cigarettes in
the state has to have a tax stamp and
actually the tax is paid when you put
when the distributor purchases that
stamp and places it on the pack of
cigarettes for other materials our
inspectors go in and have to ask for the
invoices and the retailers have to prove
to us that the material is tax paid if
they can't prove it then we seize the
material in since July of this year our
inspectors have done about 2,500
inspections in the past two months alone
we've done 146 inspections of vaping
specific retailers of those hundred and
forty-six we've had 17 seizures of
products amounting to about 290 thousand
dollars of value now that's on the
tobacco side of the house on the
cannabis front we've done about 200
inspections since July and participated
in 75 search warrants as as Laurie
mentioned we partner often with BCC and
consumer fairs as well as local law
enforcement all around the state
in addition to those visits our outreach
program because of the scope of the
problem we're dealing with we've had our
outreach teams around the state also
doing cannabis visits they've done about
758 since July and in those cases we're
actually visiting not just permit
holders we're visiting any cannabis
seller that we can find and do to sites
like weed maps and others people aren't
hiding their retail activity there are
some real challenges on both of these
fronts and I'd like to just address
those very briefly on the tobacco side
the lack of stamping outside of
cigarettes is a challenge it's much
easier to go into a store and see that
all of the product is stamped and
actually the stamps contain information
our inspectors have devices which allow
them to read the stamps and you can tell
who the distributor was when it was
distributed a lot of background
information on on each of those stamps
also on the vaping side the tax rate is
lower I think than you would anticipate
because it because the tax is based on
the wholesale cost the wholesale cost of
some of these products is relatively low
and so if a vaping cartridge is the
equivalent of one pack of cigarettes in
many instances the tax on a vaping
cartridge is much less than the two
dollars and 87 cents tax on a pack of
cigarettes so that's an issue we're also
seeing you know there's a very there's a
lot of ease of market entry in the
vaping sector we've seen people can go
online order materials for their stores
they can sell the nicotine liquid
separately from the other liquid
and people can mix them at home only the
nicotine liquid is taxed currently not
any of the other vaping flavored juices
if they're sold separately once they're
combined then it's all taxed but
otherwise only the nicotine and the
penalties have historically been pretty
low for non-compliance and that actually
goes on the cannabis side as well our
inspectors at least are operating in the
world where the penalties are often
misdemeanors where it's very difficult
to get local law enforcement even want
to get involved in a misdemeanor case
and the fines are pretty low even for
failure to let our inspectors in to
record see your books you know it's a
$5,000 fine if somebody's operating on
the far side of the law and making
millions of dollars acting illegally the
prospect of my auditors with their
pocket protectors showing up and
knocking on the door and the you know
potential if a misdemeanor that in some
cases is going to reduce down to $400 by
local courts is not a real threat to
many of these folks on the cannabis side
the the illegal market is very large the
way we have traditionally approached
enforcement is cumbersome and slow it
relies largely on the criminal justice
system which is slow and difficult it's
difficult to build the cases it takes
time with thousands of illegal operators
around the state it's not I don't think
that's a method that serves the state
best and we're looking at other ways
other things that we can do and as with
tobacco we're also studying stamping
we're working currently on a thorough
review in light of the governor's
executive order which we'll be
presenting to him at the end of this
month that will review all of these
options and see if we can't find a
better way anyway I look forward to your
questions
thank you very much and finally a to
representatives from the attorney
general's office when in cannabis
control section and also in the tobacco
litigation and enforcement section thank
you very much chairman Lowe as well as
chairman wood and chairman gray and
committee members my name is Karen lief
I'm here on behalf of Attorney General
Xavier Becerra I am the head of the
tobacco litigation and enforcement
section within the California Attorney
General's Office my colleague here her
window Kapoor is the head of cannabis
control section within the California
Attorney General's Office so the two of
us are here to represent the Attorney
General and my colleague her ender we'll
be speaking to you about the cannabis
side of the vaping issues well I will
focus my remarks on the tobacco side let
me say that we're very grateful to have
this hearing because it calls attention
to what we view is a very important
public health issue others have already
spoken to the severe health issues that
have surfaced with the use of vaping
devices in recent months as well as the
huge spike in underage use of electronic
cigarettes I don't think I need to
repeat that at this time except to
remind all of us that according to the
2019 National Youth tobacco survey
preliminary data we're now nationwide at
a point where more than one out of four
high school students is using electronic
cigarettes this is the most popular form
of tobacco use among young people today
and this is fellow public health
standpoint extremely alarming because it
threatens to reverse much of the great
work and progress that has been done
over many years to reduce tobacco use in
the United States the product that kills
more Americans than any other product it
is the single largest source of
preventable death and disease in our
country claiming the lives of four
hundred and eighty thousand Americans
every year and all this has occurred in
the face of a regulatory environment
here in California at least with respect
to tobacco is fairly robust and I will
turn my remarks to that now under
California law electronic cigarettes are
considered tobacco products as such they
are subject as my colleague here Nicolas
Maduro said to state excise taxes and
state licensing laws state smoke-free
laws state underage sales laws and
remote saw sales laws and I'm sure I
haven't given a full list but it there's
fairly comprehensive regulation of
electronic cigarettes at the state level
in addition many local communities have
adopted ordinances to regulate
electronic cigarettes in one fashion or
another mainly this comes in the form of
local retail tobacco license ordinances
but in some instances it is legislation
that is specifically directed at
electronic cigarettes or flavored
products at least seven counties and
more than 32 cities in the state
regulate in this fashion at the federal
level electronic cigarettes are
regulated but to a lesser degree the
federal Food and Drug Administration has
regulatory authority under the federal
Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco
Control Act which was passed in 2009 and
under their deeming regs
electronic cigarettes are within their
regulatory ambit however the FDA has
adhered to an enforcement policy which
has allowed electronic cigarettes to be
sold and marketed in the United States
including in California without going
through the required pre-market approval
process by the FDA now I have seen in
news reports to the fact that the FDA is
reviewing that enforcement policy and
may change it especially with respect to
a flavored electronic cigarettes but we
haven't seen anything definitive from
that agency at this point I would note
that electronic cigarettes are not
subject to federal excise taxes nor are
they subject to a number of other
federal laws that apply to other tobacco
products such as the pact Act which
governs intercept interstate internet
and mail-order sales of cigarettes and
smokeless tobacco or the total
contraband cigarette trafficking Act
which governs smuggling of cigarettes
with that I want to talk about the
Attorney General's own role with respect
to tobacco this role dates back several
decades now to really the mid 1990s so
in California among a large number of
other states sued the major cigarette
manufacturers for a host of wrongdoing
but most notably their decades-long
conspiracy to deceive the American
people about the health risks of the
products and the addictiveness of
nicotine those lawsuits were resolved by
the master settlement agreement which at
the time is the largest civil settlement
in American history it imposes a number
of
on going obligations on the part of the
signatory manufacturers particularly in
the areas of advertising and marketing
but they also obligate the manufacturers
to make payments to the settling states
in perpetuity so long as they continue
to manufacture and sell their products
in the domestic stream of Commerce the
California Attorney General's Office has
had a unit now for 20 years that has
overseen their compliance with this
really landmark agreement we have not
hesitated to sue individual
manufacturers when we thought that they
did not comply with their obligations
under that agreement so we have sued and
won on issues such as youth targeting
and we and free sampling we have
overseen their compliance with payment
obligations and they are substantial to
date California has received sixteen
point five billion dollars in payments
from the signatory manufacturers and in
2019 alone California received just shy
of eight hundred and fifty million
dollars in addition to making sure that
the companies that are part of the
master settlement agreement live up to
their obligations under that agreement
the staff within the California Attorney
General's Office and forces a state law
called an escrow statute that applies to
the manufacturers that are not part of
that settlement agreement there are
certain obligations that they have based
on their sales here in California we are
thankful we have another state law
called the tobacco directory statute
that Shores up our ability to enforce
both of those laws that law obligates
the attorney general's office to create
and maintain a public list on our
website of all the cigarette
manufacturers and brain
that are lawful for sale in the state
and there is a screening process that my
staff and I do with respect to every
single cigarette manufacturer that wants
to be listed on that directory to make
sure that they have satisfied the
statutory requirements which include a
showing that they've complied with their
financial obligations and they're
compliant with other laws such as state
licensing statutes so we have that as a
tool I can tell you based on my own
experience that it is served California
well it is a gatekeeping function that
has been very valuable in being able to
assure that the cigarettes that are sold
in California are lawful for sale in
California and to make those out there
in the field easily identified the rogue
brands and rogue manufacturers that
qualify as contraband now the MSA the
tobacco directory and the escrow statute
don't apply to electronic cigarettes
that said that California attorney
general's office has been active with
respect to electronic cigarettes among
other things that California attorney
general's office staff have overseen the
compliance of electronic cigarette
sellers that sell over the Internet to
make sure that they're compliant with
California stake Act and other laws that
apply to them and in 2019 so far this
year alone we have issued 40 more than
40 warning letters to retailers that are
selling through the internet that have
sold to underage customers or otherwise
not compliant we have also not hesitated
to sue e cig companies for other forms
of wrongdoing including false
advertising
and youth targeting and we have
judgments against too we also work
closely with other state agencies
including CDT FA we share information
with them about businesses that we have
reason to think may be operating without
required state licenses or potentially
violating their obligations to pay the
state excise taxes that are owed and in
addition the California Attorney
General's Office are more precisely
attorney-general Becerra has urged the
FDA to step up its own enforcement with
respect to electronic cigarettes to act
more aggressively in the name of public
health in earlier this year Attorney
General visera along with several other
state attorneys general urged the FDA to
prioritize enforcement of all flavored
electronic cigarettes so it is Attorney
General is on record that this is an
important area of enforcement I would
add the thanks to Prop 56 the California
Attorney General's Office has new ich
role in supporting local law enforcement
the Prop 56 as has been noted is among
other things increases the state excise
tax on cigarettes and other tobacco
products it you marks the revenue for a
number of purposes including 30 million
dollars a year that is allocated to the
Department of Justice for distribution
to local law enforcement for enforcement
of state and local laws that deal with
illegal and underage sales of tobacco so
there's a particular focus on sales and
use by minors miss let me ask you to
conclude your remarks so that we can get
on to the name
be fantastic I'm sorry thank you very
much I I was really just about finished
I appreciate your patience the the
program has funded more than 200 grants
to date and that has funded a variety of
local agencies Police Department
Sheriff's Department
local school districts many of them are
using the grant funds for dealing with
electronic cigarette issues in their own
communities so with that I will just
note that there's more information on
our public website and thank you very
much good afternoon chairman gray
chairman lo and chairman wood and
committee members
thank you for convening this hearing on
and your leadership on this very
important issue
I am going to cut some of my remarks so
in light of the time again my name is
Herman J Kapur on the senior assistant
attorney general for the cannabis
Control section in the office of the
Attorney General this is one of the
newest sections in the office and I want
to just give you a little bit of
background on what this section was
about to do the section was formed by
attorney general visera in 2018 we
represent the licensing agencies the
Bureau of cannabis control California
Department of Food and Agriculture
Department of Public Health in civil and
administrative matters we also work with
informs enforcement agencies such as the
California Highway Patrol the Department
of Fish and Wildlife State Water and
represent them in their cannabis
enforcement activities we also provide
guidance to a number of state agencies
including the Department of Consumer
Affairs the cannabis Enforcement Unit we
also advise the Attorney General on
matters impacting legal commercial
cannabis operations in California
recently the Attorney General supported
us actually he continues to support a
strong regulated market and with this in
mind AG Becerra recently signed on to
several letters in support of federal
legislation namely the safe Banking Act
and the States Act in addition
provided support for comment for FDA to
engage in research on CBD and other
cannabis related products you've heard
all about the regulations so I won't go
into that except to say that California
does have a comprehensive regulation of
cannabis cannabis products in cannabis
sales now to reiterate California has
some of the most rigorous standards for
testing cannabis and cannabis products
that are sold in the regulated
marketplace in this state unfortunately
we still have a very large unregulated
and illegal market and they sell they
continue to solve products in the state
that are of an unknown origin and have
not been tested I again will not repeat
the CDC information that you've heard
several times except to say that we need
to keep in mind that the CDC has been
unable to link the outbreak to a single
product or substance
however we will acknowledge that most of
the patients reported a history of using
THC containing products fewer reported
nicotine only products but the CDC also
reports that the patients reported that
they didn't purchase the C THC products
from licensed regulated marketplaces
they obtained them from other sources it
might have been friends family members
no one knows where they came from so as
you all know Proposition 64 resulted in
the reduction of many offenses as making
them infractions or misdemeanors
so when it comes to regulating the
unlicensed marketplace it's become a
little difficult for prosecutors and law
enforcement to pursue these cases as you
also know several sections of the Health
and Safety Code reduced crimes to
infractions and misdemeanors there
really aren't too many felonies except
maybe sale to minors if you can attach a
felony to another offense fraud
environmental impact
you have more weight to pursue a
prosecution legislature also included in
my cursor business and profession code
to 6:03 8 which allows civil penalties
of up to three times the amount of the
license fee for each violation of
unlicensed commercial activity and most
recently as part of the trailer bill you
added a Code section business and
Professions Code section two six zero
three one point five which also permits
a licensing authority to issue citations
to licensed or unlicensed operators the
citation can include an order of
abatement and/or administrative fines
not to exceed $5,000 per violation for a
licensee and $30,000 per violation for
an unwise person again each day of
violation constitutes a separate
violation by recent estimates 80% of the
cannabis industry in California remains
unlicensed and unregulated we are now 22
months into licensing those businesses
we could argue that intended to come
into the legal regulated market have
already done so or are in the process of
doing so by having obtained provisional
licenses submitted annual license
applications and/or submitted
applications to local jurisdictions
based on the volume of illegal
businesses continuing to operate in
California any meaningful enforcement
requires sufficient resources and
coordination of efforts in the past
several weeks we have heard from law
enforcement offices from throughout the
state what we've heard is where
enforcement does take place it is
questionable as to what impact it is
having due to the limited ability of
prosecutors to take meaningful action
against those in the illegal unregulated
market place again currently violations
of the law that are only based on
cannabis violations are generally
infractions or misdemeanors for an
unlegal unregulated business earning
potentially thousands of
as mr. medoras also indicated those
spines may be viewed as the cost of
doing business and might not have any
impact on deterring continued
participation in the illegal unregulated
marketplace in many instances retail
pop-up shops are shut down one day and
reappear the next day several doors away
in one recent meeting with law
enforcement representatives this was
described playing whack-a-mole
so while providing licensing agencies
with enforcement tools there remains a
gap for meaningful enforcement criminal
again the criminal penalties being
infractions and misdemeanors for
unlicensed again I want to focus on
unlicensed only it's not having an
effect the Attorney General supports
both a strong regulated cannabis market
and efforts to ensure the success for
the legal marketplace in California and
we welcome the opportunity to further
discuss how this can be done thank you
very much thank you very much appreciate
the comments that were given and then
we'll get into comments and questions
from members of the joint committee and
just as a reminder to committee members
that we still have an additional panel
as well as a public comment so we'll
first begin with dr. wood thank you very
much to all of you appreciate appreciate
the information and I can sense that you
are all somewhat overwhelmed by the
enormity of the challenges that we face
I did hear miss H actually talked you
said that you were actively working with
manufacturers and retailers and so on I
didn't hear deliveries are you enforcing
against delivery drivers and illicit
delivery operations as well yeah when we
talk about retailers we yes there's a
huge number of unlicensed deliveries and
that and I do wonder where they're
getting their products because there's
no storefront to trace it back to in
many cases
with regard to the and I know you can't
talk about because you punched thing and
so I'm not going there but it does make
me wonder how many other operations are
out there so when you guys are shutting
down illicit operations are you testing
any of the products that come out of
those stores to see are those products
in line with current standards I would
guess that they're not and I would I
kind of well I would think like to think
not I kind of wonder how many more cushy
punches there are out there quite
frankly with the value of product that
may not pass testing and needing an
outlet to recoup their the the money
that goes with that so a little
frustrating that we don't have much in
the way of enforcement tools it sounds
like to other than citations and
misdemeanors which are hardly even a
slap on the wrist it feels like so that
was more of an editorial comment but if
you haven't obviously if you have any
comment on that so depending on the you
know we get many complaints on
unlicensed activity and now especially
with all the media surrounding the the
vaping crisis we get a lot of complaints
so we work together with the Department
of Public Health and if we feel
something needs to be tested we are
working in partnership with them to have
that product tested okay with regards to
those are mr. Maduro us from CDT FA so
as we talked about the taxation taxation
those are also sort of a slap on the
wrist as well I thought I thought people
in general kind of afraid about the tax
collectors and informers so I know I am
I'm very careful about my returns and
things but I got the impression it feels
like that maybe some people aren't nice
in some of these industries I think
that's right I I too if somebody
threatened me with a misdemeanor as a
nerdy middle-aged fellow would be afraid
but alas those people earning lots of
money in the illegal cannabis market
don't seem afraid and that and the tie
here to the vaping in my
mind is that you know I would the
products that are being sold that are
untaxed are also untested right and
that's the real I just want to make sure
I think that's I think that's that's the
key and I do think in my mind it is both
the criminal sanctions but to bring a
criminal case take so long and it's
really difficult when we're got
thousands of these in my mind what needs
to happen is there needs there need to
be civil penalties or tax penalties that
are allowed to be put on very quickly
and if if they're put on in air people
can appeal but I I just think that even
going to a felony is not going to
address the scope of the problem because
it will take so long to get through the
number of illegal operators that we're
seeing out there we are trying all sorts
of ways in the tax realm including
assessing taxes and telling people you
know we've you won't give us your
records we've determined that you owe
the state a million and a half dollars
and we'll take your house and all of
your possessions and everything else
because we are trying to figure out what
the best way to I mean a they do owe the
money to the state but we need to figure
out what the best way to proceed is and
I'm not sure that what we've always done
is what will work in this situation so
sounds like you have a pretty big tool
belt but not a lot of tools that's one
way to put it
thinking a lot along these lines is and
this is more of a question for the
attorney general's office because and
linking this to vaping which is really
what this is about but this is bringing
up some other issues that have concern I
think the Chairman gray and I were
commenting to get together 22 months
into this and we have 80% of the market
unlicensed is pretty appalling and it's
and I would imagine for those people in
the licensed market it's pretty it's
pretty frustrating extremely frustrating
to know that they're playing by the
rules and we've got this and I
understand it and it feels like all of
you have tool belts and not enough tools
and none of resources to buy the tools
and so on so it is a challenge so I want
to ask a question and and I don't know
the answer and and so but I am curious
and I don't know what how this equates
in the rest of the world so I'm gonna
ask that same question if we were to
find that there was an entity or someone
who was adding something to the vaping
liquids that was causing this outbreak
that has caused great bodily harm and
death in some cases we've decriminalized
so much around cannabis
what would the recourse for the AG be
would there how would you prosecute that
case or would you be able to prosecute
it based on with the rule the laws under
Prop 64 I don't know the answer I'm just
i but I'm curious the reason I say that
I would bet that if you were growing
lettuce or spinach somewhere and you did
something and you added something there
and people died across the United States
you'd be pretty responsible for that and
a whole number of ways
so is this industry going to be this
have the same level of responsibility as
the lettuce industry or the spinach
industry or Tylenol or anything else out
there but because they've added a
product to something
cause great bodily harm and death well
as I indicated if you can attach a
cannabis violation to something else can
it becomes a felony so I think in the
case of a death you can attach it to a
different law that would create a felony
violation it wouldn't just be a you know
a manufacturing cannabis violation
anymore it would be something more than
that so there would be recourse if
somebody is some if some entities or
whatever we're found to be adding
something that caused this
whether knowingly or unknowingly I mean
creating a public health hazard well I
think you would differentiate between
knowingly or Anna unknowingly as
obviously they know they're adding it
but I don't know the consequences so
yeah other would be consequences
absolutely okay just like there would be
for lettuce growers well or or you know
a cultivator who uses deadly pesticides
and cultivation you can attach it to
environmental harm or some other felony
crime and pursue it that way
art art is the are there cases being
pursued where with cultivators who are
using banned pesticides and that have
been caught because now you've linked
those things are those other cases
actually being being prosecuted now or
or charged or or are those misdemeanors
well my office is renewing several cases
I really can't comment on what we will
end up charging but we are as I said we
do work in conjunction with state water
and Department of Fish and Wildlife and
because those are environmental those
are different laws and people have to
correct they have water codes you can
attach
okay all right Thank You mr. great Thank
You chairman lo I'm gonna do my best to
condense some of these questions and I
may provide some questions to the panel
in writing post committee because
there's a lot I want to get into and I
know in the interest of time I'll try
get to the the key points as I see them
I'm going to start over here with the
part of the public health during our
process of constructing a B 1639 which
is legislation myself and several my
colleagues and certainly members of
committee worked on we brought in the
partner public health and we brought in
ABC and talked about what sting
operations and enforcement activities
were occurring when the ABC came in it
was 35 40 45 thousand sting operations
they're actively actively involved in
when DPH came in they said we don't know
and they told me all were issuing grants
to look law enforcement asked how much
money it was it didn't seem significant
my impression that I'm left with the
Department of Health is not doing much
for enforcement in the area tobacco
throughout the state and the frankly the
grants were given to local law
enforcement aren't very enticing for
local law enforcement to get involved in
what's your response to my impression oh
we have about 4,000 visits to retailers
every year
of those in 2018 we had 340 first-time
violations which ended up in suspension
of license as 10 second time violators
and one third time violator at the local
level we really do more of the training
of law enforcement of how what they
would do I don't have information about
what specifically the number of local
law enforcement visits but I can try and
get that for you well certainly I think
we need if you don't need to find out
and we need to give you the tools either
to find and to conduct more sting
operations
it's again we don't need to reinvent the
wheel we know that what we do in the
area of alcohols been fairly effective
law enforcement knows how to do this I
think part of the problem is that we
have the enforcement any non law
enforcement agency but nonetheless I
think we make some improvement there but
it'll be happy to work with you and I'd
like some feedback when I provide the
legislation and approaches we're taking
secondly actually I think you may have
answered that how many licenses were
removed there were no licenses removed
there was one that could have been
removed except that the business shut
down so there's no license removed right
okay from the state level I don't know
about that the local level I understood
I'm gonna move on now to Bureau of
cannabis control I want to begin with
the flavor issue I recently visited a
dispensary to take a look at a
dispensary from a flavor viewpoint and
I'm gonna go ahead and read you some of
the flavors that were displaying on the
board of marijuana banana split
blueberry milkshake wedding cake ice
cream cake key lime pie purple punch
peanut butter breath so I'm curious as
to your perspective given that flavors
are a major concern for some of my
colleagues as it relates to e-cigarettes
what's the perspective on these flavors
if each cigarette flavors are driving
teenage consumption and an underage
consumption that I would assume that is
true with marijuana but are there no
restrictions so a lot of those could be
also strained names that they use it's
not always necessarily flavors they do
have
cannabis terpenes but most of the time
what we see those are strain names and
so we do look at especially from the
Department of Public Health side
you know any packaging can't be
attractive to children they can't
advertise to children but for most of
these those would be cannabis flour
we're talking about
and so restrictions on packaging again
would be still it can't be attractive to
children now what whether or not those
names represent a flavor or a strain I
think as far as we're talking about
marketing the name of a product is in
fact marketing and those certainly at
least strike me at first blush and I'm
going to try to learn more about this as
directed towards young people or perhaps
perhaps not maybe the flavors aren't the
key issue I'm certainly open to that
we've been debating that all year long
how many cannabis licenses have been
suspended or removed this past 22 months
so most of our licenses at the bureau
are provisional licenses so we issue we
issue a variety of disciplinary we can
given if we go into a retail inspection
and we find violations we can issue a
notice of comply we can also suspend or
we can also revoke we we've we've done
some suspensions like for example for
sales to minor that we had with delivery
of a licensed retailer most of the time
we are trying to get our retailers or
any of our licensees to comply with our
regulations if there's there's a public
safety issue then we will revoke the
license or in some cases the licensee
will cancel their license or whatnot so
we've had several of those I don't have
the exact numbers but I can certainly
provide those to you thank you and how
many sting operations have been
conducted on underage purchases
so that's handled by the sworn law
enforcement part of the bureau under the
cannabis enforcement unit at the
Department of Consumer Affairs and I
could certainly get those for you too as
well okay well wait for those answers
and we'll have some follow-up Department
tax and fee Administration I had the
opportunity as a young staff legislative
staffer in this building to work on the
tax stamp program working with
then-governor organization cher Jerome
Horton and my understanding hadn't
followed that program over the years is
that it's been pretty effective in
addressing black market sales of tobacco
products and I want to get your take on
it I think it has been effective in in
cigarettes which is all it applies to in
addressing black market sales that's and
that kind of takes me to my next
question which is in a in our bill that
we've been working on we've been trying
to move in the direction of a tax stamp
program for vaping products or
e-cigarette products knowing that it was
effective in dealing with the black
market risk was back up one would assume
we could accomplish the same thing with
these cigarettes do you see what hurdles
challenges tools are needed in order to
accomplish that well I don't think we
could just sort of lift and shift the
same tax stamping regimen that we have
there into vaping for a few reasons one
cigarettes are all taxed to two dollars
and 87 cents per pack the tax on other
tobacco products is based on this
wholesale cost calculation so it's not
you couldn't sell just a single value
stamp and say that that's your stamp for
every product if you wanted to be an
actual tax stamp the other issue is that
the packaging on these other products
the size the number of items contained
is also not the same with cigarettes
every single pack is twenty cigarettes
and there are machines that are
developed that open the boxes and stamp
everything and it becomes very efficient
that said
the in my mind one of the major things
that could be addressed here is tracing
where the product came from and ensuring
that it's tax paid and ensuring that
it's not a counterfeit product and those
could be achieved with with a stamp that
is required that is not necessarily a
stamp that the distributor buys from us
for a certain tax amount although that's
possible but you would have to have
varying values so it is a little bit
more complicated but I do think and this
is one of the things that the governor's
asked us to look at that we'll be
reporting out to him later this month on
that that it's possible to design a
system that would accomplish that I will
also say that I believe that initial
getting the cigarette tax step up and
running took I think three years which
is a long time I'd also like to come up
with something that we could do more
quickly those are the same issues we
were struggling with and maybe 1639 was
trying to figure out how to fast-track
the tax stamp program as it relates
although funny enough the the issue that
stalled our legislation in the state
Senate this year was in fact the issue
you raised on equivalency and I bluest
language in early August that attempted
to create a more equivalent tax between
traditional tobacco sticks that we were
going to put into a B 1639 when the
Senate found out about that the Senate
Rules Committee refused to grant us a
hearing on the legislation as they
didn't want to address a attacks at this
time but we're gonna be coming back
first thing in the year to still work on
that issue and I'm gonna provide you the
language that we have to get your
feedback I'd also like some additional
feedback on the issues you raised about
non-compliance with taxes and how we
might assist in amping up the penalties
I know chairman would raise that and I
think that's something we'd all like to
have some potential solutions on
you know that certainly can be a very
effective method of addressing black
market activities we'd be happy to
provide you any assistance we can and
you'll take a look at the equivalency
tax that I proposed in August and see if
see if that meets the mark yes okay
Department of Justice I think that
concerns me the most I've got about six
questions here but the thing that you
raised on the inconsistencies you know
in the way we're treating as different
products and the and the penalties and
tools available to you to enforce right
and and how that was as I understood it
made further difficult by some of the
criminal justice reforms that this body
in this state have enacted in the past
you know decade is that an accurate
depiction of what you said yes excellent
so I'd like to see some recommendations
from the DOJ and from our Attorney
General on what steps the legislature
can take to give you those tools so as
to have proper enforcement I think many
of my colleagues will be interested in
that as well
with that I will do my follow-up with
all of you and provide you the draft
language that we have prepared that's
going to be a consistent approach to
vaping tobacco and marijuana as well as
enforcement you know I think I think we
have the know-how you may not all have
all the tools you need but we need to
know what those tools that are missing
or and then we need to get a consistent
approach to all of these products
because what we're doing now is you know
there's certain legislators in this
building who are you know with one hand
banning flavored tobacco and with
another hand encouraging us to smoke
marijuana and moving vehicles we need to
get a more consistent policy here
there's some real intellectual
dishonesty with what we're doing in this
area
and I think we need your assistance and
I think a lot of issues have been raised
here today that don't make a lot of
sense and we need to get on the same
page so thank you for your testimony
I'll turn it back to chairman love thank
you very much it's great next up mr.
McCarthy followed by mr. Cooper I think
in the interest of time I'd prefer
getting to the next panel Public Health
Officer oh great thank you very much mr.
Cooper I view mr. gray this body's
consistent at being inconsistent
really the penalties mean nothing so
we're talking about the misdemeanor
$5,000 fine that's the same as someone
breaking window someone's window or
doing a lawn job it's a misdemeanor no
one's going to jail the County Jail to
spend any time for misdemeanor and by
time is plea bargain in court it final
be $1,000 or $500 that's a real that's a
real reality so why not do it I mean you
have a lot of good businesses that are
following the law and that are
productive businesses we have that ban
element to we've got to deal with and
just like cushy punch they had one foot
in there legal and one foot in the black
market
and we try to deal with that all the
time we know that 60% of marijuana in
California goes out of state grow houses
Sacramento's grow house central in the
entire country so what's what's
frustrating for law enforcement they'll
do a power search warrant because of
power usage hit the house deal with
electricity where it's Muhtar PG&amp;E will
and they'll leave the marijuana in the
house so he's leaving thousands and
thousands of plants that are out there
and those plants make it back into the
black market so so how do we change that
I had a bill in 17 that would have
addressed this it did with civil funding
for the state agencies and help the
cities develop legitimate cannabis
businesses that bill was gonna die in
public safety because you can't get any
of these bills that IV public safety
neither house that's really what it
comes down to and it's crazy some of the
things that go on with this it's a big
issue so we shouldn't sell the baby out
with the bathwater
but how do we do it these folks that are
the black market you find them and
punish them because it last
administration said hey we're not
signing any law that puts anybody in
jail or prison we've got a new governor
I'm excited about him and I want to
thank him for like his team to come out
here and work with law enforcement to
try and figure out how they can solve
this problem and how to attack it so
he's he's been collaborative and
hopefully we'll see more big things from
the governor warning letters and
citations they don't care you're making
so much money I'm tucking the
black-market not illegal marking a black
market in the business to make money by
selling product and the more you make
the more you go so it's worth it for the
penalties there's nothing it's like no
harm no foul
why not keep going you're making tens of
thousand dollars every day why would you
stop that
but in this legislature right now
there's no penalties for anything they
don't want to ask that forfeiture and
some of these guys are making big big
money and you have to use asset
forfeiture less that you doesn't want to
do that so how do we change that how do
we get it done
hopefully the AG will come out and help
with some of that but I do have a
question for mister Medeiros on the let
me see I'll tell you what the issue is
excuse me
as far as the open vape system that goes
untaxed how do we change that well for
the non tobacco element of the vape I
one could change the definition of
tobacco products to include that those
other liquids or if you went to nicotine
based tax then whatever the nicotine can
portion is would be taxed it presumably
a fairly robust rate and so if you mixed
it it wouldn't make any difference
because you were just taxing that
nicotine portion but not at this same
calculation that we're using currently
and for Miss Ajax in your opinion how
bad is the cannabis black-market
impacting legitimate cannabis business
well it's probably it's a number one
complaint that we get the complaints
coming into the bureau is the unlicensed
market and how its directly competing
with our licensees and I think we all
agree with you that enforcement is a top
priority and
you all work here together very well to
combat that and partner together to make
sure we're attacking the illegal market
but it there there there it is very
prevalent here
do you have sufficient resources I think
between all of us working together as a
state we have we do have substantial
resources I think we're still learning
the scope of the problem
and again we feel it's a top priority
one of the things that you've all of us
collaborate and it's not just the people
at this table it's with CDFA and local
law enforcement has been huge with
assisting us with some of these you know
serving these search warrants and but
what about your resources at BCC we have
resources you know we're still
sufficient we're still building our
structure uh-huh so well I'll cut you
off there I've never heard any
department head in my five years here
come forward and say no we don't have to
figure resources because we know who
their boss is so I get this you don't
want to diss your boss like I understand
that you want to be you want to be
politically correct but that's a big
issue you know I'll be honest with one
thing it's the state the pay sucks
sewing governor brown gut it being a
Bruin our clock enforcement there's a
lot of expertise here that has gone
that's been gone there is no expertise
with that sonar Cox is not something you
learned overnight
I spent 10 years there so it takes a
long time to develop the expertise so
most folks are in local agencies that
have that expertise so the state it's
tough to do that the pay sucks
and with pepra you know it's just very
different versions of cities and
counties so that's the tough part you
deal with it's finding the folks that
are capable that can do it so to me it
goes back to local law enforcement tap
those folks be an integral part of this
to deal with us they have the expertise
that need the funding there to make
these investigations and do them you
know we've got thousands of illegal
storefronts in LA with the right
resources they can do it and then also
changing it on the district when you get
it marijuana you run into marijuana
whatever flour whatever they call it do
destruction right away because the
reason law enforcement isn't seized
cannabis or flour or whatever is because
you have to store it and you get
thousands of plants to store in a
warehouse for a year or six months
whatever it's not feasible I spend law
enforcement doesn't take it versus
having an immediate destruction order
you destroy that and all the implements
associated with it and if you've got a
doctor's note that would leave you
you're 11 plants we're taking everything
else so it's got to change that until
this body gets off its butt
nothing's gonna change this whatsoever
it starts in a legislature and we can't
get a hit bill for a hearing in a damn
committee that's the problem that is a
problem
you have great bills that come through
that are reasonable not crazy stuff but
they don't want to hear it so that's
gonna happen in the committee so that's
really what it comes down to you know
[Music]
thank you very much mr. Cooper dr.
winter yeah just really breathe Leslie
thank you I know I feel like you you you
know sound harsh but I'm really
appreciate the work you're doing and I
feel like you probably feel like you're
swimming upstream all the time and and
you know we gave we gave the industry
tools to be come into compliance
we gave time for people to come into
compliance and it's frustrating that 80%
of the the industry has chosen not to do
that and that we don't have the tools to
enforce against that you know in in a
more expeditious way maybe that's the
right way to say it I don't I don't know
but it feels like it feels like it's
like whack-a-mole probably in in some
places and and you know it's unfair to
the folks that have gone through all the
hoops and to do it right so I thank you
for everything you you all are doing
appreciate it and before I get into any
final closing comments did any of the
five of you wish to share any
observations or responses to any of the
dialogue that was previously made on
this Dyess seeing none no okay I also
want to echo those comments and the deep
appreciation as a doctor would a number
of my colleagues on the work that you
are doing please interpret our comments
is saying that we want to best
understand how to best empower and equip
you with the tools necessary and the
resources necessary to better to do the
jobs
you know is important to do for the
largest regulated market in the world
arguably similarly along those lines
it's clear that you have all stated some
deficiencies in the areas of opportunity
and the lost opportunities that you have
had and would like to tell you to help
create a greater sense of urgency you've
talked about the lack of enforcement a
slap on the wrist comments like just in
normal modes of operating procedure for
many of these individuals but to come to
us and say this is what we are seeing
we need the authority the legislative
support to be able to tackle these
issues it's also clear to me that there
are a number of various entities that
oversee this of enforcement and with in
cannabis vaping alike we also talk about
local control and state position as well
perhaps my colleagues may also join me
in exploring then perhaps a
consolidation interdepartmental status
to make sure that we have a uniform
approach to some of these areas so we
have a sense of consistency
accountability and transparency so that
we can have a sense of how we are
tackling this all in one house as well -
so the efficiencies I think as mr.
Cooper also mentioned is very important
similarly I also want to make a point
that we oftentimes in this legislative
body have sought to try and address many
of these different issues in fact when
we talk about that of local control
cities saying that we want to maintain
local control when in fact I say again
cities are not in control there are
unlicensed dispensaries operating all
the time in many different places and so
when we then say let us help open up the
regulated market for a bill proposal on
commensurate licenses on ABC licenses in
cities that bill does not pass we also
saw a bill prohibiting delivery that
bill did not pass we saw a piece of
legislation to lower excise tax that did
not pass so we are attempting to do what
we can but what I think is going to be
helpful is if you help provide us the
specifics and saying the justification
is very clear which arguably I would
suggest and argue but it'll leave it to
public comment that is actually in
unison to that of what you're hearing
from indice
which is we regulated in the industry
that is represented in this audience
also say we want to join in lockstep we
are willing to pay our taxes we were
willing to pay our fees we know who the
bad actors are we want to be in the
regulated market but they feel like they
are not surviving and not only is that
that individuals are dying as we've all
know but small business owners are also
dying so there needs to be a greater
sense of urgency
so we implore you to help create that
sense of urgency for us because we want
to work within the state budgets help
give you more tools and resources and
people we also want to change the
legislations help empower you so that
you can go after the bad actors alike
and then also message very clear to the
administration that this is an
informational hearing that has engaged
with broad public support of all
stakeholders so that when you see pieces
of legislation that comes from us this
is getting the administration involved
and stakeholders alike so again we want
to work hand-in-hand with each and every
one of you and you provide us some good
tools and recommendations alike but
again we need to create a greater sense
of urgency for this because this is of
immense importance to not only public
health but the future that will
transcend the long before long after we
will we will be here respectively in
these chairs too so again deep
appreciation for all of your commitment
and we look forward to continuing
working with you again thank you Thank
You chairman Lowe and thank you again to
the panel at this time we're going to
move to the final panel of the day what
are the health effects associated with
vaping and electronic cigarettes of what
more needs to be done we welcome dr.
charity Dean assistant director Acting
State Public Health Officer from the
Department of Public Health if you could
come up and present your testimony
please welcome
[Music]
good afternoon chairs and members I'm
dr. charity Dean acting state public
health officer at the California
Department of Public Health thank you
for allowing me to provide an update on
the vaping associated pulmonary injury
the current status of the VAP II
outbreak is alarming nationally there
have been 1299 cases and at least 26
deaths the National Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention reports 76% of
patient self-report using THC today new
data was posted on the California
Department of Public Health website CDP
HCA gov and I'm going to discuss it
we've had a hundred and thirty three
cases in California three deaths the
median age of cases has been 27 all of
those cases have been hospitalized of
those 43% required care in the intensive
care unit and 28% required mechanical
intubation 78 of those cases have been
interviewed this means that they
self-report to the person interviewing
them what they used and where they
obtained the product the cases report
vaping or dabbing mostly cannabis
products in waxes oils and other forms
of the 78 interviewed 81 percent
self-report using THC 38 percent use CBD
47 percent used nicotine most used a
combination of these and only 10 percent
reported using only nicotine there was
one case that did self-report purchasing
from a confirmed licensed retailer many
aspects of that are being investigated
and that investigation is still ongoing
the remaining cases whose self-reported
during the interview stated that they
had purchased their vaping products from
illicit street vendors pop-up shops
social contacts or unverified sellers
and by unverified sellers we mean
retailers that either could not be
located or could not be verified as
having a license there are multiple
patterns of lung injury which are
emerging based on the medical findings
from tissue biopsies autopsies and blood
work many of these are now emerging in
published literature I'm going to list a
few that you may have heard of in the
media exogenously Boyd pneumonia the
theory behind that was that inhaling
vaporized oils can cause this clinical
syndrome that can be seen on some of the
clinical specimens like lung washings
chemical pneumonitis or chemical
inhalation injury acute asana philic
pneumonia bronchiolitis obliterans
diffuse alveolar damage diffuse alveolar
hemorrhage all of these involve acute
lung injury and inflammation so you can
see that there are now a number of
different clinical syndromes that are
emerging not just one the challenge
there is that multiple patterns of lung
injury suggest multiple mechanisms which
in turn suggest that there may be
multiple different causes different
chemicals leading to this not just one
extensive laboratory testing is being
done nationally there are published and
anecdotal reports from labs at the
federal and state level all of them
agree that at this point there is no
single device substance product or
device type that has been identified as
the cause of the outbreak
vitamin E acetate has been recovered
from some products but not all the
California Department of Public Health
received 146 cartridges or pods which
were voluntarily surrendered by patients
and the extensive testing is ongoing
there are many unknowns when I would
highlight is the unknown of what happens
when you mix chemicals together heat
that mixture and aerosolize it which may
create new
toxic compounds The effect of which on
the lung tissue is unknown another
unknown our variables intrinsic in the
devices themselves heating elements
batteries refillable cartridge
and medals and again the combination of
these with heat may be creating unknown
substances that we don't even know to
test for the California Department of
Public Health has had a robust response
to this outbreak the medical and Health
Coordination Center was activated in
August it is now activated at level two
we have issued three Cahan alerts
statewide multiple health advisories
including to the public and to
healthcare professionals we issued a
press release and have been very
responsive to media inquiries from the
beginning from August from the first day
we've collaborated with our national
partners at the federal level with the
CDC with other states that were
reporting clusters with our local health
jurisdictions and with providers in
California across our department
multiple centers have been involved they
have all come together to offer staff
and expertise to respond I especially
want to mention the work of our state
public health laboratories where it's
been a team effort
to synthesize and test various chemical
hypotheses description of the emerging
clinical syndrome includes respiratory
symptoms such as cough or nests of
breath chest pain and GI symptoms
including abdominal pain nausea vomiting
diarrhea but it also includes fever
fatigue and weakness patients present
with low oxygen levels which is why many
of them need to be in the intensive care
unit with supplemental oxygen they have
an abnormal chest x-ray many have an
abnormal CT scan as well showing
bilateral and filtrates on both sides of
their lungs not just one the unknown or
I'm sorry the long term health effects
are unknown because this is an emerging
clinical syndrome we're looking very
carefully at what's happening right now
but what happens when these patients
leave the hospital how quick is their
recovery
will they have lifelong adverse health
effects on their lungs we don't know
that yet one of the challenges is this
is a diagnosis of exclusion which is why
I mentioned this symptoms in order to
make the diagnosis of a
PK's you have to first rule out
infectious causes or other plausible
causes this will be a challenge during
upcoming influenza season so how do we
find the cause the public health
approach to this as it is to many other
outbreaks is a combination of examining
the epidemiology data the clinical
syndrome the course of illness in the
patient the patient's clinical specimens
and of course the laboratory analysis of
the vaping products themselves and it
will be that information dovetailing
together that will get us closer to an
answer it could take years for the
medical and scientific community to
definitively determine what the causes
are public health recommendations for
the public are important and we've been
sharing them in our publicly shared a
press release and health alerts number
one we recommend that the public refrain
from vaping no matter the source there
is always a risk when you inhale a
foreign substance into your lungs and
the risk of vaping now includes death it
can be difficult for consumers to
distinguish between regulated and
unregulated products considering there
are counterfeit labels that can be very
deceptive number two for those who
choose to vape only purchase from a
verified licensed retailer number three
for someone who has recently vaped and
is experiencing some of these symptoms
they should seek care immediately and
they need to share their honest and
thorough vaping history and products
used with that provider and number four
if you stop vaping do not switch to
cigarettes
instead please consider using an FDA
approved quitting treatment that
concludes my remarks thank you for
allowing me to come today and I'll take
any questions you might have
thank you doctor at this time we'll
bring it back to the committee for any
questions comments
dr. yes first of all thank you very much
and I've we've even I've been thinking
about the challenges as we do in our
cold and flu season and how how you
distinguish that and the complications
that may arise from a person who does
have the cold or the flu and how much
one plus one might equal three and
that's not a good thing in this case so
appreciate your your comments around
that people that are self reporting are
they volunteering the product that
they've used if there's any residual
left for for testing as that is that and
and how many people are actually doing
that or is it or is it consumed and all
gone before they get to you sure some
patients are voluntarily turning over
the product and they're vaping device
and those are sent to the California
Department of Public Health to conduct
testing and and so all the result the
results are it takes a while to do that
obviously so it's been a very complex
analysis and we are looking at some of
those results but it really is in the
beginning stages of a comprehensive
laboratory analysis considering how many
chemicals have to be tested for thank
you first of all thank your testimony
when we first contact the department and
looked into at that time the reported
cases my recollection was sixty-two out
of 63 cases were reported THC with one
case unknown and I heard you said
earlier 81 percent THC so have there
been more cases has that has that
information changed since I last spoke
with the department sure I can't
remember that exact week because the
data is changing so rapidly but yes you
are correct right now
81 percent of the cases self-report
using THC the nuance is that many of the
cases are combining the THC with CBD and
with nicotine and so if you're to add up
the percentages that we the data that we
published on our website today you'll
see it doesn't add to a hundred percent
because many of them are combining the
substances together and in the media
reports of lung illnesses have at least
it's been suggested linked to
black-market products and we've had a
lot of sketching about that today have
there been any cases of lung illness or
death for that matter who have used
legal cannabis products exclusively I
can only speak to the data that we have
for California of the 78 cases who were
interviewed in California there was only
one case whose self reported exclusively
purchasing from licensed retailers and
it's important to note that when we do
these epidemiology interviews for any
outbreak we're asking patients to use
their best recollection and self-report
to the interviewer and so we look at
every aspect of that and that's still
being investigated but that was only one
case that's off reported exclusively
legal retailers everyone else we can
assume based on their self-report
non-legal products or at least some non
illegal products that's correct
the rest whose self-reported even the
ones who may have mentioned a
brick-and-mortar location those were not
able to be found or not able to be
verified as licensed and how many of
them report exclusively using nicotine
vaping products and no THC or marijuana
products only 10% of the 78 who were
interviewed okay I asked my staff to do
a little research it struck me as odd
vaping is not a activity that only
occurs here in the United States but yet
I've heard nothing or read nothing about
death illness etc due to vaping outside
of the United States can you speak to
that all have you seen any evidence or
reports worldwide there have been a
handful of cases reported in Canada I'm
not aware of these clusters or outbreak
emerging in other countries does that
strike you as odd it strikes me as
interesting and as we look at all the
possible causes in the United States
including our epi data our patients that
the clinical labs that's something that
we're being were looking at what changed
and why now thank you for your time and
appreciate the answers just a quick
follow-up and I appreciate your line of
questioning there so I think it's I
think it's really valuable we said
someone reported we had one person
report that they had purchased from a
licensed regulated cannabis facility was
that verified that that indeed was a
licensed facility or was that the
patient's recollection because they
thought it was a licensed facility that
investigation is still ongoing I'll I'll
tell you that we share we as public
health when we get those reports from
patients that were interviewed we share
them with BCC so that they can be
investigated in that one case the
facility the brick-and-mortar location
that was mentioned was confirmed to be
licensed but aspects of that are still
being investigated
Thank You mr. Lowe thank you very much
appreciate that the comments that you
made and if I remembered correctly you
had indicated that the data is still
inconclusive but that you are very much
looking to the distinction on what has
been recently introduced and that when
there is a conclusion and to hopefully
finding the culprit that that
information will be readily available
but for members of the public when that
time comes to which then given your
research that you do find conclusive
evidence of where the culprit is what
then transpires so that we can ensure
that consumers will be protected does
that come from executive order does that
come from the administration then
working with the legislature how do you
see that happening I think that would
depend on what the culprit was it's not
clear that it's just the substance or
just the device it could even be a
combination of them so it seems that the
ability to stop the outbreak and and
remove the culprit substance or device
will depend on what it is right now a
number of hypotheses are being looked at
everything's on the table sure and so if
given any of those combinations and that
is the conclusion to which is causing
harm and death within transpires then do
we see the administration an executive
order does that in the legislation you
come to the legislature saying okay
here's what it is please pass the
legislation how do you see do you have a
sense on how that would then my sense is
that if we knew what was causing this
that swift action would be taken and all
options would be considered thank you
mr. Rivas and so that's a you know a
great question and certainly you know so
based on what you mentioned you know I
find it startling that this could take
years to find out what the culprit is
but based on where we are now it seems
like this is obviously an evolving issue
as you mentioned the data seems to be
changing and every state is handling
this crisis as it is from day to day in
their own way we as a state based on the
executive order that the governor signed
is that enough
is is that response enough for our state
with this crisis moving forward many
options are being considered to respond
to this crisis the recommendations in
response to the executive order are
still being finalized but many options
are on the table including swift actions
thorough options to address the outbreak
and the youth vaping epidemic even
though these are distinct issues the
outbreak of vaping lung injury and the
youth vaping epidemic they are related
there is some crossovers I think dr.
wood had pointed out at the beginning
and so the recommendations being
considered take a broad approach and
everything's on the table mr Wood yeah
finally finally thank you thank you is
the more I said you know the more we
hear the more you questions you come up
with but considering that actually
vaping has been around for a while and
not just nicotine but also cannabis does
it not surprise you that suddenly this
is happening this this this just feels
like this is isolated to something
because there have been other things you
know we go back to several years ago and
the cannabis industry that's there
Nathan's been going on for a while
certainly with nicotine has been going
on for a while but all of a sudden
whoosh there's something something's not
right and does is that that obviously is
is unusual does that does that surprise
you in some way yes and as we discuss
this with other states who were facing a
similar outbreak situation since August
that question emerged the increase in
cases that we're seeing is it an
artifact of us looking for them had they
been there all along
I believe in California the answer is no
that this is something new that we're
seeing that we haven't seen before we
don't know the cause yet so we don't
know why but we're looking at multiple
theories and asking what changed to
caused this spike in cases there are
reports in the literature
reporting similar vaping lung injury
cases from before August of 2019 but not
even close to the number that we're
seeing now that kind of brings me back
to that vitamin he asked it you
mentioned that wasn't an ingredient not
found in all cases but what do we know
about the effects of inhaling vitamin
aster I'm sorry the effects of what of
inhaling vitamin D estimate
do we know anything not a lot so one of
the challenges of investigating possible
culprits like vitamin E acetate is that
it's not just the substance itself so it
might be safe when ingested you can eat
it maybe it's a vitamin you know it's
something that we think may have health
benefits when eaten but when you heat it
up and you vaporize it and you'll inhale
it into the lung the effects that it has
on the lung tissue on the little air
sacs is unknown and so looking at each
culprit even as vitamin D acetate is
considered isn't just testing the actual
liquid itself it involves testing what
happens when it's vaporized our new
compounds created and then what happens
when it's inhaled into the lung what
does the tissue damage look like what do
the cells look like that's one of the
reasons why getting to the bottom of
this could take time because it could
involve Studies over a period of time
using animal models looking at a wide
range of toxins that are heated to the
point of being vaporized and then
inhaled into the lungs so I think your
original question was what is the effect
of vitamin E acetate a theory was that
that may have been what was causing the
lipoid pneumonia that is being examined
and studied and yet unknown
and my understanding is it's not it is
at this time a legal ingredient for
legal cannabis products is that correct
or is it in fact a banned ingredient
we're taking the action on that to your
knowledge on vitamin E acetate it's not
included in the list of things that
manufacturers must test for okay any
other questions comments before we make
her well and it is the back and forth
and it is it is making is one of the
challenges with when I'm supposed to be
specifically to the cannabis industry I
think is one of the challenges with this
industry there are things in the history
that have been used in the past that
were safe on other things I think
there's a there's a pesticide called
eagle 20 or some I may be saying it
wrong but was useful used on leafy
vegetables and other kinds of things and
it was safe but when you actually burned
it in Italy it it liberated cyanide so
that's obviously not safe and that was
not known by other people so because
we're not testing for it now through the
bureau there may be other things it
emerged vitamin D acetate on its own may
be perfectly safe but in this setting
may not and so it is particularly
challenging as people are some probably
experimenting quite frankly and adding
things to the products to enhance them
in some way but but this is this is not
an unusual occurrence or this this is an
isolated incident with this with the
industry and part of that is the
challenge of doing research and being
able to see what truly is safe and what
truly is a
I think I'm done thank you for your
testimony I think at this time we will
take any public comment
a few of us
[Music]
okay see we have significant interest in
public comment we're gonna ask you in
light of the length of the hearing here
to try to confine your comments to
around one minute thank you so much and
go ahead and begin name thank you so
much
I really really appreciate the
opportunity to talk with you today so
thank you to the chairs and the
committee my name is Lindsay Robinson
I'm the executive director of the
California cannabis Industry Association
we represent about 500 members across
the state and roughly 15,000 employees
the legal cannabis industry is extremely
concerned about the current vaping
issues as well as counterfeit products
flooding the illicit market we're
committed to building consumer safety
and confidence and our focus is on
Public Safety we look forward to a
continued partnership with the
regulator's the Newsome administration
and the legislature as you all know that
legal cannabis industry vigorously tests
all of its products the folks who are
members of CCI a and our part of the
legal industry have absolutely jumped
through all of the hoops to be compliant
and we're absolutely committed to
working with all of you our biggest fear
is that if we cut off access to legal
cannabis the illicit market thrives even
further which creates more risk to
public health so we appreciate the
opportunity to partner with you and be a
resource and thank you for this
opportunity thank you hi good afternoon
chairman gray and chairman wood and
committee members
my name is Tiffany debet I work with
cannon craft I had a bar consumer and
government affairs we're one of the
largest manufacturers in the state we've
done a lot of research on this issue it
is worth mentioning that California has
the most rigorous testing standards in
the country we did some comparative
testing of other products in California
and cannabis with regard to pesticides
is cleaner than chocolate milk it's
cleaner than wine it's cleaner than baby
food it looks as though this
beeping issues an issue with the illicit
market our message to you is that the
only way to stop the illnesses and
deaths that are happening is to help
consumers migrate from the illicit
market to the illicit market there are
three reasons why they're buying in the
black market they can't tell the
difference they don't want to pay three
times as much for the regulated product
or they don't have access to regulated
product so our what we had urged you to
do is to work on passing 1356 to expand
access to legal well tested well
regulated cannabis and look at some tax
reform thank you thank you for this
hearing my name is Dale Gehringer with
California normal I sponsored the first
published studies on cannabis
vaporization back in 2001 in 2003 which
demonstrated quite clearly that
vaporizers were very effective in
removing the toxins in marijuana smoke
and were really helpful as a smoke harm
reduction device since then a marijuana
vaporizers have come to be accepted as
the gold standard for administration in
medical studies however there are
vaporizers and there are vaporizers
there's been a lot of innovation
recently with new kinds of extracts
possible new chemicals and additives and
there is an issue about the hardware
which comes from China from many
different sources some of them more
reputable than others so I think we we
ought to investigate those things
however I have to i'm i consumers really
appreciate the availability of tested
high quality vaporizers on the market
now in california hope they stay there
and should a problem ever arise with one
of those
at least we'll be able to track it down
a whole lot better than this stuff
that's on the illicit market
Thank You Randa Martin here on behalf of
kaliba which is one of the largest
vertically integrated operations in the
state of California we appreciate the
emphasis today on enforcement we can
tell you from the perspective on the
ground is that enforcement resources may
be substantial but they are far from
sufficient we as the stakeholders and
you as the legislature have worked to
put more funds into the budget for the
last couple of years for more resources
for enforcement that was done in the
context of making it easier for legal
operators to continue to operate
successfully and also to make sure that
our tax resources were robust as as
projected but now it's taken a whole new
complete a kit on a whole new complexion
with this public health issue we really
need this coming budget cycle to amp up
our efforts to get more excuse me more
money into the budget for enforcement
purposes thank you hi I'm Ellen comp
with California normal I have an
opposite perspective a hundred years of
punitive actions against marijuana
sellers hasn't made our state safer the
only thing that will ever work is proper
reasonable regulation we thank Laurier
Jets and the BCC for enacting those
regulations in California keeping us
safe we supported the bills mr. Lowe
mentioned to address the problem of
two-thirds of California cities and
counties not licensing cannabis retailer
delivery to Larry and Kings County where
we have seen deaths due to this crisis
have no legal option available mr. gray
there was no bill to encourage cannabis
use by passengers in commercial vehicles
in California that was allowed for in
Cal in prop 64 as it is in Colorado
there was a bill to regulate those
vehicles which was sensationalized in
the press as allowing it now the
transportation bill has ensured that the
exemption for passengers and such
vehicles applies only to alcohol not
cannabis excessive alcohol use in
California is responsible for 10,000
deaths and 72,000 hospitalizations
annually the penalty in California
for illegal sales of firearms as far as
I can find is a misdemeanor with the one
thousand dollar fine there are 3500
deaths due to firearms annually in
California good afternoon chair and
members my name is jazzy gravel and I'm
here on behalf of UFCW western states
council UFCW represents thousands of
cannabis workers within the state we're
committed to ensuring the legal cannabis
industry continues to put consumer
safety first strong regulations and
strong enforcement are critical to
protecting consumers the California
Department of Public Health while
cautioning against vaping until more is
known about the root of these illnesses
has been cleared it's advice to
consumers illegal cannabis dispensaries
so unregulated and untested cannabis
products and should not be used one
thing we do know is that licensed
cannabis businesses continue to be the
safest option for consumers no cannabis
vaping products purchased at legal
cannabis businesses have been confirmed
linked to any of the recent health cases
reported in response to the outbreaks of
respiratory illness linked to vaping
it is imperative that California further
strengthen its enforcement efforts to
thwart the illicit market by identifying
closing the estimated 3,000 illegal
dispensaries operating in the state at
the same time state officials and
industry leaders must redouble their
commitment to ensuring a legal
marketplace in which consumers can
purchase cannabis products with
confidence on their safety thank you
good afternoon Lyn silver the Public
Health Institute dr. wood your former
county health officer how are you I'm
glad to see this hearing today this is
not just an issue of legal versus
illegal products this is a much deeper
problem if there is no single cause we
need to look at the forces that are
driving addiction initiation and heavy
use and thereby exposing people to
whatever hazards may be causing this
epidemic but also the many other more
serious health consequences well not
more serious than death obviously this
week for example I purchase stills e
granddaddy purp ass link a sleek pink
vaping device which I'll give you guys
resembling a memory stick with grape
flavor 78% THC
or 393 milligrams four times the maximum
THC dose for edible packages forty times
the maximum Canadian edible packages the
equivalent of 30 1990 joints furthermore
in just 0.02 ounces it is an invitation
to youth addiction legally marketed in
the state of California furthermore
recent studies demonstrate a five-fold
increase in psychosis risk with daily
use of cannabis products over ten
percent THC which is almost the entire
California regulated legal or illegal
market we need to address these issues
to successfully reverse both this
epidemic and negative health
consequences from cannabis I want to
make a couple of a few just very
concrete recommendations that I can
leave a written set of comments with you
we call for urgent common-sense action
from the state legislature and state
agencies to prevent even more serious
consequences first close the kitty
on-ramp of flavored products and sounds
like flavored products like the one
Assemblymember gray cited the banana the
this and that that may not be flavored
but certainly sound to a kid like they
are both for nicotine and for cannabis
second build on San Francisco and
Richmond's courageous initiatives and
suspends sales of vaping products a
until the e-cigarette industry proves
their safety to the FDA and for the case
of cannabis until we understand what is
going on with the vaping epidemic third
interrupt the addiction glidepath
created by products like this by
limiting the potency of THC products
allowed this will reduce youth addiction
to vaping lung disease psychosis
secondary to cannabis would Agua and
Quebec for example have already done
this fourth tell people the truth we
only have warnings in six point font on
packages today we need to have clear
prominent health warnings to consumers
in stores on products and on ads making
clear the recognized health risks from
cannabis including a dick
in low birthweight beeping the vaping
epidemic psychosis and so forth fifth
limit the marketing that kids and teens
are seeing every day for example even
the restriction on billboards that was
part of prop 64 was weakened by the
December regulations allowing some of
the spate of billboards were seeing all
across the state
do not allow marketing in restaurants
alcohol stores and other places where
kids go we bought a coffee cup in I
think was pizza or Starbucks that we
could go with a chill banner on the
coffee cup for example and establish a
scientific advisory board for cannabis
regulation that is free of conflicts of
interest that is essential to help guide
these processes with exemption the time
for action is now thank you very much
thank you for your comments let me
remind everybody we just experienced two
very long one-minute comments I actually
the committee's generally interested in
what you have to say to the degree to
which you could confine your comments to
a minute and then provide any written
testimony questions that Center to the
committee will certainly make sure
everybody sees us proceed good afternoon
chairman and members of the committee
Andres Ramirez on behalf of select moxie
and Cresco I want to thank you for
calling this informational hearing to
discuss this important topic
and thank the committee staff for all
their work through the leadership of
Cameron Forney the CEO of select we've
helped build a large coalition of 25
plus cannabis industry businesses to
come together and recommend five pillars
now we strongly believe would lead to an
effective and immediate impact on
illicit vaping products we've shared our
coalition recommendations with committee
staff and the five pillars include
addressing the illicit market enhancing
testing regulations certifying hardware
and facilities anti-counterfeiting
efforts and certified shipping we've had
many discussions and meetings with
governor Newsome's administration as
well as cannabis regulators and we
greatly appreciate their effort and
interest to work with us and discuss our
recommendations we're excited to partner
and work with the legislature
specifically your committees to ensure
that youth vaping epidemic is not only
reduced
that strong effective enforcement is
directed at eradicating illegal and
counterfeit vaping products in
California thank you thank you very much
thank you very much for the committee
for community today and having this
hearing if there's one message I would
like the committee to take away from
this is three words bans don't work my
name is Luis Hahn I'm a California
native and I have vetted thousands of
cannabis companies for the ArcView group
a nine year old investor network that
has invested more than two hundred and
sixty million dollars into the cannabis
industry a moratorium on all cannabis
vaping is not the answer
despite years of cannabis vaping
products being on the market we are only
hearing about these issues now this is
because this is a death rattle of
illegitimate producers who are using
fast and cheap methods in order to cling
on to the market share that they have
left a ban on cannabis vaping is the
exact response that they are looking for
because that will shut down their
legitimate competitors while allowing
them to continue to thrive bans will
only perpetuate this public health
crisis instead we should invest more
resources into enforcement and research
so I encourage our legislature to
consider these alternatives bans didn't
work for prohibition it didn't work for
the war on drugs and it won't work now
thank you thank you chair members Kathy
Mossberg with the American Heart
Association again like everyone want to
thank you for this hearing today want to
underscore some comments from the first
panel and talk about the epidemic we're
seeing in teen vaping we have been the
sponsors along with a number of public
health advocates in encouraging this
legislature and we hope to work with the
governor's office in banning sorry not
my best following the last gentleman but
banning the use or the sale of all
flavored ecig and and combustible
tobacco products we think this is the
way to go certainly we heard the
testimony that up into a point that the
ban has worked we have seen a decrease
in teen and youth use but that we left
out menthol so we do think that menthol
and mint need to be a part of this band
so we encourage we want to work with the
legislature these committees and we
encourage you to work on that this next
upcoming session thank you
just to clarify your comments there did
you include you said a band
THC and tobacco we have not we do not
have a position on cannabis at this
point we are looking into that but that
is an area that we haven't looked at
before we have been focused on on vaping
and e-cigs as well as men of
combustibles okay thank you
good afternoon Darya makrooh on behalf
of the California Dental Association
thank you for the attention there's
clearly several complex issues at play
here separating out the discussion of
flavors and the discussion of cannabis
and the some of the issues that could be
used to address the vaping related
illness CDA is supportive of multi prong
approaches that address all of these
through separate policy issues including
a ban on flavors thank you thank you
good afternoon Laura del Castillo with
Eden enterprises which is a fully
licensed vertically integrated cannabis
company that includes manufacturing vape
products which are rigorously tested as
you've heard today I would just like to
echo some of the comments I've been
hearing which is that yes the public
health issue is very important and
should be addressed in a smart and
effective way
not with reactionary bans but with
thorough research public education and
really getting to the root of the
problem which we've heard is directly
connected to the illicit market created
through prohibition and lack of
enforcement that being said and I agree
with others that this issue is being
somewhat conflated with the youth vaping
and the attractive flavors but if the
state and other local municipalities are
considering a flavor ban I would that
would extend to cannabis I would
encourage you to carefully consider and
make clear the definition of flavor
which should focus on artificial flavors
rather than naturally-occurring terpenes
thank you thank you hello Alicia Priya
go on behalf of the California cannabis
Manufacturers Association we also stand
ready to work with and be a resource for
the legislature and the
regulatory agencies as covered
exhaustively today this is a youth and
illicit market issue we are also looking
at best practices and have seen in
Europe that they have a very vigorous
education effort on the use of vaping
devices and hardware and also limit
nicotine content and other ingredients
inside the devices and notably do not
have the same issues that we're
experiencing here and lastly the notable
absence of reports and in cases arising
from legal regulated outlets speaks
strongly to the effectiveness of
controlled access and regulation thank
you thank you good afternoon chairman
gray chairman would Aimee Jenkins here
on behalf of to cannabis operators bloom
farms and Sunday Goods both
manufacturers of inhalable products
licensed compliant entities that are
subject to all the rigorous testing
standards and I want to echo the
comments made by cata craftsy CIA and
ArcView bands just simply will not work
in this situation and the linkages with
compliant products is just simply not
there at this point in time both bloom
Farms and Sunday Goods is committed to
continuing to partner with this
legislature and our associations I've
never seen so many groups coalescing and
working together to try to resolve this
issue we want to continue to be partners
a couple last minute comments illicit
market and we need more enforcement
dollars and we've been trying to
champion that access continues to be a
significant issue as you know and then
adopting some anti-counterfeiting
measures would certainly be critically
important thank you thank you good
afternoon Michael wheeler I'm the vice
president of policy with flow kana and
we're a cannabis distributor thank you
so much for taking time today with this
hearing obviously a very complicated
issue I ask o many of my peers with
regards to their remarks around the
usefulness and effectiveness of bans and
prohibition they don't work I think
we've talked a lot about the importance
of how how we encourage use of the
regulated market through reducing
taxation and increasing access to a
legal regulated product however what I
wanted to add to the comments today were
that I've got three kids at home
young they're not exposed to this yet
but I'm very concerned about it I'm very
concerned about teen vaping and
absolutely positively you know we stand
at your side in working in any way to to
stamp out teen vaping this is a horrible
epidemic I would encourage you what I
didn't hear any of the panelists talk
about today was some of the factors that
add to the coolness so when you get a
chance to take a look at YouTube go look
at teen they are vape tricks anything
having to do with vape tricks on YouTube
it's amazing it's really cool you'll be
your job will drop and this is part of
what makes it cool kids sit around all
day sucking on their on their vape pen
doing these tricks over and over again
it's practice practice makes perfect but
it's adding to the use of these products
so I just don't know another another
data point for all of this Thanks good
afternoon
Pamela Lopez with K Street consulting on
behalf of the Silicon Valley cannabis
Alliance cannabis is medicine
and licensed and regulated folks in the
cannabis industry are absolute partners
in working with you to get to the heart
of this crisis we would urge you to
remember that access to cannabis is an
important way to help consumers get away
from the black market illicit products
that are making them sick if I recall
correctly to date only 600 licensed
retailers exist in the state of
California
275 licensed non storefront distributors
that's down from 3,000 storefronts that
were open before the passage of Prop 64
and before cannabis was licensed and
regulated so there will always be bad
guys who are trying to sell illicit
stuff on the black market to make a
quick buck but it's our job in the state
of California to make sure that
consumers have access to products that
they know are licensed and safe hi
Sabrina pendrick with Berkeley patients
group and just to reiterate what some of
the other people have said we our
country and our state have gone through
multiple iterations of prohibition every
single time we've realized that it
doesn't work that was the whole point of
prop 64 however when you have two-thirds
of the state that are banning retail
sales it shouldn't be a surprise to
that were seeing the bathtub gin of 2019
happening or the k2 spice of 2019
happening I would also know it's
important when talking about flavors to
consider the genesis of the flavor it
was mentioned before and the difference
between naturally occurring flavors and
artificial flavors and also I wanted to
bring to your attention if and nobody
has mentioned today is looking at the
data in the UK and in Europe and this is
a very uniquely American crisis um the
United Kingdom has one of the lowest
youth use rates and actually subsidizes
vape smoking and promotes it as smoking
sensation policy and there should we
should ask the question as to why why is
there a disconnect between you know
evidence-based Public Policy and
emotionally-driven prohibitive policies
that are uniquely American that we need
to look away from thank you thank you
good afternoon members Eric Acosta with
the American Lung Association very much
appreciate the robust discussion today
on this issue and we just simply want to
emphasize the importance of including
flavors in the conversation particularly
mint and menthol again very much
appreciate the discussion and look
forward to further conversation thank
you thank you good afternoon chairman
gray and committee members my name is
Alex Thompson I'm the director of
compliance for pure extracts a vaporizer
cartridge manufacturer in Del Rey Oaks I
work alongside three dozen diligent
ethical people passionately helping
medicinal and recreational consumers
through our products as I hope each of
you can say I love my work I joined the
regulated cannabis industry eight years
ago as a Crohn's disease sufferer and
doctoral student cannabis saved my life
then and still provides me with
life-changing symptom relief
particularly when vaporized as a patient
scholar and industry member please hear
me that rash action on this topic may
have disasters fallout
since first hearing of recent medicinal
concern over vaporizer products pure
extracts began intensive research
supplemental laboratory testing and made
pointed requests of our
cannabis vendors terpene suppliers and
cartridge manufacturers for all
available research and safety data we
welcome your further guidance in
protecting our consumers safety
particularly focusing on cutting agents
use within the illicit market though
including vitamin E acetate we strongly
support additional laboratory testing
and consumer warning requirements we
will never ignore the well-being of our
consumers we are also sincerely
concerned though about the lively our
livelihoods and the medicinal needs of
our thousands of consumers please
collaborate with our industry to address
this issue and with an evidence-based
manner that provides an ongoing access
to a non combusted inhalable cannabis
option thank you hi my name is John with
weed herb I'm speaking on the illicit
market the lack of enforcement annulus
market is not really the problem it is
the lack of Licensing in the city so
many of us were in the illicit market
and a lot of these companies forget the
major companies forget that they were in
illicit market at one point in time and
how did they get the money in order to
get the license that they do have now
I've been struggling for the last three
years in order to get licensing in the
industry and nobody has been able to
give it to me so I've been doing the
best that I can in order to try to you
know get the correct information to get
in the industry so for a lot of us in
illicit market we are definitely trying
our best we have families we take care
of business and so forth but it's kind
of hard when you have people that are in
power that control the narrative thank
you good afternoon my name is Anne
delcor I chair the anti vaping Alliance
at Rio americano high school today I
brought props this is months worth of
confiscated devices from the high school
I take them just about everywhere I go
because I find that they are the best
educational tool that we have in this
fight
so it's a variety of nicotine and
marijuana devices and as we heard today
the students are vaping these devices
interchangeably I am asking that we do
something urgently
I think waiting until the next
legislative session delays this and we
are seating students and families truly
suffering with addiction already they're
spending a lot of money on addiction
counselors teachers and administrators
are having a very difficult time
educating our kids because of this
distraction and the schools need more
help so I ask you for attention to the
schools either additional personnel or
additional help at the state level thank
you thank you good afternoon my name is
laurie Bremner with the American Cancer
Society Cancer Action Network the single
most important thing that we can do to
tackle the teeny cigarette epidemic is
to pass a policy the prohibits the sale
of all flavored tobacco products passing
a flavor policy with no exemptions
ensures that youth don't go from one
type of tobacco product to another to
chase the candy flavor that got them
hooked in the first place
mint and menthol are extremely popular
among youth and exempting those flavors
would undermine all efforts designed to
limit youth initiation legislators
introduced two bills
last year that would have prohibited the
sale of all flavored tobacco products
but they did not advance
jool and other tobacco companies lobby
furiously against flavor policies
because they know they will result in a
reduction of tobacco use in our state
the American Cancer Society Cancer
Action Network hopes that the outcome of
these hearings will be for the
legislature to adopt the consensus along
with the public health community and
more than 40 California cities they're
prohibiting the sale of all flavored
tobacco products with no exemptions is
the best way to combat youth tobacco
addiction we need to hold Jewel and the
other tobacco companies accountable for
the disaster that they've caused by
passing a bill that prohibits the sale
of all flavored tobacco products the
need is urgent we need to get this done
and just to clarify again for the record
there's a lot of confiscating on this
issue that was just on tobacco or on all
vaping I'm addressing only tobacco ish
tobacco products but all tobacco
products including menthol and mint
combustible cigarettes as well thank you
hi thanks everybody for coming together
today my name is Mike Clemens I'm the
president co-founder of guild extracts
we're a licensed manufacturer out of
Oakland California and has been has has
been explored today California spent
years carefully crafting a framework of
regulatory controls to address the
public health risks that we've been
talking about today like VAP I I don't
believe that we're seeing a failure of
these controls I think that we're seeing
the result of a failure to adequately
support the legal cannabis industry
within this framework the economic
burdens on the industry from the
regulatory layer has driven up prices
and driven consumers to continue to
purchase from the illicit market to mr.
Cooper's point a recent audit found
close to three thousand illegal
retailers in California versus the 873
that ms Ajax's team at the BCC has
licensed a lack of enforcement against
the bad actors across the state has
resulted in a black market that's not
only impossible for regulated businesses
to compete with but it also operates
outside of the oversight that's supposed
to ensure products conform to a safe
standard furthermore any move to just
completely ban any product altogether
will only exacerbate a dangerous
situation by driving more consumers away
from a regulated businesses to the
illicit sources and it still fails to
address the underlying problem of
contamination in the supply chain it
would be disastrous to the industry and
to the people of California that if has
entrusted their elected officials to
work together to make this industry work
it would also threaten the entire state
program that we've all worked really
hard to create so we just need to
enforce the law and we need to make
compliance less costly for the good
actors thank you very much thank you
Maureen banana on behalf of the United
cannabis Business Association we've
we've actively have worked to push for
penalties under props as prop 64 was
drafted or only to allow for penalties
for legal operators so for the last
couple of years you've had state
agencies and attorney general
and local law enforcement not having the
tools necessary to shut down the illegal
market a B 97 is the first step that we
worked on a B 1417 which allowed the
Attorney General District Attorney's and
city attorneys to impose penalties was
held in the Senate Appropriations
Committee we've there's a crisis we are
legal we have ensured that our products
are safe a ban on all vaping products
will only push people to say legal
market we want to do the right thing and
we've been advocating this for years and
now there's a crisis now people are
saying it the illegal market needs to be
shut down that we've been advocating
that for years thank you Thank You mr.
chairman Tim Madden represent the
California Chapter of the American
College of Cardiology and since I'm your
last person I won't go too much longer
but consistent with with some other
folks that have mentioned we believe is
an organization that a ban on all vaping
products is the way to go and listening
to dr. Dean's testimony were the
Department of Public Health is saying
people should not be vaping at all we
think is the prudent approach so we want
to get to the next level and we are
asking for a ban similar to what was
done in Massachusetts although they did
it on a four month time frame on all
vaping products thank you thank you
hello Jared Kyle o president of the
United cannabis Business Association
gonna keep it short regulations are just
suggestions without enforcement that is
what we need to focus on we are trying
to build an industry and we're trying to
keep safety and security amongst our
consumers and if we don't have a good
enforcement branch we are just allowing
these regulations to just kind of go
pass us by we're not really focusing on
what the effects are not only for the
industry as its growth but also the
health and safety of its consumers thank
you thank you for your comments that
brings us to the conclusion of public
comment we'll bring it back here to the
committee for closing comments I'd like
to thank chairman wood and chairman Lowe
I think this has been a very informative
hearing I know it's been a long
afternoon but this is a tremendously
important subject that I know we all
share a desire to move forward with some
solutions in concrete activity via early
in the legislative year next year so
thank you again chairman and I'll let
you make some closing remarks
yeah just thank you to my colleagues for
working with us to put this together
obviously when you fill the room and an
on let in a non legislative session
you clearly have a topic of interest and
appreciate the information we learned
today we will use this to craft an
additional hearing to explore this issue
further and just so people know we are
not in session we cannot take any sort
of legislative action now until we
reconvene in January that's just the way
the it works so appreciate everybody's
attendance here all of our panelists
everybody who came and many people who
came from a long distance to participate
today I think it's been really valuable
information and look forward to
reconvening and discussing this further
thank you so much with that were
adjourned