[Music]
so vapor pressure deficit it's the cat's
meow tell us why
so VPD is really important for a lot of
reasons most importantly VPD controls
plant evapotranspiration so VPD is the
vapor pressure deficit and it is the
difference between the vapor pressure
saturated conditions versus vapor
pressure at the room conditions so say
you have a room that you're controlling
to 75 degrees and 50 percent relative
humidity there's a vapor pressure
associated with that and that difference
in vapor pressure between saturation in
the room conditions is what the plant
sees when it's going to transpire and
move water it's literally if you think
about it it's literally the pressure
that the air is putting on the plants to
transpire so when we have a high vapor
pressure deficit that usually means that
it's pretty dry in the room and plants
will want to use more water to transpire
when we have a lower vapor pressure
deficit and it's more humid in the room
there's less pressure on the plant to
transpire this is really key for for
both water and nutrient delivery from
the roots through the shoots and the
leaves and going to the flowers and the
fruits it's also very important for the
plant to be able to regulate its own
temperature through evaporative cooling
so when the plant transpires is also
evaporate cooling itself and and so VPD
on the HVAC side of things when you're
trying to size equipment also affects
how well that equipment is able to
remove moisture and humidify the room so
when we have a really high vapor
pressure deficit what happens is that we
have sort of this double whammy so the
plants they transpire more because the
air is dry and so they're putting more
moisture in the room but that high vapor
pressure deficit is also
really hard for HVAC equipment to
operate and remove the moisture that the
plants put into the room so here we have
more moisture in the room and it takes
now more energy for the HVAC system to
remove that moisture if we could find a
vapor pressure deficit where the plants
are gonna be really happy and not use
excessive water and the HVAC equipment
can operate efficiently then we're going
to have a win-win situation and what's
that magic number so the magic number in
general for vapor pressure deficit is
11.0 kiloPascals I mean we use this as a
general target for a lot of crops like
tomatoes and cucumbers lettuce plants
because they're more in vegetative we
tend to like a smaller or a lower vapor
pressure deficit a little bit more humid
air with cannabis plants what's going on
is that all these growers are so afraid
of humidity they're so afraid of mold
that they're driving the humidity down
increasing that vapor pressure deficit
and and are inadvertently putting more
pressure on their plants and more strain
on their HVAC equipment to remove that
moisture so if we can convince growers
and having a VPD of one kilopascal like
every other crop then we're gonna be
better in terms of plant health and HVAC
health yes so plant transpiration is is
the movement of water from the roots
through the plant so through its it's
from its roots through its chute and it
stems and its leaves and it is what's
responsible for moving the water and the
nutrients to the different parts of the
plants so every plant the the leaves
have stomata on the bottom of the leaf
and those tamanna' are like little
mouths and they're responsible for
sucking co2 in for photosynthesis but
then also releasing the oxygen from that
photosynthesis and for releasing that
water vapor via transpiration
transpiration determined by like a ray
a rate of transpiration how is it
measured Oh the rate of transpiration is
hard to measure actually I mean it's
probably one of the biggest challenges
we have as HVAC engineers is trying to
figure out what that moisture load is in
the room there's a few different things
if you are a grower if you are already
actively growing you can measure how
much water is your being your delivering
to the plant through irrigation and then
how much water is being drained away
from say the pot or their growing media
and whatever is left is really what's
going to get transpired by the plant the
plant really only holds on to maybe a
couple percentages of the water that
gets delivered to it so if you say I
deliver you know one gallon per plant
per day well right off the top we can
probably lop off thirty to thirty five
percent of that water to drainage and
then maybe two to five percent for what
stays in the plant so really sixty
percent of that one gallon is what's
getting delivered to the room and that
we have to remove via dehumidification
can you talk about a VPD gone wrong like
when you're above one and like things
you would see the cause the cause and
effect or the effect of it being above
1.0 and like what you might see if it's
way below 1.0 yeah so a vapor pressure
deficit if we don't manage it well can
have both it can have negative effects
both abiotic Lee and biotic Lee so what
that means is the abiotic is things like
having poor nutrient delivery and water
delivery to the plant so the most simple
case of that is having a wilting plant
wilting leaf if the vapor pressure
deficit is really high and it's really
dry in the room and we don't have a well
watered crop then the plant is going to
wilt because it just there's not enough
water to keep up with that vapor
pressure on the plan exactly but beyond
that you know if if you the plant is
transpiring really quickly what happens
is that it can't pull calcium along with
it and so what you actually see like in
lettuce plants or in leaves you
see leaf tip burned so like the rim of a
leaf will turn yellow because of the
calcium deficiency in tomatoes we see it
as blossom and rot and actually the
bottom of a tomato fruit will turn black
because there's no calcium being
delivered to that fruit this can happen
both when you have a very dry
environment without enough water going
to the plant and actually also a humid
environment because if if it's too humid
and the vapor pressure is too low then
there's not enough pressure on the plant
to move water and nutrients through it
so you can actually see the same
condition when it's too low the other
thing is biotic deficiencies and so
those are things like powdery mildew and
botrytis if the VPD is really low and
it's very humid sure you have a risk of
having molds that grow but what people
also don't realize is that when you have
a really high vapor pressure deficit
you're stressing the plant and just like
humans when plants get stressed their
immune system goes down and so they
actually become more susceptible to
diseases when they're stressed out
because of high vapor pressure deficit
so here we are trying to create this
really dry environment so that we don't
get molds to set in but then we're
stressing the plant so the one little
mold spore that's out there is going to
really dive into that plant and it's
it's going to get powdery mildew because
it can't fight against it it's about
education our growers aware of VPD do
they know about it or I mean more and
more growers know about vapor pressure
deficit I mean I'm I'm definitely out
there pounding the pavement speaking it
way too many conferences giving
workshops doing all these things trying
to get the word out that vapor pressure
deficit is so critical to the plant's
health and and I am very encouraged I'm
even seeing posts on Instagram and
LinkedIn and Facebook where people are
talking more about vapor pressure
deficit and understand what it is and
why it's so important so I'm very
encouraged by that but certainly we got
to get the word out more
and educate people more so they
understand the ramifications both for
the plant but also for HVAC equipment
sizing I mean if we have to oversize a
piece of equipment two times of what you
know at a kill at a VPD of 1.5 than what
we needed at a healthy one I mean what
are we doing to ourselves and you're
saying that that's basically not
necessary we don't have to do that we
don't have to do that exactly and we can
save energy we can save on cost for for
buying the equipment for operating the
equipment and again we have a happy
plant right a happy plant happy HVAC so
so obviously cultivators are rightly
concerned about mold right their entire
crops so they find themselves in the
middle you know in this tough position
is the goal to create like a a guide or
measurements that they can use to create
the right environment ahead of time to
reduce VPD or is that what the
researchers or you know what can they
yeah so you're asking I'm asking is they
the goal is to create the right
environment so that you don't have too
much VPD is that creep is that correct
that's right so really what it is is
finding that sweet spot finding that
combination of temperature and relative
humidity where we hit a vapor pressure
deficit that's around one kilopascal we
have a chart on our website and there's
a few other charts that are kind of
floating around there that say hey look
you know at 75 degrees and 50 percent
relative humidity
it's 1.5 kilo Pascal's if you were to
keep that same temperature and raise the
relative humidity you're gonna creep up
to 1.25 kilo Pascal's 1.1 kiloPascals 1
kilopascal so for a given temperature
you can find the relative humidity
that's going to hit the VPD
and I thought the mold and not create
mold exactly