[Music]
so I'm Jim fry off I'm a captain with
the Ventura County Sheriff's Office I'm
currently the Chief of Police of the
contract city of Oh aye
so right now we're in the city of Ojai
we're at a hotel called Casa Ojai Inn
that's the the host for the first ever
weed convention that we've con 2018
having never had one in our County
before we didn't know what to expect so
I brought additional staffing they were
expecting anywhere from two to three
hundred attendees so I had four extra
officers that were here but when we had
our briefing ahead of time I made it
clear that our goal is to have a
successful mellow event where we're
gonna walk through and be seen whole
people do that what the conditions are
where there's no usage at the event
maker so seen be friendly say hi to
everybody let them know we're here but
also cuz I don't want people to be
afraid to call us if something goes
wrong so we're not here to make enemies
we're here to hold people accountable
and enforce the law that's that's
correct so the the event that the weed
con 2018 I was contacted by one of my
dispensaries who let me know about the
event that was gonna happen and the
promoter sought out a temporary use
permit from the city of Ojai to have the
event with the the necessary
restrictions that the city needed a
place no I'm good thank you very much
thank you for coming up appreciate it
what kind of bike you ride it so yeah so
the promoter had to I had to submit to
get a temporary use permit to have the
event and when the promoter came forward
and said hey I want to have an event
where I want to bring different industry
stakeholders together for a convention
he asked you know this is where I want
to hold it at he knew that we had three
dispensaries three licensed dispensaries
in the city of Ojai and he went through
the permitting process and was in
secured a permit from the city to have
the event obviously there's a
substantial amount of conditions on the
on the event itself the most notable is
that no cannabis consumption could take
place at the event
location and that's a and that's not
just specific to this event that's a
city ordinance prohibition correct
except for in private we see her home
you can use is twenty nineteen gonna be
different than twenty eighteen so the
you know the state keeps changing the
regulations pretty much monthly and as a
result the cities are trying to play
catch-up on what the state's trying to
accomplish and the cities are either
trying to be more restrictive than what
the state has or at least on par with
what the state is doing so as of right
now I think our our conditions are
pretty consistent with what the state is
doing as far as events like this I it's
my understanding that a state event you
could have it I like a fairgrounds
obviously this is not a fairgrounds this
is that this is a hotel that has been
rented out for this purpose and because
this is a a brand new industry that
we're all involved in now
people trying to sort their way through
it I've see I've been in law enforcement
for 28 years and for a majority of that
time marijuana has been illegal and now
it's legal with certain parameters and
so they keep changing right so and
that's and that's just the way it is
right and they'll find some homeostasis
at some point of where those laws need
to be to keep people safe and still
allow access was what the voters wanted
so here in in the city that I think that
we had a ohai had the highest percentage
of voters that voted for prop 64 and as
a result their constituents the council
members who are working for the voters
decided to move forward with initially
medicinal dispensaries and then several
months later open them up to
recreational or adult use dispensary so
all three of our dispensaries in the
city of Ojai are licensed for adult use
voter you know support for prop 64 and
then they ban everything and it's like
that's not really the
so I think that there's a balance to be
drawn right so you certainly have the
will of the people of what they want and
then at the same time when the city is
looking at the overall well-being of
their community are they gonna jump too
fast do they open up too wide and which
I think was when the city said okay
we're to start with medicinal and see
what that looks like it was probably a
shorter period of time than I envisioned
but seven months later they've gone
adult use or recreational and in that
the transition has not seemed to be an
issue for the city yet but it's still a
very new industry we don't know yet what
the impact is going to be positive or
negative obviously from an industry
standpoint and business standpoint
there's a lot of employers now there's
certainly more employees that are
working up here at the dispensary so
there so there's a value in that right
finding good work for people to be in
that's legal is always good and so as
right now I have met with all three of
my dispensary owners I have a great
relationship with all three of them they
also want to make sure the community is
safe so they've given me great access to
all their facilities I actually have
access to all the cameras within their
facilities they've actually given our
that access to our dispatch center so if
they ever dial 911 our dispatchers can
log into their cameras and see what's
happening live and let the officers know
that responding in what's happening at
the time so from a safety standpoint
it's valuable to have I've asked all the
dispensaries to hand out fliers saying
cannabis and driving don't mix and they
have handed out those flyers with every
purchase they have stickers they put on
all their exit bags that say that this
is a still a controlled substance to
keep away from people who are pregnant
or minors and pets for obvious reasons
and so they they've been been more than
willing to help can control it in a way
that makes it safe for our key the
safest is it's possible for our
community right so from me and I
mentioned to this earlier to you that
I'm not pro marijuana in any regard
right but I am pro law and the law says
that's legal and I'm going to enforce
what is legal right so if it's legal
it's legal just like this event the
expectation is that nobody's going to
consume
marijuana's product here if they do
they'll have to answer to me now are you
under any pretense that zero marijuana
will be consumed here no no I so I
recognize that there's a good chance
that that can happen right I think that
the the effort here is to make sure that
the event holder knows what the
restrictions are and that he does his
best to control it if they want to have
a second event
he'll control it that's the expectation
oh yes so so one of the things that I've
a relation to one of the dispensaries
here locally it's Ojai greens and when I
talk to Matt one of the owners I noticed
that he had put a billboard up when they
first went into business along Highway
33 the main corridor into the Ojai
Valley and it said oh hi greens is a
cannabis just proved cannabis dispensary
for medicinal and then he was gonna
change the sign because now that they've
gone true recreational or adult use he
wanted to change the sign and I had
asked him I said hey are you willing to
include a public safety message on your
billboard will you include the statement
cannabis and driving don't mix it he
goes absolutely so two days ago the
billboard went up with the message that
says cannabis and driving don't mix it's
actually three days it was on Tuesday so
it seems like the majority of your
interactions with this community whether
it's day-to-day or here at this event
have been positive so not contentious
and they're reasonable people so has
that kind of like
how have you processed in that
experience of like so I would say that
the experience is definitely gone better
than I expected right so I think there
was a lot of reception right oh yeah
okay what's going to happen cuz we see
with the takeover robberies that
happened at other dispensaries in other
areas you know what's that going to do
here are we going to be subject to
additional violent crimes in our area
because we have a target now that people
want to hit and so that's my biggest
concern is they they're a potential
target and so by the security additions
that they've that they've imposed that
they've willingly done on themselves
that's helped to reduce their chance of
being harmed or their employees being
harmed as well I always wanted to want
more right might you know my idea of
security is different than their idea
but might just tell them you know hey
this is my position this is what I think
you should do it's it's their choice you
know they've met the minimum
requirements on what the city has
imposed but I just tell them I go hey my
expectation is you're gonna do
everything you can to keep everybody in
the community safe and not be a target
so I don't want any victims here correct
so what we're a bigger city right so
what happens is in California there's
incorporated cities and they can have
their own police departments if they
choose to
obviously the unincorporated areas are
all patrolled by the Sheriff's Office
but incorporated cities can have their
own Police Department where they can
choose to contract their services out to
the sheriff's office oftentimes there's
a lot of overhead and redundancy within
law enforcement from personnel
dispatching SWAT teams all these other
things that by contracting with a larger
agency they can they could save money
they can be more efficient in how they
do it now they don't have their own
Police Department they contract with us
so they you know think about we do a
pretty good job of trying to represent
it as we are their police permit so I'm
the chief of police for the city of Ohio
are the cars that we drive into in the
city so we let the council's decide
right it's a it's the council's town
they I work for the city manager I'm one
of his department heads just like the
many other department heads to make sure
we're delivering the service of the city
wants there are all these different
constituents right correct
you're a stakeholder law enforcement the
PTA moms the cannabis consumers that
whatever so are you attending those City
Council meetings and it's so kind of
what are the things that you're trying
to push forward and what are things that
other stakeholders are pushing forward
and how do we come up with how is Ojai
come out with sort of compromises on all
sides okay so the questions on more
venture right so so all the cities have
they're at a different stage of the game
right I think city of Ojai is definitely
more advanced so the question was how
does the city fare with how do we make
these decisions you know with all the
different stakeholders that are involved
right so yeah police you have parents
you have schools you have all these
other constituents who are involved in
trying to make up what's right for the
city and most of those redresses are
handled at a city council meeting so I
see I attend city council meetings and
if I can't one of my my assistant chief
will attend where those items are
discussed about hey this is what they
want to do it's not for me to say right
they can always ask what their what my
concerns are and I share with them what
my concerns are right because it might
might these are my concerns I'm
concerned about increase of people that
are using illicit substances and driving
I'm worried about the security for
people coming in doing robberies because
it's a cash business I'm worried about
at least now as of July at least they're
not coming with a 55-gallon drums full
of weed because it's all prepackaged
from the manufacturer so there's less of
a target for for the theft of the
marijuana now it's just the cash item
but you know all these businesses know
that that's a target they have vaults to
hide the cash in to store it in and then
they know that when they have a certain
amount to take into deposit at the bank
set they can still do banking with or
they break it apart so that the banks
are not wise to whatever their decisions
aren't right they're the ones that have
to find out what they're doing with it
until there's a greater resolution on
the banking system for the cannabis
dispensaries did you have any
perspective
yeah so all three of our dispensaries
were also given the permit for delivery
as well so when the city first stepped
into it they said they would give three
delivery licenses and three dispensary
licenses it just worked out that the
people that qualified for the licenses
we're able to provide both or applied
for and received both the delivery and
the no and then in the dispensary model
so yeah I have a concern about them
being robbed but note I have a concern
about the Domino's guy getting robbed
too right so I mean anytime you have
product and money and you have people
that you have a potential for for a
crime so one of the things that the
dispensaries know is to make sure
they're sending out their drivers on
designated routes with not with not a
ton of product or a ton of cash they go
out make their round and they come back
currently our delivery drivers in the
city can deliver anywhere in the city
anywhere in the unincorporated area and
for the city other cities outside the
jurisdiction they can apply to get
delivery licenses in those cities and if
they're granted license that they can
deliver they're in the city of Ojai the
only ones that can deliver in the city
of Ohio are our three dispensaries that
we have here nobody from outside now I
know that the state is looking at
changing that the state's looking at
changing that and I know I don't know if
that what will happen but one see and
that's one of those changes that's still
kind of unfolding but for now it's these
three dispensaries and they know what my
concerns are and as of right now have
been abiding by those concerns and
they've had it for medicinal they've had
the delivery license I've had one one
shot that's been open for a year or
pretty close to it the other two have
been open for about nine months
[Music]
right so it's not a fair comparison but
I will so what's the comparison between
alcohol and marijuana and the drama that
it causes within the you know the public
right okay so the issues that are
because marijuana has been illegal up
until just very recently it's not been
as mainstream as alcohol which has been
legal for a long time and so certainly I
would say that the marijuana the alcohol
issues are far more likely than with the
the marijuana like if you were to
compare how many occur so there was one
thousand incidents compared to one
incident of this because one was legal
and one's not the challenge will be now
that it's legal well we see that number
increase based on like you said the
fights domestic violence or vehicle
crashes and whatnot because the access
is different the active for people that
maybe had access before but were like
more cautious about using it because
they would be they were afraid of
getting arrested now they don't have
that fear anymore what's the what's
what's gonna be the new normal that
we're faced with so I'm curious to see
how that how that plays out my homework
assignment for you is to when
consumption events are finally legal in
whether Ventura County Ohio specifically
I want you to watch how one of those
events plays out and sort of in your
mind just know that no
of bytes you would see at an alcohol
sort of like a concert without all
versus an event like this because I
guarantee you and you'll see all sorts
of people just like being nice to each
other and having like deep discussions
and conversations whereas like then you
go next door to like the Oklahoma party
and it's like you see you stepped on my
toe and they like start punching each
other and getting all aggro and so
anyway all right all about me my
homeworks I try to write so we'll know
within you know as things become more
normalized it's like you know for this
event it's the first one of its kind in
Ohio and probably the first one of its
kind in Ventura County not knowing what
to expect this is this is a very relaxed
event I have not seen had any issues at
all I see part of the conditions is that
we get to walk in you know as often as
we want and I've walked through talked
to the different the vendor booths but
it's also now I'm not coming in with a
heavy hand in mind either right I'm
coming in trying to make sure that that
they know they can still call us right
at the end of the day I'm trying to
provide a public service and trying to
keep everybody safe
they know what the restrictions are I
expect that they abide by there's
restrictions there's always gonna be bad
apples that don't and if they're sought
out enforcement action may be taken
right but if as long as everybody knows
what the expectation is if they can
model that expectation we're
[Music]