[Music]
there's so many veterans right now that
yeah have you know vets that have lost
limbs and stuff and you know have their
physical incapacity
but then there's veterans like myself
that physically were fit you know to an
extent but there's veterans right now
that are in their houses with a car that
runs with a body that's able to alright
bro
to come out and be a part of something
like this that's fucking amazing but
they can't get out of bed because the
wound is in the mind and there's like so
many of us right now man that are at
home like just miserable to wear if they
understood that there's a community of
people out here that like leave your
house and comments it's been an
afternoon and watch it change your life
because that's what this is you're not I
mean like if you're like a selfless
person that's on that the military
teaches you like immediately you get the
basic training if we have like you know
core values and shit and one of them is
selfless service and selfless services
you give your life for your country like
that's where that kind of honor code
within a bet that you see like when we
die like it's for the country like that
comes from when you get to basic
training you already know you feel it
but they actually have a fucking Eastern
Court and it's like to work at all cost
just for the greater good work
regardless of what happens to you anyway
work selflessly without expectation
do right because doing right is what you
do go get the bad guys because they're
fucking hurting people like that's where
you know so life could be kind of like
that that balance you know so so like
I'm sorry your name and your
organization and like where you coming
from Florida yeah yeah I came from I'm
from South Florida my my name is Jose
Belen and my organization is mission
zero so like my story pretty much is I
was part of the invasion into Iraq in
2003 from upstate New York small town
called Amsterdam grew up there too and
you know I was that kid on the street at
12 years old on probation for fucking
burglary you know my family basically
was like look you're gonna be a fuckin
loser you know took five years but I
graduated high school but I knew like I
I couldn't go to college like I at least
knew like I didn't want to just fuck up
what I could do is join the military and
if I could join the military which my
family known in the world would ever
expect that you know I mean cuz they
given my subject' eree
you know but I got to affirm stop like
when I failed 11th grade I'm like wait
dude come on like fuck that don't let
what their your stepdads telling you be
true you know so I made a choice myself
consciously on say you know I'm gonna
fucking join the military and I'm gonna
try to do the hardest job that I can and
if I can do that I can do anything in
life like I swear my mom like that 17 18
years old man I had that conversation
where I'm like you know what fuck you
I'm gonna join the military and I'm
gonna make something of myself so that's
like what got me to basic training
and like got me through it was the
intestinal fortitude like that you know
what I'm not a loser I'm not going to be
what society has been saying you know to
me as you can I'm gonna make something
myself so my service for me you know
holds an invaluable fuckin place in my
heart and that's the thing for so many
vets it's it's so personal the reason we
enlists a lot of us most of us come from
broken homes and the broken communities
you know so it's like you know you give
that honor you know oh just say you know
what you know so when when you get the
fucking service you get the basic
training you know like there's just this
like immediate understanding that that
person next to you like we're all about
to get the biggest mindfuck of our lives
we're about to all just go through
something crazy traumatic but you know
what we're all going through the same
amount of pain at the same time and
physically being there to pick each
other up when we're all being just
broken and like that's the whole thing
with veterans like it's not a sob story
what I'm talking it's just real it's
just what it's like and there's been
like this coat of fucking we don't talk
about it you know out of services but
like that I had a Vietnam veteran Tommy
when I came home he's like Jose you need
to talk about your service he's like
because I didn't talk about it for 30
years and I'm fucked up and I watch this
man struggled as a vet before servo so
he's like listen you talk about it when
you're ready you know so this is my 15th
year home now you know but I found
I found through all the pain associated
with service you know the connection and
all that the things you experience in
combat that when we get out of service
we're very hard on ourselves you know
everything needs to be fucking perfect
and if our marriage ain't right the
whole fucking thing right because it has
to be right the main that we have to be
able to figure it out you know and make
everything work and when we realize that
that man on your left to your rights not
there you know it begins a struggle but
the thing with veterans is like we're
not mentally ill mentally strong we're
still here we're fighting a battle but
we think we don't matter we think that
all the shit that we've been through was
for nothing because we didn't do it for
the glory we didn't do it for the medals
it's beyond that but only if they
understand that so we lose hope in
ourselves but that's the biggest things
that's like look you know we all have a
story to tell and the reason I speak now
is to inspire that veteran that was just
like me thinking like the best
alternative is just to end it all okay
you know like to be there and know you
want to die that bad but you won't do it
so you put the gun down you're
consciously aware is like emotionally
you want to die but you know you don't
want to leave your dog like okay fuck
that you know you put the gun down what
happens after that
you're still faced with living the same
life that you had that pushed you to
want to kill yourself you have to figure
out a way to accept and understand that
this is your life now man like this is
where you're at right now it's not going
to get better tomorrow but you know what
I'm gonna do my best to fucking do it
cuz I don't want to die
and so right I and so my goal is to get
the vets who were right there who
already put the gun down but everyday
are still like I want to check out today
anyway
you know like look pause you know
there's 18 million of us out out of
service we can do some things together
where the private sector won't give you
a job because you're missing your limbs
we'll take care of each other you know
what I mean like that's the whole thing
there's something healing about working
with plants I know that too and like
it's not just smoking together you know
join the fruits of our labor that can
excess you know but like learning how
the plants and the animals and you're
all part of that those systems and you
can play a role in effecting the
abundance that you reap you know is like
that stuff is powerful man and like I
don't have much experience you know
working with veterans per se but I'm
working with you know people with
disabilities I've seen amazing things
like it just makes me happy it makes
everybody happy like working with good
regenerative soil practices seems to
have a positive impact on the spirit you
know
well that's the thing I can't come in
Florida that's the whole thing trying to
just rest
that's a lot that's why this is so huge
right because I'm trying to create
initiatives right now because I
understand you know how much of a
life-saving tool this is but federally I
can I'm handcuffed but you know what
that doesn't mean today they encourage
you to have the conversation at the VA
with your doctor like their host and
they don't know that's so you know it
was thanks - it's backwards right now
you know so veterans like my sit like
myself I'm left - like right now I'm you
know establishing you know curriculum in
Florida I was telling you about it so my
goal is you know Hampus you're gonna be
able to put it yeah for a hemp license
in Florida next month right so my mind
immediately went to okay how can I get
you know into this market it's legal now
I'm gonna have the ability to fucking do
it
okay what can I do to live like my my
virtue is hope happiness opportunity
purpose and empowerment like that's my
goal you know to provide to veterans
like that's my ethos personal ethos hope
happiness because if you provide a
better with happiness that's given them
you know hope you know for an
opportunity now that opportunity is
given over purpose and now he's
empowered them so what can I do now so
my mind immediately went to I want to
put in for a HAMP license you know and
you know industrialized PEM Creek you
know an installation to figure out a way
to build veteran homes but also and that
operation I want to work with a local
college or university to be able to
provide veterans that want to get
education at a degree in engineering or
AG whatever course curriculum there to
get college credits at our farm and then
create also certification program
doesn't want to go to get a degree he
can get certified at the farm eight to
12 weeks you know and now guess what
he's employable within the industries
and so what have we just done we have
provided a veteran with an empowerment
element that now it's giving him
education he's getting therapy just
through being a around medicine right
and now he's been getting towards and
coordinates within our own operation
or if he wants to go in the industry we
connect them with whoever but now you
have given a veteran that was supposed
to be disabled living off his shitty
disability now all of a sudden he's you
know built again because it's always
been be all you can be in army but what
about be all you can be when you're not
in the Army anymore where's the red tape
what's it going to take funding man like
that that's realistically I can have the
greatest ideas in the world you know
we're gonna have some fun you know so
honestly I've just kind of I can't say
the name of the college but I pitch to
college and they we've already kind of
put the first phase layer the curriculum
together you know to roll this out I've
you know so it's just been really been
finding someone who believes just as
much as me you know there's money to be
made everyone knows that the whole thing
is what is your goal when you get it and
what are you going to do with it so if
I'm coming into this to try to help you
do don't cross me in the process because
I've had to learn a vicious lesson in
this industry there's a whole other side
there's a whole that people don't know
about you know that you really have to
figure out a way to stay in your lane
without selling yourself out knowing
that it's going to be a hard-ass journey
but I believe man is strong enough that
you know I'm trying to create an
ecosystem for veterans we've got two
hundred thousand coming out of service
every year we know that number did you
call it an ecosystem yeah I'm trying to
create you know that hole because we're
killing ourselves like that's the whole
thing like there's raw data it's known
the government acknowledges we know
there's a veteran that
it's right now he's unsound and we don't
know where but he doesn't have to she
doesn't have to because we're you're
forgotten about out there you're not
forgotten about here and like I have you
know a daughter in the steps and my
daughter's gonna be seven my stepson is
going to be 18 next month you know at
the end of the day man we're all going
to clock out you know whether we want to
or not
like I learned a lesson on death and
combat that dude there's dude even right
now you know so you you really you know
get to a point where you need to
understand that it's not about zeroes in
the bank account man yeah we can all
live a life you know whatever it's not
about all that what it's about is what
is your legacy what are you doing like
what am i doing today that if my clock
runs out tonight that my daughter you
know my stepsons could say you know what
my father stood for something he stood
for humanity and that's what I want for
everybody else it's like I want to see
my neighbor win I want to see if I can
help your you know in any way let's just
just do it this sorry man it fires me up
man
what you're saying is let's just let it
grow because if it has one more day or
two more days or fucking ten more years
or who knows we live in the weird
- right let's live that day and the
plants want the same thing and so you're
connecting a whole ecosystem right and
so the intent that you bring to your
grow no matter how big sets the stage
and how you start alright so how are we
gonna let these plants grow we're gonna
pump them full of salt right and then
you go wait a minute I'm not wanting to
grow like that and so this ecosystem
you've talked about education you talked
about agriculture right you've talked
about opportunities and Kealing
employment purpose healing that's that's
that's the whole thing
it's a wheat we're we're so on to
something and veterans have there's 18
million of us and it's like if you
really think about that number and so
many of us are so doped up that we don't
even realize that the value we have and
that's what what's the heartbreak in
this whole thing it's like the
government you know I've been blessed to
be here as a speaker and I've spoken the
us have like Lobby I do all that stuff
because at the end of the day what is
wrong is like I learned that in war like
I think that's the whole thing like in
in the shittiest places I learned the
most valuable of lessons that right is
right and when you're wrong you just own
you're wrong and you'll be okay and
that's the only thing I've wanted the
government fucking to do is say you know
what you can't change
yesterday we you did to the Native
Americans you know we can't go back in
time but we can make a conscious choice
today
Lemar okay baby right now that's right
and my whole beef has always been like
why keep 18 million veterans unaware of
their true value to this country you
know make these men and women aware so
they don't want to die at the end of the
day man like when you like like I've
nearly taken my my life at a number of
times it you know one of the most
fucked-up ones was on a Saturday
afternoon like you know get into that
point
you know I was fortunate when I got out
of the service I got into the insurance
industry I was one of the number one
insurance professionals in corporate
America man like you never knew I had
PTSD I was making twenty thirty thousand
dollars a month just and all hard work
man six he said no shortcuts but you
know what I was suicidal every such day
and you know I got you know and my car
went afternoon after leaving a
barbershop I called my father I'm like
I'm gonna kill myself right now when I
get home I have a wife and two kids
beautiful house I had it all at the time
you know and you know I call all the
things you thought you meant it that's
the thing yeah because you know and I
earned it that's what I'm like you but
it'll still get it but you know what and
that's that's the whole thing like again
like the virtues of a veteran like we
learned that you earned your keep you
know what I'm saying so like you know
when I made that phone call to my dad
and I'm crying on the phone and you know
he's like it's a man you got a cold or
so I'm like yeah but I'm conquered I
know it's the last time I'm gonna talk
to my father and you know I was just so
fucking you know going off on the meds
and shit I pulled in my driveway you
know have my Sig Sauer with a round in
the fucking shaver off safety right here
just takes seven pounds of pressure you
know and hung up the phone with my dad
my wife was out with my kids and I'm
like quarter million dollar house you
know American dream man and went to war
got my fucking house god damn it I
fucking earned it you know I mean that
VA home loan I went to Baghdad and god I
brought it home with me you know so I
had all the reasons to feel satisfied
but the fog of war is so like the
twisted is so overpowering and I just
remember you know just sitting there gun
you know on my hip looking at it just
rocking back and forth crying
you know got I think fucking nirvana
playing or something and just I don't
want to fucking die and like just like
had this fight
pick up the gun and do it or just don't
touch don't don't talk don't and I
didn't and what happens is the struggle
continues you still haven't you realize
you don't want to die but the same pain
that push you to wanna die still and
you're gonna have to face it every day
you know so I want veterans to
understand they come off the ledge bro
like if that's where you're at because
I've but come on
I don't want to die yeah
is where the grind is yeah
but you get through yeah fucking not one
to die right don't you know then it
shifts and then you want to grow percent
in him right that's just that's what
it's all about
there's there's life man like that's
what I want to tell every single person
who's right now fucking suicide I don't
like it like hold on oh wait there's
like we and we got each other that's the
whole thing and that's why this is so
beautiful with what we're surrounded by
I mean the plants been here for 3,000
years for a reason we have an
endocannabinoid system for a reason you
know and it's like let's just understand
that it's going to take a lot of work
but it's up to you you meet all of us to
do it the right way if you do it and you
build it the right way it's going to
work out you know don't sell yourself
out man don't sell yourself short don't
just do the right thing and that's
that's those come from like when you
enlist in the military you know veterans
the army we have our core values loyalty
Duty respect selfless service honor
integrity and personal courage you know
I mean like and those are you know
ingrained in us in basic training let
alone you go to combat you get to the
point where you know you're willing to
die for your country you know like
there's a liberation in that moment that
you just you know you make peace with
your I made peace with my maker out
there understand like this is what it is
there are bad people doing bad things
here regardless of what the government
initiative is if I see I'm here to stop
evil my job is it's my job and there is
such a
beauty in living your truth that you
know when like I used to just look at
the flag on my arm and just thank God
look at you know in combat because you
get to a point where at least for me I'm
a field artillery better and you know
it's our job
you know most it up and seeking the sure
that you know and we were tasked with
securing Baghdad so we did more infantry
operations than anything raised and all
that stuff and you get to a point where
death it's it's just you know quick-draw
man at the end of the day it's 50/50 and
you also realize that the brother next
to you if anything there assists are
next to anything was to be put in that
person's way of harm that giving your
life for that person like is naughty
it's it's just that's what's so hard for
veterans to articulate is that that bond
is so real that like if there's a
grenade and you see it rolling towards
you there there's just there's it's it's
done it's yes it's like it's already
done like it's just at that point and
die for you bro and so that love you
know that's why when we like you ever
want to see a grown man cry fill his
brother in combat goes that's a pain you
know that never goes away and so when we
come back we're confused
because warriors don't cry yeah we you
know you know I mean because we're human
and so it's getting the veteran to
understand that just because you're not
valued by your country as you should be
warrior right like thousands of years
ago you know you would come home and you
would have land and you would have you
know things you'd be set for life
you'd be gilded whatever the case may be
but now you know there is that doesn't
exist but it can we know there's two
hundred thousand veterans coming out of
service let's create as many operations
as possible to make sure that if the
private sector won't hire no cares
create you know proud hempcrete that's
why I want how am I gonna help reduce
you know the veteran homeless issue
let's build some asses let's get it done
and then that connects to that as well
right
and let's and you leverage like when I
go to go to DC or I go to Tallahassee
and I speak to these lots it for the
lawmakers and stuff you know I just put
it too in black and white I said listen
guys I'm here not for me I'm here with a
bunch of veterans on my back you don't
see they're being ignored so when I'm
coming to talk to these politicians I
said look at the end of the day this is
a rights from right from wrong issue man
and you need to explain to me why right
now you'll make it available for
veterans to go get a narcotic but they
still can't get medical cannabis so I
say look you support me and you support
what I'm fighting for
or you're turning your back and that's
the leverage we have to put on them and
that's why I love all them see you
basically you hold them accountable at
the end of the day you have influence
that I don't and there are people that
are suffering and they can't be here to
tell you that so are you willing to make
the change or not and don't give me a
political response give me the real yes
or no that's it and that's what they
feel but we're here today you're doing
it
so we got to do it's too late we're
entering a new decade like if you think
about like the trajectory of what's
going on right there just like a
subculture that has just pretty much
gotten to a point where we can really
make some influence and we can do some
things the misfits made a you know what
I mean in a way and so heading into a
new decade
let's already start on you know this
decade in the last decades man have been
pretty bad why don't we just start the
new one just crushing it already
establishing we've always had the
opportunity to be the next greatest
generation you know we're educated we've
educated ourselves you know how to use
the internet we can just go away so
we're not dumb you know the smoke and
mirrors effect is gone for them and now
it's up to us yeah I think we know and
they the thing is now it's like it's
openly like just chaos it's like this is
what it is guys sorry at least you know
we're attempting to cover shit up but
yeah it's pretty bad and that's what
should motivate you know that's just as
much it's like you know what speak up
man
oh yes so my organization's mission zero
ww0 us my wife and I started it 2018 and
I put my corporate career you know we
let the house go move back in with my
mom like just the straight grinds you
know last two years just leap of faith
like I'm on a mission to end veteran
suicide you know it's over 8,000 of us a
year committing suicide I know I can't
do it alone I've learned through this
journey more about altruism and wanting
to just do things for the greater good
so mission zero is my organization I
just self published my first book
congratulations two works two weeks ago
it's on Amazon it's called pg-13 okay a
combat veterans 13 steps towards
personal growth yeah shout out to Amazon
for that they I wrote the manuscript
like two years ago and I just put it out
so I have a book on now it's called
pg-13 just self-published man just
follow the steps on Kindle
self-publishing like what's it about
it's it's kind of like a little helpers
guys you know for vets it's you know got
13 different chapters and I pretty much
when I wrote it two years ago I wrote it
like with this intention like if this
was ever to be a book like I really I'm
gonna put my heart and soul into it so I
have chapters on like faith and money
can't buy happiness for example is one
of them because I made a lot of money
you know I I made it to what I thought
was a Thompson in that chapter I talked
about look guys like it's not so much
about wanting to make money it's like
what's your intention once you have it
like that's where that lesson you know
because I want to guide people in the
right mindset so I put it together man
it's got five star reviews a few
veterans there was a veteran that put a
review on there he no one personally
went to combat together but he wrote
he's read it three times already and he
sent me a message saying that any time
he feels alone he breaks the book out
it's on Amazon it's on Amazon yeah just
focus on ya it's PG - 13 hos a ballon Jo
se ve le n you know Kindle just has an
opportunity for people that want to try
to put their own books out and if it
sells it sells you know it it it's like
a seed man you got a plan it