i wasn't in this game two years ago i've
been i'm an underground grower you know
and have been in the
in the traditional market for over 45
years and
coming out and meeting like guys like
colin and cam over the last couple years
has really helped me understand where
the markets morphed into
and what i really appreciate appreciate
about what you're doing is
and what i believe is critical at this
point is we need to be
preaching out and teaching out uh
correct information there's so much bad
information out there absolutely
yeah that's what i'm seeing people
people hurting themselves on oils that
they don't
understand that that's an internal and
you're not supposed to smoke the damn
thing
you know and and like my practice i'm
holistic wildcraft organic
my working with cam he's where i am as
far as our methodologies with plants
grow
and just so you understand i've been
smoking this plant since 1970
and for me this has been my lifeline
because i never really was into alcohol
and i've done all the other drugs in the
70s i'm a 70s era vet
i'm a old airborne combat engineer
uh and green brave anyway
different world different life but
stepping out of that time period is what
helped me
uh embrace the plant and and learn to
grow the plant was the fact that i could
grow a grow my own medicine be knew
exactly where it came from
you know knew that it was that i'm the
guy you don't know what's going on
at that whole thing so that's a lot of
where i am with it right now is trying
to teach people i want to teach people
how to grow their own plant and if they
can't
grow their own plant have access to
stuff like what i do and what cam
does and what colin is a proponent for
and what you are preparing it for is
high quality fresh medicine
that comes from a reputable source that
we know is clean
and that you know the end result is is i
get i get that it's an intoxicant but we
use this as a
medicinal purpose to keep ourselves
balanced and regulated and and some of
the things i put in that
text i put the other day because it's
part of my journey is
this has kept me you know i'm
i'm a trained killer sister and it's
taken me
50 years to get out of that mindset
okay and i approached the plant keeps me
i was never afraid of ever killing
myself
my biggest fear was always that i would
do something in a
short moment of losing my grasp on
things
and hurt somebody or worse kill somebody
and then spend my whole damn life in a
six by nine and that's always been my
biggest
biggest biggest concern of why i've
isolated myself and you know i'm in
rural northern
humboldt county you know i'm not down in
la i'm not in san diego
hell i'm not even i'm four hours north
of santa rosa where kevin you last like
four hours
tops in these cities i've seen it he can
last like four hours tops and i don't
blame you one bit
you know that's hard it it's
[Music]
and why i love colin so much is i
understand
his choice of being out in nature
because that's how i healed myself was
having my hands in the dirt my feet
barefoot on the ground and working
mother ganja with my hands and learning
to love her and appreciate her for what
she really is and i
and why i address it with people this is
a sacred
sacred plant this is not this is not
some kind of
it's been demonized for only about 80
frickin years is the part that pisses me
off i'm generationally a seven you know
i was a young man in the 70s so i saw
this plant being demonized
in night you know that people don't get
it though the law only goes back the
last
freaking schedule one thing that's 1970.
that's only 50 fripping years ago that's
not like that was long ago when you talk
about a plant that's been used on this
planet for
a conservatively six to seven thousand
years concern
you know i'm seeing all kinds of crazy
documentation now i read an article the
other day where they were going back
into biblical times
and finding the plant on altars that
goes back before christ was born you
know so there's
there's all these things that and me
personally i'm going to get way off on
under tangent here but i believe the
anointed one was
anointed with holy cannabis oil and
that's how i look at it
i believe that myself as well so and i'm
glad you brought that up because one of
the things that i do preach all the time
is the fact
that this plant was here way before
anyone of us that is alive today
and will continue to be even after we're
gone
but there's nothing that we can do about
that
but actually embrace it in our humanity
and be
able to make this world a better place
not only
as in the person as medicine that you
use
but also um as an eco-friendly crop that
can potentially save our environment
and give us all a better quality of life
you don't have it's not about
consumption it's about the potential
and how it can actually in essence i
know it may sound out there but save the
world
there's so many industries that right
now if they use
the fiber for for the plant then
it it would take it to to a next level
and at the same time
help uh the rest of the world
so you know this is we should not take
this lightly that's that's usually how i
preach it
amen yeah i i think i think it's kind of
and i guess part of what i've realized
is i would have been about you know i
got out of the traditional market after
my military time and i just i focused on
just
underground i mean i was literally pre-2
000 you couldn't find me i was in a
four-by-five little box in willits
california
you know and if anybody's ever been to
willis before that is a
weed community that nothing else really
pushes that little town anymore other
than the plant
and that's kind of again that whole
neigh that whole community is here you
know i am a long bale boy man you know i
am
i was raised in yokai i am a norcal
through and through you know i've left
and traveled the world i've come
back to this area and retired here and
been in this craft
for decades and decades now and it's
like watching where it's
morphed from back when i first got into
it
to where it's transitioned about 10 or
15 years ago when i you know i love
these youngsters ago i've been in it
since it was legal it's like you haven't
done
shit you know you got into a game after
we forged with our blood sweat and tears
jail time personally i've been throwing
in the been locked up for
you know they took five years of my life
back in the mid 80s guys you know over
this plant
three quarters of an ounce that's the
crazy part of this
in 33 states that's a ticketable or
misdemeanor offense
and they threw me in freaking prison
over it you know and it's like i look at
it now where how it shifted so much it's
like
there's so me it's the love of the plant
what it does how it helps us all
regardless of how you use it don't you
don't have to use
do it the way i do it do it the way that
it works for you i have friends that
i've worked with from
childhood epilepsy to a buddy i'm
helping with crohn's disease right now
and i assure you my partner with crohn's
is not using the plant to get high
he's juicing the freaking green leaves
making smoothies out of him he's
drinking it internally because of the
all the the the high medicinal value
that the whole plant has that's
again that's where this thing what i
realized a couple years ago because i
wish
dr sue was here and maybe we could get
ethan in on one of these conversations
in the future
but this is a point where that we've
taken old hippie you know
a bunch of old slacker hippies come hang
out with me for a summer and do 3
000 hours in the hot sun on the side of
a mountainside i'll show you what lazy
is
you know and i'm a mid i'm in my mid 60s
now you know it's like
this is this is not a yeah it's not a
lazy man's game you know
it is the ones that are just their true
true craft professional cannabis growers
in the emerald triangle
what cam preaches what i preach what we
do as a craft
it comes out in our flower quality and
that's what i tell i mean
again i'm going to shut up and let colin
can speak firsthand brother you you know
you've smoked my flowers before cam you
smoked my flowers
oh yeah they're wonderful well we also
need to get rid of this differentiation
between
recreational and medicinal it's all
therapeutic
and it's been used for you know all of
human history
as a food and fiber and fuel and a
medicine
and and a way to become spiritual in our
own way and
it's only been like you said the last 80
years that we've been without this
an interesting thing and i'm not saying
causation correlation
but we have had forever that um it's
only in the last several decades that
we're starting to see these autoimmune
diseases we're starting to see allergies
we're starting to see these things
where our bodies attack themselves and
we don't really have a written record of
something like that
previously but we've also had uh
cannabinoids in our diet for all of
human history
and yeah i can hear my dad saying well i
never touched it my grandfather never
touched it i was like
no but your livestock ate feral hemp if
your life stops eating feral hemp
and your chickens are eating the seeds
and your goats are eating it so you're
getting cannabinoids through your milk
through your dairy through your meat
from that and acidic cannabinoids in the
raw form are
very effective at much smaller doses to
find that homeostasis in our body and so
i think we're having to re-learn what
we've forgotten throughout all human
history
and you were talking about uh you know
finding biblical evidence
uh then uh what was it uh exodus 30
23 it talks about the holy anointing oil
well there was a mistranslation in the
early text of the bible in a septuagint
where they changed
calamus to cannabosin or vice versa
and there is references all throughout
the bible
by how much cannabis how many shekels it
costs to put it in the holy anointing
oil
and so if you're seeing you know ancient
things about jesus
bringing sight to the blind or he's
healing leprosy or he's casting out
demons
well if you have ocular pressure you're
going to be blind with glaucoma and if
you're anointed with cannabis oil
reducing the ocular pressure you get
sight to the blind
leprosy which covered all kinds of skin
conditions but if you put a topical
ointment of acidic cannabinoids even
decarboxylated cannabinoids
on any kind of dermatitis or or
some sort of skin condition it heals
fairly quickly so healing leprosy
children or people with epilepsy having
seizures could absolutely look like
being possessed by a demon
give them raw acidic cannabinoid whole
plant wonderful goodness
and you'll see a reduction in seizures
or casting out demons
now i'm not saying that's exactly what
it is but you know you got to look at
all the evidence and where we've come
from and all the altars
where they were burning seeds they were
burning this as part of a spirituality
but we've only had 80 years of
misinformation disinformation
propaganda and bullshit and we've got 80
years
in 80 years yeah in only 80 years that's
what people don't get it's like this is
only since the late the early 1930s that
this has all
changed this hasn't even been in a 100
year time period you know and i and
and again i get i get it i just don't
understand it and
you know it might to get it part is it's
all about greed and it's all about
corruption and control okay and what
we've realized now what cam hit it
totally on the head
and joanne and that colony i know you
guys know this too
we're talking about a plant that is food
medicine
fiber fuel rubber concrete
all these things all these industries
that it spills into now it's why they
it's greed they want to keep it
demonized so that people stay away from
it
you know i'm glad to see that we got
industrial hemp out of that loop and put
back into a textile that it could be
used as
and again breeders that want to breed
that thread and go
into cbd specific strains for
research and development for medical
applications to do that you know
i'm totally glad to see that that
happens and it keeps going that way you
know for me
and then for cam and and you guys too
because you guys use the plan and i know
what what colin
you know what his threat is and how what
he preaches and follows and i believe
that
in colin's mission so much it's beyond
words you know
i believe in colin's mission so much
that i drove down
750 miles one way two years ago and
brought my flowers down for his birthday
just to go hang out with him
okay and that's what my connection to
him is and
and him like a lot of people don't know
he literally knows where i
live you know in just when i told him
where i live he's got all my yeah that's
where i want to retire to i
you know that's kind of how we are drawn
together and i know colin's backstory
and he knows mine
and again we shared a similar path of
how we
went through the military and you know
his sister i don't know yours but i have
two daughters that are freaking
veterans you know and i already know
what women endure going through the
military and i
applaud you so much for what you endured
to get to where you are
and to be able to use your platform now
as a military veteran to help bring in
other
female veterans into this mix and just
it just
as a whole to you know to get it beyond
this isn't a wee thing this isn't a me
thing or i think this is a wee thing
where we can touch
a lot of people and yeah this is the
community thing thank you
it kills me you know i i because you
know
just briefly you know i got
i've been blown up twice fragged once
you know i've jumped
out of airplanes i got bad shoulders bad
knees but anyway long story short
the the regime was 750 milligram
vicodins on a 90 count on with an
unlimited supply and go home and lay on
the fricken floor
that was the recourse of western
medicine and i just wasn't gonna buy
that you know
and i don't take synthetics you know i
drink coffee i smoke my fine herb that i
produce
myself and that's about it i take
occasionally if my joints are really
really killing me i might take a little
leave or something for just
until i get to sleep but other than that
i really don't take a whole lot of
plethora of things that they want the va
has issued
you know i'm a 100 pink card carrying
member and i'm not
retired you know i'm 100 disabled i'm
not
you know i didn't make 20 years of this
i did my first tour and they damn near
killed me in my first two or three times
you know and that
that was it for me you know it's like i
got out and it's like
and have been where you guys are now
we're not not acknowledgement within the
va says i'm getting off point here a
little bit but it still rounds back to
this because i
meet young men and women that are you
guys age range now where
they're getting the same kind of
treatment i was getting back in the 9
80s and 90s when all i really wanted was
i blew shit up for a living all i wanted
was hearing aids
you know that's all i ever asked for was
hearing aids and now they owe me 100
because they wouldn't give me hearing
aids 30 years ago okay
that's just how but i hear the same
stories from young
men and women like the ones that are
getting out today
that they don't know they're they're
we're all damaged and i tell
anybody over about the age of 18 you get
out on your own
everybody has pts everybody
you know even if you live silver spoon
in your life and you were
coddled until your 21st birthday as soon
as you walked out the door somebody
punched you in your teeth
that's just the fact of life that's just
that just how it is you know
then so when i yeah
yeah you're you're absolutely right
joanne can you please cut in on any of
this
thank you well i so what i wanted to say
with respect to
my mission and what i'm doing is just i
want this information that we're having
these discussions
i want the people to be able to hear
this information because you know you
guys have been doing this for
decades there's people before you that
have been doing it as well this is
nothing new this information um
has been here like we said you mentioned
biblical times potentially back then um
this was utilized to help people
so as far as me yes um as a military
service member i had my issues
almost lost my life as well um and
cannabis saved me
after i got out where i was lost um
with ptsd anxiety um from
an accident that i suffered a concussion
lost the english language for almost 20
minutes
um then got out and
was in a dark cloud in my head that i
didn't know what to do
fortunately and randomly met somebody
who introduced me to cannabis
for medicinal purposes which honestly
it was meant to be because i'm pretty
sure based on my background you know
growing up
christianity you know and being drilled
that cannabis is a drug
and you already know the the narrative
there
um if it was introduced as something
like we're doing it
for fun likely i may have
not gone that route but i met a grower
like you guys who takes this very
seriously
that understand that whether you do this
you know when you sit on the couch just
or
because you are um looking to cure
to cure your cancer get through chemo or
something like that it's medicinal um
in in because at the end of the day
we're doing it to feel better to get to
a better
mental state or physical or emotional
for that matter
um so in that introduction um
i felt so much better like almost
immediately
mentally after three years
of being in that cloud and
i decided that i would make this my
mission you know
to to battle the misinformation because
then i started doing my own research and
one thing led to the next and then
you know the whole um if if we were
talking touching back on
what doc was saying here greed and just
uh business you know people
wanting to destroy other industries
obviously cannabis is something that
people can grow at home
if you have land you can grow cannabis
and help a lot of people
so i feel like people back in the day
you know we have the paper industry we
have
the plastics industry we have all these
other industries
that wanted to make money and this crop
is
cheaper and and to to grow and it grows
faster um it was just a
agreed you know in capitalism that
created that narrative that cannabis was
bad obviously you know
we cannot deny there was some racist
undertone as well
in denying all of that so
it's about we're in the era of
information
so i think with all the technology that
we have right now
and all the true anecdotes of real
people like yourselves like myself that
we can say hey
i am alive and this happened to me and i
have all this evidence
and i am not the only one um so that's
like what we're doing with with
veterans walk and talk with cannabis
synergy obviously you guys
and i think the fact that we can come
together
to have these conversations and then um
share it with our respective communities
i feel like
because we're not lying you know this is
actually
the fact um i think that
we it's gonna spread so i'm i'm very
hopeful for the near future
that we can um continue to have this
conversations get more people involved
you know um the the in in other
in all the areas whether it's science
whether it is
um entertainment education business
um cannabis pretty much touches on
everything
um and we we have so much opportunity
and i'm i'm glad that we're seizing it
so
thank you for having me here doc can you
give your
like returning from war and kind of
setting up
you know in humboldt and you know
growing you want yeah i mean if that's
what you want peter
yeah i i i'd like to i i'd like to hear
your story and your focus
on creating medicine for yourself and by
extension
medicine that then helped other people
well that's
is as it's turning out that's what and
so so
as breeding like you know what have you
noticed
like oh i created this plant and it
really helped me with
x and i noticed that it had these
terpenes or whatever like
get into that stuff all right all right
are you talking about like right now or
what no no
like in the beginning and then kind of
your journey of of uh
like discovering that if i breed in this
direction
like it helps me more with ptsd or pain
or
sleep or whatever and you you came back
from what it was vietnam i assume right
well i'm the end of vietnam
i'm the very tail end of it
i'm considered a cold war green beret
what they call a cold war commando i'm
an unknown variable and have we have
been up until about
2013 i was an unknown variable in the
military system
most military quite honestly 99.9
doesn't even know what we did because of
such this
that behind the freaking scenes
yeah so long story short i did
extractions and then from extractions i
moved over to europe where i was doing
working in northern africa
working in all all across europe
fighting what we consider the
uh red menace the communist bloc
that whole part of it i did two
different times
when i returned from that i basically
got kicked out in in
fort dix new jersey as a
22 year old not quite 23 year old
completely messed up young man that
didn't have a clue because everything
that i believed to be true and
fighting for truth justice in the
american way when i got
overseas realized that it was a bunch of
bullshit
after a few years of time it was really
hard for me to
get beyond i was real angry when i came
back you know and
and why i isolated myself so much
because it was so
s it was bullshit you know i knew it was
bullshit
i saw it it it crushed me you know it
really crushed me on a spiritual level
and an emotional level
and then to lose brothers in arms in in
behind the scenes as in a thing in 79
called eagle claw
desert one was the attempt to remove the
iranian hostage cri
iranian hostages ours people out of that
building
we were the group that women in the very
first joint task force ever for the
united states military the very very
first one jtf-179 you know it was what
spun the
160th soar off of that the 75th rangers
marine recon
all kinds of crazy shit stuff that
happens within the navy now that was
more from that original
mission where nobody even knew about it
you know
we crashed in the desert and lost
a half a dozen brothers and i personally
was on a team that was on the ground and
we had packed in
stealthy from freaking pakistan you know
it's like
to get where we were to be outside of
tehran and then shit blow up and be told
that we were on our own
and nobody knew we were there and
basically get your own fucking ass out
it's it's a it's a tough thing to
swallow you know to be to be
left and we were left in any way
breathe brother brief
i'm not a joke
you have any weed on hand doc of course
i've always got weed on hand i always
have weeds you know okay
all right you're within our 60s now you
know we're all in our mid 60s now
and i just realized that i have a
brother that's down in santa cruz that
he put
he was the one side of the team that the
six of us there was seven of us you know
there was only seven of us on the ground
and we basically were just
denied by our country
you're a survivor you're still here
and you guys are dealing with it too you
know you guys there's nothing's changed
you guys come back and you're denied
like we were denied in the 80s you know
it's like
i got out in 82 you know after after
a stupid six years and got out in 82 and
all i really and i went in 88 just to
get
my ears because i couldn't hear anything
you know and like deny deny denied and i
see that happening again
and i and what peter basically asked me
is what happened is like you know i
i said fuck this and unplugged and moved
off into the middle of nowhere by myself
okay and i was getting getting
flour from people you know getting flour
from people
it was okay but it was seedy weeds you
know and i was just starting there
weren't any books back then you know we
were just starting to figure out things
you know and separating males from
females and all you know i'm self-taught
you know but now my now i have a
breeding cannabis breeding company that
represents my flower line you know and
my
and my lawyers tell me i'm one of a
handful of guys that do what i do in the
world you know
and i have i have been
phenomenal hunting specifically for over
35 years now or
excuse me chemovar specific hunting for
over 35 years on pheno specific types of
cannabis
and it goes back to when what peter said
how you know i smoked the first joint in
70 and started growing my first plant in
about 72.
you know and it was trial and error and
back then it was you know
acapulco gold and colombian red
and and highland silver thai coming over
from overseas and things like that is
how what
and in mexican brown wheat coming from
down south you know
so there was this influx and then where
i'm at specifically
just happens to be the heart of the
emerald triangle you know where i
where i grew up and where i found my
sanity and what i consider my home in my
sanctuary you know it's like
that moment in time when i was it
actually was in right after i got out of
prison and i
was the only one that was able to take
care of my mother who was going through
breast cancer and i became her primary
caregiver for about 16 months
and that was me taking her back to
chemotherapy every day and
dealing with her double mastectomy
taking my mother that i love dearly and
taking her in and you know getting this
luck coming back at the end after chemo
and having to deal with her being sick
anyway this old man back then was a
young man
i decided to take old school hippie
therapy
and you know we worked where she ate
about a quarter of a brownie
you know and it helped me get her
through her being sick partying keeping
her appetite up
and you know a quarter of brownie when
she went in and a quarter when she came
out
about a happy brownie anyway this was
just how i started getting into the
medical application of this thing
and then for me for my own damage was
i didn't even really know what it was to
answer peter's question i didn't even
know what it was quite honestly guys it
was
i just knew that and you guys get it
right that decompression that you get
from a when you that you don't get from
alcohol
and you don't get from pills and you
don't get from other synthetics and you
don't get from speed or heroin or
freaking coke or
it only comes through this plant even
meditating
it's decompression is what i call it now
as you
i and i've seen this and i've seen this
with other men and women in the military
it's like go
go be with them and literally a buddy of
mine it's like take a hit off a joint
and literally
in a in a combat bet 30s
good guy a lot a lot of tough situations
in his military career
turned into alcohol and painkillers and
was hating him hating his life hating
his world
literally a guy my age but he hears his
big
brother said dude you need to smoke a
joint well long story short
now he's using the plant using the
sacred plant for his
daily working on it every day to get
better and better
that being said him to me smoking one of
my joints walking on collins deal
homeboy started crying you know laughing
and crying he said you know i haven't
cried and laughed in over three freaking
years man
and that was to me one more verification
that this
is medicine that this is a holistic
tool that we can use a natural and like
calling what i love about
natural plant medicine you know
pick it yourself grow it yourself raise
it yourself
you know make it do it yourself then you
know where it comes from you know and i
get not everybody can do that
joanne what you said sister i 100 agree
with
i can teach people how to grow in a
coffee can if they really want to know
and get them an
ounce of fine fine flour off of a coffee
can
you know yeah you start them off with
this apartment i just have a little two
by four
sun area in my back you can do it you
know
there's bonsai what i breed specifically
now is i
breed short structured plants designed
for mom and pops to be cultivated in two
to three gallon pots
and yielding three to eight ounces
depending on what your skill
level is so for a mom and pop to have
you know like
we're here anyone over 21 six plants
you know mom and pop with skills 12
plants that's a lot of freaking flower
if you know what the hell you're doing
or you don't even have to know what
you're doing just
be willing to learn how to do it you
know and
hitting me what i teach now and have for
yours is how to grow your own you know
me with what cam and i are working on
specifically is to get my flowers out
and
he does such beautiful work anyway i
just i'm so honored to even have an
opportunity that he and i are getting a
partner together
just you know it's like
if i well i have been i have picked a
business partner is cam hat and i'm
thankful for it you know and that's how
i look at this you know it's like if i
was going to pick somebody would be cam
him and his wife you know what they do
for their business model is so clean and
so pure and from a point of love and
it's like
you know just you know we're we really
try we and we're not out there you know
that's part of people that don't know
who high tide bistro is and they don't
know
who i am yeah i just sent flowers to a
we lost her brother down south i just
sent flowers to their group so they
would have
something to use for their for their
healing you know it's like
he and i this thing we're doing we're we
making agreements and he's aligning with
other veterans nonprofits where we're
going to be giving flour away
every damn month you know and we're not
talking about giving away
quarterbacks honey we're gonna be giving
away pounds of freaking fire white
because we're gonna try and grow
thousands and thousands of pounds of
flour next year to put into this threat
okay that's what we're working on right
now
you know and and and i love him so much
and i have such tremendous love for
colin and sister i'm so thankful for you
to be in on this thing today with us
you know i'm so i'm so honored that
you're part of our conversation and
and i'm getting off point here but my
cultivating
flowers specifically was about 16
17 years ago i got in 03
and again this is before a lot of people
like you before you were in this craft
you know 17 years ago most likely you
know it's like
in 2001 september the 11th happened
everybody shut down and internalized the
market
it's a luxury based item the market
crashed you know i watched flower my
flower go from five to six
thousand dollars a pound of coffee to
under three thousand dollars a pound and
it was still
the three to three three to thirty two
hundred hours a year it was to take to
make the damn thing get done
full sun this is before light depth you
know
this was before greenhouses full sun
outdoor
just the way mother nature and god
almighty intended it to be
you know 20 footers 16 foot wide 20 feet
tall that kind of crazy stuff right
that's how i anyway my old lampard and i
between 03 and 05 the market tumbled
tumbled bad from
33 000 or so where i believe is a fair
marketable price where a farmer can make
a living is about three thousand dollars
a pound wholesale that's a
reasonable rate there's a lot of money
left at a three thousand dollar price
point
a lot of money left for a retailer to
make a killing when they're charging
brothers and sisters
25 30 35 40 50 a gram
i know my flowers on the east coast on
both ends of it
and they get 35 to 50 a gram for my
frickin flowers
it's ridiculous okay i'm getting way off
another tangent my point is
this portion of reading specifically you
guys is this is what i've been working
on
for me specifically for two decades
you know threes 03 03-06
i got was getting out of the market well
we grew so much weed it took me three
years to get rid of it guys
you know and i just couldn't do it
anymore because it was the same i was
working 12 months out of the year
i got my old school and people don't
even know that you know
my old plant was from a buddy of mine
called old dave
okay old dave who has been gone for over
10 years is the original creator of the
razzleberry kush
okay and dave
has been gone for a decade and that one
of my mentors with long story short
my skunk og plant that would just lay
your ass out it still does it puts you
on a couch in about 20 minutes
my friend that very dear friend of mine
that's
a blue dream the creator of blue dream
she gifted me
a plant of female and i took as
something to do because i was
wasn't growing and she said you need
something to do here smoke this
blue dream's a beautiful cerebral smoke
it's really good for clearing your head
finding your balance it doesn't put you
on the couch i don't know all the
cbd thc but i do know what the effects
are
okay so her plant with
my old day plant which i call my og
skunk
okay what was called the mendo skunk
cam probably gets it because he's old
enough to get it he knows what the
mendocino peace plant was all about
you know the mendo skunk that's one of
my legacies you know i'm a creator of
team of creators on a lot of strains
that are
unknown the unknown breeders you know
the green mountain growers group
before you guys even before cam was born
you know it's like
these as my 40 year old son says to me
you mean before me dad and it's like yes
i'm before you
so that being said that
plant that combination and 13 14 years
of breeding is what's releasing now is
my what i call my blue skunk strain
and that is a very much created for
post-traumatic stress
for with physical damage this is
something you can smoke that clears your
head you can smoke it or vape it clears
your head
clears your consciousness and in about
20 minutes later all of a sudden you go
oh my shoulder doesn't hurt anymore man
and my back isn't aching anymore
now this is just me what's happened in
the last two years is me taking
that plant and getting it out to people
across our state and across the country
and getting the same results back from
veteran brothers and sisters going
i'm getting the same results and now in
the last since the end of
last year since the emerald cup now
breeders best is my breeding company
they're
they're helping me with patenting and
branding and and that puts me in the
same
rooms with ethan russo the neurologist
cannabis guy in the freaking country
you know it puts me in the same room
with sue sisley the
woman that's leading the fight for
post-traumatic stress
therapy cannabis therapy for veterans
she's the one suing
the va on our behalf right now you know
and them to me
they want to be where i'm at that's what
i got incept
in over in the earlier part of the year
was sue coming and searching me out with
dale so they could sit down with me you
know because they know that they're
hearing about what my flowers are doing
and that's what i'm trying to get
from this obscurity that i'm in this
unknown variable i'm in not and i don't
even care about me
it is not about money to me this is
about helping men and women helping
brothers and sisters and
arms specifically military veterans
first responders anybody in
crisis that's what my threat is and i'm
not again
i get it yes it's recreational yes you
can but that's not my thread
my agreement with my breeding company is
i can stay
conservatively stay 70 or more in the
medical field
only 20 to 30 percent of my flowers will
ever hit the recreational market and
very very on a limited scale
i want to keep it in that thread i don't
want it to go that way
you know personally for me it's about
the quality of the flower it's about
that
initial intake you know it's like
something again where cam and i
are very you know we age weed for so
long people
can't even get how long we cure our
flowers you know they don't even
understand it i'm pulling out stuff
exactly well you can sister but again
you understand it
you know and that's what i i welcome and
hope i want to see
you teaching this out i know colin
teaches this out about
how to look at plants and you know how
you know how do we bridge that gap you
know how do we get it out where
well i'm hoping this is a first step now
that you know you and i are in the same
realm
it's like we have you have act sister
you have access to a grower in humboldt
county now
i can't wait to go over there
no because i feel like this is this is
all in enlightenment i feel like we're
all in alignment in our mission
and obviously coming together would just
give it more power and reach more people
um that we're trying to help you know um
this is like you said
personal agenda or anything like that
like like i said earlier we can't take
this slightly like if we have
um this information that can help so
many people you know that you guys are
putting into work
intentionally you know to solve
all of our problems i mean even if
we just talk to veterans like we are
doing
such a service um through our community
to our people that
we know what it is in so many levels you
know
you don't have you didn't for a person
like
in the military i know people that
didn't get blown up didn't get blown by
air aircraft jet blast like i did for
instance
but they went through other stuff that
is
traumatic like it's trauma you know and
uh where they're everywhere
absolutely and like you said every
military person i believe it's everybody
you know even if you were a desk jockey
somewhere man or you know or you were
just looking at the screen
okay i i'm only saying this because i
have female
you know i have daughters that are
veterans you know i just know what kind
of harassment there was you know i just
understand that kind of nonsense you
know and that's the part
again i took my girls knew how to whip
your ass about the time they were about
16.
you know it's like you want to smart off
to me man i'll pop you right in your
jaws
you know and that's not it it's
important
it is it's it i mean no offense joanne i
call
girl
i want to get it out there you know we
need to get this out there as a
community you know
you're doing it i know cam's doing it
colin's doing it every damn week man i
see what
what walking talk does all across the
country the tremendous things that he's
doing just
reaching brothers and sisters in crisis
and literally in the trenches
that's the part that i love about what
colin does so much it isn't talking the
talk he is literally out there
seriously walking walking in the walk
yeah i'm walking right behind him
he's definitely leading a lot of us
so so just quickly doc i think you
you touched on a couple of things that i
think are critical i mean one you were
kind of like
learning on the fly about something you
didn't even know about
like you know i mean i think you you had
an intuitive sense that this was a
medicine
but then you started you know breeding
with intent in certain directions
towards you know easing your physical
pain your mental pain
you know different chemo types that
maybe you started to
realize oh my god like this super knock
you out on the couch
is great for x but it's horrible for y
and i'm gonna breed something else
that's great for y but maybe not good
for
x um it's what i'm doing now peter
it's i mean it's my focus now you know i
have more science behind it now and i
can actually you know i can go in and
look at the structural makeup of it and
go okay
i'm looking for cbg or cb cbd v
now which is really what i'm tripping
looking for okay
honestly what i'm looking for so that's
good that's where this right
but but but but back in the day you
didn't have that vocabulary
at all cbg cbn
like uh whatever and so it's kind of
it's interesting once you start to gain
that vocabulary and meet people like
ethan russo or sue sisley and
you know i feel like now we're fast
forwarded in a moment where
you're armed with kind of a team of
scientists behind you who can articulate
what your
all of you are seeing anecdotally i
think that's the big
thing here is you know pharmaceutical
medicine is kind of
top down a company spends a billion
dollars to get something approved for a
specific disease or condition whereas
cannabis is kind of bottom up where you
have
you know thousands or tens of thousands
of caregivers
noticing things with themselves and
their friends
and initially not having a way to
verbally articulate it but i think now
kind of the vocabulary is coming
and and and uh can can you and cam
just quickly touch on what happens when
you
cure flower for a longer period of time
in terms of medicinal effects okay
sure uh here this is again this goes
back to what peter just was talking
about this goes back to what
and something that i practice and i know
cam practices and most of us here in the
triangle practice is craft
okay what i realized a couple of years
ago
and this is what we need to do as a
community and another thing we need to
embrace sister and something that you
can do and colin can do is we can teach
out that white white
dabs are not necessarily anything other
than
immature flowers okay
the the the rich full spectrum plants
are amber in color those that gold
browns
rich and what i realized was and i was
talking to a
mutual friend of collins of mine because
i asked him what the hell man
you know where do i need to be if i'm
going to go into that market with my
flowers and he wants full spectrum
and he's literally told me this word for
word
and and uh calling it was blaze brother
i was talking to blaze on the phone and
he told me this and he said
that growers are harvesting anywhere
from two
three and even four weeks early to keep
the
pistols white and the trichomes white
and creamy so that when they crush it
and smash it and turn it into
whatever the hell they're turning it
into it stays white and creamy and hence
the visual
impression is oh my god it's so white
and clean it must be the best
that's like the farthest thing from the
truth of the matter really is because
when you get into like
rsos and fsos and full spectrum
concentrates
they're gold and rich and full and amber
colors and what peter was alluding to i
believe is what he was alluding to is
when when i'm in the fill watching that
i'm literally
okay i'm taking 48 years of experience
when i'm looking at my flowers in the
field per se but i have a
lighted microscope and a jeweler's loop
in my freaking pocket man you know
i only leave so much to sheer
instinct i'm go back and even when i'm
sure it's ripe i still go back in and
oscilloscope everything i pop my little
lighted microscope in there and look at
the trichome heads and see
you know in my six and b okay my rule of
thumb
60 to 65 70 clear 20 or so milky 10
red and burnt off that's me is optimum
cam that that's about identical to what
we do as well
you know so that what into what peter
was talking about
full spectrum you know how do we know
when it's optimum that's what we go
on most of the concentrate people that
i've talked to
and i talked to a couple of guys who are
really good at their craft you know they
have
huge followings online they they produce
lots and lots of material and they're
really good
and that's what they're telling me is
that clear stuff that's the commercial
stuff
is being harvested way way early i think
what we can do as a community and sister
your platform and calling
your platform brother is teach out that
what full spectrum really looks like you
know this is full spectrum
full term look how golden amber it is
look how beautiful this
cult this patina is on this you know i
have a sister that just sent me some
of hers from the middle of the country
over for me to look take a look at
and it's brown as it can be and it is
just delicious you know it smokes like
heaven
it is immediately just washes right over
you you know
and again another warrior veteran female
badass grower that i know that's a rock
star you know and sierra's just a
freaking killing it man you know and i
love what she does and that's just
that's again her what she teaches out
and what i teach out and cam and and i'm
assuming you are sister and and brother
carl and i assume you are as well you
know about whole plant medicine
and and and really what where it is for
me
personally is that's my main thread of
trying to
grow full term full spectrum
that has is rich in everything across
the board maybe high in some areas but
rich in everything across the board
because
that what i believe is the closest way
to heal ourselves
naturally with it and
joanne you said something and cam said
something both about it about the you
know we have
cannabinoid receptors in our bodies you
know it's like we're wired for this
stuff to think that it's not supposed to
be in our system it's just quite
honestly ridiculous in today's
scientific community medical community
you know back
and peter you said it earlier you know
back in the 70s and 80s man
we were outlaw you know we were
underground nobody knew who the hell we
were we only knew who each other were we
didn't put our names on stuff we didn't
advertise what we were growing
you know you advertised what you were
growing and you went to prison you know
that's just the truth of the matter you
know it's even happens now there's still
red states in our union that if they
advertise what they're doing they go to
prison over it
you know and it's like we're fortunate
to be in this state of california
why would why would like uh
right now why do you think people are
using the
white stuff as opposed to letting it get
the right color um ratio that you were
speaking about
um i feel like the white the the lighter
color is what i predominantly see
especially especially like in the legal
markets actually
that again that that is the commercial
legal market
that it is not crap what craft people do
right
it's it's it's it's harvested earlier
and to answer his question
and you said it too already joey you
already said it sister greed
grief and also like your education you
can do it quicker you can turn more you
can turn more volume over in the same 12
months you know the 12
same 12 months that cam and i would work
in where we would try and do maybe three
or four harvesters using the sun and
maybe a little light augmentation
doing a light depth outside and for what
we do
okay three or four times maybe in a year
commercially
every six weeks you know they're trying
to get six seven harvests in a year
because
again it's about greed and not about the
quality of the flower
and i and sadly i believe now i'm not
100 sure and i'm only going on by guys
that practice the craft
i'm not i'm a flower guy i'm not an
extraction whiz i i
you know the the guy that is that i have
connections to is a great extraction guy
that i
did i ask information from and that's
what he's telling me is
you know quicker harvest quicker return
less time in the ground
you know more more more more more
cheaper cheaper cheaper cheaper
and we have that i mean we really have
that we have that market that
they ten dollars a gram they don't give
a damn what it is they just want to get
high
that's not my thread that's not really
cam's thread i don't think it's you guys
have a newer thread either i get that
that's out there
but i believe what what you said what we
what we need to do is we need to teach
that that's not necessarily the best
and we can also say best but we can also
say different
because uh when we look at the
differences of those you also have the
people who insist that you have to have
flour that's over 20
thc and all of the research and all of
us know that use cannabis on a regular
basis
that some of the greatest strains are
you know seven to 15 percent thc
and so we're having to educate people
that more thc is not the end all be all
of the product
and so and this comes back to where you
were talking about full spectrum
we have to define these terms for
ourselves before other people's
other people define them that have no
business talking about it because they
don't have the experience in it so we
talking full spectrum
of an industrial hemp are we talking
full spectrum of an indoor grown clone
that's harvested at a specific time are
we talking about the full spectrum
of a beautiful cannabis plant that was
grown in full sun
in full soil and allowed to go to the
full term of its life expectancy
being buffeted by the wind and being
predated on by bugs and
and deer so that they respond and
produce more cannabinoids and more
terpenes
you know there's all different levels
and so we have to start coming up with
standardized
definitions of these so people can
understand what we're talking about
and when you spend all that time
outdoors making these beautiful plants
that the most robust broad spectrum that
you can
the better that you take care of them
post harvests
that once you harvest them that's the
halfway mark
now you've got to start working on
curing and making sure that you
stabilize all those cannabinoids and all
those terpenes that you allow them to
develop to their full potential
while degrading the things in the plant
that we don't want like the chlorophyll
so doc and i both do super long slow
cures where we leave the flower
untrimmed on the stick for months
in a dark space that is climate
controlled humidity temperature
airflow and i don't like to trim them
first i want
all of those small sugar leaves to cover
the trichomes
and protect them like a cocoon and let
them develop and
and they'll it's like a fine wine or a
fine tequila you know talk about the
colors
a blanco tequila is an un-aged tequila
it's raw
it's fresh it's young it's hoven
but as you age the can of the tequila
just like the cannabis it's going to
develop more
rich colors and you're going to get a
reposado or a niejo
style and the more that you allow the
cannabis to cure the more it's going to
develop into new things we're even
discovering
which is a prevalent a lot of handmade
temple ball hashes or charas
when you seal that hash in it still ages
and converts i have flour
you know i'm still smoking my pre-rolls
from three years ago that are developed
and they
they've just become so much more robust
but all of these parts of the plant that
there's better things for better people
somebody might need that that blonde
uh rosin uh that's got a lot of thca or
cbda or cbga the precursor acidic
cannabinoids
and then a lot of other people are going
to need a more robust profile that has a
lot more things in it
because our endocannabinoid systems are
extremely individual there's what
what works for one of us won't work for
another and so
um we just need to make sure that
everything that's going into the market
is clean and tested and
won't cause harm
so yeah as someone who spends a lot of
time testing different things that can
heal because i'm a self-rehabilitated
veteran
i wear that badge of honor proudly and
uh um
with cannabis in particular and you know
i don't want to get too into the weeds
with it but
you guys are hitting it on the head in
such an important topic because
for me for four years i have been trying
craft cannabis to dispensary cannabis
and everything in between
and i can tell you wholeheartedly now
that the past
month every time i dab or take a bond
load of a high thc
cannabis every issue i have is worse
my pain my depression my anger
my sadness all is compounded and through
my own personal research which i like to
do on my own
i have come to find that you know people
with a proclivity to
traumatic with traumatic brain injury in
their past with ptsd with brain
injury specifically the dopamine levels
affected by thc
can ultimately hinder your own
body's ability to make this so what
you're doing is you're spiking in and
out
and when you take that bond load you may
feel a little bit of relief at first but
four or five hours later your body is
not producing the same
levels of dopamine so then you're
crashing and this was happening to me
and that's why i'm off thc and i'm
specifically just taking
oils like fiddler's greens thc a acidic
thc now
and it has like night overnight i felt
better overnight
and um so it is scary to me and
the problem with that is and i come from
the cannabis compassionate world
is that um i have 200
over 200 active members of veterans walk
and talk throughout the nation
who for one reason or another need
cannabis to survive and when you
are facing them and they're coming to
your hikes and
i have to try to provide for them on on
a weekly basis when we're when we're
really active and all three of you have
hiked with us
and all three of you have donated to
veterans walk and talk
and so you know the need is great what
has happened now between the beauty
and the elegance of what doc ray and cam
do
between that and dispensaries it has
gotten completely convoluted with greed
and what happens is you get 39
cannabinoids um on the label when that
means
nothing to the average consumer and then
you get up people
like myself who take the time to try
every last product that they can
possibly find because
if you're putting it out in the cannabis
space i want to know about it
and i can tell you firsthand the
medicinal
side of cannabis has been completely
convoluted by the recreational side
it has set us back uh decades to be
honest
um the there's so much
inequality there's so much back and
forth
bullshit with the the research and the
denying of the research
that goes on in cannabis when we know
this plant works and we know it's
we know it needs to be made accessible
so
you guys being the pioneers of this and
empowering people to grow on their own
is imperative
um because the need is so great i i
can't turn away high thc
products if i'm getting them i can't i
can't be like this won't help my people
i i can't
i'm just not at that point because
cannabis
is the great unifier and it is also
in many ways for what i do for veterans
walk and talk
it is the healing basic basis of what we
do but it's also
in a lot of ways it's bait and it's a
way to get veterans
to learn that this is something that
they can
try but also get them to the group and
the community because
as i've said many times cannabis is
community
and whether you're consuming it properly
or not
you're getting medicinal value from it
all cannabis use is medicinal all
cannabis uses medicinal all cannabis use
is medicinal so like it's like saying
basketball isn't medicinal
yes it's a recreational sport you have
fun when you play it it doesn't mean
it's not a good thing for your body
so what i tell veterans
and that you guys thank you for all your
praise about veterans walk and talk
i have seen firsthand all three of you
uh cam you hiked with us in malibu i
think it was or
you came and sponsored an event in
malibu we did and docu-hike bridge to
nowhere and joanne and i have been
working hand-in-hand together for
many months now and have big plans um
i have never seen anything anything
like it it's it brings people to a place
of comfort with them within themselves
it brings people to a place where they
can
face like doc did and say things
that whether or not we are sitting
around in a table physically smoking
together cannabis is what brought us
all to this place right now and
empowered doc to share that for the very
first time
and those are the types of that's it
that's as powerful as it gets
with cannabis my role
in cannabis is compassion um
[Music]
i want to advocate for the plant the way
the plant advocates for me
and which is why i'm so honored to be
on a on a panel with you guys who
are because i know cam and doc
specifically and you guys can touch on
this later
but um getting an heirloom a province
the origin
established in humboldt is something
that i'm very
passionate about and i know you guys are
i've talked about this with me before
and um with veterans walk and talk in
particular
um it's gotten to the point
where if you're a veteran and you're not
taking
control of your own health then you're
going to fall under the va
and the va for me i am a 100
disabled combat veteran i
broke my moral code for this country i i
hurt people for this country
i um watched my brothers get hurt
for this country and uh
the fact that we have to come back and
take our own health into our hands is
terrifying for many and hard um
i'm having a baby with my beautiful
girlfriend uh cookie who's a navy
veteran
and worked with nato and served as
proudly as anybody
we are both covered by the va we are
both
unwilling to have our baby there so we
pay for private insurance
even though it would be completely
covered under the va system
if that doesn't tell you everything you
know about the va i don't know what does
because literally i mean
we're spending yes am i spending
disability money that's coming from the
va to get service
outside of the va yeah i am i'm using
their money so i can get better care
that they don't offer that is so wrong
it is wrong on every level the va's
motto is defining excellence they have
done nothing of the sort
um i lived at the va for 11 months
on the campus grounds when i got back
from afghanistan
i i tried i
tried to do it their way i i gave it as
honest and effort
as anybody that i have ever met no one
i in fact i barely rarely meet people
that lived at the va for more than six
months
11 months is like unheard of my 11 month
tenure at the va ended with me in a
padded cell
at 11 months after all the healing i did
all the effort
one argument with my roommate and i'm in
a padded cell being shot without a van
all of that out the window gone out on
the street my stuff
waiting for me when i got back to the
dormitory on the street
i was escorted by va police officers
this was after being on a board of
directors for the va domiciliary in
west la va i mean i gave it an honest
effort i took methadone
i took um i took welbutrin
i took everything that they would throw
at me just so i could be in my father's
life and be
a good veteran and none of it worked
cannabis
cannabis coming to it like i did
is what saved my life so veterans walk
and talks mission is simple
we walk we talk we talk about whatever
comes to our minds
cannabis usually being at the forefront
of that now
um mushrooms have been a amazing healing
component for for veterans we we use it
almost on every hike now there are
several veterans that are partaking in
in a in a
you know in some form of mushroom
therapy or at least learning about it
veterans walk and talk has grown to be
much more than just
a group of hiking individuals as you all
know like we advocate
we grow we are we are just
social justice warriors we are at the
forefront
of knocking down the fascist regime
that's taking over our country
we are just doing all the good work so
um
i hope i didn't rant too much but that's
that's my piece for this and i'm just
very grateful you guys are touching on
everything you're saying so thank you
now i i think that's critically
important like i i
want each of you to kind of give
concrete
and you just did it kind of here's my
personal
journey and like you know i i think
one thing you just mentioned was kind of
you know
you you come back to the us
and you're kind of pushed into the va
system and
and the current state of the va system
i'd like you guys to touch a little more
on that
and and is it changing
is this stuck in some time warp that
you just don't have any hope medium term
for
and then for each of you it's kind of
like you you took
control of your own destiny and one
thing
colin you just mentioned was like you
know
someone goes into a dispensary and buys
the
you know designer cultivar du jour
and they smoke it and they have a
paranoid freak out
and maybe they never want to touch it
again and you're like oh my god that was
that was an opportunity lost because
had that person tried something that
is right for them they'd start healing
and and they'd find something that
helped and instead they
had this you know you know anxiety
uh written experience which you seem to
have so
so can each of you kind of and colin you
you just did a little bit but if you
want to expand on it or
joanne you want to talk kind of like
what you started with what you noticed
what you realized worked with you
and then that's your personal experience
and then each of you has experience with
at least 10
20 30 50 friends who are veterans and
kind of just
be specific talk about my friend billy
like he this was his journey and this is
what we learned
on his behalf along the way
yeah i mean because these anecdotal
stories i mean
these are real stories of real people
and what works what doesn't work and
it's important for people to
to or basically for us to document wins
and losses right
i will start if that's okay because i
i've been doing veterans walk and talk
since late 2016 for four years
um for the first few years i was still
struggling with a lot of issues
and finding my way in many ways and then
veterans walk and talk and myself we
really made a name for ourselves
by driving to the va and saying i don't
give a fuck what you think about
cannabis i'm picking your people up and
taking them hiking and i'm gonna get
them high and if you kick them out i
will be at the door waiting for them
to give them a house and and this was at
the west la va
west la vie uh the chatsworth va i've
picked up veterans and also at
several um out the va outsources like
crazy so
um several uh you know you call them
shelters
um in downtown l.a that i would pick up
homeless veterans and take them hiking
yes
and they i can tell you i with with a
few exceptions i've lost
i've lost to suicide some of them i've
lost
to um to further homelessness and drug
addiction
which any anybody in this profession
it's just you you can't there's 22
veterans a day dying you're going to
lose some
and and that's why we put ourselves out
there but
the ones that that continued to hike and
continue to garner
what cannabis had to offer i am still in
touch with them they're
usually back at home with their families
they are
working in the cannabis space now lifted
up by it in many ways whether it be
security or
cultivating the plant growing it on
farms where they can seclude themselves
but they don't actually have to buy the
land as
as doc ray was afforded to do and did
many many years ago and it's what i want
to do as well
so um the the healing
like i i have 200 members of veterans
walk and talk
if i were to put out an email
questionnaire to them saying
what healed you better the va or
cannabis the
the results i don't even need to do it i
know what the results are
the the va has dropped the ball um
now it's seems a little bit
like it's getting better you can talk
about cannabis
and maybe i'd love to hear joanne talk
about what
she what she discusses with with your
medical professional because
i keep it very i use plant medicine
plant medicine plant medicine
that's what i discuss but i have a
permanent disability so i don't have to
i don't have to i could say whatever i
want to them basically as long as i'm
not hurting people with the money
they're giving me
um but for for others you know it's
terrifying to bring up cannabis use it's
terrifying to talk about mushroom use
i uh we're having a baby cannabis you
know
it's nausea come on i mean morning
sickness
it it's night and day you you take some
cannabis
you don't throw up you don't take
cannabis you throw up
i just i don't need more evidence than
that and um that's
so the va dropping the ball and an
excellent book is the
the ex-va secretary david shulkin's book
um
it shouldn't be this hard to serve your
country he lays it out
as well as anybody um just
explaining how he tried to fix it from
the internal and how it's just
it america we got to just admit that
some things didn't work and we have to
revamp them from
from the ground up basically and i'd
love to hear from joanne moore
well just before joanne starts can you
talk about
i mean you're showing up unannounced at
a va facility
and pulling people to go hang out and
smoke weed like
were there bureaucratic administrators
at the va
who were supportive others who thought
you were
doing the devil's work like did they
bring the
mps in to escort you off the facility
like
what were some of the the the
interactions with the va
staff yeah thank you very much for
asking that question
i really appreciate that um yeah
i ran into the craziest
of of scenarios picking the veterans up
at the va which is a large reason why i
can't do it anymore and what was
happening was
um my members were being
searched at a higher rate in their rooms
the v watt members were being
harassed they were being denied certain
things
they were being given unfair curfews
that
you know you have to understand the
places that i i
was picking veterans up they
have to qualify for for instance when i
lived at the domiciliary in the west la
va
i lived on both the substance abuse
track and the combat trauma treatment
track
i was a homeless drug addicted veteran
but
you have to interview for a spot you
have to qualify you have to show that
you're
have the initiative to heal or whatever
the hell that means
and they turn people away and so
if you admit to cannabis use you will
just simply not get a bed
and so yeah they were being searched and
fucked with and my i
i had to take into consideration that i
am not a medical professional i'm not a
doctor i'm not a licensed counselor i
don't have the protections that the va
has in place
so what i was running into was my most
severe cases my most severe brothers and
sisters
who i was picking up at the va
i had to listen to what they were saying
but i also had to take into
consideration that they were there
for sometimes paranoid schizophrenia for
sometimes
delusional thoughts these are and again
i had delusional thoughts
i still have delusional thoughts but i
um
i'm not i shouldn't be hospitalized over
them you know what i mean
so when these veterans were telling me
that their
heat was being turned off in their room
which they were paying for out of their
own disability
or that the water and i have video the
water is brown
running out of their bathtub constantly
and they're the only room on the floor
that has this issue
you have to wonder is it related is it
related to the fact that these veterans
aren't falling into line with what the
va is prescribing them
and again i these are veterans who
didn't
live in a treatment program like i did i
would never have been able to walk with
veterans walk and talk living in the
treatment program i lived in
not a chance i would have been kicked
out immediately
the veterans i was picking up were
paying to rent a place
on the va grounds that was leased to
them
so the va would lease the the building
on the va grounds to a company like
salvation army or the disabled american
veterans association or iava or any of
these
and then they would in turn rent it back
to the va and then
and so you don't even know you're in one
building one second you're in a private
institution you're in another building
the next second you're falling under va
rule
so there's really just no clear cut
like for me why is it that veterans
aren't given this alternative
six months into before leaving the
military why is veterans walk and talk
not
hey you're leaving you're leaving the
military in six months
in order to qualify for the medical
marijuana the cannabis that we want to
give you
you have to go or we suggest you go
walk with veterans walk and talk oh
you're in you're in a wheelchair you're
a paralyzed
veteran so we will suggest that you
instead
go do veterans art and talk go paint
if you do this you will be given
cannabis while you do it then
slowly you will be released as as you go
but
just giving veterans cannabis veterans
more medicine that's not going to work
alternative therapies
a new lease on life is what cannabis
gives you
and we need to shepherd that in every
way
and there's no reason why
alcoholism drug addiction depression
ptsd
there's no reason why all these things
we have to knock out before we come to
cannabis
cannabis should be the first thing and
then we tackle these things
so that's that's what veterans walk and
talk stigma
is trying to break the stigma of i'm
denied i can't see my son
that lives in north carolina i have two
step step sons
and a daughter on the way and a son in
north carolina my son in north carolina
i have not seen and
it'll be a year in november because of
my choices because
i won't take prescriptions because i
won't stop talking about cannabis and
mushrooms
i i don't get to see him i barely get to
skype with him if i bring up mushrooms
or cannabis on a skype it's cut
immediately
so these are sacrifices that we have to
make because we know
we know the truth of it and once you
know the truth of cannabis you can't
help but sing it from the mountaintops
so just quickly the neighbor is either
cutting a tree down or
doing something but this is what you
were talking about from david shulkin
let me just uh yeah that's a brilliant
thing
and then uh joanne you want to jump in
and kind of tell your i think
it's basically your story of you know
figuring out that this works for you
and then specifically what works what
doesn't work cause some cannabis
and form factors of taking it maybe
don't work or are less effective or
adverse
in the same way colin was talking about
where it's like i had
anxiety so can you kind of talk about
your
journey of discovery and then any
friends who you have where you can talk
about
kind of their experience as well
yeah i'll absolutely uh share
my experience um i was in the aviation
community
um here with the navy stationed in
lamar california working with uh
f-18 aircraft um during my first
deployment
working on the flight deck i was
actually blown by jet aircraft
um jet blast from the aircraft
and long story short
it was a horrible accident i
had a concussion from it and
couldn't speak english for you know
about 20 minutes um
and uh long story short
that created a whole bunch of problems
you know from
the main one that i could experience and
could put my finger on
um throughout that time was the size the
headaches
and and the back pain it was
i couldn't sleep um for more than like
two consecutive hours or um
every night so i was waking up every
hour every two hours
um and that happened needless to say
i still had time to serve i did nine
months of
physical therapy
[Music]
and went back on deployment uh
and then that deployment was where i
realized that i my sleeping became a
problem
because we were working 12 hours and i
still was up like 20 hours because i
wasn't sleeping
um and that problem
i literally was lit out of the military
because
after that i wasn't the same person
anymore so
i didn't even want to be there but um
coming out
you know that's when all the issues
uh became more exacerbated because now
i'm alone in my thoughts and
um so i fell into the hands of the va
i was not you know unlike some of you
guys i
had not experimented with cannabis even
before
that very you know in college i did do
it every
a few times but it wasn't like a thing i
had never heard
of medicinal cannabis or using it you
know i thought that
i had heard of maybe glaucoma that you
can
use it for and i thought you know it was
maybe a joke i wasn't even
that's how disconnected i was um at that
point
in my life with it and then i i met a
person who was a grower um
and he was working towards
at that point it was 2014 he was working
on
um a legal cannabis
grow you know and i'm like what does
that even mean
um but even before we got to that point
he introduced me to cannabis
um uh it was actually rso
he gave me a little syringe looking
thing
and told me take a grain of rice and i
did
it and i'm telling you right now that
changed
everything i am talking about
for three years i could not tell you who
i was
i could not i had no clue um
and starting that regimen in or that
becoming a routine you know before i
went to sleep
um pretty much i
cannabis was able to help me sleep and
that solves so many other problems you
know
um the pain with the the backaches
trying to sleep and and all that
situation
literally within a month i was already
the person that i remember being you
know before all these problems began
and i just made it my mission to make
sure i spread this message
however i could i quit my job and became
completely involved not only in trying
to figure out what worked for me
because i did um i know doc brought it
up earlier
uh there were you know some of the
things then i started experimenting with
the smoking
um i quit cigarettes um
and focused on cannabis and
never had to pick that back up again
and doing it with the edibles with the
just trying to find out where i was
um i'm a flower person i love flower and
that's what
helps me the most to not only be
functional
but also you know to manage
pain to manage the anxiety that arose
from not sleeping for years
um and just even my eating habits
it i mean it was it was just a situation
so i i
became so serious about it that i have a
journal
where i keep the names of the strains if
i'm you know if i'm able to identify
that strain
and how i felt document it you know more
of that
for creativity more of that for no pain
more of that to be able to sleep through
the night
um and then documenting to the ones who
fell paranoid
or fell you know draghi or whatever the
case may be
um and from there it's been
it's been like i said a game changer i
know individuals in my circle who
have i have a friend dave he actually
makes
a bomb at home from the plants that he
grows
and i know people in my family
um my aunt in the dominican republic
she's using the bomb right now she's
diabetic she suffers from diabetes she's
had it for
ever she had she has a wound in her foot
that she got that it's gnarly but she's
had it for 10 years because of the
diabetes she's not able to heal
um and with dave's bomb
she already has unless i am telling you
in less than six months
she's experienced she already has a scab
on it
which means that her skin is completely
being regenerated inc with the diabetes
the diabetes status is there
the cannabis bomb has been able
to i mean i can show you the before and
after
her her whole foot was
in the verge of being completely
engulfed in this
uh wound because since it didn't heal it
continued to get infections and things
like that
um with the cannabis
she sent me and whatsapp this message
this long
thanking me so much i mean
my on is like in her 80s so
you know the fact that this thing was
hindering her life
for a decade and with cannabis
what what medication was not able to do
in years a decade
in six months she's already has like a
normal healing process with her
and you know she's not smoking it she's
not getting
doing bone rips or anything like that
she
is literally using it as a topical
um and that that's like one of the most
compelling stories i have besides
the fact that i cannabis prevented me
from committing suicide i
was literally on the floor with a gun in
my hand
contemplating that um when i met that
guy
um that same week and he
introduced me to cannabis and here we
are five years later
um and i wouldn't change it any other
way it was perfect timing for me
um it became a complete journey from
there and here i am
um five years later um having this
conversation which i think is
crucial for people to um
listen to and and other people because
you know you guys are just
some people like in your area in the
humble county area
lord knows how many growers have so much
information
it's crazy it's crazy
we have to give people like we have to
give these people a platform so they can
get this information out there and i
made that you know
my mission to be able to contribute to
that in that sense
um so i'm very passionate about it very
thankful to the plan to people
that grow it like you guys through
people like colin who
you know create communities and and then
infuse the message of wellness and just
being able to be stable and the fact
that it's okay to feel some kind of way
but here you know these are
alternatives because i cannot take pills
you know i
because of the headaches that i get from
the concussion
um they give me 800 milligrams of
ibuprofen
um pills that i got to take these spills
are like
this big i can't even it's
i can't do it um you know
so i one i sometimes
had to like get creative trying to mix
it with something else
but still like with cannabis
it's it's natural it doesn't hurt my
liver you know because
with big with big pharma
medicine it usually creates
an underlying issue if you can if you
use it for
long periods of time so um
i prefer the alternative that something
that's not gonna harm me so i don't have
to worry about side effects
or long-term effects um and then being
detrimental to myself
which will eventually create another
problem
so like i said i'm super thankful to be
here i know
the power of the plant um is not even
just for
medic medical purposes it's for pretty
much
anything but creating glass or steel
other than that we can't use this
eco-friendly product
or crop to you know to help the world so
thank you for having me here i think
it's really critical right now too that
the conversation that we all for having
is this
we know this information and and i think
joanne specifically is
how do we take what we've all know to be
the truth is how do we get it beyond
this point you know how do we get it to
reach the masses where how do we
saturate more where
and i and i don't know is it you know we
maybe it is
pavlov's dog you know repeat it over and
over and over again and eventually it
sticks you know
i i've been preaching it for 40 years
i'm not sure that it's
maybe it's sticking now is it just
generationally moved so much
where so many people with a this
quasi-legal thing that we're in that
are stepping forward because the state
says are okay
you know if we can get this federal
shift to come hopefully in the next 24
months get this federal ship to come
with the d-class on schedule one
where as it rightfully should be that
that does have true medical value as a
matter of fact it's at the top of the
pharmacopoeia of medical value that's
where we need to move this to where we
can get it to open where
the ones that are still standing on the
sidelines watching that
and you alluded to it earlier of fear
you know
a fear of repercussion of the unknown
it's here too
yeah i'm kind of on the tip of the spear
here for
cannabis because i have outed myself and
put my face on videos and so then a lot
of my grower friends
as you said sisters the truth is about
80 percent of the
best genetics in the world are within
about a 50-mile radius of where i live
and and i know the bulk of them you know
it's like
there are a lot of them with what dylan
are doing two years ago they wouldn't
even come to a meeting that when he met
me up here in the
redwoods they wouldn't come to it and
this earlier this year in january on the
radio i had him on the radio with me at
k
on k mud and the people there that
wouldn't engage with me last year about
the topic of
patent protections what i'm doing plant
patent protection so people can't rip me
off anymore
okay that's my primary yes absolutely
it is and that's mostly so that's just
one side of it is branding and aligning
with cam
so that so high tide distro can help get
veterans choice cannabis across the
country
you know we're going to blow california
up but
just when the time is right moving
across the country you know
that's the big goal right now i think is
we all get the same kind of
the same phraseology the same verbiage
we're all saying the same thing you know
and
and i'm hoping maybe this conversation
we can with
other leaders within our respective
groups we can get where we're all using
like
you know let's quit saying strain you
know let's pick up the correct
phraseology of
chemovar or cultivar and and
to to make ourselves
and i know this sounds terrible but to
make ourselves look more professional
you know i mean honestly god i cleaned
up today so i didn't look so shaggy you
know and and
that's kind of i know cam yo we already
look like rough
rowdy rough next to a lot of people
anyway just because we look like
wild old fuzzy guys you know and and we
and we need people that can help us
translate across where that
you know we're talking about chemivours
and cultivars and even me personally in
the last 24 months having access to
peter led to that earlier i have access
to the medical professionals now where i
can get the correct phraseology and i
understand cbd and cbg and cbn
and things that i didn't know how to say
that three years ago you know
i got what it did and i could tell you
know if you smoke this man i promise you
in about 20 minutes you're gonna be
relaxed
and like the razzleberry kush you know
and you alluded to it
just briefly on that one that is a true
heirloom one to one cultivar
it is a full spectrum cbd
thc rich and it is literally about
15 thc most
shops won't even want to look at that
but what it also is is it's 15 freaking
percent
cbd man and you smoke that puppy and in
20 minutes your ass is taking a
nap and i don't care who you are or how
tough you think you are how big you are
i'm six four and two hundred in my prime
260 i'm about 210
now but i'm 6'4 and 210 and i'm my big
but taking a nap in about 30 minutes on
a nice joint
yeah that's how good it is yeah it's so
good i love that strain so much too
right
you know it says again it's nothing it's
nothing to you know the the shops oh my
god it's not 20
well it's not supposed to be it's a
medical cultivar specifically designed
to it was specifically designed to help
with sleep
okay doc have you had the terpenes
tested on that strain yet do you know
the terpene levels
it's it's common colin it's just you
know i'm excited for that brother you
know i'm an old man
you know i i know i know i'm doing it by
myself until
a year ago i was just you know i'm just
growing bad ass weed and only a few
people knew who i was you know
i just know that that's variable that's
it has like that camphor menthol like
almost like
licorice endnote that i'm just anxious
to find out the terpenes that make that
up man it's so good
yeah i can wing it and kind of tell you
just by the profiles what i think
but i i just literally so you guys get
it literally joanne's
this is how how slow i am i literally
left yesterday just said cam you'll be
appreciate this brother set up my
account with
sc labs and start having shit tested
and i love it because i wouldn't do it
before now they actually come to your
damn
location and pick your stuff up so i
don't have to drive so i'm thankful
sister you know it's like again i don't
want to really
i mean i do my goal is really my goal so
you
i want to shift it to the hands of my
young brothers and sisters that want to
learn the craft the way i do it
why i'm thankful to have cam our what
we're working on is aligning together
where
i can teach this out on math scale so we
can get it out there
and let people have access to good
information but also
for me to call and calling cam and are
building that damn retreat
okay yeah building outlets man
no more talk i'm done of the talk man
it's time to put your money where your
fucking mouth is man
and walk it sister you know and walk it
you know and that's what came in my
literally part of our conversations we
want to build it up because he
he he needs to ramp up his supply he
can't keep up with demand
i will i can't get mine out you're
hitting it on the head doc it's like we
got to do it ourselves or no one's going
to do it for us veterans walk and talk
has held three retreats so far and
honestly everyone has been successful
but everyone has been also
a huge risk because i am taking combat
veterans out into the desert out into
the woods with
no insurance no medical professionals
just
the knowledge that i know i can help
them and
and doing it and so it does it takes
people like yourself to just
put plan put it into action because no
one is going to do it for us period
we have an alignment we didn't have a
year ago too
colin you know now we have dale hunt in
our corner then dale again you guys
haven't been around dale yet just a
little bit it's like a brother to me i
love him so much he's like
he's the the pa plant patent guy in the
frickin country for crying out loud and
oh yeah he's a plant lawyer too oops
yeah but he happens to have a navy son
that has pts and he loves my flowers
right well it takes people like you guys
and lawyers honestly and politicians
to change the nomenclature of cannabis
from
graham dabs to anandamide from
from taking this can put you in
homeostasis why does no one talk about
homeostasis
why does nobody talk about the fact that
bong loads and dabs can spike you in and
out
and yes while you're spiking here's your
homeostasis level
you feel good while you're in that level
but you spike in and out
whereas if you take it like intuitively
you can actually stay within that level
and continually produce an endomite and
stay in homeostasis
this is what we need to be talking about
this is what we've been doing
is uh i know i didn't set out to start a
distribution company i was making pot
ice cream in the virgin islands 25 years
ago because it made me feel good
and i just kept carrying on with the
plant and
we've been my wife and i shannon we've
been growing uh
under the 215 model in northern
california for over 10 years now
and we started growing cbd strains uh
eight years ago we were one of the very
first farms
in the united states to grow cbd strains
we got our original seeds from lawrence
ringo and
we started working with labs trying to
figure out what we had and what it was
and trying to learn from all the people
like martin lee
and project cbd and dr ethan russo
and learning all of this and when i
started growing cbd strains when i take
it into a dispensary i say hey i grew
this great flower outdoors
but it doesn't really have much thc it
won't get you high
and nobody understood what i was talking
about and so we had to
educate ourselves to be able to educate
the purchasers
and then we had to go and educate the
customers so that they knew what was
happening
and so that just let us down a path of
self-education
to where we started doing free trainings
and in the last 10 years i've been a
member of over a thousand dispensaries
we offer free cannabis education to
anybody who will listen it'll be a group
of one or a hundred or however many
and then in the meantime we share we
want this information to be out there
for free
just like we want the plant to be out
there for everybody we're building
community we're at this time and place
in history where we
get to create the universe that we need
and that we should have and it's for all
of us who have been in the legal market
trying to survive
up till now we are just now getting
through the survival phase where we can
start
helping and institutionalize compassion
institutionalize community create
community over competition to we're all
out there lincoln arm and arm
telling the government let's see cicely
do her research let dr ethan russo use
quality cannabis
and we don't have to use this shit from
the university of mississippi
and but there's a lot of us out there
and i can't tell you how excited i am
when i teach classes on acidic
cannabinoids i can go into a dispensary
now and i don't have to explain what
decarboxylation is
i don't have to explain to the majority
of people what the endocannabinoid
system is
now we can get to the fine-tune things
where you were talking about the
dopamine and serotonin
levels in somebody we know that a good
level of cbd combined with thc and the
other cannabinoids and terpenes
helps balance out serotonin dopamine and
other neurotransmitters c
don't spike so you don't crash and a lot
of the people
problems that people are having are
because their endocannabinoid system is
out of whack
and but we are we're making a lot of
great improvements on the education
level in the country and
it's just all of us getting out there
and telling our stories and talking to
everybody
now my dad's a 100 percent disabled
vietnam vet
he was blown up in country he was a
marine corps infantry officer
and turned the entire right side of his
body into chewed bubble gum and he spent
a year in a body cast in japan
uh before he came home and i grew up
with
him medicating with alcohol and pills
and
you know he was a great dad he was my
scout leader but he was always in pain
and he was always suffering and
be damned if you tell them about
post-traumatic stress that's you know
that's
doesn't happen to marine corps infantry
officers damn it
um but uh you know i learned at a young
age don't sneak into the house
if i've been out late come in loud and
proud otherwise you're going to wind up
on your back
after you get right inside the door
don't sneak around
um but i grew up with disabled vets and
watching all of them
self-medicate and then myself i
self-medicate i grew up in a very
conservative christian family where
you know dope was for losers you don't
touch that shit
but we drank ourselves silly and
when i got out of the marine corps
myself i was studying for law
enforcement
and i was burning out fast i was
drinking myself to death i was working
in bars so i could fight without going
to jail
and the very first time the day i got in
the marine corps i
i smoked my first joint and just like
doc says i was able to just go i don't
have to be on point
i don't have to have my back to against
a wall looking at the door all the time
i don't have to be on alert and always
you know hyper vigilant i can take a
deep breath and i can
slow down and i can unclench my fists
and uh yeah this plant's amazing and
i can't get enough of learning about it
and we want to share it and this is what
doc and i are talking about
i started talking about the distro
company we
started creating our own district
company because nobody could talk about
cannabinoids and cbd cbda whole plant
medicine
um like we could and so
we started representing ourself and
offering free education with everything
we do
we'll we'll offer free classes to
anybody who will listen
and we started finding other small
family farms and product makers and
brands are running into the same problem
small craft family run heritage legacy
[Music]
what we want to do is be that
personalized we want to
tell doc's story and have uh doc show up
and explain what he does we want to make
sure that the people who have done this
for decades and generations have a voice
and we
create the community that we need i can
talk forever about that man
there's a lot of people though there are
a lot of there i'm just
one of thousands here and john you you
got it and you get it within a 50 mile
radius of me there there are
hundreds if hundreds if not thousands of
small craft mom-and-pops that have true
one-of-a-kinds that people don't even
know about
you know if you're not in their circle
and get access to the 10 pounds that
they create every fripping year
because that's who i am you know i don't
grow a hundred pounds of wheat i grow
five pounds of weed you know but i grow
five pounds of
different strains for myself that's what
i've morphed into with this
is getting it to a position now what
what and again what cam and i are doing
is like
we tried to contract people to do it
this year and they couldn't do it you
know so
again i'm a first through the door
motherfucker man and that's who i
am you know i've been kicking indoors
for a long time
and i'm kicking indoors with probably
the toughest cat in this state
as far as distribution that i'm aware of
who is also a door kicking old guy
too and we're going to align with people
that want to get this thing out there
and we're going to make it happen
ourselves
because i get what colin was saying
earlier he's like we have to do it
ourselves because
you know again walk the walk it's like
get out there
we we tried to contract people to make
it happen and we couldn't get it done so
we're going to build it ourselves
and that's just basically and and me and
and our alignment is that's again i
think with you you know it's everything
is it coming to a gather for a point
here where we all
are intertwined with each other now
where we know each other where
you know you need access you reach out
you know we need to get to your your
market we're going to reach out to you
these kind of things where we can all
expand what we're doing for the greater
good you know for
you hit it on the head doc it's about
access access
access access if i give somebody your
pineapple barry kush
and it helps a veteran i need to ensure
that they can
access it whenever they need it because
they don't need it just every now and
then
and so it kills me
it just goes away you know it goes so
quickly as i want to get it into the
hands of people
like where i don't mind being part of it
but i'm too old to do it myself i need
young men and women that want to get
their hands dirty and want to learn how
to cultivate
cannabis to come up to the middle of
nowhere in the
in the wild woods and the mountainside
with me and and the guy
the other bearded guy on and you know he
me more than anybody you know
we're building a thing together but it's
like i i get what he's doing where he's
at in sonoma
to where we're where we're looking at up
in northern mendo in southern humboldt
you know that's a three-hour gap you
know it's like i have people that are
vet
again other veteran growers that are
gonna that are i've already told me that
that are good at their craft that want
to learn underneath me that are willing
to come from where they are around the
world to come be a part of this deal
yeah information for free we want to
make sure that everybody has access we
want to be
educating people especially veterans to
come into the industry and have a level
of education
we want to make sure that access to
continuous medicine
for veterans there's no better business
that i can suggest to veterans to go
work in
cannabis yeah it's the best absolutely
right now
i because even the acts
the act of growing is therapeutic
yes oh getting your hands in the soil
and touching it
getting connected to the ground and
putting your hands in the soil
that plant will tell you everything she
needs she will be on her tippy toes
smiling when everything's going
well she may be looking away or drooping
a little bit when she needs some water
or love or attention
but that connection and that love with
that plant is just it
it's very important and i think
everybody should grow it
cannabis is an amazing phenomenal from
the bottom up medicine
and it grows on trees so why can't we
make sure
everybody grows it if somebody your
friend can't grow it give them someone
who have you grown
this needs to be community from the
ground up everybody should have access
everybody should be able to grow it
everybody should be able to sell it as
long as it's tested and clean
but this this needs to be none of this
trickle down bullshit this is from the
ground up
this is what's going to elevate the
community from one end to the other this
is something that
everybody can do amen and it comes back
to like what does a farmer look like
what does a scientist look like what
does a veteran look like in this day and
age
it can be anyone and if you can empower
yourself in these amazing
amazing ways to heal not just yourself
but your community and i
i i hear a lot of whispers and i want to
pose the to the question to the group
is and i know you guys have tried to do
many things like this
doc and cam but something i'm hearing
kicked around right now through the
veterans cannabis coalition is an hga a
home growers association
where you are empowering people to grow
in their closets grow in their backyards
and then they are entitled they are able
to gift
that a certain amount of cannabis away
so that there is never not a need i know
this is
difficult but it is a start what do you
guys think there's there's small
it's going on it's already especially
here in sonoma county
we have several uh cultivation groups
that are people who got pushed out
uh from 215 into 64 and they all rally
and share tips they meet every tuesday
in sebastopol
and they grow six big ones and it's free
information
and we're trying to create that
community we can share the information
where
this is this group that you can access
all their resources online for free even
if you're in san diego or
you're up in humboldt you can access
this group and we're trying to do the
pay it forward my knowledge for you
sharing
the knowledge to them sharing knowledge
so all of these little groups are there
and we're just now getting to the point
where we can stick our heads up
and see who we who we have in fact here
in sonoma county we just founded the
very first cannabis grange hall
in the united states and this is a
traditional agricultural
group we have lobbyists the two
lobbyists in sacramento and a national
lobbyist
we're all in the infancy stages of these
we need to get the granges going in
every single county and system
these are community halls where you can
share information and have classes
and hold events that we can do outside
of
any traditional market where it's
designed for community and farming
um and then finding everything
downstream where this can go
but we're we're just now getting out of
this shell shock survival mode from 64.
and we're still battling every day and i
know it it's we could say it's greed in
the industry
but speaking i i do cultivation
manufacturing and distribution
and we get fucked every step of the way
it's yeah
this is the most difficult thing i've
ever done in my life and
every day it's demoralizing in fact i
use a great marine corps motto with all
of our crew
embrace the suck the suck
love it wrap your arms around it and
every time they fuck you you say thank
you sir may i have another
and we're going to beat them at their
own game we're winning in every district
where there is no delivery no cannabis
allowed
but we have to show up we have to be at
board of supervisors meetings we have to
be at city council meetings you got to
show up to sacramento
you got to tell you know old aunt bessie
who is a staunch anti-cannabis person
explain it time after time or my dad i
said he
never touched cannabis his entire life
he was very anti and i just had to go
home
last month and help him get his leg
amputated um
above the knee and uh he has been
anti-cannabis his whole life and the va
has he refuses to go to the va from the
treatment he got there
and he was in pain and he was having
issues with opioids
and life was miserable for him and he
finally after 20 years of us debating on
the efficacy of cannabis
he allowed me to give him some cannabis
to try it was the first night he slept
in
in years he sat and so if we can
convince
that old man that cannabis isn't the you
know the devil's weed
and then we can convince other people we
just have to meet them at their level of
understanding
and give them enough digestible
information and share the resources
where we get it from
don't come out and say this is going to
heal the world and see it does
everything
no cannabis slows your body down so it
heals itself and this is how
we know what it does and just break it
down into simple conversational things
we do more sharing our stories every day
to people we meet than
you know a lot of other outlets so we
just need to make sure that we're
creating other people to go out there
and share their stories we just need to
create good stories that can be shared
the bottom line is our country through
jim crow
through segregation through the war on
drugs through everything
did a really really good job of putting
cannabis down
like a good job to the point where
people like your friend
or of 20 years it's ingrained that it's
bad it's bad it's bad it's bad we need
to do an even better job
than they ever did of unifying creating
communities
and and speaking our truths like you're
saying couldn't have said it better cam
just quickly it it seems like
you know we've been talking about kind
of the roots and momentum from the
bottom
and you know i view it as like a
you know an iceberg kind of it's moving
in a direction and
whether it's moving too slowly is
a moot point because it's happening like
you guys are going to touch more
veterans and we'll touch more and more
and
more people will try it and then become
evangelists but
let's talk about the other side which is
the top down we touched on the va
can can you guys offer some tactical
ideas and not just the va i mean think
about each of you were in different
branches of the military
so how do you put pressure on them is
there like one individual who's blocking
progress
is it you know for example like if in a
county the sheriff is
mitch mcconnell mitch mcconnell is
blocking progress
that's who's blocking progress because
he loves hemp and not cannabis
the the the the bill is sitting there
again where is it where's the hold up at
is it sitting right there they're trying
to vote on it right now to
turn it into to decriminalize it to take
it off the regulation
and it's getting voted on they just that
they're voting on it sometime in the
next couple of weeks i believe
but it's got to get past mcconnell's
desk that's the truth of the matter
and this i only said that to say this
it is small grassroots and how do we do
it you change your politicians
if they're not pro-cannabis you broke
their ass out and you put a pro-cannabis
person into that seat
and that's what i'm getting at which is
you know even a county the sheriff
loves doing raids on cannabis farmers
well that guy comes up for re-election
every once in a while so
thinking of all these different groups
that we need to change the va
is one so my question is like is the va
a monolith where like the west la va
just has to go by the orders of the
national va
or is each local va
its own kind of silo of decision making
where they could be a little more
tolerant or a little less tolerant
i will i'll address that personally uh
it is
specifically that it depends on whether
the specific
community-based outreach program is out
here here
here where we're at is uh the seabock in
eureka specifically like my
physicians there my primary care and
people they all know i use the plan i
don't take synthetics
you go to another state where they don't
have the same kind of compassion laws
or depth of understanding like we do
because this is a humboldt county
freaking facility that's a lot of what
it is
it's right down to the personal level of
what the how the
doctor interprets how the bill is
written and how the regulations are
written within the va it's but again
depending on where you're at it's up to
personal interpretation of your
freaking position but my personal
primary care literally the last time i
was in there
he's asking me about what i'm
cultivating
okay and this is all happening and in
just the last few years
you know i'm going to say it's not
immediately so i'm not but i'm going to
say in places where they're not
in the middle of the mecca for cannabis
and northern california then
obviously it's gonna you're not gonna
get the same kind of pro approach
someplace else
i believe in places where compassion
laws are in place
where the doctors can talk to bet about
cannabis with the veterans
it's tough because if you're rated and
you're not 100
secured in your rating they can mess
with your rating and take your money
away from you
that's a serious consideration for a lot
of people colin's not in that boat i'm
not in that boat you know it's like
we're beyond those points where we are
with it but there was a point where it
would have affected me too you know it's
like i have to be careful
you know it's like we all have to be
aware of what the laws are around us
not not expose ourselves to any kind of
risk if you're not 100
sure don't expose yourself i believe we
have enough legal people around us now
civilian legal people
and veteran lawyers to get advice from
where it isn't going to cost you 250 or
a thousand dollars an hour to find out
if it's safe for you to talk to somebody
in your state
that's part of the other things we need
to start be working on i believe as a
group
okay so this is these are things that i
think on a
broader national level that we need to
be because california again we're all
west coast man
we're living this bubble out here you
know we've 20
whatever 24 years of medical cannabis
now this is 96 you know
it's just that so much has changed in
where we've been in these things for so
long where our doctors are
are way more lenient in the north i
don't know about the southern half of
the state
but you get north san francisco and
coming up cannabis is a way of life up
in the northern half of the state
yeah i mean it's just how it is it's
like i i believe all our doctors
are understanding of it maybe not
completely
receptive to it but at least sympathetic
of it yeah and
and i know colin's experience with with
l.a and stuff is again a different
portion of the cut
the state and just a different mindset
of the doctors so it's going to go down
to what each individual doctor
is within your va best advice
don't say anything about your cannabis
use until you're 100
sure you can you know unless you live in
a community like where i live out or you
look
you know your doctors are 100 cro pro
cannabis they're not going to put it in
your records
but you're putting your records you're
screwed right now and again it boils
down to
we got to get mitch mcconnell either out
of the office or
change his mindset and get this bill
change on schedule one
the schedule one that is that's no
medical value is bullshit
and we all know it's bullshit and we
need our medical professionals our
scientists
our legislators and again if they aren't
pro-cannabis then
vote them out and put somebody in who is
pro-cannabis
because this is again i hate to be this
way but this is about control
and greed and corruption and that is the
truth of the matter
it's a it's everything you know keeping
keeping the masses under control
incarceration it all ties into it
how many how many how many non-violent
first offenders are in federal prison
over cannabis you know it's like it's
just freaking ridiculous
there's people that instilled the was
that the last
last prisoner project that is steve
d'angelo's project isn't that what that
one is right
it's ridiculous over joints you know
it's like 25 years for a freaking joint
are you out of your fucking mind what
the wrong is of this country how does he
you know how do we do this you know it's
like i'm getting on
kind of off point here a little bit but
this really is what it boils down to is
we have to vote with our conscience we
have to even if you don't tell people
you smoke weed
and you use that plant you need to talk
to your politicians and vote for those
people who
are that way and if they're not don't
vote for them
you know it's like here the trinity
county sheriff last year
mom and pops with 30 to 40 50 000 worth
of paid permits with their papers in
their hands
having federal agents kick their gates
in and go we don't care what your damn
papers say we're here to knock your
plants down
that's bullshit man well that's an
elected official that's an elected
sheriff at trinity county
vote that son of a bitch out and put
somebody in who is pro-cannabis
that's how it works here it's how it
works here
our county our county sheriff is 100
behind mom and pops
100 behind what we do here they won't
accept the funds they don't allow it to
happen here
it's a long time coming yeah been
handcuffed been pepper sprayed before
was it that way 20 years ago you know
when the laws first changed in the early
in the late 1990s it wasn't that way
so so there were talking about kind of
elected officials and voting them in and
out like uh
i'm gonna take the concrete example of
the west la va
where it's not elected doctors it's not
elected administrators
um colin would it be possible to create
you know if veterans in different
municipalities created lists
like could we create lists of the
doctors who are kind of
on staff at the va's and then have some
sort of
constant trying to outreach to them and
invite them to local events
and see if they'll you know because it
just takes one domino to be like
i'll come to that event and like meet
and listen and talk about
medical and cannabis and i'm a va doctor
and then he goes back and tells like
one of the other va doctors at west l.a
like i was at this thing and it was
actually pretty interesting and
you know you're just moving mindsets a
little bit at a time
yeah we we try and that's you know
exactly
what we strive to do at veterans walk
and talk with no
um non-profit flag with no business
license so that we can just subvert from
the inside
you can't go to a va in southern
california or oklahoma and not find
veterans walk and talk literature we
drop it off routinely i have people who
do it for me
um but the fact of the matter is like
what doc said is that
as long as veterans are too afraid to
talk to their medical professionals
about cannabis
there are going to be no chances for
medical professionals to leave the
grounds to learn about cannabis because
their jobs are at stake as well
the flip side to that is ucla
i know first act has partnered with the
west la va
to do more research on cannabis
um they have the canada club
at usc and ucla i have personally been
to ucla run uh
operations several of them um cannabis
operations and i can tell you
i can tell you wholeheartedly that uh
they're lacking um i've been one of them
was
was up to par the other one is just
embarrassing so
but you're you're right on the money um
you know
the va works based on
results so as long as they are showing
some kind of result in a field that
field will continue to get funded
which is why they make us interview for
a bed
and that we have to actually qualify for
because then
our position is more likely to
fruit them a positive of a positive
outcome and therefore they will get more
funding
um so yeah it's it's from the top
up that's where it has to be when you
have like i said again
people like shulkin writing books entire
books about how they tried to
change the va and couldn't do it from
the top down you know that a subversive
movement has to
has to take part and with mitch
mcconnell and the moore act and all that
stuff the va
the va it's all all lumped into the same
thing
the fact of the matter is that americans
are incapable of
admitting that we got something wrong to
the point where
they are terrified of having to admit
that these people were behind bars for
the wrong reasons they are terrified of
having to pay reparations to these
people once they are out
they are terrified of generational
conflict that they will have to face
because of families uprooted
over single plants single joints quarter
ounces of cannabis
these are mistakes that america made
there are mistakes
that they did to their own people they
are mistakes that they need to be
accounted for just like they were
accounted for vietnam
and they accounted for they need to
account for afghanistan and the fact
that they keep us there just to make
money so
these are all top-down issues
and until we vote the people out who are
afraid to admit
that they've made mistakes the mistakes
will continue to happen
because there's no accountability the
it's okay for us it's okay for us to say
that va
needs to be reworked it's even okay
especially from a combat infantry
veteran who killed people for this
country
it's okay for us to say that the
constitution needs to be rewritten
that's okay there's nothing wrong with
that there's nothing wrong with looking
into our roots and finding what worked
and finding what didn't and taking it
and making it better
america is scared to do that so our
health institutions
particularly the va they're terrified to
empower veterans in a health and
wellness manner
because they know for every veteran
empowered every veteran healed
they are butterfly affecting 10 more
and that's all sorry my mushrooms my
mushrooms kicked in so i'm just like
yeah baby let's talk about the va
and if you're wondering what guy
mushrooms looks like it's like this
no it's not it's like this
[Laughter]
i think what we're doing here is kind of
part of what we're talking about which
is we can
you know this conversation will reach
veterans who will be
impacted by see watching this
conversation
and then we'll also reach bureaucrats
and decision makers who will be impacted
and i'd like to put
you know more and more pressure on that
front and be really
tactical and it's good to hear like for
example it's interesting that that you
hand out literature like
do you notice that administrators are
coming and like
throwing the the pamphlets out or are
they
like has there been a transition where
they're
allowing it and they're cool with it and
they're actually happy you're doing it
versus like three years ago when maybe
they
threw it out as soon as they saw it yeah
but it's all hush hush
still even even even now i mean i have
to take the cannabis leaves off my logos
to do this
and stuff like that every now and then
like oklahoma to be honest um
as progressive as as we want to pretend
we are in california and as
far as cannabis goes oklahoma's doing a
great job of shepherding
the best in the country right now yeah
i agree and so in oklahoma
they have no problem at the va putting
my logo up and literature up that's not
been an issue but here in west l.a
because cannabis use is still uh it's
still a
dis disqualifying factor to get mental
health
treatment so they won't you know they
they don't want to
they they call it like you know you have
to clean yourself completely before we
will let you
get here which is just absolutely
impossible for most people
and there's also why most people in the
rehab centers
at the va look like me and our white
guys
who they think will do well and are
they're not actually given the help to
the people who actually need it
because of drug use and and racism so
that that's all we could do two hours on
that as well
so i i saw veterans die i saw them die
at the va in my arms that my brothers
who i didn't fight with they were
vietnam vets older
african-american gentlemen die on the
steps
of the fucking the home that i lived in
because they weren't allowed access
we we would trace their body we would
put flowers out there for them because
we had no
we didn't they were there one day and
they were gone the next just like that
it's what's wrong it's part of it and
calling you say we have to own
our mistakes and we don't do it as a
country and it's a part of what we're in
this
mess that we're in right now currently
it breaks my fucking heart
it part i think it breaks all of our
hearts collectively of what we see with
our brothers and sisters
that have you know signed a blank check
at some point in their lives saying
up until and including my wife i'll do
whatever it takes to defend our country
and we don't honor what
it's supposed to be and that's not
this they're not supposed to be on the
streets there's not supposed to not have
access
you know i'm a big believer of how we
treat the least amongst us it's
you know that's my my god that's how my
god looks
you know and and that's how i approach
this thing with
with who i try to be around you know who
i try to share with and
and i didn't quite honestly understand
it until the last couple of years that
the outpouring of
of the lack of access to what i do and
what
brothers and sisters that i have in my
community here this small little bubble
this utopian cannabis bubble that we
live in here in the triangle
that you know it's here
we need to get it beyond them being
scared
and afraid that they're going to have it
taken away from them which is their
ultimate fear
you know it's my ultimate fear is to
have what i want my life on taken away
and some
i'd rather be at a corporate cannabis
company than
freaking monsanto or dow chemical or
budweiser anheuser-busch you know it's
going to jump in as soon as the
federal thing changes they're all going
to jump in they're absolutely right doc
and so many veterans still like joanne i
was just going to
throw it to you because we talked about
this last time i saw you don't
you we still receive medicine from the
va in order to just keep them off your
fucking backs
yeah it's it's a it's a it's a weird
time right now you know this is a lot
i and i realized you know i realized
that earlier this year because people
were asking questions about what the
rules were for like i'm right
i'm didn't realize it but i'm the guy
they're getting references for for the
city of arcata for the editable edibles
guidelines of what milligram dosages are
they're asking me
you know and i was like there isn't
somebody smarter than me
you know that whole thing and they're
like well you know you've been good i
was like all right
this is what i recommend and i'm again
very conservative because i believe
personally as a caregiver because that's
my primary focus for the last 23 years
as a caregiver
of this of the sacred plant is to always
under prescribe so the experience is an
uplifting and enjoyable one and they can
always add more but it's hard to take
this away
if you over well said so then they were
asking the right person then
about them yeah well
that's what they said you start
you know you start um smaller if you go
all the way
yeah then you get it consensus was that
joanne that's really is the consensus
hon that
really is it you know uh we can add more
you know and that really because i have
friends like
oh man two and a half milligrams that
ain't shit you know i was like i get the
citizenship but someone that's
never ever ever ever ever ate this
before
two and a half milligrams of a certain
kind of compound in this plant could be
almost too much for them
right and me old school was you know my
friends because i i've
i've shepherded a lot of people into the
into the plant over the decades my
friends that would be around us that
didn't partake you know i've
a dear sister i love her very much you
know like family is like
very important to me as i've given her
you know
everybody all my buddies you know and
their friends and even the wives that
were doing you know a whole freaking
brownie
you know and everybody can i have a
brownie i say you know
break it in half and me again one more
time here i'm going to break it in a
quarter here you start with this and you
come back to me in an
hour and if you stop then if you want
more i'll give you more and of course an
hour later can i have more i was like
of course you know but i want to make
sure that you're
okay and comfortable with the transition
from being where you are
awake and people don't realize how
special and how clearing this plant is
to your mind
we do as damaged again we as veterans
because we're all damaged
on some level when we when we do embrace
this plan at least how i perceive it is
there's this clearing what you get it
from it
joanne calling what you get from it that
now that you're dialing in that you
don't want thc heavy plants man
you know you you can find this works for
you
i was just saying just for now i will
definitely get back to thc at some point
but i i just know i need a break exactly
exactly and and one again here's what
cam does specifically again
why we're partnering together is he's
been embracing
non-high thc strains
let me rephrase that he's been embracing
full spectrum
correct heritage craft balance strains
the way mother nature intended them to
be
that's what i see where we create this
market or this niche or this veterans
community awareness that we have of
this is how we approach this with our
with our fellow brothers and sisters in
arms man this like you know we don't
care if you want to sit on the couch and
rip bong hits all afternoon and not get
off the couch that's your prerogative
but we're going to show you how to do
this conservatively and correctly the
first time until you get your feet on
the ground
it's like anything you do the first time
you know it's like
you reference tequila i'm not a tequila
guy but i know there's a
full thing of that kind of a run you
know
you know it's like and as colin is
reaching out into now like
psilocybin and and other things that are
out there you know like
freaking peyote which is one of my
personal favorites you know it's like
and i did do a lot of mushrooms and eat
a lot of lsd back in the late 70s and
early 80s when
you know trying to process oh i didn't
get that you know i didn't get
that that's what we were doing that we
were decompressing back then when i was
a young man in my 20s you know i didn't
get that that's what we were doing that
we were trying to
cast off all his calling reference cast
off all this shit we just got finished
done in the previous 72 hours to get
that fucking off of us you know
and it doesn't get off of you at all you
know it follows you through your life
how we process it now what i'm realizing
of i thought my self-isolation was my
sanity i believe the plant is my sanity
now
and teaching people that you don't have
to self-isolate that you can
grasp this plant and it can be a
lifeline to you
maybe it's not maybe it's not but at
least
venture out beyond opioids and alcohol
and self-seclusion and embrace veterans
walk and talk and get around other
brothers and
it did this old man that hadn't been
around other brothers and sisters in
arms for years and years and years two
years ago
for that red-headed son of mine's
birthday to come down and embrace him
and be here it was two years ago and he
hasn't stopped talking since just been
out there just
talking about cannabis left and right
you can't get away from doc now
it's too important colin i know i know
i'm joking
it breaks my heart brother it breaks my
heart man
it really does it kills me the thing
that uh and i
got it how i understood it is i realized
that what joanne you led to it too it's
like
you can't people don't have access you
know it's like and i mean
literally in tears the 22 a day now
they're saying 17 brothers and sisters a
day
22 a day whatever the figure is one too
many
one one a day that's too many yeah
exactly you know
i got i got this plant running out my
frickin ears and we can't get this out
to people why can't this not happen
why can this not happen and we're making
it happen
i hope i hope we are i hope that's
i i want to touch on one last
uh topic and it's kind of you know there
there's so much
division in society right now and people
who get
really upset about certain things and i
i kind of i want to point out some
commonalities
and kind of bridging communities and
you know doc you said i'm going to bring
up two docs
doc ray who earlier in this conversation
talked about when you kind of realize
that
you know the military and the country
doesn't care about you who served it
and doc rivers who said a couple days
ago
you know we keep loving this country and
this country doesn't love us back
there's huge commonality there and i
think
people who get upset about you know
black lives matter and say
all lives matter i think any black
person would say of course
we just hope you realize our lives
matter as much
not even more than but as much as
everybody else is that seems like a
simple ask
um and just the concept of fairness and
society
and you know you're all military
veterans
do any of you get offended when
a pro football player takes a knee
at a stadium to try to raise awareness
for um just kind of
unfairness and society as a slap in the
face to military veterans like you
don't know joanne i want to hear from
joanne on this one
go ahead i mean from a veteran
uh u.s military veteran perspective
no because that is the reason why
we serve colin and i were talking about
it yesterday
we cannot go up to
foreign lands claiming that we are
fighting for the freedom of our people
and come back here and deny the freedom
that is
ridiculous obviously
freedom of speech freedom of of of being
a person
um having your own beliefs we claim that
we accept everyone here for their
values obviously we don't when we
uh think that number one i i
i'm sick and tired of people using
veterans as a pawn to
justify their beliefs or whatever they
think
number one we are just a diversified
group of people
and have different opinions and some may
agree with that and some may disagree
with that so you can
just lump us all in one
uh group because it it doesn't work like
that
um yes we do join the military we have
that in common and we
fight alongside each other despite
our differences despite our mindset
despite what we look like and make shit
happen
um do good things do bad things whatever
the case may be
but in there um we're all doing that
and even in the military you know there
are people that are racist
and still have to work alongside a black
person and get the job done
um and you know same situation um but
ultimately
no i'm not offended i think that is
exactly
why i went to war twice you know that
for people to be able to do that here so
no to answer the question it does not
offend me
i think it's the way it should be
so you know they're not it's somebody
that's not
breaking a law or um hurting
anybody um but actually standing up for
something they believe and something
that
does need to be addressed obviously look
at the circumstances we're in
so if that wasn't predicting that hey
putting a shedding light on a situation
in america that
it's you know it's about time we get
over that hump
um clearly so not at all
i think it was necessary and i think
it's still necessary for people to stand
up for what they believe in
or what or you know for stuff that's
violating
uh human right rights in america so no
not offending i'm proud as hell so i
i want to hear from the three white
males in this conversation who all
served our country
your thoughts on someone taking a knee
to try to raise awareness for social
justice
are you offended because people watching
this
are white males who
[Music]
think it's horrific and and not
patriotic
so talk to those people i mean i'm i'm
happy to
talk about this i am not offended i
think that
it is uh thank you for unmuting my mic i
think that is
um heroic i think that it is something
to be revered in this country when you
stand up to something that is wrong
that should be celebrated um i am
reading a book right now that has got my
uh absolute mind it's called how fascism
works
and i can't recommend it enough it is
very informative
and what this lays out and what has
happened throughout history
is this mythic past of patriotism that
everyone holds on to and this
patriarchal
society that everything is war is good
if you go to war
be proud about it no matter what you did
no matter if you did bad things don't
talk about those things only talk about
the good things
your your beautiful wife at home should
be proud to be making kids and be taking
care of those kids
while you're off fighting this war that
nobody seriously
really even understands and what it goes
back to for me
is admitting mistakes because it's it's
okay to make mistakes it's not
that's what life is to to be
to be human is to air to air is to be
human right
shakespeare so um you
making mistakes is okay but admitting
them
is just where we get off and we won't
admit our mistakes and so we built up
this mythic past of america
as being this great land of opportunity
the heartland the heartland the
heartland the the
the people that feed us the farmers the
people they should be revered
their opinions everything it should be
preserved pride should be preserved
that is all systematic racism and if you
don't admit that you are
fooling yourself the fact of the matter
is
people like colin kaepernick taking a
knee takes more bravery
than a lot of people understand that is
not easy
it is it is it is almost impossible in
this day and age and look at the
look at what it's caused i it's one man
one man
and look at what it's caused for good or
bad people are still talking about it
and that's what's important
for me i see
i you cannot get you can't i can't have
a conversation with people
who start off by saying this this
country isn't racist this country was
built on racism this country sends
people to war based on racism
all i i can't speak for everybody here
but for me i came to the army at my
absolute lowest point i had no other
alternative that's such a common
story why is that the case why are why
are our most
downtrodden and hurt people why are the
people who are impoverished in this
country the ones serving it the most
these are all things that need to change
and until we admit it
it won't so absolutely i don't
right now i i'm having a baby in
november or i would be on every front
line of these protests
every single one and i i i can't
everybody out there protesting don't
stop
well you have been though so we've been
approaching that's true yeah
that's true we have and i wouldn't i'd
be there out there every i wanna i mean
like i
i feel this call to action now but it's
almost too like it's
too great like it's like i want
something to put my hands on i'm just
like i can
get and grasp you know like if racism
was right in front of me i could just
choke it until it was gone but
it doesn't work like that which is why
these books are
you don't understand like the level of
effort
that goes into dividing us it is crazy
and cannabis
is the great unifier and put it back
around it
brought it back around to that shirt i
love that
and what i think people don't realize is
this isn't about taking away from
somebody or a group or a class of people
this is about
raising everybody up this is about
looking all of our brothers and sisters
in the eye and having that contact and
that love
and if you listen to the people that are
spewing the hate they're angry at people
who they've
never met on the word of somebody that
is a known liar or
is out there to mr misrepresent i've
been very blessed to be able to travel
all over the world
and every place i've been i haven't been
to shithole countries
i've met beautiful people everywhere
i've been
and i can't tell you how i think i think
travel will solve a lot of that
but the powers that be are trying to
divide us so we don't unite
and we just need to look at each other
and and listen
this is my time right now to listen to
people and hear what's happening and see
is i'm at that weird transition where i
still think i'm 18 but yeah i think i'm
about to get an aarp letter
but everybody keeps talking about our
kids how they're lazy they're shiftless
they just do
play video games no we need to listen to
them we need to be
mentors we need to support them we need
to show them that there's more community
than
anger and vitriol we need to show the
younger kids that
it's okay to listen and to love another
person that you disagree with
and i i'm hoping you need great trauma
to heal
and i think we're going to have to rip
the band-aid off rip the scab off
re-break the bone and let it heal
properly add a little cannabis bomb in
it
it'll fix yeah this there you go
well said and that's all about admitting
that we were wrong
let's just admit we were wrong about so
many things i mean
we we we're not even like we're talking
about this joanne yesterday in our
podcast like
growing up as a american man learning an
education system
schools where i was taught segregation
like not
about it i was taught that it's how you
should live
cliques are a word for segregation you
know you're
these things are taught to us in our
institutions that we're supposed to
trust
there's so many america is a beautiful
beautiful country
it it has potential it's also was the
first of its kind in
many ways and an experiment that is just
over 200 years old
so it's okay to admit we made mistakes
we're that young i mean
we barely know what we're doing can we
just admit that
and then move forward like you said let
it scab over put some cbd bomb on it and
move forward
period period
[Laughter]
so the for me the the contrast
is and that that for me was really
important because i
i you know
there are a lot of impressionable people
who watch this
and i want them to hear from real
veterans that
you're not offended uh and and
they the people who are offended didn't
serve in the military so i'm like
well that's the truth in the military
that is the point i wanted nobody this
up
well that's what i said about the people
that use the military
as a pond like us to mask
their agenda and lumping us all in one
category as if
we all think collectively as one thing
so for me the most egregious thing
was discovering that the nfl
had their you know pay-to-play
patriotism where they were collecting
money from the armed services
for all the dramatic uh you know
national
anthem like military jets flying
overhead
uh that makes you want to throw up
the nfl the atlanta falcons yep
go ahead and so
so it's interesting to see what people
get upset about and then
you said it though peter you said but
you said again in in colin you alluded
to it too is that false patriotism the
ones that are the ones that are upset
there are
veterans you know again generationally
because i'm hearing it from you
guys generation of me ben i give a damn
what color you were
okay quite honestly my teammate was
black
i love him so much you know we we we're
partners you know we were intertwined at
the hips man
that we depended on each other you know
and i don't care man
it's just the bottom line of it you know
it's like and it breaks my heart because
i raise my children just
to be color blind also and it just
really breaks my freaking heart
because i personally had thought this
was something we had worked through and
what i realized is we haven't worked
through shit
in over a half a century and i grew up
in that time period in the 60s and saw
this
saw a lot of this turmoil and unrest and
it and the thing that
kills me and i'm sick and tired of it
and maybe as a veteran community
we address it these posers man
these things that show up with their
indignants with their flags and their
body armor and all their crap trying to
say that they represent us and they
don't represent us you know how do we
come in and play a part in this thing
you know i'm not sure how to address
that one peter
but i do know this part of it there is
that
that part of it that i just it's like
i don't see it cam's saying he doesn't
see it
colin's saying he doesn't see it john
said she doesn't see it we're
generationally
we're talking 44 decades of freaking
military
covering it all and we as a community
don't necessarily embrace it i'm not
saying that there's not that
fringe that does see it but we have
worked integrated for
freaking decades and we as a team
approach things as a team
we don't see black and white we don't
see yellow and brown
we see green or we see blue
or we see od and that's how we function
and we all depended on each other to
keep each other alive
so when they come out this false
patriotism thing at the
football football games and all that
nonsense it's like it's just a bunch of
nonsense man
and i don't know you you helping voice
the veteran community to us getting out
is like the true ones of us that have
paid
sign the blank check the ones that has
really signed that piece of paper
and did the time we're not the ones that
are up in arms about this thing man
it's it's ones that aren't really part
of it it's one that aren't part of our
veteran community the
the distractors the naysayers whatever
you want to call a man
the the instigators whoever they are
they think they're trying their personal
gain on something that
isn't and joanne says you know trying to
get what they want off of our blood
sweat and tears and our backs man it's
like
that's part i don't think we as a
community well again we as a community
don't get addressed 99
of the time why because only three
percent of us on the whole freaking
country
ever served this country and then it's
even more integrated when you get into
families that are military families like
me
i have four grown children and all four
of them have served
okay i have three that are active right
now
okay this is part of again we are a
military community i have a baby brother
that is a marine corps my old man was in
the air force
we are a military family okay
that sways that three percent by a lot
when it's one or two families where
their whole family served
you know and as we see we've seen
generationally since vietnam
people that come from underprivileged
backgrounds find it as a way out
to get out and get where they want to go
that don't have
a slot at an ivy league college you know
as a military family we
we we worked poor we worked hard you
know
what no silver spoons here that whole
thing it's like we this is that
the military was a way to get away from
it
you know get you to where you wanted to
go what happened with me
generationally i shifted i instilled in
my kids because i knew they were going
to do it
instilled in them to get what they
wanted out of it they've also
selected career careers within the
branches that they thought would best
serve them
after the fact okay and i'm off topic on
this thing but to
assume that we as a veteran community
get offended because someone takes a
a knee during a sporting's event for
crying out loud it's a freaking game
that that's what i've always laughed at
is how did sports events become
these patriotic uh you know like
national anthem at the beginning of
every professional
and college sports game it's because the
department of defense has an
entertainment budget
period as long as the department of
defense has an entertainment budget and
a recruiting budget
there you're going to get false
patriotism that the the fact of the
matter is the department of defense pays
the nfl in order to put flags out and
put guys who look revered and and do all
that stuff
so that their recruiting numbers in this
in the worst parts of our country
will be beefed up because football and
people of color and all these things are
severely affected by
so much of the poverty and so much of
the systematic racism
at the top of our country right now
whether or not you want to put out
everything else that that
that man as our president has done
that man wouldn't last two seconds on a
line
two seconds now for me that means a lot
what put that man on an aircraft carrier
and watch him watch what happens if he's
blown by a fucking
aircraft jet see what happens to that
man i'm pretty sure he's not going to
get back and go to work like i did
and he's and he's going to be milking
that forever and
here's the thing with that is like
i joined the infantry in 2007
late 2007-2008 i
had to go through rigorous psychological
and psychiatric
psychiatric testing before i was able to
join i had to take an iq score
i had to take the asvab i had to
because i admitted to using cannabis i
joined the military at 26 years old
because i admitted to using cannabis
more than 50 times before prior to
joining
i was made to see a psychiatrist
these are all things i had to go through
in order to go to war
and be in a lethal instrument
of this country why is it that
anyone with the money to put their name
out there
can climb to the very top of that pillar
and be in charge of everyone that is
so backwards and
wrong in so many ways again
we just have to come to an understanding
that some things we've tried have not
worked
and i think we will grow from them
hopefully so hopefully we'll see that
and i and i'm not speaking for everybody
but i hope that we see a
shift that we haven't seen quite
honestly i'm i'm going to go back a
little bit for some of you guys when
clarence thomas was
going on to the supreme court and anita
hill we've seen this
the swell of females and
people of color and unrepresented
move into the political spectrum that
wasn't there
previously it took you know then that
was 91 it's like that's how far
back this goes since the last time we've
seen this kind of grassroots movements
within our politics and i'm so thankful
to see so many women coming quite
honestly
it pisses me off being a crotchety old
white guy to get looped in with all
these other jackasses or crotchy old
white guys because i am not one of those
motherfuckers no
i'll tell you something we are all aware
that not everybody is like that
um i i'm thankful for it sister because
i i don't
i'm thankful for that not everybody is
like that and quite frankly
even in the military where i
experience individuals who came from a
background where
perhaps growing up the only perception
of a black person they had was what they
saw on tv
um and then coming into contact and
seeing like
whoa and admitting like i was completely
like i
never thought um a black person would be
able to do this
or act a certain way or um so
even in that happened in the military
and quite frankly
witnessing that gave me number one an
even more
greater understanding of the fabric of
america and the limited exposure that
people have
um and at the same time people can come
to to their senses once you know coming
like you said
i think it was kim that said earlier
traveling just completely changes your
your perspective because exposure
matters
um and also even on tv like
representation matter so if you
have this race portrayed as a
way on tv and that's the only
access that these people have to view in
that
clearly it creates some systemic issues
um in the fabric of america and i think
the fact that all this stuff is arising
and
we are all even no matter which spectrum
which side of the spectrum you
end up as far as your beliefs um we all
know there's a fucking problem
and i feel that we are all actively
working towards
um making the necessary corrections
um we don't know the there's a problem
that was created like colin said we
can't put an
actual face to it so we can
punch it but you know we just got to
continue to move forward
we have to continue to admit that
there's a problem awareness
and then what can we do personally how
far can we reach
to cause an impact and a change um
and the fact you know that we have these
conversations colin and i get together
weekly and have
um discussions that we know are not
being had
so if we have the eyes on ourselves
we should go ahead and discuss them um
and
right now because we are most of us are
just enclosed
not everybody we we're not so caught up
in
in life um now we're home with this
whole kimono virus shit it has
literally um it's it's had us glued to
a box for the most part whether it's
your small screen or
or the bigger one um and now
we have we can't turn away so now you
know
we all have to actually do something
which honestly guys
um it excites me you know that the fact
like okay so now
you really don't got much going on what
are you gonna do to make the change
because now you know that something has
something has to change um and i'm super
proud of at least a circle around me
and obviously by extension with you guys
that
we are all towards elevating everybody
elevating you know we are aware that a
group of people black people we've not
been elevated by this country so it's
about time
that we equal the playing field and we
are human too and we've contributed
as a collective um to
lot just as much if not you know
speaking from
from my culture we've we've contributed
more than enough to have a seat at the
table and that's
a man sister honestly because
cannabis bringing it full circle joanne
cannabis
as you've said as we've talked about is
a matriarchal
industry it is a plant that we smoke is
a female plant
it is a matriarchal community and
america is as you know father first as
it gets
so that threatens the fabric as you said
of america
but it needs to be threatened and it
needs to be
sowed the the matriarchy and the
minority-led
empowerment that cannabis provides is
one of the most exciting things about
being in this community
yeah i think we can cannabis um
definitely
can be an industry that we can
we can we can pioneer this movement
continue to
show that we all can work together that
you know through medicine to what
through wellness
um we can create like cultural change
from the root you know from the seed
um if you really i i always like to uh
take it back whether it's in business as
far as the industry goes or
as far as medicine go like we are just
planting seeds
whether it's education the scientific
aspect of it
the cultural aspect of it the social
we're planting seeds um in
literally and figuratively figuratively
speaking
and um we just got to be patient and
continue to do the good work
um and the plants will sprout and
eventually
we will we will be causing a radical
change
um positive change for not only for
america but
global at a global scale that's that's
how much i do
believe uh in not only what we're all
doing here but
like the plan itself and where we can
take this
so amy and sister amen
farming and agriculture and cultivation
mono cropping and monoculture is
never sustainable you need a bit of
everything you need a broad spectrum of
everything
flowers and vegetables and trees and
fruits and
all kinds of we can't have a monoculture
in our culture as well or our
communities
exactly that thank you for beautifully
um coming into there making it come
together so that's exactly what i meant
well why don't we why don't we uh that's
a good mic drop moment
uh why don't we end there and we can
always regroup at a later date
we can get ready for part two whenever
that may be
i can't wait guys it was such a pleasure
it was
an amazing conversation um totally guys
oh y'all as well you're doing the work i
i look forward to working together you
know
um whether it's coming back and
regrouping or um
just getting the word out there so thank
you so much thanks colin we need to talk
a little bit more
thank you because every all of this is
happening at the same time and i've had
this is the third conversation like this
i've had this week
the universe is putting us all in each
other's paths and we're all asking
the same questions how do we get this
knowledge out there how do we make a
change what can we do
in my neighborhood in my family my town
my state
and we're all here together and so let's
keep this going between us too on how we
can help each other to move this forward
as well
because you know we we have a good reach
and
this is what it's going to take to get
us to move forward is conversations like
this
and you know we all each have a piece of
this puzzle
and so how are we going to all put them
together and how many more people are
out there that have pieces that we've
been looking for
so we just need to to keep this out
there and raise your hand saying i'm
here to help
so absolutely thank you all i appreciate
you no thank you guys unbelievably fun
thank you
thanks everyone