how y'all doing over here with
Rocksteady cannabis cultivation I'm
rocky aka rocky slick well you're trying
to talk about these uh phenotypes that I
have with his THC bomb this is a video
that was requested by a future cannabis
project you know I love what you guys do
and I just wanted to oblige what you
guys asked for it you know I mean him
but I offered to you so this right here
is one phenotype the THC bomb this was
actually a seed that I had and as you
can tell it's a season over here by take
a look at the stem it's just huge and
thick I have these in 25 gallon plastic
grow bags with dr. earth dry amendments
a couple other things I use you know I
gotta say man organic is the way to go
man they'll never find flavors and
tastes and just strong plants like like
you would somewhere else with chemicals
you know these plants have been trained
and taught you know I do a lot of a lot
of training man you know so I can get
organic no-till method I just don't have
a mulch layer up right now you know if
you're curious about some of the some of
the nutrients that I use I use a mixture
of a few things I use fermented fruit
fertilizers that would be the jar right
there that's cantaloupe meat and organic
honey and raw unbleached sugar and you
put it in that mason jar and you let it
do its thing for a little while and then
for my nitrogen boost I use this Alaskan
fish fertilizer and then over there
further down is going to be here
and more of a pumping girl I use that
for pH control 2 for my water instead of
using anything else I use that for pH
and you know just for a quick added
boost you know it's a good to feature
microbes you know also down here in the
bottom I got the compost from dr. earth
man I've gotta say this stuff is great
you see the plants blow up really really
fast man
I also use the dry amendments the dr.
earth brute fertilizer tomato herb and
vegetable and I also use the flower girl
which is like a two nine six or
something to that effect but it's
definitely for flower and these plants
need to be watered right now once they
need to you know when they're thirsty I
let him tell me so that they can you
know pull everything out of the ground
like they want to you know you know
they've been up for a little while now
you know this medication just came to me
out of nowhere this strain man I was
actually trying to get some power
cookies and some sherbert man and my
friend tossed this to me kind of
accidentally he said and it ended up
being a blessing my wife has
degenerative disc disease she's 41 years
old and sometimes can't walk you know
it's really bad we have four kids and
this specific strain not only the
cannabis plant itself of course helps a
lot but this specific strain really
gives my wife quality of life man I mean
we have four boys and we wouldn't be
running around and doing we had to do if
it wasn't for the strain that just was a
blessing in disguise you know
this other Fino i have over here is
definitely showing good traits I mean
it's so thick strong you know I gotta
say this is like no other strain I've
ever grown when it does flower out it's
like you can't trim me I have to get
teflon coated nonstick Fiskars to be
able to trim and it's just insane man
it's the dry sift and if you guys are
doing hash or dry sift or anything with
this pressing it
this plant is built for concentrates I
mean when you lie to join if it it just
catches on fire because of so much resin
and oil production inside of the plant
itself you know this is what I want to
do really man this is gonna be my
profession I'm just kind of starting how
slow and low you know and I really want
to know what you guys think about what
I'm doing here you know and if you have
any more questions or you guys want
access to any other genetics I do have
that and I'm happy to oblige especially
the people who have paved the way for us
know so I just want to show you guys
this video and give it to you with much
respect and you know with admiration as
to what you guys do cuz you guys showed
me a lot two minutes so thank you very
much Rocksteady cannabis cultivation