[Music]
so we're talking volatile organic
compounds and one thing that kind of
blew me away is every time I've ever
thought about you know greenhouse or
indoor cultivation and having kind of
odor control systems it's always been
about the smell like the neighbors don't
like the smell or you don't want people
to know you're growing a sense
perspective or a security perspective
but there's actually a totally different
reason why you don't want the terpenes
floating out of your facility and into
the neighborhood so you talk about that
yes happy to sow terpenes are volatile
organic compounds volatile organic
compounds are important because they're
an ingredient to ozone and ozone
although it's protective in the
atmosphere when it's up high it's kind
of acts as an insulating blanket for our
atmosphere but down low in you know
where we're breathing the air it's
actually a toxic air pollutant it
oxidizes our lungs that actually
oxidizes plants as well you actually see
the plants almost like turn black and
look bruised in a high ozone environment
so ozone is formed when volatile organic
compounds are released into the
atmosphere and react with nitrogen oxide
emissions nitrogen dioxide emissions are
combustion emissions cars power plants
anytime we're burning anything we get
nitrogen oxide as a result so when
nitrogen oxide and volatile organic
compounds meet in the presence of
sunlight they form that ground-level
ozone which is toxic for us to breathe
in Colorado it's it's a it's an issue
that we're looking into because all of
our cannabis cultivation is in our urban
environment co-located next to all of
our our major highways our cars our
power plants about 60 to 70 percent of
our marijuana cultivation is within our
urban environment and so we want to know
how many pounds of VOCs are emitted per
pound of marijuana grown and then what
is the ultimate influence on that ozone
reaction because it's a public health
issue it's toxic for us to breathe it's
toxic fire and by
and so we want to be its a heightened
and it puts a new perspective on your
odor control system right a heightened
sensitivity because now you're not only
controlling odor for nuisance reasons or
for security reasons you're actually
contributing to the public health of
your community by controlling those
odors because of the rat secondary
reaction that can happen with ozone
formation right so just to be clear if
you're growing and somewhere like
humboldt or Mendocino or somewhere kind
of removed you're not really creating
that problem but if you're right you
have a big greenhouse next to the
highway in Santa Barbara or down in LA
you have an indoor grow and you're
pumping what smells to me beautiful out
you're you know a NOx rich area and so
when you have a NOx rich area like in an
urban environment like downtown LA
there's a smog problem you guys haven't
there industrial sources as well that
you know provide combustion emissions
and so when you bring in this new source
of volatile organic compounds that
traditionally wouldn't be there you get
new ozone formation I have a question
so terpenes are obviously found in other
products as well are they problematic
there are tours there's something about
cannabis that is especially problematic
sure so VOCs come come in many different
products anything that traditionally you
know has an odor with it is you're
smelling the volatile organic compound
coming off of that so you know personal
care products deodorants you know
perfumes and then industrial sources
would be like solvents and paints you
know but any other agricultural source
pine trees they're all putting off
different volatile organic compounds but
what's unique about cannabis is that we
took it from the forest and put it in
the the urban environment to create
those reactions and then also it just
happens to be that the terpene profile
associated with cannabis those terpenes
are highly reactive on the scale for our
ozone formation compared to other
terpenes so one of the things I feel
like Mira Singh pioneering limonene
was the other like top the top Turpin
Alina pennilyn like those are some of
the most egregious in terms of ozone and
what's the nitrogen oxide yes you can
short as NOx nos yeah so does it make
sense for a state to mandate where
terpene rich products and agriculture
are grown within the state but I mean
that's one factor you know in Colorado
we had a lot of regulatory drivers that
drove our our industry indoor and in you
know our urban environment zoned
industrial co located next to these
sources and so it just you know the
environmental impacts of that was a
little bit of an afterthought and so
we're trying to just quantify what is
you know what is the impact it's really
important to point out that there's no
regulatory drivers here because cannabis
is an agricultural process at least the
cultivation of it and agricultural
processes are exempt from air quality
regulations this is unique agricultural
process in that no other agricultural
commodity has the profit margins for it
to make sense to grow it in the way that
we grow cannabis we would never grow
tomatoes downtown next to Coors Field
you just wouldn't do it we do that with
cannabis you talked a little bit in your
panel today about how carbon filtration
can be designed specifically to you know
to correlate with phytochemical data how
can phytochemical data collection be
standardized at state and hopefully one
day federal levels to improve that
outcome and also I hope improve consumer
outcomes as well because now they have
the ingredients available to them yes so
knowledge is very powerful once we know
the dieter Pina mission profile is
specific to these cannabis facilities we
can design carbon filtration that's
customized to capture those molecules
because carbon filtration is a physical
solution to a chemical problem the way
the carbon filtration works is there's a
lots of pores within the carbon filter
and
actually physically traps those
molecules so if those carbon pores are
too big or too small
we're not effectively capturing those
molecules so we want to design the
carbon filter specifically for the
pollutants that we're trying to capture
and so in this case those top four
terpenes they're each physically a
specific size so you'd have a carbon
filtration system that had pores that
were each of those sizes so it's going
to captured yeah and it might be you
know those four might have like they
might be in a family where it's even a
similar size where we're targeting that
specific molecules but and very
different carbon filtration for plant
molecules versus you know industrial
sources of VOCs like maybe an ethanol or
something like that right okay so now
the other interesting thing we were
talking about was the wine industry and
they're noticing kind of neuter paint
like someone makes their Cabernet in
Sonoma and they're noticing a new
terpene yeah they're cherry that wasn't
there before and they're attributing it
to cannabis cultivation yes that is
happening in the wine industry and
they're interested in my vo C research
from that perspective because they want
to know what are the dominant terpenes
coming off of cannabis cultivation and
are those dominant terpenes showing up
in our final wine profile and what is
the consumer response to that do we
embrace it as you know only Santa
Barbara wine has these cannabis terpenes
in it or you know do do we fight against
the grain there and so that's something
that the wine industry is having to
adapt to you know with this this new
influx of industry being co-located next
to them but then also from the cannabis
you know farmers perspective they're
heavily regulated on what pesticides
they can use versus the wine industry is
not so you can see from you know the
transport cannabis is transporting
terpenes to the wine wineries and then
the wineries are transferring you know
pesticides to the chemicals it's really
interesting because the beer industry or
parts of it are embracing terpenes and
actually putting them into him creating
new products that are terpene rich and
killing it
yeah yes yeah I mean I mean there's also
cannabis products to where people are
adding terpenes you know concentrated
terpenes and to get different flavor
profiles you know what is it yeah I had
a really interesting lesson about
extraction or very early on because I
was naive and thought well why doesn't
everybody do co2 extraction so we don't
get those volatile organic compounds off
of solvents someone had to educate me
and tell me well with co2 extraction
you're not getting the terpene profile
extracted you're only getting the
cannabinoids so that'd be akin to like
you know drinking Everclear versus a
fine craft beer or a wine where you're
getting those flavor profiles so I had
to really shift my perspective to
understand the consumer needs that are
driving these processes peanut gallery
any other questions are you guys just so
overwhelmed by these details you know
well the one thing I thought of was that
even if it's not regulated the argument
to get cultivation out of urban areas
into you know rural areas or even
farther out is a really strong one and
might counter the NIMBY a fact that is
you know really problematic in
California you know so many
municipalities that you know are saying
no to cannabis um if they could be
incentivized or you know they had a
really powerful reason which this is you
know these industries will if they're in
in if they're in your area it's it's a
it's a it's a it's a quality it's a
quality of life benefit you know the
environment benefits in a big way so I
mean that's one of the things that I
thought about I don't think it could be
regulated but it's one way or another
you know the the production and the can
you know in California the patchwork
system is just not working so I you know
that was one of the I think the the
biggest lesson we can learn you know
collectively for the cannabis industry
from Colorado is the willingness to be
nimble and adapt our regulatory
structure to the needs of the cannabis
industry
you know very early on with us being one
of the first regulated markets we all of
our regulations were focused on safety
security no diversion to the black
market the the environment wasn't
necessarily considered in that
regulatory structure and so now that
we're you know a couple of years into
legalization and and the house didn't
fall down and so to speak we can start
circling back and finding efficiencies
in our regulatory structure and working
with the cannabis industry to still meet
all of the needs of safety security no
diversion to the black market but in a
more logical sensible way I think the
best example of that would be you know
either the 50/50 waste rule with plant
mixing half team to mix with 50 percent
non marijuana waste which doubles our
landfill footprint or you know from the
packaging perspective of childproof
packaging yes we want to protect our
youth but can we do it in a way that's
not five layers of packaging could we
manage to do it in one and then I always
you don't need a packaged flower well I
I also like to throw it out there from
an environmental perspective now the
public health side of the house doesn't
like this perspective but from an
environmental perspective we don't do
childproof packaging on alcohol or
tobacco why cannabis or keeping it in
the family and you know focusing our
efforts on creating hemp cellulose
packaging that is far more sustainable
yeah we're starting to see advances and
hemp-based plastics certainly in
Colorado and they they do have they
break down a lot quicker than plastics
traditional plastics well and I talked
to brands that are kind of making these
packaging decisions because it costs
more so it's kind of like does the
consumer care enough to pay a tiny bit
more you know that's the question right
now at least so before you go is there
research on your next well no she I'm
joking yeah it's 520 so she has to go
but is there research being done to
assess like what like what the impact is
of these terpene VOCs like what are they
how much they
like the amount actually yeah I'm doing
that research yeah so I am collecting
air quality samples from commercial
cannabis cultivation facilities getting
speciation results what are the terpenes
being emitted and in what concentrations
and then we will be putting that into
very sophisticated air quality models
that already know what are the sources
of of nitrogen oxide what are all the
other sources of volatile organic
compounds and put that all together add
the layer of cannabis emissions what's
the resulting impact on ozone this is a
very complicated scientific process and
you're in the earliest stages of this
research um well we actually we hope to
publish the results this summer so so
we're we're pretty far along but this
summer hopefully initial findings are
like oh the biggest thing that I can can
share at this point is just the the
dominant terpene emission profile that
we're seeing is you know mersin pining
limiting and Turpin alene I mean those
are by far the dominant terpenes that
we're seeing we're we're definitely
seeing a whole family of other terpenes
but at much much lower concentrations
those are the dominant ones that we're
seeing and I think that's really
important information to know because
now we know what we're controlling right
we don't know the concentrations yet but
we know what we're controlling at least
so at the end of this you'll have a
sense of say in Denver here's how much
ozone is being emitted as a result of
these practices correct
awesome that should be the results of
that should be super interesting and
should have an impact yes absolutely um
you know in Colorado we're using it as
an educational piece you know we want to
know we want to understand where our
ozone is coming from and all this
building block information absolutely
and it will have impacts nationwide and
across the globe for sure thank you yes
thank you for having