[Music]
hi my name is Jeremy Moberg I'm CEO of
Kennesaw farms and president and founder
of The Washington Sun Growers Industry
Association which is a group in
Washington state that represents some
growers and hi guys I'm Jade Stefano and
I'm CEO and co-founder of puffin farm
also a Sun grown farm and I'm also on
the board of directors of the Delta
Washington some growers Industry
Association as well and we were going to
talk about start the conversation off
with how we select strains and how we
kind of follow the market trends on
strains which can be a really annoying
thing actually so I know that I I don't
think I've chased the strains as much
and I don't think you're big change
trace chaser either I'm not following
the instagrams looking for what's hot
you know was it wedding cake or wedding
mac or mac or any of that I think we've
I've taken sort of a kind of a slower
approach but not to say that we don't
have what we call signature strains in
Kennesaw farms which is a really
difficult thing to do to kind of claim a
strain and to make it sort of your brand
strain I know you've had you have a
couple strains strains that we are that
are have a cult following in Washington
we have a hindu kush which originally
came out of Oregon as a clone only and
we also have a high CBD strain called
dancehall which originated from Spain
and those are seeds that we imported
from Spain prior to legalization back in
the medical day so you sprouted and we
sprouted that one yeah and so both other
one was a clone the other one was a
clone that we were given by an Oregon
grower a friend of ours and so those two
strains the reason why we have stuck
with those is when you're growing
outdoors you can't really grow every
strain you have to grow it works in your
environment so we originally started out
with maybe 50 100 strains and we've
winnowed it down to like the ones that
really win on our terroir so like some
strains they might be beautifully
indoors at our farm they don't do well
and they might do well at Jeremy's far
I've taken a little bit of different
approach I believe that I can grow any
strain except for the completely
equatorial strains those are just out of
the question can't be can't really be
grown in a commercial environment at all
um do you get irritated when you see or
have you ever seen a different like the
Hindukush produced by a different farm
yeah so there are other phenotypes out
there and which we've been told ours is
the best one in Washington and so
they're not the other ones are not super
popular from what I can tell and people
say that ours is the best so ours is
kind of really establish yourself in the
market but there are and it's kind of
hard to own a string but we have this
phenotype though is is very special it
is a huge producer outdoors it is an
early season finisher and it tastes
amazing yeah it's beautiful bud
structure it looks like indoor weed so
it's got everything going for is disease
resistant it's like a miracle strain and
we just got so lucky and blessed to be
given that and so you know that was pure
luck we didn't even seek that out
someone gave that to us as a gift yeah
so that was our that was definitely a
clear champion and every year after year
it's a great producer and does amazing
it produces often 10:00 to 1:00 to other
strains that we grow like dancehall for
instance and some of the CBD strains we
do specialize in CBD strains which has
differentiated us in the market but
there are abysmal producers for the most
part but we provide that for people that
need it we like to grow it and it helps
us get a niche that we wouldn't
otherwise have we have 3/4 of an acre of
canopy 30,000 square feet our farm we're
on a 20 acre farm by the river we do
full season Jeremy does job and so we've
got a little different model going as
far as and he can grow more strains like
he said he can grow anything because he
does like that but with a full season
you're much more limited you're so
limited at the northern latitudes by
what you can grow full term and so it
really becomes the full terms you know
it's great its low its low cost you can
produce some really nice material from
it and it's really an expression of the
tirar of the of the weather and
everything and so we do have sort of our
signature strains we call them kind of
pick them up when you know in 2011 when
you started seeing clone markets in
Seattle you know that was the very first
time where I could like go get genetics
and
by a clone you know besides like from a
friend you know and that was really
amazing so I started just getting
everything that I could and I went up to
about 250 clones at the beginning and
have whittled that down and I'm always
somewhere between 80 and a hundred and
fifty different clones and our signature
strains as we call them are our Alice in
Wonderland which was a clone that we
picked up in the medical market in 2011
mm and cheesecake was also a Columbia
picked up back then and then cashy's
honey which came from the CBD project
and Ringo's farm in California and
that's been an amazing one that we have
popularized as as a strain and then in
the full term side we had a strain that
local Okanagan where we our man had been
breeding and it was it was harvested
like in mid-september which is just
great for outdoors and so we started
crossing that with everything because it
was high terpene high camera noise so
now we have all these juicy crosses I
got the juicy double lemon juicy turbine
juicy Allison Wonderland
and so that's kind of how we've handled
the full term outdoor market one thing
we've discovered we've both been
licensed for five and a half years at
this point we're going into our sixth
season and so it's definitely a game of
like branding and distinguishing
yourself and and going in and talking to
people and you know getting to know the
bud tenders getting to know the buyers
and so we spend quite a bit of time at
events going into stores talking to
people making friends you know smoking
people out and there's a large social
element to all this and you know you
could be a really great grower and have
beautiful flower but if you can't get in
and and be there on the ground - I'm
interact with people it gets really
difficult and then in the brand is
really important - you have to have a
brand that resonates with people that's
attractive that's pretty you have to
think about packaging and there's a lot
to this it's not I mean you can grow
great weed but if you can't sell it
it doesn't do any good and selling it is
a lot more about personal relationships
as well as packaging and branding than
it is necessarily about the quality and
that is actually proven when there's a
lot of shitty weed and beautiful well
branded packages it's doing quite well
ya know it's and when you have a brand
you're trying to appeal say to a 45 year
old demographic and your bud tenders and
your and your buyers are in their
mid-20s and more concerned about the
Instagram account then really you know
the sustainability or the practices that
you're using that becomes very difficult
so your your audience is maybe a 40 year
old woman but you've got to get past the
25 year old kid that you know for some
reason is in charge of buying because
the owner is a little bit disconnected
and thinks that well all the other young
kids no we'd the most you know and so
that becomes difficult to get past and
you know and then so then you're like
you're really having to schmooze these
these bud tenders and you know and
they're the ones that are reacting like
to the next greatest strain and
everything yeah and so there is
definitely this market pressure to sort
of chase the next batch strain we kind
of believe or I kind of believe that a
lot of my demographic or chemical
consumers really want to establish what
they like and they want to stick with
that and they're not really chasing the
next thing I think that's more of the
younger ya generation yeah I agree with
all that and one thing I am seeing
though just to give a little more hope
to the situation is that um some of
these young kids are they're smart and
they they they start learning about
terpenes and they start actually tasting
a difference themselves and it kind of
opens their eyes to like this whole new
world so once you get past that barrier
with them that they can that it's about
terpenes and it's about the experience
and the flavor and it's not about the
brand or how the buds look they get
really excited about it and there's
actually you become a following there's
like young you know millennial kids who
are like living soil fanboys and
fangirls and it's really great to see
that and that's something that is kind
of the last two years is becoming more
and more evident where you'll see these
millennial but hunters showing up to
cultivation panels to listen about
living soil which is just great and
that's given me some hope and Washington
in particular like Oregon in California
doesn't have this problem so much in
Washington we have such a long history
of indoor growing that uh there's just
this there is this sort of look and feel
for marijuana that the market has has
going after and to see the bud tenders
finally starting to understand that high
quality cannabis can be grown under the
Sun in fact what we're learning is
higher quality cannabis because we're
not only not even to mention the
environmental impacts but also the
camera noise and the terpenes are
generally higher when grown outside
under the right conditions and
particularly light up when you're taking
advantage of those hot dry summer days
and so we're we're slowly starting to
get some bud tenders to kind of come
around and understand the value of Sun
grown and the harm of indoor grown and
in one way we do that is that we we are
about ready to come on to our second
annual Sun Cup and that's held right
around 4:20 and Earth Day because before
4:20 there was another holiday it was
called Earth Day and now 420 kind of
took over Earth Day and in Washington
particular they're celebrating indoor
grown a cannabis that just has a huge
environmental impact so we're trying to
bring that discussion back in and then
the judges are all bud tenders so we're
you know trying to get bud tenders to to
appreciate sun-grown
give them give them a judging position
they all get excited they they tell all
their friends you know and then all of a
sudden you start to lose the biased
against it but Washington unlike other
markets well at least what California
and Oregon is very biased towards
endorse and I think we're gonna see this
bias continue as legalization goes to
the east and we really Washington really
needs to get a handle on this I mean for
example you know Willie Nelson has a
brand out there and it's primarily
indoor grown and then he puts out a
brand called Sun grown and of course
it's cheaper and and lower quality and
at the bottom of the shelf so even
Willie you know probably unbeknownst to
him is is propagating this idea that
indoor cannabis is is a higher quality
and should be more expensive our
companies in particular we're where we
believe that people want to pay for
these words sustainability organic
things that they're used to seeing as as
as top shelf you know when the when the
consumer comes in and they're driving a
Prius and we're in Paragon
and they asked for Sustainable weed and
they're sent to the bottom shelf you
know that retailer just left money on
the table and so that it's starting to
change where we're being active in
changing those perceptions but
Washington in particular has a really
strong biased against sun-grown
absolutely yeah we get one harvest a
year maybe two so we can we can grow the
same canopy we've got 30,000 square feet
as does an indoor farm which can flip
that canopy five plus times so I'm an
indoor farm of the same license size can
grow five to ten times the amount
depending on the strain choice and a lot
of growing methods there's a lot of
other stuff that goes into yield co2
enrichment light intensity so they can
grow much much much more cannabis at an
indoor farm and we have to shoulder all
the same expenses the only the only
place we have the lower costs of
production is with electrical the
lighting the HVAC which is a nice place
to be able to save money but when they
have the economy of scale of having five
to ten times the production they can
kind of absorb that extra cost and put
the craft growers in a really hard
position where we have a lot of the same
expenses we can't sell our weed for as
much because it's outdoor and we can't
grow as much and it's it's it's
surprising to hear probably that we you
know would say that indoor has the scale
and that's because of the of how the LCB
in Washington has regulated canopy it's
by the square foot so they didn't pay
attention at all to the annual cycle or
how many times you could run that square
foot so our square foot of a Sun grower
is not equal to an indoor square fly you
know you can run that indoor square foot
five times so a Tier three indoor is
actually equivalent to five two or three
sun-grown and so that's where that
difference comes and we've we've you
know there's there's an idea in the
industry that the overproduction is
coming from outdoor grown and that
definitely is partially true however
indoor growers are also adding to it and
it really hasn't that impact has not
been assessed correctly by the LCB they
just did a canopy report and came out
and did canopy assessments at all the
farms and they failed to
to account for how many times that
square footage was being used and so all
the things all other things being equal
they want to say well the outdoor
growers have seemed to be growing more
over canopy but really without the
temporal aspect of it clearly the indoor
growers are able under the same amount
of square footage able to produce much
much more yeah and in fact Washington
State was gonna make outdoor growing
completely illegal initially and thanks
to Jeremy here he kind of saved the day
along with a couple other people they
went in and he lobbied and he educated
the politicians and the administrators
and you know was able to make it so that
we can grow outdoors but at the end of
the day we were given a penalty which is
the canopy he was we weren't able to get
a canopy with parody to indoor growing
and so and we were put at a disadvantage
and a liquor board has been quoted as
saying that we made a business decision
to grow outdoors so we can grow less
that's our fault for not choosing to
grow indoors and having to spend five
million dollars to build out a facility
is the unsaid part there as well as
pollute the environment and increase
global warming and do all these other
things that really kill the orcas if
they don't benefit society while we're
in the midst of a environmental global
warming carbon crisis rolled out that is
increasing this problem by our governor
who's running for president who was kind
of asleep at the wheel as as the
cannabis industry sort of you know just
came into being and started consuming
two to four percent of the state's
hydroelectric power you know this is
clean power that is not producing
carbons and should be protected the last
thing we should be doing with our clean
hydroelectric resources is producing a
recreational drug crop when you can
produce it under the Sun and you know
the governor has really not sort of been
sensitive to this issue even though he
claims to be you know a staunch carbon
carbon governor and and one example of
that is recently Washington passed a law
last year that for an organic standard
in in the state and we were both on that
Advisory Committee to the that the
double USDA the Washington Department of
Ag put together and we were adamant
a plant that has never seen the light of
day or put its roots in soil should not
be called organic well some threw some
wonky sort of federal rules governing
USDA and hydroponic rules it's actually
allowed you know we we appealed to the
governor and said hey you know you don't
we're not federally regulated you do not
have to follow the W the USDA organics
lead here you can say no that we are not
going to allow indoor grown cannabis to
be called organic and we failed at that
we didn't get that and that was a real
missed opportunity for a governor that
you know claims to be concerned about
carbon yeah and you're giving the the
consumers real information when they
when they're buying organic they're also
buying sustainable absolutely and I
think one of the failures that have
happened here is that cannabis
legalization is a very typically a
liberal kind of Democrat left-wing issue
and so and it's been grown indoors due
to prohibition and whatnot and so I
think a lot of the policymakers didn't
actually understand that you can grow it
outdoors they saw indoor cultivation as
like the default kind of best way only
way you can do it in fact and they're
people there's a narrative out there
that you can't grow good cannabis
indoors and supporting the narrative
show that is dominated by light
companies HVAC companies led companies
there is there's an industrial complex
that has a vested interest in keeping
very expensive indoor operations or now
that kind of see oh well we have a
problem with you know with how bad
indoor is for the environment well we're
gonna move it to these greenhouses but
we're gonna add more lights and we're
gonna we're gonna add more HVAC and
those we're calling hyper greenhouses
and dr. Ivan Mills who's well known for
assessing environmental impacts of
indoor grows recently put out a white
paper I was about a year ago sort of
assessing that these hyper greenhouses
are really better and I feel like the
excitement of cannabis legalization
among the liberal left and the kind of
Pro cannabis people in general had
they're not so excited that they forgot
to get deep into the environmental
policy about it they just want it legal
so badly and so it let them
they gave a big hand out to corporate
infrastructure companies unintentionally
I think to some extent because we're so
excited to just get cannabis legal and
and the drug war and well and your
company I mean you made the right
decision even though you were based out
of Seattle and kind of lived you know
cuz Seattle is you may know is not a
good place to grow cannabis outdoors so
Jade actually sort of you know a lot of
people looked at that and said oh well
we can't do that we have to go to
indoors we live in Seattle well she was
like no there's Eastern Washington and
so she's got half of her her productions
out in eastern Washington and her
processing is in Seattle which it's kind
of the best of both worlds because
you're close to the market but you're
growing sustainable a lot of people
won't make that decision and I've heard
people say well what were we supposed to
do you know were we supposed to move to
Eastern Washington yes
Central Washington where our farm is
actually 90 miles from Seattle so it's
not even that bad yeah I'm for that he's
four and a half hours but there were
options there are options that are
closer in I think some of the bigger
Tier three companies ran numbers on
production really the 5-time canopy
would be something that they could yeah
and I think a pet peeve of ours is these
when these indoor growers sort of steal
our language and they start claiming
sustainability that becomes a real
problem for us like you know just
because you put up LED lights does not
make your your indoor grow sustainable
and so the you know these people are
taking our language they they're they're
putting in little you know the LED
revolution you know and even even
calling themselves there's some farms
called there's one indoor grown farm
that is sunshine farms you know and then
I saw a tagline that said yeah indoor
Sun grown and it's just like what do you
mean are oh there was one indoor grown
light touched or Sun touched Sun Sun
types that was a good one you know I
actually have more respect for these
indoor companies that you know don't
really take that language from us you
know and and then we've got policies
sort of backing this up where you could
you can be running an indoor grow and
you can go to your your local utility
district and you can get a rebate and
there has been like 200
thousand dollar rebates given to 502
farms in Washington in order for them to
buy their LED lighting which is just
ridiculous like we don't have any funds
available to us and we're already
sustainable like why didn't we given
money to or why not give them money to
not have lighting at all give us light
money because we're not using lights
there's some crazy sort of wonky rolling
out across the country is that the kind
of the infrastructure lobbyists and
stuff are actually getting ahead of it
so even before medical becomes legal in
states there are already people at those
government agencies and lobbying against
saying that in outdoor is a hazard or
outdoor is gonna be dirty pot we can't
keep stairs and they're well ahead of us
and so right now they're in states like
you know in the Midwest and Missouri
Oklahoma everywhere and they are already
crafting policy that is gonna make it
really difficult to grow outdoors
nationwide and when it's really scary
yeah we for a long time we always
thought we needed a little a little
committee like a little I don't know
fired committee or something that would
fly to these different places and be
like hey guys you can crow it out sore
outside and if you don't this is the
carbon footprint you're looking at
because I mean Western Washington is
fortunate to have a lot of carbon free
power as soon as you start going east
it's all carbon or nuclear so you know
it becomes much more important as we
start legalizing to the east that they
grow outdoors but like you said there's
they have lobbyists now they're
protecting their their industry we just
saw plant growth canopies the big
company out of Canada
you know they they've got the massive
massive indoor gross well we saw the CEO
their lobbying the Parliament that maybe
we shouldn't have sun-grown and that was
the worst thing they could possible do
and invoking the children's actually
illegal and is going to be allowed
in 2020 but that's two years after the
rollout of medical legalization so
that's giving the Indore big
infrastructure company that huge head
start and and there yeah and so I've
been talking about Canadian actually
about this so he's gonna start growing
in two years outdoors in Canada but but
they are way behind because they were
not they were not allowed to grow
outdoors and I'm thirty miles from the
water I mean I could take my operation
which you know a sustainable low-cost
high quality product and just move it
right across the border there's any
Canadian sir and the unfortunate part is
the regulators and the policy makers in
the states outside of like the kind of
epicenter on the west coast they're
they're kind of ignorant about how it
grows so they have like quote experts
coming in and telling them it has to be
indoors it's not safe if it's not
indoors it's not clean there's gonna be
security issues and so they're being
lobbied like really early on with you
know typical reefer madness on fear
tactics actually about the kind of
scourge and danger of outdoor cannabis
and and their their driving policy as
this stuff rolls out nationwide and
there's really no one and there's no
organizations in a national level yet to
kind of counter this and so that's
something I would like to do soon Jeremy
is we need to deal with this yeah yeah
yeah we need to try to stay ahead of it
a little bit because we don't want to
see the entire country with 90 percent
indoor cannabis creating a huge carbon
disaster that while you know our world
is drowning and people are dying and and
our children are gonna have a really
shitty place to live in our
grandchildren and you know maybe it's
too late but I like to think we should
still you know try to at least do what
we can to modulate how bad it is we also
have to realize what cannabis has done
to it has created this whole new form of
Agriculture called industrialized indoor
agriculture so well now it took a
high-value crop like marijuana to sort
of advance the science enough that LEDs
are cheap enough and that you can kind
of you know now we can consider sort of
just full indoor agriculture which is
just kills my yeah you know it just it
it's it's yes maybe in some futuristic
world where we can't breathe the air or
we got to go to different planets we
need this technology but farming is is
the way that you sustainably produce
goods
food in this country remain yeah and we
need to try to preserve what we have
like you know I don't think we're at the
point where we just write it all off as
a complete disaster and that let's just
you know fuck like you know we're not at
that point yet and we should never be at
that point there's always hope and we
want to try to have this planet at least
you know go downhill a little bit slower
we want to I keep stuff nice so and the
other thing that sun-grown has done at
least in Washington Washington really
has the most successful legalization in
the country and because the people that
are measure legalization success is not
the business owners it's the tax
collectors and the consumers and the tax
collectors are reaping it in in
Washington and the consumers are loving
it too they've got an you know of course
it's all on the backs of farmers let's
not let's not forget who's actually
bearing the cost it's not the retailer's
it's even not even the processors it's
the producers that are that are the ones
and we've seen this story over and over
and over right this is how agriculture
is gone in America is that the farmers
get screwed so we're kind of we're what
we think it was gonna be any different
but sun-grown
really is what made Washington such a
successful experiment and legalization
because you come to eat you go to
Colorado you're gonna pay more and
you're gonna have less quality you're
gonna have less choices and they're
collecting less taxes you go to
Washington you're gonna pay less even
though there's more taxes collected
you're gonna have more choices and the
quality's gonna be higher so you know
you can thank your son growers for that
the question is what's sort of peaking
our interest in the production side of
of cannabis and you know I've actually
sort of taken it the other way I'm
buying less products than I ever have I
am doing less sort of compost teas or or
or anything and and it's really because
I've fully adopted living soils and and
understanding what living soils are you
don't buy living soils you don't
purchase products that get you living
soils it's really a long term
to building up your soil health and
after five years you know I'm finally
realizing that benefit and so I'm buying
very very little nutrients you know
there's two ways to look at nutrients
one is as a streamflow right and
hydroponics are exactly that right the
nutrients go by the roots and when
they're done
they go down the drain and then if you
gotta bite be treated before phosphates
or nitrates whereas my view of nutrients
are the more sustainable view of
nutrients is it's a bucket and you fill
the bucket and then as you grow you know
you pull just a little bit out of that
bucket as you harvest and you just need
to tap that bucket off a little bit you
know and so that's kind of how I how I
think about it and so it's really just
my thinking that's changed and and it
reminds me back at their guerrilla days
of growing in the hills you know because
that was the Korean natural farming we
just didn't have the words for it you
know we used to go out into the woods
and we kind of carry fertilizers they
were too heavy and so we would go out
there and we'd oh there's some deciduous
trees you know we'd go grab the
deciduous soil and then we'd grab the
Duff under the pines and then we would
you know get them all together and that
that's really kind of what's got me
excited and really just not having to do
anything to your soil and still
producing high-quality product is yeah
and I I'm right there with you Jeremy
I'm like just reducing inputs like your
year after year and the same thing our
first few years we bought a lot of stuff
and every year we buy less and less soil
gets better and better and that's like
that's a really and the nutrient
deficiencies exactly and trying to juice
and trying to figure out ways to also to
streamline via like reduction in
nutrients and also you know utilizing
kind of conventional agricultural
techniques like you know vineyard
trellising so that's something we have
been geeking out on the last two years
is for some reason cannabis trellising
has always been this like huge truckin
project like you know they'd use like
like fence like metal fencing and like
you know that plastic net ena so just
know it's disposable every year you have
to throw out a bunch of platen asti
plastic netting where does that end up
probably in the ocean some of its
getting swallowed by whales I mean so
we've been eliminating plastics from our
operation and the form of ground cover
we have moved to all you know basically
cover crop
weed so we have a blend of cover crop
and natural weeds and you know whereas
we used to be much more concerned about
the weeds we've realized actually the
weeds are not causing any problem
they're helping us retain water and
they're providing a habitat for
beneficial insects and they're keeping
the dust down and like so we've stopped
stressing out about weeds oh we we do
fetch clover and then we do some
beneficial insect attracting plants like
yarrow Colangelo some radish family type
plants cilantro parsley so we put a
bunch of that out kind of around our
parameters to kind of provide habitat
for beneficial x' on our Isles we do a
mixture of we seed with vaatrik and
clover and then the natural weeds are
very vigorous and we can't really stop
them and we've given up crying and it
causes no problems and so we've saved a
lot of labor and energy like fighting
weeds and that's something where a lot
of new farmers they think weeds are the
enemy and we've got to fight the weeds
you got to weed it you got to hold them
up and it is such a waste of effort cuz
we were there we tried that and all it
was was labor and back-breaking horrible
you know sweaty well anywhere that grew
back two weeks later I better was set up
by rule you know but then we were
talking earlier about how there's
constantly rules that seem to be
advantageous for indoor growers and
disadvantageous for outdoor growers and
one of them was yeast in molds yeast and
molds is the most arbitrary measure of
that you could possibly apply it means
nothing you know in fact we know that a
lot of these yeasts and molds are very
beneficial and so in the early days I
was so concerned about yeast and mold
that I we buried my entire farm and I'm
glad I did I think I've totally reduced
my amounts of fails for for use in molds
we eventually got that that requirement
for testing removed thank goodness
there's still some states out there
doing it totally dumb you should stop
now we replaced it with with testing for
mycotoxins which actually kill people
can actually hurt people I mean before
under the old rules you could pass a
yeast and mold test and you could be
full of acidulous and actually be
harmful so now you know that was a huge
win for the Sun growers another rule
that was really disadvantageous to us
was the requirement for the harvest date
on the packaging and you know
didn't understand that curing and all
that and so they would just call it old
and then the retailers you know they
would use that date to see be like oh
it's been six months we want a 20%
decrease in your cosmic well actually
it's cured longer and it's more
expensive yeah
and so but back to the cover cropping
I'm totally geeking out on that for the
first time too because my new farm you
know that I don't that I'm building now
I I don't have those same concerns
anymore now that the yeast and mold
requirement is gone so I'm adopting much
more of the practices that Jade has and
totally geeking out on like what you
know crimson are not crimson but a white
clover and annual ryegrass and that's
you know hopefully to knock out some of
the perennial grasses and and compete
with the weeds so I'm really excited
about that I'm getting a roller for my
tractor so I can roll them in and yeah
and start to start to put that nitrogen
fixing stuff in there just don't pay for
stuff yeah I stuff in plastic bags don't
generate waste and your farming you
really don't need to at the end of the
day it's a plant and it's a very special
plant but as far as growing it and stuff
it's not that special and there been
farmers growing all kinds of crops for
thousands of years and humans know how
to farm and so just applying like you
know ancient you know you knowledge and
farming knowledge that we've been
gathering for thousands of years to
cannabis is a perfectly reasonable and
preferable approach everyone wants to
reinvent the wheel of cannabis and it's
just it's already we can do this we know
how to grow plants humans are excellent
at it so we just need to you know use
our existing knowledge and and just get
better that way we're ground growers
we're in the ground we're big believers
of being in the ground you know the
smart pots I call them dumb pots I mean
they're they're so dumb I mean you got
two hundred gallon yeah I know they're
around here somewhere you know you got a
two hundred gallon pot you can't you
can't move
you got a fabric a case that's Denari
elastics
you know you don't yeah you don't
totally know what it's what's my about a
Grampa
and they're just silly and they dry out
you know right especially when you're in
the desert and whatnot just doesn't work
every farm is different we are blessed
with sandy loam soils so we can tractor
til it we can plant you know we got good
drainage there are situations where you
might have poor drainage the soil is
rocky clay where I'm remediating that
soil and getting it to a point where you
get drainage would be ridiculously
expensive so bringing in soil and doing
raised beds is a very reasonable
approach in some situations and that's
what we did and that's what yeah you
have to assess your individual soil type
and location and make the decision we've
done that we followed Phil we did Phil
and drill because you know the cost of
just basically bringing in 12 inches of
soil is extreme and often with negative
environmental impacts so our approach
was to drill a hole in the ground and
fill it up with soil and of course you
know we don't use Fagin on peat moss
that's a unsustainable non-renewable
product that is widely used in this
industry we have a peat bog within 30
miles of the farm that's hip numpy which
is actually a much better peat in my
mind as far as holding water and whatnot
and that is deliver mixed up by a local
guy and then delivered in a 60 yard
truck so you know we don't grow in the
native soil at all in fact I I'm very
careful to keep the native soil even
from even from coming into my holes it's
just it's this it's this silt that if it
gets on the top of a hole it'll create
an impermeable layer and the oxygen
can't get through so you're lucky to
have good soil we've it's probably been
one of our biggest cost but it was a
one-time cost you know you we brought
the soil in one time and now we're in
our we're going in our sixth year of no
tail living soil yes yeah so Tarara can
only go so far you know like in you
gotta have good soil for grapes like bad
soil seems to be a thing yeah you know
but for marijuana no it ya likes good
soil and you've got to have good soil so
you
it gets difficult to talk about tirar
and particularly if you're an indoor
grower
don't talk about tirar just leave that
alone that's our language
you've got drywall terroir indoors
Chinese drywall but it's the surrounding
structures in the environment so yeah
welcome 156 percent humidity and 72
degrees do for you 24 hours a day you
know I mean here's the thing with indoor
gross right there they're the they're
the definition of monoculture
environments I mean they are such a
controlled environment that that plant
is not expressing itself I mean the
terpenes are a response to the
environment and if your environment is
always 72 degrees and 56 percent
humidity you're not good you're not
getting a response out of that we're not
gonna get a higher quality product at
Bastyr I studied herbal medicine and so
one of my teachers who I see as one of
my mentors he's one of the most
brilliant minds in herbal medicine he
taught us in this class called farm acog
nnessee he said the best herbal
medicines come from plants that are
slightly nutrient deprived slightly
water deprived have weeds when there's
insects around and insect pressure and
those plants you're gonna get the
highest production of secondary plant
compounds which are what cannabinoids
and terpenoids are they are plant
defense mechanisms and so by having
those stressors you're gonna get a
higher quality medicine and cannabis is
a medicine and those compounds that
we're all looking for terpenes and
cannabinoids those are those compounds
that you need those stressors to
maximize those items and that was
something that he taught us not he
didn't even teach about cannabis at all
but that applies obviously to cannabis
and and we need to get that narrative
out there oh yeah and and you know I've
got some old-timers that have been
around weed forever and they're like oh
that indoor weed just doesn't do it for
me and and there's reason that it's not
doing them for forum and you know that I
have one guy who's like just doesn't
have legs you know and it doesn't
because the Cameron oi profile is very
narrow
you know indoor growers are harvesting
early because they want to they want it
they got a big power bail and they don't
want to keep on going so they're not
allowing the cannabinoid profile to
widen out with the CBN CBG CBC's
everything else that that really adds to
that
a fact and if and if all you're doing is
is growing short flowering time early
harvest then you're gonna end up with a
very narrow terpene profile and a very
narrow camera knowing profile and that's
why the old-timers there's some truth to
what they're saying you've got to go
back and you got to hit that bonk ten
minutes after you eat it and it's just
they don't doesn't have legs it doesn't
stick with you because it doesn't have
all of those camera noids interacting
themselves in the entourage effect and
making that long-lasting effect but it
looks pretty right it looks in the joint
you see it that's what's driving these
these bud tenders to sort of you know
have this undue preference for indoor
grown is that they they look at it and
I've tried to explain to them it's like
look you're not looking at it you're
gonna smoke it you know and and and I
call it loud weed I've been calling
indoor weed loud weed for you know ten
years and it's not a compliment and you
know loud weed is it
it looks bright green because they was
pumped full of ammonium nitrates because
they wanted the yield you know and then
they had to use a cleaner too like those
nitrates so it doesn't you know end up
being a black ash at the end it's it's
white and try Co me because it's like
like crystal try because it wasn't
allowed to mature so a lot of those
trichome structures get really jacked up
and so it's not that there's actually
more cannabinoid in there but the
surrounding cuticles on it cry trichomes
are larger and so it looks more
crystalline it's not more cannabinoid
it's just more kind of the surrounding
structure of that try crow trichome
filling in from extra carbon dioxide and
nutrients and also not allowed to turn
milky or even not allowed to turn
reddish which is an indication that your
gut your CBN's and that you're actually
getting to a mature plant you know so
there's all of these forces that that
kind of contribute to this loud weed the
other thing is that you know you open it
up and it kind of overwhelms you in the
initial or odor well that's when your
volatize entertain like that that means
you didn't cure
at all and and and that's not gonna be
good either because you're gonna end up
the taste is gonna have this fresh e
greenish taste because it wasn't allowed
to mellow some of those compounds out so
that's what loud weed is bright green
smells amazing and doesn't get you high
as like got like sun-grown does
[Music]