because becoming big we're really
starting to talk about our waterways and
and and the way that we're what water
runoff is happening now if it's a crop
that can save the earth what's what's
going on and and how can we save our
waterways specifically Layton how what's
a big solution in this talking about is
very simple to do on a large scale it's
that crop residue I wanted to talk about
water harvesting I know you guys all
know about a sister and connected to
your gutters right it's easy to collect
water when it's raining but how do you
get water on a large scale when it's the
middle of summer it's not that
complicated
driving in here I saw a few up upland
bogs okay so it's just basically a pit
where there's a bunch of moisture that's
collected and so instead of connecting
your gutter from the cistern and then
dumping it will create a bog and what
that bog does is it holds water long
term what's in the well you can go Hugo
put in log sticks chips and that will
hold the water long-term and prevent it
from migrating the key to water
harvesting is slowing it down we all
know what erosion is an erosion has to
be avoided it's strictly in the organic
matter its stripping the soil that
you're you're trying to hold on to so if
you can slow water down you can prevent
erosion you all know what's whales are
what's a BIOS well fill it with logs
fill it with chips cover it with dirt
and plant it now that's gonna hold water
long term it's not going to evaporate
the roots from the plants on top will
prevent that hundred year storm from
washing it away which is again erosion
we've got to prevent that so that when
you're looking at water movement across
your soils those roots are critical
let's go a little deeper cover crops
love them what do they do well they
build tilth they help put or gain
matter back into the soil they put
carbon which feeds the microbiome the
biology so all of these wonderful things
are happening and guess what that water
can now infiltrate instead of just
running across the top because of that
never having soil bear always having
roots to hold it together and to
continuously build organic matter which
guess what stores moisture so let's take
it a little deeper groundwater we all
know what groundwater is in the old days
we all dig what we all dug wells and
those wells we use to feed our animals
or water our animals and sometimes for
our own drinking water what does the
well do well it actually gives the water
a place to go so it does two things it
allows you to see how well you're doing
no pun intended as far as building
groundwater up around your property and
during the summer you'll see that there
actually is water there where's it
coming from your bio swales the upland
bogs which are slowly releasing that
water back into the ground another thing
it does is if you pull water out of
there it helps to wick the water back
into that well so it's an emergency
situation you've got a drought going on
and you need to water your plants the
more you pull out of there the more
it'll come in so you're really giving
yourself a lot of options to allowing
yourself to harvest water slowly from
the soil in order to water whatever you
need and this can be done a large scale
or small scale do I love ponds I do I
hate the restrictions the reason I'm
even talking about this is because of
Wendy two years ago she told me what the
state of California did to her in trying
to get a pond in and I was horrified to
hear that she's not allowed to have fish
in him she has to have a bowl fraud
mitigation plan
no both frogs in the pond or we're going
to come and pump it out this is insane
how do you stop nature well who are
these people that are deciding that they
should control nature so instead of
building a pond for all that expense get
smart build bogs build swamp build
swales again bioswales and and store
that water slow
down so that in the summer you have it
when you need it