[Music]
uh this is city council direction to
staff on regulating the sale
manufacturing cultivation transport
Taxation and Licensing all in one night
of the adult use of non-medical
marijuana in the city of West Hollywood
we have staff with us to give a report
thank you mayor council members my name
is John assistant director devel tonight
we bring to you the topic of adult use
marijuana also called non-medical
marijuana as we all know personal use of
marijuana will become legal in January
along with personal use comes a lot of
um decisions that local jurisdiction to
make regarding um land use regulations
of
marijuana a planning staff along with
the city attorney's office Code
Compliance and finance have been
reviewing state law and attending
various seminars on this topic tonight's
staff report is not asking the council
to adopt an ordinance um or to make any
specific decisions instead it's to
provide the city council information and
to ask the council for direction on how
the council would like us to respond to
the the new world that's coming towards
us in January so um with that I'd like
to introduce Jerry hman um a contract
planner that is working on this item for
us and he will provide the presentation
thank you honorable mayor and council
members as you know the um proposition
64 was approved last November and it
legalizes non-med use of marijuana by
persons 20 years 21 years of
age and uh allows people to cultivate up
to six plants it creates a state
Regulatory and Licensing system that is
in the works right now and it allows
local government s to prohibit or
regulate
license commercial retail sales and uh
actually encourages them to do that
prior to January 1st 2018 when the state
will start issuing
licenses this is a um comparison chart
showing medical versus non-medical
marijuana
regulation under taxation as you know
you can um have license fees but in
order to do a sales tax you would have
to have a ballot initiative and the
earliest to could do that is in
2019 uh it allows local regulation to
prohibit or regulate non-medical
marijuana and then personal cultivation
is
allowed and um that can be done indoors
but uh outdoor regulation can be
prohibited you can also regulate the uh
indoor cultivation by commercial Growers
and the outdoor cultivation as
well on personal use people 21 years or
older can use marijuana you can uh
possess up to 28.5 grams that's about a
baggie of loose marijuana or 8 grams of
concentrated such as a food product and
of course you can May smoke or inest
marijuana or marijuana products now
there are some personal use restrictions
there's no smoking in a public place
there's no smoking where tobacco is
prohibited uh within 1,000 ft of a
school when driving uh or riding a
vehicle and cities May prohibit uh
smoking in city-owned buildings and
employers may also maintain a drug free
workplace again uh cities May regulate
or reasonably regulate the indoor
cultivation of up to six plants you can
do it on a greenhouse or other
structures and local governments May
regulate or prohibit outdoor
cultivation what are reasonable
reasonable regulations you can require a
cultivation permit that requires uh the
city the the permit holder to allow the
city to come in and inspect to make sure
you have a six plant limit uh you're not
drawing from the electrical power grip
uh or presenting a health hazard or
using more water than is reasonable also
you can enforce the building and fire
codes um cities May regulate or prohibit
marijuana but you cannot prohibit the
transport on public roads so if someone
wanted to transport marijuana through
the city on a public road have to you
have to allow that uh the state
standards are minimum standards the city
can regulate much stricter than the
state
can now under a commercial operations
also the city
uh does not is not required to enact a
regulatory scream however again the
state will begin issuing licenses in on
January 1st
2018 and the city can place prohibitions
on uh and
regulate commercial marij
now there are again as John mentioned uh
we want you to look at some local policy
issues about what the city how the city
wants to regulate or prohibit certain
parts of this marijuana
proposition and uh the first one is do
you want to enact regulations for
non-medical marijuana
businesses also do you want to require
retails retailers to um enforce
eligibility of medical marijuana
cards which would enforce a sales tax
exemption and also do you want to impose
local taxes on
marijuana also uh moving on should the
city allow existing medical marijuana
collectives to also sell non-medical
marijuana that would limit it to the
sell the four existing collectives that
are already in West Hollywood Al and
next two bullet points just talk about
do you want to reeval evaluate the
licensing requirements for dispensing of
medical and non-medical
marijuana then moving on should the city
limit the number or location of
marijuana retail
stores and then getting to the taxation
issue again should the city tie approval
of any retail sales of marijuana to the
passage of a related sales tax bot
initiative which could the earliest you
can do that is 2019 so have to wait till
that
time uh also prohibit smoking or use of
marijuana can P public property again
prohibit The Possession and smoking of
marijuana in any public place do you
want to allow the manufacture extraction
testing or processing of marijuana
plants or products and also warehousing
is another thing to consider should that
beow out or
regulated then again uh should the city
impose uh
indoor uh cultivation regulations that
are reasonable and to the city allow
outdoor
cultivation now the next steps towards
non-medical marijuana regulation we
propose uh holding a series of community
meetings this month and next month
coming back to the council for further
Direction
in late summer of this year in the fall
we'd go to the Planning Commission and
review a draft marijana ordinance and
then bring that ordinance to the city
council for approval in the fall or
winter and uh thank you and we're open
for questions
on regulating
marijuana thank you mayor I just I just
want to ask a question of Staff before
we get to speakers when we're talking
about regulating uh marijuana in this
area does it have to be tied to the land
does it have to be a land use issue or
can we tie it to a business license and
make it a business licensing issue
instead of a land use issue or can we do
both or can they preclude one
another I think typically it would
probably be both that's how we did um
medical marijuana there's a planning
it's allowed in the planning in the
zoning ordinance but then it's really
regulated through the business license
permit because the reason I ask is there
may be some operators that we want to
continue to work with and others who may
be a disaster for us that we don't want
to continue to be in business with them
so all right thank
you
okay how how leis Jackie subac followed
by Wesley Bridal First my name is Hal
Lewis I am extremely excited um as you
know I did have a business here at one
time uh called Alice's Care Center which
helped uh patients
um get through their times of need um I
own a Manufacturing Company who deals
with topicals only we're not trying to
get people high we're trying to get
people better through topicals tinctures
and
suppositories uh so I am excited to be
able to come back to West Hollywood now
let me get this up because I have a
statement um from Jackie subc and a lot
of things have changed one of the things
I'd like to ask is if we could change
the name from marijuana to cannabis
which The BMC uh BCR did because
marijuana is a derogatory basically
Comon it has it's a slang word for
cannabis okay good evening mayor this is
from Jackie subc good evening mayor and
council members I am sorry that I'm
unable to attend this session tonight I
am certain that you all know how very
important this topic is to me and that
if I could be here I absolutely would
but unfortunately that is not the case
this evening and in the meantime I
prepared this statement in the interest
of creating Fair Equitable and inclusive
cannabis policy for West Hollywood
Community I'd like to reference two
major things that just happened in the
state one the governor recently proposed
a trailer bill as part of the state
budget to serve as reconciliation
between medical and adult use regulation
and two the state agencies responsible
for cannabis including the Bureau of
marijuana control and cannabis control
issued the first draft of the
regulations this past Friday
unfortunately these two sets of proposed
regulations do not line up the way we
believe they should be so it's going to
take a little time to get this all
sorted out I'd like to make note that
some of the information contained in
your staff reports has already changed
and will likely change again after the
45-day public comment period is complete
one simple example of this is the
question of should the city allow
medical and adult use cannabis to be
sold in the same place depending on how
this all goes down at the state that may
not be allowed anymore I believe thank
thank you
Hal Wesley Bridal okay can he finish
statement excuse me how can you finish
that statement yes thank you I I I
appreciate it I'm sorry I'm not that
fast
um okay not be able to be sold in the
state yeah not to be able to so sold in
the state I believe it is really
important at this juncture to not limit
the amount of licenses in any category
especially for dispensaries although I
urge you to continue this conversation I
also encourage you to hold off on making
any financial decisions because at this
point many of these proposed regulations
could still change as it relates to
State Licensing and could have a direct
impact on the existing cannabis
businesses already established in the
city finally I just want to impress one
other point upon you that involves
public consumption we all realize that
this is a safety issue and one that
really affects law enforcement Food For
Thought rather than ban it and force
people out on the streets to legally
consume which is exactly what will
happen issue on-site consumption
licenses to any and all retail
establishments in the city that
requested as long as they are compliant
with the city and state laws there
should be no problem and it will
immediately alleviate any public safety
concerns thank you so much for your time
I look forward to continuing this
dialogue with you sincerely Jackie zuc
thank you thank you H Wesley Bridal to
be followed by Aaron
Burke Wesley a bridal uh West Hollywood
speaking as a private citizen thank you
mayor and uh Council members and thank
you City staff uh people say West
Hollywood is an lbgt City and I agree
the city is supportive and
representative of the lbgt community but
I would take it a step further and say
that West
Hollywood uh is a city activists our
city has activists in every shape shade
and gender
identity uh we have a big tent of
advocation that includes cannabis
activists it has been said that West
Hollywood is a creative City but when I
look look at the staff report I don't
see our Hallmark creativity I see more
of the same Alma has uh provided for the
adult use of cannabis and has given us
the opportunity opportunity to show our
fellow Californians how a city at the
Forefront can be a welcoming to a
burgeoning news sector of our
economy uh yet the staff report doesn't
mention any of the new businesses that
are allowed under prop 64 it speaks
nothing of on-site use locations like
coffee shops in Amsterdam nor does it
talk of other cannabis businesses who
operate in upscale Health and Beauty
sectors new economies need new ways of
thinking and to change our Norms here in
our city we have sex shops and loud and
proud bars that might be shut down if
they had to operate under the same
legislation that we subject our cannabis
disp to not to mention that our local
laws have left us with a list of people
who want to open cannabis dispensaries
30 plus long While others mysteriously
transfer ownership and
management uh only one of the four
dispensaries still operates under the
original owner now I don't want West
Hollywood to go to pot I don't Envision
a radically different West Hollywood I
Envision the same city that we know and
love where we take a stand against
oppression and imp Implement Creative
Solutions to build towards a more
inclusive Society so in a time when 45
appointed attorney general Jeff's
sessions says good people don't smoke
marijuana it is my hope that West
Hollywood is a town that says we welcome
the Cannabis cult culture and our town
will continue to be a tourist
destination location for all oppressed
people thank you for your time and
consideration thank you Wesley Aaron
Burke to be followed by Amanda Hyde
thanks to the city council for for
considering this issue uh my name is Aon
Burke I'm with monk provisions and uh
half of our team lives here in West
Hollywood um we hope that the city
eventually adopts a rigorous application
process for folks that are hoping to get
uh a license uh we're local but we've
worked in a number of states uh worked
with Regulators in Arizona and Illinois
and Massachusetts and seeing how it's
gone down in a lot of these different
jurisdictions uh the more involved
legislators are the better The Operators
end up being a number of states have
tried to uh some places have gone with
the lottery system and not tried to uh
do a qualitative review and it's just
ended up uh um leading to subpar
operators and and and um uh the types of
dispensaries that that that are less
desirable that that we've all seen um
let's H would have supported some of the
medical dispensaries here in town uh
it's led to some of them being the the
the the leaders in the State uh without
local support dispensaries have a hard
time operating the way they could and
the way they should now that prop 64 is
passed um and the industry has
widespread support the city of West
Hollywood has an opportunity to raise
the bar and to remain a leader um and uh
to continue to inspire cities and folks
like the Icelandic folks that were
mentioned earlier that are so excited
about West Hollywood and I think that uh
you know there are a number of us that
look forward to making you very proud so
thank you thank you Aaron Amanda hi to
be followed by cat
Packer hello Council I've lost my voice
so you will have to excuse how Kathleen
Turner I
sound um we have been a leader in the
Cannabis world and so we've set a tone
for that world and people look to us for
our policies
and we are in a rare position of having
the infrastructure the means and the
social programs to um curate and create
the Cannabis experience that we want
whereas in other cities where they don't
have the means and the money they're
going to take in everything because they
want that money coming in um to do
things like Phill pot holes and such so
we're in this rare opportunity where we
aren't beholden to like
the same thing as they are um and so I
think rather than taking a pause and
watching what everyone else does we need
to be creative as like we like to say
all the time and actually be leaders
rather than followers um also I think
the current I think leaving things the
same is not creative at all I'm
personally not happy what things are
who's to say that the things the
businesses that we have right now are
the best of the best if it was an open
market that was inclusive would those
businesses last because I know that West
Hollywood's business experience you kind
of have to be the best of the best in
any form of business in order to survive
here we really curate original unique
amazing experiences as businesses and I
don't understand why we wouldn't do that
the same when it comes to this as a
business and we wouldn't take in that
taxation so that we could keep on having
the social services that we have I just
see it as a um missed opportunity I
think we really need to reach out into
our community because I think we have a
very amazing um demographic of people
that are successful in business and
successful in ways and we should really
I like that we're going to have
Community meetings but we really need to
make sure that the community knows
they're going to be happening because I
go to all this and I have a hard time
finding out what's happening but thank
you so much thank you Amanda cat Packer
to be followed by William mcney hello
again to city council my name is cat
Packer and I'm a policy coordinator with
an organization called the drug policy
Alliance uh through my work with the
drug policy Alliance I've been focused
uh very heavily on the implementation of
the adult use of marijuana act in its
reconciliation with the medical cannabis
and Regulation and safety act uh as how
Lewis had already said um just this past
Friday the Bureau of medical cannabis
regulation released uh its draft
regulations and a few weeks prior uh the
governor released his trailer Bill all
of that to say that there's a lot moving
around the state in terms of cannabis
policy and a lot is changing uh I've
been participating uh very heavily
Statewide and in particularly uh in Los
Angeles County and the city to have
conversations about how to make cannabis
policy uh more inclusive and more
Equitable and the reason why this is uh
particularly important uh and especially
here in California is that uh having a
cannabis license can be the very
difference between uh profit and a crime
and here in the state of California
low-income communities and uh
communities of color have been
specifically targeted
uh I don't necessarily know what the
demographics and arrest uh statistics
look like uh for the city of West
Hollywood but if they Trend uh similar
to the rest of California let me get
just give you one statistic uh in 2015
black people were two times more likely
to be arrested for a marijuana
misdemeanor and two times more likely to
be or and five times more likely to be
arrested for uh a marijuana felony and
this was in 2015 where we know that
folks could have just paid $40 and walk
into uh some place on on Venice Beach
and so as we're talking about uh jobs
and creating economic opportunities I
want to make sure that we are thinking
and being inclusive of those communities
that have been criminalized for the
exact same plant thank you thank you Cat
William mcney to be followed by Michael
boich good evening my name is William
mcney Bill um well good evening Council
and staff um I'm here to support uh the
fact of having having
recreational and have uh medical
marijuana uh I agree with a lot of the
uh State suggestions that I heard about
last Monday um saying that uh they he
the governor prefers that the uh medical
and recreational be sold at different
not on the same location or the same
space um I agree with that um I think
this would I reiterate what other people
said this is a creative City I know you
come up with a creative solution you did
with medical marijuana you were a leader
I see no reason why you're not going to
be in this instance also and I hope you
do so thank you very much thank you
Michael vich will be our last speaker
council members of the public good
evening again Michael
voage so another very easy breezy staff
report that centers on a complex topic
on a burgeoning industry that stamps
from a very potent
drug West
Hollywood has the greatest proportion of
people within the
county versus other
cities who receive housing assistance
with Federal
money and as anyone should know but most
people don't because staff chooses to
over look this the use of marijuana
medical or otherwise is
prohibited so you're talking prohibition
from residents who are either Section 8
Project based Section 8 anyone receiving
hwa funds in this
city doesn't take
responsibility to acknowledge this fact
and to say what is going to happen
should that person choose to believe
in proposition
64 and not be advised on what they're
willing to
risk it's always interesting to
hear the benefits of Taxation that will
come towards Social Services when in
many ways Social Services
is adversely affected by marijuana it
has an ill effect on those with mental
illness especially those who are
homeless so I just ask you to think
about this in some deeper terms and to
have the wherewithal and the
responsibility to advise your residents
what their rights are and are not thank
you thank you Michael
council member
Duran thank you mayor I have some more
follow-up questions now maybe for staff
and staff doesn't know maybe some of the
people in the audience May uh the far
roacher Amendment to the federal budget
would have prohibited uh the DEA uh from
using any funds to go after medicinal
marijuana and those states that have
medicinal marijuana was the far roacher
Amendment included in the budget that
the Congress just passed this week does
anybody
no we don't know anybody out there that
from drug policy Alliance know did
farbacher make it don't know okay all
right
so all right so the the reason I I ask
is uh because that's a question we're
going to have to deal with as we
continue to uh try to regulate in this
area this is actually a topic I know a
lot about it's ironic I know because I'm
sober and don't use alcohol or drugs but
I actually know a lot about uh this
particular issue because of the history
of the AIDS epidemic and the role that
medicinal marijuana played when we used
to have to uh argue in court of medical
necessity uh long before there was a
proposition 215 and long before there
was a proposition 64 I think that um the
biggest concern I have is the continuing
conflict between federal and state law
that's going to continue to exist and
how we attempt to navigate and regulate
in an area with um uh a federal attorney
general and government that could
potentially be hostile uh to the states
or localities on this issue I mean we we
know what happened when we the city
helped the Reverend Scott imler buy a
building here in the city of West
Hollywood for the Los Angeles cannabis
Resource Center back in
1996 and in the year 2001 the Bush
Administration seized that building the
city uh actually we were we forfeited
the building was taken under the drug
forfeiture laws from the city of West is
the one and only time that the United
States actually took an asset from your
municipality citing drug forfeiture laws
so what I know to be true is when the
federal government wants to play mean
and nasty they they will play mean and
nasty in this area um to me I I I think
the idea about Community meetings I I
don't think I support that and here's
the reason why I think it's always great
to get public opinion and public input
and there should be a place for that but
I think in the upcoming months we should
get some teams of experts rather than
just Community input uh people will have
a lot of opinions uh uh about this
particular issue what they won't have is
a lot of expertise and I think what's
going to be more helpful to us is to
have expertise on the issue of you know
what governor Brown uh is doing up in
Sacramento I heard Mr mcne say Governor
Brown is recommending that the medicinal
non-medicinal be in separate places I
thought I read in the LA Times the
governor wanted them merged together
that's correct right yeah the governor
actually wants them merge together uh
medicinal and non-medicinal in the same
place uh I think it's best we have some
expertise on that we're still going to
run a foul of the the banking issues
that exist that uh people who are
involved in uh marijuana whether it's
medicinal or adult use they still going
to have problems with banking systems
that will not allow them to bank because
it's a violation of federal law Mr V
levage brought up an issue that does
actually exist and at some point we will
have to educate uh our residents about
the fact that if you're caught smoking a
joint in federal HUD property you will
be evicted uh notwithstanding
proposition 64 or the uh easing of the
laws on U marijuana use in the state of
California because it's federally funded
building those are smaller issues I
think we we um the issue of cultivation
I think is problematic in West Hollywood
because we don't have a lot of uh real
estate we don't have a lot of G we're
too dense for cultivation I think trying
to get into the issue of regulating
cultivation in people's homes or
backyards is beyond the uh enforcement
resources that we have and we should
probably not not do that but I think
that we probably should prohibit
cultivation in the city because I don't
think we have enough geography or real
estate for that to happen we've also
received Communications from Edison that
they're not sure they'd be able to
supply the power uh that would be
necessary to to do that so I think
ultimately we're going to be involved in
the distribution issue I also want to
understand from the experts if
proposition 64 on the issue of
transportation and distribution delivery
services means that the health and
safety code sections that have to do
with transportation of controlled
substances are no longer going to be
enforced in the state courts
traditionally you cannot transport uh
Controlled Substances um and I just want
to make sure that whatever we're doing
here that we're not running a foul of
the criminal stat statutes on
transportation and distribution uh for
control
substances uh the uh the issue around
taxation I think the people of the city
of West Hollywood have voted repeatedly
to tax themselves on everything from
homelessness to Transit and I imagine
that there will be strong support in
fact we know from a recent Community
survey there's strong support for
taxation of marijuana in the city of
West Hollywood so I think we should move
forward at some point of getting that on
the 2019 ballot uh I just want to
understand then uh how we're going to
possibly uh get into the regulation
business before we tax them and making
sure that if we're going to then move
forward to taxation that we do it in a
way that's timely uh I'm open to the
suggestion of expanding beyond the four
existing uh uh collectives that exist I
don't know the number I don't know how
many uh I'm a little concerned about the
merger of medicinal marijuana with adult
use for the reason that I think the the
Trump Administration has given early
signals that they're going to leave
medicinal marijuana alone but they're
not as clear about adult use and um I
actually think the medical marijuana
collectives in the city would be have
far greater protection in their current
role as uh medicinal uh Distributors and
if we allow them to then expand into
adult use did we place them at risk uh a
federal prosecution uh should we be uh
making them aware of the risks that are
involved let them decided what risk
they're willing to take so I think that
you know
ultimately opinions uh from the
community are great but I think I need
we need some expertise to help guide us
through some of these policy decisions
uh on the issues of the conflict between
state federal and local regulation uh
how we are going to regulate uh through
Planning Commission or Business License
Commission or both uh in terms of uh the
operation whether we expand beyond the
four uh I'm open to it uh and I'm I just
don't know what the number is uh and how
we would go about doing that I I do I
know that staff told me at one point
they were keeping a list of people who
are interested in doing this I I don't
think it should be a random draw and I
don't think it should be a who's ever
next on the list draw I think that we
should have some sort of process
involved that we can check the capital
that exists behind any of these
potential operations their level of
expertise uh on these uh these
particular issues uh uh background
checks I I'd rather have a little bit
more of a thorough vetting uh if we were
going to expand uh rather than just
going who's next in order or a random
draw through a lotto uh and how we do
that in a way that's fair and Equitable
when obviously there are a lot of people
who would like to get into this very
lucrative business potentially um that's
the what's got me scratching my head I
don't have the answer to that but I
think that's something we can look at as
we uh as we move forward on these issues
so I know we want to try to get this in
by the end of the year and we've
probably got a couple of stops the
Planning Commission and the Business
License Commission before it comes back
here but I think in the short term um
getting the right experts at a a meeting
a public meeting where the public can
provide their opinions is going to be
more important to me than just meeting
with the community thank
you mayor Pro 10 oh council member Deo
thank you mayor um I uh I really want to
thank everyone who uh number one took
the time to uh stay with us through the
previous part of this meeting to speak
now and um uh I continue to learn and
know there's a lot more learning to do
and so this kind of information delivery
which is pretty direct is very much
appreciated and certainly uh all of you
are welcome to contact my office
directly I'm meet with you uh sit down
and discuss at length as I have with
several different sets of people already
um and I'm willing to and want to talk
with all of you as well because I think
um uh the recurring theme that I agree
with the most um and it's really a sort
of three-part theme one is that uh we
have to we have an opportunity to do
this in a really extraordinary way and
um the
four uh dispensaries that we have I
don't think are ready to sort of operate
uh in prime time yet I think they serve
the medical use Community quite well uh
exquisitly in fact um but I think uh I
can imagine a $400 a night tourist on
the Sunset Strip uh having a certain
experience and uh someone shopping on
Melrose having a different experience um
someone on the east side uh having yet a
third experience and none of those
experiences are captured by our current
series and
um maybe that's three of uh uh three of
three experiences or maybe that's three
of 25 experiences but I think the market
um will give us some hints uh pretty
quickly and uh so I'm I'm interested in
in that I I
uh I'm also interested in figuring out
how we can coordinate this effort with a
tax uh uh with a tax and I guess one of
the questions I have for staff is can we
issue uh business licenses that
would
uh uh expire if the city does not adopt
a
tax um so on January 1st 2018 you don't
have to answer now but I think this is a
question we want to I would like to get
answered on January 1st 2018 businesses
can go into business but if the city
does not adopt the tax on March whatever
it is 5th 2019 those business licenses
would expire and they would have to
close in 60 days or some something uh
during which time we could make a
different decision but I think uh uh for
me I'm not willing to have us wait until
March of 19 to open
dispensaries um I think that's uh you
know maybe we don't need to be in a
hurry but I just think that that does
doesn't really put us in uh the cat bird
seat as it were um I I also uh think we
should have a a fairly lenient policy
about uh on-site use um I I uh this is
now a legal product in the state of
California and telling people that they
can only um buy it and squirrel
themselves back to their house to use it
um I can't actually think of another
product uh that we treat in that way I
mean certainly there are products that
are maybe best used in private locations
but uh I just think um in some way
uh we should
um we should not just allow for that
opportunity but we should we should
carefully figure out how that
opportunity is the best version for our
city and uh uh what are the parking
requirements for it and all kinds of
things uh because um
uh because this is the world that that
we're in and our state voted for it and
I think um I for one understand why it
passed and I think that our city can
provide a a fairly Exquisite experience
around the entire the entire the entire
experience and um
uh finally I want to return to something
Michael voich said and I think council
member Duran followed up on um yes we
have a we have a federal
government uh
it's we we all know this it's 3500 miles
away and sometimes it's in our bedrooms
so uh we have
to be sure and careful that as a city
we're delivering all the information
we're telling you how um how this works
uh and how it doesn't work and where uh
where some of the traps uh and pitfalls
and danger zones may be um because as
council member Duran said we can't
necessarily protect you from the long
arm of the federal government um
especially if
they were to choose West Hollywood as a
location to make a point so um I think I
think that's an important an important
piece that we can't leave behind the
education uh of what our federal
government thinks of what it is we're
we're doing um and I have one last
question that I also don't need an
answer to tonight but um I'm just
wondering if uh if it's possible to set
a minimum fee for a business license or
have an auction as a way to raise
revenue for uh the city's implementation
of this um or if uh or if merely setting
the business license cost is the only
way to to uh engage with with possible
vendors
um and I think that's uh all the things
that I wanted to bring up uh so far
thank
you council member horbath thank you
mayor um I want to thank the members of
the public who came out to speak as well
um I think that this we're in um mostly
Uncharted Territory although uh we've
been at the Forefront of the piece that
isn't Uncharted Territory and I hope
that we stay there moving forward um I
think there are certainly a lot of
considerations I think um as I
understand it staff is asking for
direction from city council um on where
we want to go next but there really
aren't recommendations
from staff based on what sort of options
there are so um I wish we had some more
information from you about um what you
know what some of the consequences of
some of those choices might be I agree
with council member Duran that um we're
going to get the best information from
folks who are stakeholders in this
industry and who have some degree of
expertise so I think working with them
first to make sure that we're
understanding you know from folks who
are doing this and are aware of you know
the latest and greatest in terms of
Regulation but also in terms of um you
know what sort of businesses are out
there um I'm certainly open I think um
I'm certainly open to expanding the
number of licenses and the kinds of
businesses that we have here um I think
that retail is very a retail um shop
that sells a topical um is much
different
than um a a cannabis bar that would be a
place for on-site consumption so
regulating those two things would be
very different for me one feels like a
Cosmetics place and one feels like um a
bar and so um I think uh the question of
medical versus adult use um is one that
we've heard brought to us from the
community there are concerns about
access of um IAL cannabis um as opposed
to you know those who are um
participating in the new regulation
under 64 so I think um making sure that
we are creating and continuing to
protect safe access for patients is
important um and also uh equally
important is making sure that we're
keeping um cannabis out of the hands of
underage non-patients um so um separate
facilities I understand there's a debate
about where the governor at on that and
where we're going to go but I think that
when you keep the facilities separate um
you avoid issues like that um although
without necessarily understanding from a
you know informed point of view what the
consequences of separating them might be
for that same issue um so I would like
some more information on that um I think
you've addressed um you've raised the
issue of uh whether there would be um
consumption in public spaces and for me
this feel that issue feels a lot like SM
smoking or drinking smoking cigarettes
or drinking in public so I don't agree
with the comments that were made about
we're just going to shove people out in
the streets um no we're not um but I
think that we have to figure out what
the right spaces are where people can
consume um cannabis and in what Manner
um I I understand there's been
discussion at least brought to the
Planning Commission about um delivery
services and I don't know how we
regulate other types of delivery Ser
services at this point in the city
anyway so do we
regulate um pharmaceutical deliveries do
we regulate wine deliveries do we
regulate what kind of deliveries do we
regulate if any and um you know so uh
again echoing council member deo's
comments since this is a legal substance
what are some of the things that we can
be comparing it to and comparable uses
um that uh that would make sense in
terms of Regulation um I think are
certainly a number of Public Safety
questions we need to um to ask there are
questions I know some of my colleagues
and other communities have been raising
the issue of um what amount of I I don't
know what the right language around this
is but uh what amount of consumption
what would a DUI litmus test or
percentage be I don't even know if
that's possible I don't know Sciences
behind that at this point but um but I
also know that um another public safety
issue is Banking and making sure that
we're not uh that whatever businesses do
come to West Hollywood that we're
helping them figure out what Financial
mechanisms they're using to make sure
these businesses don't become targets of
um some of the crimes of opportunity
that we've seen happening in the city um
from time to time so I think there are
as much as I would like to provide
Direction I feel like that's almost
about as specific as I can be given that
we don't have a lot of information to
start from I agree that I'd like to
start with um expert expert opinion and
bringing that information into the
conversation um before we go to the
public um I think uh we have to have an
informed policy to be considered by the
public um not sort of the other way
around and I'll see if I have anything
to add after uh as we're moving towards
a motion thanks okay thank you mayor
pm thank you and thank you to all the
people who came out to speak tonight um
I don't use marijuana I don't drink um
have a a lot of history of substance
abuse in my family so that's a choice
I've made uh the voters have made a
choice in California to allow for uh
adult use of marijuana uh it's something
that I think the voters in West
Hollywood support it pretty uh heavily
uh and I think we've had as a city a
history of supporting certainly medical
use of marijuana uh the voters have
decided that uh medical um adult use
marijuana is something that is permitted
now in the state of California and I
think that we should as a city embrace
it in the same way that we embraced the
use of medical
marijuana we are not really in the
business of opening up one of these
establishments
um the people who want to do that are of
course risking the federal law being
enforced against them they have to work
out their own relationships with
landlords uh and the risk that's
entailed there they have to work out
their banking relationships that is not
something that is the city's respons
possibility we're not opening up one of
these establishments we're here in a
regulatory capacity and so I think that
we need to figure out what kind of
regulations are appropriate given that
this is the reality uh you put in here
one of the possible actions would be for
us to uh ban the uh operation of adult
use marijuana facilities in or can
facilities in West Hollywood and I think
that was put in there kind of
rhetorically because I don't think
that's where the city is going to go and
certainly not where I think we should go
you asked us a series of questions and
I'm going to go through them um in order
of the questions you've asked and I
understand it's difficult for us to
answer them because as Lindsay
said as Lindsay said we don't have
complete
information um the first one is should
the city allow the existing medical
marijuana collectives to sell
non-medical marijuana that sounds like a
question that we can't really answer
because that may be decided by the state
so perhaps that's an issue that needs to
be deferred should we limit non-medical
marijuana to locations where there are
currently licensed medical marijuana
dispensaries I don't think that's the
appropriate response um as my colleagues
have indicated if they're combined maybe
they're not the the best people to
operate those facilities they may be but
I don't know that we necessarily want to
limit to four locations for any other
business coffee shops you know the ones
that sell coffee um
we we allow the market to dictate right
people can open up the business if they
get their license and then the
marketplace determines who's successful
and who isn't but I think this is
different and I think that we do need to
be more cautious about this um and I do
think that we need to have some kind of
limit on locations as you already
indicated we probably need to keep them
away from schools we need to keep them
away and that's what state law already
contemplated the initiative already
contemplated that um I like my colleague
suggestion council member deos about if
we go ahead with licensing and
regulation um having those regulations
tied into or terminate once we you know
have a sales tax uh if we don't have a
tax then the um permissions or the
licenses uh expire so having some kind
of provision to do that
um the use of non-medical marijuana on
public property I I think we already
prohibit smoking in most public places I
think we should treat this in the same
way that we treat
tobacco
um home delivery that's the one that you
know as Lindsay said we don't
necessarily regulate other Home
Delivery I'm just concerned that home
home delivery of marijuana that it might
become a target for criminal activity uh
especially if you have a a big delivery
truck like a Brinks truck delivering
marijuana that could be a target for
people so I I'm not certain about what
to do there
um allowing uh licensed non-medical
marijuana to cultivate marijuana indoors
I'm just not certain uh uh aot ing
manufacturer extraction testing or
processing again I'm not certain I'm not
certain that our commercial areas are
really appropriate for that I don't know
enough about it um the warehousing and
storage doesn't seem appropriate for
West Hollywood we really don't have any
other warehouses here for any kind of
product so I just don't know that that's
appropriate um reasonable regulations on
indoor cultivation
to Ure it doesn't exceed the parameters
Allowed by law I I think that seems
reasonable that we would uh make sure
that indoor cultivation complies with
the law and uh outdoor cultivation
backyards private patios or
balconies I again as long as it's one or
two plants I don't think anyone's going
to notice or particularly care or that
it's going to be a priority but I'd want
to know a little bit more about that uh
and I do think we should prohibit
smoking of marijuana on city property
just like I think we prohibit smoking
tobacco on city property I may be
incorrect there but I think we we
probably should do that on the bigger
policy
issue I think the big issue for me is
how do we ensure that we get the best
possible operators the idea of opening
it up and having you know first come
first serve doesn't get us the best
having a some kind of bidding more
doesn't ensure that we get the best it
may ensure that we get people who have
the most money behind them but that
doesn't mean that we're going to get the
best operators so I really want us to
come up with some kind of process where
we're reviewing proposals and making
sure that the people who are going to
get the licenses in West Hollywood for
this are going to be high
quality um businesses that are serving
the local community and serving visitors
to West Hollywood and providing a very
positive
experience thank you mayor proam I have
some questions uh first of all does the
ABC allow smoking marijuana in places
that sell
alcohol I mean we we won't I mean I mean
that would be something to think think
about we we'll look into that we don't
know that right now okay and then
um uh we do allow smoking tobacco in our
parks and so I but we also
don't I mean there are there are going
to be uh restrictions in terms of being
near daycare centers and whatever so I
think that's something that we have to
think about and and also just to double
check your map about where daycare
centers are uh and schools because I
think mamones is missing from uh from
the map and um dayare Center on
Huntley right and there is no daycare
center on Huntley however there are
daycare centers that are in Los Angeles
which are within a few you know blocks
of West Hollywood and I think we need to
take that into consideration whatever we
decide should be in the spirit of you
know the of of our law and should apply
to La as well um I can see where we at
least starting out we would want this to
be a planning and uh business license um
we we have uh M mcups for uh for alcohol
licenses right we
need is that so I mean I think it is
something that we should um you know
look into um I would imagine we want to
look at you know maybe you know whatever
what whatever we have in terms of the
medical marijuana now with um radius uh
of how many you know we would want
within you know a th000 foot radius uh
how many uh how close we would want to
allow a store uh to residential knowing
that you know our residential and our
commercial are very close together and
we have had um you know some concerns
about about uh places being uh you know
what uh close to uh to residences so I
think we need to be uh mindful of that
um I know that we you know we want to be
a leader in this but I I don't think it
hurts to look at what what other states
have gone through to see what they've
done right and what they've done you
know what they've done where they're
changing their their own laws now
because of you know for example in
Colorado wherever just to to to learn
from others experience I I don't think
we necessarily have to reinvent the
wheel um so I would um I would suggest
that we look at that I mean I honestly I
wish that we had had this report in
January uh because it is complicated
it's probably one of the most
complicated issues that we're going to
be dealing with and um I agree with
council member Duran that I would like
to get um you know uh advice from from
experts in this field to um to have a a
just feel more confident about about how
we move forward uh with this um I also
wonder um if if if this is a cash
business how do we how do we ensure that
we're
getting the tax money whether you know I
don't know the sales tax or any tax that
we put on
locally you know you know experience
with cash businesses are That You Don't
See That You Don't See necessarily
everything
that cash that's you know passing hands
um I also have some concerns about uh
delivery and so I you know again I mean
I at this point I'm open but I think
that it is important that we look at all
sides of this because not only do you
have the possibility of of a public
safety issue for the people delivering
but also the people who are who are
receiving you know that they're that I
mean someone a stranger is going into
someone's home so I mean these are just
all things to think about
um and um you know regarding medical
having uh some that are um the medical
marijuana places versus the non
non-medical I mean I can see where there
would be benefits to keeping them
separate also for the consumer because
uh you know the experience might be very
different um you know for a consumer
that is is using marijuana for for
medical purposes for medicinal purposes
they may not want the Frills and the you
know fancy or whatever you know whatever
different things that might be offered
um they may just you know want to make
sure that they go in that they feel safe
that they you know get their medicinal
marijuana and they leave um and again I
just think this is a this is a really
complicated um a comp complicated issue
and it's complicated in terms of land
use and it's complicated in terms of uh
licensing and um I think uh we need to
um we need to move on this now pretty
quickly if we want to make the uh
January 2018 deadline because I don't
think I don't think not doing anything
is the
answer council member Deo thank you
thank excuse me thank you um Mr Mr hman
can you uh go to the slide that showed
the sort of suggested next steps I think
it started with Community meetings and
then a Planning Commission and so um I I
just wanted to bring up for the council
and the staff and actually really our
city manager because he's our sort of
Point
person when we're not when we don't have
a staff report but so I have the sense
that we should probably have maybe uh 45
Day updates or something like like that
that really keeps us checked in I'm with
council member Duran and I guess council
member horv actually I don't remember if
you said this or not but I'm I'm
actually not thinking we need to have
too many Community meetings I think it
wouldn't hurt for our uh Chamber of
Commerce to have a meeting and maybe one
of their chamber mixers can be a uh
cannabis you know a Canabis
discussion um but I think uh I think our
community you know we voted
you don't want to buy pot don't go in a
pot store I mean would sort of be it's a
little flip but I think mayor Horvat I
mean excuse me
mayor
me uh uh was clear that we want to uh be
really careful about the neighborhoods
we're placing them in and how we're
going to interact with that but I just
don't see that
we we need to have several Community
meetings to get input from our community
members I think we need experts to tell
us and I'm I I'm just concerned that
late summer is a little late we have a
meeting in typically a meeting in July
and a meeting in August and last year we
had one meeting in September one meeting
in October one meeting in November one
meeting in December so I'm thinking we
probably need to have uh this discussion
sooner than uh late summer which is
September or or August uh because I
think we need to give you enough time to
do this and get it to the Planning
Commission and have them and also our
state will be making choices as well so
um in terms of that process that's what
I wanted to lay out two things that we
really try and push up the council city
council Direction on regulating
marijuana and we have that maybe in July
or August at the latest and that um
uh we have I'm sorry the first meeting
in a August I think there going to
probably only be one so the first will
be the only but and then uh
uh ask our chamber to participate and
maybe do one community meeting but but
maybe that community meeting can happen
after we make our initial direction to
the council please can I suggest that
maybe we have a study session the city
council and uh maybe with if you know
with these experts I think that you know
it's kind of unfair to have this
discussion during a council meeting uh
when there's you know we we really need
to have the time and not feel pressured
by the fact that it's you know 10:30 at
night maybe a subcommittee how about a
subcommittee of two so we can move more
quickly you know I'm I'm fine with
whatever my colleagues want uh you know
I I don't think it would hurt to have a
study session because I think we all we
all want to have an idea of what's going
on and what it all means and um and if
we can do that maybe in June but maybe
would that be too early well I was
thinking before we got to the study
session maybe a subcommittee of counil
get in there and start working with the
experts so at least we have two of us
plugged in with all the experts and so
we're able to talk to one another at the
study session sure and then and then
maybe have a study session in uh in June
or July um with the council so that you
know we can get our questions answered
not feel like we're under pressure
public would have an opportunity to
listen and to uh you know give provide
input um but again I think this is a
complicated issue and I think you know
having this discussion at 10:30 at night
um when really I think we all we want we
want to do this
right um and I think it would be helpful
at least for me uh to have that mayor if
I may um we also did approve as a
council the um annual cannabis education
Forum that will be coming um and I
believe it's happening in August so
perhaps that might be an opportunity for
folks to get a sense of the direction
we're heading and what's happening um
maybe we can at least have some role in
that conversation um that's happening at
that time mayor with the subcommittee I
have an interest in doing it just
experiences I have I don't know if any
of my other colleagues wish to do
subcommittee on
this I'm interested but if you're
interested or you're interested or I'm
interested in doing it very much so I'm
not really in favor of a subcommittee
because I think it as the mayor said
this is really important and I think we
should all be involved with it from
beginning to end okay that that seems
fair too especially if we can do what
she what she suggested is have a study
session early at you know a six o'clock
study session that maybe defers the
start of our meeting a bit but gets this
out because if we did that we would have
150 people listening and that might be
part of the community effort as well
okay and then um looking at staff um
could we come back at the second meeting
in June with that schedule of when we're
going to have the study session and we
could explain what the panels we'll have
a panel and I we can do that
yes mayor Pro yeah I I think that based
on what I'm hearing there is some broad
consensus here that at least on some
major points that the city does want to
allow for um adult use cannabis uh I
think council is recognizing that we
play a regulatory role that we we have
some questions about the nature of the
regulations and some of the details but
I think on the broad policy issue there
is a some consensus here that it makes
sense for us to be a leader here and
have regulations in in place um
beginning January of 2018 and I think
there's at least a couple of us who've
talked about the importance of um of
Taxation as well so I I think this is
something that uh you've gotten some
direction and hopefully when you come
back to us we can narrow the focus and
we'll have some more information but
again thank you also I think I also
heard I think um that there wasn't a lot
of support for um warehousing or
manufacturing were those the only things
taking place I was just actually going
to jump in on that
um I while I understand that
geographically and based on the kinds of
facilities we have in the city uh a
warehouse and how we think about it is
not probably not the likeliest thing to
happen here but I do think that there
may be some um and this is where experts
will be really helpful there are some
potential opportunities for cultivation
and sites that are the size of existing
buildings in West Hollywood and so and
there might be some benefit to keeping
all of that in one site versus having
things traveling and transporting um I'm
not sure sure so while it sounds like we
are likely in agreement about the
likelihood of it happening in the city
probably not I'm I am interested in
knowing more from experts what the cost
benefit of that might be and and I sort
of want to say the same thing about
manufacturing I think um a sort of uh uh
small um I don't want to say homemade
but a a small Manu a small manufacturer
who manufactured products uh in small
batches that you know sort of that was
their thing that was what they were
providing you know here's where we make
it here's where you buy it I I think we
want to we want to allow for for that as
well like a like a fine restaurant or a
wine bar or you know so that sort of
thing
okay one one last thing as we look at
regulations I think council member Deo
brought up the point of on-site use we
treat on-site consum of alcohol
different than um a retailer that sells
alcohol and perhaps that's something
that we should be looking at as
well any anyone else okay
exed so do we need a motion or did you
just get I think that's the direction so
I think we got a lot of good direction
like you indicated um it's pretty clear
that the city council wants us to go
forward with looking at opening up up
the city and making sure that we address
um this subject in a strong
way thank you
[Music]