[Music]
okay so I want to get into your journey
going public
so the original you're based out of
Portland and the original company / you
started as a farmer correct okay and
what's the name of the brand so the name
of the company that we originally
started was eco firma farms yeah which
was an indoor cultivation facility in
just outside about 30 minutes outside
Portland Oregon okay and the company was
crushing it in the Portland market the
company was crushing at the Portland
market even though our market in the
Oregon Market Eco firma farms was the
first company in the country to
nationally advertised that they
wholesale cannabis and put a phone
number and email address to go with it
back in 2012 and so we took it a
full-page ad out in high times and made
that statement with our logo and to be
honest with you most of my friends said
you're gonna go to prison and that
didn't happen and we established
ourselves as a brand and kind of took
off from there and went down a path of
sustainability looking at how you could
cultivate cannabis indoor and be carbon
neutral how could I look at an outdoor
farm we said you're destroying the
planet and feel good about myself and
say no I'm not so so we took off down
that PLAs path and we were 100% carbon
neutral our power was 100% wind power
because we had that opportunity in
Oregon and then that just kind of
planted the seed of how do we get rid of
our garbage how do we use light how do
we use automation how do we grow
vertically what do we do to to be more
sustainable and what we learned was that
by being environmentally sustainable we
actually started creating corporate
sustainability and financial
sustainability so when we went through
our public audit when we sold the
company and we were the primary company
in an RTO to go public we found in the
audit that we had made it to 189 dollars
a pound to produce indoor cannabis which
is in a lot of cases less expensive than
a good deal of outdoor farms
you
it was really access to capital for the
expansion looking at Oregon and that
market in particular I think it was a
good representation of what you can see
in a supply demand as it gets larger
throughout the country and everyone's
going to see it eventually but Oregon
was a great example we went in a 90-day
period from a wholesale price of $2,600
a pound to a wholesale price is 600 a
pound in 90 days
so the attrition rate there is really
really high and what happens is you get
a lot of farms then who will start
selling cannabis for below their average
cost to produce just to try to get a
little back into the retirement account
right so for us we saw that and said we
need to a we need a lot of upgrades so
that we can produce cannabis for even
lower and we found ways to do that and
we also need to create a vertical
integration model here between
processing and retail and in order to do
that we're gonna need a lot of money a
lot more than usually a individual
investor is willing to put out right so
we looked into doing an IPO or an RTO
reverse takeover or initial public
offering and in looking at the RTO and
trying to decide how you do an RTO
figure it out where do you go where do
you start how we happen to have an
opportunity where another company had a
show already and they were looking for a
cannabis company and we collided in the
middle and we helped them take their RTO
into cannabis and they helped us take
our company public so you're now
basically in bed with this other group
right like they own a piece of equity in
the new co so they own a hundred percent
so what we did in the in the sale was we
struck a deal for and it's a lot of it's
public you can read about it but we
struck a deal for cash and for
investment future investment to move
forward and so they acquired you this
under purse okay got it
and now but you're saying they now own a
hundred percent of the company so you
don't have any equity in the company so
we did what's called a share purchase
agreement yeah so we took a lot of
shares okay right all right yes all
right so it's a pretty deal it was an
equity deal because it was mostly stock
not a lot of
that's one of my passion subjects
because I'm always curious that implies
that you believe that their share price
is not currently overvalued and will go
up I do because a lot of these deals
that you see in the press every time I
see a deal I say I bet it's like 90 plus
percent stock a couple million dollars
of cash and so that was your deal but
you were so it means you have confidence
in that group because they're gonna be
steering the ship correct yes ah maybe I
should say that different okay um you
ever heard the phrase the first one
through the door takes the most rounds
so typically the first one through the
door takes the most rounds they also get
the best deal so the deal that we struck
at our time going with them I was
confident was going to be a multiplier
for us in value in the future
that being said future deals don't tend
to get the same deal so a lot of times
when you see the Cresco labs 850 million
dollar purchase of a distributor in
California that's not their first
purchase and so how much of that is
stock and what is the lift going to be
out of that and where are they looking
for in a merger that is a completely
different play than to be the first
company to go public or the first group
of companies to go public and in my
opinion and the great thing that I got
to learning going public was I got to
learn from the very beginning how to do
an RTO how to take a cannabis company
public how to raise money for that
cannabis company and how to recognize a
lot of pitfalls that could be in what I
like to call the 1.0 of public cannabis
companies that's going on right now and
I believe the 2.0 is starting now which
is why I opted to leave the company that
I was with and go start this new company
I start so to come leaving the company
is the one that just went public but
you're starting something new because I
was going to say it everything you're
talking about is implying that you're
gonna go through this process all over
again which implies that you're not
working full-time at the public code
that is correct so when I so based on
you sold your company you are now out of
the operations of it and you're now
focused on starting your next thing with
the cash part of what you receive from
the last deal
yeah the cash end the experience right
and okay so what are you now doing so I
am now opening I'm going to do an RTO
and we're going to open we're going to
consolidate companies once we have the
companies consolidated that we want
which were in LOI is with right now we
will then as a group take all of those
companies public with a shell that I
already possess okay and and what what
what part of the supply chain are these
companies in that your cobbling together
we're looking at everything from full
vertical integration so indoor and
outdoor cultivation processing retail
and then we're also looking at some tech
pieces and some manufacturing pieces so
like your LOI s are they with like a
processing company or like a retail yes
yes and yes okay so basically you're
three quarters of the way through
getting the whole vertical stack
together the band together and then it's
announcing the public going public once
we have them we build all the financials
and have everything there to show
investors what they would be investing
in in our potential for gain in the
future and our experience level then we
will take it public and go raise capital
for that larger endeavor with all the
companies together so you're inspiring
to all the dudes who are actually guys
who know what they're doing from a
cultivation standpoint so you're an
example of somebody who's not going to
be a finance guy coming and rolling up
the cannabis space you're a cannabis guy
who's gonna do what the finance guys
have been doing in the industry correct
I'm a cannabis guy who got the
opportunity to learn the finance piece
of it over the last three years in on
the public side and so I'm gonna take
that experience with me into this new
endeavor and I was also fortunate enough
when we built eco firma at least from
what we've seen on public market and
what we've seen with REI and the power
score we also built one of the most
efficient gardens in the country so
being able to take that experience into
other businesses and be able to work
with them to create that efficient model
it's
where I would like to be someone will
shoot me for saying this but I would
like to be one of the first cannabis
public cannabis companies to right out
of the gate start giving out some
dividends even if they're not much yeah
because it would be about that would be
not yes I don't think many of them are
very close to that right now so you're
not going to be stretched super thin and
trying to madly acquire things and
overpay for things and okay so basically
it seems like on your pitch deck you're
probably showcasing the fact that you're
the lowest cost indoor producer in terms
of capabilities and then you want to
scale this across the country and into
different markets like you want to do
the vertical and integrate so you're
doing the vertical integration in Oregon
right correct and then you want to start
attacking other states we're doing the
vertical integration nationally so
Oregon will have pieces in it and organ
is just a good example of where vertical
integration is key because of the market
that they are but vertical integration
in different states all have different
value points and so looking at a state
like um Nevada which I think is a great
example or Arizona Nevada Las Vegas
we're looking at 40 million tourists a
year that come through here that's the
that's the population of California that
come through in a year just in tourism
having a footprint down here in retail
is a really good idea that being said
cultivation down here is substantially
more expensive than it is in say
Humboldt County or Southern Oregon once
we can open those borders up and start
moving cannabis south having an indoor
facility looking at the markets across
the country
and figuring out whether this is what
always blows me away about the money
that has spent then spent on those like
Desert Hot Springs facilities where all
you can think of in your mind is you
guys realize that in three years or five
or whatever it is that this facility is
going to be
a complete waste and so the implication
is that yes they do know that but they
think that they can make so much money
in the short term to justify that huge
capex correct right it's all an
estimation of ROI but I don't think
they're gonna make it out what we're
gonna find out in California we're gonna
find out all right so basically you're
so but your roll up do you have a name
by the way
yes okay you're gonna have sex your
brand names than that right yes okay
thanks
the mantas growth is really just for the
public capital public market in terms of
you you want to roll up a couple
companies and then go public with a big
tada moment my question and I just want
to make sure I understand the answer is
you're rolling those companies up in the
Oregon market like when you say you're
doing it nationally does that imply that
you're you're you have an LOI with like
a manufacturing company that has
manufacturing operations across multiple
states okay so good questions we are
entering an LOI right now in California
to acquire 32 licenses Oh
so in color for the the supply chain so
it could be a district distribution so
that's from one company that's from one
company okay so you're gonna you're
about to roll up a company that has that
is doing well in the California Mark
like building out this vision in this
market specifically so you'll have them
and then and then we're looking at a
company in Nevada that has cultivation
and a retail footprint but you don't
like cultivation I don't but you are
gonna sell that as retail alright so you
would keep it you wouldn't try to
immediately sell that off right okay but
it has to be right for the purchase
price of the valuation to understand
what are we paying for it now what are
we looking at for the retail side if we
have to close down cultivation at one
year two year three year what are we
looking for for capex to be able to fund
that or not take a big hit grow and
that's really the discussion of the LOI
right and that's really the
responsibility
of us to the investors if I am taking
public money from investors be it I
bought 10 shares myself or I am a
private placement investor my
responsibility is to ensure that you may
not know the cannabis space really well
I do so my responsibility with your
money is to ensure that I spend it
wisely so that we can gain value in
those shares whether it's for the no so
that's so that's interesting that you're
so you're gonna you're tada moments
gonna be with like vertical integration
in California like what's up world we're
vertically integrated in California
we're vertically integrated in Nevada
and like maybe one or two other states
and then so so I am right in thinking
that your your long-term vision is to
basically you know since every state is
for awhile gonna be its own silo of
economy right you're you're gonna just
build that out into all the legal states
and then in each state you're gonna
decide which part of the stack we want
to be operating in okay how well will it
play together when we can bring all the
states together when we can open up
federal borders sometime in the next
twelve to thirty six months I really do
think that's probably a good estimation
a timeline and within that timeframe if
you're looking at your asset or at least
if you're looking at what you're
acquiring for assets across the country
with that mindset that eventually
they're all going to blend together and
how are they going to play together have
we made a giant mistake or not that
that's what we're looking towards am i
putting up ten million square feet of
flowering canopy space in Ottawa Canada
I mean I hope not and I'm not saying
that it's a terrible investment are not
saying terrible things about a company
that's there I'm just saying there's a
you know there's there's a reason people
don't buy substantial amounts of wine
coming out of Paducah Kentucky it's not
because Kentucky's a bad place it's
because grapes grow better in California
it's just nature so looking at
acquisitions as a whole for whether it's
retail or technology or cultivation
trying to make sure those puzzle pieces
are going to fit together right in the
future is what I think we should be
doing
talk tech acquisition so you're implying
that you'd want to roll up some tech
type operators as well like what kind of
technology are you looking at I believe
that there is some really interesting
technology out there surrounding
genetics and crop management cultivation
has really interesting crop management
across an erp scale for one but even on
the cultivation side if you if you are a
fully vertically integrated company and
you think about what it takes from the
time you plant the seed or cut a clone
until the time it sells at a retail
dispensary what the consumers going to
want and how to trend that and make sure
that you have enough durbin poison in
the month of July because that's when
it's the most popular to sell how do you
know when to plant it and where to plant
it and which fee knows to plant it and
what environment it grows best at being
able to track that with software and
data to ensure that you can put that in
the hands of a $15 an hour employee and
it's all done right that's gonna be a
pinnacle piece towards towards crop
management for these large companies so
so it seems like with your vertical
integration you you could almost build
out like what you would want a
technology solution to be able to do for
your vertical integration and then take
all the data coming out of all that
making sense of it but then scaling it
to then selling into other operators
yeah that data becomes very valuable
yeah if I can tell you exactly what
plants yield exactly how much in every
product from pink shirt raw flour to BHO
what our highest price points are what
our best turpan e terpenes are what our
best cannabinoid profiles are and how
they sell in each market and all of that
is not six people crunching numbers as
cost accountants in an office that we're
paying for but it's taken care of and
software and it's one cost accountant
that can look through it pick apart the
numbers analyze it and then the software
can actually tell us what we need to be
doing that all the way down to the crop
level for harvest or all the way up at
the retail level for distribution those
pieces are right so base that you'd be
looking to either build or acquire like
do
analytics capabilities that are getting
that are servicing and getting data from
different parts of the of the supply
chain yes and there are companies out
there working on it now okay so we've
been in talks with a couple of them got
it cool all right I like I like the
vision and I guess the special sauce is
you know what do you bring to the table
that nobody else does it's basically I
can grow indoor weed for cheaper and
better than anybody I wouldn't say
better than anybody but point being like
right I think of generally right
I started at I've started what I like to
think of as a competition for people to
be able to produce higher quality for
lower cost and at a completely
environmentally sustainable way so that
we're not robbing Peter to pay Paul I
mean the end of the day we're all
polishing the brass on the Titanic
around here if you think that you can
don't rob Peter to pay Paul I'm not Paul
but so yes I think the experience from
going through the the small-scale
cannabis cultivation all the way through
a public acquisition and also being able
to do this cultivation and be able to do
it more efficiently right now than
anybody in the country on an indoor
scale I think those two pieces put us in
a very unique positions you know current
as obviously the technology you're using
in your indoor grow operation is going
to change over time but like current
snapshot in time can you walk me through
what you're currently using so you're
using like fluence lights so we're using
fluent lights we're using packaged HVAC
units at this moment which are already
antiquated because we built the grow
three years ago we're using regular soil
that we grow in that we amend with a
higher concentration of perlite so that
we have a little better drainage yeah
we're using an automated feed system
that also tracks all of our feed all of
our data and can back net tie into all
of our environment and Westham is a
rhythm to say and then
we use 20% salt based nutrient right now
10 to 20% and are you shouldn't say we
the company that we sold that's what
they were using when I left are you are
you making your own like that at what
scale would you make your own nutrients
instead of buying them like who do you
buy nutrients from right so time to do
that right now so maybe I should
backtrack the three most expensive parts
of running an indoor cultivation
facility at least for us when we went
through an audit was humans were number
one power was number two nutrients was
number three so humans finding ways to
you can reduce humans by upping volume
the more I don't need to double the
humans I have employed if I double the
amount of volume I am cultivating once
we had proof of concept of how we
cultivated it in more of an automated
fashion so we could have doubled our
cultivation and probably only added one
to two employees so we can fix the human
scale right we can fix humans there in
our costs for cultivation power we're
looking at renewable energy like we had
a large grant for solar so you can start
chewing that power away solar batteries
putting up a solar field Condesa it's
done a great job obviously with putting
up solar fields but you're also using
wind right and we use a hundred percent
wind power so you have like a little
wind turbine on top of the so everybody
says that because it a distributed wind
power or throughout the gorge in Oregon
and Washington there are massive wind
farms so we buy our power from the wind
farm okay
and then obviously nutrient and
nutrients the big one right so for when
I left the company that was where we
were just getting into like being able
to dial down on how do we solve this
problem buying nutrients in a bottle
you've got vehicles on the road that are
having to deliver it which is cost
you've got ninety percent of it which is
water which has cost a lot of marketing
cost the waste the recycling of the
bottles all those pieces so yes I will
tell you right now at five thousand
square feet of flowering canopy space if
you're doing it efficiently it is time
to get rid of bottled nutrients now we
had dry
yeah but all right so but when you
hadn't scaled up like what were the
brands you were like what brands do you
like um we were using gosh I got to
think through it Botanica dragonfly yeah
we had some natural bat guano's that we
were putting in we had some see a green
that we were using and then you go to
concentrate some buy bulk like humic
acids humic and fulvic acids stuff like
that kind of a combination of all those
pieces the salt base that we were using
was the the a and B base of Botanica
that was our only salt okay so basically
your soil alone was not it you're
actually adding basically the a and B
right we were adding the a and B and
then we were adding biologicals and
beneficials and microbial life to the
soil along with fungi so that we had a
good living we had we had good life in
our soil where microbial life was in the
neighborhood of 400 I forget the
measurement so that's that's gonna be
outside my education right but I guess
my so that the the a and the B weren't
like killing the okay
no because if you actually look into
Botanica and what they're using on the
salt side for a and B it's it's it's a
very small amount of mineral salt that
they use and that was a really big
question for us like well is it really I
mean that's what you hear but was it
true right so as we added beneficials we
would test it we would test our
microbial life from veg all the way
through bloom and we would look at right
after we fed two days after we fed when
we were when we were uh if we were
running just a cycle with straight water
and no food like what were those
microbial life levels were they
diminishing were they increasing were
they staying the same and we found that
even right after we fed we were not
losing any microbial life and it would
gain over time so so what a night and
then because you have the soil I assume
what you're adding from an A&amp;B
perspective is super diluted it's like
you're just adding a tiny
right right the plants are really
efficient in the methodology of
cultivation that we were using where
we're growing in a vertical stack and
we're sharing an environment and we're
tooling up LED light and bringing up co2
levels and bringing up feed levels and
then monitoring actual runoff of feed in
the soil so that we aren't just throwing
nutrients down the drain we could get
really precise with how much each
cultivar wanted to consume and it got
really interesting because you could put
for example we had rooms where we'd have
up to six strains in one cultivation
room and you would see things like the
flav you would test it in week 3 of
flower and it would be at 35 parts per
million of phosphorous and maybe a 5
percent difference between the top and
bottom of the plant and then you would
in the same room at the same time test
the pineapple cush and it would be at
300 parts per million at phosphorus with
a 10% difference between top and bottom
so looking at the mobility of the
nutrient and that cultivar you learn
that I need to give Flav way more
phosphorous at week 3 but we don't need
to put as much phosphorus fin over here
and you can really get finite with your
nutrient input and those cost savings
get really big over time right so all
right so and then are you making like
tees or anything like that or when I was
leaving we were just moving down the
path of wanting to go into a compost tea
but you know it was um being a coming
from the base of being a grower it's
always really fun to like throw all this
cool stuff at the plants and watch it
happen when really it it was time to be
really methodical so let's take away
just this one piece and watch let's add
just this one piece let's test
everything and find out so that we could
be really scientific in in our movements
and ensure that we weren't hey with did
compost tea plus we're testing for these
nutrient levels and we're changing our
nutrient water levels on a regular basis
I've lost track of what's affecting what
now I was wasting money on labor and
time and testing bread so we had just
started to get ready to make compost
teas and go down that path when I left
right because there are farms and this
is the direction we wanted to go and
I've I've since looked at other farms
met with other farms there are farms out
there who are using bed cultivation
they're cultivating in beds inside
they're rotating their soil they're
using a hundred percent organic input
and they're doing it under high
intensity LED light which is hard to do
because too much light not enough
nutrient if the plant even if you have
enough nutrient for the plant isn't
capable of uptaking said nutrient which
is always harder with an organic
nutrient you're never gonna succeed so
just saying hey we're gonna recycle our
soil we're gonna use all organic
nutrients and we're gonna grow under LED
in a tight proximity that that's not as
easy as it sounds right and a lot of
trial and error and then you were also
saying before that living what was the
living soil common living soil so
there's a really big you know there's a
lotta and it's just kind of nomenclature
we use right we use living soil we use
no-till that you know it's kind of the
catch phrases of the day for cultivators
living soil no-till soil their their
cultivation catchphrases of the day
right the last year or two it's been a
really big catchphrase for we're gonna
do living soil or we do no-till Korean
natural farming is another one right
they're really popular and they're
popular methodologies but we sometimes
as cultivators just trying to get our
point across we'll use that terminology
inappropriately and so to say that we're
using a no-till indoor maybe you really
are doing that but there are a lot of
methods to having a cover crop and a
living true living soil which the soils
not alive it's the life inside the soil
but we all know that to have it to truly
be using a no-till methodology indoor is
extremely difficult to do that
efficiently and that begs the question
what efficiency are trying to accomplish
because if the only thing you're trying
to accomplish is say that I use a
no-till and plant cover crops indoor
well then congratulations like you've
accomplished it but if you're looking at
it from the bottom line or
mathematically or if you're
you can get it from a sustainability
whether it's financial corporate or
environmental sustainability you have to
look at it from the point of why am I
doing this am i doing it so I don't have
to spend more money on soil because I
can continually reuse it am i doing it
because it's better on the environment I
am not flushing salts down a city sewer
system because I grow in an industrial
section in the middle of LA did I build
a bio Swale out back that will then an
Ag land be able to put native plants and
they will burn off whatever nutrient
organic or non-organic that goes in all
these factors play in what is the
purpose and if the purpose should always
be sustainability and sustainability
financial and sustainability
environmentally because at the end of
the day if you can't keep the lights on
you're not making money nobody's gonna
hear a damn word you have to say about
saving the planet right ok but so so
what I'm hearing is that you're saying
it will cost more to produce in a living
soil indoor we're talking about so the
way you'd have to say is yeah but that's
my number one priority I'm willing to
pay a little more maybe the market could
like maybe there's a branding
opportunity where the market appreciates
indoor cultivators who are at least
trying to be as environmentally as
friendly as possible so good pull back
the actual thing that I'm trying to say
I've always been trying to say is that
that's the myth it's actually more
sustainable and more efficient it is
cheaper to cultivate indoor
environmentally sustainable than it is
to not to use salt based nutrients in
smart pots with soil that you throw away
every time compared to figuring out how
to use organic inputs that take water
only on efu land in a hundred percent
carbon neutral sustainable cultivation
methodology it is less expensive to do
that and you will create a better
product for the end-user but your when
you left you guys are using you're not
living soil you're adding salts
we were because we were moving because
we had changed so many things on an
environment to just figure how to do it
that when I left we were still using
that but we were moving down the path
the
rid of it which is why I say we were at
189 a pound when we went through a
public audit I have 100% confidence that
had I have stayed with the company and
we implemented the pieces that we had
looked at we could have gotten below 75
and part of that is adding like a living
soil gameplan getting rid of all of
those bottles you misunderstood what
you're saying I thought I were saying
that it's impossible with living soil to
reduce the cost lower than other nozzles
what I was saying is using a
regenerative soil methodology endure
under LED light requires a lot of
different input it is not the same as
growing under a kavita using advanced
nutrients they are 100% different
methodologies and you have to get really
comfortable being uncomfortable changing
that and finding your way through it and
believe me we fell on our face figuring
out our pieces of it and so basically as
you launch the new company your grow
operations will be soil no salts we will
be focused on a large scale with an
ethos around sustainability cool 100%
that doesn't mean that the companies we
take have to be there when we get there
they just have to be open to changing to
get the right one you're talking about
like what you liked about being able to
kind of like you know have your a and B
so it seemed like you were saying with
what you just left you could say strain
a has its own nutrient supply it's not
it's not running the dosatron the
dosatrons not running the same stuff to
all the different strains but you're
gonna lose that when you move to living
soil like full-on regenerative soil
because you're not gonna be adding that
stuff so they're all gonna have are you
gonna are you gonna amend your soil
differently based on what strain you're
growing and well there's the amazing
thing about plants is once you get into
organic inputs and regenerative soil the
plants get the opportunity to take what
they want perfect okay all right so your
so while you like the fact that with the
salts you can dial things in and out
you're excited to move to regenerative
soil because you don't need to do any of
that right got it
got it right we're 100% on the same page
[Music]