you're all working on interesting stuff
and I know some of the work you're doing
all three you but you're always
constantly refining in switching process
with something you excited about this
year you know whether it whether it's
for the market or not but like what's
something you're into yourself that
you're working with you'd like to see
people access in any form gosh
so many things but I want to say on what
Jason had brought up and what me and
gene brought up Beth did you speak this
weekend Beth Schecter hi okay so the
open cannabis project looks to protect
the cultivar the strains that we're all
you know we've known and loved for a
long time and and hopefully combinations
of all of them so that we can all keep
doing the work that we've been doing
breeding and cultivating and it's a
nonprofit organization and there's
definitely gonna be some big bad Wolf's
come in to get genetics and it's really
hard that what do you do you hide them
away like don't give them away
you know don't come to an event like
this and and say here have a few of this
and a few of that because you know maybe
there's somebody in the room or
something you it's almost impossible and
so we just got a kind of support and
organization like that is really the
best way that we can keep cannabis open
source and keep like the genetics of
cannabis accessible to everybody because
the Syngenta's and the Monsanto's would
like to you know just tie up all these
strains and of course there's this
phenomena that's unusual where something
has been in under prohibition for you
know since in all of modern times that
has been basically illegal so you know
any innovation that has happened has not
been documented
because you know it's like at Humboldt C
company we keep
freaking notes during the breeding
season and then burn them in the fall
because it was like you know I'm not
trying to keep notes around about you
know how many goddamn plants I had and
you know so charge enhancement back in
the day
what's that charge enhancement you know
it's although you were in the game
I caught an extra couple years on a case
I had to fight because I had
spreadsheets comparing operations and it
gave me a criminal mastermind charge and
we all laughed and I said if I was so
smart I wouldn't got fucking caught but
no nonetheless the enhancement was
really punishing because I was using
tools to document work those it was
impossible to keep this much data when
you're running this many operations and
I had my hand and a lot of cookie jaws
way back in the day yeah you know and so
you know those those folks that look to
capitalize so much could easily come in
and and try to you know to say that
they've created something that's new
when really me and jeans been breeding
it for 20 goddamn years and you know so
on and so forth so that's a good
organization to support I really
appreciate what Beth's done and you know
as far as some exciting stuff that we're
doing I think you know really that big
phenotype on effort was exciting for me
and what else are you gonna release the
product this year dropping the sort of
selected cuts like Daniels farm we
picked one that we're calling magic
melon and that one just really smells
like melons and it's kind of gassy fuel
finish but yeah I don't know I just I
feel really just happy to be able to
work on in cannabis and share
share the the genetics and and
definitely like what it did I got an
email the other day and I looked at the
email and I thought it was kind of
weirded it said Burpee in the email and
so I replied to the email and did some
fishing and sure enough it was Burpee
and I don't really I don't know like are
they big bad wolf or not I mean I don't
I didn't follow the corporate ladder all
the way out but that's the kind of stuff
that's happening so definitely be
careful but you just gotta we we got to
keep charging forward and so exciting
things just breeding more and more all
the time and and we're doing some
genotyping and putting it in the public
space so that's a way that you can once
you do that if you don't patent it in a
year then it becomes public public
domain and so that's what I would call
defensive IP versus offensive IP which
is getting a patent and you know sending
out cease and desist letters to
everybody in the room who doesn't pay
you a fee for for growing it or whatever
and I think that there's you know I'm
not saying I'm completely opposed to
patents but I think definitely that it's
it's a slippery slope and so you know
there's a lot of things out there that
just are that should just be public
domain I mean if I could just take a
snapshot of the whole cannabis space
right now and make sure that that could
continue to be the way it is and people
could continue to grow the plant I think
that would be a good thing to do but
it's cost
cost a lot of money to genotype so you
know that and and that's not the only
solution - there's other ways to go
about it
but yeah so that's that's exciting
I don't do min gloom you know no but
what the thing is though it's hard
they're all in the real everyone in the
room is in the real yeah and and a lot
of it is the struggle because that's so
much the reality of what you're having
to deal with and what I wanted what I
want to make sure though is that the
things that you see and that interests
you because see you guys are your the
painters that create the the ink that we
use to do our work and so you know you
see you broke out the melon and so the
thing was he said hey know what we found
was something that was unbelievably
Melanie with the beautiful fuel back and
we think it would be attractive and it
would be valuable for the market and and
that's that's what I'm seeking from it
and and the part about us all struggling
is as real as it can be and and I try to
make light of it cuz otherwise you go
i'ma cry and you know and tissue paper
is expensive so what about you big Jane
what you messing around what direction
do you go with your lines cuz you you
work some some lines that you've had for
a long time but you switch the direction
on them and it's kind of neat because it
lets you swing a picture yeah I mean
what I'd really like to do is do I'll do
the I'll do those fresh hybrids and then
[Music]
try to go through and seed a lot of
plants every time I do anything so then
I think you can go in all these
different directions so when you make
that that fresh hybrid you get you know
if stuff is if stuff is fairly
consistent you start with then you you
get a pretty you get a pretty it's
pretty predictable to know what you're
gonna get but then when you make that f2
you get all the weirdness and then when
you go when you get all the weirdness
then that's where you can really you
know make one thing into a million
things you know so with with some of
them I've tried to take them different
directions and then some of them is just
a real clear direction
like this year I'm really trying to work
on like the root beer stuff that's
really cool because it's it's a trip
like with doing seeds there's a whole
lot of seeds that are really interesting
and they're and they're awesome and like
they all are you know really valid in
the space as far as going okay we need
to have all these things but it's really
a trip because when you go to actually
sell a lot of weed it kind of has to
look a certain way it has to have you
know there has to be something about it
where it's like okay that's shiny that
has people really like a little color to
it as to at least have a silver look if
not dark or purple or blue or red or
whatever you know regular green but
better be really tasty and really stinky
to be able to compete you know so like
the root beer is a cool one because of
the the way it smokes the way it grows
all that stuff so this year I'm trying
to do like a back cross to that clone
twice and the original male I started
with was almost the same thing so it was
already pretty consistent right away and
then going back to it a couple times
made it made it really nice and then
what I'm gonna try to do with that is um
I'll probably go back one more time to
the root beer clone to make it so that
it's like really root beer seed because
it has got more and more frequent when
you backcross not everything does that
if it's too inconsistent throws too much
weird stuff you know but it comes
through so it dominates in the crosses
and and then but I think what I'm gonna
do while it's still just a little more
open at the at the at the two back
crosses I'm probably gonna do a bunch of
out crosses of it this year and then do
the same thing with the cherry limeade
and the reason being that when you get
like if you go to get clones from
somebody you know how it is it's like
you have to everything's cool to have
some like okay I'm gonna have some of
this I'm gonna have some of that but
when people like want units and weight
of something you have to be able to have
something that people look at and even
if they don't know the name its
recognizably what they is in their
paradigm of what's
dank some of the best weed might look
like shoelaces and be all messed up and
look like dr. green spoon or something
you know but when you when you really
want something that you can have in your
bag to people go okay you you just want
that instant yep there it is
and so those are things that do that you
open the bag you I want that so like I'm
trying to do that because when you you
know you want to have plants that grow
well for you as a farmer and then you
need a product that's really gonna be
that thing and that's the whole thing I
was talking about with like with brand
recognitions like people go oh a type a
type of type it's like will hype hype
doesn't last so like I remember when
cookies came out it was like that's hype
it's not good it's like well maybe it's
not as good as it's not as strongest
headband or cam or whatever is your
thing but you're you know it's like if
if it was just hype it wouldn't be here
ten years after I got it it's still here
and all the crosses are still that and
when you really get into it you go okay
this is cool stuff and but the reason
why it's valuable to grow it is because
you know when you finish it you can sell
it like if you're a tomato farmer you
know most people are gonna wind up like
okay this one has shelf life it's good
boom we're gonna grow these Roma's we
want to grow these really cool air loom
rainbow tomatoes but when you go in the
stores only a little bit of those the
over here you got this whole tier of
these Roma's over here what our
beefsteak so ever so we're gonna grow
those so you need things to fit in
people's paradigms so I'm trying to put
out some stuff that's really like people
go oh it's the hype stuff oh it's just
it's another gelato cross it's this or
it's that but it's a trip because if you
don't have something that people on a
knee-jerk reaction will look at and go
that's the stuff that's what everybody
wants then or do you really want to have
350 pounds of it and you you wanna you
want to have a quarter pound for your
head or whatever to share and you know
maybe you got somebody who wants this or
that but you know I'm just trying to
really make sure that like the stuff
that I'm putting out is stuff that when
you're done with it it's what people
come back that's like this last stuff I
released was like I had that peen
the pina a lot of times a CVD plant but
it's super Hardy its structures great it
does will not get p.m. it's like so easy
in such a great you know you could
probably dry farm and I haven't tried
but I have seen my buddy leave the Pina
across cherries that I made in some
three gallon pots basically in a in a
desert in a in a greenhouse that wasn't
being grown in so it was like a hundred
and thirty degree desert in there every
day and the plants he watered him when
they were starts they never grew but
then they butted and they finished and
there was this killer weed in there that
we basically found going to his house
and I was like well that's got value to
you know but but it's weed that when
people you know it originally I was like
it's CBD people only want Kush I'd have
a little bit of it people would show up
and they'd be like no we want more of
those we want that one so that's you
know something try and trying to put
stuff out that's actually like can
really be practical for people that are
farming it's like the sky cuddler Kush
like that's in the conus favorite weed
you know it's like got the knee jerk
okay this is cool I understand that it
smells gas eats but as a grower - it's
really performing you know so that's
just the focus of like the stuff that
I'm working on in general is to be like
that like I love the lime and the lime
is great but the lime is a little bit
more it's a little more leafy when you
grow it it's so I'm trying to work it
into a little bit more different stuff
so that's like cross it back with a og
keeps the nose gets a little meat on the
bones that's what the lime pop cush is
you get the huge plants of your own big
plants so I've been working on that but
then I made like I took like the cherry
limeade f5 and I put it on gelato herb
you know things that you're like oh
that's a stupid but it's like yeah but
that's what people want in their bag to
buy so you you got to have that you know
what I mean so that's kind of the this
stuff I've been I've been trying to work
on more stuff that's like that and then
at the same time I'm always doing my
regular stuff that's for me that I you
know that I that I vibe with even more
but I you know you can't help but but
also vibe with something that you look
at and you go whoa
it's incredible I mean I went to the ego
clash in Holland down there and I saw
all the stuff and everybody I walked up
and they go which one which one you know
would you say would be good out of there
and I missed the part where you smoke
and all that and I just looked in the
case and I was all that number 14 that
looks like that's that's fire right
there I don't know what it is but it
looks good it's got that good old school
Gani
frost it up look and then they announce
the winner and they're like oh the
number 14 gelato 41 or something you
know and I was like oh alright well I
mean you can't really argue with you
can't just like just hype pocky strain
whatever it's you can't you can't you
know yeah I learned that from a guy that
was in fashion and and I've not
historically been known as someone who's
been fashionable so I asked people who
are fashionable about you know fashion
yeah and they said you can't argue with
trends that people do because what
you're saying is that you're not
intelligent enough to recognize that
they made the choice to do it and so
what happens is you cut yourself right
out of the trend and I think that's the
same with what you're talking about the
plants at the bottom line is if if 41
cut wasn't hot then why is it moving at
a rate that's supernatural and it
doesn't mean you need to jump on it but
you need to understand why the white
what I learn from someone is tooth
there's two things in life those that
know how and those that know why and
those that know how work for those that
know why and for us it's the why that's
what's important for us otherwise we end
up just being how how do we make it and
we don't want to understand why are we
making it and what what is that
direction and and I agree man I see all
these modern cultivars that are red hot
and I go I got you some of them are my
personal preference but I don't deny the
fact that it moves at an unbelievable
velocity and when you do objective
testing where I take I take things that
I think are hot and I give them to
people who are in markets that are
unbelievably picky and they have money
which means they have access and I let
them run them to find out compared to
each other which one has the velocity
and then it lets me really understand of
these elites which one really is the
attraction and why and it
so lost lets me understand which ones
didn't I think had the attraction and I
go whoa the market still likes that but
so much of it is that that that visual
appearance and you've been trained to
choose those things because that's what
we've got the last 30 years in cannabis
and I always tell people some of the
strong spot I have a smoke that it
looked like it was a piece of cabbage
run over by a tractor and it got me so
high that I had to drive around the
island three times cuz I couldn't figure
out how to get off the highway on the
on-ramp and I was I was out in Hawaii
and I got so lit that I couldn't really
get off the freeway and I was laughs and
I just said screw it I'll just drive it
out and at some point I'll come down and
I'll be able to figure out how do you
get off the freeway you know and what I
wasn't laughing at the moments I was
like whoa I am scorched but if I could
get my hands on that again I loved it
but the thing was you know I challenge
you to sell it because it looked like it
was some cabbage run over by a tractor
yeah yeah yeah so that's why that's what
it's like you know like oh yeah gelato
just gelato cross you know what I mean
like yeah I made a gelato cross I made a
shirt cross like the mail I started with
those f5 and those generations to get to
add to get to f3 took a while out of the
twos to get to the four took a while out
of the threes it's not like I just want
one two three four five boom a gelato
and even that is a lot of work but you
know going along the way to go okay cool
we got rid of this we got rid of that I
mean I think you probably grew some of
the early cherry generations that I had
that have all the weird
herckel recessives in it that pop out
with that still have little duck foot
and they're teeny and they won't grow
and the weed is amazing incredible I
already think you've got to get both and
then so now like I have cherry lime F
sixes and if you grow those they're all
big fast vegging plants they all have
the same bud structure they all have the
super high 5% terpenes at SC 18 22
percent THC real consistent all the same
doesn't mold doesn't break doesn't care
if it's windy you know and then take
that like what I use to make that and
then that was out crossed
to these you know height whatever and so
then you know with that then you at
least know you've got some
predictability there and at the same
time you have marketability so that you
you you're bringing because you've got a
there's only so many enthusiasts and all
of us enthusiasts can go ahead and go
okay cool yeah this is this really rare
weed thing you know like this is this
trippy like it's it's out there like um
like Caleb right now is working with
that Australian bastard cannabis and
people are like why would you want this
and I'm like if you really like plants
you want that because it's not the other
one you have but you're not gonna go
okay I'm gonna switch over my hoops to
this people are gonna go once it's
trimmed in the bag it probably isn't
even different because the leaves are
cut off and the leaves are what's cool
and it has valuable things and you want
to have it in your arsenal I looked
right out it and went if I can get a
plant that's like a bomb-ass Afghani to
grow with this size leaves you're gonna
have yields that are gonna crush
everything because if you can get a fat
bud on something that veges faster than
that with a tiny little leaf it's just
gonna get Sun right to the bud the whole
way she can have these huge buds like
this but instead of being on the end
with these big fat leaves that block
everything out you're gonna have them
six feet long so that's where you get
like the cool stuff and those things are
valuable for breeders but you buy a pack
of seeds you're like dude I want to grow
this and maybe I want to find a clone or
I just want to grow these and just have
good bud
like I try to make sure that my seed you
plant a row of it I have to be able to
plant a row of it and have 10 or 20 of
them and hundreds or three hundreds or
whatever and look at him and go okay
cool I'm glad I grew that in my garden
so that's what I tried to do that's what
I try to put out you know but with the
new the new stuff too was it's I'm
trying to like make sure it's you know
always cuz the cutting edge turps and
something that that fits into the
picture remarketed yeah j-just do a
smart business yeah and that's why
that's what I was saying about what
better to loop back that's what was cool
about the root beer is it almost looks
like a cookies or it looks like it's
something like that but it's cuz it has
black affi in it way back in it in Hindu
and then it has the headband the la cush
like Mandal had back in the day and so
those it makes it like this ultra potent
thing like if you're used to smoke and
cookies and you smoke this you're like
okay this is super satisfying smoke you
know it breaks up a little better and
it's got you know just really killer so
those are those are ones that are that
are going and that's the that's the
thing maintaining those cool that cool
all that meat stuff and then being able
to go okay here's what we need to be
competitive because we do have to be
super competitive and all you really
need is a plant that is that special and
people will go oh okay I got it like
it's good it's great for everyone to
share everything it's great for everyone
to share especially these bulk these
these bulk gene pools you know what I
mean but like if you have your own clone
and everyone's like all you can't get
like maybe you don't want to give that
clone away cuz maybe you want to have
something that you're like no I know how
to do this you might talk to someone's
grandma she's like sorry you can't have
my cookie recipe no because it's not
want to have this I want to win the I
want to win the contest at the whatever
you know what I mean or whatever it's
for like there's a there's a there's
something to that you know so like
definitely everyone's got a share but it
there's there's a huge edge to being
able to go okay I have this thing and
I'm the only one with it
and it's something for everyone to think
about that find that plant where you
know you you're you might not be able to
sell sfv you're like I owe you I was
getting you know three grand for this
sfv now people want to give me 600
everything's crashed but then you go to
talk to somebody in they're like dude I
have this one and no matter what
everybody my buddies got this for a Mont
diesel it's like pre sour diesel diesel
you know like I don't know if it really
is but that's how it is it's like just
straight like super skunk it smells like
skunk and then underneath it's just like
clove and it's super super bomb and he
just calls it diesel and anybody who
looks at that and they tell you oh sorry
this is good indoor but I'm only gonna
give you a thousand for it you're like
cool where's the next guy
because one out of three people who
smell this shit are gonna say dude what
do you want like if I have that I can
sell that to people for whatever I want
to ask for it and it's just because
people don't all have it if everyone has
it people see a bad version of it now
all of a sudden it's whatever it is it's
cool its cush but there's definitely
like a value and that of looking for
your own thing having it and you know
being able to being able to run with
something that's you know got a little
edge on it but so that that's what I'm
always doing trying to make stuff like
that I took all right G that's
absolutely right and you know like when
I look around this room I think what the
reality is is that so many of us like if
you think of it's a race or whatever a
racetrack so many of us are actually
like lapping the whole industry that
it's easy to look like you're behind but
we're really all just like so far ahead
and say what gene was saying is like
sometimes you gotta you know give them
what they want and so you know you do a
few draw two crosses or make sure
everything is you know a certain THC
level for for the year but never ever
give up on those cultivars that like
that mean everything to you I mean I
can't like back god eight nine years ago
people would give me such a hard time
really why do you have seeds that make
purple cannabis everybody hates purple
they were like oh it's it's because it's
deficient your your weeds purple because
it's deficient in whatever something
they tell me and I'd be like no it's
it's not and this is like so the trends
and I guess the whole lapping thing like
we're always like a one-lap ahead and
sometimes it can look like we're kind of
behind the pack but really we're just
like ahead of it and nobody knows it yet
so I think does for gene
so ya know same thing you got you got a
lot of killer stuff you you you work
some interesting directions since I've
met you and I like that you know you've
been you've been really putting together
some interesting combinations and the
number of people that bring me material
that you've done I got spend my job
right now someone said man I got some
kill equilibrium working I said oh nice
what is it
and I laugh because each one of those
samples was radically different than the
other because the lines were different
and I I like that when I see people have
separation and what they're doing and
and your desires to go these different
trends and so you've been you put some
cool stuff what we've been what are you
doing going on I'm I think this young
and shy dig deeper into I've got so many
seeds and so many things I've collected
over the years and I kind of want it I
like that branching out in a whole new
direction just like kind of outside way
somewhere where maybe it's something
that's been sitting on the Shelf that
I've been meaning to get to forever and
I haven't decided anything I'm gonna
work with yet this year but there's
there's a few contenders the Malawi
lines did really well you know over the
years there's been a lot of people
coming back saying the African Orange
was something that was really mold
resistant for them and I've seen some of
the flowers if somebody you know brought
me some of the flowers today from
Humboldt that was that was just probably
one of the most citrusy versions African
Orange I've ever seen and that's
certainly a direction I want to go in as
things that do well on the coast because
I've been in you know I was in Santa
Cruz for so many years and it's it's
hard to grow almost anything in a lot of
the areas around that County that's
actually where I first saw some mean
genes work as I had a friend out there
that we kind of shared a little patch
one year and he I guess I guess he he
had gotten some seeds from you and he
grew the root beer and we grew the the
PK
your cherry lines and it was like oh
cool I'm I forget some other and they
were just beautiful just the Oracle line
was insane especially in light of what
you were talking about with the the bag
appeal just like there were just these
bulbous buds that just just looked
amazing and probably the probably the
cherry lime at everything was was the
favorite at the end of the year just
just getting to smoke it and you know
the root beers were a little later but
they just when they when they filled in
they were like just so Turkey and and
and enjoyable and and last year your
Humboldt dream was my buddy's biggest
plants in the garden last year he's got
a picture of him just in the Anderson
Valley with this plant that's just like
gigantic
you know so he's like oh I'm doing this
one every year now so you guys kudos to
you guys for you know putting out the
quality work and I think yeah this year
you know I'm gonna probably pull out
some of the other Malawi hybrids maybe
I've seen a lot a lot of buzz around the
chocolate Malawi which is one that I
haven't been working with as much in the
past and so maybe pull that one out I
think that's probably one at the top of
the list
is the chocolate hash berry to the
heirloom malawi and you know the the
glue line is one I've been working for a
little while is trying to find a
reliable glue back cross and find a male
out of that that I can hit two things
and get that you know chocolatey gassy
aroma and taste out of the hybrids that
come through and you know maybe we're
gonna pull off some some crazy land
racism should I work with some you know
some wild some wild stuff and you know
try to try to see what you know what
else we could put out there that that is
gonna be unique this it's all about
setting yourself apart in this industry
and yeah like you're saying maybe you
find a cut that you don't want to share
with people and I would love to hear
that somebody found something out of my
work that that really worked well for
them and they wanted to keep around for
years and years and and and maybe it
helped keep them afloat
in in
tough times and so so certainly we're
gonna keep working for mold resistance
which is you know even more of an issue
nowadays with you know the testing
requirements and you know some of the
other projects you know might might
include you know maybe maybe some of the
other Malawi's or you know I've kind of
got a rough sketch but but we haven't we
haven't nailed anything down yet you
know I think get back with the team and
see what everybody else wants to do too
and you know maybe go back and look at
because I try to I try catalog
everything all the all the seeds you
know everybody that gave me C's today we
traded I'm gonna go and try to catalog
and keep keep a list of everything and
you know you do that long enough and
you're gonna have a nice nice collection
you know I hope I hope everybody starts
getting into more of their own like Fino
hunts and and finding things that do
well in your local situation which you
know whatever property that you might
have might be even totally different
from your neighbors parcel because
they're on the other side of the ridge
you know or or maybe maybe the people
down the road or you know a little
closer to a valley and they get more
wind or you know so so it's a it's great
to be here and see oh you know all the
different success stories from different
strains because that definitely has a
big effect on my personal you know
decisions of what I'm gonna go and breed
with is when I go and talk to the
community or I go to you know the
Emerald cup or you know you know see
somebody out you know you know in town
or something and they'd be it so oh well
you know you're you're you know sour
orange or you know your your Grandaddy
orange or you know maybe one of these
you know dream queen blue or this or
that like did really well for me and
that's I love I love hearing everybody's
stories of what they've done with my
genetics and what what they really liked
just like you know I've got folks that
rave about these two guys genetics that
that they've tried in previous years so
you know just yeah keep the stories
coming so awesome and you know what I
like is that it's rare that most most
people in nowadays what I learned the
internet is where you talk shit
so you can get recognition cuz otherwise
you don't exist and unless you're
flapping your mouth throwing rocks at
someone else you're not even real person
and we're sitting there hanging out and
you're talking about your experiences
with genes work back in the day and and
that's work with your boys stuff and you
know it's just it's just cool appreciate
it thank you
[Applause]