[Music]
hello everyone thank you so much for
coming to hear our little discussion and
I'll let dr. Andreas start with telling
her a little bit our telling you a
little bit about her story then we'll
kind of tell here a little bit about
mine and didn't you'll be able to notice
the difference of where we're coming for
but also talking about one particular
topic so incredibly different we agree
in a lot of fundamental issues that are
germane to the topic today which is
understanding sort of the cannabis
strain
fingerprint so even though I sort of
even the more bio medical background I
believe that truly understanding
cannabis as medicine starts with the
plant and so in my role at G B Sciences
we have been dedicated to creating
standardized raw materials that we
provide to customers we have operations
in both Nevada and in Louisiana where we
hold licenses to cultivate produce oils
and make finished products for sale in
those markets and so when I'm talking to
you today I'm wearing two hats I'm
wearing the Hat of we're part of the
industry we're part of the supply chain
of cannabis materials that go to the
patients in medical markets as well as
to the folks in adult use markets like
Nevada but at the same time at GB
Sciences we've also taken the position
that it's not enough to just create
standardized products that we also
wanted to verify safety and potential
effectiveness through research and so to
that end we have sponsored research with
nine different universities where we're
trying to get at you the cannabis plant
is full of lots of different compounds
and anyone who tells you cannabis is one
thing is missing the point okay so we're
trying to get at this great mystery of
how
you align strains with particular
diseases or particular symptoms that we
need to treat and the only way to do
that is in controlled trials but those
take many formats in different just
jurisdictions so that's kind of a
complicated thing but today what we're
here to talk about is strains and the
chemical components of strains which
we're calling a fingerprint but - but do
you know that we're coming at this both
from a place I'm coming at this from
both the place of we grow as well as we
do research so it has a little bit of a
different I have a different perspective
on it than pepper but I think we agree
on a lot of the essential things so
pepper very well said I'm coming from
the angle of I am a naturopathic
holistic practitioner in Humboldt County
so most of the patients I have or
clients that I have or students that I
have in the cannabis program for the
cannabis holistic Institute are coming
in with multiple different dis ease dis
element discomfort and we are trying to
put them in the last eight years in
combination to a particular strain or
cultivar that's going to be helpful for
that particular ailment I've been lucky
enough to be doing that for the last
eight years the thing that kind of
guided me in that direction was because
I had my own discomfort within my body
and just to name a few in the last seven
years that I've been working with
physically just my own personal stories
include PTSD anxiety cancer tumor
endometriosis reproductive issues I mean
it's a slew of them God chose the right
person cuz then I was in Humboldt County
running around on farms asking for
particular strains or cultivars from
friends of mine that I knew grow organic
or grew organic and I mostly focused on
doing non psychoactive CBD so that's
what kind of got me into what I'm doing
now and educating people around the
world and working with patients and
clients and students around the world so
I'm coming from you know more of
Humboldt County organic farmer boutiques
trains growing that industry and
cannabis culture in that way because
most of those people I've been working
with for so very long and giving them a
plan
form to speak on their particular
expertise that may have gotten lost in
the shuffle without some kind of program
to really have speakers allowed to talk
on there you know but they're best at so
anyways that's what we're gonna do it
now we're gonna talk about um what's in
a strain the cannabis fingerprint in
Humboldt County and I'm sure many of you
have understood that it is about this
it's not just particularly about the
strain or the cultivar it's about the
whole cannabinoid system and which
particular ones do what with what
particular body systems so that's kind
of how I started working with different
cannabinoids I was working with CBD THC
a raw form plant for a book so and so on
and then it's about connecting those two
with your body structures so today we're
going to be talking about the cannabis
active ingredients and do you want to
take it for a second yeah I do add a
little bit to the idea of strains so I
know that stray names are very near and
dear to the breeders out there that have
work to perfect their favorite ones and
the ones that are this is Sally fun but
one of the things that we're going to
advocate for as a part I'm a last part
of this industry is that strain names so
there's a reliance on strain names from
regulators from our marketing campaigns
that I think does patients a disservice
because strain names do not always
capture the active ingredients that are
in the plant and ultimately it will be
the active ingredients and I don't mean
single active ingredients I mean the
whole collection out of the potential
480 active ingredients in a cannabis
strain is that energy yeah so we need to
keep track of that and patients it
patient it's hard because humans want
things to be simple right it's like part
of human nature but cannabis has a plant
part of its power is that it isn't
simple so we have got to we've got to
find a way to communicate the complexity
of active ingredients in plant based
products with our consumers with
patients in a way that they can
understand okay so and that is the big
divide we've got to get across because
right now what they're relying on when
they go into dispensed
is a well-meaning but tender who's gonna
tell them about into couch and sativa
right and you know and some other like
lore right but one of the things that we
that we try to do is we're data-driven
I'm a scientist right so we did two
studies one of the studies we did in
2014 in California in conjunction with a
third part at third-party testing lab
and what we were asking the question of
it we took over 20,000 strain profiles
that you know the potency analysis of
the cannabinoids and terpenoids that
will define something called a chemo bar
or a chemical variation okay so remember
cannabis isn't one thing there are
certain cannabis strains that fall into
these different chemical variations in
2014 in California when we did it there
were 25 chemo bars we did the same thing
in Nevada which is the state that our
primary location is in and we test it
we've also partnered with a third-party
independent testing lab there and there
were we're looking at I believe no quote
me on this something like 40,000 so I'm
sorry something like 4,000 strain
records and we published the second
study the one in Nevada in the journal
called cannabis and cannabinoid research
back in May and what it showed was
during the medical only period in Nevada
there were three hundred and ninety six
different strain names but when you did
the chemical variation analysis there
were three and 90% of all the samples
tested were in a single chemical
variation that was high THC and almost
and very little in the way of minor
cannabinoids and terpenoids we sent them
off to have genetic analysis done
because you know it's possible that
because in Nevada you have to grow in a
greenhouse and there's a lot of
convergence and how we grow we were
trying to give people the benefit of the
doubt that maybe the chemicals were
aligned because we were growing under
the same conditions but on the genetic
level there three hundred and ninety-six
strain names correlated with twelve
genetic variations and blue dream which
is an incredibly popular strain name was
present in all 12 genetics
so I think that if in a system where we
rely on strain names to sell things to
patients who are looking for the same
results strain names are doing them a
disservice because if you're in Nevada
during that medical only period and you
picked up Blue Dream off the shelf
somewhere you had a one in 12 chance
that it was the same thing as you've got
last time you bought it so anyway I'm
going to come from because where I'm at
in Humboldt County we are
I mean pridefully so you ask anyone
that's growing pot in the Humboldt
County we are organic we're biodynamic
or focused we are proud of our strains
we are proud of our cultivars or variety
of cannabis we know what we're doing or
they know what they're doing I don't
grow any longer but they know what
they're doing and they've been doing it
for generations and generations now as a
naturopath when a client comes to me
asking for something I love the idea of
saying ok you need this this this this
and this fingerprint this particular
cannabinoid system like combination but
you give that to the average client you
give that to the average person they're
not gonna know what to do with that so
to break it down I get what you're
saying and I get where we're going but
for the average person not even in this
room they don't know what they're doing
and they're going to have to find a
direction strain name is the best thing
we can do right now now testing those
making sure that those plants are truly
that before the dispensary gets that
that's a whole nother topic right and
that's what we want to happen but we
have to trust our growers that's another
reason why we go organic and we know our
farmers that we're getting our cannabis
from and boutique's training is for me
being from Humboldt County that's the
way we're pushing it that's what we're
seeing and we're seeing it happen all
the time and it's phenomenal and I think
that's what really gives this pick no
the panel of the two of us a difference
in perspective because I don't get we
disagreement for example you're coming
from in Nevada
data you know it's a commodity okay
we're fully into adult use
and you know I can't swear and we grow
ourselves and we're really proud of our
Jenny couch thank you very much there's
a point for it there's a valid reason
for it but that said I still can imagine
I can imagine something different than
what we have right now I can imagine a
way to break down the complexity of the
active ingredients into a way that
there's a simple pattern recognition
that patients can help yeah I definitely
agree with you on that for certain for
certain it's going to take a shift yeah
for people to recognize we need to talk
about the minor cannabic yes and that's
what we're starting to really educate at
least in my field particular clients who
are needing things say for their nervous
system which of those particular minor
cannabinoids work best from that and
then we can refer them off to strain
dosage use whether they're gonna be
juicing when they're gonna non
psychoactive tincture whether they're
gonna do a concentrate then we kind of
do that but right now it's just like
piecing that all together at least from
where I'm standing because I'm doing it
as a private practice yeah so so - so to
our first point about the cannabis
active ingredients I think right now
because there's been the most research
on THC and CBD that's where people feel
the most comfort and where I think
people is going to understand the
significance better so right now there
is a reliance on information about THC
and CBD and I think that's appropriate
given where we are in our research but
this is where I see the future and the
future will include information about
minor cannabinoids and terpenoids
important okay so a study that I was not
involved in but that I heard at Ken mad
two years ago there was a trial
happening in Israel where they had
patients they were all children who had
epilepsy and they were being given coal
plant extract from a cannabis strain
that naturally had a 22 1 CBD to THC
ratio and because they didn't want to be
reliant on a single farmer they gave to
farmers the original strain and they
told the farmers we're gonna test this
and if the THC to c8t zbd ratios aren't
the same when you hand over the products
we
accept it that'll be our quality control
staff so everything was going good the
first first part of the trial there the
children were having fewer episodes
there was no huge behavioral problems or
adverse events but then something
happened midway through and there was
suddenly a huge amount like one part of
the patients were suddenly having an
increased amount of behavioral events
like just really dramatic like punching
people and just really off the rails to
the point where they ended up shutting
this to trial down and when they did the
backwards analysis they found that all
of the samples that were provided to the
children had that right ratio of 228 to
1 but when they did a deeper analysis
and they looked at the profiles of
ingredients beyond THC and CBD in one
farmers crop it was equal to what was in
the original strain and one there was a
completely different profile of minor
cannabinoids and terpenoids and clearly
I don't think this farmer was trying to
hurt children right but it's much like
if you're babysitting for someone's
goldfish and they die you go to the
store and you look for the closest match
of goldfish that you can find unless
you're a better human being than me and
you have children and they found
something that matched you know they
couldn't tell from it from looking at
the tea the CBD to THC ratio that it was
any different but you better believe
when they did the profiles beyond that
they were incredibly different so what
that shows is that while it's important
that we're monitoring the THC and CBD
down the road as our understanding
becomes more complete those other
compounds are incredibly important in
whole plant extracts and I'm it is my
belief and I think we share this that
whole plant medicine has potentially
greater clinical value than these
individualized compounds but we got to
be careful it's a double-edged sword
more molecules can mean potentially
better effects or unexpected effects so
I think I think thank you for all that I
think that cannabis itself what we need
to remember is that it creates
homeostasis in the body which then
allows the body's systems to regulate
and heal themselves so whether you're
getting it across the board I don't
think it's going to
I mean obviously and into where you're
at but I think that's the most important
part is to focus on cannabis as a whole
sure plant and getting it in that
direction I think and I can go off on
tangents about that but that's not in
our topics today so let's get back on
we're going to talk about terpene and
why terpenes are so important and the
terpene can canopy which is so very
important for patients and clients and
all of us to recognize it's not just
about the cannabinoids it's also about
the terpene that are in that particular
plant so for example you know if you
have particular terpenes in particular
cannabinoids those two together will
isolate and be best for a particular
body systems that's direction I'm going
specifically and of course they're gonna
be good for everything but if you're
really dialing it in if you're really
neatly in a haystack like I've been
doing for the last eight years those are
the kind of things that I'm looking for
in a cannabis strain or variety or
cultivar and so back to the what I was
talking about before where we did the
the the data analysis to try to define
like the chemical variations for the
study that we did in California those 25
different chemo VARs that we identified
were all distinguished based on a major
and a minor terpene the CBD and THC
levels were actually sort of
insignificant to the analysis and that
even holds true in the in the nevada
analysis we did that the differences
that we're gonna see in between the
different strains are really in the
terpenes and i believe that's also true
from a clinical side and it also is what
naturally so for people who love whole
plant in the raw form those terpenes are
also what adds to your enjoyment right
so I think terpenes are an under valued
resource that we have in cannabis and
it's something that we are also looking
at on the research side so one of the
things that was known for a long time is
that cannabinoids have interactions in
your body with receptors well in our
research we found that it sends true for
terpenes we've identified specific
terpenes and the specific receptors in
our bodies where they're interacting so
they have just as much greater potential
for being real effective medicines as as
the other components in the plant that
we that we're have been
studying more extensively over time yeah
in cannabis farmers in Humboldt County
and around the world I'm sure but like
we eke out on that right there
we've been doing it for generations and
generations of finding this particular
plant as this particular you know minor
cannabinoid with this particular
champion and this works fit this I mean
they are like intense up there oh it's
really really great to be a part of that
community okay so let's talk we had this
discussion about sativa and indica and
how to you know currently this has been
like the hot button thing for for a
while now most people think either
sativa or indica now about five years or
more there was so much hybrid in
happening that it didn't really make
that much sense and so a big huge like a
huge group of people are staying away
from sativa and indica but those people
who are coming you know from the very
ground up those consumers that have
never used cannabis or have been afraid
to use cannabis this is the terminology
this is the language that they're using
even though we're trying to stay away
from that and explain to them it is more
about the cannabis fingerprint than
anything else the the main consumer this
is what they're looking for they're
going into the Spencer E and saying I
want something that's indica dominant
well where where are we going from that
now that's an issue so it's more about
really educating people I'm you're
shaking your head what do you got so and
so so adding to that so I've had the
opportunity to go to these conferences
including one by the International
cannabinoid Research Society which is
the longest-running cannabis research
you know geek fest that you could think
of and and but the cool thing about
going is that these are these I got to
hear botanists who've been studying
cannabis for like 45 years talk about
indica and sativa and they've done a lot
of genetic analysis and so because
they're hearing feedback like you know
patients get told indica in the couch
and things like that they know that
that's out there they decided to go
ahead and try to address that using
science so I just saw a talk recently
where they they were looking at samples
from the United States Canada and across
the world and they were trying to say is
indica sativa a real phenotype can
you actually use that as a way to
recommend to patients and unfortunately
what they found that from genetic level
most of the things for session
specifically in the United States are
mostly hybrid so it's really hard to
lean on those those old paradigms about
indica and sativa but I think that there
is something that we can take away from
the indica sativa myth which is I think
that indica and sativa are sort of
correlating with profiles of terpenes so
I think that if we can certainly just
reimagine that there's still some truth
to it it's just that rather than
ascribing it to the word sativa or
indica it's really about the profile of
terpenes because I think that there's
almost a one-to-one correlation there
yeah I definitely agree with you on that
absolutely now it's about educating the
student as a client yeah the community
that you're in on looking for a
particular terpene that works with your
body system right
Linna Lowell being in lavender which is
calming and relaxing you're gonna look
for a fruity purpley yummy cannabis the
smell that has that same entire like
terpene profile it's gonna do the same
thing for you so it's about educating
people on a much much deeper level than
just like hey let me grab that one jar
that says indica which from what you're
saying might not be so let's move on I
there is something that I want to talk
with you about about hemp and cannabis
this is happening a lot in our
communities it's been happening for a
very long time with the explosion of CBD
that we started to see a few years ago
it's really interesting whenever I
talked to patients
I talked to clients and I talked to
students I talked to people around the
world on what they believe that is can
you from your perspective of being a
grower and focusing in that direction in
science more clinical I want that
described very clearly for our audience
okay so I'm sure that for a lot of
people I'm gonna say it's not new but
we'll just get it out there so we have a
platform a common sort of place to start
talking from so hemp and cannabis are
the same plant scientifically it was the
government who's creating a few buckets
for them right and it's it's based on
artificial designation
of the level of THC makes one hemp and
one cannabis but they're the same thing
but that's it that doesn't mean there's
not phenotypic differences much like
among dogs some varieties of dogs you
have your large dogs your small dogs
working dogs and lap dogs and you know
all everything in between cannabis is
the same so breeders of industrial have
have over time move the properties of
industrial hemp so that they have long
fibers and so that they are good at what
they're supposed to do which is be
building materials and such right but
and that's why I'm at because the
consumers are looking at CBD based
products and from that type of heavy
industry exactly exactly whereas that
make schema in general cannabis has been
used more medically will say and reckon
and as a product for consumption
so therefore the properties that the
breeders were looking for were different
they were looking for higher production
of oil and things that you know higher
THC levels let's just be real and so
there's been a drift between what is
classically called industrial hemp and
classically called cannabis but they're
still the same print and they will still
breed right so that that shows you that
they're the same but that said what
we're finding is that in the world there
are pockets of germ plasm or people who
still have in plant repositories ancient
strains of cannabis and that are sort of
it not as differentiated and there are
people in the world like the colorado
hemp project that people who are trying
to really nurture
cannabis strains that have THC below
that limit that makes them makes them
happen but that are still good producers
of oil and but these are really isolated
people in the world in general if you're
talking about stuff you order off the
internet it could be industrial hemp
from China or it could be you know and
so what I think most of the people who
order these products don't understand is
that CBD within the industry is more
controlled than out there in the
marketplace so but absolutely and I see
people come to me all the time with
convenience store or CBD and it drives
me absolutely nuts as I travel around
the country yeah
thing is they're getting the best they
can get and I kind of say what's like a
raw food desert if you're in the middle
of the country and all you can have is a
salad from fast food restaurant at least
it's a salad but let me educate you let
me sit with you for 20 minutes and tell
you why that's not the right thing for
your body system and so that's where I
get super passionate you guys want to
threw it in there real quick
yeah okay so let's talk about the
entourage effect we had this discussion
the other day and we were on this topic
for a very long period of time this is
the hot button word a lot of people as
I'm interviewing them or speaking with
them I also do a podcast and so I
interview people this is the word that
they're using and we had this great
conversation about it's not just about
THC it's like the entourage effect makes
you think that there's one shiny star
and everything else is just surrounding
it right Oh show yeah yeah okay but do
you had a great story that I'd love for
you to share with me again if you'd like
sure yeah so one of the things that
we've done in our basic research is
we've been trying to take the complexity
of whole plants and then through the use
of things that are more common to the
pharmaceutical industry because they're
called high-throughput screening and
medical model is an animal testing and
such like that we've been trying to
determine what what assortment of
ingredients from a from a whole plant
extract do you absolutely need to be
able to have high clinical value and
what we're finding is that single
ingredients barely move the needle when
it comes to clinical effectiveness the
power of whole plant medicine comes in
the combinations of compounds that are
in those plants when when we start our
analysis and when we start to look at
the readouts of if we measure the
ingredients separately most of them
don't have any signal at all so we
realized that if we didn't have access
to the whole plants we never would have
found the right mixtures and so but what
we're finding is in most of the pet so
we've also filed patents on these and
that we're doing them for specific
conditions like pet Parkinson's disease
Alzheimer's disease neuropathic pain
cardiovascular diseases but one of the
common themes that our research seems to
be that THC isn't always the star and in
fact in all of those conditions that I
just mentioned
isn't a part of the formulation that we
ended up with when we did a screen CBD
is important in South about 25 percent
so what we're seeing and this is really
early research is that the next wave of
cannabis medicines is really going to
leverage minor cameras and terpenes a
whole lot more and specifically in
mixtures and nobody haven't many big
pharma companies that have stepped up
and say you know what I'm gonna go to
the FDA with something that has nine
ingredients but we are we've got a
pharmaceutical composition that we're
going to try to take the FDA next year
he's got nine and group active
ingredients and so but what we can what
we're trying to show is that the power
of this kind of medicine is in the
combinations and we've done a lot of
like the geeky science stuff to show you
need all of those ingredients and that's
what you should take away from whole
plant medicine it's not just that it has
THC or CBD it's that it has the whole
assortment and that for molecular
synergy Molecular synergy so we've tried
it stucks not call it entourage effect
and try to call it molecular synergy
these molecules work better together
than they do apart and that's the
powerful plant medicine yeah it's fair
yeah okay I think that we are about
wrapped up and you had a couple okay
well we can continue go if there's any
questions that you may have we'll take a
few for Q&amp;A can we go right into Q&amp;A all
right going again yep go ahead is that
if we could if we could encourage people
to do one thing is try to find ways to
label beyond CBD and THC I know it's
gonna be hard but I've there are in
different states I've been talking with
people who are either using color coding
or there's lots of different tricks that
we can use to help break down the
complexity so that when patients go to a
dispensary they can get the same thing
every time right that's super important
for maintaining their health and so but
none of this is going to happen without
patient education and money has to come
from somewhere so we need to we need to
as an industry be putting rolling back
into patient education and basic
research
[Laughter]
[Applause]
does it affect so does the delivery
method of a turn hundred percent of okay
so what what would you talk to me tell
me what well that was it chirping is the
delivery system Atlanta stand a Charpy
fact the the effect on the body of the
terpene absolutely what would be in your
opinion like three of the best delivery
methods for turkeys to get you by system
it would depend on to make an effect
okay it would depend on the particular
body system that you were wanting work
with so let's narrow that down saying
like the nervous system for example if
you're doing it for the nervous system
the best delivery method would possibly
be depending on the person the age I
mean there's a lot of things that go
into that you have to dial it in but
once you do that then you look at
possible tinctures tinctures are going
to be the easiest way to get that into
the body system the digestive system
works completely different though if
you're doing an edible and it breaks
down in your intestines that's a
completely different thing we've all had
that happen we've had the brownie and
then you know three hours later and then
four hours later sibling was great
sibling was great I work mostly with non
psychoactive cannabis and so getting
those particular the body system or the
the way that the dosage method that I
suggest for most people are sublinguals
tinctures and topicals but it depends on
what particular body system is needing
that medicine right so from the producer
side there's some challenges with
terpenes terpenes as chemicals are
lighter and so when you're trying to
prepare cannabis based product so they
just naturally go into the air right so
no co there is a no so there is a real
challenge to so if you have a whole
plant if you're talking about flour then
this is less of a problem right like
what will matter there is how it was
cured because you can use a lot of
terpenes depending upon how that that
raw plant material is cured
and process before it gets into the bag
or jar right but for terpenes when it
comes to extraction different extraction
methods usually the terpenes to end up
in a different fraction or different
part of the equation from the
cannabinoids so it's yeah so that's
where some people are getting creative
with like the juicing and stuff so that
so you're taking a raw plant and juicing
probably is going to give you the most
natural blend of the terpenes that were
in the original plant however you know
if you want a more convenience of some
of these other methods what producers
have to do is you have to then add them
back usually because in an attraction
method usually likes at the end up in
different places so in the final product
you have to add them back and then with
respect to their absorption into the
body that's challenging too because like
I said nursing one of the most common
terpenes out there is the smallest and
the most likely to end up in the air
great so yeah in some of the trials that
we're doing we're showing that has and
other people know this too is that it
has a high potential for pain relief but
how do you actually get it into the
product that you're trying to take and
how do you you how do you not lose that
the terpenes yes yeah so one of the
things that we're doing but this is
still experimental is we're doing
something called creating nanoparticles
nanoparticles make them heavier and
compatible and they increase the
bioavailability but like I said these
are sort of next-gen type stuff but one
of the things to be careful of right now
with the stuff you're consuming if you
want to make sure there's terpenes in
there as figure out how they processed
it the thing that's closest to fresh and
raw is going to be the closest to the
real terpene profile yeah and read
labels I think we touched on it a little
bit but I think that we're really
pushing getting everything tested know
what is in your product know what's in
your product there's so many times I go
and I ask someone to go into dispensary
or I go in myself and I look at the
label and it just says this percentage
Tse this percentage CBD and I said what
plant did this come from
what is the terpene profile what's the
cannabis fingerprint it's not on there
yeah so how can this be good for this
particular ailment that I'm trying to
you know get down to the and one of the
things that's true so make sure we're
advocates and as
producers in producing single strain
whole plant extracts but those are super
rare okay and so you know so there's got
to be also feedback to the people who
are creating the products and to the
only the whole system has to understand
that there is a demand for that because
right now the kinds of things that
people ask for in dispensaries are
usually pretty straightforward but if
we're ever going to get beyond where we
are today in sort of the next gen of
what cannabis medicine can be it's not
just on our side we can make these
products but if nobody buys them and if
we haven't educated people to understand
why they need to buy them we'll never
get out of this phase well to the next
phase where cannabis medicines are
considered of course we're using
cannabis for this that's where we need
to be it's coming we're just educating
at which in the education I have a
question of alkaline water and cannabis
a combination of how applying water can
open up and give more oxygen to the
plant to consume I want to know if you
guys have any studies or heard anything
about that I have been approached by a
vendor who provides out the water but I
have not seen studies that support
claims just from Agassi I'm just saying
I don't have any evidence to evaluate
alright if I would tell you from a
logical perspective I would imagine it
would be really healing because it's
very healing to the human body yes right
but there is no studies that I know of
yeah thank you for that question just
I've been hearing about flavonoids is
that a different term is that something
else I just read it that's better than
aspirin or something cuz we read that
too and very exciting yeah so we're big
we're being advocates of learning all
the compounds of the plant that are
potentially active so like when I quoted
this there's a study that showed that
there's over 480 compounds in the
cannabis plant that could be potential
drugs because they have bio activity and
so there's the cannabinoids there's the
terpenes but there's also the flavonoids
and there's other compounds too that are
that are in that commission so but
here's the thing the studies are so
early yet but I think that's gonna be
one of them are active areas of research
and to that GB is actually sponsored
trial what we're doing in with the
University of Athens
Greece where we're doing something
called metabolomic analysis where we're
looking where we've defined that these
plant strains seem to be good at this
and we're looking at not just the can of
- and terpenes that are in there but
what are the other compounds that we
don't normally measure that could
potentially have clinical value so I
think you're right that is gonna be some
brand new drug categories which will be
pretty awesome dr. small Howard did you
say that Mersin as a as a as a terpene
is good for pain relief today that is
what we've our work is still in
preclinical meaning we've done salivates
and we're doing animal trials right now
but the other thing that we've found is
that we were able to demonstrate that
mercy and a couple of the other terpenes
binds directly to receptors in the human
body that regulate pain so it's not just
we put some stuff in there and it seems
to work we were looking at the molecular
mechanism and then we've also used
nanoparticles to help because mercy was
so hard to deal with we put we put these
compounds into nanoparticles so it's
easier to orally dose them without them
floating into the air so my question was
I just wanted to make sure if you
correctly cuz you know it's on the prop
65 list right know that it is yeah there
are two marijuana smoke and mersin are
the two things in cannabis that that's
why we have to put the prop 65 warnings
and so I was just wondering if you knew
why I don't with that but that's
something I want to look into and write
a letter okay right so that's
interesting yeah we have time for one
more question yeah
a great talk dr. Nathan Schramm Here I
am in the sunscreen business as one of
my businesses and we we make a sunscreen
that's mineral based but um nano is a
big no-no in sunscreen and the European
Union is is regulating it heavily
because nano you know it passes through
cell membranes we don't know where it
ends up even in the environment for in
terms of like zinc oxide and titanium
dioxide which are in sunscreens it can
deposit into the coral reefs and be
damaging I'm wondering if if any of you
have concerns about nano and cannabis
and terpenes so let me address that so
certainly something we've considered
because at the end of the day we want to
be helping people right but like many
fields nano means that nano technology
covers a huge variety of technology it
there's nano and medicine there's nano
in paint
there's nano and building materials
there so nano is touches a lot of our
lives that we don't even know and so
there are both responsible molecules
that you can use in building nano that
have already been tested like
extensively and then there's ones where
they're showing either bioaccumulation
or potential toxicity so we are very
cognizant of that and we're trying to
steer away from things that don't
already have a safety profile that's
established but but you're right that
the nano because people don't understand
the whole breadth of the field is a hot
button but on the other hand what was
the thing that made me a believer in
nano is that at the University of
Sevilla they published a study where
they had taken a derivative of THC
called CB 13 and put it in a
time-release nanoparticle and they
orally dosed with a single oral dose to
a rodent in a neuropathic pain model one
dose gave 11 days worth of relief to in
that mouse model whereas the same
compound without the nano gave 8 hours
I'm not saying out eight hours his son
is horrible but what if we could extend
the therapeutic window of cannabinoids
in a way that was controlled like that's
just for me that was the future so but I
see every advance also has potential
pitfalls so it's good
the people keep on that no thank you
guys so much have a wonderful time at
your ab and a great weekend
[Applause]