all right we're just talking about being
arrested and being put on a DEA list so
there's that so quit are we on a deal I
don't I that's the question I mean this
came up the other day right I
strangely feel kind of good about that
it means that I'm doing something enough
to be recognized in this space and the
question becomes this like what happens
when say it does become federally
illegal does that de glaze like kiddy
rates right yeah I don't know right
probably all of a sudden the government
starts looking at that list to see who
to tax right that's what that list
becomes as far as making sure I actually
had someone the other day this is really
interesting someone come to me the other
day with a request to work with us to
get license to like we want access to
all of your dispensaries okay and there
were a CPA firm I was like okay well
talk to me why why are you interested in
that they said well the city is really
interested in finding out who's not
paying their fair share of taxes so
they're leveraging your platform to
figure out how much how many sales are
doing that cross-reference that's what I
do
that's shady and I was like I can't do
that I can't in good conscience I like
you want me to narc out on my my
customers like that's yeah that's good
look really good right right that's a
good way to make sure you're not going
to get sales but otherwise I was like
honestly that's just real shady like you
don't want to do that to come now I mean
if anything would be that guy what do we
what are we paying our government for
like if they can't figure that out
themselves right if they don't have the
tech to do it effectively yeah exactly
it's it's also potentially an
opportunity right true but I think
that's a that's but isn't that like
isn't that what metrics should be doing
Yeah right shouldn't they be going to
the companies like metric to say hey we
need records on all these dispensaries
right who's paying who's not paying like
from a data perspective I could see the
government connecting with the data and
even like partially funding a data
company yeah to be able to get access to
all that connects I mean Washington did
it necessarily partner with the data
company but everything has to be
recorded through the state so have some
sort of a platform in which everything
gets recorded yeah that's public in yeah
I mean and you really want it you want
to get it at that bottleneck that's
where you want to get the data from
cause otherwise I mean you know as well
as I do how how segmented this
marketplace is right you're gonna have
to work with a big handful of companies
to try to piece it together
do you remember what la did before
before California went wreck you know so
la posted a list of every single
dispensary illegal or no that's right I
do remember that and they're like
basically saying like we know who you
are we know you are we just laptop yeah
and everyone got real scared
yes about what was gonna happen and then
the worst thing that possibly could have
happened happened which is that nothing
happened nothing happened right and it's
like all right so now either the
government is like underfunded or it's
understaffed or they're understaffed and
under under attack yeah under that
definitely I think we all know that
they're under attack and so the question
becomes when are you gonna start seeing
that I think recently they actually did
didn't it I started doing some rates in
the last month or so I think they kind
of had to yeah big
[Music]