you've had you know some of the bigger
companies start to think about where
they want to be in a couple of years for
a long time was how quickly we have
licenses in eight ten twelve fifteen
markets so a lot of the companies
weren't necessarily you know really
thinking about exactly where they wanted
to be it wasn't the other way you think
about traditional retail location
location it was much more can we get a
license in the state can we represent to
the investors that we have licenses and
you know four or five regulated states
than four or five of the states that are
a little bit easier to the secured
license in that's that's starting to
change you know we definitely were
watching guys that just said I want
plant as many flags on the ground as
possible now you're watching the the
same CEO say okay we're already in X
amount of states now we really want to
identify you know what are the best
places to be within that state do we
want to you know be in some small town
with the small populations just to say
we're there or we really want to go
after a marquee location and say you
know we're in downtown Los Angeles or in
New York City or in Chicago so a lot of
the multi-state operators now are really
focused on finding the right asset
because they realize it like at non
producing asset it gives them you know
some sort of exposure to say we're in
that state but it doesn't really do all
that much their bottom line and as we're
evolving away now from blue sky and
really going back towards fundamentals
it's just much more important for these
guys to have something that they can
tell the investor class like yeah we
actually think that the trajectory here
is going to be able to allow us to grow
into what our market cap is today our
most operators getting back to
fundamentals because it seems like a lot
are still paying premiums and trying to
get marquee assets
I think of Fifth Avenue locations and
right yeah those guys are definitely
overpaying for assets still I think
they're going to continue to overpay for
assets as long as they have investors
that are willing to overpay for their
paper so you know I look at the
competition for deal flow right now and
there's only so many really marquee
names out there so that when you
actually have a business that's for sale
that's actually a really good business
that you'd like to own there might be
four or five suitors and that's
especially true or was especially true
as these guys are going into the RTO
process which is that the reverse
takeover process in Canada and they're
trying to say okay before we actually go
out there and go on our road
we try to raise you know 100 million
dollars we want to make sure we've got
as much to show the investor base as
possible so if it means that you know we
raised around before the RTO that we use
specifically to deploy into you know
buying a couple assets those are the
ones that are you know really hotly
contested from from a deal flow
perspective but now these guys have you
know a different currency and we talked
a little bit this last time we spoke
where it's a combination of using their
paper and using cash as well to secure
transaction you know now they're they're
being a bit more careful about how
they're structuring their deal but know
they're still they're still overpaying
for the asset from the standpoint of
what multiple you'd attach to a business
but they also look after the perspective
of you know if it's an oleg a
police-style state you know meaning that
there's only a certain amount of license
that's given out and those licenses have
already been given out which means
there's no no more left to give then
they'd rather go into those states and
say okay if we can secure it now and
hope that you know states can expand for
away from just being a medicinal market
so let's let's use Illinois as an
example it's you know a really a good
example that under a rauner the the
governor rauner the market didn't expand
all that much but then all of a sudden
you know you had the opioid bill that
allowed the patient population to double
and now under JB Pritzker coming into
office very likely you're gonna see
adult youths recreation happen in the
next year so if you had the opportunity
to buy a license let's call it in last
year with a small patient population you
might have overpaid for it but you
didn't overpay for it for what the
market is going to be you overpaid for
it for what the market was so in those
states like the New York's the Florida's
the Illinois it's questionable but we'll
know in four years whether or not they
were paid for the asset they certainly
overpaid for it by it what the the
revenue was of those companies today