besides yourselves as you look at two
other people doing extraction do you
respect even if it's something like I
wouldn't why I do test some of the best
extractor in Kalia there is a lot of
them that I respect he'll connect the
two of the two of the two twin days of
it there is a bunch of them because
because by using butane they have the
ability to capture them over a tile tap
an and they produce projects at our
amazing that I have no hesitancy like
it's in the you teammate tool to capture
the most volatile Turpin and to separate
every compound that the plant is giving
you so and I come from the perfume
industry so I have a lot of respect for
it it's not because I am stuck in my
niche there is already so much for me to
learn just about ashes that is like
there is despite the fascination an
attraction that I live for I have for
extraction there is no way I can
dedicate time to it you know what I mean
because it's another monster altogether
I mean like Frenchie said some most of
the best hash and Cali probably doesn't
even hit the dispensary like it's
ridiculous it's ridiculous that you
can't make hash on your farm like it's
ridiculous that they won't let you you
know get some bubble bags and do it kind
of old-school so a lot of those I feel
like a lot of those clash makers have
been left behind but it's it's kind of
cool for them because they don't have to
worry about taxes laws and it's so like
small-scale I think they do without
those constraints like I would love to
not have to worry about when you're
making hash and all all the new laws all
the packaging laws yesterday I was
sitting at least a good 6,000 units
because the rnd test didn't match the
compliance test proposin see everyone
just like oops and I'm like cool that's
what I spent my day doing I mean as the
hash maker I don't think I should be
reoccurring stuff there's no for small
companies there's no option like you you
got to go in and get it done you got
orders to do so yeah I mean yeah I mean
when the Golden State Warriors are
playing you try to get people to work so
I mean as harsh makers there's so many
talented ones one that are not in the
market
I think what's really beautiful is
seeing all the half hash makers have
their own little niche like their okay
like some people like Rosen's some
people like you know rosin that's
buttery some people like broken rosin
everyone's kind of expressing themselves
and all these manners and I think that's
super cool that they have that mastery
over the plant I come from a completely
different school of thought where I'm
like if the farmer is good the hash will
be good surely you don't have reason in
your head I mean I like full spectrum
but I like full spectrum hash I like
smoking full spectrum - we're doing a
show your petty limited opening is to be
to have that wall new play field with
CBD and then because we have CBI CBD we
can play around with ICBC with ith CV we
can play around with a lot of main the
main can I'm in a weight of the of the
specific train but it's like it's patchy
limited but at the same time like I was
telling you like when you make us in in
in my inner inner region in in the body
of the and project there is a matrix
that created all this cannabinoid and
all just happen like in a wine you need
the skin to make the wine you can
extract our alcohol from the seeds and
from the juice but you cannot make wine
if you don't have that matrix that
created the juice and and the sugar so
when we go into the world of extraction
they have an expansion and the domain of
g vs EG that is fucking on
that we don't have when you make
traditional ash so it's like it's all
under the concentrate umbrella but we
are closer to the entourage effect and
the main gift of the plant but of play
feed is much more limited than even guy
making awesome because so clean stuff up
thank you you take you take the juice
from the from the food when you do Ozzy
in you extract but you just with
mechanical separation you can do some
crazy stuff that we didn't think we
could farm and not even two years ago so
thank you to see every different new
type of consistency okay the way hash is
moving in the u.s. I mean it's it's like
it's at the forefront at experimenting
in all those little things