what kind of pricing were you seeing
like at the bottom and then kind of what
are you seeing the trends going zoo so
you know I'm seeing you know the price
to farmer is back up you know at a
thousand eleven hundred dollars right
now and for your outdoor okay your your
better light depths or at like 12 1250
and your indoors are up at fifteen
sixteen again and then your true exotics
you know that are exotics 30 percent is
you know they're up above to where they
should be and what were all those
categories like end of 2017 so we were
looking at five to six hundred for
outdoors we're looking at eight to nine
hundred for the like depths we're
looking at thirteen hundred for the good
indoors 1250 1300 and then your exotics
were commanding you know 1850 you know
so we have seen a boost in the in the
last six weeks of price to farmer you
know makes me regret this year that I
didn't just take everything and bury it
don't know