[Music]
essentially the question is problems in
the regulated era that farmers are
facing as far as rigorous testing
procedures failing for contaminants that
we didn't even know existed and maybe
some possible ways that we can mitigate
those difficulties so a little
background about myself I guess
I use a microscope to analyze soil
biology I've been working with Elena him
for the past three years very closely
she offers some classes online I took
those early on and then continued with
everything she put out there I took the
online classes that dr. Laningham
offered and at a certain point if you
finished all the classes you have the
opportunity to work on a one-year
mentorship where you become certified
when I started that it was in the
infancy of the program so I got to work
directly with her on that and she
literally walked me through a lot of the
procedures of helping some of these
larger scale farmers make it at this new
scale so that was a very valuable
experience to have her interpret what I
was seeing in the field so I think
there's a really unique opportunity for
me that was extremely valuable and it's
turned into some really fantastic
insights as to where the problems are
starting and what are some rational
cost-effective solutions to get through
that process and actually produce
material that can be tested afterward
and make it through the process
so how we use the microscope in that
situation is we can count the organisms
in the soil and based on different
populations or different ratios of
organisms to different organisms it can
speak to the volatility or the stability
of the system which can also tell us
where past their disease pressure is
likely to come from and so when we move
to this larger scale we can look really
tightly and specifically with this
microscope and say we actually have a
problem in group 2 in Bay 3 we don't
need to send employees in to spray
everything every Monday we need to
address the underlying issue at the
environment in the corner of the
greenhouse and being able to
mathematically quantify what's happening
in the soil it's led to an intense
understanding of how the environment was
negatively affecting the soil that is
negatively affecting plant health which
is leading us to use really toxic
chemicals by looking very precisely the
groups of plants across the facility we
can then zoom way out of that and look
at it on a macro scale as like a an F
grade a C grade in an A grade and F
grades become red boxes on the thing and
we can we can zoom out and an example
that I just saw is is five long beds in
a greenhouse and the water comes in at
the center between bed 2 and 3 and the
pressure is highest there and so beds 2
&amp; 3 get over watered and slightly
saturated and so they spend more time of
the day not producing nutrients because
the organism is a really specific
specialist and they operate during very
tight tolerances of moisture and so
those two beds are creating an
oversaturated event that shuts down
nutrient cycling and negatively impacts
soil stability and so we can see that
mathematically with the different
organisms that are there or are not
there and percentages of disease-causing
fungi to beneficial fungi so we've been
able to use the microscope to
mathematically quantify the organisms in
the soil which can give us an indication
as to where
the problem is coming from whether it's
a hostile environment that's negatively
impacting the soil environment or an
over watering event which is suffocating
the aerobic oxygen living organisms
creating a mold pressure or from over
feeding constantly over stimulating the
system which is 99% of living soil
farmers they are way over doing it yeah
because there's not enough to process
this massive amount of nutrients we're
trying to cram into the top of the pot
right so so we have this really
beautiful shift that's happening from
people going from these really toxic
really harsh growing styles to more
sustainable respectable farming styles
and literally genuinely the biggest
obstacle to doing that is changing your
mindset and we're coming from a nutrient
quantity style farming where we need to
put this many PPM's into a reservoir to
get a certain plant growth response and
yield and turn that into a harvest and
if we take that mentality into the
living soils we're constantly throwing
way too many nutrients on top to cram
them into the system and if we have a
deprived biological system meaning we
only have bacteria because that's all
that's available in over the table
products and most compost lacks an
actual soul food web so most people are
growing with just bacteria in the soil
bacteria mineralized nutrients and store
them in their body so they're the
fertilizer bags of the soil and so for
those to become plant available and do
something beneficial for our plant we
need a predator to eat it and rip the
top off of that bag and make it plant
available for our plant and that's
literally what's happening it's a bunch
of things eating other things creating
nutrients and almost everything that
we're doing is hindering that thing and
also this thing that is not there and so
we can zoom in really closely count the
organisms and zoom out and go what is
about the layout of this facility that's
causing this situation what is about our
process that is creating a disturbance
event in group two that is leading to
pest pressure and disease susceptibility
an example of this would be standard 30
by 96 greenhouse with five long beds in
it
water comes into the center between bed
2 and 3 and that's where the water
pressure is highest so out of the drip
tape those beds get slightly
oversaturated compared to the other five
beds this effect in its own can lead to
pests and disease pressure later on in
the life cycle of the plant for two
reasons
organisms are really specific when they
operate with moisture percentages being
a big important factor so as moisture
gets to high these organisms that are
producing nutrients go to sleep and they
go dormant and they wait till conditions
become ideal for them to execute and so
when we overwater those beds it puts
everything to sleep and they're slower
to wake up so those plants have nutrient
cycling issues and if the water amount
is too much after a certain threshold
you actually start to deprive oxygen so
much that the dormancy becomes death and
the fungi and these other organisms that
create soil structure naturally to allow
the natural storage of the water
die soil structure collapses and now it
is the same effect to your root system
as if a hydroponic reservoir took the
aeration out it's the same effect so the
same problems we see over here in
hydroponics and we don't have enough
aeration to the root zone that same
thing is happening in our living soil
bed but we can't pick that plant up and
look at the roots and see that they're
brown and look like dready ropes because
that's under the soil and we don't look
at it that way and so so in that
situation with the five beds we just
adjust the water and then we can count
the organisms again and see that the
tides have changed or if they haven't
changed typically we can see if in
effect or if a change was effective
within seven to ten days and you can
take a soil that is please
straight up most problems are from
excess saturation right now I'll answer
this more thoroughly but an actual
usable answer is we have an intense
pressure on farmers from the investors
to produce widgets and so people are
feeding twice a day people are feeding
multiple times a day they're upping
they're upping they're pushing the
pushing and pushing they're pushing and
from a biological standpoint the floor
of that abandoned Rose grower house is
loaded with disease-causing fungi and
spores and we can count those and see
that and we just pour water all over
this facility that the soil is loaded
with water molds and those things pour
and germinate and attack your plant and
literally it's because their water molds
and they can only transfer on a film of
water so the more times we leave a film
of water everywhere that's the more
we're spreading proliferating and
creating disease to fight so that's a
specific answer but mathematically
[Music]
depending on depending on the
populations of the disease-causing
organisms we've just seen enough now
that most people are following the same
four trends most people are following
the same four recommendations that have
worked you know they have merit I'm not
discounting things we do because we're
able to do the more than once so there's
a component of effectiveness that allows
the technique to keep going but as we
move into the regulated era the material
we're producing is being more tightly
analyzed and a proactive approach can
avoid costly errors in the end and and
that's essentially when we've really
done the most work is after somebody
just had a confiscation really and so we
talked about the confiscation try to
identify where the problem came from try
to change the soil environment so it's
more conducive to thriving and not
disease
[Music]