[Music]
to me Willow Creek is a pristine
environment and it has the perfect
climate for growing cannabis
Willow Creek is a community that has
been cultivating cannabis for decades
and generations Willow Creek is River
fun in the Mountain Sun
[Music]
thank you
Willow Creek is different than other
growing climates in Humboldt because we
are at the foothills of the Kalamath
mountain range which holds one of the
most biodiverse forests in North America
so our Waters our air and our
environment is directly a result of our
position between the coast and the
Klamath mountain range and The Trinity
Alps
Humboldt in general to me is the Napa
Valley of cannabis this is where it all
started and I really feel like that
Willow Creek region the farmers here
really are putting all their love and
passion into what they're doing
we focus more on quality over quantity
to make sure we are producing and
providing the best quality product to
the end consumer
this is craft cannabis grown small scale
with the farmer in touch with every
plant every bud we're growing in clean
air with clean water
we grow our herb with the seasons and
with our property we don't try and push
too much on the boundaries of
lights and other environmental issues
that's really what it's all about for us
is is trying to uh
to bring that best product and make it
in the most environmentally friendly way
I think the community is really
empowered and energized and looking at
fun ways to help create a better place
for us all to be and have our kids in
and to experience life in
we actually minimize the ingredients
that we put in our cannabis to make sure
that we leave it as organic as possible
we use
natural organic fertilizers and only as
much as the plant needs we're not using
salts we're not over fertilizing
we should be trying to make the most
mindful choices possible so when we're
producing cannabis under sunlight it
takes a hundred years for this Farm to
produce the carbon impact of one ten
thousand square foot indoor cycle
between heating cooling and electric
costs the social responsibility I think
is you know it's in the hands of
consumers to really digest this
information and be able to make an
impactful choice for a climate
sun-grown cannabis is a completely
different product than industrial
Factory farmed cannabis
what we would hope is that people can
start to understand that they're a clear
climate Solutions and while it may seem
daunting every person has that
opportunity to make a difference with
how they purchase
if you put in some of your personal
values it's almost always a win-win when
you buy craft cannabis
buying craft cannabis is supporting
communities it's supporting families
it's supporting the environment
so by choosing cannabis from the Willow
Creek region you get to experience a
little bit of the natural beauty and the
love of the community that went into
growing that flower for you
we eventually found this community here
in Humboldt and
it was an instant like oh These Are My
People this is my place
and you know a lot of that does have to
do with the Cannabis because it is just
a way of life here it's completely woven
through daily life and culture
just trying to embody
a more sustainable ecologically sound
way of farming and life
the Willow Creek Community is a really
resilient group of people who are deeply
committed to sharing Prosperity with
each other it's what I've experienced we
recently had a fire come close to the
property and the amount of community
support and outpour and a time of Crisis
and need really
you know shook me to a place of humility
and gratitude
yeah Willow Creek is a really strong
community
we are so supportive of each other
I feel like the community now is a fresh
younger
revitalized Awakening of Willow Creek
we're the farmers that put all of our
heart into it and so
support craft cannabis
it's our lifestyle it's what we do we
love it
foreign
from Humboldt it was made with love
I couldn't imagine doing anything else