what's up everybody this is windy city
garden
um so
um i'm a new grower first let's get that
out of the way
um i am a medical patient based out of
illinois
um they recently changed the law to
allow uh recrea or medical grow um and
so i got my
my license to do that and um so that's
what this garden is is
this is a caretaker garden um that i'm
helping another medical patient with
um so you can see what we got cooking in
here just
doing some little maintenance on these
guys um
so yeah we'll walk you through the
property we used to have five plants
actually we had a problem with root
aphids earlier this year
we'd started off in this bed and
out of the five plants that we'd put in
the bed the root aphids killed
everything but two of the plants we
ended up treating with
nematodes and dr zymes treatments
and we ended up clearing the beds and we
still were able to save two of the
plants
this is the remnants of one and i'll get
into why it's like that
in just a second if you want to lay any
bets as to why
that's what we've got left of a plant
submit your
submit your answers now um and then this
was the other plant that we had in here
uh this is an acapulco gold and we had
pulled it out of the bed put it into new
soil
treated all the soil with nematodes and
um
dr zimes and uh we got rid of we got
past the aphids problem
uh up until this week we actually had a
full
the biggest bush that we had was this
one right here and it came out i mean
we had stake marks all the way out to
here which is about four feet off the
bed maybe three feet off the bed
and uh had full trellis systems on it it
was massive it was gonna be
i mean i don't know a lot this is my
first season but it was going to be
in the pounds yieldage for sure
what we're working with now though is
for uh four plants
these are critical plants from
seed stalkers based out of spain uh
so three of them are the are clones of
that
um and then this is an acapulco gold
um and yeah this is uh
this is what we've got for our garden um
the one that was right here was actually
a bag seed
and uh you know so not surprising
uh if that gives anybody else any any
more tips why i guess
i'll just say it uh that plant ended up
herming
and yeah so we had to cut it
because it started to seed itself um and
i've been doing some inspection on these
plants to see
uh if they've been seated at all and
some of them look like they might have
got in touch with pollen somebody said
to look for brown
brown pistol hairs which would indicate
pollination and there are definitely
some on some of these plants so
we'll see hopefully the damage was
somewhat contained but it's hard to say
[Music]
we're growing in an organic super soil
out here
um with a lot of down-to-earth
amendments
really love the shape of these plants
looks really nice
focus these are 15 gallon containers
um with you know blood meal kelp meal
lang banite seibert guano uh
alfalfa meal insect frass
all sorts of amendments dropped into
there
and yeah they're doing pretty well i
would say
we started transitioning to flour on
these three plants
um at the very beginning of august i was
very surprised to see how far along they
got
the very beginning of august oops there
we go
um and
this one this acapulco gold i think
because it's got that deep sativa nature
to it it's uh
it's waiting for things to get closer
probably to the 11 and 11 hour cycle
so we'll see how much later it takes
until she really starts to
to flower up but so yeah that's what
we're working with
um four of the five plants that we
had started with uh about halfway
through the season
uh we had killed three we had lost three
uh that were also backseat actually
um and
you know uh turns out that was probably
for the best because
that bag seed was uh was a herm
so had some her hermit hermaphroditic
tendencies
so yeah in terms of
pest management since we got past the
root aphids we've just been deploying uh
beneficial insects
um we were using neem up until flower
but
then i saw the um the talk with scott
scamnis
scott scamness i'm i'm sure i'm
butchering his name uh where he talked
about how the azerachmann
and nimoy was a problem so we cut that
out and we went
basically right to beneficial insects at
that point so we've got ladybugs we've
got
green lace wings which you can see down
here
we've got trichogama trichograma
um parasitic
wasps and um
and assassin bugs so we've kind of got a
full assortment of
of beneficial insects um that are in
here right now
and uh hopefully that protects us from
caterpillars and any other would be
passed
uh until we can finish the season
um yeah so this is again this is a
caretaker outdoor patch
that i'm helping somebody with and in
just a second i'll show you my indoor
let's see genetics critical
from seed stalkers acapulco gold from
barney's farm
critical from seed stalkers critical
from seed stalkers uh they're just
clones of each other so these are all
the same plant uh it wasn't you know
that i picked out a particularly good
pheno it was literally my first time
growing and um you know you google where
to get seeds and
you order some seeds so it was really
like that simple and now that i'm like
a little further into it i wish that i
had gotten maybe better you know
quote unquote american better american
genetics or something that's maybe more
aligned with um
where i'm growing uh maybe like breeders
out of michigan
would have been maybe a good place to go
or massachusetts
just in terms of finishing dates and all
that kind of stuff um
and also stuff that's well suited for uh
you know in october that can get wet or
uh or cold
but um didn't know about that at the
time didn't do enough research kind of
just ordered seeds and
uh and off we went and um you know next
season i think i'm going to go in with a
better plan
but this has been a really fun learning
and
uh i guess pun not intended growing
uh experience so yeah
um in illinois we're legally allowed to
grow five plants
uh with a medical license and um
so now we're down to the four sadly
because we lost this one it was a
yeah it was a hermaphrodite so just
beware of bag seed man test it out
before you run it
full time um and hopefully it didn't get
too much to the rest of our crop because
those seeds are going to be useless
really um so yeah
here's the outdoor let me know if you
have any questions and uh
i'll show you the door in just a second
so i'll take you into the cave in just a
second but i figured that we might start
out here so that we can talk about sort
of what i'm i'm growing
all organically using a lot of
down-to-earth um
amendments and you can see what i got
working with here is um some neem seed
meal
gypsum for calcium um
we've got just an all-purpose 444 which
is a blend of all of this stuff
some humic acids this is um azomite
right here
um which is from micronutrients from
what i understand here's kelp meal
and here's langbanite which is a high
potassium
source here's some alfalfa meal blood
meal
um seabird guano um
crabmeal then some combination of all of
these are in my
um in in what was in the outdoor and
what's in the indoor
um it's been pretty good i was looking
for a system where i would basically
build the soil
and then all i would have to do is add
teas and water occasionally
and that's pretty well um the direction
that i've gone in i've really enjoyed it
it's been
fairly easy um i'm growing in three
gallon bags
um for most of my stuff um at least on
the indoor the outdoor is obviously
bigger it's 15 gallons um and then we're
doing occasional earthworm casting teas
along with this is recharge
from real growers so
infusing our microbe microbiology
and microbes into the soil to regulate
ph so i can just water in regular water
in between those
and we're also adding in occasionally
epsom salts
and silica
the actual bags of these live over at
the outdoor which is why
so the way that the law works is kind of
silly you can only have five plants
per property it's not even per medical
patient so if you have two medical
patients that live under the same room
you still only have five plants total in
the house which is just like
it doesn't make any sense to me it seems
like a poorly written law in michigan
you can have 12
recreationally like i just don't
understand why you know
um but in any event the law changed in
january officially on the first of the
year
and in the recreational law they
included the provision for home growth
for medical patients and that's what
inspired me to get
uh to grow my own uh and that's what led
me down the rabbit hole so really i got
started after getting my
my card um i got started in
march and basically started acquiring
all of this stuff doing research on the
internet we popped bag seed and then i
ordered the other plants and we'll talk
about that in just a second
under here i've got my water which is
basically just tap water that i'm
aerating the chlorine out of using these
air pumps
and then i've got this bigger air pump
for making compost teas while actually
earthworm casting teas
with recharge um to inoculate the the
soil with
along with some macro nutrients and some
micronutrients like i'll throw in some
calcium and some
um and some azomite along with some
phosphorus and and potassium for
um and i'll and i'll try to make it you
know i don't have
um i don't have a microscope
to really see what i'm getting into it
but what i understand and maybe this is
like
you know bro science maybe it's not is
that if you
use earthworm castings and you and you
go for more than 24 hours in a compost
tea you wind up with a more fungally
dominated
compost tea generally speaking
you know fungally dominated compost teas
are good
for uh for flowering cycle which is what
we're in uh in all of these plants that
are in here
here's the two by four tent that i've
got um again
started this in march so i've just been
trying to acquire equipment over the the
course of the pandemic basically
um these are some autoflowers that i
started
86 days ago um and
you know they've been fine but they're
finicky i feel like autoflowers it's
like if you don't get everything right
and veg
and then you flip into flour um and
everything's not right like
you your yield's gonna suffer your
potency will probably suffer
like i just don't know that it's the
most in one way it's efficient because
you could do a
perpetual cycle of autoflowers it would
start to cost a lot in seed
but from a home grower's perspective i
think that that's one method that you
could do once you get your system dialed
in so that you're really good
and that you're not wasting any moment
of veg
or any moment of flower so i think you
need to be really dialed in to work with
autoflowers
successfully um i think in the future
i'm gonna work with
photo periods just because there's a
little bit more graze to it there's a
little bit more of like if you mess up
uh you know you still have time to like
correct mistakes and veg before you flip
into flour
these are the critical uh plants this is
the same
this is the mother of the plants that
are out in the outdoor right now
um pretty nice growth
this is the first seed that i popped and
i decided that it was time to throw it
into flower
um because next time on the the flip of
this tent what i really want to do is i
really want to do a proper
pheno hunt so i've got a pack of 14
seeds
that i that i'm going to be running once
everything is clear out of this tent so
there's four plants in this tent
um and yeah this one is gonna be
this is the mother plant for those other
ones and we're just gonna try and grow
as much nice bud on this as we can
oops gonna do a little maintenance
forgive me um
and then this one is a clone of that and
what i want to do is i just want to kiss
it with pollen and a couple of the bud
sites so that i can make my own
seeds i'm not going to use the
hermaphrodite um pollen from the other
scene i've actually got a different
um pile that i'm going to use and i'll
show you that in a second but
uh in the meantime yeah so there's two
gorilla glue autos going right there
there's these two critical plans and
then i got some pollen going in the next
ten well almost going in the next tank
uh so this is my 2x4
let me close this up real nice and tight
so that i can be
very intentional about where the pollen
gets give me one second
okay i'm so sorry about the blurble
again like i'm just acquiring equipment
and trying to make it work
this is a night terror og plant from um
from rare dankness out of colorado um
so i i popped a couple of seeds and i
ended up finding this male in here um it
is
cool because um you know it's got a lot
of
characteristics that i like on a female
like i like the way that this is
stacking out and i really want to use
the pond from that so
this is in the same room sadly so i mean
maybe that's a big mistake is to have it
in
even in the same room even in two
different tents um everything is sealed
up you can tell
with zip ties um on either the
all of the outside things so hopefully
there's nothing leaking out of this
except for when i open the tent
um and at that point you know hopefully
we're not
exposing things too long to uh
to the air so um yeah and the other tent
is fully sealed every time that this
gets open so
uh that's the goal um
yeah the blurble light i'm sorry about
that it really kind of sucks
um but you can see i got some boys in
here we're gonna get the pollen out of
this and i'm gonna
just kiss a couple of the colas on the
plant that i have going
uh with the idea that then i've just
gotten set with my own seed
for some amount of time
because you know it's seed's not cheap
um
and i'm not a cheap guy and i don't want
to do this a cheap way but i'm also so
interested in the uh and the
characteristics of breeding and like
what you might get and um you know i'm a
guy who likes to like just take projects
and run with them so
uh we're gonna give this a shot and see
if we can make something
something work yeah so that's all i got
um
peter let me know if you need me to
record anything else uh
and i'll be happy to talk ad nauseum
uh about what my thoughts on on growing
and all that kind of stuff
thanks so much and have a great day