this is Richard Mendelssohn Richard
Mendelssohn internationally-recognized
why mori ER with Dickinson Pete Minh and
Fogerty and Napa he also directs the
wine law and policy program at UC
Berkeley law school and he is the sole
proprietor of Mendelssohn wines that
produces a pinot noir and fortified
dessert wines he's a graduate of Harvard
Oxford and Stanford Law he is the author
of from demon to darling a legal history
of wine in America wine in America law
and policy and appellation Napa Valley
building and protecting an American
treasure so without further ado please
take us away into the appellation world
thanks Chris and Thank You Blanc it's a
pleasure to be here welcome to my home
in Napa I've been asked to set the stage
for our discussions today by giving you
kind of a tour de force of populations
and geographical indications around the
world and how we get to the point we are
today of crafting our cannabis
appellations and what the background to
that is so I'm going to divide my
remarks into the following sections if
you could move the slide to the to the
next one please
Chris first I'm going to talk about the
road to GIS GIS we're going to be using
a lot of acronyms here kiai stands for
geographical indications and it started
with the Paris Convention this is an
international perspective all the way
forward to tricks which is the
trade-related aspects of intellectual
property rights it's an agreement as
we'll see that was adopted by the World
Trade Organization and this will tell us
what Appalachians and geographical
indications are and the issues that
we've been trying to deal with both
nationally and internationally then
we're going to move roughly equal time
segments for each of these sections to
wine Appalachians in both the old world
and the new world because really it's
well by no means our why is wine the
only commodity for which Appalachians
apply its prime primarily the the focal
point because it's
such long-standing particularly in the
old world that we have a lot of lessons
to learn and of course we have the
experience in the United States and
other new world countries of our
American viticultural areas which is the
third bullet here a BAS and I'm going to
tell you basically what the experience
has been with a BAS in our country what
we've learned what we've created what
the regulations say this is an area in
which I've participated actively
throughout my career in in actually
forming AV A's in California and
elsewhere I want to spend a little bit
of time talking about what I regard is a
very important subject conflicts between
Geographic trademarks that is a mark
that includes a geographic term and GIS
which primarily are geographic terms
sometimes they appear in both both a
geographic mark and in a GI and there
can be conflicts between them I know we
have a session later in the webinar on
that specific topic and so all I want to
do is introduce the points and then I'm
going to leave time for for Q&amp;A so
that's the road map let's start section
1 the road 2 key is it started in 1883
with the Paris Convention for the
protection of industrial property this
is an era in which rapid
industrialization was occurring around
the world and this is really the first
legal agreement that deals with they use
the terms indications of source and
appellations of origin but that
agreement didn't define either of those
terms that came in later agreements and
you'll see down at the bottom that there
are a hundred and seventy-seven
contracting parties to the Paris
Convention including the United States
it's a very agreement that that was
broadly adopted around the world now the
important thing about the Paris
Convention is that it only addressed
false indications and not misleading
indications so for example the agreement
at war
did deal with both false and misleading
but not with respect to origin so
article 10 B of the agreement is the
provision that says that not only would
it be prohibited to use a false
indication of source or appellation of
origin for example if I said on a wine
that it's Napa Valley and in fact the
wine
none of the grapes come from the Napa
Valley that's false but it also the
agreement wanted to get at misleading or
deceptive uses of those names and that
can take many forms it can take the form
of just saying that this is like Napa
Valley or similar to or Napa Valley type
that would be one indication where it's
not really from there and you're you but
it could be misleading or variations in
spelling so you'll see that the
agreement prohibited not only false
indications but also those that were
liable to mislead the public as to the
nature the manufacturing process the
characteristics the suitability for
purpose or the quantity of the goods
interestingly it doesn't say origin
origin was in an earlier draft of the
agreement but it was pulled out because
there's always been a controversy about
the use of generic terms which we'll
talk about in a minute and other kind of
indicators to tell someone that a wine
is for example like a Bordeaux even
though it's not a Bordeaux wine let's go
to the next slide so the next agreement
in this litany is the Lisbon Agreement I
don't know why the heading this is very
garbled I'm not exactly look there we go
thank you Chris the Lisbon agreement we
roll forward all the way to 1958 but
it's a very important agreement because
it for the first time defines an
appellation of origin and you'll see
that in the first bullet it's a
geographical denomination of a country
jayati designating a product originating
marryin and these are the important
words the quality or Karis
characteristics of which are due
exclusively or essentially to the
geographic environment including natural
and human factors this is the causal
link that we talked about between
product in place that that it's not just
that a product is manufactured in a
place or even that the raw materials
come from that place basically the final
product whether it's an agricultural
crop a handy handicraft textile whatever
it is whatever kind of appellation
system we're talking about the quality
or characteristics of that final product
are tied directly to the geographic
environment so in a case of an
agricultural crop that's actually where
the crop is grown which we refer to as
terroir all of the aspects of the
natural environment but it also includes
the human factors and by that I mean how
you farm that land
what is your planning density what's
your route stock what's your what's your
trellis system how do you make the wine
in the winery all of those human factors
that result in this final product so
finally in 1958 we have a definition of
appellation of origin we also have a
registry maintained by WIPO the World
Intellectual Property Organization in
Geneva where you can let the world know
that you as a contracting state of the
Lisbon Agreement have recognized an
appellation of words and in your state
and you'd like the all the other
contracting States to abide by it and so
they are given notice by WIPO and within
a year they they have the right to
refuse protection but they have to state
why and and those can be that for
example that a wine name was you in use
in that country for a very long time
without having an indication of without
being an indication of origin so there
was a pre-existing use of that name
there are other reasons why a name
maybe refuse to protection interestingly
the Lisbon agreement covers not only
false uses but also any usurpation or
imitation even when used in translation
or accompanied by words such as kind
type or light and once it's a name is
protected it cannot fall into genera
side it cannot become a generic name
once it's protected in this in the
contracting state so this goes much much
farther than the Paris Convention in
protecting against false indications
protecting against misleading
indications and also defining in a very
direct way the link between the product
and place in order to qualify as an
appellation of origin now the downside
Chris if you go to the next slide is
that there were very few contracting
parties and you'll see that they were
mostly in Europe they're in Canada the
United States etc Australia they did not
join even when there was a an amendment
to the Lisbon Agreement which took place
in 2015 the Geneva act because the
Lisbon Agreement was seeking and white
but was seeking to make the this this
treaty this Agreement more widespread so
that they amended it in 2015 to cover
not only Appalachians work good reason
to turn off your cell phone sorry about
that um also they cover the registration
of GIS which is the agreement that we're
going to turn to next next slide please
okay so this is the World Trade
Organization agreement on trade-related
aspects of intellectual property rights
trips agreement 1995 and for the first
time we have a definition of
geographical indication a GI but what
you're going to see here is that GIS are
a more liberal a looser definition than
an appellation of origin or to put it
another way appellations of origin
are a subset of GIS a GI according to
article 22 of the TRIPS Agreement
identifies a good as originating in the
territory of a member or region or a
locality that's identical to the
appellation of origin definition so far
except for the bold-faced language where
a given quality reputation for the first
time we see the word reputation or other
characteristics of the good is
essentially not exclusively essentially
attributable to its geographical origin
there are 164 member states that signed
this agreement including the United
States so it like the Paris Convention
its widespread approval around the world
and in fact in article 23 there is a
protection that is more elevated than
for any other goods and services for
wines and spirits specifically like the
Lisbon Agreement the the GIS are
protected against false and misleading
deceptive uses whereas all the other
goods that are GIS that are wines and
spirits are not protected against
misleading and deceptive uses but only
false uses so this is important
article 24 contains exceptions we have
exceptions for Geographic trademarks
which we'll talk about later for generic
names where a name has been used in a
country for a very long time for example
a lot of the cheese's in America like
feta and parmesan that really don't come
from their original sources what's
important to know about the troops
agreement is it's a minimum standards
agreement meaning that member states
have the right to put in place stricter
rules governing GIS some have their own
GI systems we call those soui generous
systems others as we'll see in the next
slide will use their trademark laws to
recognize key is the last point about
the troops agreement is that there is no
multilateral register where you can look
to WHO as you can
WIPO for the lisbon agreement and see
the list of GIS around the world next
slide please
here are examples photographic examples
if you click one more time Chris I think
some more will come up names that you
all know Parmesan cheese from Gianna
Reggiano and its translation to parmesan
Darjeeling tea Parma ham Indian River
navel oranges from where I'm from in
Napa cone of coffee which is a story
unto itself and even things like
traditional knowledge on the bottom left
ayurvedic
in in india let's go to the next slide i
was mentioning the u.s. protects gi's
through the existing trademark laws and
does not have a soui generous GI system
as the as occurs in the European Union
and other countries we use certification
and collective marks and I've just
listed some of the certification marks
and the registration numbers in the US
to give you an indication of this Parma
ham darjeeling jamaica bluemountain
coffee the Dahlia for onions coming from
Georgia parmigiano-reggiano and wrote
for and here I give the definition if
you were to look this up on the PTO
Patent and Trademark Office a site you'd
see that wrote for is a cheese it's have
been manufactured from sheep's milk
cured in the caves of the community of
Roquefort in accordance with
long-established methods and prophecies
these methods and processes are the
natural are the human factors that go
along with the fact that the sheep's
milk and the caves are inside of the
area of the Rope for Appalachian and and
these are protected in the US as a
certification mark okay what are the
differences then between GIS and
appellations of origin just in summary g
eyes require a link between the quality
other characteristics or reputation of
the product and its place of origin
appellations of origin require a
stricter link namely that the products
quality or characteristics are due
exclusively or
essentially to the products geographical
origin this means that the usually means
doesn't every country will set up their
own rules but typically it means that
the raw materials are sourced in the
place of origin and that the processing
of the product takes place there now on
the bottom of this slide are the seals I
mean we're going to talk about seals I
think in the next session for the PDO s
which are the of the appellations of
origin for the PGI's which are the GIS
the geographical indications and then
they often also have traditional
specialty products these are the three
seals that are used in the European
Union to differentiate that is the
European Union doesn't just pick one
it's not just that every product in the
European Union is an appellation of
origin
some are PGI's and some are traditional
specialties so you don't have to choose
one or the other
next slide Chris yeah thank you one
important thing to note about
appellations of origin and G is any G I
will call appellations of origin a
subset of G is is it there is an ongoing
tension between tradition and innovation
in these TI products you know an
appellation of origin for a product
that's been around for a very long time
has history and tradition to encapsulate
in the production methodology and all
the well what we call in our cannabis
appellation regulation standards
practices and cultivars and and so there
is tradition to respect but there's also
innovation that's important for any GI
because a GI can die and there are lots
of examples of deceased GIS because they
didn't keep up with the times methods
the consumer demands so we find tension
I gave two examples here below we won't
spend any time on them because I'm going
to move quickly but mustard Damascus och
in the Languedoc region of France and
teeny yellow which is an Anton or
one of the most famous Super Tuscans
both of these lines and their wine
proprietors were innovators and they
didn't like being bound by the
appellation of origin controls and in
order to innovate they literally had to
sell their wines as table wines and they
broke out of the alo system in fact it
was the AOC and the DOCG systems in
their respective countries in order to
do their own thing to try to show that
their innovation would make a better
product a higher quality with even
better characteristics more recognizable
and distinctive characteristics
interestingly they were both successful
and what happens is then the appellation
authorities recognize that and change
the rules so this is not a static
process it's a dynamic process next
slide please
okay let's turn to wine now and if you
click through all of these bullets Chris
you'll see the bottom one is to piss a
day and you'll know you're done I wanted
to start with the controlled
appellations of the old world this is
the a Palacio Dora gain control a
meaning control or do-si-do Romo nazione
Dora Jean control Otto controlled what
does it mean to be a controlled
appellation what it really means is that
you are in essence a an appellation of
origin and not a GI because you are
doing your getting into the issues of
standards practices and and cultivars in
a way that typically a GI does not so in
the old world and I show the example of
La tache which is one of the most famous
Burgundy wines and it's an AOC you the
Great's have to be totally grown within
the appellation only permissible grape
varietals can be grown you can grow
anything you want
in that area but you just can't use the
AOC you can't call yourself Latasha if
you're not using Pinot Noir grapes if
you want to grow Cabernet there you'll
be a a rebel and you can sell your wine
as a table wine and then there are a
host of other criteria both in farming
and in winemaking that you need to
follow I've given some examples here the
yield of grapes minimum and maximum
alcohol percentage but it's actually
much broader than that this is called a
Calle de Chartres is what the French
call it and it's really your it's not a
recipe it's a range of parameters so
that you can still as a wine proprietor
practice your artistry and produce a
unique product but you have to stay
within these given ranges and then
ultimately you have to pass a chemical
analysis and a to piss 'ti tests
literally where a judge taste the
product and says is this typical of a
latosha wine given all the vintage
variations and everything else that can
cause variation
but if it's not typical then it can be
thrown out and it's not allowed to use
the AOC on the label next in the United
States we didn't really have much of a
concept of provenance coming out of the
ashes of prohibition in 1933 and trying
to pull ourselves up by our bootstraps
largely through innovation and technical
expertise it really wasn't until the
paris tasting of 1976 when some actually
Napa Valley wines bested the wines of
France that people started to use on a
more routine basis geographical
indications appellations of origin on
their label but nobody knew where they
were they weren't regulated so here are
two examples of Louis martini California
Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon I'm sure you
all know where California Mountain is
well it's wherever you think it is
there's no such thing and Northern
California well all of us Californians
can tell you we where there is no real
definition of Northern California and
people have their own views as a result
if you go to the next slide Chris we
ended up adopting a system an
appellation system in the late 70s it
took effect in 1983 where we have for
our Appalachians for wine you can use
the United States a state or a county
those are political Appalachians of
course those boundaries pre-existed we
all know where they are but the new
invention was this concept of an
appellation or an American video trail
area in a VA that would going to be
created and established by the federal
government this is not at the state
level it's the Treasury Department and
the tax and trade Bureau alcohol and
tobacco tax and trade Bureau that does
that runs this program but a DA's would
be created anew and in for each of these
Appalachians because American
viticultural areas are a form of
Appalachian under the American system
you would have to have a certain
percentage of your grapes from
area in the end the wine but it did not
control and it does not control which
variety of grapes you use your yields
your farming methods your winemaking
practices only where the grapes come
from and where the wine is made so if
you use in a VA on the label the wine
must be made in the state in which the a
VA is located that's important and in
order to form in a VA well you let's go
to the next slide we'll get into how you
form an a VA in a minute here's the
definition defined as a delimited great
growing region distinguishable by
geographic features interestingly those
are the same words that we find in our
proposed cannabis regulations the
boundaries of which have been recognized
and defined by TTB here are two examples
down below the Ohio River Valley on the
right finger lakes in New York on the
left appearing on the label in direct
conjunction with the grape varietal the
VOA and ruse on on the right and the
pinot noir on the left let's go to the
next slide so just two and one more
click please just to show you examples
let's take the hug off and label that's
a Napa Valley wine the fact that it says
Napa Valley means that 85 percent of the
grapes are grown in the Napa Valley the
fact that there's a vineyard designation
Heston vineyard increases that
percentage to 95 and in fact there's
even more information on the label which
you're allowed to use the L block of
that particular vineyard for example
next slide so far we have formed 245 80
A's in the 32 states of the United
States I'm you're not supposed to read
the whole that small type but this is
right out of the of the Code of Federal
Regulations go to the next slide here is
how you form an ABA first you must show
and this is anyone can do this it could
one person it could be someone who's not
in the wine industry at all doesn't grow
grapes and doesn't make wine anyone can
file a navy a petition with TTB whoever
files that petition whether it usually
it's a group of vintners and growers
together filing it
you must adduce name evidence that
currently and directly associates the
name with the area in which you
viticultural exists so there has to be
some great growing there all of the area
within the boundaries must be nationally
or locally known by the name specified
in the petition although the use of that
name may extend beyond the proposed a VA
boundary so you can have names that are
over inclusive you can't have names that
are under inclusive and they must
remember this is all done all of these
regulations for wine in the United
States are under the federal alcohol
administration Act which is in part a
consumer protection of consumer
information act and this is to give the
consumer information to guide their
purchasing decisions there's boundaries
obviously and they tell you if you'll
see down in four below those are based
on characteristics seen on United States
Geological Survey maps those are topo
graphic maps so most boundaries are done
based on elevation contours that show on
those maps rivers and roads mountaintops
and the light not like in France where
we actually use parcel lines the lines
of your property to define an
appellation and then the most important
point in my from my perspective is
distinguishing viticultural features
climate soil geology physical features
in elevation the petition must explain
with pet specificity in what way these
features affect viticulture and how they
are distinguished viticulture Lee from
features associated with adjacent areas
outside the boundary it's so funny many
of these criteria reappear in our
proposed
Cannabis Appalachian regulations next
line
we have had over the course of what is
from 1983 to today so that's 37 years
we've had the process of actually
subdividing Appalachians
we call them nested abs or sub a bas
where for example on the left there
you'll see that Napa Valley in that
lighter tan tone has been subdivided
into many other smaller area a VA s that
capture more distinctive geographical
features more distinctive grape growing
environments within the Napa Valley
similarly it's happened in the
Willamette Valley as you see on the
right and Lodi and past Robles and many
other places this is around the world a
very common thing whether it's coffee or
tea or whatever the commodity is to to
have nested a VA s larger down to
smaller and then the consumer can play
the I call it the appellation name name
game if I want to know about Napa Valley
that's one thing I want to spend more
money because it usually is more money
and buy a house out and wine and explore
those differences I can do that so it's
a way of understanding for the consumer
better understanding the final product
okay next thanks Chris yes well this
point is just to reiterate what I said
certain Appalachians command higher
prices this is important this is the
value add that comes through an
appellation that isn't the the owned by
one individual farmer or winery it's a
collective of growers and vendors inside
the appellation that collectively owned
this property and in fact when you put
Napa Valley on a wine compared to its
California wine you're gonna spend
$19.80 more on average according to this
was a UC Davis AG extension a study and
if you go and use Oakville or how amount
and you'll be $40 plus more than that
California wine so you're paying more
and the question I always ask in the
classes I teach is this is why we do
tastings is it worth it is it worth
to pay more for that how a mountain wine
than a California wine well only you the
consumer will know and hopefully the
producer is producing something that has
to go back to the definition of
Appalachians that has characteristics
and qualities that you can find and
refined the next time you buy that wine
and help guide your education and
purchases next slide
well quality in fact is not a criteria
of the a VA system because we don't have
the standards practices and cultivars
that are that are required to use an
appellation name it's much more leaving
it to the collective to experiment it's
it's part of the American pride and
innovation rather than what we don't
have as long of a tradition particularly
the traditions we had were interrupted
by 13 years of prohibition nevertheless
the successful Appalachians of which I
would certainly include the Napa Valley
as one if not the foremost um will do
their own efforts at consumer education
they'll do the research they'll do the
promotion they'll be interested in
sustainability whether it's social
environmental or economic and and this
is important to their having loyal
customers so even though it may not be
regulatory it is aspirational and
voluntary and and now a a real effort on
the part of a VA s that want to succeed
in the marketplace next slide here are
two examples Cora Mendocino and lowdown
rules each of which take the form of a
logo these are certification marks by
the way these are not they are AOC style
controls but on a label they you will
still find Lodi and you'll find
Mendocino on the label is the
appellation but you'll find this logo
that tells you what additional grape
growing or winemaking rules that they
have voluntarily adhered to you know
to put this sticker on the label so
again going back to this tradition and
innovation this is the ABA s that don't
have the tradition seeking to have more
a OC style controls wanting to honor the
traditions that are now being
established in those areas next slide
okay we're just going to take a few more
minutes and then we're going to leave
ourselves open for questions I'm going
to keep us on a tight time line but I
want to talk for a minute about the
conflicts between Geographic marks and
GIS this would be an example of where
somebody comes into an area and they
pick the name of their town or of a
creek nearby and they may be unwitting
that's the only they don't want to use
their family name and they call their
brand by a geographic name and then
later or maybe it's even before the
appellation was established whether the
appellation was established before the
trademark or after can be is important
as the third bullet there shows first in
time first and right which is a common
trademark principle but just as
important and number one for me is the
fact that nobody owns exclusively a
geographic name nobody owns the Napa
Valley nobody owns the name Humboldt you
may use it and you have to use it
descriptively and that's called a fair
use
anyone can say I live in the Napa Valley
I live in Humboldt County I live in the
Mottola Val um you don't want people to
be mislead this is I think and then this
goes back all the way to where we
started with these international
agreements you know you don't want
people to be misled or deceived so if a
geographic mark just make it up you know
um well use it in in in the in the
cannabis world Matt ol brand is put on
products that do not come from Atoll
Valley whether the Mottola Valley is is
is recognized prior to that or after
that it misleads consumers as I said
with respect to the third bullet
typically a most intellectual property
lawyer
would say that this should be resolved
in who registers first if the trademark
pre-existed the appellation well they
get to continue I'm not a believer in
that I think it's much more complicated
than this and I believe in the rights of
Appalachians I think it's a collective
right and it's an important one
sometimes the priority is legislated as
it is in the EU which is much more much
more akin to my views of giving priority
to the Appalachian sometimes it turns on
good or bad faith and I've got great
stories here that I'm not able to tell
you because I don't have the time but
let's go to the next slide
Chris because I think this will set the
stage perhaps for the later session on
intellectual property rights these are
the kinds of things that should be taken
into consideration in determining how to
resolve differences between trademarks
and GIS and by trademarks I mean
trademarks that include gie names the
reputation of the region the reputation
of the mark the length of time that the
either the trademark or the region has
that name has been out in the public the
extent to which the reputation of the
trademark assisted in the development of
the reputation of the region and vice
versa the value of the trademark and
whether the the trademark holder is
likely to be prejudiced or with the
appellation holder be prejudiced if one
is given priority over the other and you
know from the proposed regulations that
CDFA has proposed a a three-year
sunsetting period for anyone who has a
trademark incorporating the name of a GI
you have would have three years to
continue to use it after which you'd
have to discontinue pick a new brand
name unless and this is an important
exception unless your wine or your
cannabis or whatever the product is is
descriptive and does qualify for the
appellation of
to name so no one is putting a trademark
folder out of business they're just
saying you must use that name maybe it's
after three years after a sunset period
you must use it descriptively and
accurately the last thing I'll say about
this and then we'll open it up to
questions is that we are at the
beginning of the Appalachian Program for
cannabis this is what excites me so much
about it that was at the beginning of
the of the American wine appellation
system - it's an exciting time we have
the chance to minimize right now the
number of conflicts between Geographic
trademarks and Appalachians for example
I would say anybody who after the
proposed regulations were more made
public who goes out and registers a
geographic name that later becomes a GI
they should not get the benefit of
grandfathering they're on notice that we
will have a geographical indication
system or an appellation of origin
system for cannabis in California so use
geographic names at your at your
discretion but also at your potential
peril if they later become an
appellation so with that I think I've
kept - my time and I'd love to answer
any questions that you have thank you so
much that was a wealth of knowledge and
I have to admit that I have been flooded
with text messages telling us how how
valuable this has been so far so I
really really appreciate that there's so
much information there it's almost hard
to come up with sort of cohesive
questions but one of the things that you
really hit on was the purpose of the
Appalachians from the consumer
perspective is to be able to experiment
to be able to find and refine certain
qualities of a product that you like
that you want to continue to experience
in the US you mentioned that the Avs are
primarily geographical whereas in the EU
they sort of take into everything into
account right they take in the soil the
the farming practices or the human the
human aspect of that when you're talking
about the ability to communicate - it
consumer sort of the region how helpful
is it to sort of include more of those
factors rather than less like the u.s.
system it seems like that just having
the geographical indicators the bare
minimum
how much more utility is there an
appellation system that has those higher
identifiers z' that we saw in sort of
like those Lodi brands that you brought
up or the other ones there well I think
the answer to that Chris is in part will
a consumer once they know what an
appellation product is will it help them
will they be willing to pay that extra
price will they would be willing to say
now I know what a Mottola Valley
cannabis is like you know I know it's
these cultivars that's grown with these
standards and practices I can rest
assured when I buy the next one even if
it's somebody some other cultivator I'm
gonna find again those things that is
what will allow that customer to pay the
additional dollars to invest in that
region now even in with a Vaz v'n though
we don't have that by legislation the AV
ASR doing it themselves the vendor
grower groups inside the ABA s are
seeking to bring that value add
proposition that education that
guarantee of certain characteristics or
qualities to the consumers and they're
doing it through privatization through
voluntary certification marks and the
like so in the sense gif and
Appalachians end up you know it's a
dynamic they go back and forth
ultimately you're trying to have loyal
consumers absolutely and speaking of
that sort of consumer question this is
actually a question from Rebecca Steen
white who's running our business of
Appalachians panel a little bit further
down the road she's wondering you know
is this a chicken or the egg problem is
the sort of that that consumer
investment and a particular reason what
drives an Appalachian or is the
Appalachian itself and the producers
that are coming up with these
Appalachian what drives sort of that
consumer interest do you have a feeling
about that well it's both but it's the
producers first and foremost they're the
ones who are going to pay for this to go
through this process
they're the ones who know their product
best there are the ones will know what
the collective I mean they're they're
going to be the ones who collaborate on
all the information that goes into a
petition and and they want to express
this to their consumer so I think it's
the the the not just the onus of the
responsibility the desire really comes
first and foremost in my estimation my
experience from the producers but the
consumers you know they're at the bottom
they're the they're the final test this
is why in my class we taste every
product if you if you can't see the
difference if an Appalachians
standards practices and and cultivars
and everything that goes in it is
meaningless then your appellation will
die on the vine sure yeah if it if it
doesn't have those characteristics
they're recognizable for the rest of us
then then what good is it in the first
place I guess is the question thank you
so much Richard we are unfortunately out
of time for this first very very
introductory presentation there is so
much there and four on our next camels