[Music]
have any wood chip shot oh yeah you know
like here's my road slide here's my road
slide which is relevant is some IMO so
I'm like there's my road sliding out you
know there's like my road okay so look
I'm like I reach down oh that's nice
you know so I was like oh bring that
back with me and something but wood
chips jLF that's gonna be like plant
food that's all
that's like all gonna be plant food you
know basically just stems and leaves
nothing fucking fancy and all its you
know but I was gonna make a liquid plant
food out of it so that's the beauty of
that that's kind of what I was the point
I was trying to make earlier it's for
when you intentionally do an anaerobic
jLF where you are putting this stuff in
a barrel culturing it anaerobically
speeding up the breakdown process
instead of nature taking a year having
to put it into a hugo bed so that nature
can break it down or you know whether
you leave it outside let nature do it
whatever time
that's that takes time if you you put it
in a barrel and you go anaerobic on that
it breaks it down in like two weeks it
shit's like gone
you know what I mean it's like mush it's
like and it's like lick and it's
available and the bacteria that the
plant wants are right there you know it
cultures those specific bacteria so
therefore you're out competing out
competing anything that's not beneficial
that's not that's not welcoming because
it's not there it shouldn't be there so
whatever's there is beneficial so if
you're just focusing on not bringing
outside things in and well I mean even
though I am doing well woodchips in my
environment there's there's trees
everywhere so woodchips you legit you
know I'm trying to like you know mimic
nature you know but you know but that's
more of an intentional anaerobic process
process you know
I almost wanted to jLF wood chips I was
gonna like like doing anaerobic wood
chip actually I am because some of the I
have thrown some of my mulch in there
which has wood chips but I'm not really
going for
I should do wood chips and see what they
do
I don't know what do you got on with
chips
I got wood chips this when I was looking
at these are some piles though yeah that
we're oh but I did what I was going to
show you what I originally pulled up was
you know some of the starting material
which like this right here you're
chipping that he's chipping like this
this one right here is a rental
hi I have an 8 inch chipper which could
chip something that size but we use a 12
inch chipper when we're gonna chip this
like we're trimming hundreds of yards
away I so watch I think about chippers
all the time I want one so bad yeah so
this is what I know oh yeah it's just
that thing now this is this is right
here this this is I have no idea how old
it is but it's
what I guess I'm saying I know that it's
been sitting in this pile for twenty
years but I don't know if it was already
starting to break down but what's going
on here is just some really broken down
/ but this is actually straight off of
oh right on
straight off the law baby
straight off yes so we got like like
this pile here I guess it's it's
predominantly like woodchips and worm
castings and that wisteria
hundred-year-old wisteria tan oak leaves
grasses from weed-whacking I mean like
anything that looks good
wood without like raping you know kind
of it's easy to like do the IMO it's a
sensitive thing you know anyone like
over harvest like like the IMO and in
the forest you know it's like mining it
so you really do want to be like really
gentle with it and then and then grow it
in wood chips okay so this is actually
something like I go down this road a lot
so the the ethics of using stuff we have
[Music]
on our property sorry but oh yeah stuff
out it's very obvious for the stuff that
needs to be pulled out but then at what
point does that go into its own way of
forest management so it's live on the
forest floor but it's helping to build
soil for the forest by being there and I
pull it out a Chapman and juice it in my
garden
am i damaging the forest that being said
they're not using it for commercial
production well that's why yeah once you
start reaching that if you you start
questioning your own practices you
really need to start like thinking about
them like like Jamaa methodology would
say you know like young son
going nature grab some vodka
in case it would be like some weed and
go ask the forest how we can use the
forest to do that you know work with the
forest you know what I mean and and just
what's thinning it's great anyway so
it's like the basically maybe like cut
more trees down and and just and just
inoculate piles yes so and then you're
thinning the forests of the forest happy
I've got a flail mower from my excavator
so I can go up to like a 25-foot tree
and even like a 35-foot tree because I
can flail mow the top off and catch the
top in midair and suck it into the flare
mower and vaporize it that's like a
whole move I like a trick move and I've
developed but regardless of that you can
just straight up like slow-mo a tree you
know to the ground you can vaporize the
branches if you want if you you know go
into the branches slowly from the you
know and let the flail mower stuck them
in it'll it'll really just vaporize them
and shoot them right to the ground or if
you want to go in like just like fucking
wild like chunking like just throwing
shit everywhere you can kind of do that
too you know it's like throw shit
everywhere I'll get down to the ground
and then you'll like it's clear and that
works fine too in certain situations you
know but sometimes you just want it more
clean you want to clean it's easier to
clean up too if I you know vaporize it
but clean up with a with a leaf rake is
like easy and then you have leaf mulch
you know like I mean then you have like
mow just like you know mulch up to your
knee you know I mean it's like two feet
three feet thick sometimes it's like
insane how much material that is when
you mulch at all a bunch of you know
wisteria or ceanothus or like some tan
Oaks or redwoods
it's amazing what how much how much
material is there get it to the ground
and then it just feeds and protects you
know erosion and
- you know just physics all on and on so
yeah I love my my flail mower it's a
great way to build up your material you
have that can be composted in a quick
manner anyway to accelerate that I just
yeah you don't have to touch it like
with the chipper but I have limitations
you know on size but you know you end up
with like a piece sticking up so I just
cut that down you know and just toss
we're going to do whatever firewood or
just make it disappear oh yeah I mean
the tan oaks don't die the redwoods
don't die I'll flail mow a redwood down
to it just a little nubby stump as much
as I can get it to the close to the
ground and it'll be in one year it'll be
you know this high again tan oak - they
don't die madronas don't die the furrow
died yeah it just seeds itself really
close like that - I just find it like
just yeah just it's you know so I just
like flail know it and it so I saves me
like you do like ten years worth of work
in like ten hours it's sort of like that
but it's it's a rotary one it's it
rotates this way it's not like this way
you know the blade has a it has flail
teeth on a hydraulic drum that rotates
like this so I have I have videos of it
it shit throws material I mean it's like
a chipper without the chipper it's like
having twenty flying goats like eating
shit like it's insane you have to be
careful yeah it's it's awesome yeah I
would never be able to do the type of
work you know that kind of brush work
manually as one guy a wall of like you
know whatever and I just it's like fun
he just it's like painting he just like
mow it down it's easy I love my flower
I killed the motor on it I was operating
it on high my hot on my hydraulic pump
on high so I was that way I could really
like you know get some production going
on because it was kind of too slow it
was like you have to just kind of go
into a cut like this and it was really
limiting me to like kind of like you
know like work with the you know get
so I brought I brought my pump up what
amount of float what amount of flow do
you need to run like it was like I was
running it at like 25 which might pump
good hand Mike that's my flail mower
pump couldn't handle you know my
excavator Oh what kind of excavator to
many loader I know I wish I did
I need a track floater I need something
with either a PTO or something I need
something either tracks
I don't want wheels but I can't afford
tracks but so I'm just trying to use my
excavator is like the all-purpose you
know do it all I've got a bunch of
attachments for it so I can put any
attachment that fits on a skid steer on
my excavator so you know I've got like a
hookup so yeah I can put like Forks I've
got Forks on it you know I was gonna put
a chipper on it for a skid steer chipper
on my excavator so then I could reach
down the hill yes yes I'm not yes okay
that's what I wanted to hear yeah I was
going to I was curious about that if
that was like a super good idea because
or I could reach up the hill and put the
chipper up in the woods and put the
chipper down in the woods you know and
then actually you know when the hills
are so steep then you just kids like
sidehill drop something downhill and
just feed the butt of it two feet right
into the chipper
and then you don't them move really
you're not moving you're not dragging
brush you're not winching you don't have
to reach down there all the way cuz a
lot of stuff you can't reach you know so
it's crazy what we have to do too you
know what I mean work on the site of
like a hill to me it's nuts
but yeah he knows yeah we live with we
live with woodchips and they usually
have wood chips on my hat I just use
them straight up yeah yeah he was asking
about like that's any screen evening to
me I think eyes they're breaking down
those veins or punished you know they
just break down so easily you just find
a good vein or a pocket
yeah and then it's kind of like I like
the wood chips because they kind of got
like a lot of meat on the bone you know
what I mean they they last for a while
where other things just break down
quicker so you know if you're just like
it takes energy to apply them so you
know you might as well stay around for a
while where like grasses will just break
down quick you know like grasses or you
know plant material breaks down super
quick so you're you know you're kind of
just messing with it you know that's why
I like the wood chips they're just like
[Music]
that's yeah
protein high protein carbs not like
glasses which are sugar
you know like less less less of that but
more and then the jus Dom thing just
breaking down those grasses anyway into
a protein getting the protein out of
those grasses instead of focusing on the
sugars in the grasses you know I guess
you know so I don't know I think that's
something like that it's but I know the
stinkier the better it seems there were
maggots in it I mean seriously like
giant giant like maggots in it I was
like I can't believe I'm really using
this
- kitchen scraps yeah some some gnarly
people turned up in there you know even
though it's sealed
oh there there I don't know how they get
in there I'm pretty they're obviously
there that I don't know I'm not claiming
to like be any like like I really I
don't have a background like science or
a guard you know and I was my dad was
like a sign painter I'm a welder and a
carpenter you know I mean that's like my
background I'm just kind of like winging
it and listening to whatever you know
I'm just yeah I don't know a lot of the
technical terms you know like I'm stuff
just because it's like there's so much
science and information now we've been
maybe I've been doing something for a
long time but you don't know what it's
called how long you been doing a KNF for
the one yeah even I mean I guess I've
been doing G Dom since I've been growing
because I've been doing like this
no-till thing since the beginning you
know so I've been basically and then I
been I find I basically like about like
five years ago I I went anaerobic just
on yeah yeah I went all anaerobic which
was kind of just an experiment because I
had broad mites so then I took all the
plants with the broad mites and
I put him in a barrel and a sealed
55-gallon barrel that was sealed with
the seal top and then added water and
some other you know a couple other
things but basically I just was you know
killed them you know that was a way to
kill any bugs
I deal in the Sun and what I did was
basically cultured I guess an anaerobic
like homeopathic remedy which I then
sprayed on the plants it was just like
spray I was like I I can't even believe
I was doing that I was like I'm actually
gonna do this like this nasty-ass like
and I was just like oh I couldn't resist
us like doing it do it and I just don't
do it my wife was like what the fuck are
you doing I was like I don't know I'm
just I'm just like I'm just like I don't
know I can't I get a watch something's
taking control of me I have no it's just
I have to do this
and so I did it and it and it worked and
it was fine there was like no problem in
fact you know I mean that was the year
that everybody had broad nights there's
a big Broadway from oh what oh yeah yeah
yeah that's probably one of our yeah
yeah yeah that would those are probably
oh no yeah these are I don't know one of
them is yeah this is the most this is
kind of like a mix
[Music]
but like yeah that's the mimosa
yeah that's like white Tahoe that's like
the that's the grow off strain from last
year I'm still smoking it this is like a
year and a half old yeah see I have
three year old need that looks greener
just like this from the when I when I
placed third at their moved up in 2017 I
put out two jars or with two mason jars
away basically you vacuum seal it in a
mason jar and put it in the freezer and
it will stay good for a long time it'll
stay green and like this has been stored
that way this this white Tahoe was
stored look at that yes I mean that's
like a year I got those that's like a
year and a half old for sure every bit
of a year and a half old and it's been a
it's been out of the freezer for a while
yeah you just don't don't just oh you
don't open the jar when you take it out
of the freezer you just let it sit until
it's there you know all the humidity
goes with all the moisture goes away
I guess and just then you just crack it
or sometimes I'll just pull it out of
the freezer crack a jar pop it open grab
some buds while it's like all icy and
shit grab some buds put the top back on
go over to the vacuum sealer reeve a ql
it stick it back in the freezer just
like that that's mostly what I do
that's just like easier that yeah then
you just take your little head stick
whatever half-ounce follow that out you
know whatever let it do its thing
sometimes it's perfect in like ten
minutes you're like it's perfect
whatever you know sometimes it's
sometimes if it's if it's like if it
gets to be like two years sometimes
it'll need
airing you know just yeah yeah at about
like two years because I've got some
like beer over three year old and it
looks literally better than my it looks
just like my my fresh silver like I'm
not even kidding
[Music]
I know that I'm not gonna even like
really like oh yeah yeah no yeah they're
just starting to like kind of break down
probably you know because I've had the
jar out now it's getting oxidized you
know I've been smoking on it yeah but
it's still you know you know what I want
to do now is test this I want to retest
this because I know I had the test from
when I harvested it so now I want to
test stop start testing stuff three or
two and three years later and I can I
would like to prove I would like to
prove that yeah with our techniques we
can keep we'd like at like fresh for
like three three years apparently
style covering ground yeah yo cuz you
did ray did ray tell you about like the
eighths that in jars compared to the
same weed same batch same harvest
in the the weed that street heat
congregated together oh shit now we
fucked up now we don't have any eight
jars but they're dry and like it's
starting to turn the smell is starting
to go but if it's kept in the turkey bag
with the other stuff it's fresh like
vacuum sealed Oh different jars
themselves yeah those jars so we should
do should we should I don't know anybody
that's frizzy flowers and taking it like
storage to the show
[Music]
level shit real like actually
incorporating that and I did let give
that away so everybody could read your
space yeah I mean that could be a thing
and then if you work with the retail or
some specific retail there's like no our
stuff is kept in the freezer and we take
it out and thought for you so it's like
a time machine it's true it's like a
time machine yeah and if we vacuum seal
it
then freeze it and open it won't be Oh
at least it'll be vacuum sealed in the
back and then the jars are just like in
flats and they get even the samples can
be fresher is there so showing samples
that are like super old and oxidized and
oh yeah open closed open closed open
closed for months and then you could
just take out as they need it from your
freezer keep it like a fresh sample like
that's cute quality control right there
I mean cannabis Humboldt sunrise farms
yeah working with the legacy farmers in
over 40 years with a bunch of goats and
worm castings he's been doing a
regenerative leave before regenerative
Lee was the thing
but now we're trying to implement some
of these like an empty fuel beds and
making the transition you know to more
regenerative stuff so hopefully I know
we can talk about some sort of
certification in the future throw it out
there you know there's certifications
yeah whatever the you know any round
it's like it's just beyond that it's all
good but you know it's just like labels
and whatever and you know I
yeah we're trying to figure out
packaging's though ourselves like what's
the most eco conscious packaging you
know like some some corn plastic some
hemp plastic we'll be like will be cool
some vegetable stuff yeah they got some
hemp plastics coming online right here
but we're still rocking like the glass
you know I mean we got our this is what
we're rocking here you can check it out
look we got the Emerald cup thing on
there from 2017 where we took third in
our third decade old living soil with
just water and
one compost tea just as a default and
default style just like one just like to
to compost teas a year to my soil and
and a top dress of woodchips and tie
fungal just you know and and then the
Hugo's like it's kind of like a hugo bed
within a hugo bed so you know it's it's
like yeah basically it's kind of like a
hugo bed inside of a hugo bed inside of
a hugo bed how do you start in the
trench or like oh great i do like a
subterranean pit thing little trench
things well looks like a full greenhouse
size like that's why i have an excavator
that's why that's why i say there's the
more work you put in on the front end on
the back end and i'm not kidding
like you know I don't do there's a big
difference between growing okay here it
is like in pox and then you have you
know on the big pots on the ground then
you got like raised beds on the ground
and then you've got like in the ground
and then there's like subterranean in
the ground you know what I mean which is
it just is some serious magic going on
there but you have to you know you have
to make some impact on the environment
yes forever he'd go for control with it
so as far as because we have Gophers so
you're kind of like a lot of that like
tractor work is almost like because of
Gophers you know I mean case if you're
doing like high production like that you
kind of have to like lock your space in
you know I mean so like do you kind of
like lock it in from the Gophers or or
critters because they'll just fuck your
shit up so you know you got no choice
but to take you know measures but after
a certain amount of years
of regenerative practices cover crops
and soil too it's like okay you might
disturb the soil you know you disturb
the soil initially but it's like okay
because you know what we're doing is
like it's so easy to bring it back with
like make a ji message a Dom microbial
solution which is what I was like using
this year with sea-salt potatoes and an
anaerobic you know culturing of your
microbes in a readily available liquid
form that you can spray through a
sprayer foliar or just water it in so
which is just like solid microbes you
know it's like I like uh like I'll just
as just a layer of just beautiful like
microbes so you just you know just just
trying to out-compete anything else like
not worry about anything else just like
keep on the you know proactive make sure
that it's always inoculated at the good
stuff yeah there's so many beneficial
microbes and bacteria and fungus that
like you know whatever brand or was it
bar'el it was barley barley is just like
kind of invasive cover crops natural
crap I've got some lambsquarters that
shows that I like invasive gardening
techniques you know I mean stuff that
just like in you know it's just like
makes my life easier yeah always they're
like nettles man I was like nettles and
purslane and like chick weed and
different
yeah I got the cellphone that is our
nothing South African ground cherries
yeah they're just like a tomatillo and
vining kind of they'll pop up through
the trellis and out-compete her hands
and I'll just have to step on it and be
like no you chill out right and then you
get some some of those some some good
juices yeah I just like step on them you
know like step on them in there you know
they don't take too much nutrients from
the front I won't even worry
I have potatoes in there oh yeah like
every whatever everything in it works
trying too hard you know you can use
whatever you know yeah hell yeah
whatever's available and yeah it ever
wants to be there I just kind of like
the pull yeah man that's all with it try
yeah that works I'll say Nettles oh
that's what's good yeah
- no you do the horsetail Equus either
oh yeah yeah we have horsetail on our
property our Sabine spring creeks got a
ton of horse tail so we were used we
were going you know we jail left horse
tell ya it was fullering horse tell
what's the jLF process it's your job
yeah that's that's that anaerobic you
know the culturing yeah that's what the
culture more you instead of like
fermenting I don't know it's probably
just like tomato tomahto yeah yeah you
know but like can that KNF we are more
focusing on fermenting oh I feel like
I'm more culturing I'm not really like
fermenting with like sugar and trying to
like do that fermentation you're not
sealing it up yeah you put a
fermentation lock on it I mean it's so
easy it's not even like rocket science
by animal you know it's really just so
easy just that we just you know the
first time I play this is the first year
I played with some horse tail extract
and I you know went out in the morning
got the little new girl Spears of it you
know five gallon bucket of it some
boiling water mashed it up and then
not related with the lactam serious lack
of the soul serum you know let that let
that cook for a week sealed up I mean
the plants did some big things like that
they just went on old mode and the pest
pressure was like yeah I really don't
know what was going on but something
good I'm do do some more of that for
sure this stuff works
yeah it's a really work yeah get some
lab this year yeah would you a foliar I
did a foliar even it like week had like
a couple of some was like leaf necrosis
I show up you know like trying to just
keep the beneficial back to you
yeah buddy look for the labs like do you
harvest them from the air you use in
some em1 because that I just get a
bottle I don't even make this one it was
my buddy made it I know you gave me some
labs so I used it and because we were
like I was like I think I need yeah I'd
like this play because somebody got K&amp;F
like sloppy or K&amp;F crazy on my shit you
know what I mean
so and I they gave me the plague we were
calling it the plague I ended up with
like what we were calling a plague which
was like a leaf necrosis like like
eating like fucking like Leafs we're
stuck like eating into it and like
whatever you don't want to hear it you
know whatever you know it came from the
dude left his sprayer in the Sun okay
with this shit didn't clean out his
square left in the Sun sprayed after
that did whatever basically did whatever
happened in there went on to my plan and
that wasn't good that's not what where I
was going for I noticed someone I said
KNF sloppy some mutant serrations from
K&amp;F done wrong so I had to come in with
like zaimes to just kind of like get
like but at that point the plants were
so loud that that it was literally like
i tearing like they were
and I was like whoa and then I signed
him and it killed it it really did take
out that it took that out but I mean
it's still loud but it was yea infected
the Terps for sure but I feel like I had
to do that because I look it's not what
I wish is a dangerous situation you know
and it was 2019
I got to pay the bills you know what I
mean and not to be like that but it was
like it's a lot that was my only harvest
of the year - I didn't have any so I
really just had to just you know make
sure it was good yeah try not the
spaceship but yeah it was fine it turned
out fine don't work and then I'll add
and then I which I was going to maybe
hit it with the Janome sulfur and the
whole the whole Jidong you know and I
was like you know I just gotta like you
know know do something that I'm is more
reliable like I wasn't ready for that
I didn't made up and they and besides
that and the ethic pressure oh yeah okay
there's that there's a natural cycle to
this we're gonna you know we're gonna go
spraying like three times in the in the
morning I would spray off I would do
spray zaimes in the morning for the
aphids yeah and then I would come
through and and physically spray off
again physically remove them dead bodies
and spray them off that pressure was
like yes they get him off and then I
would let that draw you know dry off and
then I'd come through and spray like
rosemary horsetail whatever I was making
a bunch of stuff like that JMS Jayla
yeah spicy peppers oh no I was just more
going like beneficial you know not past
not necessarily for them you know fight
the past but just for their plants you
know just a restore the leaf surface was
all in like the morning that was the
mother that was like three sprays in the
more he just like that's how every day
yeah every day
three three Oh like whatever as long as
it doesn't you don't even you don't ask
how long it's just for whatever
yeah then forever until for whatever you
need to do otherwise but then once you
get that shit under control then it was
like but never really got super under
control from what I saw I just saw that
they didn't end up in fest they didn't
like to infest in the resin they don't
like to like have babies and prolific in
the resident in the flowers you know so
like it wasn't a big problem it was
really scary
in late bed early flower but cuz you
seem like they're on the buds there on
the bud sighs what's going on man but
after the resin showed up that started
like oh it's protecting itself and we
didn't I don't think we needed to worry
about it as much as we did I'm looking
at their neighbors that really didn't do
shit they just let the green lacewing
show up in the ladybugs show oh yeah oh
yeah I did lady balls I thought they
were yeah you know and they showed up in
such numbers that they thought there was
an infestation of some mutant shit but
they were green lacewing larvae you know
they were just just watch them in the
macro video just chomping away
it's so it's like they've like they need
the Athan pressure so that the
population so the beneficial population
gets to balance you know and I think
next year we'll be able be able to ride
the aphid problem a little bit more
smugly hope I know like I don't even
want to say what what problems we could
have and all of it's always something
hopefully it's not a every other year
he'll give us a break the lack of
extreme temperature in that winter and
like we didn't have much snow and a lot
of it was cold and have a lot of heat
and right didn't have enough heat to
process through some of the food you
know like we were like we fed nitrogen
in coal and conditions you know and they
don't have the Sun to process it a lot
of bad things come out you yeah if you
have like a fire if there's a fire and
the Sun gets well the Sun is like super
inconsistent I mean it's never like the
same twice you know I think like no day
in your life will be the same as a
amount you know of life you know quality
and quantity of life it'll never be as
it's just so inconsistent that every day
the Lovelight levels are different in
your life that'll never be like the same
right now so that's just sure that's
what we're dealing with
that's like maybe that's wrong I don't
know maybe somebody's going to prove
that wrong I don't know
that's somebody something told me so I
don't know just so yeah it's why 2018 is
a little bit different in 2019 yeah
that's why edits drive every year is so
different I mean it is part of the
beauty yeah yes guys why you need tools
in your toolkit to adapt that's where
the full spectrum comes in there's
little pockets lower elevation or the
cold sits for a little bit longer it's a
little bit more humid higher elevation a
little bit more dry a little bit more
intense exposure to the Sun out of the
trees you know and you see the the soil
dries out a little bit differently you
know
different at these different elevations
and microclimates
I don't know trying to stick to the VPD
you know a little bit to get that you
know that Turner pressure going firing
all the time it's tricky because you got
all these you comment in multiple places
that get at different times you know so
I'm thinking about the soil down at 1300
feet versus you know at 2,000 feet and
there's totally different things going
on you know it's a cool little thing to
follow yeah you just gotta like adapt
and try to keep everything consistent
that's what it's all about consistency
consistency consistency so like no
matter whatever you're doing you want to
mean yeah there's like doesn't matter
like do every whatever whatever whenever
it's like that's its consistency
consistency consistency that's what
equals quality I think ultimately
consistency equals quality or I know a
bunch of other shipping course