[Music]
um we're with yummy Karma it's we focus
on Edibles topicals and tinctures um
where we are a little different than a
lot of people is that we're our Target
is women um and a lot of people asked us
when we got into the industry why
because I mean a lot of people kind of
have this idea of what a cannabis user
looks like um you know so uh we wanted
to help change the picture of the face
of cannabis we wanted to help normalize
the products um thank you especially
with a lot of you being moms and stuff
so we're going to hit on three different
things that we kind of want to talk
about tonight that we thought was
important um one of them being that
there was a gap in the marketplace for
women the why we started yummy K in the
first place and actually Jasmine Hub at
our first we were kind of thinking that
going in this direction and our first
women grow meeting Jasmine um you know
I'm sure hopefully you know who that is
um so she was the first one to stand up
and say women please let's make products
for us you know there is a definite lack
in the market um so
I mean two years ago when I would walk
into a collective I didn't really feel
like a lot of the products spoke to me
there wasn't really anything that jumped
out you know like we shop a lot and I
didn't have that feeling when I was in a
in the collective so um that's when we
started focusing on women and when you
think about what does that mean it
doesn't mean just making something pink
um yeah so we were trying to approach it
more in a way of how do we create a
product that fits into your lifestyle it
can be discreet especially if you have
children I know that can be a it's
almost like a shaming thing people
cannot enjoy cannabis the way they can
wine like different alcohol so that
became a major Focus for us whether it
was our branding our packaging the way
we looked at doing things so we're
evening the way our company runs we're
very approachable uh patients feel very
comfortable emailing us all the time
asking us questions and we answer their
questions we don't treat this as
Corporate America even though we're
trying to fit into a really traditional
business model and that's what we're all
really asking for we want this industry
to be just like any other industry so
you have to treat it that way but I
think the great thing about everyone in
this room as far as Canabis is concerned
is we are different and we have to
embrace that and we have to be
approachable we have to answer people's
questions yeah exactly and honestly
women shop differently than men um we
did a little research if you're starting
a business you know if you're going to
do Edibles or something that's going to
be sold in the collectives I highly
recommend that you find someone that
will let you sit in their Collective for
a few hours and watch how the patients
engage with the we used to call them Bud
tenders and now they like to be called
cannabis Consultants
so it's true it's true we'll give you a
demonstration of how men shop and how
women shop so we have samples here
here's what a man does before she even
finishes what this is they're already
putting it in their mouth they walk away
they're like this is I haven't even told
them what it is a woman comes up and
she's like hi what's your name oh where
did you where are you from do you have
any children I do and we know their
whole life story they know every single
ingredient in the product how we made it
at what temperature what time day week
and everything else so there are
differences well cuz usually women are
more likely be like okay so how much do
I take and how long is it going to take
till it kicks in and what about this and
how much do I apply if it's a topical so
we started to realize that a lot of this
information wasn't on the packaging and
it wasn't being addressed and it wasn't
being taught to the Cannabis Consultants
it's a really hard one to break for we
know as centers exact we will have them
again one day when we have like cafes
you know that's what they'll be called
but um so that became a big part of how
do we address you know the problem Gap
in the market exactly so I think this
kind of takes us into they all kind of
lead in together so compliance was
something that was just talked about
Tracy pointed out a very good fact um we
all have to be good players I mean I
know if you look on you know your
Instagram or wherever you can see people
who seem to be in it for a quick Buck
short term they're definitely not trying
to focus on being around in a long time
from now so as far as with compliance
with what we've done including a lot of
legal bills
a lot we have like 10 lawyers yeah there
are things that you can start doing that
um doesn't just include which you should
get a lawyer for this but there's other
things you can do so one of the things
we did was we started focusing on the
Northern Market nothing against you guys
down here in LA but s a little easier
down here than getting into the club up
north if you're making any products
right so San Francisco and Berkeley are
way ahead on regulations whether it
comes to Packaging um the first time we
walked in with the product we were doing
sauce bottles and stuff I was actually
chased out of a collective she's she
stop folling a little bit I was chased
out of the collective by a buyer because
my packaging was not compliant yeah and
you don't want to have that effect
although that Collective did just call
Rec lastek yeah so we're back but um
there are things you can start doing
like for example Edibles you know you
see a lot of products right now that
have pictures of the edible on the
packaging not a good idea it's not going
to be legal in 2018 don't waste the
money into doing that you can do side
things instead if you really want to
show up your products for example we do
potato chips so our bag and if any of
you guys want to look at our products if
you haven't seen them it's um like on
Instagram it's yummy karma.com or yummy
Karma
yummi wasn't the most clever thing to do
at the time um but you'll see that we it
is it's appealing but it is not child
friendly we make sure it's child
resistant I think I went off of what I
was going to say though well we just
became one of the most compliant edible
companies in the state it and that has
kind of led to Media attention so now
yummy Karma you're the most compant
edible company in the state with your
packaging how does it feel that has
gotten us so many collectives to call us
and say I want to carry your product
because responsible so it is a big
investment but it pays off and you don't
want to think about what you can today
you want to think about what you can
sell for 5 or 10 years or if you want to
sell your company someday what what can
you do to set yourself up for that and
so we are thinking of ourselves as down
the line we're not looking at today and
I think that that is what this set
packaging is not cheap so when you do it
you want to make sure that you're doing
it for the long term exactly and when it
comes back to the CL compliance issue we
were fortunate enough to go back to
Colorado
um if you get the chance it's an amazing
opportunity to see how the industry is
unfolding there um we made friends and
had mentors I don't know if you've ever
heard of Love's oven but they were the
second uh edible manufacturing company
to get their license in Colorado and
they gave us a tour and they were very
nice um shared a lot of information and
the one thing they kept saying was over
compliance over compliance over
compliance over compliance because like
Tracy said people the officials the city
everybody that's trying to figure this
out is going to look towards the good
players they're going to want to work
with the people setting the right
example yeah and let me tell you that
you guys are probably the first meeting
we went to we heard someone stand up and
say I have 10 lawyers and I didn't
believe it but they really do and I
don't we looked in we like we have like
$5 in our bank account so how are we
going to manage that but I'll tell you
what it doesn't cost a lot you can go
online go to San Francisco or or any
Collective that you strive to be in or
if you're a grower you know anyone that
you respect in the industry you can even
look on the County's website up north
and they literally will tell you say
this this this this berley Patients
Group is a good one they literally have
like 20 pages of what you have to do in
order to get into their colle nothing
against the lawyers Lisa I don't want to
put it but it's a good starting ground
so if you can follow those guidelines
and then if you're already at that point
and then give it to a lawyer to look
over that saves you a lot of money right
and the compliance actually like we said
goes back to targeting women targeting
women who have children in the house not
having something that is appealing to
children and our bags are now child
resistant as well so and we have I mean
there's other brands that we know like
um Mary Jane I always get it wrong which
one miss Mar the Miss Mary Jan too
many um you know they've switched over
too so there's a lot of us that are
trying to be the good players in the
industry and that's what we need today I
was reading up on weed week and in
Colorado there's a backlash right now um
70% of the cities have banned commercial
uh cannabis so you'll hear a lot in
California oh the vote's going to happen
we're going to be good it's going to be
legal it's going to be fine that's not
necessarily the case right now
everybody's watching and anybody who
messes up could affect all of us so we
need to make sure that we're all in this
together to create a safe in industry
you know so um that's the great thing
about our industry everyone's so
friendly you guys are our competitors
but we don't look at you like that we
all look at each other as friends and
what can I do to help you we talked
about going to Love's oven in Colorado
if you call any company I guarantee you
they will give you a tour of their
facility they will give you advice in
the lease they will help you they'll
point it's like oh yeah I met this
person and I think that they can help
you we're all trying to we're we are all
on in the ground floor we all can can
move up together and that's why you guys
are here right yes so um I think that
kind of leads us to branding and
marketing where we might get a little
harsh um no if you'll notice uh our
products when you were to see them for
instance like in an Instagram post
they're very it's it's obvious what it
is we have big lettering it's easy to
read everything is laid out I can't tell
you how many times when I'm looking
through every morning cuz I'm always
checking to see who's new and who's out
there I can't tell what it is and it
drives me crazy so first and foremost
remember when a patient walks into a
collective and they're looking and they
have all of these Brands they could pick
from you want to not only stand out but
you want to make sure that your product
is obvious because a lot of people are
getting really into the look of it and
um and when you can't put a picture of
it cuz we would love to put a we
actually had pictures on our bags
originally and those and they were
no and they weren't they weren't even
pictures of food for instance we do a
sour cream and onion chip we had a
picture of an onion like a drawing can't
do that so you can do that right now and
not in San Francisco or Berkeley though
but leading up to 2018 you know we're
encouraging other people we see people
come out with this awesome packaging and
you can tell they spent a lot of money
it's a big portion of your budget trust
me and you don't want to get stuck with
it make sure down the road and if you
look at your paging it's great if it
looks great you're just looking at it
but picture how it's going to look when
you're in a sea of 500 products how is
it going to sit on the Shelf is it going
to sit upright or is it going to lay
down like our chips for example we had
to toy around with are we going to punch
holes in each one and have them how are
patients right now you care about how
patients are going to look at your
product and how it's going to stand out
without being child friendly and there's
there's a fine line be difficult so a
little story on one of our mistakes that
we did um so I always think it's good to
share something so that you guys don't
do it um when we started off yummy Karma
we actually had a different logo it was
a Buddha real original um we liked it
I'm half Japanese I was like this isn't
offensive well if you're trying to grow
a national brand or even go
International it's it could be so the
other thing was is it just didn't stand
out there was a lot of people doing a
Buddha um luckily we didn't have a
generic name yummy karma for some reason
people just tend to remember um but we
invested a lot into it we didn't really
you know we bought the trade show stuff
we bought shirts stickers everything
everything
wewh yeah and then we went to a show and
we were like oh we're not the only ones
there's a Buddha no there are all buddas
and it's difficult my advice to you guys
is you can get attached to anything
anything you make any logo anything you
have to be open to hearing what the
market tells you we have ditched so many
products that we were like this is the
next best thing and now it's don't fall
in love with your product um no you can
after it makes you a lot of money but
until then it's it's smart to listen to
the feedback don't get defensive about
things I mean people are they're being
brutally honest but that's kind of what
you want so um it was painful to throw
it all away things that we had to ditch
too yeah and you have to remember we got
some of this advice that you are only as
strong as your weakest product so even
if all of your other products are flying
off the shelves and you have these
strains that are doing really well the
buyers of the clubs are going to
remember the weakest one cuz it's going
to be sitting there and they're not
going to reorder until that's gone so
that was something that you have to
remember you made love product B love it
if it's not moving move on kill it um I
think the final thing which this is the
side effect bring my
job well one one other thing we wanted
to talk about is when it comes to
branding you have to know who you are
better than anyone else out there you
need an elevator pitch and you've heard
that with TV and everything but you
really do need to be able to if you have
someone in an elevator tell them what
your brand is right away have ra have a
one liner like we are a California
Lifestyle brand of cannabis that targets
women that is our brand we're also for
the generation that can up so we have
kind of a younger audience and so we're
able to tell people exactly what we are
we know who we are and that makes it
easier when we work with anybody for
example we have a Distribution Company
call if you're here we love you yeah all
right they're the best that could be
biased yes bied I think think the only
other thing that I was going to bring I
can't remember what the other thing was
well you were going to say that if you
have Kaa in your name oh yeah but
there's people in here that do so unless
you're
Tracy then you're okay unless you're
Tracy if you want to have a commercial
brand that really makes it think about
what's going to work at Trader Joe's so
if you have beer you don't call it beer
so if you have a cannabis product don't
call it can of something you can right
now but in a few years it's going to not
be a brand that maybe stands out you
reminded me all right before I forget um
yeah think about how you if you're
starting a business and I know this
doesn't speak to everyone because not
everyone's doing kind of what we do but
think about where you're trying to head
in the next year two years 3 years down
the road are you trying to create a
boutique type edible where you're going
to make something fresh every day and
you're going to deliver it to the local
collectives and you're just going to
build a local presence an example would
be like uh Pete treats which is actually
up North so I don't know if any of you
know who that is but um they heavily
blanketed the Santa Cruz area you can't
go anywhere without anybody knowing
about Pet's trades and they were able to
do that because you know they can
service that small area when you're
trying to service the whole state think
shelf life and think you know will it
melt you know we're in the Central
Valley where it's 100° thank goodness we
don't do chocolate it would not be
successful we try yeah but think about
all these things because you'll think
you have this great idea but if you
don't walk it through the whole way from
sourcing what you need and you know
looking at food prices all the way
through the distribution channels to the
actual Collective how like you said
earlier how is it going to be packaged
is it going to melt can it get squished
does it have to be chilled the whole
time um if you want to build an Empire
you have to make sure you can actually
service all over the state over the
country exactly we're all rooing for
that and I think last thing is we want
everyone to have fun this is you have to
approach every day because it is always
changing like Tracy said you have to
come in with a smile you have to be
passionate about what you do and you
have to come out to events like this and
you guys already made that amazing First
Step so round of applause for all of you
guys absolutely and we love questions
questions all
right when you guys decide to use a
strain or or flour or concentrate to
make your
Edibles how do you research that to know
that you're getting the topest quality
that you can can or do you grow your own
no we don't grow our own we definitely
Source it um it depends on what we're
doing so for example we
actually don't Focus so much and some
people in the room are going to
completely disagree with this but we
don't Focus so much on whether it's c or
an Inda um mostly because when we
process it and apply it to like the
chips or anything we lose the Turin and
so you're kind of losing a lot of what
determines it so um we actually just
work with a hybrid for that and the way
we actually deal with the indicus dativa
thing is we have a line of tinctures for
example um if you're most of you I'm
sure are familiar it's a liquid form of
cannabis so we've developed sleep
tincture which is called driftway and
what we do instead is we focus on what
we combine it with so this one was
actually developed from my mother she
was on prescription sleep pills for a
long time and um my little sister's in
the room she can attest to this it's
scary um when someone's taking sleep
pills they are incoherent sometimes
should we appreciate that um what we did
is we combined we worked with an
herbalist and we combined it with
chamomile lavender melatonin um and
that's what we actually use to Market
to get the effects of what some people
would want into come for um same thing
for our our lifted tincture we we Market
that as more of a daytime one so the
rest of the people on the Shelf all say
sativa tincture ours doesn't but what we
do instead is we add natural caffeine
and b12
um jury's still out on it
but oh yeah there's th yeah we worked
with an herbalist to enhance the THC or
CBD so we have seven different teamates
four contain CBD and three are solely
THC yeah okay so um we did a line of
Edibles early on and we did it based on
what I was using for my medication and
it was really a lowd dose edible what
was interesting is when we went to
dispensaries a lot of them were like
you'll never sell this because it's not
strong enough yes and we kind of Ste to
our game went said oh you got to make it
stronger make it stronger but we just
felt that not everybody wants to get
whacked out so we left it like that we
went to a conference about a year ago to
a bunch of attorneys pun Lisa but uh
they were talking about the edbl and
they came was an attorney for Dixie
Elixir okay and they were talking about
bosing yes I was learning if you're
going to say that word right and it's so
funny that it's come around to that that
so many people don't know you know this
w't take the edge off so how do you
address that that's actually interesting
because our chips um are considered low
in the industry they're only 50 Mig um
so compared to sometimes you see like a
th000 milligrams in a bar um that
actually also goes back to like a lot of
the people we target are not looking to
just pass out all day um so we consider
a lot of our products micro doing all of
our tines are labeled on the milliliter
so you can know exactly how much you're
getting per milliliter um we do go on
the low end but we've actually found
that the clubs love the micro doing um
Buds and Roses which we're in now Raves
about it and so you're seeing a lot of
professionals women elderly people who
are entering the market um and a lot of
people I'm sure most of you or some of
you have had the experience where you'll
never have an edible again you know it's
like uhuh I did that one time my sister
made brownies one time and I was like
I'll never do it and now I did but it is
it's a dosage thing I mean I can eat a
bag of our chips and I'm fine
I didn't today but um but yeah I'm
curious to know what dose were you doing
for yours I'm what most people would
call a lightweight so I for me to take
the edge off 5 Mig and then I can kind
of dose whatever through the day but
right I'm fully effective
and yeah I I think that you have hit the
market at the right time right now every
Collective we've gone into recently and
I think CX our Distribution Company can
probably tell you the same thing they've
told us that they're able to sell our
products better because they are micro
doed so and they're clearly labeled so
it's not necessarily if you you can have
1,000 milligrams in your package but you
need to let people know that there are
100 doses in there right so as long as
it's marked and they're able to you know
you can't have a square of chocolate
that has 500 milligram and they just
nibble on the corner none of us are
realistically going to do that I'll eat
the whole thing but um so you need to be
able to have it in a form like our
tinctures you can just easily Take 5 Mig
of our tincture so and our in our
package shows you how to do that so I
think that that's a key and that's and
that's and that's how Colorado is doing
it too so and that's what we looked at
Colorado yeah because you're doing a
great job thank you oh thank you you too
did you explore independent sales teams
uh before going with the Distribution
Company or what was the thought process
behind hiring a Distribution Company
versus anything else um well we're
really handson to the point where we
don't think anyone can do it as good as
we can so that was really hard um but we
looked at sales teams
and actually c m is going to become like
a pitch for them um they do sales and
distribution that's why it's such a
beautiful pairing um so they do it all
literally they come they pick it up we
get to focus on what we do best which I
highly recommend we only focus on the
product and making it perfect and we let
other people handle the sales the
distribution now that doesn't say you
know we're backing them up on stuff we
still do a lot of promotions and certain
things like that um to supplement but I
would definitely find a good partner in
the industry who's doing what they do
best because we ran the numbers on doing
our own celles team and distribution and
all that and it honestly didn't make
sense and you're not going to be able to
in 2018 you're going to have to go
through a distributor because um if it's
going to be required so they can cross
check and they can test your product
before it gets on the Shelf so that's
also a good thing to know I wouldn't
invest in a sales team right
now what tpes are in your various
products I'm interested in the Sleep
product uh what turp that you have
decided to include for that's a
very or your Inda right which I kind of
touched on earlier because our process
is proprietary that too too but it's
also heated so um we're working with
along with other edal companies who are
researching actually extracting the
interes before and then adding them back
in but right now that hasn't been yes
yeah so that right now is unfortunately
not really yeah
sorry hi I have a question about
distribution I work for a Distribution
Company and I find that a lot of people
are really scared of me when I talk to
them about what I do or hesit to get
involved and you as a vendor how do you
how did you reconcile that from yourself
so who scar I'm saying talking to
vendors and stuff that come down to
being uneducated well the the
Distribution Company probably doesn't
like me that much because I'm on the
phone with them all the time um and
that's that's another thing but um a
relationship you have to be able to
build a relationship and that's just
like here let me tell you a quick story
goes to this uh we went to a women grow
event and we met a woman who owns three
very high-profile collectives up north
and we watched every single one walk up
to where and go you have to carry our
products you have to carry our products
we walked up and we said Hi how are you
you want to have a drink yeah and we did
that for a full year and we just got
into our we have good times yeah we have
fun that's for sure um so it's about
building relationships in this industry
you can't just walk in with your pitch
and I think that goes to a lot of things
but truly in this business everyone
thinks they're an expert on cannabis
right your next door neighbor your
cousin oh you're in the industry oh let
me tell you about this you know so and
they may be but you need to walk in and
have relationships so you know rather
than and and we just talked about this
we get a lot of emails from a lot of
distribution companies and a lot of
other vendors in their own right if they
started off with a pitch it goes to the
trashman because we really truly don't
have time to take pictures but if it
starts off and it says hey I read about
you in The Economist this month or I saw
you in High Times and wow that was so
great all all you have to do is do a
quick Google search find out what
they've just been in find out a little
bit about them give give us an
introductory line or two and then say
hey I'd love to take five minutes of
your time will you be at women grow La
this month that's a great way to do it
rather than saying hey can I schedule a
call with you I don't we really don't
have time for that we honestly work
around the clock so in order to do that
meet us at women grow pull us aside and
say hey I sent you an email you know it
takes about three times I think and
that's how we build all of our
relationships and that's how the
Distribution Company worked with us too
when I asked that question I actually
forgot about this fact but I definitely
emailed you guys oh did you start with
the pitch I bet you did I bet you did
well we'll give you a second chance I'll
take you out of my trash folder I'll
reread it
okay who
else hi there um I'm wondering how you
advertise and Market I know you're
marketing but how do you do that given
the
constrictions of this whole industry and
then also like are you finding that
you're kind of limited by using things
like maps and you know there's only
minimal um access for people my answer
is easy it's get Crea so we don't look
at the restrictions we've been in for
the economist we've been in all of the
major players we've been on all sorts of
media stations because we don't view
oursel as a cannabis company we view
oursel as a company and that's what
we're all trying to do here we're trying
to just be normal so we sponsor things
for example we're sponsoring the women
grow retreat in Lake Tahoe how many of
you guys are going next month oh no one
oh no you guys need to go that that
event will get you business if you're
looking for vendors go AB um but so we
basically I write news releases and I
don't send them to weed maps and leely I
send them to Fox News and CNN and MSNBC
and so that's how we've been successful
we send stuff of orbs we send stuff to
The Economist and then they start
writing about you and the other people
pick up we do advertise an industry
magazines which has been great I don't
know if Farley from mg magazine is here
um he was one of the first people that
we advertised with and he really opened
yeah he opened the door and introduced
us to a lot of people so we get creative
I was going to say yeah cuz we
originally started going to the shows um
we did like haveon and chalis then we
realized we didn't why are we here
there's nobody that we're targeting um
there's a few but not that many but when
it comes down to advertising you've got
to get like she said be creative whether
it's your social media or whatever but
what we really realized was the smartest
thing sorry the smartest thing to do was
to actually invest into the people
behind the counter of the collective
because it that's how many times you
walk in and you're like I don't know
what I want what what's good and they're
like this is good all right I'll take
that um so what we do is we created um
and I'm going to call them BT tender
buckets because that's what they're
called so when we get into a new
Collective we give all of their Bud
tenders samples of our products we come
in we'll buy them lunch we entertain
them they love us and when people love
you they want to help you for free so um
we realize that investing into the
people who are actually going to be
talking to your customer was really
really smart
yeah think so hi is there an average
industry markup right now for between
your price and the price this charging
yes it seems like they always double it
so um we were told that you're supposed
to do 2.3% markup if you're a collective
but I'm thinking that's by a city um
typically anything that you sell it for
wholesale they double the price um you
can have some control depending on per
se what the product is um whether it's
like really specialty you know celebrity
selling it or that type of thing but um
and milligrams really controls the price
so whenever you're making something just
remember that people tend to look at the
average industry right now is about a
dollar every 10 milligram yes so for
example our chips go for $5 typically um
which is actually a great price point
because it's kind of like a grab and go
thing so
that does play into whether or not like
what you can create so for example we've
got a friend that does um dark chocolate
and it's very expensive so she has a
very hard time doing the micro doing
just because her price point is already
so high so that's good question question
how did you guys capitalize all this
what how did you capitalize all
this where'd you get your money oh okay
um friends and family
that's typically the best way to go
right
now I have two questions um the labs you
test your your shape or your flowers
from where is that and how much did your
certified kitchen cost you to pick out
of we have multiple Labs we don't work
with just one because they tend to have
varying results um that's actually
something that's been difficult in our
industry with um Edibles um American
first Americans for safe access I think
recently did a lot of research on that
and found that um a lot of the machines
that they use for testing was never
really me to be tested with like cookie
matter or potato chip matter in it so it
definitely skews the results obviously
we test all of our base material um we
use SE Labs um SD Farms we've
used I'm not thinking of the one up
north steill Steep Hill yes um so we
tend to work with multiple and we cross
check them because it just seems like
the best thing to do right now your
certified kitchen how much do that cost
you to put out oh
Welling no certified kitchen I mean the
actual space came empty so that was
cheap but um putting it all in you could
spend anywhere from 80 to $200,000
building out I would say depends on your
Machinery depends on what you need and
how automated You Are we almost bought a
chip bagging machine for qu million
dollars thank God we didn't do that
because it was really not that great
when we saw it I mean really people
catch things a lot more than automation
we were like yeah we'll just get this
machine and we'll just let it run all
day that's not the case it still took
just as many people to run the machine
as it did to do something that was more
rudimentary for packaging so um don't
get sold by
salespeople on on their shiny Machinery
it's very tempting you're like super
excited cuz you're putting out like
thousands and thousands of bags a day uh
go to the like actual facilities we've
taken tours of manufacturing companies
we've seen it all run and now we know
exactly like what pieces to get because
it's costly we did buy one piece of
machinery and it doesn't work and it was
very expensive so I was going to say
also we hired a former FDA inspector to
come through because they won't know
current FDA inp ector is going to come
through a cannabis and do this so we
hired someone to come through set it all
up for us and we paid him so that once
we are able to run in a legal manner or
at least in a way that we're same with
manufacturing right same with
manufacturing we hired people who worked
at huge plants to come through and say
this is what you can do and this is what
you can't do because you know we didn't
want to wear a hair inet but we do think
about it we're doing food and cannabis
it's like the worst idea ever it's the
best idea but it's like the worst cuz
you're dealing with the health
department food County all that and
you're trying to deal with a new like
the compliance issues of cannabis
anybody in the ancillary business out
here smart very smart yeah
need okay I know we're not supposed to
do anymore but
okay that
come
okay lawyers yeah we we do read
everything they send us and like Tracy
said it's constantly changing so it's
scary when you're making decisions about
where to even get your permit or certain
things cuz they can literally pull the
rug out from under you um we know
someone who I think might be in the room
but he had a got the license in
Washington and was totally ready to go
and then his County banned it so um
basically the you it's it's a lot of
risk but it's high risk High reward so I
mean just trying to stay on top of
everything the best thing you could do
really is just get good legal advice I
would say and we've got a lot of good
lawyers if you need some I think her
question was specifically about the
adult use initiative that's coming up in
November how would that affect you well
by being one of the more compliant or
most compliant companies now in the
medical we're looking at what Colorado
did which is they only gave licenses to
people who were doing recreational and
had that license or excuse me medical
and had that license before they could
get recreational um so the main focus
right now and if I'm hopefully answering
this right um if you want to get in the
recreational game make sure that you're
around in 2018 with the medicinal game
because that's who's going to get their
license
first excellent all right well let's
give the two of
these
oh