the Israeli scientists because
neutrophil not cool mccoullough Mikula
he's the one who discovered THC about 25
years ago and then discovered the
receptor sites or at least worked on the
team worked on those and has also been
involved in some of the endogenous
cannabinoids natural substances we all
have in our brains and bodies as well
still very active right are those coming
to endorphins or they're a different
group of chemicals also endogenous
though that use different receptors
there are different receptors for the
opioids morphine and codeine those two
substances so the endorphins are among
these agents that help energize the
neurons to put out transmitters in
various centers of the brain and
cannabinoids or the components of the
marijuana leaf are yet another system
pharmacological system so that
endogenous system I think they call it
the endorphin like substance in some
Anatomy it's a Septon and amide yes the
one that is best developed it also uses
the so called cb1 receptor cannabinoid
one receptor and such as THC does and
then there's another one that's 2 AG
Iraq and Daniel glycerin Wow
which is another of these and endogenous
cannabinoids like substances have they
identified the primary action of this
receptor system
there are many actions actually there
the receptors have been identified and
cloned actually and they can be cited or
located in various parts of the brain
that had to do with pain perception with
movement control with control of
vomiting with warm and pleasant feelings
with sedation and so forth so they're
common throughout the brain so that
there is definite what should we say
therapeutic action of these substances
would that be well I mean that I
wouldn't say the actions that you
mentioned seemed to me to be therapeutic
in nature could be therapy but they
might be exploited for therapeutic uses
that's correct because there are these
systems yes in place and that's the
reason I'm sure that people have found
some utility for the use of these
cannabinoid substances before the
president of the Institute of Medicine
asked you to be a co-investigator can
you tell us about the process that led
up to the Institute of Medicine
conducting this inquiry yes the White
House Office of National Drug Control
Policy which is directed by Barry
McCaffrey ask the Institute concept to
consider such a study and was willing to
fund it about the same time a major
foundation also thought this would be
worthy of study but the Institute
thought it better and so did it
apparently general McCaffrey
if only the one sponsor were responsible
and so a proposal was made to the his
office by the Institute staff
which led to a statement of task so
called and then the funding of the study
what was the mandate from the Office of
National Drug Control Policy on that
didn't they exclude they just wanted the
medical report nothing to do with
science sir well there's no that's the
science yes they wanted the scientific
basis for any benefits or harms that
might come from the medical use of
marijuana or its component substances
and we were not restricted but we were
not picked either to address issues of
social legislative regulatory etcetera
kinds of considerations I think it would
have been a very different statement of
tasks and a very different group but it
would not have included me were you
involved at all I know that the
Institute of Medicine produced to report
15 years before regarding marijuana not
specifically as medicine there was
viewed that oh absolutely I was not that
was in 1982 and it was frustrated by the
lack of clear science rigorous
experimentation and called repeatedly
for research in various fields in the
meantime there's been a explosion of
knowledge in the basic science field all
of these an and amide and receptors and
neurotransmitters and sighting of these
things and various control areas in the
brain have been elaborated so we were at
a distinct advantage over the people who
did that study and we hope we carried
things a bit further because of that new
science could you address that explosion
in science and discovery of the receptor
system and a bit
- for our audience well it really was
the identification of the receptors
themselves cloning them citing them
wherever they were found both in the
brain and peripherally the CB - that
cannabinoid - receptor is primarily in
the immune system and more peripheral
nervous system and CB one is primarily
in the brain these endogenous
cannabinoid like substances that I've
mentioned were elaborated and a good
deal of just straight pharmacology done
on them so that we had the advantage of
oh for example showing the effects in
animals on pain and showing the effects
on control of motion things of that
nature from these basic science advances
they were really quite remarkable and
pretty exciting - an internist clinician
like myself had no idea that he had
existed