we want to let everybody know that we're
law-abiding citizens and that we respect
the law so let's relax it and tax
it got to have it relax it and
tax nothing but the blood of
Jesus Oh preious Legalize It Legalize It
Legalize It Legalize It
[Applause]
and
I
ioke and I
[Applause]
[Music]
it
fre
now
now free down
[Applause]
freee
[Music]
[Applause]
legal legal legal legal legal
legal
[Applause]
to run on H foil one acre yields 300
gallons of biodiesel do you want your
fuel dollar going in the pocket of an
arrow Chek or an American Farmer which
would you rather see your money too how
many American boys have to
die give me weer give me
[Applause]
death