Thank You Ted thanks everybody for being
here I'm Tobias read I'm a Beaverton
state representative and I hope not only
to follow Ted wheeler on stage but into
office as State Treasurer you know
Oregon is a pioneer we're not the first
state to legalize but we're still well
ahead of the curve it means that the
decisions we make in Oregon are going to
be the ones that the rest of the country
looks to when they legalize all over the
state legal cannabis businesses are off
to a really strong start exceeding
expectations 14 million dollars in sales
in January alone that doesn't even count
medicinal marijuana and when extracts
and edibles come online that is going to
only increase the number but because the
federal government is dragging its feet
it's leaving states like Oregon in a
bind banks and credit unions can't
confidently extend their services to
legal cannabis businesses without
risking the violation of federal law and
imagine how dangerous and scary that is
for cannabis business owners perhaps
some of you are among them you have to
keep thousands of dollars in cash on
hand to meet payroll to pay taxes and
buy inventory and supplies we have to do
better than that and while we haven't
solved all our problems that's one of
the reasons I helped to pass the
cannabis banking bill in Oregon in the
legislature the federal government still
needs act but we're one step closer by
removing criminal liability in Oregon
for the provision of banking services
we're helping to remove those duffel
bags of cash that are moving around our
neighborhoods and putting businesses and
neighborhoods at risk we've got lots
more to do but this is an important
first step and I hope you'll all be with
me as we continue that effort I
appreciate you being here and wish you
great luck on a successful event thanks
very much