you know we're marching in conjunction
with over a million people around the
world there's over 400,000 people
marching today in Santiago Chile almost
200,000 people today in Buenos Aires
Argentina 50,000 in Toronto Ontario you
know we've got some regulation in
marijuana people are going to jail our
legislators done a good job in making
some good changes a few bad changes but
some good changes but there are a lot of
people still going to jail around the
world and this is the global marijuana
march and we need global marijuana
freedom and so until we have that we
aren't going away you know marijuana
prohibition was never really about drugs
marijuana prohibition was always about
money and power and the further
centralization of economic and political
control marijuana prohibition is really
about energy it's really that we can
drive our cars on hip fuel and we will
when we can grow high THC cannabis
without regard to its THC content but
for the varieties that produce the best
seeds and the most seeds over 400
gallons of hip seed per acre with a
byproduct of four tons of high protein
food at 40 tons of fiber we can not only
give the world clean energy we can wipe
out world hunger with the seed meal left
over we can stop deforestation with the
byproduct of fiber we can decentralize
wealth by taking money out of the hands
of Exxon Mobil the Saudi sheiks the
Nigerian despot instead of having all
that money go in to their bank accounts
in the Bahamas the Caymans the Swiss
instead of it going there it'll go into
our farmers pockets and that money will
enrich shuts all and that's the main
reason that marijuana was prohibited
it's really about
battle between the natural cycle and the
synthetic cycle and the people who
brought us the lies about marijuana the
misinformation campaign are the
petrochemical pharmaceutical
military-industrial transnational
corporate elite fascist sons of a
and when we could restore him
for fuel we will change our whole
economic paradigm and reestablish
freedom you know freedom isn't just
about speech assembly those are
important it's also about consciousness
and feeling good and hip grows on trees
it should be cheap it should be
plentiful when we start growing hip for
fuel the whole world will change
medicine will be cheap our economy will
decentralize and we'll have a
sustainable world and that's the goal
and that's why I marching today want to
thank you guys for coming out here keep
working until we restore hip