it's so great to be here my name is Ted
wheeler I've got to say it excites me to
have been here today to talk to some of
the cannabis industry leaders some of
the cannabis industry entrepreneurs I am
enthusiastic because they are excited
they're pumped their visionary and
they're excited about the economic
opportunity of this industry for our
state for our region and of course for
the great city of Portland the people of
this community is you just heard
overwhelmingly voted for a legal
regulated tax cannabis industry and as
long as I am the treasurer for the state
of Oregon which is only about seven
months and as a candidate for mayor of
Portland I promise you that I'm going to
do everything I can to uphold the will
of the voters in this community I think
there's a great amount of energy here
today this is a pivotal time for our
country for our state for our city but
folks let's be honest there's a lot more
that we need to do I've heard from so
many of the entrepreneurs about the
importance of making sure that Portland
remember obtains its place as a
respectful and open community to the
industry if we do that what's going to
happen is people are going to want to
open businesses here they will want to
employ people here and that can only be
a good thing for our economy let's also
understand that under measure 91 there
were rights that are ascribed to medical
marijuana patients they deserve a safe
respectful indoor location to consume
that was the intention of measure 91 and
we should work hard to uphold that
intention we also need to acknowledge
that the entrepreneurs that were here
today only a year ago they were
criminals and they were treated as such
under Oregon law and we have to
acknowledge that there is a path here to
help make sure that fresh start Oregon
which was created with the legislature
and other efforts including expunging
over
thousands of Records criminal records
that were nonviolent in 2015 is help
getting people back to where we need to
be as a strong community at the end of
the day here's what we've got to do
we've got to acknowledge the cannabis
industry for what it is it is legal it
is regulated it is taxed and it's a
tremendous opportunity to uplift our
community help get people employed
reduce income in income disparity which
we all know is growing across our nation
or state in our community and it can be
a great boon to our community done right
and done well and as your mayor I'm
pledging to do that