Mar
the
Tre
help
Mar
think
the voters of the state of Washington
passed an
initiative and the voters in the city of
Vancouver passed that initiative by an
even larger margin
54% said yes to the legalization of
recreational use of marijuana we're
pleased in the city of Vancouver to
support the voters of our community
we're going to have six up to six
businesses operating in the city I'm
happy to be here to kick off this
opportunity with Main Street marijuana
I'm pleased to see so much energy and
excitement around this from our
community so please enjoy do it safely
do it within the law support our local
business I'm proud of what these guys
have accomplished I know they want to be
good neighbors they've outreached to the
businesses and the neighbors here in
Uptown Village and I think this is a
great this is a great turning of a new
chapter for the city of Vancouver thank
you to each and
everyone all
[Applause]
[Music]
right all right man yeah come on
everybody number one
[Applause]
one it's just it means like you know
just pretty much we're getting our
freedom to smoke I me and you know what
I mean it's a it's for everybody now not
just it's not limited anybody
everybody's got access to it now and you
know and it's you know the the taboos
are like over you know what I mean how
it impacts me personally just because
it's i' I've been around it for so long
so like I it's it's nothing really new
for me but I it just makes me happy to
see that everybody can enjoy it now you
know you don't have to worry about going
to jail now not having to worry about
being persecuted or you know arrested
for or harassed
and part of History 3:30 this morning
got up here from s at 3:30 this morning
and didn't line ever since
so I I'm hoping it was we'll find out
here in about 20 minutes when it get
somewhere where I can enjoy it good
thing for oh yeah great thing for the
country not just Washington but for the
whole nation really you know it it's
bigger than Washington this is the
really a huge step Colorado took the
first one we took Washington took the
second I'm just glad I was part of it
the price will come down as soon as uh
Supply meets up with demand um prices
will come down and it'll be marginally
higher than what it was on the streets
just to compensate for taxes and I'm
willing to pay that um to be able to do
it legally and not be persecuted for it
and you know if the state can generate
income and fill up some Gap budget GS
hey I'll smoke a bowl for schools any
day you know you know for me it means
that we can actually start funding our
schools putting more money into our
police departments and hopefully find
the cure for cancer