in Canada which is basically the only
place in North America where you can
legally produce any hemp right now uh
the main product is seed and the grain
that correct what's the use of the fiber
that's produced is it the farmers
growing separately for fiber and
separately for grain in the initial
beginning we were growing the taller
stature cultivars that came over from
mostly from the Ukraine but now that the
you know industrial hemp has been
legalized in Canada since 1998 they've
developed breeding programs to actually
breathe for short stature cultivars and
that we wouldn't read ealing with a
fiber so we have with the hold up right
now is that we have a lack of decor
dication equipment and this is an
infrastructure that it's going to take
to actually decorticate the fiber so
you're getting the vast and the herds
separate for whether you're going into
animal bedding composite application or
into ahem Creek or building pressboard
types of applications and also you're
not able to haul the vales completely
across the provinces so you need to have
them really regionally located closer to
where the grower groups are because if
not it becomes an economical to be
frating bales on the back of trucks to
facilities that are hundreds of miles
away is there a paper production going
on in Canada with that no no no there is
a little bit of fiber that is coming
into the u.s. to be made into some
artisan type papers but not on the scale
we need I mean it's a huge business
opportunity to recognize the fact that
there's a growing demand for the hemp
building now you have all these other
kind of interesting products and
mandates from companies to actually go
green and use these type of green
composites in their in their parts so
it's an opportunity for somebody to
recognize the fact that you know we do
have this production we have farmers
that are looking for another venue of
you know increasing the farm gate and
that's one of the major ways to do it is
to take this fiber