my name is andrea herman and i've come
to oregon state university
as a co-lecturer for wse 266
ecampus course on industrial hemp
underneath the
college of forestry's renewable
materials section
well over the last couple of days i've
learned that here in oregon there are a
lot of press board factories and of
course since you have ample amounts of
wood here but we are also focusing on
how we can
change the dynamics of how we're using
those wood products and looking at what
other products we can incorporate in
also i've learned that there's been a
decline in the need for the grass seed
production here so that opens up acreage
for hemp cultivation
we also have companies here that are
already milling products into
powders and food grade products so
that's something that oregon
oregon can readily pick up and include
in their production and market zone
i think here in oregon particularly you
know you want to call up senator white
in merkley's office and tell them thank
you
let them know that you're a constituent
and that you care about this issue and
and let them know if you do have any
concerns about industrial hemp in your
area
and beyond that if you have family and
it's in any other state
call them talk with them start talking
about this at lunch at the supper table
make that communication flow start to
open up
and i think we're never going to have
that federal bill pass unless people
voice their opinion
so like i say if you're if your senator
is already a sponsor
call them and say thank you if they're
not a sponsor call them and let them
know and don't just call once call more
than once
have your your family your colleagues
your husband your kids make the phone
call the more phone calls we make the
diff
the better and the more difference it
will end up making in the long run
don't give up yeah don't give up i think
you know i mean for me this is something
that you know
was a dream for me i i felt passion and
and i had a lot of desire to see where
hemp was going to go
it became a passion it became my dream
it became a goal internally and
externally
and fortunately enough i i stuck with it
and and that's what's led me down this
path
so i hope that other people will be able
to follow in in my path
and through this course being offered at
osu it's really going to open the
opportunity for people to really follow
their dream academia wise
and then be producing professionals
coming out of
the universities that are ready to go
into the hemp marketplace and and
provide background and institutional
knowledge that otherwise we
don't have right now in the sector