and now here's the host of your show
Paul Stanford and Paul Loney hello and
welcome to another exciting edition of
cannabis common sense we are a
production our show is a production of
our Oregon political committee campaign
for the restoration and regulation of
hemp and we sponsor a petition here in
Oregon the Oregon cannabis Tax Act and
we are in the final month of our
petition drive we need your signatures I
am one of the chief petitioners on that
my name is Paul Stanford and I'd like to
introduce you to our attorney he is also
our treasurer
a fellow chief petitioner on the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act and the president of
the Oregon Wildlife Federation mr. Paul
Oni thanks Paul we're back again the to
Paul's Paul said we're here to talk
about our initiative among other things
and to bring some common sense to this
the this whole sort of war on drugs
madness warrants some drugs madness you
know it provides you with the answers
then you know and then maybe if you have
questions call us up and leave us alone
try and answer those but we do have a
phone number in our office 503 two three
five four six zero six that's our phone
number you can call there and get more
petitions ask questions about our
petition and and that's also you know on
our petitioners that dress the mail back
in once you have signatures on there and
we need them all back now if you've got
signatures now is the time to mail them
back to us we have to have all of our
signatures by the end of this month by
the end of June and if you have them
mail em in if you don't have them call
us at this number two three five four
six oh six yeah definitely you know
we're here to to try and get this
initiative on the ballot to get to the
debate out there's some real information
this is on a belt we're gonna have real
debate real facts getting out there some
of that's missing right now that's one
of the reason why you know we found that
our our show here cameras common sense
is so popular is that we're providing
common sense
you know some real answers about this
whole issue and I'm sure is probably
some of our you know what the Portland
is a fine it's watching this show and
you know it's like I like you folks if
you're watching to stop and think about
it you know it's like you know think
about what you're doing and and why
you're doing it I mean it's just it's
just a hopeless nuts because you're
following orders hopefully it's not
because you want that next paycheck yeah
stop tyranny stop arresting nonviolent
marijuana offenders support the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act call us you want to
tell them what doctor will do well yeah
and thanks Paula for minding me octa
will will allow doctors to prescribe
medical marijuana to patients at cost
through they can then pick up at a
pharmacy you can go to your local you
know Rite Aid or Walgreens or Fred Meyer
or any any pharmacy of your choosing and
and pick up your prescription they're a
lot easier than try and find a black
market
another thing that'll do it will allow
our farmers to grow industrial hemp in
which they will give them put them in
the forefront of the emerging market
around the world for industrial hemp you
know cannabis taking off on industrial
hemp movement now Europe's been on it
for a few years now the US has fallen
behind in this new emerging market it's
like if say 20 years ago the US said ban
computers here the rest world would have
leaped ahead with computers and we'd be
sitting here doing nothing and and it's
a good thing we didn't you know and a
good analogy because right now our
farmers are falling farther and farther
behind Canada this year has allowed the
first commercial hemp crop yeah so in
Europe its subsidized more than any
other crop yeah because they realized
the benefits of it which we can get into
a little bit later but the other main
aspect of our initiative which would do
and be allow sale to adults so long sale
marijuana to adults through state-run
stores ie the liquor store system or in
bars and clubs the bars and clubs would
have to sell alcohol but they'd be
license and run just like a the
today you know it's well yeah you know
so it's regulated so you know people
know what's going on and then that way
no minors can have access and then of
course they would that would be DEP
aspect would be taxed directly I know
adult recreational sales would be taxed
and I think that would raise more money
than the lottery we really can't
quantify it officially well and then
also to I mean people are thinking more
and more about you know the law is not
such a good thing I mean there was a
proposed initiative this year about bein
lottery here in Oregon but they backed
off for a while I think partly because
they realized there wasn't the
replacement revenue but something like
this could be the replacement revenue
for a lottery lot of people don't like
the lottery because specially video
poker a lot of people get addicted to
that so easily and then there goes our
whole paycheck and and so this could be
the way you know this could be the
answer and part gonna raise a lot of
money when we regulate marijuana yeah if
Oregon's the first state to regulate the
sale of marijuana to adults then we're
gonna put our industries at the
forefront of an exciting new industry
we're gonna just make lots and lots of
money there farmers are gonna be happy
the tourism industry is gonna be happy
the liquor store owners are gonna be
happy the bars and coffee shops that get
a license and don't let minors in
they're gonna be happy well and all the
small little crafters out there who can
take industrial hemp products and make
them into clothing you know with
different fiber making it into food make
it into oil there's a lot of things they
can do and you know I think that we'll
have a much healthier population here
because of other medicinal use you know
being you know it's because they'll be
up to a doctor and a patient for what
its prescribed for you know there's not
a checkoff list saying okay this is what
only the only way you can prescribe own
things you can prescribe marijuana
forming this list here you know it's
like now it's up to the doctor and up to
the patient because we know that you
know medical science you know they're
discover new things every single day and
so moves
say that tomorrow they may find another
good use medical use for for cannabis
it's true you know there are several
different compounds in cannabis or
marijuana that have medicinal benefits a
lot of people talk about THC or
tetrahydrocannabinol and that's useful
for lowering nausea however if you're
pretty nauseous might be hard to keep
that pill down there are other things
though that THC doesn't treat but that
marijuana does and that's because it has
other compounds that are medicinally
effective one of them is cannabidiol or
CBD and that controls muscle spasms and
has an analgesic effect then their CBC
and cannabic Romijn and that is an
antibiotic and has some other medicinal
properties those drugs aren't available
by prescription they're not synthesized
and sold pharmaceutically the way that
marijuana is so we want our farmers and
[Music]
industries to have access to just those
items so that they can raise lots and
lots of money you know yeah I think it's
you know it's it's a fascinating thing
and you know one thing I want to talk
about is how just oh really recently in
Washington County for the first times
that I'm aware of an attorney was able
to raise the choice of Evil's defense in
a case of a patient multiple sclerosis
patient who was found growing some
plants you know this patient said that
he tried you know you know buying on a
street and black market but that was
expensive and it was scary you know he
didn't like having to drive you know
down to Portland here when the cannabis
buyers club was operating you need it
you know he didn't like that whole scene
and so he just well you know grew a few
plants at his home there because it
helped him out he said he helped
momentously multiple sclerosis I've seen
multiple sclerosis patients use
marijuana I've seen them locked in a
spasm we're almost convulsing and taking
they couldn't swallow a pill and keep it
down and wait an hour for it to take
effect
but a puff or two of marijuana Ellis
yeah what you know and that's what this
gentleman said then and he was able to
they brought in a doctor who testified
that yes you've seen you know it worked
and documented case he had documented a
scientific study of this patient and ms
elsewhere and it at work and they
although the jury still convicted as
person I think it's a victory the fact
that the media reported the fact that
there was a choice of u.s. defense and a
medical doctor testifying as an expert
that the fact that marijuana is
effective for multiple sclerosis I mean
I you know think that's a great victory
you know overall for the movement but
it's a you know defeat for the
individual right you know this
individual I mean I hope that you know
that they don't sentence him too harshly
now you said he didn't want to be a
poster boy for the legalization of
marijuana movement but he was willing to
accept that role because he shoved upon
him well we're we don't need to shove
this role of a convicted felon this role
of deviance on any more people yeah
especially a you know a patient a
medical user hears somebody who has you
know a horrible disease condition am not
sure if to call disease or condition but
somebody who has this I mean it's just I
mean people have this you know it's just
horrible to have and you know and I
think anybody who knows an MS patient
realized that they definitely have great
benefits from using marijuana
medicinally and so once again folks give
us a call so we can get this initiative
on the ballot and so allow doctors and
patients to have freedom to choose and
freedom of privacy what to prescribe 503
two three five four six zero six and we
need register or grand voters to sign
our petition and circulate our petition
if you only get your own signature on
there or yourself and your partner's
signature that's great send that back in
if you've got them in there and
on your dresser at home mail that back
in now as Paul said this is the last
month this is crunch time
yeah we're rapidly counting down to the
end of our petition drive we need all of
our signatures by the end of this month
by the end of June if if it comes down
to the last week of June and you've got
some signatures for us don't put those
in the mail call us at this number we'll
come and get them or you can come drop
them off at our office anyway call us
and get involved we're looking to
contract with petitioners right now to
pay them for circulating our petitions
so if you need work or you know someone
who needs to earn some money call us at
this number two three five four six zero
six and we'll pay you you know some
petitioners earn a lot of money I would
say the average petitioner out there is
going to earn about twenty or
twenty-five dollars an hour
a lot of petitioners can earn better
than that so call us at two three five
four six zero six one petitioner just
last week got over 1,300 signatures on
octa in a four-day work week and there's
more that people can do so call us two
three five four 606 yeah and getting
back to our discussion on the judicial
use of marijuana you know there's a
increasing o dialog going on right now
among cannabis activist cannabis users
about the fact that people are saying
more and more that all use of cannabis
is medicinal that we shouldn't be afraid
to state that that the fact that
everybody uses it too weathers to relax
and unwind that's like medicine I mean
like some people take an aspirin to help
them relax after you know a little
headache after a hard day of running or
you after your muscles are tight or
playing tennis whatever or some people
relax with a you know alcohol and and to
that that's medicine you know anything
that anything that changes your state of
mind is medicine according to some
definitions and you know people say we
shouldn't be afraid of that
say that all use is medicinal and that
should be up to the to the user to
decide how they want to medicate
themselves exactly and in a lot of cases
people are medicating themselves
medicinally for a variety of different
things that aren't recognized
traditionally in science like depression
I've known people who have depression
who've given up very dangerous drugs and
just use marijuana and find that it
controls their depression better than
the very dangerous drugs do yeah I mean
it's just you know I mean I'd say I
think it's just an interesting dialogue
that's starting to happen among some
people who are who were just have the
the checklist mentality of you know
marijuana is only good for these these
specified things and and if you're try
and say it's good for anything else why
then you're just you know harming the
cause and and I don't know I'm still
learning myself on that but I'm trying
to think that more and more you know all
use of cannabis is medicinal I know that
dialogue is really taking place in
California which is in total at the
forefront these days of medical
marijuana and the attacks by the federal
government and the California Attorney
General and you were mentioning earlier
today about the would happen down there
with Dennis Peron exactly Dennis Peron
was one of the people who came up with
the concept of pushing for medical
marijuana politically through the
initiative process
he passed an initiative in the city of
San Francisco back in back I think it
was like 77 that got 70% of the vote the
highest plurality in any election ever
in San Francisco for medical marijuana
passed another citywide San Francisco
proposition to de-emphasize and defund
all marijuana enforcement by the city of
San Francisco then back in 95 and 96 he
organized a statewide Medical Marijuana
petition known as the compassionate use
California's for compassionate use and
that passed and it's caused the federal
government a lot of heartache
headaches I should say and a good thing
too because it's brought the debate to
the forefront yeah it is I mean it's it
makes the federal government look like
hypocrites if they take medicine away
from people you know in a state where
California said marijuana is medicine
and here's the government coming in
taking away people's medicine I mean you
know it's just bad PR you know they you
know they still don't know how to deal
with it yet they've raised some mclubbe
down there and then Dennis Peron had to
close his club yeah he said and admitted
that he had helped us apply marijuana to
other clubs and that wasn't specifically
written into his initiative and so the
judge reluctantly said signed an order
to close the club but the police chief
and the district attorney in San
Francisco Hallinan and the mayor Willie
Brown all said that they support the
club and the next day in reopened and
hazel Rogers took over the cannabis
buyers club in San Francisco the largest
in the nation and she's a 72 year old
grandmother and the city endorses her
running the club and of the state
government the feds tried to close it
down in a subsequent injunction but the
judge wouldn't issue the injunction so
that's where it stands as of would we're
taping exactly and then you know part of
the fact that he was supplying to other
clubs but also he was also he's a firm
believer than all use is medicinal
exactly and you might say he's he as far
as I know he came up with that concept
yeah I mean I and and that's he is the
one that's you know brought to the
forefront you know even for that you
know for the checklist mentality folks
you know there's two two camps in
California people for medical marijuana
there's you know Dennis Peron and other
people saying that's like what we have a
doctor in a patient want and then
there's the checklist folks that saying
it's a line for only for these things
and the the checklist folks had a lot of
money still have a lot of money but
they're losing
you know the public opinion is not on
their side a public of pain in
California saying it's like what's the
big deal and you know it's up to the
individual you know and whatever doctor
you know our initiative goes just a
little bit farther than that we
implement the production of marijuana
according to the guidelines of
international treaty now the courts have
ruled that international treaties have
the same weight as the Constitution so
we complied with the conditions set by
the Single Convention treaty in the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act we use their
specific controls in terms of the
licensing requirements requirements
under the Oregon cannabis Tax Act yeah
you know and of course now that there's
a movement of fun a front foot in the
United Nations to change that you know
single convention to make it stronger
because they realize people like us and
other people around the world are
starting to say hey you know this is a
way to regulate it to get it back from
you know the underground and and the
black market bringing above-ground so
exactly we pioneered that so there's you
know there's movement afoot to tighten
it all up and so it's real interesting
you know I know there's you know folks
over in Europe right now being really
strong keeping an eye on that because
they've got a strong movement over there
and a lot of these they had a big march
in London recently so that's you know
and didn't get a lot of publicity here
in the u.s. of course you know as a
major major march and protests in London
and about freeing cannabis right and you
know if they're trying to strengthen the
treaties to stop our ability to do it we
better strike now while the iron is hot
hot we better
seize the day carpe diem call us at two
three five four six zero six because you
need to get involved to stop the war on
drugs as I've often said and Paul might
be getting tired in you to hearing the
war on drugs I firmly believe is the
issue on which the future of freedom in
America hinges help us protect freedom
help us restore him call two three five
four six zero six yeah the one draw
is a wait for the powers that be the
ruling class the owning class run a
column to control the rest of us to
control probably the 80% of us that you
know don't own everything in the world
you know that those of us that just want
to live you know and in a in a society
of tolerance and openness and you know
they don't want that because they make
their profits off of controlling folks
so give us a call or check out our
website you can actually print our
petitions from the World Wide Web if
you're hooked up to the Internet already
and go the library or your local school
or whatever look at CR our H dot o-r-g
name of our committee is campaign for
the restoration and regulation of hemp
and that goes with our domain name CR
our H dot o-r-g now we're getting a lot
of hits from people who want to see our
videos we have over a hundred videos now
that stream on the internet tons of
things from 60 minutes and national
documentaries and film releases like
reefer madness and a movie back a few
years ago sex drugs and democracy so
look at that site CRR H dot o-r-g
definitely you know as Paul said you can
print our our petition out from or just
directly from a website if your if you
have the right software and you've
gotten some of those back in the mail
recently correct yeah you know then and
just even your own signature on there be
fantastic even just getting yourself and
your next-door neighbor on there be
fantastic
because it doesn't it doesn't take a
whole lot of people you know we probably
need raw signatures you know a hundred
thousand you know in a Portland area
alone you know what does a million
people live here more than a million
people you know so I mean that's just
you know 10% less than 10% you know so
why not ten people you see in the street
Beach one of those with scientists you
know we'd be there easily and then
that's how easy it is to get signatures
get your own signature and your family
or your friends signature we're running
out of time to put this on the ballot
this fall this is the last month we need
all of our signature
Cheers by the end of June if you're one
of those over 1500 people who've watched
the show over the past year and called
and asked for our petition we've mailed
it to you mail those back in today we
don't have much time left if you can't
get those in the mail by the last week
of June call us at this number two three
five four six oh six bring them into our
office send them on a bus but make
certain they get to us no later than the
last day of June our they don't count
yeah you know Harper on us right now
probably but and we need those
signatures back the time is now you know
if we delay we're gonna be lost again
for another two years or more yeah
that's what will happen between now and
then exactly so you know we've got it we
got to show them that you know hey we're
out there and we're not going to take
away the have our rights being seen
taken away lightly you know we want to
take back control of our own lives we're
not going to give up control of these
people that you know want us to you know
to submit to obedience training as
Frederick says so give us a call and you
know because we want to make sure that
doctors have the right to prescribe what
they feel is necessary for their
patients and that's a key component of
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act and it says
that right in our ballot question it
says legalizes marijuana for medical
purposes and to adults so we need your
help get involved there's not much time
left we've got to the end of this month
to put this thing on the ballot so if
you know someone who needs a job who
needs work we don't have we don't employ
people but we do contract with petition
circulators and we paper signature so
call us at this number two three five
four six oh six
yeah and it's time for us to you know to
you know get together and think about
you know you know maybe you're watching
the show and you've never used cannabis
in your life but you probably know
somebody who has you know and that
person isn't a bad person that person
holds down a job or you're watching you
hold down a job you pay your taxes
and you realize that it's not a big deal
it's not the the big fear that the
government is is telling us you know I
read folks out there like Gordon Smith
senator Gordon Smith hiding behind
children well I'm a County Sheriff Dan
no le hiding behind children saying that
oh we've got to like take away your
right so we can protect children and
it's like that's not true if they really
want to protect children using that
mentality they would take away alcohol
and prescription drugs the more people
die from you know wrong use of
prescription drugs every year then all
the illegal drugs yeah by so will die
from prescription yeah so they wouldn't
give out any prescription drugs for that
with that kind of mentality and I don't
know why they're you know it just
because they realize they can't win the
argument on logic or reason they have to
hide behind children and it's sad you
know grown men and women hiding behind
children I can't even stand on their own
ideas
yeah just last month Paul and I held a
news conference to counter senator
Gordon Smith and sheriff Noel when they
said that we have to stop marijuana in
fact sheriff Noli said I saw him on this
news conference that we were who we
opposed him and the TV thing he said
that if you get a marijuana petition
shoved in your face don't sign it
well sheriff no Lea we don't shove
petitions in people's face I've never
shoved anything in anybody's face I
don't like the implication I don't like
you coming and arresting our fellow
citizens for marijuana and we're gonna
stop you buddy
so call us and help us stop this crazy
Sheriff call us at two three five four
six oh six yeah I mean you know we've
got to send sheriff no Ellie a message
and yeah look you know so you know it's
coming up you know in the fall you know
he'll be on a ballot you know right
somebody else's name in there's a guy
named slider who's running and I don't
know if he's good or bad but it's got to
be better than this clown oh that's but
then you know sliders piss tree though
because we're talking about to fall
ballot now oh so I mean right yeah right
somebody in
just so noelia doesn't you know walking
in a landslide and you know and we got
to send those folks a message you know
very cats you know and all the city
commissioners you start rolling this
year well we've got some a message
yeah because she'll be out there or you
know hiding behind kids or self you know
and because they can't win this they
can't win the argument on ideas our
reason it's like slowly the motion of
children and you know the right message
of children is think for yourself I mean
that's how you know anybody you know who
has been brought up in a in a normal way
realize is that you know you tell your
kids to think for yourself you know
because a parent can't be there behind
them 24 hours a day
and so that's what that's what this is
all about folks thinking for yourself
picking up that phone give us a phone
call
getting initiative filling out with your
signature and hopefully some other
signatures send it back to us and if you
have it already sent it back now we need
it the end of June is our deadline so if
you are going to get involved in the
petition drive you better do it now if
you're out there and you know someone
who needs to earn money have them call
us we're closing our show now we want to
thank you for watching last reminder if
you have petitions send them back that's
right folks and thanks for watching
we'll see you next time yeah it's been
another exciting edition of cannabis
common sense thanks for watching
you