[Music]
video taped at the studios of city video
it is time for cannabis common sense the
show that tells you the truth about
marijuana and the politics behind its
prohibition now here's the host Rachelle
pol Stanford and Paul Loney hello and
welcome to another exciting edition of
cannabis common sense our show is a
production of our political committee
the campaign for the restoration and
regulation of hemp our political
committee is the sponsor of petition
drive that is now in full swing the
oregon cannabis Tax Act and we are the
three chief petitioners I'm Paul
Stanford I'm dr. Philip Levesque and
thanks folks for tuning in as Paul said
for another exciting edition of our show
and Paul what is our topic for this week
well we're going to talk about hemp BC
and the situation that's developed at
least during the first part of the show
before we go on to some news up at hemp
BC and Vancouver British Columbia some
of you may recall we did a series of
interviews that were over a month of
shows last year where Paul Loney and
myself and our art producer went up to
Vancouver British Columbia and
interviewed mark Emery sister I see and
some other people that worked at and
work currently do at hip BC so we are
going to play a bit of the interview
that we didn't get into the the show
last year when we covered that we didn't
use this interview where mark Emery
actually was across the street from the
two businesses he started yeah I should
give you everybody a little background
of
and what's 40 lead into today's
situation as it's probably a lot of you
know Marc Emery was the you know the
founder of the HEVC Empire that's known
up there and he started off with a
magazine cannabis can of Canada which is
now called canvas culture and it's still
a very good magazine I mean he also had
a seed sale store that he that he found
it and he does that by mail order now
and he founded a outlet store for hemp
clothing and smoking accessories and a
little restaurant next door to that
which was called cannabis cafe which was
had all sorts of delicious food and
beverages that had hemp involved in the
preparation of it some way from cannabis
coffee a mixture of coffee and cannabis
into a nice hot beverage vegetarian
burgers with hemp seed in it and a lot
of hemp seed oil and I thought delicious
what did you think Paul I thought the
food was great
there was homemade fresh using fresh
organic ingredients and hemp seed oil
and in just about everything in hemp
seed meal which adds a kind of a nutty
flavor in a texture to the food when the
the hulls of the hip cedar are present
yeah I thought it was great it was it
was a the whole it was such a very nice
atmosphere up there very low-key people
there were respectful of each other of
the city itself I mean you know they
didn't have people congregating out
front
you know you know looking like derelict
sore anything or I mean it was just like
if you walk by on the street you think
there's two more businesses in the
middle of you know urban Vancouver doing
a really good thing it's there on its
west hastings street folks if you get up
that way i definitely recommend you
check it out it's right near the gas
light district or it might actually be
in again what guys like district I know
the actual boundaries but it's on West
Hastings and and recently marc emery
started all his business and because he
become such a high-profile person and
was always challenging the authorities
taking out
to ads when the heads of states came in
to Vancouver BC and fight them all down
to enjoy a nice bowl at his restaurant
that the government felt they had to
crack down on him because he was too
high-profile I mean he was very media
friendly very photogenic very quotable
person as you'll see in the interview
they went after him and they had a lot
of phony they had rage where they came
in and they may be able to haul out his
inventory worth thousands of dollars ten
thousand dollars and had all locked up
which is his money and he had employees
and if we had to put out of work and he
finally you know had a deal with the
authorities up there that he could sell
his businesses for the hemp pcs store
and a canvas cafe store and his Law
Center that he started to protect people
who were busted for growing or
possession he had sell those three
businesses to the folks who are right
actually running the businesses for him
and he would get out of that totally and
he would just be into himself his
magazine the seed sales and so that's
where it was lashed this is about two
years ago that's where it was last year
in Reptar visiting and you'll see him
like every talking about it as part of
that deal he wasn't allowed on that
block where his shops were that's why we
interviewed him outdoors across the
street from there
exactly and from that point sister I see
took over the hem PC store and I don't
remember who though who was actually
running the cafe at that time but his
name was mark but I can't recall his
last name but then that's where it was
and then in the meantime sister I see
had applied for a business license since
was a transfer of ownership and she has
a temporary license and the city said
okay we're gonna make you you know go
through all these hoops because even
after she came in took it over they raid
a place twice claimers underage use in
there smoking and they had to remove the
vaporizers from the cafe part of it and
show she was going through a lot of
hassle having to spend a lot of money
and hiring lawyers to defend her right
to have a legitimate business selling
clothing and smoking accessories and
they were still
not owned by the same person but the
cannabis cafe was next door while we
were there they just pulled the
vaporizers off of each of the tabletops
but they now at this point they've made
it a Members Only Club where you have to
come in and become a member before you
can actually go into the cannabis cafe
and eat and perhaps
smoke there but right around the corner
there's another stall store called
little Amsterdam and since then they've
been busted once and then just in late
April across the street another business
is opened up that sells marijuana this
time now hip BC sold marijuana seeds but
never actually sold marijuana per se at
the store where this new business
directly across the street there on West
Hastings sells marijuana for medical
purposes however you can state your
medical purposes so someone with our
show was up there just recently as we're
taping and they went in said they had
migraines got some marijuana so it's
it's pretty easy to do it's not like
here in Oregon with our ballot measure
67 you have to have the your physician
fill out a whole raft of new forms that
they've just come up with and put down
an application fee before you get a
picture ID there you can just go in and
immediately access marijuana and buy it
also under our bill no sales are allowed
so the patients have to grow it
themselves and that's often very
difficult for a wheelchair-bound MS
patient or someone undergoing
chemotherapy for cancer yeah well we can
go in and talk a bit about sister icees
current problems and what happened up
there with her business license appeals
a City Council because they denied her
and she had to appeal the City Council
where we could run the video mark first
what would you think let's go ahead and
run that video it's four and a half
minutes I think it's a real good
interview it's right across the street
from mark stork or so he'll explain all
that in the tape yeah they'll give you a
good history and we can update it when
we get back so roll the tape please
[Music]
we're with Marc Emery across the street
from MPC and cannabis cafe
this is a street you can't cross Mallya
the famous place there's the cafe at the
quarter million dollar thought finding
the restaurant now at least get good
reviews in New York Times and Rolling
Stone another place from the hippest
store we used to call the hem PC
superstore the little grow shop was
downstairs MPC upstairs a cafe on the
one side we were also residents of the
second and third floors we were building
a Montessori School the NBC Montessori
School was being built on the third
floor and the second floor is going to
be where cannabis Canada magazines good
and then when they cancer our licenses
we canceled all those programs but we're
gonna have a school incorporate there
for the children of our staff that's
perfectly linear oh yeah we had a lot of
wonderful but we employed 43 people
full-time up till the end of January and
of course basically 30 people are still
kept but only nine under my actual
employment now those are run by their
own new owners and
what was it quite a sort of like
divesting yourself of your being oh I
was sad for a couple of weeks but you
get to accept everything in this world
I've learned to not you want to come in
for this bit I've learned not to be too
concerned about property or things that
the women property they all come and go
you've got to enjoy the process by which
they've you know come and gone and to
that degree I'm really happy with what
we've done not necessarily happy with
what I've ended up with but that's a
great no that's the end isn't here yet
right that's true totally oh they'll be
happy and eveness oh they're still happy
and there's lots of happy endings every
day and there's always tragedies and the
things that get in the way and obstacles
to that's the inevitable process of
living we just can't be got to be
courageous and face up to them and not
be cowardly and look at our obligations
straight in the face and go ahead and do
the work that needs to be done so you're
not allowed to go across the street to a
door I cannot leave this park and go
down
and this is after they raid you the
second time no this is after they two
Americans went back and claimed they
gave them $5.00 per hash yes and then
that was held around for a couple of
months until they decided they wanted to
keep me awake for that block the Rolling
Stone article just came out they did not
want they wanted to torture me by having
all these people come to find me and
look for me but I'm not allowed to meet
them type of thing
so I had to sell them in next to nothing
but its own to my employee so they're
run by people who understand how to run
them and then you kept the debt oh yeah
I kept the debt yeah they didn't even
put any money down they just paid me on
a weekly basis like a salaried employee
for five years haha and yeah so I'm busy
paying off the debt
well the debts not that bad all things
considered it's on you about $100,000
will pay that down a couple of are you
trying to challenge the restriction from
going to the store no no the please one
that's so bad that if I just learned
they just tried to make something else
to get the judges you insane
sometimes you have to learn to play ball
I mean like I said anyone united states
that be in jail for 20 years right so
Canadians have learned they'll put up
with me to some degree I'm in the
establishment
but you know they can play hardball when
they want but they also like to send
messages in lieu of any really big
action and despite what it would appear
to me like duties and $14,000 was
bedroom Tori over four years in two
rates it's pretty big but to them that's
just a message
you know this is the street in
hard for you
one of the work camps cafe was
when where MVC is was where the Eastern
art store has moved over cabbage we
think this new that was
another building down there can rebuilt
it was abandoned across the street where
the FBC legal assistance center is now
as a fire bomb building and the
building's adjacent were abandoned
including this whole thing and now the
box
and it's anchored on our businessman
feature in the
they say you know in talk about public
safety unique people around
people around going in on this so we
used to patrol the streets we used to
have our own private police here there
was nothing
when we rented we had people patrolling
and so we had private cops everything
our own people all that it's very nicely
organized block
oh yeah that's just right over across
the street here right oh yeah right
when we've heard all of your neighbors
really loved you yeah
so I hope you enjoyed that interview I
think it kind of illustrates some of the
crazy insanity that our drug work can
lead us to and in particular with Marc
Emery do you want to update him on the
story of what's happened with well we
have a sister I see the the woman who
Marc Emery sold the store to as he was
forced to sell a story to get out of his
legal problems she was she was deer
running the store great baking then a
couple times and raided they hauled off
some of her inventory once and they then
they charged her at one point meanwhile
Bush likes a back up bit here she was
applying for a business license and she
hang on from the City Council because
the license bureau was recommending
denial and then meantime one times in
the investor they charged her with
what's the term they have up there was
facilitating the use of cannabis you
know the little substance by actually
selling these smoking devices they
charge her it's almost like livin of
like delivery which is pretty serious
charge and she was fighting that and
then but same time she went after them
saying that they were you know had
unlawfully seized her property and so
that was a stay enough in the court
system there and that they had they had
sister a cease claims that they had made
a deal where they would drop the charge
of her facilitating use of cannabis
myyy by selling these products and and
she would drop her claim of them season
her property and going for damages and
then therefore the but none of and so
that couldn't be brought up at the City
Council printed process the process of
her you know I've heard being charged
with contributing to the use of cannabis
who selling these products but when a
hearing came from the City Council they
had different hearings the mayor had to
recuse himself because he stayed on the
first and the first hearing that these
people be gone by Christmas so he had to
recuse himself but he meanwhile he was
backstage pouring strings for the
temporary mayor who had the advice mayor
who was
there in the chair ran the show they
they brought all these up all these
charges alleging that she was
contributing to the use of cannabis by
selling his products
her lawyers did a good job of
complaining and saying this it should be
allowed to hear those evidence the City
Council didn't care and then they went
on you know the city attorney was saying
you know bringing up all the old horror
stories that we've all heard about
through all the years that cannabis you
know leads from everything from your
hair falling out to to you know murder
of innocent children and finally even
the City Council had to cut them off
because the same tourney was going so
far to defend on this but they voted
unanimously to deny her their license
saying that she is contributing to the
delinquency of Canadian minors
Vancouver's minders by not you know
carding people who come into a store at
a shop and and by selling to anybody you
know talk to anybody and everybody that
there was open smoking going on in her
store and it's very interesting it came
out at one point that a US Marine and a
royal K Mounted Police went in
undercover to the store and verse you
know asking for marijuana in the store
claimed that they had health problems
and they were saying that therefore
that's one of the reasons that because
she was held to a u.s. Marine and we all
came out to police that they should
close her down and so they came after
her and so they vote deny she's
appealing out of the court system and
belief that she can temporarily keep her
store open but if she was in court she
will have to sell the store to somebody
else
and they go through all the print
process or they closed the store and
meanwhile she's running a large legal
bill up there and when they you know and
they use little snippets of her talking
about how she uses cannabis to you know
for her medical problems and she thinks
there's a great medical benefit
and and how her children are all healthy
they use these little words this
bulletin if it's from interviewed she's
given like the one she gave in our show
years ago last year but saying that she
believes in cannabis and they said oh
that makes her evil in any case that's
where it stands as a another sad story
of government oppression up there but I
just fire on saying that he had a u.s.
Marine going to cover up there under
what authority I'd like to know but I'm
trying to dig into that
I thought they couldn't use the military
in law enforcement here in the United
States I don't see how they could send
them into Vancouver at the different
country so Marines are invading Mandy
has a different country so up there
maybe they're Marie you know they'll
they somehow I try and claim if they're
undermined the US military or something
by smelling selling cannabis to folks
I'm not quite sure I mean do you think
that you know they be up there undermine
the US military by selling cannabis to
people or I think they'd be undermining
the US Army your marine corps and
undermine that mindset that this is evil
well strange thing about it is that
cannabis has been used not only as a
food product but also as a medical
product for perhaps 5,000 years and
Thomas Jefferson and George Washington
grew cannabis in the early days of this
country it was mostly used for making a
rope and cloth at the same time I'll bet
some of those dudes were smoking some of
this stuff because it had been smoked
for thousands of years in Asia you know
there's a paper in Jefferson's papers
from governor Morris governor Morris
according to James Madison Madison who
weakens called father of the
Constitution wrote that the the stock
quote the style and finish of the US
Constitution properly belongs to the pen
of governor Morris in quote and Morris
while he was the ambassador to France
just following up after Jefferson was
amp
to France while Jefferson was Secretary
of State for Washington
Morris sent this paper called notes
respecting tobacco to Jefferson that he
wrote for publication in France and in
that paper he compared tobacco and
cannabis and he had the paper was
actually discouraging the cultivation of
tobacco by the French but he compared to
backhoe and cannabis and said they
called it Indian him he said hip is at
all times to be preferred in a populous
country I don't know why they were
comparing tobacco in cannabis but you
know I have my bias toward thinking it's
because they were both smoked but I
don't think anything that I found anyway
verifies that but it's an interesting
follow up on your comment about
Jefferson and watching it yeah I'm sure
you know for very least because both
were were grown in us and the other both
were trying to you have us was trying to
make sure that they could succeed
financially as a country the galatea
were you know cut off from Britain and
were on their own I was independent
country they had like something you know
some of the trades so things that need
to import because then you gotta
remember you know it's not like today
where the US is a giant financial power
back then the US wasn't that big
advantages over backwater colonial
outpost you know at that time you know I
mean Britain and France were it in the
world far as financial power is then
probably you know its heart of the
Austrian Empire was maybe third
somewhere there the Russian Empire so in
fact in the American colonies prior to
independence the British required that
all colonists who had 40 acres or more
of land had to put 10% of their land
under cultivation for him and that 10%
of hemp cultivation was their taxes that
was how they paid their taxes what the
British would do is they'd take that
hill and they'd use it to make the sales
in the
for their ships and they'd also create
what we call oakum which is the clock
that went between the boards to make
sure the water didn't seep in when they
were out at sea so they found that him
rigging and sails lasted three times
longer than any alternatives such as
cotton so if you're at sea for six
months in your sails fall apart you're
in big trouble I'm rather surprised to
hear that okema suit was made out of
hemp because during World War two
I worked in shipyards and they were
making budges and they were driving
oakum into the seams between the boards
and then they would seal them with Chris
oak pitch but the strange thing about it
is that the oakum had the odor of
creosote and I didn't know where the
stuff came from I I wouldn't be
surprised of it if it was Canopus him at
all but yeah just like he said I didn't
know what that stuff was but I don't
think anybody was well what we use this
stuff for because it had this Krita soda
on it is we used to put it in the in the
band of our hats to keep the mosquitoes
away because of the Chris Opitz that had
on it and that worked real great that's
interesting you know you're a world war
two veteran you walked into Germany I
think for several months you said on
some of our previous shows then after
that you went to medical school and
started your medical career here at the
University of Oregon Medical School
that's correct yes yes I taught in
medical schools for 22 years and I
practice medicine outside for another 10
years these folks here won't brag about
themselves as much as I think they
should but doctor Levesque is a retired
professor of pharmacology and toxicology
all Loney
is an attorney and you were to secretary
the Green Party I believe are the
Pacific part now they're the Pacific
greens Dobbs the greens correct right
and president of the Oregon Wildlife
Federation so I would should probably
throw in that those other groups are not
affiliated and don't necessarily agree
with the points of our TV show cannabis
common sense but I thought I are maybe
they do
vitamin that's I thought I'd mentioned
that yeah that's good I mean I know in
the past the the Pacific Party which is
now said that greens has endorsed the
past versions of the cameras Tax Act and
in May at the May convention for the
Pacific greens they're going to take up
the endorsement of the new cams Tax Act
the one for the year 2000 which we need
what does it call me senators we need
for that one sixty six thousand seven
hundred and forty eight valid registered
Oregon voters signatures are needed and
that's ten and a half percent less than
we're needed over the last four years
that's because of the low turnout in the
Guba toriel race last November 1998 so
we need a buffer though more than the
court out about thirty percent so we
need to turn in roughly ninety to ninety
five thousand registered Oregon voters
signatures to ensure qualification well
yeah when I'm sorry for is that we have
a hundred thousand signatures when we
turn in hundred thousand draw signatures
ones that we've gone through and
obviously you know get that rid of the
ones that are people to turn out
correctly in Rock County whatever not
completely five hundred thousand draw
signatures and I think they'll take us
there and I think that's a viable goal
it's a good number to keep on our heads
to keep that positive focus that people
talk about to think positive and I can
say you know and make your teeth Pacific
green part we'll be voting on it to
endorse well in what
I know the American in that prohibition
Lee has endorsed you know the octa for
the year 2000 and I'm sure you know
other groups are lining up right now as
we speak
as is being aired to endorses exactly
you know last year we met with the
Oregon retail liquor Association and
they voted 17 to 8 to endorse ACTA if we
put in a clause that would guarantee
them a certain percentage so we've done
that we've given them a 15% Commission
on their sales I think that's a
reasonable Commission it's not too high
or too low and so we're hoping that
they're going to vote again to reinforce
our initiative the libertarian party I
want to remind viewers it's kind of live
later than we normally give this plug
but please call us please call us and
let us send you our petition you know
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act petition
will tax and regulate the sale of
marijuana to adults in Oregon State
liquor stores it will license farmers to
grow the drug for sales the Oregon
Liquor Control Commission the Oregon
Liquor Control Commission will place it
in pharmacies in Oregon and potentially
other states at cost where it won't be
taxed but then the sales to adults over
the age of 21 through state liquor
stores will be taxed will also allow
adults to grow their own and the sales
of all strains and seeds and stocks of
cannabis will not be regulated finally
it will also allow farmers without a
license to cultivate industrial hemp for
canvas Road laced linen and all the
50,000 plus products that industrial
hemp can produce and just in closing I
think we'll talk about it some more in a
future show but in North Dakota they
just North Dakota has become the first
state to legalize industrial hemp so let
Oregon follow that [__] of that lead
and call us at two three five four six
zero six that's two three five four six
zero six
we've just got over our first thousand
signatures as we're taping here in late
April
we need a hundred thousand more ninety
nine thousand mores Paul was saying so
we need your help to do that call us let
us send you that petition two three five
four six zero six
yep and come downstairs at the Portland
Saturday market every Saturday and also
at the Eugene starting market here in
Eugene location always something happens
if it's raining we're not gonna go down
and set up because we don't have it the
rain tarps and it's it's nuts not
productive but if it's a sunny day we'll
definitely be down there so come on down
this Saturday market so thanks sunny and
think all righty cameras TaxACT for year
two thousand hundred thousand signatures
2 3 5 4 6 o 6 our petition drive is in
full swing so let's send that to you
thanks for coming again dr. Levesque and
we'll have it your back for the next few
weeks and thank you Paul
good night
[Music]
Oh