b
hello and welcome to another exciting
edition of cannabis common sense
cannabis common sense is a production of
our political committee the campaign for
the restoration and regulation of hemp
and we're circulating this petition the
oregon cannabis tax act i would now like
to introduce
our attorney
our chief petitioner my fellow chief
petitioner actually the treasurer of our
political committee
and the president of the oregon wildlife
federation mr palone well thanks paul um
and that's paul stafford if you haven't
guessed yet um but
the campaign for the restoration
regulation of hemp we have an initiative
out there which paul is displaying
proudly it's the oregon campus tax act
this initiative is a comprehensive
regulation of marijuana it will allow
medical patients to purchase
marijuana at cost in pharmacies with a
prescription from a doctor it would
allow our farmers to grow industrial
hemp the low thc variety and it will
allow recreational
cannabis to be sold for profit at state
liquor stores with the money going into
our state coffers to lower all of our
tax rates of course
and part of the proceeds will then go
into funding real drug education
programs and real substance abuse
programs
yeah for the alcoholics and addicts that
need help and you know currently ninety
percent of the alcoholics who seek
treatment can't get it they're turned
away so we'll fund that with millions
maybe tens of millions of dollars it's
real hard to quantify what the black
market will do but we need your help to
put this important issue on the ballot
right now as we're taping in early april
we have about 24 000 signatures we need
at least 50 000 more really a good
segment more than that no later than the
end of june so if you're one of the
people who's been watching this show for
over a year now that it's been on and
you've received our petitions or you
have them send them back in to us right
away if you need petitions
call us at 503
if you're inside the portland area just
235-4606 because we want to send you
these petitions we need them back no
later than the end of june
that's right we need those positions as
soon as possible if you only have one or
two signatures on them send them back in
in tonight's show once again we continue
to show you parts of our recent journey
up to vancouver bc
the marijuana bread basket of the
pacific northwest
and the leader in the
emerging canvas culture
we will continue with
mark emery the founder of hemp bc and
still the publisher of cannabis canada
cannabis canada the magazine
all about the cannabis culture and we
still have um let's see we have what is
mark going to talk about in this one
he's going to talk about
the politics behind the prohibition and
other issues regarding what's going on
up there in canada you know he's been
selling marijuana seeds quite openly in
fact he's been quoted on the front page
with a picture on the wall street
journal well actually it's not a picture
in wall street journal politics it's one
of those drawings that's what that's all
they have in the wall street journal but
still if you're going to get anything in
the wall street journal it's going to be
one of those little etch-a-sketch
drawings well just to be perfectly
truthful here right it's not a
photograph but it's a picture a line
drawing but it's there in the wall
street journal he's been in rolling
stone over the past few months he's been
on cnn
uh he's been out there and in fact he is
the world's most famous marijuana smoker
and i've got to say when i was up there
at him bc i got to sample some of the
finest in
british columbia's herb and
it's it's a big tourist draw he's really
cleaned up his neighborhood too yeah
that's the one of the kind of real
encouraging things is that with his
cannabis cafe and his retail store and
the legal assistance center all being on
one block up there in west hastings he
has turned that block around from being
a block full of balanced luck dirty
boarded up stores yeah panhandlers
everywhere and a lot of hard drug
addicts and alcoholics on the street now
it's it's a it's a bustling friendly
street that's true all of his neighbors
in the surrounding area support him and
thank him for building up the area
improving the area and uh bringing
thousands of tourists streaming right
into the the the edge of gas town in
downtown vancouver yeah and i think it's
probably our time to go to the interview
in this part of the interview
he's going to be talking about people
who have had to leave the united states
because of political pressure because if
they were growers or because they were
outspoken against the government who had
to leave and carried up these strains
that were developed in california oregon
washington up to canada and continued on
with their experiments up there
i think it's a quite fascinating
process of what happened
and just so i think without further ado
go to the interview
you know and that could be like some
poor bastards that i know who and my
first rate of a wonderful man like will
smith came up here from oklahoma and he
just got popped back in his own place
yeah and he was in jail for 95 years and
he said no no no no
he had four
42 plants allegedly allegedly and
he agreed to go back because they said
they wouldn't forfeit his property which
his family still lives in
his children and his wife and he got 20
years for 42 planets and they figured
he'll serve about seven to ten oh how
nice 42 [ __ ] plants man i've tripped
over 42 [ __ ] plants in some people's
grow rooms i mean i've had easily 42
plants in my own grow rooms and around
here you might get 500 to a thousand
dollars fine for that
20 years of a man's life can you imagine
there's no society so sick as we do that
and yet there is it's called the united
states of america and it's a bad bad
place and there's thousands of americans
up here who are weed refugees who have
fled that in fact george van patten is
up here living now writing about
canadian grow operations and so many
people have come up here and it's been
great that's how we got our great pot in
the first place american war resistors
came up here from 1968 to 1972 and they
bought all their best strains for them
they sailed in british columbia and they
gave british columbia which had no
particular reputation for ever growing
any good pot they gave it a fabulous
gene pool to produce the world's
greatest pot and these people stayed and
we continued to cultivate and the
situation got uh
hospitable here and more so in the
courts and over time we end up revolving
towards the greatest pot and of course a
lot of stuff they sell in amsterdam is
produced out of seattle oregon and
british columbia more these days out of
british columbia because there's more
work going on here in the sense of
genetics breeding crossing things are
happening so much faster than the united
states because there's really crushed
yeah exactly well
hey money is a great coward and what
happened is the expertise and the money
went north where you were if you were
smart and you want to grow a pot this is
where you'd grow it and that's what's
happened so portland of course they've
recriminalized marijuana they're at
least that's what we stopped yeah thank
goodness about that
but that would be a terrible backwards
step terrible backwards step for oregon
that would really place it in the back
waters again like oklahoma where texas
where you know it's your three your face
with putting rest in spending the rest
of your life in jail growing pot
and you know why bother my advice is
just come up here you don't need to show
people you're american or canadian you
just need to show them the cash
as that cuba gooding line goes show me
the money it's still pretty relevant
anywhere and just get an asian landlord
they don't bother you they never ask
questions
and they're nice people and you should
you know deal with them the white people
are too [ __ ] nosy they're a pain in
the ass go with asians
that's why those white supremacists are
wrong right there to pod growers you
can't count on whitey to help you out
here they're the people that turn you in
they're calling 911. it's not the
chinese guys it's not the east indian
guys they don't want anybody knowing
what they're doing either so they're
just going to shut up
you know and everybody's got their own
private business except the white people
seem to think that they have a right to
be everybody's business in my opinion
and so you got to go for an asian
landlord
and people have a good success for that
i see
yeah you'll get some immigrants who see
this show you never know
right and we'll probably get lost we get
them all the time they just show up here
and they
next you know they're acting like
canadians they're americans are hard you
can always tell because they're noisy if
you give them a chance
but you tell them just you know you
remember if you get caught yeah you
won't go to jail but you'll get deported
remember you get to go back to america
that's punishment enough so don't be so
american
you know
you know because they tend to be a
little more pushy brassy you know
nothing like a new yorker when you meet
them on a holiday or you can always spot
them the loudest course they look like
they never relax they never went on
holiday they're
selling but you know most americans
actually are pretty good but uh you know
you don't when you're in a foreign
country growing pot you don't really
want to draw anybody's attention if you
can avoid it but you know even then
we've got some guys who are american are
going to be deported we got them out and
they've got a refugee status claim going
we've got the uh soos who's from oregon
himself who invented product 19 or
developer who's a grower here he's now
having refugee hearings today and
they've accepted initially his claim
that he's a weed refugee which is what
our claim is that he would face
substantial penalties going back to the
united states that are unreasonable
cruel and usual which we can get here
and that's the basis of a claim
because cultivators don't go to jail
here in first or second offense
it doesn't matter how big a crop is you
know whereas you know in america you're
facing 10 years that could easily be
construed as cruel and mutual punishment
yeah i know so many people who have
unfortunately been locked away right now
yeah well all right
send them our way
don't let them go to jail for that
america's not worth sticking around for
five or ten years in prison you know
being a guest to the united states
government in that situation it's worth
deciding to look for greener pastures
and they're here
so is there any um
any backlash at all you see for anybody
talking about you know weed immigrants
coming up to vancouver no never had a
single complaint from the public i've
never had a letter never seen a letter
never seen a letter in the newspaper
never seen any kind of criticism about
marijuana basically from the general
public at all you know the people you
see criticism from are always cops
they're always trying to spread some
bizarre propaganda because it props up
their own industry and the urine testing
people you know the people who are these
counselors the world's plagued with
counts of drug abuse counseling so i see
marijuana addicts every day in my office
i'm thinking yeah but it's like the rape
crisis council all you see is rape
victims all day but hey not everybody
works the way you do we don't just all
see victims all day long the rest of us
are out in the real world where we've
got thousands of people with no
dependency problems they don't abuse
people they're not harmed so in the
general public you tend to meet 99 of
the public knows how to conduct
themselves properly and then one percent
doesn't and that's who these people see
they see the people who couldn't handle
reality and they end up with you
alcoholic heroin users whatever i mean
any guy who goes and says i'm addicted
to pot he's really looking for a
rationalization because why what do you
do well i don't get up well you're a
[ __ ] lazy son of a [ __ ] so stop
smoking pot and get to work right end of
story right he's not addicted he's just
[ __ ] lazy he was lazy before he
smoked pot he's lazy when he smoked pot
it'll be a lazy [ __ ] after he quits pot
too you know but that's they blame pot
because you know it's like parents you
know who when they then they're
teenagers it's not my son anymore he's
changed he's hanging around with hippie
chicks and smoking pot and going to
disney movies and rallies and there's
another kid i took fishing and yeah well
what happens he grew up and now he's on
his own and you don't like it so you're
blaming all the peripherals you know it
could be vegetarianism it could be
nudism it could be marijuana whatever
he's doing that you don't know that you
didn't do rather that's affecting his
you know that's a
symptom of his new way of living you're
going to blame that not your son it's
not he's not changing or anything you
know he's not becoming an adult and
making his own mind up you know it's the
drugs you know or something like that
whatever or you know the most common one
with my mom was blaming my girlfriend he
was such a nice boy until he started
going with all those women they changed
him right whatever you know marijuana is
just a popular scapegoat for a lot of
people i always laugh when i hear that
because i mean invariably it's some drug
counselor guys well i see victims of
marijuana yeah well what are you you're
probably a former alco yourself isn't
that right yeah and i said what are you
doing with your living so you parlayed
your alcoholism into a life like career
opportunity well that's really
interesting sounds like a cop you know
go around morally lecture people if they
don't listen to you crack their skull
and you get paid for it i said that's
very interesting i said you have the
problem but we're made to pay you know
and then you get to lecture us about our
supposed problem which nobody said we
have one but you're clearly unable to
handle yourself so you've got a job as a
counselor because you've got lots of
experience being a dick you know
anyway
world's full of people making a paycheck
on something wrong
yeah well i'd like to
ask is there any part of vancouver area
that you know the weed refugees are
moving to or taking over you intend to
be an east fan because every third house
is a grow up there
south fan is a little more expensive and
a better place to be because it's more
residential but then see the problem is
to have a grow up in a lot of places
you've got to look like you're normal
you know you've got to show up you've
got to be sweet to your neighbors you
got to sort of hang out you'd be great
if you had kids living that's a good
cover but you know bottom line is you
tend not to the house tends to be all
one big [ __ ] grow operation that
you've rented out and you don't really
want people coming you don't want to see
them so it's a bit of an art you know
but unfortunately you know be grateful
we don't get all the government we pay
for as well roger said because they have
more cops and basically the cops can't
keep up even if they bust someone every
[ __ ] day in the lower mainland they
certainly do that's peanuts they might
get you know maybe in all of the lower
mainland they get like a thousand grow
operations well there's at least 125
000 grow operations and the whole lower
mainland it's like way beyond what they
can they'll never catch them all and it
you know they keep raising the threshold
well if it's under 20 plants we can't
bother with it it's under 30 plants we
can't bother well now it's under like
100 plants we can't bother it because we
know hundreds of places that have more
than 100 plants and like you know they
stack them up and they keep whittling
them down and the threshold keeps rising
and basically the way to defeat this is
that more and more people have got to
grow pot don't worry about whether it's
illegal don't worry about what's going
to happen grow more pot because you're
forcing the threshold up if a whole
bunch of people start growing 25 50
plants then you know it's going to be
like 200 plants are over to make it
worth their while right so your own
protection just by
forcing the numbers up get that pot out
there you know
and of course
all right and we're back back to remind
you that this interview is brought to
you by the campaign for the restoration
regulation of hemp
and we have an initiative out there that
we need your help on
the oregon cannabis tax act which will
allow adults to grow their own marijuana
it will tax the sale of marijuana to
adults through state liquor stores
licensed bars and taverns to sell
marijuana to adults will
allow doctors to prescribe marijuana to
patients and
allow farmers to cultivate industrial
hemp to produce paper fabric protein and
oil we want to send you this petition so
call us right now if you're registered
to vote in oregon or an oregon resident
call us at
503-235-4606 that's 503-235-4608
yeah call us and
we need your help getting signatures if
you already have the initiative and got
a couple signatures on it send it on
back in
we need them soon end of june's the drop
dead deadline
if we get enough signatures get on the
belt get the pass
maybe we can start improving gen x here
like mark emery set up in vancouver um
up there now they're like part of the
world's leader in the genetic
experiments on hemp and cannabis well
that's where oregon used to be and we
want to be back there so if you can give
us a call
put us on the ballot and it passes we
can be back in that boat we're talking
about a real economic boom i think you
know the tourist industry is going to
boom the farmers are going to boom
there's just tons of economic potential
here that we can channel with the oregon
cannabis tax act well a lot of good
i think the old-fashioned mom-and-pop
businesses will come out of this and i
think it's
you know if we have this regulate here
in oregon we can we can have stores we
can have cafes and a lot of small
businesses will come out of it that
people who don't want to work for the
big corporations or the government
whatever can actually get behind this
and um and you know making money off at
the same time supporting supporting the
government right we'll raise hundreds of
millions of dollars in tax revenue for
the state which means less tax dollars
that they'll need from the rest of us so
help us with the oregon cannabis tax act
call us right now to get our petition at
235-4606
if you're outside the portland area
that's
six zero 503-235-4600 if you're one of
those people with access to the internet
check out our website at http colon
slash
www.crrh.org
yeah and um check out the web page give
us a call um to call during business
hours usually bruce or we'll be there to
uh to help you answer any questions all
about the initiative if you're not quite
sure how to fill it out call us up and
we'll let you know and send you a
package to mail we usually have
instructions but sometimes you know
those are
sometimes those aren't as clear as they
should be but so but if you talk to a
human call us yeah and we'll be happy to
to walk you through it and at least get
your name on the on the initiative and
if you should then you go out and get
one or two of your friends
we need everybody
to get as many signatures as possible
call 235-4606
don't delay do it right now and we're
going to cut back to this wonderful
interview with mark emery
we went up to vancouver british columbia
and spoke with him you've got to admit
that mark emery tells it like it is and
and puts his opinions out there so back
to that interview all right
you know
and of course the americans are always
really good they buy up everything you
know and people say well what happens
when everybody's growing pot and we
can't get rid of i said it'll never
happen because there's always america
and america is a endless appetite for
things that they shouldn't have can't
get or whatever you know america is just
an endless appetite you could never
build enough casinos you could never
have enough drugs for america you could
never have enough marijuana for america
you could never have enough french fries
for america there's just a lot of things
in america you could never give them
enough of so to me america is just one
endless place to put pot it when they'll
always have lots of american money you
know because pot is a universal
commodity everybody wants it it's
saleable everywhere you know before
prohibition before america made
marijuana illegal you know you could get
pot maybe three or four places in the
world india pakistan afghanistan and it
was exported to the world from there for
the few people that wanted it when it
was made illegal in canada 1923 there is
no known record of everybody ever having
smoke pot there no one's ever written
about it no one's ever been recorded no
one's made any testimony there's no
evidence that it was ever grown here for
marijuana it was grown for hemp all over
the place right and but nobody grew up
for pot well then they made it illegal
now grows in every village every hamlet
every city every town i know a guy
growing north of the arctic circle in
frosher bay with two thousand watts of
light and he has an rcmp visit every
three months he's got to take it all
down
the whole growth thing is time
cyclically to match that rcmp visit so i
can take it all down put it away put it
back up when it goes i mean we've got
guys growing in the most inhospitable
environment on earth as well as every
other country nation province place
under their growing pot thanks to
america's prohibition so one thing's for
sure
if it well i wouldn't be surprised i
mean after all why not that sun there
would be great that'd be an excellent
dude
when the ozone layer is deteriorating
then you put that pot under there
because it will thrive and it will of
course replace the ozone layer that's
lost by adding more carbon dioxide or
sorry more oxygen to the environment and
giving it you know excellent excellent
thing to grow under when you've got
ozone depletions just grow endless
amounts of marijuana
and that will begin to reverse the cycle
and but now pot grows everywhere every
place in the world is pot every street
on vancouver has five to 25 grow
operations cops will tell you they can
go down the street tell you about every
third one which is a grow up they know
they can't even get the time to bust
them right in some rural areas around
british columbia they're not even doing
that it's called so listen your
landlord's such a grown pot you gotta
have it done by tomorrow i'm coming by
right so that means you gotta rip it all
out take it it comes by okay maybe
doesn't come by he calls him says did
you write it down yeah okay
you know because he doesn't really want
to bother you but on the other hand he
knows it exists so he's calling you now
of course that's actually
unconstitutional because that
constitutes a fishing experience you
just call it the phone book saying we
know you've got pot in there like
jesus christ you know it'd be kind of a
good april fool's joke you know this was
officer mcgill caught in here and uh you
know actually would be a sadistic april
fool's joke yeah
i don't recommend that yeah i don't
either especially if they got vista 2000
they say who it is called your ass is
grass man i'm gonna get you anyway i'm
surprised more that doesn't go on
there's a wonderful song by sibling
called oak's crazy fools and it's about
putting a bullet in the people that call
9-1-1 to turn us in and i think that's
an interesting thing worth considering
to one degree i said because there's
nothing more evil than somebody in the
so-called free society who turn you in
at the risk of going to jail for five or
ten years over a gardening project you
should deal with those people harshly so
you know i have certainly no sympathy
for informers and people that drop dime
you know and cause great untold misery
those people should be dealt with
harshly and i certainly advocate
you know a little private vigilante
american cell justice for those people
and you know others involve the drug i'm
always amazed nobody with a rocket
launcher brings these helicopters down
as if you're not going to find you that
helicopter is coming down it'll be hours
before they comb the air and look for
some guy in a rocket launcher in his
hand so i don't know i i'm amazed you
know where all these militia guys when
you need him yeah what the [ __ ] are you
waiting for you've got a police they'd
blow those [ __ ] out of the sky
you know you've got all the arms and
everything what the hell are we waiting
for be a hero now
you know you'll be 20 million americans
will silently think thank your praises i
mean that's what else do you want out of
living here you know these military
martial guys get in there and raise some
[ __ ] take down the what needs to be done
the u.s military do them in
you know that is a big enough challenge
for those guys they're they're like
rambo yeah they're unstoppable i'm a
tough guy i've got all these weapons
right we'll get to [ __ ] work
you know
america's out there and it needs to be
destroyed now get to it
jesus christ said you guys with
fertilizer bombs blowing up fbi
headquarters good idea originally but
then there's people and kids there like
what's that what you couldn't have
waited till there was a big staff
meeting or something you know i mean
what was the problem there i mean stupid
you know mass you know justice seekers
like that
america needs a training course on how
to properly execute government officials
and you can always edit this later of
course it's just the humorous you know
we might i would say
okay
we're the radical franchise i don't know
it makes you wonder you know you've had
helicopters over humboldt county for 20
years and nobody's decided that they
wanted to
test out all that surplus they brought
back from nan come on well the only time
i ever heard of them they were doing a
helicopter was in the oregon coast range
and it was they were spraying herbicides
for the new forest to help the new trees
grow up and that was making people sick
and also of course they had little grow
up in the woods at that time there but
they actually blew up one helicopter on
a padded that's not good for them so i'm
not that's good safe professional yeah
nobody dies yeah that's right you know
they did it uh nice and professionally
yeah no see there should be more of that
i don't you know i don't understand what
happened to proper you know green
revolutionaries and they have it like
ira you have on one hand political guys
like us advocating in the public and
then you have a a bunch of crazed guys
who will blow up anything
government-owned that's dealing with
that's attacking the marijuana industry
and then you know you have them totally
paranoid on one hand you know they could
die at any moment and on the other hand
you've got smooth talkers like me trying
to negotiate in the public realm with a
little bit of help from our armed
buddies out there you know
i mean nobody'd be listening to that
sheen finn guy now if they weren't like
blasting people's kneecaps the last 20
years they want to end that right so the
american government understands they're
in a war when they fight back because i
notice you guys lose when you have a
determined opponent
like in vietnam and you know and where
who else has kicked your ass lately you
know it's only you know
lately america's been really good on
guys like iraq you know like real
only brought into the 20th century about
a decade ago so you know but they lost
again you know so i'm thinking i think
in america somebody that could be beaten
because the rot from within is so
extensive you know actually i'm just
giving you a hard time don't worry about
it that's okay yeah yeah that's good
we're riffing now this is just the
outtake for your party
hey
emery said some funny things here let's
get to show you this stuff and we're
gonna put that out there so those
radicals okay
yeah but you might lose your cable
access our camera is brought to you by
the campaign for the restoration and
regulation of hemp the sponsors of the
oregon cannabis tax act which is in
paul's hands
yes the oregon cannabis tax act will tax
and regulate the sale of marijuana to
adults allow adults to grow their own it
will allow farmers to cultivate
marijuana for sales through liquor
stores and bars and taverns also allow
medical patients to have access to
marijuana at cost where
marijuana sold to adults will be taxed
we'll
also allow farmers to cultivate hemp for
paper fabric protein oil and just tons
of things yeah it's it's a great thing i
mean that's a fabulous interview with
with mark emery um he tells it like he
sees it doesn't he exactly i mean he's
just a a visionary um and he's had a lot
of success up there in
vancouver bc
and it's time for us here to to put our
vision into action
and give us a call at
503-235-4606 that's 503-235-4606
and let us send you these petitions and
have you fill them out if you have any
questions give us a call and if you have
petitions
they're already filled out or with a few
signatures send them back as soon as
possible
and the june's coming before you know it
and it's always one of those things like
oh gee here it is july i forgot to send
them in i'm you know every you know that
always happens every campaign and
i sure hope we don't get calls in the
middle of july saying oh i had a couple
thousand would have put us over the top
go ahead and send them in so please send
them in today
don't forget exactly you know
our campaign to date has been almost
entirely volunteer but now we are
actually paying petitioners so if you
need work or you know someone who needs
work call us at
503-235-4606 we're paying petitioners
now however if you want to help us as a
volunteer please do paul and i are both
volunteers we donate our time and
talents and money to help this cause but
a lot of people can't do that a lot of
people have to be reimbursed for their
expenses and their time so if you need
to be a paid petitioner call us right
now at 503-235-4606
or if you're a volunteer call us there
send it back though send it out well
definitely you know we need volunteers
because you know who knows how long
before the money well dries up and we
can't pay people um you know right now
you know we're fortunate we could pay a
few folks however
we still need we're probably going to
end up with a majority of our signatures
being volunteer that's this is the way
it's going to happen and so we need
yours
and don't feel don't think that it's
because we're paying a few folks for the
moment we don't need your one or two
signatures we do we really really do so
please give us a call send back
petitions
503 235
it's 503-235-4606
um and
what can i say just get sent
back send them back in because we need
them
if you send them back right away we'll
mail you new petitions you know we've
got a new petition format so dial that
number in closing i'd like to say that
if you live in inner southeast portland
or inner northeast portland and you're
in house district 14 i'm running as a
democrat the democratic primary is on
may 19th which is coming up any day now
and if you
are registered as a democrat or you're
not registered with the party as an
independent vote for me d paul stanford
in the
democratic primary on may 19th
thanks folks and i'll see you next time
get the oregon cannabis tax
you