video taped at the studios of city video
it is time for cannabis common sense the
show that tells you the truth about
marijuana and the politics behind its
prohibition now here's the host of your
show Paul Stanford and Paul Loney hello
and welcome to another exciting edition
of cannabis common sense our show is a
production of our political committee
the campaign for the restoration and
regulation of him or CRH we are the
sponsors of the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
petition which is out there now
circulating so if you see it sign it
we're the cheap petitioners I want Paul
Stanford I'm following I'm dr. Philip
Levesque sorry and for this exciting
edition of camp
Canada's common sense we're gonna
discuss the current state of medical
marijuana here in Oregon and in the
country because it is this is the
cutting edge right now with cannabis and
with him it is medical use this is where
research or at least compliation of
reports are being done nationwide and a
lot of you're right here in Oregon and
so what are we what do we what is the
actual state right now about the Rebekah
medical marijuana here in Oregon well
what's going on right now is that a
person who wants to use medical
marijuana in other words has a disease
process which includes wasting disease
of AIDS multiple sclerosis glaucoma and
some people even use it for various and
sundry types of problems and there is
virtually Enrique in particular in
regard to pain pain is so subjective
that there's
no way for somebody to measure the
degree of pain of the intensity of pain
or even the relief of pain or anything
else they're just they're just no way to
do this but if a person says I have a
bad back or I have a bad dis or bad that
I'm in pain and that smoking marijuana
helps I I don't think that anybody
should deny them the right to use that
now what's going on in Oregon at the
present time is that people who are
using marijuana for medical purposes
have to get some sort of a letter from a
physician which says marijuana will
alleviate the problem pain or whatever
it might be for this individual this
letter is sent to the Oregon Health
Division
dr. grant higgenson is the person who is
the I guess he's not the director of the
Rd Health Division but he's a number two
person there and and the number one
person is not a physician but he is so
he is the one who to whom these letters
are addressed and he is the one who will
issue the equivalent of a marijuana
users license now the strongest thing
about it is that it is still a federal
offense
- in many respects about the use of
marijuana so you know at the present
time nobody knows what's going to happen
but this hasn't prevented people who get
benefit from the use of marijuana from
using it there are an estimated 200,000
people in the United States right now
who admit to using it for medical
purposes and there are probably as I
understand it around 10 people 10
billion people excuse me who use
marijuana recreationally now this is I
think the so-called recreational
use of this is a kind of a port term
because I don't think people smoke
tobacco for recreational purposes III I
don't I don't know why people smoke
tobacco but whether it's for
recreational purposes or whatever it is
this is a sort of a strange terminology
that that is used so like when they use
alcohol that's social drinking or
something well I suppose that that's
that's truly I've never heard of the
social well they still use it alcohol
use of alcohol in the social use of
marijuana so the the the terminology
here is very very obscure or muddied or
whatever the right word is imprecise
absolutely now I think one of the
strangest things about this is that the
federal government raises marijuana in
Mississippi
the federal government has it harvested
and processed to make marijuana
cigarettes and there are eight people in
the United States who have letters of
permission from the Drug Enforcement
Administration to use marijuana for
their medical purposes
now if eight people can use it for
medical purposes for relief of their
medical problem why can't nine or ten or
a thousand so it's it's a very very
strange situation and a year and a half
ago I was one of six doctors who
testified at the American Medical
Association convention for for the
American Medical Association to stand
behind the rights of patients to use
marijuana for medical purposes and this
was passed by the House of Delegates
of the American Medical Association
in Dallas the headquarters of the
American Medical Association has I don't
know whether the word is they've sat on
their hands or sat on their heads or
whatever they have done but they haven't
done anything about it
and we six doctors have written a letter
to the Journal of the American Medical
Association as the equivalent of a
letter to the editor asking why hasn't
the American Medical Association taken a
stand on this well the first letter we
wrote they sent back that we're sorry
but we're rejecting it because we have
too many other things to practice 'men
magazine or something like that and then
about six weeks ago the American what is
it the Institute of Medicine Institute
of Medicine Institute of Medicine and
science from the National Academy of
Science came out very highly publicized
throughout the United States that there
was considerable evidence that marijuana
was good for certain medical medical
problems and the American Medical
Association has been strangely quiet
about this but in view of the Institute
of Medicine we six doctors again wrote a
letter to the American Medical
Association and the Journal of the
American Medical Association say the
Institute of Medicine says that it has
some benefit in medical purposes and why
should why should people who use it be
thrown in jail for using it for medical
reasons
so as somebody pointed out a few minutes
ago we are at the cutting edge edge of
this and with the vote I guess the last
two elections we had for medical for use
of medical marijuana November of 98 here
in Oregon yep
and Washington and Arizona Arizona they
voted on it for the second time you know
they originally voted in 1996 along with
California to legalize medical marijuana
and I think I think if I understand
right there are six states who have
passed initiatives is that what it is or
yes six and then that's not counting the
District of Columbia of where the United
States federal Congress has not allowed
that vote to be counted exit polls
showed that it passed with 72% but an
amendment to an appropriations rider by
Georgia representative Bob Barr defunded
the counting of that vote and said that
the District of Columbia cannot count
the vote on medical marijuana that was
on their ballot well they couldn't count
they were accurate the federal
government basically is the treasurer
for the District Columbia to handle our
money and they said they can't spend any
money on it and so that's you know now
they've figured out that you know since
the machines already automatically
tabulated that it would take about a
dollar and 67 cents
public money well that's for them to
count it because it's already counted
the rest of the ballot so that's what
the proponents of us saying so
detractors the BOK are folks of the
world they're saying would actually cost
more like ten thousand dollars uh-huh
there's a whole computer run and time
and all that kind of stuff so somewhere
in between part of the real number but
our kind of thing could be further grow
and and doesn't matter anyway because
the people should be able to have their
voice heard especially in DC which is
you know that the capital of the you
know of the world these days supposedly
you know in the free world the free
world now I'm you know promoting
democracy everywhere which except from
their own backyard and which is which is
quite sad so if you're out there
function and you believe in democracy I
would say you know right - Bob Barr you
know so many email saying hey what are
you doing
deny democracy to people United States
he cannot treat treat DC like a couple
of foreign colleague Senator Bob Barr
senator you know our other senators you
know and send our representatives most
of them to sit at her hands because they
know they'll have to do anything people
don't demand from them that's
interesting that's kind of is a good
segue into this article that our
director Lanny
Swerdlow sent to our representative here
in the third District in Oregon were
representative Earl bloom an hour Lanny
sent him a letter urging him to support
Barney Frank's bill House bill 912 for
medical marijuana and he got a letter
back from Earl bloom an hour where bloom
an hour doesn't really acknowledge that
Lanny asked about House bill 912 at all
he also doesn't acknowledge that we
voted on it here in Oregon what I read
representative blooming hours letter in
its entirety and then we can dissect it
it says dear mr. swert of course it's
named Swerdlow
but dear mister swert thank you for
writing me concerning the legalization
of marijuana and other drugs for medical
use
I appreciate you contacting me about
this sensitive issue recently California
voters passed a ballot initiative that's
designed to ease restrictions on medical
use of marijuana Arizona voters approved
a similar initiative but also relaxed
controls on heroin LSD and metha and
feta means is what Luminara says both of
these initiatives are at odds with
existing federal law and are posed by
the Clinton administration shortly after
these initiatives were approved White
House drug czar general Barry R
McCaffrey announced that the federal
government would prosecute doctors who
prescribed illegal drugs there are many
unanswered questions about the
methodists medicinal uses of marijuana
and other drugs I will certainly keep
your concerns in mind should legislation
regarding this issue come before
Congress if I can be of further
assistance please feel free to contact
my office
first of all though representative bloom
an hour knows that we voted on it here
in Oregon that doesn't matter all he
knows about is two and a half years ago
they voted on in California and Arizona
and even though Lanny's letter opened
and closed saying please become a
sponsor of House bill 912 for medical
marijuana bloom in our doesn't
acknowledge that and says I will keep
your concerns in mind should legislation
regarding this issue come before
Congress well there is legislation there
and you asked him to be a sponsor I are
I get upset about these things it's you
know typical of these you know limousine
liberal Democrats that they just don't
want to offend anybody and they want to
make sure that you know they keep
control of everything that's how they
can make sure they don't offend folks
who stay in office I mean it's like yeah
I talked about recently California
voters was like two and a half years ago
I mean in Arizona you know it's just
it's just quite shocking that he has no
idea well this is a form letter that his
staff composed two years ago they have
an update of it I'm not sure which is a
dated March 29 yeah one letter though
his staff came in with two years ago
that's the case whooping I was like god
newborn ride his bicycle he's got to get
out there and see what his staff is
doing in his name I'd be embarrassed if
I was if this was Lance going out under
my name so early I'm sure you're not
watching but you are you hadn't
embarrassed
don't make us Earl
you know many unanswered questions but
listen uses of marijuana her drugs well
there's many unanswered questions about
whose use of any substance out there
we're not sure every every day is an
experiment as I'm sure doctors affect
will tell us when they use medicines
it's you know every individual different
and they're not sure everything I always
find new information about drugs we've
had for a very long time and any day the
fact that doesn't realize or doesn't
acknowledge
spell 911 to exist it's pretty sad but
well survived that could mean Florida
State is there every day you know we
find out who information about drugs
have existed for a long time I mean it's
not like the book is closed you know
once they come out with a drug at first
place well I think it's very interesting
that we know from historical records
that that kena's cannabis has been used
for literally thousands of years and
nobody has ever reported any bad effects
from the use of it yeah and when you
compare that to tobacco or to alcohol
there's absolutely no comparison between
between tobacco alcohol and marijuana
there just absolutely none whatsoever
and and the statement that that
marijuana is a gateway drug to heroin or
cocaine or whatever this was verbally
thrashed by the Institute of Medicine
that said there was no evidence
whatsoever that this was the case so I
think I think the main thing that we're
doing is supporting general mccafferty
and a whole bunch of DEA agents who are
making very high salaries and don't want
to give up the the the game is you know
you might you might say so the people
that are making money on the marijuana
issue are the DEA agents and the people
who grow and sell marijuana and don't
don't pay any taxes on any aspect of of
the money that they make and if they're
caught they get sent to a federal prison
where it costs at least $40,000 a year
to keep them in prison so I guess the
federal prisons the guards and the
prisons are probably also recipients of
a lot of money
from the marijuana business so exact
it's really a straight strange
absolutely bizarre situation that that
this has gone on and I can't understand
why some of these politicians in
Washington DC and elsewhere can't see
this or understand it or whatever the
right word is I don't I don't understand
it either
yeah yeah I tend to think that way
that's just you know plain inertia for
you like the vast majority of
politicians you know you have some you
know my knowing in one hand or this drug
war is out now more holistic drug
warriors and then he has a few
politicians that say yeah I know we've
got a you know basically say let people
decide for themselves the most of them
it's just like you know status quo they
don't want to change anything because
this is a system that they're used to
operating in I think if you brought in
you know an outside economists who've
had no exposure at all to you know that
the drug underground substance
trade in and in this world I don't where
you'd find such an economist but you
know like the proverbial management
miners or something coming in and take a
look at this and they would laugh at us
and they say well you know the way your
system is working is supposed to work
and the way it's set up you know you
know people are opinion taxes they're
making money and therefore it's it's a
drain on the on the government it's a
burden on the rest of us because we have
to pay more taxes because those folks
aren't paying their fair share for the
roads the bridges you know the sewer
systems and then we have the fact that
it's costing us money now they're paying
their fair share but causes money to
build the building prisons to pay the
guards to staff these prisons police to
arrest you know the the judges what's
more courthouses they're building that's
one of the reason that though this huge
Mark Hatfield courthouse in downtown
Portland here fact that they're
arresting more people for drug crimes
you know it was just a simple you know
interstate white-collar crime stuff we
all probably need like one or two judges
you know and and you just it's just
something that I think an outside
observer would look at they were just
at your head and say well what were you
guys thinking of you know I think that
given the end of prohibition we're going
to look back on the outline of marijuana
much the way that we currently look back
on civil rights legislation in the Jim
Crow laws we look at the Jim Crow laws
that kept people on European Americans
in a subordinate State and we look at
that and think that was wrong those laws
were wrong and that that was the you
know we're glad that that's over well
we're going to look back on these
marijuana laws and do the exact same
thing and and I think that you know we
want to urge our viewers out there to
help us lead ourselves and our state out
of this morass that phone number is two
three five four six zero six that's two
three five four six zero six we have the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act petition
currently in circulation would you like
to tell them what the Oregon cannabis
Tax Act well the whammer's tax said it
will tax and regulate the sales of
cannabis to adults through state stores
which are be operated like to take
liquor stores would you go and buy
liquor in or bars for that matter to
adults over the age of 21 it'll also
allow patients to get marijuana at at
cost in pharmacies you can go into a
pharmacy by that cost and they're you
know and then doctor who they'll
prescribe it instead of this having to
grow your own or getting a caregiver to
grow it for you and what if you have
brown thumbs that would green thumb and
we're also allowing our farmers to grow
that dust really hemp so we can you know
compete with the rest world industrial
hemp so that's industrial have medicinal
marijuana available at cost at
pharmacies and allow adults to purchase
in state operates stores for
recreational purposes with the
seeds going to the taxes on face we've
been going to the state government to
funding whether state government decides
to fund we decided we put 90 percent of
the proceeds and we expect there's gonna
be a lot of money generated by this we
can't really say what the amount will be
right now but let's leave that aside
look we did we denote that ninety
percent goes into the state general fund
so it'll be up to the legislature to
decide how to spend it hopefully they'll
put it into education but there'll be a
lot less need for prisons in courts so
they won't be putting it there hopefully
the other of the remaining ten percent
eight percent goes to fund drug abuse
treatment programs for people with
alcoholic and other substance abuse
problems and then one percent would go
to a comprehensive drug education
program for kids in schools to teach
them about the dangers that substance
abuse can have on their development and
finally the one final 1% goes to fund
the state agricultural committee that
will support and promote industrial hemp
products made from fiber protein and oil
and their associated industries so and
so you know we need your help folks that
number is five oh three two three five
four six oh six as five one three two
three five four six zero six and we have
a website out there that call over here
there's real good that's a pretty
amazing website that I'll put stuff
together on including our shows right
you can watch this show on the Internet
it's WWC rrh dot o-r-g an you know we've
won every major web award we were named
by netscape s what's cool by project
cool as a today signing by cool side of
the day as a cool side of the day choice
side of the month we've won most major
awards for our websites and i encode
videos so there's over a hundred
different videos you can watch their
feature-length movies like the 30s
classic reefer madness that shows that
if a person smokes marijuana they'll go
crazy and kill their family and friends
that's the 1930s movie that helped
criminalize it one of them anyway
and other feature link films and
documentaries like ABC's pot of gold
about the economics of cultivating
marijuana CNN's higher times they're
literally a hundred different shows
currently we have about 25 of these
shows on there and a backlog of another
twenty to ten code and put up so we urge
you to look at our website you can
actually print our petitions out from
the website if you have a laser printer
using the free Adobe Acrobat printer so
if you can't use the internet though
call us at 5:03 235 for 606 as we're
getting used to here to having to always
give the area code from now on that's
true so 503 235 for 606 now doctor the
vet I want to ask you that's one thing
that I've heard some doctors say is
about whether or not marijuana that it
can causes a depression what people try
to get off of marijuana you know enjoy
everything about that nothing about that
I I know a lot of people who who smoke
marijuana and I have never heard that
said okay well we have folks for the
record he's a professor of pharmacology
and toxicology so I don't think you'll
find many people more qualified to make
a statement I said I think excuse me but
I I think I think the CIM the comparison
might be easy to make about what happens
when somebody tries to quit smoking
tobacco
[Laughter]
there's the patch in the chewing gum and
the the pills and all of those things
they can take to quit smoking tobacco I
guess for folks that have problems
there's also groups called marijuana
Anonymous out there
they aren't used by many people but if
you'd like to quit smoking marijuana we
recommend that you contact marijuana
Anonymous if that's what you want and if
you feel you're having a problem
talk to somebody about it I mean you
know we don't believe in substance abuse
we believe in adults to choose choosing
wisely and using wisely that's what we
believe in but and then no we asked you
out there to write your congressperson
and you to support has some support
House bill 912 the federal version of
medical marijuana introduced by
representative Arnie afraid Frank that's
House bill 912 right for them column
asked to support that and is the Salem
session line down to an end ask if your
local representatives to support the
letter to the federal Congress asking
them to support medical marijuana what's
that
it's a House Resolution that's it gee I
can't remember the number rather top
right to your or call your state senator
he reserved they'll know what you're
talking about you say the House
Resolution supporting medical marijuana
at a federal basis it just says that you
know now here in Oregon that we have
medical marijuana
the US should catch up to us and the
other five states that have supported
medical marijuana and voted for it
overwhelmingly that's right and so I'd
like to urge you again we want your help
in this petition drive you know we need
about a hundred thousand signatures we
need sixty six thousand seven hundred
and forty eight valid registered Oregon
voters signatures we need to turn in a
hundred thousand to ensure that we
qualify so call us and get on a petition
at 5:03 two three five four six zero six
all of us are volunteers we need your
help if you can sign it if you can get
your friends to sign it even if you can
just get one or two signatures calling
us get that petition at two three five
four six oh six then turn around and
send it right back to us if you've got
the petition already send it back to us
right away don't delay don't forget
about it don't stick it in the back
bedroom drawer send it back to us so we
can get it into our account and help
build up to that hundred thousand
signatures so that we can force a vote
to regulate the sale of marijuana and
restore industrial hemp here in Oregon
and restore freedom here in America so
call two three five four six zero six
are the webpage WWC r rh o RG well good
night and thank you and thank you Paul
my pleasure
and thank you viewers good night
[Music]