this is not a war on drugs this is a war
on my kids that need medical marijuana
to make their day pleasant to help them
relieve the symptoms of nausea to get
over the symptoms of chemotherapy to
make them feel good each day they get up
in the morning that's what this war is
about turn on all your friends all your
relatives all your grandmas and grandpas
talent that this war on marijuana is
[ __ ]
[Applause]
[Music]
but going to the buyers club we've got
today all kinds of food good all the
food is five dollars a piece
those are peanut butter cookies these
are chocolate chip cookies banana bread
made by my partner agreeable Rice
Krispies made by Larry who also works
here at the buyers club cooking leaf
this is so this way you can cook these
things at home for yourself and be able
to make your own pink shirt it's
marijuana make blended in and you just
take a few drops of that we also have
marijuana that you can spot on the side
depending upon the quality of it
determines the price so of course this
being the most potent this would be the
most this is the most expensive one with
the skate sliding scale the two here are
California green and these two to the
left are Mexican and this is 40 this 65
and 75 75 is very very kind
very aromatic I like to tell you a
little bit about the buyers club and how
it came into being my best friend my
water brother of 14 years
Jonathan West had AIDS Jonathan was
taken a myriad of drugs like every AIDS
patient and all those drugs had severe
side effects from constant nausea to
appetite suppressant and to making you
feeling really bad the one drug that was
really helping Jonathan was marijuana it
was the one drug that allowed him to
ease his nausea to stimulate his
appetite yes and it was one drug that
made him feel a little bit better when
Jonathan died me and my friends collect
16,000 signatures to put a medical
marijuana initiative on the ballot and
the people of San Francisco responded by
80% to legalize marijuana as medicine to
help people with AIDS and cancer and
multiple sclerosis the Board of
Supervisors in a resolution 741 - 92
ordered the district attorney and the
Chief of Police to place the marijuana
enforcement laws for medical purposes as
to be the lowest priority marijuana
although it is illegal helps people I'm
working to legalize it for these people
and one only has to spend one day at the
buyers club to know that this is a
medicine that works for a lot of people
I'm 75 now
I didn't used to smoke irregularly I
just things have been they were around
or celebrated you know I was diagnosed
with glaucoma a year ago April and I've
been told for years that was helped the
pressure for my blindness off but I went
by ophthalmologists expecting him to be
able to ride up out of prescription and
I found out that it was illegal I hadn't
paid a lot of much attention to him
before you know I started a nutri sale
deal anyway then I started writing
letters to officials and one saying
another real letter to Angela Alioto who
is the president of San Francisco for
supervisors and I told her why had heard
that her husband who had had cancer and
the Jews never wanted to help him
through his death and anyway she I wrote
her letter but it was on my mind and she
wrote me back told me he called Dennis
never even heard this before and this
was it maybe in last January
[Music]
so I called him and Dennis invited me
open and having glaucoma is uh and in
for me you know we all we all who are
members here are so dead letter
diagnosis from your doctor HIV cancer
mochas grossest serious back injuries
paralyzed disc injuries essentially
anything in marijuana is good for if you
have the anorexia the marijuana would
work and for P management marijuana
works and if you're extremely depressed
instead of Prozac marijuana does work
[Music]
my nephew was injured
I have an hiv-related kind of arthritis
of the spine
[Music]
alleviates nausea helps
relaxes me and helps me control
manipulate stress and setup well
basically I'm here because three
different reasons I can get bought
better quality consistently and cheaper
here than I can on the street which is
but in terms of medical reason is the
fact that I've got something called
drusen to the optic nerve is basically
sort of a wart like expressing sits on
my high memory and it what it does it it
is decreasing my field of vision as well
as increasing the pressure in my eyes
and also produces a lack of binocular
focus when I smoke pot helps reduce
pressure and brings back my do not go
focus so I can see someone still can't
see completely but I can see a lot
better after I'm supposed to join the
night before
[Music]
she made sleep easier correcta kids
for reasons I acknowledge to need in all
human beings to get high to remove
themselves temporarily out of an
everyday frame
[Music]
another friend you might say somewhat it
solves and over the everyday
[Music]
there's a great deal of relaxation
listen I'm in serious
[Music]
it's hard to believe that seven or eight
years ago I was able to ride my bicycle
from here to Santa Cruz this place is
really great to marijuana from because
for one thing you don't have to take
your chances out on the street like the
going to Dolores Park for example we're
never quite sure what quality you're
getting or if you're going to be robbed
or it's just dangerous this is this is a
safe place
I think it makes a lot of sense reality
is the medical marijuana clubs have
operated without interference from local
police or federal drug agents our
manpower doesn't permit to really
operate at the street level so it is a
low priority right now
yes it would be program are very sincere
and they're trying to do something to
alleviate their pain versus other
methods I think it's something that the
the the the justice system has not
responded to that particular social need
yet
[Music]
and from there I went to San Francisco
General Hospital needs outpatient Lord
I've been there I call them all my kids
because anyone who's could've did they
could have been here they couldn't get
anybody in this and so I was baking at a
safe house I was baking for about 20 or
25 kids whatever I could know whenever I
could get enough belief donated I would
make this videos I could delete that was
donated and I was in the room two kids
that are they free of charge then of
course I got busted that seems to be the
shocker around the world for medical
marijuana they wish they never ever who
busted me my kid was selling a little
marijuana on the side too you know
Poorna legs or income and they were
basically after him and I was up there
baking that day and they got me to and
thought they he
they said guess what we've got here
brownie marry and they thought that was
a big deal however really backfired up
the book is basically Genesis and all
the other people have made contributions
to it my contribution was just that the
recipes and the story of my baptism
activism there's all kinds of different
it's a great shrimp casserole there's a
rice side dish there's a black bean soup
macaroni and cheese ham salad dressing
chestnut stuffing there's a good recipe
for chocolate chips and so we all
together
[Music]
right now we have 22 people working here
from the makers to scale people to
doormen and people that just roll joints
for the people everyone that works here
is easily got a cancer or multiple
sclerosis
do you screen
I'm the baker yeah they're there several
ways of of doing as like THC the
leafless is some pitches suitable and in
any kind of oil or butter and there's
another way of using alcohol and
increasing the potency which I'm which
I'm just like experimenting worse
so five just like used my leaf and in
the crock pot was butter let it soak
overnight and then get magnificent
results from
[Music]
they don't quite have their backs
statement on there yet
the can I say it was really good and I'm
gonna have one and basically I'm
actually only gonna have half of it
because a hole would make me feel sleepy
to sleep and I'd rather do at home
the whole thing at home
these aren't Mary's brownies these are
somebody else makes these if if I get a
chance to get one of Mary's brownies
makeovers those are the best smoking you
know gives me that right away freely but
this actually takes an hour and a half
or so to really start to feel it I have
HIV
perfect the drugs that the surgeons gave
me to alleviate the pain born after
surgery are toxic and marijuana isn't so
I became an addict of prescription drugs
I really never used marijuana in my life
yet I was 220 pounds I had terrible pain
from my surgery I couldn't even move
without pain now I'm 170 pounds I biked
20 to 30 miles a day in rural Butte
County without that much pain I am in
school and getting a 4.0 GPA in a very
hard graduate program I'm 73 years old
for 16 years not considered a drug but
rather for nerves
[Music]
and you Chosun honey for our minced
remains
[Music]
it's some people say that Mexican is
harsher to smoke that the taste is to
keep your buzz and a lot of people are
not able to smoke it because of their
lungs because of respiratory systems and
parts what have you and smoking is bad
so eating it really is becoming more and
more popular every like these actually
really caught on these rice krispies you
know these really caught on it's somehow
a taste right the taste of marijuana is
odd it doesn't go with everything
nothing tops home made
and like this this is an ounce of
marijuana and it's the shake and the
leaf from the flowers that that this is
but this is enough we sell this for what
15 dollars enough pots to make a batch
of brownies about 12 doses homemade is
really good because when you first take
it out of the oven and it's hot it is
heated and it's like it's like slightly
smouldering
baked or man very very so a batch of
brownies when you take those brownies
out you meet one of those brownies way
mostly if I'm going to eat it I probably
would eat it in a cookie form usually
browning or sometimes I might make
something special like pancakes but
usually I smoke
[Music]
well it's 2 grams in there so I don't
know
[Music]
if it doesn't work then you give her
another quarter
[Music]
everything here has medicinal value
everything here is available to the
members it's calculated by weight at the
same way we buy it and as you can see we
have in shards it's pretty amazing isn't
it very large as a matter of fact of
growing that marijuana some of these are
beautifully tendered and manicured you
can tell people really put a lot of
energy into their Gardens there really
is a little bit less quality as the
flowers that crumble to dried
[Music]
it was diagnosed I in April while I was
HIV positive in April of 89 when I was
diagnosed and with AIDS May of last year
and I gained approximately 15 pounds and
six weeks so it's very good for me
because I was down I'd lost almost
please
my name is Beth and I work here I do a
variety of things greeting people
signing them up giving them hugs helping
them at the counter showing them around
I am HIV positive myself I love that
we're like a big family the people that
come in here when they leave they feel
just a little bit more loved and at ease
and they did when they came in
I've seen people improved I've seen
people come in having to be carried up
the stairs and I've seen people come in
later these same people come in later
with just walking up stairs or maybe a
little bit of help I've seen definite
improvement I've experienced this myself
I've just seen a lot of miracles a lot
of miracles here they can get dirty wood
very sick people searching their parks
for marijuana I think is 3100 people
these people are as in boredom in the
winter of their life
Nate sir every respect excited to give
them
I may have to pay price um
but in prison what I'm doing but I
believe what I'm doing
what just has to be here one day you
know
we're doing right thing we are helping
the crisis time of them
you could say this club is that
marijuana but it is really about love
[Music]
Californians for compassionate use we
feel calls from all over America every
day we get pause from people out there
that want information on this topic and
we've been trying in our own humble
little way to influence national policy
in this area as best we as a citizen
activist group can do it was passed by
both houses in the California State
Legislature by a nice margin it was a
bipartisan vote Republicans in both
houses passed this bill and we lobbied
for this bill I had the honor of going
out there with NS on numerous occasions
and watching some of the patients also
go out there and testify for the bill
and that was quite a process
I mean Dennis actually and some of the
patients went door to door legislature
to legislatures and it was quite a thing
to see because Dennis is a master and
this was something I would step back in
generally watch he really had to see
this to understand that the power of
speech because it was his voice would go
up and the infectiousness of his
characteristic of what he was explaining
would go up into and these offices
aren't that big usually you've got
another legislator in the backroom is
letting you know you've got Dennis
talking directly and discourse
incorrectly with these legislators
without you know just just pure pure on
its own merits and really really swaying
them with the conviction of argument it
was really something to see we didn't
personally get to see the governor and
we brought 30 patients by and we
presented the governor Dennis presented
the governor through his office with a
major pile of materials
supported the bill Californians for
compassionate uses spearheading a
statewide ballot initiative the vote
will take place in November of 1996 the
voters of the state of California well
at that point be able to decide if it's
okay for a sick person to grow a couple
of plants of marijuana use it for
medicine with the oversight of their
physician
[Music]
[Applause]
the cannabis buyers club I want to tell
you a little bit what's been happening
at the club for over two years we have
been operating without police
interference that we have served 4,000
people we're at our door on Wednesday
videotaping members following sick
people home
[Applause]
[Music]
resonates patients and cancer patients
the Sun set up their life and that's not
right and we're here to tell them to
leave
[Applause]
[Music]
the people of San Francisco behind done
the politicians the therapist is going
behind their support to the light and in
fact the cops have sent us three members
who have a to a boycott the worst part
they sent them to the club even though
they're not going to do it I'm not going
silently into the night I won't be
dragged into that building
I have fighting for your rights so any
medicine you have in the sunset of your
life
I'm here to protect you and if they
arrest me
they are arresting you and they have to
know that because we know that we've
watched our friends and our families
killed themselves to death on the modern
medical miracle of today's science can
we know the therm helps them and we're
not going to let them close the club now
I don't know about you but I'm also not
gonna let Dennis Ferran go to jail alone
[Applause]
I started selling marijuana in 1970 and
I paid a dear price for it including
getting arrested child huge jury trials
1977 again I was arrested for running
the big Top Pot supermarket it was kind
of the one-stop shopping
three scales no waiting treated like a
king and my friend Harvey Milk and I
conspired to legalize marijuana on the
1978 ballot by Proposition W we won that
vote by 58% at Harvey Milk in in a note
to my jail cell told me he was going to
see that it was enforced and that mo no
city funds were gonna be allocated to
enforce the marijuana laws but that
wasn't a P because Harvey Milk was
gunned down by an assassin's bullet and
it also put a bullet through the
marijuana movements heart because see
Harvey was our spokesman moving on to my
wall this is a poster of when I ran for
charter commissioner I ran for charter
commissioner when I was in jail for
selling marijuana from the pot
supermarket and Harvey Milk endorsed me
for that race I unfortunately lost but
not by much and not before Dan white
denounced me and Harvey Milk in front of
the board supervisors the same time I
had proposition W on the ballot I
unfortunately was in jail for that we
have elections so I did see my
initiative win by 58% and myself come
within 1500 votes of actually winning a
seat on the Charter Commissioner and now
my restaurant and they
the island restaurant it was in the
heart of the Castro district in Harvey
Milk's headquarters for 75 and 76
assembly race he used my restaurant as
his campaign headquarters for that race
and he didn't win that race but that was
not to be because he was meant he was
meant to win the race in 1977 we became
the first openly gay like the supervisor
and let elected official in the whole
country and his legacy was one of love
and community he showed the world a lot
of hope and compassion
[Music]
you