you
I've at the studio is a city video at
the rage nightclub it is time for
cannabis common sense the show that
tells you the truth about marijuana and
the politics behind its prohibition now
here's a host of your show Paul Stanford
and Paul Loney
hello and welcome to another exciting
edition of cannabis common sense our
show is a production of our political
committee the campaign for the
restoration and regulation of hip
we are circulating a petition the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act and I would now like to
introduce my fellow chief petitioner our
political committees attorney our
treasurer and the president of the
Oregon Wildlife Federation mr. pollow
nee
well thanks Paul for that fine
introduction yeah our initiative was a
comprehensive initiative which would
regulate marijuana and a comprehensive
system obviously it would allow the sale
to adults of marijuana through state
liquor stores for profit tax go into the
state coffers to cut our state income
tax and it would allow at cost sales of
medical marijuana to patients with a
doctor's prescription or allow our
farmers to grow industrial hemp the low
THC variety to provide all sorts of
products of the fiber fued food fuel and
it would some of the proceeds would go
into drug education programs realistic
ones not the phony Dare ones that don't
work and it would also go into treatment
programs which are desperately needed
it's say like I say it's a comprehensive
system it's you know a way to end the
prohibition this that's destroying our
way of life destroying our democracy and
it's just causing tragedy to families
you know we can save untold millions of
dollars in tax revenue that's spent
today on incarcerated marijuana
offenders locking up marijuana growers
we can bring in hundreds of millions of
dollars in revenue for Oregon state
coffers which is going to lower
the tax burden on us all when we tax and
regulate the sales of marijuana to
adults so we urge you to get our
petition we want to send this out to you
right away
call us at two three five four six zero
six you're outside of the Portland area
call 503 two three five four six zero
six
if you already have our petitions send
those back to us right away we've only
got a couple months to go we've got to
turn in all of our signatures by the end
of June so if you send us petitions
right away we'll send you back petitions
we are even paying some petitioners so
contact us for more information about
that or if you're a volunteer Paul and I
are both volunteers then help us out let
us send this to you call us at five oh
three two three five four six zero six
yeah
like you know I always say it but even
you have only your own signature on the
petition send that in get your signature
get your best friend your partner
whoever get them a signed petition with
you and send it on in if you have
questions call our number bruce's person
will probably answer the phone sometimes
Paul answers the phone you know please
give us a call and you know let's make
our vision of a much more safer and
saner Oregon reality like they have done
up in Vancouver BC you know we've been
doing some shows now with Marc Emery the
founder hemp BC today's show we thought
we'd show you a different person one of
the great things about Marc Emery hemp
BC that there's been a great community
gathering up there of just some really
wonderful folks doing great things and
the person in today's interview sister I
see there's another one of these
fabulous persons that she's got a great
story to tell and she's a wonderfully
strong he would be yeah she mark Emery
is actually passed on hemp BC to sister
I see so sister I see is now the
proprietor of hemp BC Marc Emery is
actually keeping the seed sales business
where he's the largest seed seller in
the world
he is keeping cannabis Canada but he's
turned over management and ownership of
hip BC the retail and wholesale outlet
to sister I see and we interviewed her I
think you're gonna like this interview
folks she's a real warm-hearted person
and so I guess without further ado let's
roll the interview right city of
Vancouver
we are here at hemp pcs retail store
interviewing the proprietor sister I see
thanks for having us pleasure
yeah it's good to meet you ng gentleman
all right and so here at the hemp VC
store what does the MPC store so the
HEVC store is a lot of different things
it's a ham store we carry a wide range
of products everything from rope and
twine to clothing to cosmetics MPC is
also a place of advocacy we advocate the
decriminalization and deregulation of
cannabis in all its forms and that would
be you know him for fiber and fuel and
such and marijuana as well for its many
uses at MPC it's also a pretty major
tourist attraction and there we see a
lot of visitors from all over the world
a lot of people from the states as well
so it's just a few of the things we so
you saw a wide range of products
what sort of do you like your books
there and your clothing we have a really
large library
everything from information on him and
its uses in industry to grow books to
enable people to grow their own
marijuana hmm
have any problems with robux some girl
books here it hasn't been a problem I've
managed the store for a good good time
now and we've never you know the police
have never given us any problems about
it so actually an in the raid in
December they left the grow books alone
and such when they you know took new
paraphernalia and see it's a
they left the books alone so I guess
it's not a concern but the rate in
December that was the second rate
they've been won some time before right
yeah chamber of 97 was the second one
right the first one was January 96 and
they did basically the same thing came
in on mass and closed the store stole
pipes bombs what they consider to be
paraphernalia seeds and in this raid
growing equipment of light and then in
both instances we were open the next day
and doing a steady stream of business
well that's great thanks for fighting
for our rights yeah and you know that's
what we consider that we do here and
that's a large part of what we do is we
are fighting for individual rights and
freedoms and we believe that it's
everybody's own choice you know how they
choose to live within you know certain
confines that society dictates and as a
pot smoker I can honestly say I'm not
hurting anybody by my habit if you'd
like to call it that
certainly I'm productive and
contributing to society in my estimation
so yeah and it seems to me a said Oh act
of civil disobedience you know it's like
when you got no other choice but you
still have to live your life what you do
this is it yeah and then you come to a
point in your life where you decide if
it's important enough something to fight
for
and I certainly consider
you know that's what I do here and so
will you hear the the day of the
December 97 bust yes when they came in I
certainly want to talk about that it's
always kind of interesting to me anyway
to hear what happens when they come in I
guess this was a unprepped they came in
with like albinius like 25 it's really
it was really quite ridiculous you know
and when you could stand back and look
at what was actually going on there were
20 25 officers that came in with a
search warrant in time of day was this
it was just about 420 that was kind of
auspicious in any case they came in with
the search warrant and read the search
warrant to my system assistant Tamara
and and that stated that they were there
to confiscate illegal paraphernalia for
illicit drug use and that and they
proceeded kind of they took the names of
the customers that were here there quite
a number of customers in the store it
was a nice afternoon and let them leave
and finally stopped a mirror for making
sale she was ringing in sales all the
time they were
then again it was really quite funny and
he got particulars from all the staff
members and then they were told to leave
I hung around until Mark got here and
after a little while they escorted us
out as well apparently you're not
allowed to stay on premises while
they're skating there's a large diverse
nation kind of gathering during this and
everybody went outside and waited and as
the crowd grew and grew it was really
quite reassuring actually to see the
support that we gathered in such a short
time you know it grew to about I'm not
even sure maybe 300 people I'm standing
very peaceably his plot smokers tend to
do you know around the police tape that
had been put up and so it's kind of
blocking out in the street or was it
just on the sidewalk I know we spilled
over into Hastings absolutely yeah but
that's because they wouldn't let us
stand on it had a growth dog stopping
traffic on Hastings yeah yeah yeah so
how did the word get out for all those
people to show up we actually got on the
phone as soon as the police came and
started calling the local media and such
and for the area and the people who came
out on foot it's just that the numbers
in the area who do support NBC
we do here so what are some others
fellow store offers as per providers on
the street here where do they think of
your business they actually were
interviewed after the last trade for
that reason and most of what I heard or
actually saw on TV was very favorable
they agree that NBC is a good thing on
this block we certainly have kept the
the hard drug users the other side of
candy Street just because we attract so
much attention there's always people
coming and going and traffic and we're
good for business and we attract a lot
of people to this block
HEVC is an extremely busy retail store
and so you know all in all we're very
good for them and they have said as much
that's good to have support from your
neighbors I heard when this first opened
it was boarded up and maybe burned out
or something perhaps across the road
yeah the first store was an old boarded
up some kind of bookstore alternative
something I can ask my so do you also
sell hydroponic equipment and other
things like that no we don't any longer
that was the little gray shop that that
was here when Mark owned the business
um that's closed down that's closed as
well as mark Emery seed sales are no
longer on premises here we're not
affiliated any longer and so what we do
have is the our big beautiful store yeah
and it is very so he understand their
licensing problems and they they said
they weren't gonna date of licenses
mm-hmm what City Councilor City Hall had
said to Marcus that they weren't going
to renew his business license for this
year I'm sure totally
motivated by you know whatever that's
it's happened and so what Mark decided
to do instead of loose or risk losing
the whole business because he would have
been you know operating without a
license and such I'm not sure you know
how far that authority extends but it
would be better to divest himself of
these particular Holdings and in that
way we were able to retain I think about
21 of the former 35 full-time employees
of Hamelin EC the other 14 of course
lost their jobs they were casualties of
this drug war and and so yeah employment
was spawned in the growth store and our
wholesale business closed down so but
this way you know there's still a lot of
us working and that's good so that's
good yeah you know we're from Oregon in
Oregon when the they've really cracked
down we used to kind of be the cannabis
center of the west coast until the 80s
and the federal government started
enforcing federal laws in local areas
and people are being incarcerated for
really long periods of time and police
are using infrared detection to find
halide lights and grow operations and we
like to tell people about that what's
going on here in Vancouver where now
that then Vancouver has been the center
of freedom here at least when it comes
to cannabis of the Western North America
as far as police efforts go I mean the
police are always talking about you know
looking at looking out for the big
growers the commercial Brewers the the
people like that who they assume are all
bikers and what I know is that a lot of
people in Vancouver grow pot for their
own consumption they may have one room
in their house where they have a light
and they have some marijuana plants
growing and and that I think is the the
largest kind of
in Vancouver definitely you know is the
personal gardener and there's a lot of
great mm-hmm so the police don't harass
him and remind you once again that this
interview is brought to you by the
campaign for the restoration renovation
of hemp and we're the sponsors are the
Oregon camera TaxACT take it away Paul
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act will tax and
regulate the sales of marijuana to
adults through state liquor stores it
will allow adults to cultivate their own
marijuana
it will allow bars and coffee shops to
open up things like wineries we are also
allowing farmers to cultivate hip for
fiber protein and oil we will tax the
sales of marijuana to adults will allow
the untaxed sale of marijuana to medical
patients with a doctor's prescription we
need your help right now we are less
than halfway to the ballot we need 75
thousand registered Oregon voters
signatures by the end of June to put
this important issue on the ballot at
this point we want you if you've already
got our petitions to mail them back to
us today and if you don't have them call
us at 503 two three five four six zero
six we'll send them to you if you mail
some back to us we'll send you more if
you need a job give us a call because we
might be paying petitioners today so
call us at five oh three two three five
four six zero six yeah it's very
important that we get any signatures
that you have sitting at home on your
desk in your drawer mailing back to us
because we don't want you to forget
about them and then shake your head come
July because you forgot the mail back in
so it could make the difference folks
yep you know it doesn't it you know of
all you folks out there watching it's
got a couple signatures will be there
and you know and help us make our vision
of Oregon with regulated hemp available
to all a reality like you know we do in
a series of interviews up in been up in
Vancouver BC and they have their own own
vision up there they have their own
rally they're creating their own reality
that the creative community you know
we've interviewed Marc Emery now we're
doing sister I Z and it's just a
wonderful community up there and future
shows you'll see other folks that we
interviewed from this great community
and we want to crank that community here
and you can help us create that
community by giving us a call at 500 3 2
3 5 4 6 0 6 get a petition get some
signatures if you have questions give us
a call or write us and we'll answer the
questions yeah we only have until the
end of June
right now we're closing in with just a
couple months left so send those
petitions in call us if you have access
to the World Wide Web
look at our web page at WWE our Rho RG
you can actually download our petitions
from our web page there at WWC RR h o RG
r if you don't have access to this
newfangled technology call us on the
phone at five oh three two three five
four six zero six let us send you these
petitions and if you already have them
please send them back to us right now
don't wait all right and let's go back
to our interview with sister IC from
hemp bc up in Vancouver BC isn't she
great it's a very same person larger
than our city Portland and Portland
there they're doing several a day
several a day they have to do property
seizures and rocking home seizures and
things like
conjunction with it do they do that the
property seizure here in Canada actually
with the passage of a bill of C eight
last year they do now have they can
apply to do that they can apply to have
property seized it's never actually been
tried so I think there was a case of
Victoria where there was a house seized
and what they have to do now is apply
there to keep it is anything away from
the other but again it's not been tested
so let's see so it's just being
implemented yes
we'll see if Canadians yeah hopefully
not supposed to have to have a line here
needs work
you know if property taken right and
left in our country so like I say it's a
good service obedience we don't know you
know breathe the law I don't want to
change it just have to live your life it
really corrupts the criminal justice
system as well because the police are
going after property they don't you know
they're really looking and making
decisions on how much money they can
make and doing positive there's one
horror story that one of our guests a
few months back
forfeiture attorney Constance Krueger
was talking about one of her clients was
arrested for growing marijuana and they
took everything took his refrigerator
and stoves TVs his furniture and then
they charged him in federal court where
he was facing an incredibly long prison
sentence and he committed suicide and
his family went to get you know some of
his belongings back or the police said
they wanted to keep this refrigerator
and microwave for their office and so
that's what they did well
yeah for shame yeah so that's really the
situation in our country unfortunately
it's a shame that our government's
pressuring years to try to make it where
fascism creeps here as well yes and it's
becoming embarassingly obvious so here
we are you know doing what we can then
yeah we're gonna stop it
yeah well that's immense while they look
like your store here you're getting
information out to people so they can
use it you know how to you know grow the
plants that they want you know the uses
of plants they can buy products made
from a plant this is just such an active
so there's a being it's right there
almost is telling people something that
they don't know we have to educate you
know that's the only way I think it's
the only way to change all this is to
make people more informed and to show
them where the lies of being told to
them all these years you know it's just
we've got to stop believing everything
we're fed by the Machine I just have to
stop yeah yeah it's great that you can
take over the business here and help
when did you take over the business
Oh on the 8th of March thank you thank
you very much
I'm thrilled it's just an awesome
opportunity that Marc Emery has given me
and yeah I really want to live up
yeah that's a good challenge so if you
got any that ran plans for how do you
want to see the story evolve and we're
just gonna keep growing we're just gonna
keep growing and keep providing people
with with what they want and we're just
gonna see how it goes I mean I'm not a
firm believer in making very concrete
plans I think things are a little more
kind of unstable than that but so we're
just gonna keep going on and then doing
what we know is right in that I don't
think we're gonna feel so it's good yeah
yeah I just this is kind of neat that
you've knit be able to do this when the
city fathers mothers daily giving you
permission the proper policeman yeah no
not yet we I have applied for a business
license probably not enough time for
issue of it exactly you know yes those
wheels turn slow like there was some
concern from the people at City Hall
about seed sales and the grouse star
both of which you know I've assured them
that both are gone and they won't be
back here and I hope that just
alleviates their concerns but we haven't
heard back as yet so we're waiting
patiently the the licensing inspector
that I spoke with a couple of weeks back
when I went to meet with him
assured me that he would not close him
VC
well my my application
it's being processed so so you know
we're confident that we can continue to
open our doors every day do some
business you know sorry did I give your
timetable of when they might decide no
no secret probation they have you on
double-secret probation
no we're behaving ourselves so I don't
foresee any problems well good it's
pretty unusual I haven't ever been the
Amsterdam that's pretty unusual to come
in let's see people openly smoking in an
establishment that's really cool I think
Rick Lee myself but what's that like
yeah you know pretty you don't I don't
think there's any place else here on
this continent that you can see that and
I want to congratulate you for helping
pioneer this well thank you and I have a
lot of brave souls upstairs you know and
again they're all doing what they think
is right you know Marc Emery said
something a time that really stuck
that is if you want freedom sometimes
you just have to take it you can't and
that's what we're doing it's an awesome
feeling when it's brought to my
attention I mean I do this every day
this is my life and I don't really
notice anything out of the ordinary but
when we have people come in and say oh
that's amazing that you can do this and
it's so free and and Wow Vancouver's
such enormous in place you know it's
really it's exciting you know it really
is that we're showing people something
that you know it's real freedom nobody's
you know doing something that you know
they deem important and there's it's not
a big deal you know and it's not it's
only flour so and that's what we're
trying to show people that's what we're
trying to present so the flour that
hasn't caused one death in recorded
history it's probably the oldest
agricultural problem all archaeologists
agree it's among the oldest
try the truth yeah all right
once again like your mind folks that
this interview with sister Isis brought
to you by the campaign for the
restoration and regulation of hemp and
we have initiative out there the Oregon
canvass tax act and we need your help
jörgen cannabis tax act will tax and
regulate the sales of marijuana to
adults allow bars and taverns to sell
taxed marijuana to adults it will allow
the untaxed sale of marijuana to
patients medical patients with a
doctor's prescription
it will allow industrial hemp to be
cultivated by farmers without a license
to produce fiber protein paper fabric
rope thousands of products tens of
thousands of products and it will raise
hundreds of millions of dollars in
revenue to save all of us from further
taxes from our lovely state of Oregon
we're only taking registered Oregon
voters signatures on this we need all of
our signatures by the end of June so if
you have petitions please mail them back
to us right away if you don't have
petitions we'll send them to you and
call us at five OH three two three five
four six
0/6 if you're outside the Portland area
if you're in Portland call us at two
three five four six zero six yeah and
you know we need your help and we need
your signatures if you got just one you
know this is the filled out sheet which
is beautiful to see it's a beautiful
sight oh and but you only have two or
three signatures on there or even your
own we still need that mail it back in
today
you know because every signature counts
and there's a lot of folks out there
that can only have one or two signatures
and that's great
you know maybe you go get your friend's
signature your partner's signature and
that would be fabulous but give us a
call and if you have questions there'll
be somebody there hopefully to answer
the phone if not leave a message and
we'll get back to you you know we need
your help getting us on the ballot we
want to create our vision and here in
Oregon our vision of a of cannabis back
to where it should be restored to its
rightful place and one of the many
things that humans can use for medicine
for food for fuel for fiber and for
recreation so let's let's restore that
folks by give us a call at five OH three
two three five four six
oh six restore canvas to its rightful
place and we can make it happen here
like Sister isyes doing up in Vancouver
we can make it happen here yes we'd love
to send you this petition so ask for it
right away just in closing here in the
final minute I'd like to mention that on
May 19th there will be a primary and if
you live in Inner Southeast Portland in
House District 14 I am a candidate for
the Democratic nomination for state
representative from House District 14 I
want to abolish the income tax on those
making less than forty thousand dollars
a year I want to establish ecological
sustainability taxes and of course I
want to tax and regulate marijuana out
of the hands of kids and substance
abusers put it in the liquor stores
where the age limit of 21 strictly
enforced which is what the Oregon
cannabis
Act will do so give us a call get this
petition it's two three five four six
zero six we need your help to make it a
berry community thanks folks thanks for
watching tune in next week for another
exciting edition cannabis common sense
bye
you