[Music]
video taped at the studios of city video
at evolution it's time for cannabis
common-sense the show that tells you the
truth about marijuana and the politics
behind its prohibition and now here's
the host of your show Paul Stanford and
Paul Loney hello and welcome to another
exciting edition of cannabis
common-sense right over here we have
Paul Loney who is our political
committees treasurer and an attorney
here we have dr. Fred orther I pop in as
a guest and a longtime activist for
freedom here in the state
I'm Paul Stanford welcome to the show
yeah and this show was brought to you by
our political action committee that
campaigned for the restoration and
regulation of hemp it's all volunteer
effort and exists solely to put the
Oregon camest tax act on a ballot which
exists solely to get back some of our
freedoms which allow us to enjoy
cannabis recreationally
I'm handed out as medicine through
pharmacies and our farmers can grow
industrial hemp
yeah the Oregon cannabis Tax Act would
allow the state to make some money just
the way they make money off beer liquor
and tobacco in terms of taxing it
through the state liquor store system
like they do with distilled alcohol the
state would license farmers to cultivate
the drug for sales to the state
commission then the state commission
would distribute it at cost to
pharmacies and to the liquor stores
where they'd make a profit would also
allow farmers to cultivate industrial
hemp and him par viewers know produces
more fiber for clothes
in textiles and paper and more oil for
fuel and food and more protein than any
other plant on this planet so our job
here is to stop the war on drugs and
we're trying to do that through using
our most powerful tool the pen through
the initiative process and we need your
help so we urge you to give us a call at
our number which is right there on your
screen
it's two three five four six
oh seven in the Portland area and if
you're outside of the Portland area just
style 5:03 2 3 5 4 6 o 6 we'll send you
our newspaper and our petitions because
we want to get you involved there's a
bunch of different ways to get involved
outside of petitioning - including
transporting people to events data-entry
delivering newspapers but most of all we
want to get you involved right Paul
yeah it's very simple to gather
signatures just the other day Paul and I
went out with a new person and within
you know half an hour he had picked it
picked it up and was raring to go the
next day out by himself and it's just
and it's fun you're actually out there
you know you're meeting people it's a
good place to people watch and it's it's
amazing to find out how many people
don't care about their own personal
lives out there you ask them if they're
you know you know if you want to look at
its I initiate eveni and say no then we
ask what what the initiative is they
have no they don't care about their own
political rights anymore that it's like
to involve themselves to do anything
about it you know because they're just
it's it's that you know our society has
taught us to you know go inward I mean
not think about anything else
mm-hmm voting is just one way of
democracy you know democracy is really
power in the people and not to wolves to
the sheep voting on the menu which is
what's become right mature they call it
majoritarianism
but politics and voting you vote a lot
of ways you vote with dollars you vote
with your feet you vote with ballots and
if it comes to it sometimes in some
jurisdictions they've voted with bullets
they did here a couple of hundred years
ago 1776 and and but the the initiative
process is a way to peacefully
participate in the political process and
under the the theories that we we call
our own we're supposed to be able to
change the rules under which we live and
that's well you know I'd like to tell
people that petitioning is one of the
most effective and effectiveness
oriented activities that you can take on
a previous show I've given this analogy
that I think vote if you don't exercise
your political rights you lose your
political rights and just just like your
any other type of exercise if you don't
do it you're going to lose that power
and if you look at voting voting is a
very important activity and I wouldn't
want to say to denigrate it at all but I
think voting is like lifting a two pound
weight and if you're going to write to
your Congressman or write to your local
newspaper
that's like exercising and lifting a
five-pound weight if you're gonna get a
petition though and circulate it among
your family and friends
well now you're exercising with the
10-pound weight but it the most
effective thing you can do is to go out
in public and meet people you don't know
and if you do it with a group of us it's
fun and you have people tell you how
grateful they are that you're there
doing that and that to me is like
lifting a hundred pound weight in
comparison the different ways we can
exercise our political rights I like
that I like that metaphor when I started
petitioning I wasn't very good I knew
what I knew but I couldn't express what
I knew and by the time I had talked to a
thousand people and explained what I was
about I refined my explanation down to a
very few very succinct cogent correct
words
and after I'd listen to a thousand
stories I knew what it was and I was
able to respond to people's concerns
what are their common questions around
this issue and to me it was invaluable
political training I it was for me it
was better than going down to hang out
in Salem that doing that kind of
apprenticeship I know that you did an
apprenticeship sort of this summer you
you were I did I tried to go in there
and stop this darn recriminate were
lined up against us it's all process you
know you can't be goal-oriented you
you're you can't stop Leviathan you
can't now off the locomotive now you
were down there honing your skills you
were down there putting a little
pressure on it at all it all counts
that's what politics is about yeah I
wanted to have you talk a little bit
about something you and your intro you
talked about what what happened when
they did when they ended alcohol
prohibition remember we had like 13 or
14 years 29 to 33 to end alcohol
prohibition and what did they do at the
end of prohibition what they did was
they set up what I call non criminal
distribution basically and you've
addressed that in in the thing about the
the liquor stores and I wish you'd tell
me a little bit more about how that's
gonna work I'm very because there has to
be non criminal distribution exactly
that there's gonna have to be that
mechanism somehow it's going to have to
be set up and and worked and it's gonna
have to be made fair and all of those
things okay well what would happen is
this a farmer who is interested in
cultivating the drug for sale would get
a license from what is currently the
Oregon Liquor Control Commission however
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act our
initiative petition changes the name of
the olcc to the ICC the Oregon
intoxicant Control Commission using the
term intoxicant to represent what
both liquor and marijuana due to people
and so we decided to skewed the term
drugs because that might include
pharmaceuticals well anyway a farmer who
was interested in that would apply for a
license the state would determine how
much it needs to purchase in a given
period then the state would equitably
distribute the license among the
applicants and they would buy either the
maximum amount the farmer would grow or
they would buy approximately the same
amount from the different farmers now
according to specifically the Single
Convention treaty the state has to have
a commission and this is the single
convention treaties an international
treaty that governs the way controlled
substances can be sold by the
signatories and has over a hundred
different nations that have signed up to
it it's a it's a it's not a good treaty
by any means and personally I'd like to
see it repealed but it's the structure
that we first have to work in and the
way to repeal it is to go to the United
States Senate and have them repeal it
well it's a real hard job to go to your
hundred US senators and get them to do
something like that
so here we tried to write our initiative
in compliance with that treaty so that
it be upheld according to that treaty
the state has to collect the entire crop
within four months of harvest so the
cannabis would be harvested by the
farmers and then it might be processed
into cigarettes or any one of a number
of things and so processors would have
it but within um four months of harvest
the state would take control of that and
then distribute it to pharmacies for
medical need and it would be it cost for
pharmacies it wouldn't be taxed and it
would sell it through the 270 store
liquor store system that we have here in
the state of Oregon here in Oregon we're
one of the 26 states that has a state
controlled storage system for distilled
alcohol products and rather than
creating a new infrastructure to comply
with these international treaties we
decided to work within the existing
structure
so the state would take control of it
and put it in the state liquor stores
however our initiative allows
individuals to cultivate their own
marijuana without a license and it also
makes it illegal to prohibit any
specific strain of seed or cuttings so
if you want to go to your local garden
store and pick out the variety you want
or the seed that you want the the trade
in the seeds and starts is not regulated
but the trade in the Dragons basically
it's like wine and beer if you want to
brew your own beer or make your own wine
you don't need a license to be able to
do that but if you want to brew enough
beer or make enough wine to sell and you
want to sell it then you've got to get a
license and the government is going to
come in and make certain you're applying
the laws that the legislature
legislators enacted does that explain it
is there anything that's missing here
yeah we have again the in short a
non-criminal distribution system it's
set up we have the skeleton or the
outline or the it's already there
does the single convention deal with
alcohol as no substance no so that's out
of the exactly the purview of the single
Kimmage okay that's not a scheduled
drugs and then they don't and it's not
and tobacco also it's not a scheduled
drug no not at all it's not even
considered a drunk yet even though the
settlement with the tobacco company so
in the in the u.s. now that the FDA has
the authority to regulate that with the
drug it is a drug yeah okay so we should
see some interesting things you know if
it was if it was health and safety as
somebody pointed out not too long ago
they would be confiscating the homes and
cars and money of people who use alcohol
and tobacco or who buy and sell alcohol
and tobacco and and that's the
the prohibition approach and they have
they have chosen not to do it at all as
far as tobacco is concerned until
recently and that's 400,000 deaths a
year according to yeah yeah more
statistics yeah 400 and yeah far more
than alcohol
yeah alcohol you get a hundred thousand
deaths a year but for marijuana
zip zilch and all he wrote folks even if
you believe their numbers all all that's
they're not illegal drugs put together
is less what five thousand something
like that it is yeah because very few
people you know actually died from the
illegal drugs they died from you know
poor nutrition because they're doing
illegal drugs pharmacist it's same thing
it's the same thing though farms are the
drugs the people of poor nutrition and
they're doing pharmaceutical drugs yeah
but it's from all the side effects that
the impurities that they mix with these
drugs yeah
like even these days with cannabis you
never know what's sprayed on cannabis I
mean that's you know frame we'll just
consumer out there that's the scary part
you don't know what somebody's sprayed
out so in light of that I'd like to
point out that the Oregon cannabis Tax
Act takes that into consideration the
cannabis that is sold has to be graded
and tested for adulterants and the
packages have to say what adulterants
what additives are included in that
cannabis if you look at tobacco we all
know they put saltpeter in there to make
them burn they actually put a little bit
of ammonia in there to release the the
nicotine and make it pass through the
the blood air membranes in your lungs
they put in I've heard upwards to I
don't know what is it 400 different
chemicals in a tobacco cigarette but
you'll never find that written on any
package about no cigarettes what they do
is they chop it up and they put it into
a sludge and they add a bunch of stuff
to it then they dry it out well
according to the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
if they wanted to do something like that
with cannabis they'd have to list every
single added
and they would have to I warn of the
health danger of any that have harmful
effects known harmful effects to human
health they brought it on themselves you
know when I was the kid fifty years ago
we all called cigarettes were called
coffin nails everybody knew that one
cigarette short took a day off your life
that was or an hour you know there was
some kinda that that was common
knowledge if there was it was it was
vernacular proof and you know they've
gotten away with that for years they run
that scan but science hasn't proven well
yes nobody asks science they ask shil
stopped but and she'll say oh no there's
nothing but you know the this they have
not treated tobacco very well it the
thing I find historically interesting
about alcohol prohibition is we have
prohibition from 29 to 33 and
historically to me it looks like for the
next 50 years after alcohol prohibition
was repealed that the public attitude
was so bad about anybody that talked
about alcohol that we couldn't publicly
recognize that that that hundreds of
thousands of people were dying or being
injured in drunk driving accidents every
year the people were dying of cirrhosis
the people have brought these problems
up were ignored because of that 13 years
of moral grandeur that they called
alcohol prohibition with gangs with with
increasing federal enrichment into the
lives of private citizens and also into
local politics the feds got big into
local law enforcement politics in
prohibition and it took 50 years before
society as a whole and our rulers as a
group could begin to address the problem
of alcohol consumption it's not wasn't
just that I think because if you went
back when they repeal prohibition it was
a two part thing as usual the government
always gets the second part part number
one repeal prohibition part number two
there was to be a massive education
campaign
to the American public about the dangers
the use of alcohol which is be funded by
the alcohol companies but you know that
was the agreement but you know next to
the next day they Acts Part B if it
happens all the time now I don't know
wait you know but I mean that's that's
that's where the real problem was and
that's why you know the abuse to this
day rains with alcohol and which is why
among our children that's the highest
drug they abuses alcohol but we know
with Oregon cameras TaxACT a different
story
yeah we we wrote the TaxACT base to
specifically distribute the profits and
the taxes that will be the state's
windfall when they tax and regulate the
cannabis market you know right now
marijuana is the number one cash crop
here in the United States and in an
Oregon it's the number one cash crop by
probably the largest factor in in the
United States with the possible
exception of Hawaii here in Oregon we
have one of the highest per capita
production rates of cannabis what our
initiative will do is it would bring in
that money out of the black market and
put it on the table for all of us to see
and the state would have a share in that
you know in 1989 the DEA said that that
was 2.6 billion dollars that's the price
of marijuana is about doubled since 1989
so it might have gone up maybe
productions gone down it's very
difficult to gauge these things but
let's say that we could bring in 20% of
that if we could bring in 20% of 2.6
billion dollars we're talking five
hundred million dollars that by far
dwarfs the amount of money that's coming
in from the lottery the lottery proceeds
are projected over two years where this
would just be a single year over a two
year biennium as our financial and
physical statements are made by state
government we'd be talking about a
billion dollars or maybe a tenth or more
of total state revenue well I thought
you know you're gonna get into the fact
organ cameras TaxACT put all that side
that we direct money to go into exam
treatment programs education that's the
important thing too it doesn't matter
what the money figures are cuz people
will always argue with us but but if you
can point the fact that we're going to
direct proceeds to treatment programs
education programs so that you know that
people will be able to get help if they
want help well ninety percent of the
proceeds would go into the state general
fund as revenue for state programs but
then eight percent would go in to drug
treatment programs you know right now
alcoholics and addicts are turned away
ninety percent of the time when they
seek help usually they only can get that
help after they've been found guilty of
some other crime
well our initiative would increase
funding for that by several times and it
would 8% of the total proceeds would go
in to substance abuse treatment programs
one percent would go into funding and
creating a comprehensive and realistic
drug education program for kids and then
the final one percent would go into a
state agricultural committee to promote
industrial hemp since hemp has been
repressed and many people myself
included believe that the whole
marijuana smoke screen pun intended
was created to divert attention away
from the fact that hemp it produces more
fiber protein and oil than any other
problem we we think that one percent of
the proceeds from the profit of the sale
of the drug going to reestablish this
vital and sustainable energy industry is
is quite appropriate we think it will
help put oregon on the cutting edge of
exciting new developments and
technologies that are truly sustainable
well yeah i you know believe that we
can't just as we can't throw all sorts
of wild numbers about tax proceeds
coming from this we do we don't know
what the industrial hemp market would be
because it's been so long we've been
caught up in this cult of you know of
modernity we said okay we now we can
have petroleum now we can have plastics
we can have cotton
and people were so excited by new modern
things they forgot him because hemp you
know also became that was for the low
class people wore hemp clothes
meaning the upper classes were silk and
then cotton you know and so it became
service thing like only the lower-class
people would would wear it and would use
it as a fiber and then only lower cut
people would use it as a intoxicant and
that's the you know and that's what you
have to get back away from right either
better we all got a cop to be in low
class people yeah yeah and we're not
that were not but it's you know we've
got to learn again what what him can do
for us we've forgotten and that's what
it comes down to if there's to be a
chief and a halfway chance of saving the
remaining trees and putting the put in
the farmland into in the useful service
hemp is is the way to do it until about
a hundred and forty years ago over
ninety percent of all the world's paper
yep of course remember 100 four years
ago very very little paper in his world
yes a lot less yeah so we don't I mean
so when people start throwing numbers
around is what I put that in perspective
that we just don't know what industrial
hemp will do for us because we haven't
used it so long it's time to experiment
I know my household is now where we're
active we we read a lot we write a lot
and and so forth but we're jacking out
the equivalent of 20 foot of tree every
two weeks in in terms of newsmen you
know three foot of newsprint 20 foot of
tree yeah and every two weeks were
firing out 20 foot of tree yeah and I'm
a pauper and and penal we cut down and
we recycle and I'm just appalled between
the mail the newspaper and then you know
the computer paper and and and the the
advertisements the the stuffers you know
is that much thick clay paper in in an
Oregonian when it comes by waste of the
shiny stuff weighs almost as much as the
paper itself yeah
but there's a tremendous amount of of
trees going up the chimney that need not
there are other sources of pulp and
fiber now as some numbers that I do like
to refer back to are the United States
Department of Agriculture studies that
were done at the turn of this century in
1916 the US Department of Agriculture
began looking at hemp Hurd's which were
traditionally a waste material Hiep was
traditionally grown for the bark or the
bast fiber that's the outer part of the
stalk the interior part of the stock the
hemp Hurd's were a waste material that
was used as animal bedding or sometimes
burn as a fuel but with the introduction
of the dekor diecutting machine at the
turn of this century that waste material
could be collected much more efficiently
than it could previously be done when
when it was the the bast fiber was
separated by hand in 1916 the United
States Department of Agriculture did a
bulletin USDA bulletin 404 the name of
that bulletin was hip herds as a paper
making material and in that they said to
provide a mill that makes a hundred tons
of paper a day by today's standard a
hundred tons of paper day is a very
small mill but by those standards it was
an average mill back at the turn of this
century to provide that mill with enough
trees to feed the mill would take 40
thousand five hundred acres to provide
that same mill with this waste product
from producing him vast fiber and hemp
seed oil and protein would take just ten
thousand acres under cultivation now
that's according the US Department of
Agriculture's bulletin 404 admittedly
it's a dated document and agricultural
techniques have been improved since then
but those techniques haven't been in
practice with him well we really don't
know what it back this time to
experiment once again you know and you
know pun intended there once again you
know we have to experiment with him to
find out what it can do for us you know
and we've forgotten at a society you
know it's
time to say okay you know let's do it
and that's why we have the Oregon campus
Tax Act you know asking folks out there
to get out there and petition it's you
know it's it's the fun thing to do you
get out with friends it's amazing how
quickly time goes by and how many
singers you can get in a hurry you know
if nothing else get your get your family
to sign this and you're a few friends
but best thing to do is come out and
petition you know at some summer event
concerts waterfront parks or ad malls
and there's also out there now the
Oregon drug control amendment put out by
the American and a prohibition League
and then there's a referendum on the
recrimination bill so help us out and
what sometimes you can active what's our
phone our phone number which is on the
screen you should call it if you're in
the Portland area and is 2 3 5 4 6 o 6
if you're outside of the Portland area
and you're watching this it's 1 5 0 3 2
3 5 4 6 0 6 and if you're on the
internet you can just pull our petitions
and everything off the web at WWE get
those petitions because that's the way
you can have a real impact and it's the
most highly effective activity you could
take to stop the build-up of coercive
police power in America that's what I
think
yeah and initiatives all these so-called
political consultants and the
politicians in Salem themselves say that
if you get something down to ballot
that's when they pay attention that's
true it's like what happened last time
with the Oregon clean stream edition
they have a guy on a ballot but it lost
but governor kids however they had to do
something this year you know they had
because it was on the ballot it's like
you know the so this will do this will
tell the folks in Salem that were we're
serious about this taking back our
freedoms that's absolutely right but we
can't do it ourselves you know I often
hear the question what are you going to
do to legalize marijuana well we're not
going to do it by ourselves
we've all
all in this together and it's going to
take all of us to stop this and it's
going to take us going to our family and
friends it's going to take us getting
petitions thanks for watching it's been
another exciting edition thankful Oregon
thanks both thanks and read TaxACT and
cannabis common sense
thanks for coming Freddie good thank you
folks
oh right
[Music]