the Oregon cannabis Tax Act petition
will do a lot of different things we'd
like to talk about the phone sure thanks
Paul
our petition once it becomes enacted
will enable pharmacies to sell at cost
to patients medicinal marijuana
it will our farmers to grow hemp and
compete in the world markets it will
allow individuals to grow and their own
personal quantities of hemp and will
allow the sale of marijuana to people in
coffee shops in bars and in liquor
stores just like hard alcohol is sold
now it's a it's a comprehensive
reworking of our laws as ours like to
tell folks you know this initiatives
gonna raise hundreds of millions of
dollars in revenue for the state we
don't really know exactly how much but
we can say hundreds of millions of
dollars because I like the sound that
hundreds of millions dollars well I also
Paula don't want to forget that it's
also going to allow us to save money
they won't be so much money on putting
people in jail hiring no district
attorneys hiring police officers public
defenders judges it all adds up so we'll
be saving money as well as getting tax
money off of this hundreds of millions
of dollars and you know we dedicate that
money ninety percent of it to the state
general fund where the legislature can
decide how to spend it we hope they'll
put it toward education but the other
ten percent eight percent of that left
goes to drug treatment programs so that
alcoholics and other people with
substance abuse product problems can get
the help they need when they need it
final two percent one percent would go
to a comprehensive drug education
program for kids in schools taught by
educational professionals not by the
police like the DARE program is today
then that last one percent would go to
fund a state agricultural committee to
promote industrial hemp to try to
restore its place here in our economy
alright then getting to today's show
which should be a lot of fun for folks
it's a it's a real enjoyable one just
we've got
good interview later on show but coming
up first we have some more scenes of the
million marijuana March up in Seattle
that took place on may day right and so
right off the bat we've got an
interesting couple of characters here
that were singing a song that we found
rather humorous so roll that tape please
[Music]
[Applause]
everybody
[Music]
Oh
[Applause]
[Music]
now everybody's talking about Brian
dying twice
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
we
[Music]
yeah
[Applause]
that was a great song folks I really
enjoyed that song the whole March was
great and gosh it was just a whole lot
of fun being there and Paul who's our
the next clip we have well we've got the
the million marijuana March organized
you know at the end of the March started
out with I would say about a thousand
folks and by the time it finished in
downtown Seattle it had grown to three
or four thousands the estimate
stretching for three or four city blocks
through downtown Seattle the organizer
of the March where the folks that do the
Seattle hip fest and that's a huge rally
that they have every year it's coming up
on August 22nd this year down on the
waterfront in Seattle but the organizer
is Vivien McPeak and he was the emcee at
the rally after the million marijuana
March so Vivien McPeak who is also the
emcee of the Seattle Hempfest which
generally has about 50,000 people at it
the past few years is up next on the
stage at the Westlake Center in downtown
Seattle at the conclusion of the million
marijuana march Callaghan was supposed
to be here today
Nora is the director of the November
coalition out of Colville Washington the
November Coalition is one of the most
powerful organizations in the country to
end the drug war it started around 1977
right before the Seattle Hempfest that
year what the November coalition does is
it puts names and faces behind the
prisoners the POWs of the war on drugs
and the war on pot and also behind they
hidden the victims of the war on out of
the war on drugs which is the children
the orphans the wives the husbands the
brothers and sisters the parents the
families of the people whose lives have
been destroyed and crushed will spend
years years years decades in jail for a
harmless benign therapeutic herb which
never killed anyone with an overdose
never killed anyone toxicity
if somebody tells you different if a
bold-faced lie there's a reason that
Nora can't be here today
Nora's brother Patrick is serving a
23-year prison sentence mandatory
minimum sentence no chance of parole he
was caught in what's called a dry
conspiracy under conspiracy laws you
could be sent to prison with absolutely
no concrete evidence whatsoever you can
be served to prison on hearsay evidence
alone by paid informants who are already
felon incarcerated you have nothing to
lose but everything to gain from lying
[Music]
Nora's brother Patrick Callahan is Anna
Federal Penitentiary in the other side
of the country serving his 23 year
sentence and he's in the late stages of
liver disease he's not very well now
it'd be a good time to send a healing
prayer a Healing thought a healing vibe
the Patrick and Nora and all are on line
how many people raise your hand or
online with computers right on now put
your hands down how many people are on
him net as your internet service
provider that's gonna change soon
ham dotnet is an internet service
provider
it is done all of the web design for
sale that's website how many people seen
our website wwlp.com I introduced you to
my good friend and colleague Robert lund
a owner and operator of him net hello
Seattle right here in the middle
Westlake Center you guys are awesome
those of you to some of the marches
against prohibition last year I'm sure
you can appreciate the members we see
here today today we've been marching and
speaking out against the numerous and
justices brought on the American people
by the war on drugs we may be a diverse
group of people with differing opinions
on the issues but one thing is common
amongst us all the war on drugs has
affected the lives of everyone of us
enough so that you're willing to get in
the streets and March and say that
things have got to change the drug war
is wrong
we know the truck was wrong because it's
fraught with injustice forfeiture laws
are unjust because they allow a home or
car to be taken without an individual to
be charged with a crime mandatory
minimums are unjust because there's no
room to consider the circumstances that
go along with the rest the judge should
have the option the legislature should
not be saying you go to jail for ten
years because you are related or heard
about a drug bust and the cannabis
prohibition is unjust our laws are
hypocrisy parla it's hypocrisy that we
can drink alcohol we've killed hundreds
of people every year
[Applause]
it's a [ __ ] receipt you can legally
smoke nicotine and yet it kills hundreds
of thousands of people every year and
yet I'll say it here is that you have
the right to do that you should as a
free American being able to consume
nicotine to drink alcohol and smoke pot
so what's the result of this unjust war
well for example there's a mr. gray who
was the US Marine for five years he went
off and served this country in the Gulf
War he came back with numerous
unexplainable illnesses uncontrollable
vomiting he went to the VA hospital 20
times they prescribed numerous legal
drugs none of them which could help him
so finally he turned like many sufferers
of the Gulf War Syndrome due to
marijuana and he found relief and how do
we thank him steal his [ __ ] house
[Applause]
another Justice is the Eastside
Narcotics Task Force we allow them to
engage in terrorist tactics destroying
homes and traumatizing children house
after house after house that's unjust
and just that will foster the crows
marijuana for his own personal medical
reason should be sentenced to 93 years
in jail
the drug more needs to change 80% of our
forfeitures occur where no individual
'its was charged with a crime I think
this is such an injustice and we don't
have to look farther that our own law of
Washington to see the problems with his
law so I'm going to read the three
pillars of the Washington State
forfeiture law tenet number one and this
is in the hip voters guide if you saw
this last year number one in cases
involving property personal property the
burden of producing evidence shall be
upon the person claiming to be the
lawful owner of the property that's you
that's not the cops if they plan
something to shove you up to you to
prove it if your friend has a joint in
your car and they take your car it's
your responsibility to prove it there's
no due process in that and there's no
justice in that look at the next two
floors of the Washington state farm to
drill on number two is each seizing
agency sorry meant to the state
treasurer and about equal to ten percent
of the net proceeds of any of the
property for critism final pillar what
happens to the other ninety percent
property and the net proceeds not
required if I'm paid to the State
Treasurer shall be retained by the
seizing law enforcement agency
[Applause]
and as an invitation for corruptness
it's no longer a balanced justice system
that we're supposed to have in the
United States the forfeiture laws and
the drug war needs to change
[Applause]
alright and I hope you enjoyed a little
flavor that day up in Seattle the
million marijuana March it was a great
sunny day where there was perfect
weather for the March people had a lot
of fun as you could see good speakers
and you know once you tell us a little
about the whole idea behind the million
marijuana March Paul well you know it
has a long history it's been called the
million marijuana March for about the
past three years and up until this year
it had just taken place in New York City
it had a history in New York City going
back to like 1970 as the Fifth Avenue
made a pot parade that put on by the
yuppies the group started by Abbie
Hoffman and Jerry Rubin back in the 60s
but anyway they've been doing the march
there but back in about 1995 when they
had the Million Man March by the Nation
of Islam they they start calling up the
million marijuana March and this year
was the first time that they had broken
out into other cities and in fact there
were marches taking place all over the
world in Amsterdam and Auckland New
Zealand in Sydney Australia and San
Francisco and New York of course Chicago
I can't even begin to name all the
cities that this thing was going on in
and maybe it did approach a million
people when you talk about it on a
worldwide scale you know that's what I
heard they did approach a million I
think that's great you know that's the
whole idea behind it a pass I've never
had a million this year they had a
million marchers across the world
speaking up for marijuana and hoping
next year I made a it'll grow even
bigger so remember that date folks
May Day next year take part in the the
marijuana million marijuana March I made
am next year something else you can take
part in
you know we're circulating the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act petition
this will allow adults to legally buy
marijuana
two state liquor stores bars and other
shops that get the license will be able
to serve marijuana the same way they
serve mixed alcoholic drinks it will
also allow farmers to cultivate the drug
for sales to the Oregon Liquor Control
Commission the Oregon Liquor Control
Commission would sell it through
pharmacies both in Oregon and outside at
cost we're just cover the cost of the
agency and the farmers expenses and then
it would sell it at a profit through our
state liquor stores and raise lots of
money so it would also allow adults to
grow their own and allow farmers to
cultivate industrial hemp without a
license so that they could produce paper
fabric protein oil fuel and 50,000
different products so we need your help
to put this important issue on the
ballot you know if you can help us
petition in public if you can help us in
our office if you can help us on our
phone banks if you just want to get the
petition just so you can sign it
yourself
call us and what's that number Erico 503
two three five four six zero six
that's two three five four six oh six
call us we have voicemail if we're not
right there and you can also look at our
website it's one most of the major
website Awards from Netscape what school
and so on but you can print our petition
out from the internet you can watch this
TV show on the internet you can watch a
hundred different videos but you can get
our attention directly through the
internet at WWE our Rho our G so now
we're going to go into another segment
of our interview with the Dean emeritus
of Oregon Health Sciences University dr.
John Benson dr. Benson was also one of
the two principal co-investigators for
the National Academy of Sciences
Institute of Medicine report that was
issued in March 1999 called marijuana
and medicine assessing the science base
and this is a real good interview it
technical at times goes into a lot of
the the details behind the pharmacology
of cannabis and its use as a medicinal
agent so I guess we'll just run right
into that hope you enjoy it some of the
people who were on the panel I've
recalled that the Israeli scientists
because neutrophil not cool mccoullough
Mikula he's the one who discovered THC
about 25 years ago and then discovered
the receptor sites or at least worked on
the team worked on those and has also
been involved in some of the endogenous
cannabinoids natural substances we all
have in our brains and bodies as well
still very active right are those coming
to endorphins are there a different
group of chemicals also endogenous
though that use different receptors
there are different receptors for the
opioids morphine and codeine those two
substances so the endorphins are among
these agents that help energize the
neurons to put out transmitters in
various centers of the brain and
cannabinoids or the components of the
marijuana leaf are yet another system
pharmacological system so that
endogenous system I hope you think they
call it the endorphin like substance
since the anatomy it's a Septon and
amide yes the one that is best developed
it also uses the so called cb1 receptor
cannabinoid one receptor and such as THC
does and then there's another one that's
2 AG Iraq and Daniel glycerol
which is another of these and endogenous
cannabinoids like substances have they
identified the primary action of this
receptor system is that there are many
actions actually there the receptors
have been identified and cloned actually
and they can be cited or located in
various parts of the brain that had to
do with pain perception with movement
control with control of vomiting with
warm and pleasant feelings with sedation
and so forth so they're very common
throughout the brain so that there is
definite what should we say therapeutic
action of these substances would that be
well I mean I wouldn't say the actions
that you mentioned seemed to me to be
therapeutic in nature could be 30 well
they might be exploited for therapeutic
uses that's correct because there are
these systems yes in place and that's
the reason I'm sure that people have
found some utility for the use of these
cannabinoid substances before the
president of the Institute of Medicine
asked you to be a co-investigator can
you tell us about the process that led
up to the Institute of Medicine
conducting this inquiry yes the White
House Office of National Drug Control
Policy which is directed by Barry
McCaffrey ask the Institute concept to
consider such a study and was willing to
fund it about the same time a major
foundation also thought this would be
worthy of study
but the Institute thought it better and
so did it apparently general McCaffrey
if only the one sponsor were responsible
and so a proposal was made to the his
office by the Institute staff which led
to a statement of task so called and
then the funding of the study what was
the mandate from the Office of National
Drug Control Policy on that didn't they
exclude they just won the medical report
nothing to do with science sir well
there's no lens the science yes they
wanted the scientific basis for any
benefits or harms that might come from
the medical use of marijuana or its
component substances and we were not
restricted but we were not picked either
to address issues of social legislative
regulatory at cetera kinds of
considerations I think it would have
been a very different statement of task
and a very different group that could
not have included me were you involved
at all I know that the Institute of
Medicine produced a report 15 years
before regarding marijuana not
specifically as medicine there was
viewed that oh absolutely I was not that
was in 1982 and it was frustrated by the
lack of clear science rigorous
experimentation and called repeatedly
for research in various fields in the
meantime there's been a explosion of
knowledge in the basic science field all
of these an and amide and receptors and
neurotransmitters and sighting of these
things and various control areas in the
brain have been elaborated so we were at
a distinct advantage over the people who
did that study
and we hope we carried things a bit
further because of that new science
could you address that explosion in
science and discovery of the receptor
system and a bit for our audience well
it really was the identification of the
receptors themselves cloning them citing
them wherever they were found both in
the brain and peripherally the CB to
that cannabinoid to receptor is
primarily in the immune system and more
peripheral nervous system and CB one is
primarily in the brain these endogenous
cannabinoids like substances that I've
mentioned were elaborated and a good
deal of just straight pharmacology done
on them so that we had the advantage of
oh for example showing the effects in
animals on pain and showing the effects
on control of motion things of that
nature from these basic science advances
they were really quite remarkable and
pretty exciting to an internist
clinician like myself had no idea they
had existed I hope you found that
informative I really did and it's I'm
glad that we were able to interview him
so in the closing here in a show don't
forget to call us again if you want to
help us out put put our initiative on
the bell at the Oregon campus TaxACT our
phone number is two three five four six
zero six and again Paul what will I do
in a little thumbnail sketch it will
regulate the sale of marijuana to adults
in state liquor stores let people grow
their own let doctors prescribe it
through pharmacies and finally allow
farmers to cultivate industrial hemp you
know I'd also to give us a call at two
three five four six oh six you like to
also thank dr. Philip Levesque for
helping with the interview with doctor
Bentsen there the dean emeritus at
Oregon Health Sciences University so
thanks dr. Levesque who is also along
with Paul and I chief petitioner on this
petition that's right so if you want to
help us put this on the ballot it's two
three five four six zero six a website
at WWE are our hor G so check out the
website give us a phone call help us out
if you can
you know Paul and I and dr. Levesque and
our whole film crew we all do this on a
volunteer basis so we really need your
help
to help change this marijuana law so
call us yeah we don't want to sound like
pitch people up here but many hands make
light work so help us and thanks for
watching and I hope you found this
informative and next week tune back in
for more of the million marijuana March
from Seattle and more of this great
interview with the Dean of Oregon Health
Sciences University dr. John Benson so
that's right next week well once again
we'll be informative and we'll be
entertaining thanks for watching and
have a good night
Oh
[Music]
well now everybody's talking about Brian
diet
Brian bye
[Music]