it's time for cannabis common sense the
show that tells you the truth about
marijuana and politics behind its
prohibition now host of your show to
tell you the truth about marijuana and
the politics behind its prohibition
let's welcome all Stanford welcome to
another exciting edition of cannabis
common sense as you may know cannabis
common sense is a production of our
political committee campaign for the
restoration and regulation of hemp and
that's C rrh for short and if you are
aware we are circulating a petition and
a referendum at this time the petition
our initiative is the Oregon cannabis
Tax Act that would license farmers to
grow the drug marijuana for sale to the
olcc the olcc would sell it through its
liquor store system and put it in bars
and taverns that got a license to carry
it and it would also put in in
pharmacies at cost it would tax the
recreational use of marijuana through
the liquor stores the bars and taverns
and smoking establishments but the
marijuana sold through the pharmacies
would not be taxed and that would be
with the doctor's prescription so if
you're registered to vote we need you
give us a call get our petitions sign
the petitions sign the referendum the
referendum is different from the
initiative it is a legislative bill that
the was an enacted by the legislature it
hasn't gone into effect yet it will
wreak rimmel eyes a simple possession of
under an ounce of marijuana which has
been legal here in Oregon for the past
24 years since 1973 and we get enough
signatures by early October to put this
on the ballot for a vote in November of
then the law will not take effect in
October of 1997 as it's currently
scheduled to do
it will be held in abeyance and its
eventual outcome would be decided by the
people in a vote in November 1998 we
need your help to get signatures if
you're registered to vote give us a call
or if you aren't registered to vote and
you're living in Oregon register to vote
because if you don't vote the people who
want to put us in prison will so give us
a call two three five four 606 that's in
Portland Oregon if you're outside of the
Portland area give dial one 503 two
three five four six zero six we need
your help like to welcome Donna
back for a another episode thanks thank
you and Donna's a longtime activist the
treasurer of Portland normal the
Portland's branch of the National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws normal it's proud to announce that
we register more voters than any other
organization in this state that's right
and we would like to register you if
you're not registered let us know
exactly you know the initiative
campaigns in Oregon actually have
registered more voters than the
Democrats and the Republicans combined
so we're out there in the streets
contacting people and registering our
constituents and we're trying to get
them out to vote so that will have a
bigger impact on the entire political
process not just the drug policy to be
well as I tell people they don't when
they if they bust you they don't care
whether you're registered or not that's
true
so you better be registered then you
might be able to have some effect yeah
and if you are busted you can still
register to vote you know in other parts
of the country you can't register to
vote if you've been convicted of a
felony and a lot of people here in
Oregon are under the misperception that
they can't register to vote some of the
people I like to register the most when
the amount in the street petitioning are
people who don't think they can register
to vote because of the laws if you run
into that Donna where people said I
can't vote and so well yes you can every
time that I have collected signatures at
one of our events people will come along
and say well I really wish I could sign
your
petition but I can't read but I can't
read it I'm not registered and I said
well we could register you I said I
can't register I'm a felon I said does
it matter here in Oregon felons
well not in jail but when they're on
probation or parole after they've served
their time and done their debt to
society they can register and vote and
should do so they're going to be
affected by laws they must they should
have definitely a say in producing them
mm-hmm so give us a call if you have
access to the web you can get our
petitions right off the internet on your
own home Brenner assuming you have an
inkjet printer or with waterproofing or
a laser printer you can just print them
right there in your home you don't even
have to wait for us to send them to you
our web address is w wh o RG no Donna
you've been a member of a local club
called the alternative health center
that's right and that's a club that
allows the medicinal access to marijuana
and even though it's illegal currently
the people who are running the club and
you're not really involved on that level
but the people who are running the club
are taking a great risk to themselves I
think oh they certainly are I mean
running the club you are as far as the
police are concerned you're distributing
and they could be arrested for
distribution but they believe that it's
so important to get marijuana to people
who need it that it's worth running that
risk and they're running that risk every
day and as are their patients I know
quite a lot of the patients at the
alternative health center and your heart
goes out to these people I mean a lot of
them have cancer are been chemotherapy
they've lost their hair they've lost
I've met a man the other day who just
had who had just had his his arm removed
two weeks previously because he had had
cancer in the bone right here a lot of
people with AIDS are there who are
taking you know people with AIDS take a
real
large number of drugs the new Proteus
inhibitors evidently are doing a
wonderful thing about their effect on
the AIDS virus but they also make people
really sick and it can't eat they can't
eat one is wait right you can you can
die from that too right they call that
the wasting syndrome from people who
have AIDS and many AIDS patients say the
only thing that helps keep them alive
where they can increase their appetite
is by using cannabis in marijuana to
combat the wasting syndrome that
companies the use of all those
pharmaceutical drugs and it's also on
appetite stimulator for people who are
undergoing chemotherapy with can zoo
people who are undergoing cancer
treatment find that by using marijuana
it stimulates their appetite for that
week after chemotherapy when they can't
keep anything down
it stops nausea mm-hmm now there are
several different medicinal products in
cannabis there's THC
tetrahydrocannabinol THC is the
substance that combats nausea it stops
nausea increases appetite lowers inter
ocular pressure there are other and it's
actually available pharmaceutically but
for oral that's not all right that's
Marinol and it's available
pharmaceutically but taking it orally is
really difficult if you're nauseous
really you'll throw up three or four of
them and those pills are not cheap yes
I'm very elusive cost six dollars and
the big ones cost eighteen or twenty oh
my god and you throw up three or four
$20 pills you're you better you're you
better either be rich or have a good
health insurance that's for sure and
unfortunately in the case of a lot of
people they don't have that so but they
find it by just taking two or three
puffs of good marijuana that they're
able to keep food down they're able to
keep liquids down and they're not
throwing up and that's what THC
does and lowers inter ocular pressure
it's probably the most psychoactive
ingredient in cannabis as well
now there's another constituent of
cannabis cannabis all and that is CBD
and CBD is just slightly psychoactive
not so much as THC and it is an anti
[ __ ] agent so people who have
multiple sclerosis find that that
portion of the chemical mix in marijuana
that helps them and people who have
multiple sclerosis anything that causes
them to go into spasms they find that
use of CBD is very useful but that is
not pharmaceutically available it's only
available in the black market there's
also one other constituent of Kavanagh
of cannabis or marijuana and that's
cannabic Romi Mar CBC CBC is not
psychoactive at all but it has an anti
infection property it's lowers
temperatures for some people it stops
the onset of fever and has some other
medicinal properties so cannabis isn't
just one or two constituents it's a
variety of them and a lot of them have
different medical effects that's true I
know several patients who either have
multiple sclerosis or in are in
wheelchairs or have had injuries and are
paralyzed from wherever down one person
I know particularly is paralyzed from
the waist down he says that if you are
in this situation you have spasms in
your limbs that you cannot control and
also that pain can suddenly strike
anywhere evidently if you interfere with
the spinal cord you have no control over
what the nerves are going to be doing
and that smoking marijuana he said is
better than any drug he'd ever taken for
me for for both calming the spasms and
for making the pain go away yeah you
know we at
the campaign for the restoration
regulation of him are not involved with
the alternative health center the club
here in Portland
there are also clubs in other parts of
the country especially in California now
with the passage of proposition 215 that
allowed medical marijuana down there but
we refer people that asked about it to
the club and we don't have a problem
with that we are happy to see a patient
that needs this to have access to this
medicine and we wonder why the state has
imposed itself between the doctor and
the patient which would you prefer to
decide your medical issue should it be
your doctor should it be you personally
or should it be the police officer who
wants to seize your property because you
might own a house I think the answer is
pretty clear you know with the
recrimination of marijuana bill that's
passed that we're circulating a petition
to try to stop the police said that the
Maine that this was their number one
priority the top priority that they had
with all the murderers and rapists and
thieves out there they're making this
their top priority they solve this
problem Oh Robert oh my god yeah we know
arson here and there we know here in
Portland that if you have your house
robbed or your car stolen police don't
even visit you anymore they send you a
form in the mail so they they say that
this is their top priority and that the
real reason they want to do this even
according to the governor of the state
when he issued a press release was so
that he could expand the powers of
police search and seizure he said that
this has less to do with marijuana as it
does with expanding the powers of police
search and seizure you know I was really
disappointed in Governor Kitzhaber when
I voted for him I thought he was a
progressive Democrat would you know had
good ideas about what to do with this
state and it was my impression that he
had decided to veto this bill because
the state couldn't afford it if it can't
afford to keep the libraries in Portland
open it can't afford to employ the
amount of teachers it takes to
teach our children it can't afford to
create more shelters for domestic
violence victims I mean I thought that
the state could not afford to
incarcerate a bunch of pot smokers and I
thought the governor thought that do you
ever talk to him
I ran into the governor when I was down
working in Salem and lobbying against
this bill the governor told me
personally when I ran into him at a
coffee stand I was there to get a an
expresso drink a drug at the drug stand
there you go it was an open-air drug
market right in front of the State
Capitol they were selling caffeine
beverages and these caffeine ones
sometimes I bet you get whatever strings
you want you know you want double dose
triple dose they'll they'll sell them to
you at these open-air caffeine markets
and the governor was there in line
waiting for his caffeine laced ring as I
was going up to get my caffeine lace
drink my coffee express it Moke actually
I don't drink coffee I drink and there
he was and I couldn't resist half this
rare once-in-a-lifetime opportunity okay
exists pause I was I was supposed you
know I've been trying to stop this
recrimination bill and I thought I will
never get to see the governor they
wouldn't let me see him
I run into him at the coffee stand I say
governor Kitzhaber this was early April
I said governor Kitzhaber I'd like to
take this opportunity to urge you to
veto House bill 36:43 well it hadn't
been passed by either house of the
legislature at that point but it looked
pretty certain to pass there were a lot
of different interests that were backing
it everyone in the Republican Party and
they held control of both houses
unanimously supported it well one
senator limb out in Gresham opposed it
one Republican but anyway the governor
turned I said and he goes well okay I
said governor I want to urge you to veto
House bill 36:43 the governor said well
which one is that I said that's the one
that would wreak reminisce possession of
marijuana the governor got his drink
from the man he turned around he looked
at me says you know we really don't have
the money for that and I'm going to be
to it that
what he said he says we really don't
have the money for that and I'm going to
veto it well I couldn't agree more
I was happy that's right in the end the
governor claimed that he reluctantly
signed it and he said it wasn't because
of possession of marijuana but that in
fact it was to expand the police powers
of search and seizure well we need to
send a message to the governor and the
legislature and you can do that by
getting our petitions get the referendum
petition give us a call at two three
five four six zero six that's two three
five four six zero six we'll get you to
the referendum we've got to get 50,000
good registered Oregon voter signatures
by July no I bother
October 3rd of this year 1997 that's not
if we do it'll stop it from going to
effect it's not much time at all you
might be seeing this show in in
September I'm not sure maybe even
afterwards but if we don't get enough
signatures by then we're still
circulating the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
which would legalize the sale of
marijuana to adults over 21
it would allow doctors to prescribe
marijuana to patients through pharmacies
at cost it would tax the recreational
marijuana that sold in liquor stores and
bars and coffee shops and it would also
legalize industrial hemp so that farmers
can grow industrial hemp for production
of thousands of different products
everything from paper and fabric and
building materials from the stems of the
marijuana plant to oil for food and
energy and protein from the hemp seed
you know actually hemp produces more
fiber protein and oil that any other
plant on our planet they've taken this
plant it grows more in the temperate and
cooler climates than any other plant on
the entire planet and they've prohibited
this plant and to me I believe that that
is truly evil to take a plant that
produces more fiber protein and oil and
say oh you can't grow that one folks
because we want to say you petroleum we
want to sell you pesticide lace cotton
whatever you want to cut
on all the forests and there that's what
really bothers me is to think that
they're not only cutting down trees for
timber and things like that I can
understand that but they're cutting down
trees to make paper write paper from
Hampton you can from wood anyway yeah
paper was that's a renewable resource
it's an annual it grows every year you
don't have to like grow a crop for like
sixty years and have lunch dreams
running through it and animals living in
the trees and all that and then cut them
down you can grow it like wheat and it
rejuvenates the soil really actually him
has a very long tap root and it draws up
subsoil nutrients and when the Leafs
fall off and go back into the soil it
brings those nutrients up from the
minerals below and puts them into the
the soil for other plants to use so it's
a very good plant for breaking soil and
for revitalizing soil in a crop harvest
and it'll grow anywhere I've seen him
growing in a swamp condition in China in
China in fact they invented paper 2,000
years ago from him and the first cloth
and textiles were made from him all
archaeologists agree that hemp was one
of the first plants purposely cultivated
by man
there are three other plants that they
can't distinguish which one was the very
first one but all archaeologists agree
that hemp was definitely among the first
plants so you're talking about the plant
that perhaps agriculture was invented to
to service bins need for him for both
medicine protein fiber and oil and the
plant that produces more of this protein
fiber and oil to me that's just a
travesty we've got to change that a
plant that's as useful as him I wonder
why they would make it illegal I mean it
baffles me
you know the American Medical
Association actually went into Congress
in 1937 a dr. Woodard and testified that
they should not criminalize hemp the
Annabeth's had many medicine properties
and that what they were saying
marijuana caused at the time they said
smoking any marijuana would cause you to
go crazy and kill your family and
friends they actually laid out documents
that and the doctor the lobbyist for the
American Medical Association told the
congressional committee that that's not
true that those things aren't so and he
opposed it and several legislators
harassed this doctor and told him he
shouldn't be trying to stop lawmakers at
work and then when it came to a full
vote in the House of Representatives one
senator from that committee stood up and
lied and said that that doctor had
supported the bill when in fact he had
opposed it that's um so it passed
without debate sounds a lot like I've
made my mind is made up don't bother
true though that it happened actually
was August 2nd 1937 so here it is just
over living in infamy so here we are a
little bit more than 60 years later and
we're facing a drug war who's the winner
in the drug war I don't think there are
any winners is there any sign that
there's going to be a victory yet after
60 years I don't think so instead you
see the patients in the alternative
health center they're facing the rest
they're in danger of going to jail and I
mean these people are sick what's it
what kind of care is there going to be
for them in jail I don't believe that
they're going to be able to and how much
is it going to cost to care for these
people in jail I mean how many
wheelchairs do they keep in jails I
don't know but they want to take them in
there and book them and possibly
sentence them to up to 30 days if they
have an ounce or less now if the patient
can't afford to go and buy marijuana in
the black market and they happen to be
growing one or two plants well it's
escalated folks that's those are that's
a Class A felony it's the same as murder
rate it's worse than man's
slaughtered rape actually it's the
equivalent of murder and those people
have their homes taken away have their
property seized they're convicted felons
they have to go through drug treatment
and diversion it's really a very
horrible system folks and we need to
send the message to politicians and you
can do that by calling us and getting
the referendum to stop the recrimination
of marijuana to referendum on House bill
3643 and we need to get 50,000
signatures by early October and you can
get the Oregon cannabis Tax Act we need
to get seventy five thousand signatures
by July of 1998 if we get enough
signatures then they're both on the
ballot in November of 1998 give us a
call at our office here in Portland it's
five oh three two three five four six
zero six you can also download it off
the internet we also have a newspaper if
you come down to our booths we're at the
Portland and Eugene Saturday market
we're at various events we'll be at the
bike we'll be at the bike here in
Portland in mid-august
will be we have the Rose Festival we
were at the Rose Festival and will be of
course that was before the
regionalization happen so we weren't
carrying it then but the recrimination
petition as we're going to tape here in
early August has only been out for about
three weeks now hmmm but we urge you to
give us a call and get in touch with us
and get our petitions because the only
way we're going to make a difference is
if we get out and show the support by
putting these things on the ballot we
need your help to do that
so I urge you to call us today don't
delay because the next door to be kicked
in may be your own that's the truth it
always amazes me the things they say
about what like you're saying that
burned that smoking marijuana makes
people crazy and they were going to kill
their friends and that's the kind of
thing they call that reefer blast how
many people in this country have smoked
marijuana at some time is it twenty
million is it
well no 20 million they estimate our
regular monthly users narrator but the
total number I think of people who'll
admit to it is about 80 million are
almost half the population immense that
even Bill Clinton said he huffed but
didn't inhale and Newt Gingrich says he
he smoked marijuana for some period of
time I believe Al Gore Al and Tipper
Gore inhaled as well yeah these people
didn't ruin their lives they didn't
start killing their families I mean you
know that that's a lie I mean even those
of you who don't smoke marijuana
yourself so you know somebody that does
and they're just people like anybody
else they have jobs they have children
they have homes actually some studies
show that marijuana smokers have a
higher instance of on time job
performance being at work on most days
non marijuana smokers actually have a
higher rate of absenteeism and I think
that's indicative of some of the
propaganda most people find that hard to
believe
well that's why they don't record it
very much driving stream media but the
fact of the matter is that the media
manipulates certain groups manipulate
the media particularly the law
enforcement people and the folks in the
drug treatment industry that oh that
makes me think you know with the
referendum I believe that one of the
things is mandatory drug treatment the
drug treatment industry is going to make
a lot of money from this they've got to
be the behind supporting this yeah and
it requires the a mandatory diversion
project for anyone who's convicted and
you have your license suspended for six
months and if you're under 18 you don't
get your driver's license until you've
turned 18 and that doesn't it doesn't
matter where you've been arrested with
marijuana to have this happen you could
be in your bedroom you could
be out in the woods you could be
anywhere and those laws are in effect
they'll take away your driver's license
and make you go into diversion you have
up to 30 days in jail they'll seize your
property it's really a terrible system
and we're trying to change that by
circulating the referendum and the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act so once again I
want to urge you to give us a call get
help us put the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
on the ballot help us stop the black
market you know right now the main
people who are controlling the black
market are kids
and users substance abusers by night and
people who have used other substances
besides just marijuana I'm sure and
that's the reason that marijuana is
labeled by some as a gateway drug you
know it's a gateway but it's a gateway
to the black market if we take marijuana
out of the black market like they have
in the Netherlands then the rate of use
of all drugs is going to decline
according to a survey that was quoted in
the British Medical Journal back in
December of 1995 it's called D
glamorizing cannabis and that article
said that the rate of use of marijuana
in the Netherlands by people who are 16
and 17 years old people who have legal
access because in the Netherlands you
can buy marijuana when you're 16 years
old that the rate of use is less than
one-fifth what it is here in the United
States that's obviously indicative of
the fact that prohibition isn't working
so we want you to get our petitions want
to thank you for calling thanks for
being on the show Donna thank you Paul
my pleasure contact us get our petitions
the number two three five four six
oh six help us stop the drug war before
they kick in your door that's right and
call us today thanks for watching tune
in next week have good time
[Music]
you