[Music]
video tape live at the studios of city
video app the rage nightclub it is time
for cannabis common sense the show that
tells you the truth about marijuana and
the politics behind this prohibition now
here's the host of the show Paul
Stanford and all loading hello and
welcome to another exciting edition of
cannabis common sense my name is Paul
Stanford and I'm Paul Oni we're here
with the campaign for the restoration
and regulation of him we're an Oregon
political committee that's circulating a
petition the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
which will tax and regulate the sales of
marijuana to adults and allow medicinal
marijuana and completely legalized
industrial hemp it's true that's as our
tagline begin the show says this is the
truth we're here to tell you the truth
and our petition is about telling the
truth and getting the truth back out
there which is why we would call our
political action camp committee to
restore hemp we want to restore hemp to
its rightful place to its truthful place
yeah him produces more fiber protein and
oil than any other plant on this planet
and our petition would allow Oregon
farmers to cultivate this valuable crop
and allow Oregon industries to develop
sustainable products and practices yeah
the entire crop will be purchased by the
Oregon Liquor Control Commission and
then be sold to state-run stores and
packaged that way for for use but part
of that also would they would package it
to pharmacies and control it for
pharmacies and so we would work that way
with it
which would help patients who need it
for medical purposes yes it would also
allow doctors to prescribe it through
those pharmacies and that wouldn't be
taxed the marijuana in pharmacies would
be sold at cost so it'd be very an
expense
the sales to adults through the state
liquor store system we would have a tax
on the sales of the product to adults
and that and through any bars or public
houses that wanted to add marijuana as
something as long as they bar minors
from entering and they have a license
they could be supplied by the olcc
we actually change the name of the olcc
to the oregon intoxicant Control
Commission rather the Oregon Liquor
Control Commission because we'll be
including cannabis in there Everywhere's
and and it would make more sense anyways
because the Oregon Liquor Control
Commission right now does deal with
certain medical drugs and it packages
liquor as medicine for some people and
so then also what we're we really want
to point out is that this does allow
this question always comes up it does
allow people to grow at home because if
we don't we classify seeds and starts as
hemp and hemp
not regulated by this initiative you
allowed to grow hemp so as in the
Netherlands today the cultivation of
marijuana for personal use and the sales
of seeds and small plants and starts or
cuttings would be legalized and so you
wouldn't be mandated to go through the
state system but since most people who
grew smoke tobacco don't grow their own
tobacco we would guess that the there
would still be a pretty open market
through the liquor store system and
local taverns and public houses but
definitely cuz not everybody has a green
thumb let's face it and not everybody
wants to take responsibility of watering
a plant on you know on a weekly basis or
whatever and and have them to worry
about it's um you just want to pop down
in the local store and buy some or go
into the local public house and enjoy a
little bit with their friends and so
that's what this is all about it is
basically restoring freedom and freedom
of choice and one thing I want to make
clear up front is surely you know I can
see public houses open up after this
initiative passes but
it's still illegal under this to drive
under the influence under the influence
of anything is still illegal so we're
gonna make that perfectly clear to start
off with but and I'm real happy that
this does cover the medical purposes for
marijuana a lot of people out there use
marijuana on a daily basis some some
people use on a weekly basis when the
need strikes but they do need marijuana
for a medical purpose and this addresses
that this takes them out of the black
market out of the hands of the common
criminals out of their hands of trying
to grow it for themselves and says okay
wording you know treat like a regular
herb a pharmaceutical herb exactly it
would allow the sale through pharmacies
and so people would be certain that
they're getting medicinal quality
marijuana through pharmacies so we're
doing that through a petition process
and right now we have closing in on
about two almost twenty thousand
signatures we need to turn in about a
hundred thousand signatures because we
need seventy three thousand two hundred
and sixty one valid registered Oregon
voters signatures signed to put this on
the ballot so we need your help to do
that we've been sending out a lot of
petitions in the past month we've mailed
out well over thirteen hundred
we've been robbing our liquor store
systems we will need your help to put
this on the ballot
we've only got until July of 1998 to get
the rest of the signatures so even if
you can only get one signature your own
or you want to get your friends or you
want to help us by coming to something
like the Rolling Stone concerts on
January 30th and 31st we'll be staffing
that if you'd like to come out and help
us in public please give us a call at
two three five four six zero six that's
two three five four six zero six our
offices man from 10 a.m. to 3 p.m.
Monday through Friday you'll find us in
there a lot of the times otherwise and
we have an extensive voicemail system
that can handle over a hundred calls so
please call us we'd like to
this petition yeah and if you're outside
a portent of you an area of course it's
area code 503 and the Rolling Stones
concert does up here in Portland but
definitely it should be a lot of fun
we're getting people together to go out
there and petition and teams on both
night so come up for you know up for one
night or both nights yeah it's a Friday
and Saturday night and I'm sure
afterwards we'll be retiring to a nice
place to you know have a celebratory
drink so come on down and help us
petition and meet some friends and like
if you can't do that like Paul said get
your own signature that of your bed of
your friends that of your parents your
roommates whoever so we need all the
signatures we can get give us call and
get those petitions that's number on
your screen
that's area code five oh three two three
five four six oh six if you have access
to the Internet at your home at the
library or through a local university or
school you can look at our website at
WWE
you even print these petitions right
from the internet and watch streaming
videos and other things so we urged you
to look at our website because it's just
chock full of information we've got a
news archive of stories on cannabis from
around the world that goes back to 1992
that's mirrored in the Netherlands and
other places yeah and so please help us
he can tonight we were gonna have a
guest on her show a victim of the
marijuana task force a victim of a
illness that needs marijuana needs
cannabis to help out with those symptoms
of that illness that would have been
dying Densmore who probably ought to
have heard of today was a victim of
marijuana task force she ran the
cannabis buyers club a local version of
it here which helped out people here who
who needed as their the drug of of
missile need and this will help and but
she can't be here because she's
suffering from some medical problems
right now do the fact that the police
have harassed her
she can't get access yeah actually I
talked to her this evening and she was a
person who was running the alternative
health clinic here in Portland and was
busted I guess it was in late September
initially and they came back in late
October and busted her again and took
her to jail for over a week they held
her in there and I'm sure most of you
feel a lot safer because this lady died
and Densmore was locked up but she is
now having to take a urinalysis test at
least once a week call in daily seven
days a week down to the Multnomah County
Jail and their supervisors and report
periodically to them upon demand and to
undergo your analysis testing and
because that she can't use her medicine
and she's doing really really poorly she
says her cardiac problems are starting
to increase and she's got a number of
other medical problems and then she's
under an incredible amount of stress and
she misses her friends the people she
used to work with in the the club she
really said she she was missing some of
those folks so if you want to get in
touch with Dianne dents more and give
her some support give us a call we can
put you in touch with her call us at two
three five four six zero six
she couldn't make it tonight hopefully
she'll be back with us in mid to late
January when we tape again so she'll be
hopefully she'll be feeling a little bit
better and you give us a report directly
yeah it's just really shame that the
police had to spend all of our tax
dollars on this you know there's a they
had a multi most surveillance on the
internal health center they sent in
undercover police numerous times they
sent in informa descend street and
forming in and the thing is that you
know they had a real doctor write up
real notes and we don't know why this
doctor did this whether this doctor was
was pressured because he was under some
sort of
suspicions himself or some sort of crime
or whether the doctor is the drug
warrior and while I take pardon and if
that's the case then he's writing you
know false notes in which he's reported
to the state licensing board of medicine
the figure out why this guy's writing
phony prescriptions for non-existent
alum elements there's a lot of questions
there that haven't been answered by the
local police department or the local
district attorney and so I would suggest
you know Colin locust attorney's office
up well know McAllister Attorney's
Office there live in the tri-county area
there any blue pages of the phone book
under Multnomah County District
Attorney's Office call up and say hey
why are you folks prosecuting dying
Dinsmore and others it's not just her
there's other people as well that were
arrested you know from this whole fall
out at this marijuana task force it's
just a travesty yeah yeah they they
arrested some of the people who were
helping they're volunteering and it's
it's a shame that very ill people people
who who are dying in fact the
alternative health clinic a few of their
patients would be dying every every week
or a lot you know people who have cancer
and advanced HIV and they found that
cannabis helped them cannabis helped the
the cancer patients undergoing
chemotherapy restore their appetite
cannabis helped the AIDS patients
restore their appetite that were
suffering from the wasting syndrome
so to go in and arrest the people
providing relief to these people to me
seems particularly evil and cruel
unfortunately some of the officers
involved when that have questionable
ethics in my opinion a lot of officers
though support innovations like the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act and they want to
make certain that they don't have to go
out and arrest nonviolent family raising
adults using marijuana and the privacy
of their home so a lot of times we have
law enforcement officers sign our
petition so we urge you to
help us put this on the ballot give us a
call and get the petition at 2 3 5 4 6 o
6 yeah correct call us and get the
petition you know you'll be amazed at
how many your friends have already signs
petition or would be willing to sign it
as soon as they you know see this a lot
of people you know stolen how it exists
out there so we need your help to help
get to worry out that hey there's
petition out there to make cannabis
legal and regulate it in this state and
you know we can be the leaders once
again Oregon is known as being the
leader for for many things and
especially in health care and you know
we can do it
so we need your help but you know right
now let me talk about you know with
Diane Densmore the any other folks
arrested I mean it was just a travesty
the Portland Police come in spend all
that money and there was no you know no
no complaints from the public on this
this was all police generated the whole
controversy about this there's no the
you know the police you know they didn't
say they're getting calls from the
public to go out and bust these people
people all had gotten some publicity for
running they'll turn of health center
for providing cannabis for people who
desperately needed it as medicine but
the police didn't you know they created
their own their own crime in a sense it
seems to me that they have a political
agenda at least the officers in the drug
enforcement units that pursued this case
to arrest medical patients because the
District Attorney of Multnomah County
Michael shrunk had said that he wasn't
going to prosecute marijuana cases well
here he is prosecuting a marijuana case
so that's one politician I guess but
we'd like to point out that you know
some people say that marijuana is
medicinally available over-the-counter
because there's a substance called
Marinol that contains one of the
psychoactive substances that's in
cannabis contains THC or
tetrahydrocannabinol there are other
site non psychoactive and psychoactive
substances in mayor
Oana that have medicinal properties CBD
or cannabidiol is a anti [ __ ] agent
that stops multiple sclerosis patients
spasms very efficiently if you're
undergoing a spasm of with multiple
sclerosis you can't swallow a Marinol
pill and wait an hour and a half for it
to work just a few hits of marijuana
helped multiple sclerosis patients and
the British Medical Association just
noted that in a survey and an article
they had in the British Medical Journal
saying that marijuana should be
medicinally available
you know the Oregon cannabis Tax Act the
question itself says exactly yes vote
permit state licensed cultivation and
sale of marijuana for medical purposes
and to adults it really stresses the
medical aspects of our initiative
because we set up a number of medical
studies through the Oregon Health
Sciences University and other medical
research facilities here in the state of
Oregon and all of that's funded through
the taxation of the recreational sale of
marijuana so our initiative will help
medical patients not only get medicinal
marijuana but also access the health
they need yeah it's you stop and think
about it you know smoking marijuana is
the best delivery control substance for
THC you know much better the pill as you
said that you pill you know you have two
difficulty swallowing sometimes the time
it takes for it to break down your
stomach then they go through the stomach
walls with lining into your bloodstream
and then to the muscles that need it or
the nerves or wherever it needs to go to
versus smoking it's always bad for
things in their lungs but that's the
only choice you have
in your lungs right away I mean you're
it's getting the oxygen and blood mixes
right away so within minutes you know
it's it's where it needs to go to some
of the patients that take Marinol
complained that an hour and a half later
they either too stoned that the effects
strike too suddenly
and to intensely or they don't get that
effect at all and so they really can't
get an effective dose very they can't
measure it too well orally no it is the
best love control substance and wanting
it back to a point you made about
Michael Shrunk local da being a
politician and yet is you know and you
know I've heard him interviewed on this
talk show where he a talk show here in
town and and he basically said that I'm
a politician and right now
marijuana is against the law but I mean
you know obviously left it open and if
the law has changed you know he'll be
supported michael shrunk is not going to
be out in front of the band leading it
some people think that Michael shrunk
should be and you know his job is a
politician and he's not going to be out
in front of the band which is where we
come in we have to lead a band there's
you know majority of people here in
Oregon want to have medical marijuana
available and you know we can do that
through this petition and then people
like Michael shrunk will just say okay
yeah it's there you know this is the
people I've spoken and you know we can
we can do this with this initiative so I
just I like how to say you know Michael
shrunk is a politician and he's being
pushed around by the police department
here certainly numbers of it yeah you
know I heard a report recently that
Michael Strunk actually admitted that he
had a very ill relative up in Washington
State
that was undergoing chemotherapy and
that he actually procured and supplied
marijuana to this very ill relative so
now he's his office is in charge of
prosecuting a number of very ill people
that like his relative needed marijuana
to help save their lives to treat their
some yes I don't know whether that's
true or not but still though I mean it
just shows you that if Michael shrunk
was saying earlier he wouldn't prosecute
these but he was presented by the police
department such a high-profile case is
where it comes down to this was a very
high-profile case and a deputy da that
really well numb once just no but he was
presented to them by the police
department if it would have been just
one little person growing and given to a
few others he could have you know had to
fall between the cracks
but because the police spent so much
time on it so much money so many
officers doing this and to you know
well-publicized raids I mean both raids
were you know Oregonian front page news
I believe and on every channel and and
so so that he had he couldn't just
ignore it he had to go ahead and and
prosecute this you know the police
pushed him into it or certain members of
the police certain members of police you
know don't don't believe in your rice
that's what I've got is you know that's
that's the simple sad fact you know most
police officers do believe in your
rights but some don't and they're the
ones that are you know pushing you're on
a DA's office sadly so another ass thing
that the our ballot title says
specifically on the medical issue is
that Commission will sell marijuana at
cost to pharmacies and medical research
facilities for medical purposes we need
your help that's why we're here is to
get your involved in the Oregon cannabis
Tax Act so call us please @ 2 3 5 4 6 o
6 that's two three five four six oh six
and get these petitions if you're
outside of the Portland area call 503
two three five four six zero six we'll
be happy to send you out one to a dozen
fifty petitions however many you need
let us know because we need your help to
put this in about well you know that's
that's important that the Commission
will sell this medical cannabis to
license research facilities because one
of the first things that Ronald Reagan
did when he came into office he cut off
all funding for research for cannabis
and as we all know that researchers are
dependent upon funding usually federal
for their research especially in medical
and if you don't do research you don't
keep your job as a professor at a
university or you don't get tenure to
keep your job and then you got you got
to keep doing your research and keep
publishing papers and what soon as soon
as Ronald Reagan cut off the federal
funding for cannabis you know every
researcher just dropped it yeah and if
we can present
to them at a reasonable cost medical
marijuana cannabis there'll be a lot
more researchers back into the subject
here yeah also they they cut off the
supply to get legal marijuana for
medicinal purposes for a study you have
to get permission from NIDA the National
Institute of drug abuse and NIDA hasn't
granted permission there's one study
that was going to go forward done at the
University of California at San
Francisco Medical School and they wanted
to study the effects of marijuana on HIV
infected patients and the dr. Abrams
there Donald Abrams sought permission to
receive legal medical marijuana and his
study was funded all through but NIDA
and approved that a number of different
levels but NIDA denied access to medical
marijuana yeah yes it's difficult for
these researchers not only to get
funding but they can't even get the
substance from that's why I said so I
said that this one here because we'll
we'll provide it to license research
facilities at cost I mean it's gonna
open up a boom in research for this yeah
and a number of states allowed medical
marijuana but they never provided a
method to supply medical patients in
fact 36 states including Oregon had
medical marijuana at one time or another
over I think it's 26 now have medical
marijuana today legally allowed but only
in California are they allowing patients
to cultivate their own and that's the
only place where there really is a
system of delivery for patients you know
and of course though every every
researcher who's actually studied us has
said that basically there's enough
research out there already that says
that cannabis does work for a number of
illnesses
where'd want to call it a problem for
the human body we all we know that you
know that every time they do a research
they just go ahead and catwalk
all the past studies and they're doing
it again yep they're doing another the
fellows constitute of Medicine have the
National Science Foundation is just
doing another one at the behest of the
federal drug czar yeah that was the
passage of the bills in California
California Arizona they wanted you know
come up with another one because they
were pressured into it they were denying
it and so now they can say well actually
we're doing something where we're
cataloging all the past research they're
not doing new research no they're doing
a few forums around the country one of
them in Los Angeles New Orleans and a
final one in Washington DC where they're
allowing all sorts of public input a
couple of the researchers actually are
from Oregon Health Sciences University
there are only five researchers involved
on the project and two of them are from
right here in Portland at the Oregon
Health Sciences University but you know
our initiative is what we hope is going
to allow patients to legally get medical
marijuana through pharmacies and I think
that's a big breakthrough for them yeah
and it is going to be a big breakthrough
for the patients you know so many people
you know you know this the idea that
they can just go to local pharmacy and
get it with their prescription so much
better than I stated earlier and then
trying to find some local dealer that
has some you know and hoping that it's
that it's good clean stuff because you
never know what's going out no
pesticides or who knows what and there
was what they spray on the stuff to you
know make it seem better but just that
simple you know in their mind they know
that it's safe I mean it's it's just so
much better it's just a travesty you
know that we don't allow this medicine I
mean right well I should the government
tell you what is medicine what isn't
medicine you know we're all adults
enough to make up our own minds so get
our petition that's the solution that we
keep working at here and we urge you to
call us and get these things at two
three five four six zero six I hate to
be redundant but we do need your help
without your help we we might not make
it we need everyone's help
possibly can and so give us a call at 2
3 5 4 6 o 6 and get a petition get some
of these and get helpless get some
signatures even if it's just your own
we'll be happy to send you one if you
just want one and help us put this on
the ballot yeah cuz I'm sure you know
most you out there watching us you know
have known as somebody personally who
has been helped by medical cannabis you
know it's some way or somebody with
multiple sclerosis or chemotherapy or
you know wasting syndrome you mean you
know it or just you know horrible pains
from all the chemical exposures people
that's a new one coming up with these
chemical toxic exposures people have
that cannabis helps that relieve that
total oliver body pain morning sickness
yeah and menstrual cramps cannabis was
actually prescribed back to Queen
Victoria over a hundred years ago for
menstrual cramps and was used for that
for many many years so met right now
marijuana isn't allowed for morning
sickness and menstrual cramps and in the
areas where it has been studied in
conjunction with pregnancy and women's
health issues they found that is
increased the birth weight of babies and
had no detrimental effects upon women's
reproductive systems no no no maybe did
its extensive study down Jamaica and no
problems at all and actually the mothers
that smoked high amounts of cannabis in
Jamaica had healthier babies higher
birth weights less problems so it's just
if we know it then we know it works I
mean early the century you know cameras
tinctures with a rage you know the
people knew knew it works so well but so
we've told you the truth hopefully about
medical cannabis and we hope you enjoyed
us yeah we urge you to one last time
give us a call and get this petition
we'll get some research on this issue
let our university scientists study
marijuana and find out the truth about
its links to women health issues call us
at 2:35 for 606 thanks for watching
another exciting
addition of cannabis common sense right
let's end the probe dish unless that
truth get out there thanks thanks and
good night
[Music]
[Applause]