[Laughter]
hello and welcome to kin of his common
sense this is a program that's about the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act an initiative
petition to tax and regulate the sales
of marijuana here in the state of Oregon
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act is an
initiative petition sponsored by our
political committee campaign for the
restoration and regulation of hemp
I'm Paul Stanford and I'm one of the
three chief testers and I'd like to
explain several of the aspects of the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act here in Oregon
our initiative will tax and regulate the
sales of marijuana through Oregon's 280
state liquor stores you know through the
state liquor stores the age limit is
strictly enforced so only people over
the age of 21 will be purchasing it the
oregon cannabis Tax Act will allow
doctors to prescribe marijuana to
patients through pharmacies so that
people who need marijuana when they're
sick or ill for various ailments
everything from glaucoma and to combat
the way a the aids wasting syndrome to
fighting the effects of chemotherapy in
relation to its use to stop cancer
marijuana helps in all of those cases it
will also allow farmers here in Oregon
to grow him for fiber protein and oil
and make everything from textiles and
rope to paper and from food to energy we
believe that the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
by legalizing industrial hemp will
create thousands of sustainable jobs
right here in our state we urge you to
help us with the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
this is our petition and it will as I
said tax and regulate the sales of
marijuana and we urge you to call our
office at 2 3 4 2 3 5 4 6 o 6 that
two three five four six oh six and help
us put this issue on the ballot
you know our petitions currently in
circulation we have until July of 1998
to gather enough signatures to put this
issue on the ballot we need your help
so give us a call at two three five four
six zero six and help put the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act on the ballot the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act will raise
hundreds and millions of dollars in
state revenue ninety percent of that
money will go into the state general
fund to lower the tax burden on us all
the other 10% is split among eight
percent for drug abuse treatment
programs so that people have substance
abuse problems with alcohol or other
drugs can get the help they need when
they need it currently about ninety
percent of those people are turned away
the Oregon cannabis tax act will
increase funding for people looking for
help with substance abuse problems by a
factor of at least 10 and perhaps as
much as thirty one percent of the
proceeds from the Oregon cannabis Tax
Act will go to create a educational
program for kids in grade schools and
secondary schools so that they can find
out the real dangers that substance
abuse might pose to their development
the final 1 percent would go into
creating a state Agriculture Committee
that would promote Oregon hemp fiber
protein and oil that committee would be
funded by the proceeds from the sales of
marijuana you know marijuana is useful
as a medicine in fact the oldest medical
texts the and Cara vada from
north-central India about five to six
thousand years ago listed marijuana is
one of the primary medicines and today a
lot of research has been done around the
world that proves that cannabis and in
various constituents in marijuana are
useful in treating various medical
ailments one of those agents in cannabis
is tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid that's
THC and
GHC has been synthesized and isolated in
a capsule form called Maron all are
technically Travon all that product is
useful in turn and it's the main
psychoactive product in cannabis it's
useful in stimulating appetite but it's
not the only active substance in
cannabis there's also CBD cannabidiol
and cannabinoid e all is useful for
treating spasms it's anti [ __ ] agent
and that's completely separate use for
from THC that's why marijuana in its
vegetable form is useful for PMS
patients patients with multiple
sclerosis because it helps stop their
spasms and helps them control that
there's also another pharmaceutically
active substance in cannabis that isn't
psychoactive at all and that's Canepa
chroming RCBC canna backrow mean is an
anti-inflammatory agent which is why
cannabis in its raw vegetable form is
useful for arthritis and any other
inflammation of the joints or problems
along that line so cannabis is a very
useful medicine with several different
medicinal compounds and this the pill
form THC or Maranatha is not completely
effective medicine for everything that
cannabis can treat you know the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act will allow doctors to
prescribe cannabis through pharmacies
and that will be it cost so the cost of
medical cannabis will be just a few
pennies on the dollar compared to the
recreational cannabis the cannabis sold
in the state liquor store system to
adults over the age of 21 will be taxed
and that money the revenue from that tax
will go to the state general fund and to
help with drug education and drug
treatment but the medical cannabis won't
be taxed in fact adults or any sick
person would be allowed to grow their
own you know currently
the THC pills which at once again only
have one active agent from cannabis
those THC pills are six dollars each for
a person who has AIDS or multiple
sclerosis that has to take them
regularly that's $30,000 a year in
medics just medicine costs now if that
cannabis was grown commercially without
the black-market in place the way it has
inflated the prices today the amount of
money that would be needed for that
person's medicine for an entire year
would be about 50 dollars compared to
the 30 thousand just using THC Marinol
pills you know for the people who are
undergoing chemotherapy they have
violent nausea for over a week for the
people who have the AIDS wasting
syndrome or have multiple sclerosis and
can't keep down those $6 pills sometimes
they'll take one pill and they'll throw
it up two or three times before they can
keep it down well and it takes up to an
hour and a half to go into effect so
they take this pill they throw it up a
couple times finally they keep one down
and then it goes into effect about an
hour and a half later and that's at six
dollars a pill about a nickels worth of
cannabis one or two deep inhalations and
it acts instantaneously the war on drugs
is not about drugs at all the war on
drugs is about money
and the continued centralization of
economic and political control the war
on drugs continues to centralize
economic control we see huge amounts of
money just in the Marinol industry going
to pharmaceutical companies instead of
going out to farmers and out it's a
decentralized sources to spread the
wealth to us all the pharmaceutical
company has a huge interest in keeping
this Marinol and the the synthetic
pharmaceutical product out there you can
see at $30,000 a year let's say there
are a thousand people here in the
Portland area alone and that's probably
an underestimate that need to take that
and so that right there is thirty
million dollars a year just from that
one market here in Portland multiply
that by the rest of the United States
and you can see why the pharmaceutical
industry is against the sales of
marijuana as a medicine they can't make
the money off of it that they can off
these synthetic drugs and the synthetic
drugs have side effects that the organic
ones don't you know marijuana has never
in human history ever caused a lethal
overdose we see the effects of alcohol
we see the effects of valium we see the
effects of many other pharmaceutical
drugs and how many thousands of people
die each year here in the United States
from the use of pharmaceutical drugs
where marijuana has not caused a single
lethal overdose in recorded history
marijuana in fact is one of the safest
drugs known to man there's an article
from The Lancet which is one of
Britain's oldest medical magazines The
Lancet it's been published for over 400
years
it's the oldest english-language medical
text and in their editorial from last
November of 1995 just a little over a
year ago they said in their editorial d
glamourizing cannabis that the use of
cannabis the smoking of cannabis even
long-term is not harmful to health now
you know many people tell us that
marijuana is a dangerous drug but here
we have the oldest peer-reviewed medical
journal in the world saying that the
smoking of cannabis even long-term is
not harmful to health why do these
doctors say this when the industry's and
people who are control our economic and
political systems here in United States
tell us differently they have an
economic incentive to do so and we want
to stop that we want to put economic
control back where it belongs you know
we
think that the government has abdicated
its responsibility to control this
market the government has a
responsibility to control the sales of
marijuana and we think the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act will do that it will
force the government to take control
back
currently they've abdicated control to
the black market the people in the black
market who are controlling it outside of
a few small a few small number of people
at the top who are making the most money
people who control it by and large are
children and substance abusers we want
to take control out of the hands of kids
and substance abusers and put it back in
the liquor store so the government can
control the sales and make certain that
it's only going to those over the age of
21 you know currently by putting
children and substance abusers in
control of the market we put these drugs
in the hands of kids who are selling
them in the classroom we look back at
alcohol prohibition we see that during
alcohol prohibition kids were selling
gin whiskey rum they were selling these
various products in the schools in fact
back during alcohol prohibition from
1917 to 1933 entire schools closed down
for a day because everybody in the
school was drunk
well that doesn't happen today but we do
see the effects of weapons and fighting
over control of the markets for these
illegal drugs we think that marijuana in
the black market is dangerous for our
youth and in fact you know we think that
marijuana is not a gateway drug that in
fact it's a gateway the black market and
this article in the British Medical
Journal from December of 1995 just a
year ago shows how that in fact is the
case in their article called the war on
drugs league prohibition isn't working
some legalization will help they said
that the use of marijuana by minors in
the Netherlands is roughly less than a
fifth what it is here in the United
States
the thing that's amazing about that is
that in the Netherlands they allow the
sales of marijuana to anyone over the
age of 16 through the Netherlands coffee
shops here in the United States
marijuana is completely prohibited in
the Netherlands since 1976
they've allowed the sales of marijuana
to anyone over the age of 16 but the use
of marijuana by those between the ages
of 17 and 18 is less than one-fifth less
than 20% what it is here in the United
States where it's completely prohibited
marijuana isn't the gateway drug but
marijuana prohibition is the gateway to
the black market we believe by taking
marijuana out of the black market and
letting the government control its sales
that the use of marijuana will decline
and the use of all other drugs will
decline as well this same British
Medical Journal article says the use of
hard drugs such as cocaine and heroin by
minors in the Netherlands is less than
1/10 what it is here in the United
States less than 10% so clearly what the
Dutch are doing is working and we want
Oregon to emulate that policy you know
just in the last few months in this
November the state of California passed
Proposition 215 proposition 215
has allowed patients in California to
use marijuana to combat various
illnesses including glaucoma for which
it lowers the inter ocular pressure
thereby saving people's eye sight for
the wasting syndrome associated with
AIDS or cancer chemotherapy in fact a
study in the Journal of Clinical
Oncology a cancer publication they
surveyed all oncologists cancer doctors
here in the United States they found
that 42% of all oncologists had
recommended marijuana to their patients
even though it's illegal and 48% of
those physicians
said that they would recommend marijuana
if in fact it was medicinally available
and 56% of them said that they thought
marijuana was useful medication to
combat the side effects from
chemotherapy to treat AIDS you know
currently here in the United States we
have a system where medical patients are
arrested for marijuana we should ask
ourselves this question who should
decide what medicine is best for a
patient should it be the patients should
it be the doctors who are deciding what
medicine is good for patients or should
it be law enforcement today we put law
enforcement in charge of that fact in an
article from the San Francisco Journal
just last a week as we tape this show in
January perhaps a little bit later as
it's being shown just they just reopened
the cannabis buyers club in San
Francisco because of proposition 215 you
know the Attorney General in the state
of California dan lundgren went in with
hundreds of officers and closed down the
cannabis buyers club last September he
did that to send a political message to
try to stop the passage of proposition
215 well recently a court judge issued
an injunction to stop the closure of the
buyers club and the buyers club is
reopened and now they are legally with
the courts blessing selling cannabis to
patients who have a medical need you
know here in Oregon there are some brave
people who are operating a buyer's club
to help patients that have a doctor's
order we think that that shouldn't be
that way in fact there's a legislature
here in Portland in the state
legislature as our oregon oregon
legislative session starts George Amy
and his last name is spelled e i GH m ey
George amy is introducing a medical bill
so the legislature might enact a
medicinal cannabis provision so that
patients can receive the cannabis they
need in fact went back in California
when they passed prop 215 one of the
things that influenced them was
Doonesbury Gary Trudeau in his
doonesbury comic-strip began to lambast
the Attorney General dan lundgren and
dan lundgren actually responded and
asked that somehow the newspaper be made
to stop putting out dooms Barry's
cartoon you know Bill Clinton is
lambasted as are many politicians by
Doonesbury and various cartoonists very
few of them ever pay attention and say
to stop but Len Lundgren actually said
that it they that they should stop
printing the doonesbury cartoon and one
of his spokesperson even went so far as
to say that they think they should
arrest the cartoon characters in
Doonesbury let just shows the extent to
which the drug warriors will go to fight
this war because to them it's not an
issue about drugs it's an issue about
money though the officers who are
benefitting from this make a lot of
money they have a lot of power they
seize a lot of objects that the
government sells and brings more money
to the government's coffers here in
Portland when they arrest someone
they'll often only prosecute people who
have equity in their home and they will
seize that equity so that they can based
on just a few small plants in a person's
home they can come in and seize their
equity and their life savings and the
people count themselves lucky if they're
not put in jail you know a good
percentage of these people are doing
this for medical need and we need
to allow these people to have access to
cannabis our initiative the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act will do that we need
your help in getting signatures on this
I urge you to give us a call come in get
our petitions let us mail them to you
somehow get hold of these petitions and
get signatures for us at the very least
get your own signature and send it back
to us get your friends signature give us
a call to do that at two three five four
six zero six that's two three five four
six zero six if it's not your standard
office hours we have voicemail hooked up
to that they can take many messages we
urge you to give us a call and ask us to
send you our petitions today two two
three five four six zero six the
decriminalization and regulation
taxation of marijuana has been receiving
a lot of publicity lately for instance
here is the cover of Time magazine where
they're talking about the increased use
and increased awareness of cannabis in
fact they have a Doonesbury cartoon on
there I'm sure the Attorney General of
California dan lundgren doesn't like
that too much but you can see that it is
getting more and more publicity and so
we're here to try to urge you to help
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act if you can
call us and get our petitions we'd be
happy to send them to you or you could
come down to one of our booths we have
booths at the Saturday market the Lloyd
Center on occasion in fact we could use
your help to staff our booths or to
staff our office just give us a call and
get hooked in and help us put this
important issue on the ballot there's
another magazine here the nation a
progressive magazine with a long history
here in the United States and you can
see that they say the war is over and
drugs win the drug war is a colossal
failure of unprecedented proportions
it's been fought for an incredibly long
time at the cost of billions and
billions of dollars and it's a failure
we want to stop that failure we want to
lower the costs associated with
enforcing these crazy laws you know
we've been tracking convictions and
incarcerations here in the state of
Oregon been tracking them over about a
period of a year and a half we found
that a little bit more than 55% of all
convictions and incarcerations in the
penitentiary here in the state of Oregon
are for marijuana are for drugs 55% of
those and half of those are a little bit
more than 25 percent are just for
marijuana alone the cost associated with
this are enormous it cost tens of
thousands of dollars to incarcerate
these people every year cost hundreds of
thousands of dollars to arrest them take
them through the court process and
prosecute them then we have to spend
millions and even billions of dollars to
build new prisons the way we're doing
here in the state of Oregon you know
we're can increase our prison population
according to the newspaper The Oregonian
over the next ten years from an article
on March 30th of 1996 the prison
population will increase by a factor of
a hundred and fifty eight percent in the
next ten years you know we already have
more people in prison per capita than
any other country in the history of the
world we have more people in prison than
South Africa had under apartheid we have
more people in prison than the Soviet
Union had under communism they say they
aren't its it isn't done yet the rate of
incarceration continues to increase at
an ever quickening pace we urge you to
write your representative we have their
their addresses right here on the screen
we urge you to write to your
representative write to your local
newspapers for every one of you that
writes we know there are a hundred of
you that wish you could write and wish
you could do that
we urge you to take up your pin the most
powerful weapon of all we urge you to
pick up your pin and write your
legislator and to write in to us and
help us change these terrible laws and
the impact they're having on our society
we can do that through the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act excuse me
the Oregon cannabis Tax Act once again
will tax and regulate the sales of
marijuana to adults in Oregon state
liquor stores where the age limit of 21
is strictly enforced
well raise hundreds and millions of
dollars in revenue in addition to all
the government savings there'll be
hundreds and millions of new dollars
pouring in
to our state general fund and that will
lower the tax burden on us all it will
fund drug treatment programs so that the
alcoholics and addicts can get the help
they need it will fund drug education
programs to warn kids about the real
dangers that substance abuse might pose
to their development it will fund a
state Agriculture committee that will
promote Oregon hemp fiber protein and
oil creating thousands of ecologically
sustainable jobs and helping the state
of Oregon be on the cutting edge of
environmentally sustainable development
it will allow Oregon doctors to
prescribe cannabis through pharmacies
that cost so that sick people could get
the cannabis they need to help their
health and help them survive it will
allow farmers to have a valuable new
crop that will help save small family
farms and help the rural economies
throughout the state of Oregon we'll
take what is indisputably the largest
cash crop in our state it perhaps is the
largest industry even in the black
market today with it illegal the largest
industry in the state you know you can
find out more about the Oregon cannabis
Tax Act by looking at our website our
website address is here on the screen
it's WWC R Rho RG that's CR R HR that's
the name of our political committee
campaign for the restoration and
regulation of him or you can write us an
email message at our address
octa octa @ CR rh o RG we need your help
you know i urge you in fact to not wait
to pick up the phone right now to give
us a call let us send you these
petitions with your help you know we can
put this important issue on the ballot
we want to be able to stop the massive
deforestation that's happening across
our planet and create sustainable
economic opportunities by allowing
farmers to grow industrial hemp for
paper use we want to stop the excessive
dependence on cotton which is the most
pollution intensive crop most people
don't know that 30 percent of all the
pesticides in the world are created to
go on the cotton crop hemp can grow
without any pesticides and produces many
times more biomass give us a call right
now at two three five four six zero six
that's two three five four six zero six
we need you to call we need you to
contact us we hope that you will get our
petition I hope you'll sign it and get
your friends to sign it and get it back
to us as soon as possible now I'd like
to thank you for watching tonight this
is Ben cannabis common sense I'd like to
thank our camera crew Lani swear low mic
mark the other people that have come
down here to help us tonight and I'd
like to thank you for tuning in and
watching we urge you once again to give
our campaign a call help us tax and
regulate the sales of marijuana and
educate people about the real benefits
and that can be had by instituting
industrial hemp and medical hemp and how
we can turn our economy around and
create environmentally sustainable jobs
by putting Oregon on the cutting edge of
that development thanks for watching
[Laughter]
[Music]