e hello and welcome to another exciting
edition of Cannabis Common Sense my name
is Paul Stanford and I'm one of the
chief petitioners on the organ cannabis
Tax Act and here with me is my co-host
my fellow Chief petitioner the treasurer
of our political committee the campaign
for the restoration and regulation of
hemp and the president of the orgon
Wildlife Federation Mr Paul Looney well
thanks Paul I like that introduction and
yes we are here um to try and get you to
help us out out with the organ Camas tax
act as Paul said this show is part um of
our political action committee the
campaign for the restoration and
regulation of hemp and he's showing you
there one of our wonderful initiatives
um at this time on these show here we
got some special treats for you tonight
we're going to have uh um some
interviews up in Vancouver British
Columbia where we spent some a few days
up there checking out the seat up in
Vancouver um and I think we had a good
time up in in Vancouver Paul U we went
up there for what 3 days was it yes I
had a wonderful time it was an excellent
trip up in Vancouver the police
basically ignore the marijuana laws and
uh they don't arrest people for smoking
marijuana there's several establishments
where people openly smoke marijuana and
we visited there and interviewed some of
the people so tonight we'll have Mark
Emory on who is uh the founder and
original proprietor of hemp BC yeah it's
I think um the viewers out there would
really like that it's it's quite
educational Mark Emery is a quite an
inspiration to everybody I think he's a
definitely unique individual um and he's
got his own points of view which are we
may all agree with all of them but um
he's got a vision and he followed his
vision I really like that fact that Mark
emry had a vision and he filed it and
it's taken him incredible places as
he'll talk he's been on CNN featured on
a number of CNN things he's been on the
cover of the Wall Street Journal with
his own little picture there
and uh just tons of places and he was
nice enough to let us interview him for
a long period of time and uh tonight
we'll show a portion of that interview
we'll have some more on subsequent shows
as well yeah and we'll have other
interviews with other folks up in
Vancouver um because up there in
Vancouver they have the Cannabis Cafe
which sells food made from um marijuana
products um all vegetarian a lot of good
vegan dishes has the hemp BC retail
store um all sorts of products made from
hemp clothes um and of course it has the
smoking utensils it has books on growing
and it has just books on the plan sell
the history of it and interviews with a
cannabis Canada magazine which is one of
the best magazines out there today on
the whole hemp issue and interviews with
the um some people who like say who work
for the magazine and there some scenes
of uh Vancouver yeah Vancouver is a
lovely city and we we got to go up there
and kind of taste the Cannabis culture
so to speak and we're happy to take you
there and inform you of what's going on
in our show but before we go to our Mark
Emery interview or at least part one of
that we want to remind you to give us a
call at 235
4606 we're circulating the Oregon
Canabis Tax Act petition as many of you
know and if you have some of those
petitions I want to urge you to fill in
this box on the bottom and mail them
back to us right away way if you're
going to get some more signatures do it
now mail it back to us we'll mail you
some more but let's get those petitions
in what the Oregon cannabis Tax Act will
do is tax and regulate the sales of
marijuana to adults it will allow adults
to cultivate marijuana it will license
Farmers to cultivate the crop for sales
it will also uh allow medical marijuana
and uh the industrial cultivation of him
to produce paper fabric protein oil and
literally ,000 other products so I want
to urge you to call us at 235
466 that's 235
466 yes um definitely give us a call and
help us out I me we want to change the
entire culture here in Oregon that
surrounding hemp get rid of the
prohibition culture and go into the um a
much more of a regulation culture that's
like you know the first step to freedom
is to you know get rid of prohibition
and and you know we want to just
regulate it the same as alcohol is you
know we would have it for recreational
use in state liquor stores um and that
would be I think a very good way of
doing it because there there's only you
know adults they check
IDs um and then you wouldn't have people
on playgrounds selling marijuana people
staying on the street corner selling it
it' just be much more of a pleasant
atmosphere um and we would and the state
of course would raise money off of that
and I think everybody would have a much
better time with it um and as you can
see up in Vancouver um there's such a
wonderful atmosphere up there there's a
great community and I hope that comes
through in the in the shows that we have
upcoming here the various interviews
that the people up there just really
know how to respect the plan um and then
therefore uh everybody's okay with it
the police are okay with it um it's
against the law there but the police say
Hey you know long as you're not
bothering anybody why should we bother
you right right and that's the way it
should be so the first part of this
interview uh is with Mark Emory we want
to urge you to call us and get these
petitions though at 235
4606 now once again Mark Emory does say
a few radical things I don't know if
we'll get into it this portion but of
course he has his own views and he's
really done a lot to uh change the
perceptions and misperceptions regarding
marijuana with some facts so let's
without further Ado let's go to the Mark
Emory interview
here we are in beautiful Vancouver
British Columbia in Canada interviewing
the most famous marijuana smoker in the
world it's latest this is Mark Emory
thanks for having us Mark how are you
Paul glad to be here thanks for having
us um you originally were in Ontario Oh
yeah I was you uh were an activist there
oh yeah for since 1980 I've been an
activist you know I was greatly inspired
by a Rand and the book Atlas Shrugged in
the Fountain Head in 19 9 had become a
real activist ever since in issues of
human freedom and liberty and nothing
more pressing than marijuana
legalization in that front but for the
first 12 years uh from 1980 to 1992 I
went to court in jail for many different
things uh opening my stores on Sunday
which we were convicted of and sent to
jail we used to sell everything that the
government banned so we went to court
and were convicted there and I during a
municipal garbage strike in 1986 I
provided my own private garbage service
for free for the public picked up 72,000
lb of garbage just to basically uh show
people they shouldn't be helpless during
you know government strikes I mean I've
done all sorts of stuff but prior to uh
the marijuana legalization issue which I
really started in Earnest in around 1991
mhm in ' 91 was that when you moved here
was that back actually that was in
Ontario we started selling illegal
banned books on marijuana I was shocked
to find that they were illegal but I
always wondered why High Times was never
on the news stands in Canada and why you
couldn't buy any kind of material about
marijuana and it's because Canada has a
law that basically
says anything that promotes Advocates or
in any way condones marijuana use um is
illegal and subject to $100,000 fine and
that's on video or in printed form it
specifically points ask for marijuana no
it says any illegal drugs so you can't
promote any illegal drug and if
marijuana is illegal of course and this
the primary one I mean there's not a lot
of people promoting LSD or heroin
although there certainly is a lot of
medical documentation that would also be
illegal in those areas too and of course
all books about the subject are illegal
etc etc and there are no EX iions and it
provides for $100,000 fine and or 6
months in jail and that's not a first
offense a second offense $300,000 so
anyway there isn't any fine bigger than
the criminal code as it turns out and uh
that's all for books about marijuana so
anyway we started selling them but I
didn't get charged for that one they
that was clearly unconstitutional so we
end up selling them in front of the
police station one day after a big press
conference and hundreds of people there
and they still wouldn't arrest me so
that was my history in Ontario and then
I went to Asia to live for a couple
years came back here in March of 94 and
founded HC on April 11th 1994 mhm and
then we really kicked up some dust mhm
yeah so what what is or at that time
what was hemp BC because um a lot of us
don't know what de time when I came here
there were no hemp stor there are no
pipes or bongs all that's illegal um
there were no books about marijuana in
High Times magazine was illegal in all
of Canada and not distributed here for
four or five years by that time and
there was nothing and so I knew there
must be a market there somewhere and
what I did is from April 11th through
July uh of that year I sold High Times
magazine and growstone door to door to
houses to people at bus stops to variety
stores I sort of was a mini distributor
to about 4050 stores who were willing to
handle it but by the way four fifths of
all the people approached in stores
refused to handle High Times because it
was banned they said and so you know
human freedom and liberty is not alive
in the in the minds of most book sellers
but we did find some who'd sell it like
here in there 5 10 20 copies and stuff
like that and that's what I did for 3
months sold things door to door and then
earned up my to start the to pay the
rent on the location at 324 West
Hastings which became the original HC
and where we were first rated and is now
the stop you here just for a second
where did you get the hemp times or the
High Times from oh we would just import
them they didn't stop them at custom
they stop at custom no no that that that
that law was not being enforced but the
fear factor involved in having a law
like that meaning you could be charged
at any time meant that Distributors
wouldn't conventional Distributors
simply wouldn't handle it because the
the climate was also different in the
1980s and the Reagan Bush period you
know people were easily scared off but
that started to thaw considerably
especially with the influence of the
emperor wears no clothes in the late '
80s and early 90s and eventually uh we
did open on July 7th 1994 the HC store
which is now the HC Legal Assistance
Center that location MH and understand
that block was all boarded up when you
came to it and that it's bad block yeah
the exact location of where HC was
founded used to be a communist Albanian
Bookshop and it had been put out of
business when somebody torched it so the
place was all fired and charred inside
and there was urine smells and urine all
it just was a filthy block and that was
one of the filthiest buildings and but
it was run by a guy who would be was
anxious to have anybody renovate the
place and fix it up and that's how we
got in in a seemingly controversial
business we had an Asian landlord and
all my landlords are Asian for this
building all our stores because they
tend to only care if they get the rent
they don't really care about what you're
doing in that building and we really do
renovate all the buildings extensively
all the properties we've ever been in
have been improved considerably so they
benefited by that trust in us and and
from there though we launched a separate
grow shop down the street right after
the first rate in in January 96 we
opened the little grow shop 3 weeks
later just next door and then we
Consolidated those into the HBC super
store that you see now MH so what was
the initial reaction of the authorities
when you opened up the first hemp PC
store we never got any reaction I've
never yet had a complaint sent to me by
letter for form written form from the
city hall from anybody in fact I've
never had a complaint from the general
public either and I used to work there
six days a week and I've never had a
single person say I don't agree with
what you're doing I've never had it it's
the least controversial Enterprise I've
ever started that's great to hear yeah
well you got to understand that
Vancouver and British Columbia are very
much a live andl lit Society the problem
is they don't get politicians that
reflect that that and uh and that's
typical because living live people don't
tend to go vote people who tend to vote
tend to be people with property vested
interests you know people from
Vancouver's West Side who have a lot of
wealthy property and they don't want
anything to change and they don't they
don't want to keep it white Caucasian
and you know that old Vancouver people
who want the new Vancouver are the
immigrants the new people here the
movers and shakers young people people
who don't conventionally see any purpose
to voting and to a large degree they're
correct there is no real purpose to
voting but the problem is we're
victimized by the electoral process in
the absence of that so that's a problem
well what do you see the the future here
in um Vancouver the city and the The
Province BC about democracy then if this
many people are flouting the law M and
you know and they won't change the law I
mean is that going to have any sort of
impact on Democracy here you think well
ultimately you know politicians are like
a flock of seagulls they follow the
leader and the leader is public opinion
and public opinion if it lingers long
enough in the One Direction will
eventually permeate Society completely
and all people will presume that that is
the proper way to think and so things
going to happen in a very gradul way
without any like momentous decisions on
behalf of parliament or some some Old
Judge who you know is not going to
deliver Liberty to us because you know
we think we're due judges are very
frightened old men really who've been
insulated behind a court bench for a lot
of their lives and don't really
understand the real world and aren't
used to shaking things up in any proper
controversial way especially Canadian
judges cing judges are particularly
conservative they like to think they've
got a heart of gold and sometimes they
do have a compassionate heart but
they're not they're not the kind of
people that are courageous enough to
change laws and you're not going to find
politicians I mean you have 3 million
pot smokers in the country about 15% of
the adult population perhaps even more I
mean you have clearly no one in favor of
prohibition in Canada any longer but
nonetheless you don't have a single
advocate for marijuana legalization in
Parliament I mean not one single guy has
taken on the issue of civil liberties
for marijuana smokers even though you'll
find people in Parliament having the
same interest in homosexuals of whom
there are far fewer in Canada and you'll
see the same people having the same
interest in First Nations or Chinese or
Asian people's rights and all of those
are legitimate but there's far fewer of
each one of those groups in Canada than
there are marijuana smokers and for some
reason we have been considered suitable
scapegoats like they have in America for
60 years and there's no explanation ever
offered like in Parliament they never
give an explanation so why we're keeping
prohibition nobody says yes we need to
criminalize a million Canadians and you
know arrest 100,000 every year and for
what purpose and you never get that
answer you never get part two of the
opening premise like okay if we're
having this police dat what's the
explanation well we don't have one you
know and so it goes like that and that's
most in incomprehensible well but isn't
it great what's going on up there Paul
in Vancouver British Columbia oh it's
just fascinating what's going on up
there and you know we can do better here
um by getting our petition and getting
signatures get on of ballot this
November and then come January 1 we
could have um cannabis cafes here in
Portland all over Oregon right and uh we
need your help to do that we've been
doing these shows for a year now if you
have called us previously and got our
petitions please send them right in if
you're not sure where to send them to or
you want more petitions call us right
away at 235
4606 in some cases we are actually
paying ition so if you'd like to help us
give us a call at 235 4606 if you have
access to the internet look at our web
page at
HTTP
colon
www.
crh.org you can actually print our
petitions online so uh uh we want you to
turn your petitions in though right go
correct turn them in so we can get a
count out there as soon as possible
because we know it is everybody kind of
hangs on to them sort of forgets about
them but you only have two or three
signatures on there send them in because
they all count you know we've sent
thousands of those out there we've just
got a tiny fraction of them in so we
urge you to send your petitions back in
we have to have them by the end of June
so if you have petitions send them back
and if you need more give us a call at
503 235
4606 if you're in the Portland area
that's 235 4606 six so I guess we should
get back to that Mark Emory interview
you know it's just fascinating yeah it
is it's good to know that early history
of how hemp BC started and how the whole
culture there started in community so I
think it's going to be great um watching
the rest of the interview and think
about how we here in Oregon can do the
same thing with all of our help so here
it is the Mark Emory hemp BC interview
thanks for
watching as long as we're moving towards
Freedom then you're moving in a positive
direction and certainly since the time
I've been in here things have moved on
the marijuana issue a very positive
direction I mean you know when you
consider that you couldn't buy a pipe in
this town you know and you couldn't buy
a book or magazine about marijuana and
you know I mean productivity has
probably tripled since I've you know
been here in the last four years and
we've been on every major media which
was Unthinkable before they would never
think about putting a marijuana seed
dealer on the front page of the Wall
Street Journal and you know CNN the mass
media the Ted Turner you know uh Time
Warner corporate establishment giving me
a great review on CNN or for that matter
Rolling Stone the old the old hippies
and the new capitalist and rolling stone
gave us an excellent review too we
always get good reviews there's a daily
paper you've got article from two days
ago another great full page article
they're always great reviews the media
is completely on side in a lot of issues
when they interview me it comes out fine
I always ask them whenever you do a grow
bust you know you always take these cops
press releases and say you know four
hydroponic operations or seed why don't
you ask them what their moral
justification for that is if resources
are short how can you justify chasing
down any marijuana growers when we know
it's harmless when everybody in British
Columbia approves of it when two-thirds
have clearly got on record saying they
don't think marijuana should be illegal
why do you waste anybody's time why do
you destroy people's lives why do you
violate their civil rights why do you
continue this police state for nothing
they never asked that question they
can't get up the nerve to ask the cops
that question but if every every
journalist asked the cop that question
every time there was a girl raid you'd
see them drop they just wouldn't want to
get gred anymore you know you wouldn't
and then people who are raided would
call the press to alert them and the
relationship would be reversed they'd
call them say I've just been violated
and these people would record their
point of view instead it's repeatedly
always the police point of view just
print the police um news bolt in verb
yeah now they're a little more inqu
inquisitive here because they know that
the most of the population is not
supportive of this marijuana War the
police are waging but you know the media
could do a lot more to accelerate the
liberation of several million people and
most of the reporters are on side it's
again the older editorial staff the
people who have more corporate interest
in mind would like to tread a fine line
between supporting the police as
everybody has to knee- yourk do so in a
corporate you know democracy like we
have here everybody has to say you know
the police May done something it's not
like we're against the police for
anything blah blah blah even though they
know they've been like ruining lives and
families in this unnecessary drug work
for their own self-interest you know for
the last two decades I mean sure
politicians Inspire them but cops can
tell them to [ __ ] off really we got
better things to do and no one would say
boo about marijuana but cops do it
because a lot of people thousands of
Canadians for example 2,000 cops are
employed every eight hour shift to just
chase down marijuana so if they made
marijuana illegal tomorrow you got 6,000
guys right there who are immediately
super and probably 10 or 20,000 other
cops I mean if you didn't have a drug
war at all you would need half the
police officers in North America that
you've got today oh yeah absolutely
fraction of the prisons yeah exactly I
mean exactly fraction of pris and you'd
have a great increase in society safety
see prohibition accomplishes the exact
opposite of every stated aim it raises
the price of Marijuana or drugs or all
drugs so that you and I the consumer
have to spend more of that on our
supplies as opposed to our children or
education or buying a new computer or a
home or investing in the economy or
starting our own business a lot of our
money goes to the herbs and and drugs we
seek it encourages police corruption
armed uh Crim gangs it destabilizes at
least 15 to 20 foreign governments in
the world right now whole countries are
in total D stabilization because of a US
drug war in South and Central America
you've got uh whole Aid programs geared
on whether they have a crop eradication
program going on in that particular
Community like India or Bangladesh
you've got um you know organized crime
profiting because it's illegal you've
got biker gangs you've got you've got
police corruption you've got people
being shot dead in their homes during
raid you've got every kind of civil
liberty disab from urine testing to kids
riding on you at school to parents
riding on their kids I mean it's a whole
terrible system we' fostered with this
drug war and not a good thing has come
of it it's destroyed everything that's
supposedly held dear in America Freedom
privacy Liberty money uh Law and Order
uh clean government prohibition ruins it
all well I mean I think the one that one
yeah one that we really lost in America
I don't know how how you guys are going
here but a right to you be free from
search and seizure in America I mean
when I was was a kid growing up that was
you know always held up to be one of our
greatest ones we don't have that here in
Canada really there's no privacy or you
know cops do what they want you know the
thing is they tend to be politer about
it's friendly fascism you know in a
sense but uh but then you know I should
talk so on one hand if I were in the
United States I'd be in jail for the
next 20 years so right you know so you
know I've got 17 counts including nine
trafficking and I'm still walking I
don't know how long that'll last but you
know I'm still out on the street even if
they barred me from my own businesses
and for forced me at gunpoint to sell
them the fact as all of it still
basically exists except I'm not allowed
to own it you've got to be flexible you
can't go on that block yeah you can't go
on that block well these are
revolutionary times and for a
revolutionary to still be allowed on the
street not shot dead maybe I should be
grateful yeah yeah so what kind of legal
charges are you facing well we've got uh
eight counts of trafficking from two
different uh times and most recently the
one that got me barred from my own store
is allegedly and this usually I get
charged by the way after I do a major
national interview of some kind or we
get raided or something like that and I
was on the Vicky gabo show live for 25
minutes
Nationwide and then the next the later
on the day I got served with I was put
in jail I tried for two counts of
trafficking marijuana and hashish and
apparently two months earlier some
Americans had come up to my Cafe a man
and his three daughters and I allegedly
got them high allegedly gave them a gift
of $5 worth of hash which would be about
that much I guess half a gram a quarter
of a gram and they went back to United
States and they got caught with it and
they said Mark emry gave it to us and
they were let go and but you don't
really recall this happened oh God no I
mean it could well just be a story they
say oh Mark oh yeah well I find it
fantastic that it's even you can use
that I mean that way what about the guy
who's caught with a big truck full of
pot he can just hey Marky told me to
deliver this billinton yeah or the mayor
Vancouver but anyway so they sent this
back to Vancouver and they sat on it for
six s weeks and then all of a sudden
right after did that interview they
chared to move two counts of trafficking
and there's no witness because they're
not coming back here to testify there's
no hash no cop ever saw and not and the
only person who took a statement is an
American Immigration officer so it's not
even within the legal jurisdiction of
Canada that anything is alleged to have
happened with any but the thing is they
charge me and we don't come to trial
till next December so for the whole year
so anyway they put me in jail so that's
what that's what led to you not being
able to visit yeah because they they put
me in jail and they said listen if you
don't agree to never go back to the 300
block you have to sign this agreement
undertaking and and the failure to obey
it is indefinite imprisonment right then
we're not letting you out we're going to
ask him to hold you in because you've
already got tons of trafficking charges
and you know and so I had to agree to it
or they would never let me out for
months and months so now if I'm uh go in
the block where my old shops are are
then I would go to jail indefinitely
until it comes up at TR in
December isn't that great what's going
on up there in Vancouver once again I'll
have to say it's fabulous I mean it's
just so interesting you know Mark Embry
is such a great person yeah he's
fascinating how he stood up for all of
our rights up there and pioneering
things uh with direct Civil Disobedience
yeah exactly I mean from what he started
off with just like selling banned books
and banned magazines to saying okay
we're going to sell you know smoking
utensils to a multi-million dollar
Enterprise with 43 employees he just
pulled himself up by his bootstraps uh
basically going door to-door selling
magazines and using that to open his
businesses yeah I mean that that's kind
of interesting you going from shop to
shop saying okay here you know you want
to take couple cop magazine that can get
you busted you know and it's just and it
was quite um impressive how we did it
like I say I mean the man he had a
vision and he followed it and he got
there um and I think you know we here
have a vision in Oregon right and that
is to completely legalize and regulate
adult sales of marijuana to allow people
to grow their own to license Farmers to
grow the crop commercially to allow
medical patients to access marijuana
through pharmacies with the doctor's
prescription and to allow Farmers
without a license to cultivate
Industrial Hemp to produce thousands of
different products and we can do that
here in Oregon with your help that's
right call us 503 235 235
4606 and uh give us a call today um and
you know help us put into a reality our
vision um you know Mark Emer like I say
had his vision up there in Vancouver for
all British Columbia and for eventually
all of Canada and he wants to have for
all North America I mean he's quoted in
a rolling stone interview um the one
that has a Buffy the Vampire Slayer on a
cover if folks want to go out and look
at it it um a great interview with Mark
in there and he's saying that you know
he wants to spread his vision elsewhere
and he doesn't mind who else copies it
right in fact he said that and it was
picked up in the Portland magazine the
wamit week that Portland is going to be
one of the next places to follow that
example so we want to go farther than
that we want to regulate the market and
just end prohibition here and now so
help us with the Oregon cannabis Tax Act
call us at 235 4606
if you have our petitions send them back
in now we'll send you out some more but
we have to have all of our signatures by
the end of June don't delay send them
back today or call us right now and
we'll send you the petitions in a week
so call us right
away yeah you know give us a call um you
know talk to us if you're feeling alone
out there that you know there's nobody
else out there like that that's going to
um like you that likes to see it
regulated likes to see patients being
able to um get this with with a doctor's
prescription for whatever the doctor
thinks it should be needed for um you
know call us and talk to folks who are
just like you who want to see this
regulated who want to see an end of
prohibition who want to see an end to
Crime who want to see an end to the war
on some drugs who want to see a
beginning of Freedom um to bring back
our liberties to bring back the the fun
that marijuana can can give you any kind
of recreational Pursuit and to stop this
incredible buildup of prisons and the
prison industrial complex in the United
States if you want to help restore
freedom in America help us with the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act by calling us at
23546 06 yeah definitely give us a call
and like I say I mean I just you know
it's to uh ban a plant is just so
ludicrous to me I mean something that
grows it shouldn't be banned I mean it's
just like who you know we think we're
more powerful than nature um that we're
more powerful than a plant you know it's
like a plant grows naturally I mean it's
just like it's a downfall of our society
when we try to ban things that are
natural so call us at 235
4606 and in closing I would like to tell
you that I am a candidate in the
Democratic primary that's coming up on
May 19th I'm running for state
representative there are six different
candidates in the for house district 14
that's inner Southeast and Northeast
Portland so if you live between Holgate
and the Banfield freeway from Southeast
50th down vote for me in the May 19th
Democratic primary here in inner
Southeast in northeast Portland that's D
Paul Stanford for State Rep thanks for
watching call us get our petition call
us at 235
night
e for