hello and welcome to another exciting
edition of Cannabis Common Sense this is
our 50th show so it's a real Milestone
isn't it Paul yeah it's uh definitely a
milestone and I'd like to thank
everybody that's volunteered
um down here to help us put the show on
yeah we'd like to thank Lanny for making
his club uh the rage in downtown
Portland available to us and Gregory and
everyone involved so thanks a lot my
name is Paul Stanford and I'm one of the
chief petitioners along with our
associate Paul Loney here on the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act and that is a petition
put out by the campaign for the
restoration and regulation of hemp
exactly the our political action
committee says it all the campaign for
the restoration and regulation of hemp
it's a comprehensive initiative which
would regulate marijuana it would allow
sales to adults through state liquor
stores it would allow patie to access
medical marijuana at pharmacies at cost
with a prescription from a doctor it
would allow our Farmers to grow
industrial hemp which is the low THC
variety
and it would provide for some education
on and real drug education programs
exactly it would create thousands of
jobs in industrial hemp and it would
also bring in hundreds of millions of
dollars in state revenue you know we're
circulating it as a petition right now
and we need your help we are at about 24
000 signatures as we're taping in early
April we need 73 000 good valid
signatures by the end of June we've sent
out thousands of these to our viewers if
you have our petition already we urge
you to mail it back to us if you don't
have it yet let us mail it to you right
away call us at
503-235-4606 yeah get to get the
petitions back to us today if you only
have one or two or three signatures on
it make sure your signature and at least
your best friend's signature on that and
get them back to us or call us up and
get more signatures and today in today's
show we're going to go back up to
Vancouver BC the marijuana bread basket
of the Pacific Northwest as is now known
and continue view our interviews up
there in Vancouver yes we're
interviewing the second half of our
interview with Mark Emery Mark Emery is
a long time activist who's been
practicing Civil Disobedience he founded
a multi-million dollar business hemp BC
and the Cannabis Cafe there's also a
hemp BC legal assistance center and a
wholesale business and a magazine called
cannabis Canada that's just spectacular
isn't it oh it's a fabulous magazine I
think it's the most comprehensive
Magazine on cannabis in the entire world
right now I think so as well and it's
and it's professional oh and it's done
very nicely very nice layout very nice
Graphics photographers are all great the
people we met up there were all great
and generally they have something that I
personally really like they always have
some hemp paper in there some of it's
printed on the fibers paper made from
the fibers of the marijuana plant so
yeah they're you know putting their
money where their mouth is or and so I
think it's time to get to the interview
get into the interview last the last
plug call us at 235-4606 to get this
petition and uh we'll hit Mark Emery's
interview he starts out talking about
some of uh his legal problems since he's
come out in the media with the Wall
Street Journal and CNN so it starts out
with that and goes into politics
then I would go to jail indefinitely
until it comes up a patrol in December
okay
so uh so they've got ways of making a
breaking you know if they want to break
you they can break you you know and they
rated me twice and they certainly racked
up a pile of debts and cause my assets I
mean I could I that restaurant cost me
40 million dollars alone it's probably
one of the most famous restaurants in
North America but I sold it for about
fifty thousand bucks over five years
because nobody will buy a restaurant
that doesn't have a business license
it's under constant police supervision
for no particular reason mind you
um and you know that's you can't
liquidate a commodity like that but on
the other hand I was given like about 10
days to sell so it's like classic Jewish
pogrom in Russia you know you're getting
three days to get out of town you can
sell all your stuff and for whatever you
can get which will be like one you know
tenth of its value and you have to
liquidate and you're just gone and if
you don't liquidate they just come back
in season anyway like they've already
done they didn't need any any special
permission to raid me twice and they
don't need and they clearly told me we
don't need it to do it again so get out
the hand no they came back and said
listen we're not even going to wait till
you go to court to contest the license
suspension we'll just come and take all
your stuff and so well see if you sell
the business and a new license
application they have to be given up to
a year to two years to be tested because
if they don't break the law or they
don't appear to be advocating breaking
law like I do
um then they can't be denied a business
license you are protected in some ways
but as a guy who's gone on every major
media and said I break the law every day
seven different ways to Sunday that's it
I've already you know cashed in my
ability to go to before a judge and say
I'm a good citizen I have a laws I don't
know weight loss it's real clear that I
don't obey them I've got 16 counts
against me of various things and some of
them are really outrageous all of them
are outrageous they're all related to
this marijuana issue and they're all
idiotic I've never solved marijuana
never even been accused of selling
marijuana some of them relate to seeds
two of them relate to giving somebody a
gift to five dollars worth of hash these
are all life sentence uh
convictions yeah that's interesting and
I've been taken to jail twice for just
giving out brochures on government
property legalizing marijuana they
handcuffed me and jailed me twice for
that I'm charged with assaulting a
police officer but what it is I spit on
him when they waited this last time they
started beating up my employees and I
was there watching it happen right in
front of me they told me to back up and
I spit in the cop's face and they
stopped beating on them and beat on me
and threw me in jail overnight so you
know that's how I got that but that was
the intention of spitting on the cop
anyway right and it was just you know so
uh you know and to me that's a pretty
reasonable form of contempt you know a
spit on a cop in one of my you know
where they're beating uh yeah you know
your boys I mean also what am I supposed
to do in front of my employees anyway I
mean was to stand there and let the cop
do it I mean so anyway I chose the most
suitable line of resistance that was the
least resistance
and uh are there others there must be
like oh yes I've got one charger
promoting paraphernalia I've got one
charge of selling paraphernalia and you
know so they've kind of got it all
covered you know way nine trafficking
two paraphernalia uh one literature two
you know so
um the other assaulting the cop the
usual you know
so including literature he said they got
you for yeah no they're not promoting
literature giving out brochures because
I'm not I had to get permission and my
understanding was you don't need to get
permission to give up brochures on
government property related to a
national issue I had a petition to
Parliament and so they they busted you
for that yeah I refused to move so they
just said well we're just gonna have a
handicap you take away so we'll handcuff
me and take me away and that's what they
did right we were at City Hall or no no
is that the West End Community Center
which is where I live uh just right
beside the library oh okay yeah so you
know democracy is not necessarily alive
and well and not that it wasn't it's any
good if it is but I mean it's a very
peculiar
Place Canada well it's interesting right
now that to to us you know down the
state especially in the Pacific
Northwest part of the United States
Vancouver is sort of like a shining
Beacon well it is
yeah that's right because basically it's
a police state unless you fight back and
then all of a sudden you might find that
they give in and they relent and so you
know basically everything we do do is
illegal and they didn't bother us they
never bothered us until American
government pressure was put on our
police they probably never bothered me
because I'm a good guy you check all my
interviews you check the CNN show they
say nice things about me you check the
article that's in Rolling Stone cops say
nice things about me they always say
nice things about it because there's
nothing bad to say about me I'm a
totally upfront honest guy I pay all the
money that everybody's entitled to I
give tens to all the governments my
always great to my employees I improve
that neighborhood vastly I've you know
contributed probably to two million two
billion dollars in economic growth in
British Columbia because marijuana has
really gone through the roof has become
easily the major crop in this province
and you know why because they got a
great promoter they got a great
spokesman in me and where you know when
you think of great pot everything's BC
I'm sure there's a lot of bogus pot
Trading
you put say that about a pot people are
going to be interested in it you know
and a lot of what's in Portland is from
BC though and same with Washington and
certainly California in a bit of
Colorado Idaho and that sort of thing
but uh and it made me a low figure to
say it's four billion dollars in
production every year out of British
Columbia loan but you know I certainly I
take a lot of credit for that because we
have made British Columbia famous and
it's all good so it's easy to promote
but at the same time you know there was
nobody before I existed like nothing
absolutely there was no infrastructure
there weren't 40 50 hemp stores you see
now or hemp symposiums being held down
the street you know at the Pan Pacific
Center there's none of that going on
before we came by and now there's
hundreds of hamsters and a couple
magazines and lots of you know just lots
of activity in Canada there's tons of
activity
and we subsidize everything in the time
in the period when I could you know we
gave easily last year a hundred thousand
dollars and money and free legal help to
everybody to everybody everybody so you
know but the police knew that that's why
they attacked us because they wanted to
damage us financially because that money
was subsidizing the whole war against
the drug war right
so we sold three and a half million
dollars and I recirculated all of it but
the 80 000 I keep so that's a lot of
money to turn back into you know our our
information campaign really and we got a
lot of interviews I mean we've been in
everything my three proudest ones are
the worldwide CNN broadcast which has
been aired three times now and uh that's
the impact the impact show yeah which
was fabulous that's on our website too
yeah and the uh the Wall Street Journal
front page on December 5th 1995 I'm
really proud of that one that was great
they had five editors go through every
aspect of my life you could do because
they weren't going to be oh they said
they were not going to put a drug dealer
with any negative connections on the
front page if there's anything that came
up like any single thing and they
couldn't find anybody to say anything
about it maybe if I'm not from a cop to
my old teachers to any employees to
anybody could not find a negative
comment we couldn't go we went to my
neighbors couldn't find anybody there
and so they put me on the front page and
the only thing on the front page I
didn't like face there that's a
beautiful article
um and the Rolling Stone article which
is really nice because it goes to a
different Market they're all different
markets you know CNN Wall Street Journal
rolling and you know so now that I've
been sort of kicked out and forced into
some degree of retirement I feel at
least we've accomplished a lot in that
period like we certainly set the ball
for a lot of people to do stuff so what
are you um what businesses do you still
have now oh we have cannabis Canada
where we're filming right now and we
still do mail order cannabis candidates
and we still sell bongs and pipes and
magazines and books and seats by mail
okay and uh but you know the retail
outlets were the real cash cows you know
we sold we used to sell
five six thousand dollars worth of seeds
a day there and four thousand dollars in
the NPC store and the caffeine ever does
too much like a thousand dollars a day
there but you know that's now that's
they've got to pay for their people
because those those places now still
having about 22 employees so you know
their money gets turned back into the
suppliers and the employees is basically
the same thing it's the one we protected
as many jobs as we can we still have
about 31 people in the NPC family
whereas we had 43 on at the end of
January we had to let go anybody who
really couldn't
couldn't be justified financially
anymore and the legal services aren't
free anymore now so because we lost all
our you know most of our sources of
revenue so you know all the freebies
I've been and we we sponsored cannabis
Nation radio out which is a weekly radio
show for our Coastal College Canada we
paid for that entirely paid for
everybody's Legal Services at the law
office and whenever people never charge
for that that was easy a hundred
thousand dollars a year for that one you
know we subsidized tons of stuff most
hamsters and Canada receive money from
us
Etc et cetera which we can't do anymore
yeah and the police you know that was
the intent of this whole thing sounds
like is you know like they're saying
like why are you letting this guy you
know he uses his money very efficient is
what they're admitting he's real good
Whack Him you know get him out I mean
also we've been there all the world
leaders were here we bought full page
ads and all the daily papers those are
great ads have you ever seen them uh I
there's one in the cafe actually on the
table take a look at that full page ad
there yeah I heard about it okay can you
describe it I was doing it yeah
nobody was here and now that this issue
of the newspaper that we bought an ad in
was really a corporate suck up section
it was all about Apex so that Apec
leaders could read about themselves and
everybody at Apec and then all the ads
were like BC tell FedEx you know full
page corporate advertising and no one
expected us to take advantage of we got
it in the mail automatically as a
routine thing and we said we'll buy full
page ads in all in all the daily papers
that day and so we had to when the big
headlines it was time to end the war on
marijuana and then it's got the Cannabis
culture of Canada welcomes Apec leaders
and delegates to the world the North
America's marijuana Bread Basket British
Columbia and a headline and I'm just
thinking there must have been a half you
know a lot of big Canadian guys who just
really had a heart attack when they were
like because you know the guys from
Malaysia and Singapore are going we kill
people like right yeah and they said
come and have a smoke with us four
blocks away because it was only four
blocks away from the Pan Pacific so I
invited all the leaders to come down and
have a 10 talk with me and check it out
and discuss why they still think
marijuana should be illegal if they're
so concerned and and basically we also
cited the human rights record of each
country would go that you know marijuana
Traders are executed in China Singapore
Malaysia in the United States 640 000
people are put in jail blah blah blah
George Washington Thomas Jefferson's you
know sowed him and Bill Clinton wants to
put everybody in jail that does so today
and you know and we made fun of the fact
that America still calls itself a
pluralistic democracy in the land of the
free while locking up everybody in sight
who doesn't agree with you know the
president's point of view on marijuana
and uh basically tried to shame and
embarrass them and pointed that we're
decent people we're your leaders were
your children were your teachers were
your uncles we're the kid next door or
the people who sell you stuff or the
people who work with you et cetera et
cetera and that it was idiotic Advocate
any kind of policy that put us in jail
as well as which it was good medicine we
listed off it was good medicine it's
great for fiber you know and it's a
wonderfully articulate beautiful thing
in the bottom it's got a hemp BC
Canada's Cafe in the little grow shop
and then invite everybody to come down
and check us out four blocks away
yeah
that's a lot considering they'd have to
have the nerve to come in and I think
four of them were Canadian one was
American one was Mexican and uh two were
from Asia
okay
hi hi I just want to remind everybody
that this interview has been brought to
you by the campaign for the restoration
and regulation of hemp our political
action committee which is the sponsors
of the Oregon campus Tax Act the
petition over here and so please help us
out make the vision of Vancouver BC
become the reality down here in Oregon
by give us a phone call
503-235-4606 that's
503-235-4606 and Paul remind us what the
initiative does it will tax and regulate
the sale of marijuana to adults it'll
allow adults to cultivate marijuana for
personal use and allow Farmers to
cultivate the drug for sales through
liquor stores it'll allow medical
patients to receive prescriptions
through pharmacies at Cost well tax
adult marijuana sales and it will allow
Farmers to cultivate Industrial Hemp to
produce thousands of products everything
from the diesel in our trucks to the pay
paper on our books and the fabric on our
back yeah and one of the things that I'm
excited about with our initiative on the
medical aspect of it that allows the
doctor and patients to decide what to
use marijuana for what to use cannabis
for some of the other initiatives going
around the country there's like a set
list of what a doctor can say it's good
for and if you know if not on the list
well you're out of luck but not ours
it's between a doctor and a patient the
way it should be
in Pure Freedom
no prohibitions no regulations on
doctors or on patients so give us a call
and help us out send back petitions if
you've already got them so we need them
now time's going short or call us if you
haven't petition yet or if you lost
yours that's
235-4606 and help us make it legal here
and maybe we can Mark invite Mark Emery
down here once it's legal and he can the
greatest marijuana smoker in North
America he's called or the world this
day I guess that's what some of the
media is calling him yeah the world's
greatest marijuana smoker well you know
we can we can have them down here
um once we change those laws because he
doesn't want to come down here while
there's a lot more freedom up there
there's no sense in him coming down here
and facing the wrath of uh the federal
fascist state so call us and get these
petitions at
235-4606 and now I guess we're back to
uh the conclusion of the mark Emery
interview back with the politics part
and so that was pretty good yeah we got
a lot but what was really important and
this was really hurt us later I know the
ads got
re-reported all of the world New York
Times picked it up a lot of American
Press picked up European television film
to the Cannabis Cafe Reuters came in and
we got calls from France and Germany
said they'd seen us there interviewed
and then we got very syndicated
magazines and so it kept going outward
like that daily newspapers would comment
because the thing is the great thing is
the newspaper was delivered during a
boring news day as well so there was
endless people commenting on this
incredibly cool ad and they would read
it aloud and stuff like that and so you
know it it it it it got everything I
wanted to get out of it but the problem
is I knew there would be a consequence
yeah maybe a repercussion I remember
when CNN was here and they just wrapped
up and the last question they said so do
you think there'll be any negative
repercussions to you being on this show
and I looked at the guy real up close
and I said well don't you I mean of
course I do I said it's probably the end
I said but it's a good way to go yeah so
well you're still doing cannabis Canada
and oh yeah it's stable too it's not in
any danger or anything like that it was
three weeks ago when after we were
forced out of our retail business our
printer demanded all the money for the
last issue and a half of this month's
right up front now you know okay and we
found it for him so that's so at least
we're really caught up we've never been
as well you know as well caught up in
cannabis Canada as we are right now so
it's stable here but you know there's
you know I'm not involved in really
anything else at the moment other than I
give a lot of interviews and you know
I'm still you know when you won an
interview about pot and you want it to
be favorable you're going to call me up
because you just have to quote me and
most journalists are in favor of
marijuana legalization so by calling me
you know you're going to get what you
want because they've been suitably
propagandized now so they know what to
promote too so most journalists are
getting good at it they know what they
want so they call me up because they
know they're going to get great quotes
you know and I convince people I
literally convince people like I mean
the climate has gone from 39 of Canada
one in legalization only three years ago
four years ago and now 51 percent of the
country runs legalization and in British
Columbia went way off the scale 63
percent you know so that means you've
got 33 that either said they were
against marijuana or didn't have an
opinion or anything well where you got
63 are willing to say yes conclusive but
I want marijuana legalize so you have a
much more hardcore pro-marijuana segment
of our society than you have anybody who
cares about making it illegal in other
words the people who are against it are
ambivalent at best they don't care
really that doesn't concern them you
know maybe there's teenage son took
smoke marijuana they didn't like how he
turned out so since then they're against
marijuana that tends to be the commonest
kind of reason to be against any kind of
drug that I've ever heard is not because
in and of itself prohibition works it's
just that I didn't like my kid doing it
so I don't want him to ever see it again
blah blah or whatever and therefore it
should be illegal these are always
irrational nonsensical people and when
you look at the people in favor of
prohibition they're always total idiots
it's like when people look at white
supremacists why are you worried about
white supremacists I said they're all
mongoloids they look at these people
they're not the master races are people
that couldn't get accepted in the lowest
Social Club you know they've shamed
heads you know a little off to the side
like a little you know Egghead type
things you know wearing bizarre things
out in Montana that's the best [ __ ]
place for those people let's isolate
them let's send them to Montana I don't
hope they never show up for the rest of
us right that's what you want to do with
those people right so I mean most most
times people get worked up over nothing
and they ignore all the real problems in
life that's what I found
so do you have any uh what's your vision
of the future of the magazine and yeah
well we're going to put out more
magazines we have a pot puzzle book
coming out that's lots of fun and
cannabis Canada will issue like Avalon
Sunsplash the holding company which I'm
the president
um we'll put out more magazines of
different subject matters we just go we
have to like diversify we're still going
to handle the mail order here and
that'll expand in this department and uh
but we'll just go a little slower I mean
after all the other things are well in
place and other people can look after
those and I've also got to pay a hundred
thousand dollars in debts because I pass
on the businesses in a debt-free
environment no money down debt free that
way you know I know you'll be successful
but I got stuck with debt so I have to
pay down about a hundred thousand
dollars to suppliers so you know they'll
get it in the next two months you know
and so then we'll consider new projects
at that point in time but right now I'm
in businessman mode paying off the old
debts okay you know and oh well when I
say business memory I still give like
five to ten interviews a day of that
kind so like like on Saturday we're on
the front page of the London Free Press
the cafe was on the front page of the
Toronto Star on the same day last last
Thursday that was a full page article on
me in the daily paper this Sunday I've
got another article coming up later on
this week in the Vancouver Sun this
Magazine's writing an article on me I
mean it's the Saturday night magazine I
got radio shows you know blah blah blah
there's tons of them right so like great
the great thing about being a CNN
Rolling Stone and the Wall Street
Journal is hey you can't those are the a
list that's it that's true AAA list when
you've been acknowledged by those in the
60 Minutes calls ABC News oh I got an
ABC News special coming out in April one
hour special called victims of
victimless crime oh really and yeah and
that'll probably get more trouble
because what I do is I go to a grow
operation here where the guy's got a
thousand plants in this house and then
they asked me to describe what's going
on then they say what would a guy get if
you were caught in very spicy United
States I said well starting with
Oklahoma you'd get 50 to 100 years
minimum in Florida Texas Arkansas uh and
and then listed off about seven or eight
others you'd get 25 years and I said
about 20 other states you get 10 years
and every other state in the America I
said because a thousand plants is
definitely Federal I said you're going
to get minimum mandatory we were five
years absolutely without question likely
10 to 15 I said this guy would get two
thousand dollar fine if that since he's
an invalid uh B get less maybe
and she's disabled so you know they
probably would say who cares you know
like I mean basically the judge say who
cares anyway unless you're there for the
tenth time like I'm going to be before
some judges with quite a rap sheet so it
looks it's worse for me because they're
you know they piled the charges on to
make it look bad so they you know they
can start and the police have to from
their perspective of fighting a war you
know it's like you know the enemy
General's right over there we could kill
him but that would cause more trouble
than it's worth so we have to hassle him
and you know a number of things to keep
me to marginalize or disable my
Effectiveness and if you have to go into
court all the time and show oh well no
it soaks up all my money I'll never have
any spare money to buy full page ads I
won't be able to start any businesses
and they know that right so it's their
way of waging more but you know there's
a there's a a couple of lines I often
use I said you know it's good to be
underestimated for one they never knew
how good I really was at this until it
was too late that's what I liked about
that you know they think well how much
trouble could he be he's got one of him
so four years later oh [ __ ]
why didn't we just beat him up and throw
him in an alley when we had the chance
you know and uh so now they're stuck
with me and they've got to play ball
because I'm actually one of the most
well-known people from British Columbia
we've attracted tons of money that
nobody really wants to turn away and I'm
really good at what I say I mean I'm I'm
the kind of person you everybody could
be proud of you I'm BC he's proud of me
because I make BC sound good I make PC
sound tolerant pod smokers are proud of
me because I look so dignified and and I
don't look like a typical hippie I'm an
employed person with children like
concerns like every other middle class
person and you know the cops like me
because I you know I'm polite not a
problem you know type of thing only if
they're beating up your employees no
even then you beat up your employees and
for me and all I do is spit on you you
could be thankful you know I mean if I
was an American maybe I'd have a gun or
something you know I mean pod smokers in
Canada or surprisingly docile passive
people they're peace lovers I mean
they're not prone to fighting so it's
not surprising that we're one-way
victims in this drug war but the fact is
you know we're winning while being
abused and and and hurt and and so you
know there's truth sooner or later
people realize the Injustice situation
but they're very slow to act and they're
very cowardly and people value money and
comfort above freedom and of course
ironically they'll lose that too if they
don't pay attention to freedom but the
thing is it takes a long time you know
in four years we've just made dramatic
rapid progress you know to me it's not
fast enough but it's been pretty good
you know I mean we have without
government subsidy it made marijuana at
a bridge probably the best in the world
we it's the cheapest in North America
it's the highest quality we've increased
production by about three or four times
in the last four years
and uh you know it's perfect it's a
perfect economy you know you start off
with [ __ ] some seeds some water and
the natural Sun basically a very small
investment and three months later some
Americans giving you a big wad of money
he goes and takes this marijuana and
he burns it which is incredible he burns
and he has to come back for more at
least when people buy a car that car is
going to last five years anyway that pot
doesn't last two weeks it's gone it's
burned it's been destroyed and they've
got to come back for more now that is a
perfect economy from water [ __ ] and
a bit of time you come up with a
multi-billion dollar industry where
everybody's happy
you know and so the the fact that as
taxpayer
all right once again this interview has
been brought to you by the campaign for
the restoration restoration regulation
of hemp
um the sponsors of our initiative Drive
the Oregon cannabis tax act so we can
have it here in Oregon that same
turnaround as Mark said two weeks they
burn it up right we can create that
industry here and we're trying to do
that with our petition the Oregon
cannabis tax act so if you have our
petitions if you're one of the people
who's already called us and had to send
them to you send those back in right
away we need uh all of our petitions in
no later than the end of June and uh if
you need more if you send them in we'll
mail you back some more right away if
you haven't got them call us at
235-4606 that's
235-4606 if you're outside of the
Portland area
503-235-4606 only registered Oregon
voters can sign and circulate this
petition but we need 73 000 signatures
by the end of June to put this thing on
the ballot and here in early April what
are we at about twenty four thousand
yeah somewhere around there in early
April and if you have any questions
about the initiative give us a call
we'll be happy to tell you how to make
sure to fill it out correctly make sure
you know just one County
um solely on one page and make sure you
get that right only Lane County people
can sign Lane County Paige kind of can't
mix Lane County and Douglas County
and we mail them out we kind of mail out
an instruction sheet as well but if that
doesn't make sense give us a call you
get a live person usually Bruce Bruce
can walk you through it pretty well so
give us a call and help us out we really
need you know you to help us out to
bring freedom back to Oregon to bring
back that whole economy that Mark was
talking about where it's just a
wonderful thing that you know people can
buy it and then two weeks later they
have to go buy more because they're
they've smoked it up let's let our
farmers do that exactly we need to give
keep this wealth here let's not export
it out so help us put the Oregon
cannabis tax act on the ballot to tax
and regulate adult marijuana sales
legalize Industrial Hemp legalize
personal possession and cultivation and
regulate medical marijuana call us at
503-235-4606 exactly and give us a call
it's not just regulate marijuana medical
marijuana it frees medical marijuana
it's the choice between a doctor and a
patient in closing I am a candidate for
Oregon state representative in the
Oregon House of Representatives in house
district 14. if you live in inner
Southeast Portland and the little far
northeast corner of inner northeast
Portland please vote for me for state
representative on the May Democratic
primary if you're a registered Democrat
or you're not registered with a party
you're an independent you can vote in
the Democratic primary that's D Paul
Stanford for house district 14.
get our petition to stop the drug war