this is a song this next song I've had
the privilege of playing this in front
of millions of people now uh some folks
have called it the hemp national anthem
I call it let's all be farmers and uh
this is why I'm here this is why we were
all here this is why Jack gave his life
for everything that he's done so um
anyway I love love you jack hope you're
up there playing with Captain Ned and
having a great time sitting in your 63
VW bus and smoking a
fatty well let's all all be
farmers get filthy
rich instead we're wrecking the planet
oh and it's beginning to [ __ ] on that's
all the
[Music]
farmers and save the
trees I can grow my own oil thank you
and without the pain these are let all
be
Farmers the pain must
stop this is the new the old the
original all billion dollar coron all
farmers and save the
[Music]
Seas I can grow my own oil thank you
without the pain clean let's all be
[Music]
Farmers index on
rain oh I can grow my oil oh without the
pain it's all be
Farmers oh now that you
know well who am I to tell you
oh you should go let all the
[Music]
Farmers let's all be
Farmers all it do
watch that last tree
fall
Will
D oh I could have had a all it's all be
farmers
[Music]
let's all be
fun let's all be
fun let all be
[Music]
fun
oh all be
[Music]
let all
be let's all
be f
[Music]