you
alcohol Awareness Month is an opportune
time to be talking about the relative
harms of alcohol and marijuana this
billboard isn't simply saying go ahead
and choose one or the other it's saying
don't just drink think about the
circumstances think about what you're
consuming if you're enjoying a glass of
beer if you're enjoying a glass of wine
a great Oregon IPA if you're enjoying a
great Oregon Pinot Noir you think about
how adults who choose to use marijuana
for many of the same reasons to relax to
socialize with friends to enjoy
themselves to be responsible but to
consume responsibly in that manner think
about what message we're sending to
those adults and what message we're
sending to future generations when we
tell people we're going to punish them
for making a choice that is safer than
alcohol and we are going to encourage
them to consume a substance that's more
dangerous if you are in a situation
where you can choose to consume alcohol
or you can choose to consume marijuana
society will tell you it's better that
you choose alcohol even if it's bad for
you even if it makes you violent even if
you're breaking the law in some cases
underage drinking so we as a society
have been encouraging people to consume
alcohol and what we are saying in Oregon
is we're not we're not jeopardizing and
we're not threatening the stability of
Oregon's beer and wine industry there
are combined three billion dollar a year
industry they're going to be fine what
we're saying is for adults who choose to
consume marijuana because it's safer for
them because they prefer marijuana over
alcohol they shouldn't be criminalized
they shouldn't be ostracized they
shouldn't be stigmatized we should be
treating them with respect and we should
be letting them make that safer choice
what we're saying is we have established
a way to regulate alcohol in this
industry in this in this economy and we
celebrate alcohol as a society we're
going to do that knowing the harms that
alcohol presents let's at least not
punish people who want to make a safer
choice
are you worried that the billboard might
discourage people from going over to
your festival and drinking some beer
wine not in the least i'm looking
forward to those people coming over and
we're looking forward to this moving
forward and hopefully it will get
legalized at some point it brings in a
lot of tourist dollars and we are a
tourist industry when we put on this
vessel we get people from all around the
world we'd like to see more people show
up and enjoy our fine products and this
is going to be one of them all the
batter do you think marijuana is safer
than beer and wine it is safer than beer
and wine why are you so certain well
I've been using for 44 years so I have
at least a little bit background on it
and I feel it's extremely safe for
people and it's actually it's not just
say it's medicine how do you have a
medical miracle i do have been in
america and i wish this would progress
sooner i'm glad that or Washington and
Colorado have taken the lead on this
Oregon should be right there with it and
if we could move it along quicker next
year Easter is on 4 20 well there you go
what about moms and dads who are
watching who might have teenagers at
home who are impressionable and think
this sends the wrong message to them
that is a discussion they will have to
have with their kids
you