maybe we can close in just a little bit
more on that you can see there are
300 marijuana cigarettes in this this is
from the federal
government uh from the Research Triangle
Institute it was processed it was grown
in Mississippi in Oxford Mississippi at
the naida uh medical marijuana research
facility and then processed in North
Carolina into cigarettes and they send
these out 300 cigarettes is supposed to
be a month supply and this is one of the
tens that they would send the cigarettes
out in it's uh got Nifty little layers
of Styrofoam and stuff inside here that
the cigarettes you can see the residue
is still there from the how did they
send that cigarettes that they send it
via the mail I thought it was against a
lot now here is something from Park
Davis it says right down here at the
bottom it's a cannabis medicine it's uh
for neuralgia from Park Davis going and
that's that's nerve pain folks nerve
pain going next to it we get into a
whole line of four different Eli Lily
products here we have uh fluid extract
number what is that
96 cannabis yeah Number 96 and then
right next to it we have uh tincture
number 17 of cannabis from Eli Lily uh
it says on the front that they're
poisoned but on the back it says
formerly thought to be poisonous but not
considered so now down here next to it
is the powdered extract of cannabis from
Eli Lily now all of these bottles are at
least 80 years old and in some cases
they're up to 120 years old right next
to it this one's exactly a 100 years old
and this is a uh flu another extract
from Eli Lily of cannabis indicia before
they gave them the numbers here now next
to it is an unopened bottle of kol for
colds and cough and it's it's got the
label on it is in about 13 different
Lang languages this is from
1892 and it's German and French and
Italian and Spanish in addition to
English right next to it is lynon's
cough bossam it also has a
multi- lingual label with the
instructions in in Finnish and Dutch and
other this one's still here we can
actually take it out and see that it is
full here it is lynon's cough bossom
with real cannabis included now next to
it we have another mentholated cough
bosom now you can turn this and you can
actually see it has that green look of
cannabis and uh what is it it's h
mentholated cough bossom from Clay Shaw
Clay Shaw where is that that's in uh
West Virginia of West Virginia cannabis
cough
bosom next to it we have hexat Tetra
hexat Tetra with powdered Cannabis
sativa it says right there in the middle
of the the label you can see hexat
Tetra that's kind of nifty and then f
one of the last we have uh from Great
Britain actually from Liverpool a
cannabis tincture bottle tincture of
cannabis from a pharmacist in Liverpool
England and then here we have Ecto plast
corn rings from Cannabis and I have a
collection of about 150 different
cannabis medicines and about 35 of them
are different corn removers and what
they do for corns and warts is they'd
apply this to the top of the Corn and
wart and they'd leave it there for about
three or four days and then they'd
remove it and then the corn or wart
would just scrape away with your
fingernail