we're going to do a little showand tell
now as we often do little sharing as
they call it these days I brought this
on last week but I was just liked it so
much I thought I'd bring it back how
close can you come in here soia this is
Johnson and Johnson Little Closer Closer
still oh that's getting better see
Johnson and Johnson cannabis indicia and
solstic acid aspirin and cannabis this
is a big tarp it was used for psoriasis
or warts or corns it was just a very
valuable aid for a wide assortment of
skin diseases and Johnson and Johnson's
The Trusted name that we let our I think
my kids still use Johnson baby shampoo I
know we used the baby oil in earlier
years right next door to it this is from
England and from boots Pharmacy boots
pharmacies are are big in England and
these are corn strap Rings it's cannabis
and a aspirin again it says apply this
to your corns and leave it on there
overnight then put a little warm water
on and your corn will come right off so
that's a Nifty thing next door Dr
Bronner pure Castile hemp peppermint
soap this is really good stuff this is a
refill bottle I use this at home and I'm
about halfway down I refill my my
smaller bottles with this big jumbo
bottle next door we have hemp held hemp
nuts these taste like cashews or and
walnuts kind of a very rich nutty uh
nutritious uh food that's high in the
essential fatty acids omega-3 6 and N
next to it we have hemp flour this is
hemp seed that's had the oil pressed out
and left over is a high protein hemp
flour to make hemp burgers or hemp
protein shakes right next to it now I
take about seven of these or eight of
them every day this is cold pressed hemp
SE and oil now here it is next door in a
big bottle I I just can't eat it raw I
like it better in the capsules myself so
I I take it in the capsules but you can
use it in salads you can use it in all
kinds of different things anytime you're
using olive oil or anything else then
last but not least distributed right
here in Portland by Living Harvest we
have Living Harvest chocolate hip milk
they comes in vanilla and unflavored so
you can get hip milk it's lot more
nutritious than than soy milk and that's
the end of our showand tell for this
evening