first of all we have a box of Frosted
Flakes with Michael Phelps the world's
fastest swimmer uh who uh says on the
back Michael rules with eight for eight
and obviously marijuana didn't slow him
down I understand that he came out and
won another meet here a couple weeks ago
and didn't test positive for marijuana
and the urine test associated with there
so he must know that he has to wait a
month or so after he smoked before hear
obviously didn't slow him down and he
seems to be seems like he grew gills he
does now right next to it we have a a
cannabis extract this is from Eli Lily
another drug company that's still in
existence today it's a extract Number 96
Eli Lily had about 15 different cannabis
preparations and this is just one right
next door we have upjn cannabis extract
a cannabis tincture both of these were
liquid extracts of cannabis now this one
is from from Merill drug company which
is merged with another company this is a
powdered extract of cannabis this was
powdered hash or Keef and this bottle
held an ounce 1 oce it says here on the
back 1 oce of powdered extract of
cannabis indicia nice this one's really
old it's a Circa 1870 the uh it's got
what they call label underglass or lug
lug stands for label under glass they
used to put the label on then put the
glass on top and so uh this is a can of
AB extract Circa
1870 right next door we have a rare
combination of an unopened cannabis uh
container from specific medicines and an
empty bottle so we know there inside
this there is a full bottle and it's a
Lloyd Brothers uh extract of cannabis uh
it's pretty nifty having a a completely
unopened and still sealed one here then
right next door we have a larger dug
bottle these are dug out of the ground
and this one has it embossed right on
the surface of the glass it's Dr H James
cannabis indicia uh extract uh from
Philadelphia Pennsylvania and it's
embossed right on the surface of the
glass says right here on this uh second
line cannabis indicia cannabis indicia
those of you which HDTV you get the
benefit tonight and right next door uh
Lyon's Balsam we have a couple of
different Balsam medicines for coughs
and colds this one has many languages on
the back everything from Norwegian and
Finnish to Spanish and Portuguese and
Hungarian uh the insert comes with 11
different uh things and there's a full
unopened bottle of this cough medicine
right next to it is Dr bliss's Bliss
native balsom for coughs and colds uh
contains one half of a gram of cannabis
indicia to each ounce uh along on with
other valuable
ingredients next we have a colic remedy
colic for spazmatic and flatulate cic it
says on the back not something you want
to be around with this one is a uh from
from catco drugs of Lincoln Nebraska
it's a glycer phosphates with cannabis
and leian sounds like it was pretty good
I think this was this was something
these guys were way ahead of their time
oh definitely now this is the one that
is always right up here at the top
little label says chocolate coated we
love that chocolate coated then down
here come one how many this held 500
compressed tablets of cannabis indicia
and opium op chocolate coat cannabis
indicia and opium pills oh that was
something that just knocked you out
there that beats M&amp;M's any day yeah
that's I wonder if it melted in your
mouth or in your
hand and then next we have a modern
product from Manitoba Harvest held hemp
seeds or hemp seed nut shelled hemp
seeds taste a lot like uh walnuts and
and kind of a cross between walnuts and
cashews so this is a very healthy
product that has all your essential
fatty acids Omega 3 six and n and a
perfect balance for human health so this
will keep you alive when you can't eat
anything else bag of that will keep you
alive with a complete protein