have these cannabis indici extract pills
from who is the manufacturer of this one
up John's they're still around today
around they're these mini itty bitty
teeny tiny pills uh it says that they
contain one to four grains of cannabis
per itty bitty teeny tiny pill now
somebody would ask you is that still any
good no and of course it's not no it's
it's about 110 years old so it's no good
now this one is about 125 years old CIP
persa pills and they're coting this
little purple stuff you can kind of see
some of them there in the bottom and so
that's that's an interesting one and
then here we have the neuralgia pills
from
Mumford uh in Philadelphia they're not
around anymore but these guys are Eli
Lily in fact the Bush family owns a lot
of stock in Eli Lily but uh this is uh
back from about 1920 or so it's a
cannabis extract what is it Number 96
they had about 10 different cannabis
products including powdered hashes from
heli Lily I'm curious if they still have
the patent for that with there was never
a patent it always was grandfathered in
they couldn't patent any of these
medicines this one's from Park Davis and
it's also one of several Park Davis
products cannabis indicia extract then
we come to two Nifty sharp and Dome and
they're still around too sharp and Dome
products this one is cannabis from
Cannabis Americana grown here in the
United States and this one is for Mig
migraines a lot of people wonder if
cannabis is useful for migraines this is
a sharp and D medicine from 1890
migraine number three with extra active
cannabis listed right there on the then
finally we come to a new product that's
uh you can get at your health food store
uh Manitoba Harvest shelled hemp seeds
these things taste like a cross between
cashews and walnuts or pecans so they're
really good and good for you with all
the Omega-3s and all that good stuff