disease and tonight we're going to talk
about a strange disease called gerd
it's a gastroesophageal
reflux disease there are a number of
people
that have
this problem
and it's very distressing because
when you swallow your food normally you
feel no
untoward effects
but in people who have gerd they have
severe indigestion now indigestion is
one thing but severe indigestion
secondary to gerd has some ominous
implications and bear with me for just a
minute i'm going to draw you a quick
picture of the stomach
now
when you swallow
food comes down the esophagus
and it goes through a little valve that
is positioned right here
and that valve allows the food to go
into the stomach
but it doesn't allow any of the gastric
acid that's in the strum stomach that is
responsible for breaking down
the material that you've swallowed in
other words food comes down
but it doesn't go up in people who have
gastroesophageal reflux disease
they have a
valve that is non-functional as soon as
food hits the stomach the stomach
agitates the food and
cells along the lining of the stomach
are called parietal cells and they
secrete acid that helps break down food
products
well what what's above the little
valve here it's
our esophagus it's the same tissue as
your skin
so if acid from the stomach
goes up into the esophagus it burns the
esophagus just like it would be if you
poured acid on your skin well that is
the flaw
in
gastroesophageal reflux disease there
are surgical
procedures that are helpful in
controlling this but many times the
symptoms themselves can be ameliorated
with the judicious use of cannabis so
if this
area here is not functional
and acid gets
flushed up into your esophagus you
experience the burning if we can control
that
the patient feels a lot better and last
but not least
the cells that are lining the esophagus
right here
are skin cells over a long period of
time
acid being flushed up into those skin
cell areas
and burned can cause a bad problem
called cancer of the esophagus it's the
so-called barrett's disease of the
esophagus so if we
can
discourage
the ongoing flush of acid into that area
and discourage the pain we have helped
the patient
thank you doctor thank you