we still need a long way to go before
cannabis is treated like the relatively
benign and harmless herb that we know it
to be how will we get there how will we
get to that point that place where we
can live freely in peace without with
our plant that has so much to offer our
community how will we get to cannabis
Freedom well we will not get there be a
circular firing squads where we infight
and attack each other ignoring that the
root cause of our misery is prohibition
not each
other we will not get there by finger
pointing or insults or deing ourselves
at every
chance we will not get there by
depending on our state legislators to
protect us and protect our patients and
Empower our community to serve its
own we will not get there by expecting
the federal government to protect us
from the insanity and the Injustice and
the persecution of federal
prohibition cuz we know that prohibition
every single time treats us like
criminals it creates criminals where
they don't
exist we will not get there by Smashing
windows and turning over cars and
lighting trash cans on
fire no our path has always been the can
perform movement's path has always been
and always will be the high road
[Applause]
still we are stronger than prohibition
and what we're showing is that we're
stronger than the United States
government we're stronger than than the
strongest government in the history of
the world because we're changing it and
it's freedom and Justice and Liberty
that's making it
possible still we've been stereotyped
we've been scapegoated we've been
targeted incarcerated stolen from denied
basic human dignities
and lumped in by our society with some
of the world's most dangerous criminals
and
most dysfunctional citizens in America
but we're not daunted we're a
steamroller
we're we are a tsunami of conviction and
determination we're in this for the long
ha this movement was built to
last we will we will get to our victory
by understanding the value of each other
by uplifting everyone around us by
embracing the values and principles of
unity and cooperation we will get there
by being a United Community despite our
differences by King the common ground
that joins us in our struggle for
Liberty and Our Endless Quest to simply
be left alone when we're not harming
[Applause]
anyone we will get there by putting our
Focus not on personalities but on issues
not by demonizing people but exposing
bad
policies we will get there because
everything is changing we are getting
there we're waiting well we might be
experiencing a few steps forward and one
step back well we might be disappointed
by the setbacks and the speed bumps on
the path of Victory we are changing the
world right now before everybody
Li you know back when we started
when we started you know we did the
first march here in 99 but all the way
back in 91 we started the Hempfest and
of course this movement's been going on
much longer than that so many people
laughed at us they laughed they said
you'll never get there you're wasting
your time you're pissing in the wind
probic will always be there they're not
laughing at us anymore the same people
that said we' never do it are now
rushing to capitalize and make some
money off of this new thing because we
worked so
hard we marched for workers rights so we
got them you marked for the vote for
women that he got it you marked for
civil rights legislation that it
happened you marked for gay rights and
they're here we get to Vietnam and it
ended because history is often made in
the streets of America as fris Douglas
as Frederick Douglas noted in the runup
to the Civil War power concedes nothing
without a demand we demand our freedom
we equality we Justice
what we need to do resist oppose and
educate because we'll never be stopped
until Victory thank you so much