we're going to now run a film clip from
Oregon normals medical cannabis award
panel I believe this one has some
Physicians we'll discuss it when we come
back hope you enjoy the
clip the Psychiatry That I Used to Know
does not exist anymore which is talk
therapy um and it's all pill pushing
it's
all
medication and to the end we really
don't know what is happening and this
extends not just to
psychotropics but I'm going to read you
a short letter to John a kits hamd
director Center for evidence-based
policy Oregon Health and Science
University and this is who I suggest if
you want to contact to embarrass a
little
bit uh on February 25th I happen to view
a panel presentation by your
organization on cpan on the cost benefit
study of different Pharmaceuticals
contracted by
AARP the sum total of that that uh panel
was they could not develop any cost
benefits analyses because in in
analyzing the pharmaceutical literature
they discovered it was all promotional
rather than objective and
scientific so everything masquerading as
science is Not So based upon California
clinical experience with a range of
chronic conditions our findings
indicated significant advantage over
other Pharmaceuticals conventionally
utilized because of improved quality of
life and fewer adverse effects
consequently we request the opportunity
to discuss our findings with you
attached as a list of conditions
and guess what the response
was so I'm glad this is going over cable
TV in the Portland area and hopefully uh
somebody out there in the viewing
audience Can U can give the center a
call and ask them to uh include cannabis
in their studies and especially about
the mental health issue I I would be
fascinated to hear the response but I
won't hold my breath may I interject
just very briefly that obviously there's
so much reduction in pharmaceutical use
that it's an enormous it's an enormous
opening for research which unfortunately
Physicians who are who are taking care
of patients in a primary care setting
they don't seem to be monitoring the
change in prescription drug patterns of
their patients before and after they
become members members of the OMMP and
it's remarkable because these patients
are reduce they're basically reducing
opiates tremendously and actually
there's research I'm sure you guys are
all aware of about the synergistic
effects of the receptor effects of
opiates and cannabinoids where they
basically are hitchhiking with each
other and small much smaller doses of
both medications create the same benefit
with of course much less side effects
these are really remarkable find ings
and and I really regret that there
aren't Physicians who are just
monitoring the the reduction in the
prescription patterns of their patients
if they doubt that cannabis is useful I
would encourage them to please do so and
just I mean before an after evaluation
of their prescriptions will show how
much reduction or how much change there
is but it's really a lost opportunity
there's a lot of possibilities you know
what you just said you you think that's
new if you read marijuana medical papers
uh in the Ohio State Medical Society
meeting on
cannabis in
1860 a Dr fondiller from
Ohio reported that U using an
alternative alternating courses of
opiates and cannabis for treating caric
conditions reduce dependence on
opiates 18 19 59 this was
written and so you know this is
something new now we're we're talking
about the Takeover by big farm and
ruining policy through their special
interest money and furthermore the fact
that this whole system this Mo can I use
the my paper oh why
not monomolecular Mercantile
Madness this is all patent office driven
if you look back to what it was before
the single
molecule ascended to its uh role in
current commercial
medicine um you'll see that it it's all
secondary to what can get
patented and they claim that the newly
patented materials increasingly better
blah blah blah but then you see what's
happened to the literature
it's gotten thoroughly corrupted and
perverted so that you don't know what's
happening and here we have now a a drug
seeking drug hungering public convinced
they need all sorts of uh combinations
of patentable
materials and this and it's really
sickening our society and when they
started directly advertising to the
public for psychotropics especially ask
your doctor
social anxiety
disorder um all these these kinds of um
influences to influence you and their
bottom
line any other
questions okay that was uh uh Dr Todd
mcara who wrote medical marijuana paper
back in the early 80s and directly to
his left that was an RN by the name of
Ed Glick to his right was Dr Rick bear
the chief petitioner on Oregon's ballot
measure 67 the medical marijuana law
that passed in
1998 then the other fellow off to the
side there that wasn't talking much In
that clip was Dr Cohen from uh uh Oregon
another physician who helps medical
marijuana patients how are you doing Don
I'm great Paul it's good to see you Don
dupe here is currently a social worker
but he's also a retired Portland Police
detective with a what is it a 7