M canvas foundations collection this one
is from specific medicines in Columbus
Ohio and it's just cannabis the text on
this bottle is hilarious I'll try to
read a little bit from it in a moment
it's got a Nifty back light cap with
their logo on it for Lloyd brothers and
specific medicines this next one is
really unique it's for migraines can you
see it right there on there migraines
it's from sharp and Dome that's another
company that's still around got two from
companies still exists sharpened Dome is
morphed and it has cannabis extracted
cannabis as one of its uh ingredients
for migraines we had a question about
that last week and this one is from Park
Davis says right there Park Davis and
it's cannabis
tincture uh and that these about a pint
bottle there another Nifty we have
several of these this is the most recent
acquisition we probably have about four
or five of these Park Davis pint bottles
in the THCF collection right now this
label is uh not the best example by far
but very legible and right next door we
have some hip milk that is distributed
here in the River City Portland Oregon
and it's made up in BC there's chocolate
I drank most of this and we have vanilla
which is going to some of the folks in
the control room who