next up we have uh from Churchill and
drugs a tincture of cannabis indici I
don't know if you can read that it's
probably a little faded maybe we close
in good job there closer closer there
you go tanure of cannabis Inda and so
this is like an 1890s bottle this next
one is one of our nicer bottles in the
collection we have a couple of these
actually and then it has a cork up here
in the top uh which is a uh they they
quit corking bottles of medicine back
about 1890 as well and this is bliss
native bossom for coughs and cold and it
contains a half a grain of cannabis to
the Ounce I've got the little fold out
hand out here I'm going to read it's
Bliss native bossom for coughs and coals
contains 2%
alcohol and uh this is the large 4 o
size and it contains one/ half grain of
cannabis indicia to the Ounce and the
promotional materials from about 120
years ago read we strongly recommend
Bliss native bossom for coughs colds
bronchitis the syrup made of simple
ingredients and of pleasing taste acts
promptly in soothing the inflamed
membranes it's a serious mistake to
allow a cough or cold to get started or
to linger carelessness will prove
dangerous when you first feel a cold
coming on or notice that you have one
start taking bliss's native bossom at
the same time keep the bowels open with
bliss native herbs and uh there it is
blisses need a a full bottle and uh a
nice our next two medicines are
Veterinary medicines and this is a
collic compound Dr hess's collic remedy
and I guess you're supposed to force
this down the throat of your horse or
cow if he's H for the treatment of
according to the back of the bottle
spasmodic and flatulent colic gripes
acute or chronic indigestion impaction
of the stomach inflammation of the
impactation of the colon Etc from Dr hes
and Clark of Ashland Ohio next door we
have for horses and cattle says right
here for horses and cattle uh it's
cannabis chlorohydrate and cannabis
indicia oh this has 36 and 2/3 grains
per ounce it's Nifty uh embossing on the
back of the bottle here says sloes
anticolic SLO then jumping forward 120
years we have Manitoba Harvest hemp
seed uh H hemp seed you know H hemp seed
takes the outer crunchy shell off of the
marijuana or hemp seed and it taste like
cashews and it's very it's really good
if you like nuts and things anyway it
says from The Amazing hemp seed manit
toara H Seed nut is created we've taken
the most nutritious part of the hemp
seed the inner nut remove the hard out
ouder shell and sealed it in a shelf
stable package to lock in the freshness
to ensure quality Manitoba Harvest grows
processes and packages all of our own
products daily in our kosher and USDA
organic certified facility hempy nut is
delicious source of Omega 3 and six
essential fatty acids and essential
amino acids or protein sprinkle it on
your salad cereal or yogurt can be used
in your favorite cooking and baking
recipes but keep the temperature below
350 fah so that you do not damage the
precious
omegas the next door to that we have to
thank Aiko for donating this six-pack of
hemp ale from the Humbolt brewing
company founded in 1987 it's an all
natural hemp and Ale there have been a
few different hemp alses out there over
the years they've come and gone but this
one's still there and uh you can rush
out to your store and get this it's f
family own and operated since
1987 right down in Northern California
so there you there you have it