here is a
cannabis indica powdered cannabis indica
on the back of it it says one ounce this
was powdered hashish from uh
the merrell company in cincinnati and
it says poison up here at top a lot of
these medicines say that uh they believe
some people believed it was a poison but
this was an ounce of uh powdered hashi
sharqif and it was uh both park davis
and eli lilly had some products like
that now here we have cannabis tincture
number 17.
it's physiologically tested and
it's from
park davis and there's a little pd on
embossed on the bottom of the bottle
there
next door we have a cork that's kind of
broke off and residue in this bottle you
can see it says it is poison right there
and this is cannabis uh fluid extract
number 96 from eli lilly so where this
one is tincture number 17 this is fluid
extract number 96 and i can't really
tell you right off the top of my head
what the differences between those are
this one is one of the rarest things
that i've run across it's from the al
air woodward company of pieroya illinois
and it is still full it is a package of
cannabis and i don't know exactly what's
in there i'm not going to try to open it
but it's uh about uh
90 years old it says the properties are
a nerve eye and it'll cure your nerves
and a dime knock you out uh pseudorite
an anti-spasmodic and anti-epileptic so
a lot of the things that we are
currently allowed to use medical
marijuana for they were using it for
back then in
1910. on the bottom the common names are
foreign indian hip hashish
gallow grass
bong
gunja
achuris
and uh
one other
you hamp
from the german so this is a pretty rare
package here
and this is a package from the san
francisco cannabis buyers club back in
the 1990s this was the way they packaged
up
looks like this was five grams very
brightly colored package it says warning
may cause drowsiness dry mouth mild
euphoria and short-term memory loss do
not drive or operate heavy machinery
it's printed by the purple tree trading
company
and uh the price was sixty dollars for
an eighth
back in the 90s
uh it the uh
and it's grade california green 5a
next to that
we have a full bottle very rare thing
from uh
the adamson drug company of clarenburg
west virginia it is your improved cough
and cold compound a valuable expectorant
and sedative for coughs colds and simple
ailments of the throat chest and lungs
the compound is valuable and in the
treatments of coughs colds simple
bronchitis and spasmodic croup
it also says an unusually effective
cough and cold preparation contains a
specially selected remedial ingredients
of rare quality
so
there
it is your idea
and this is uh something i've been
holding on to for a number of years and
some uh chocolate preparations that were
quite popular back uh about six or seven
years ago before the the the feds came
in and shut them down this is a dragon
bar it's chocolate almond dates with
medicinal cannabis
this one is called uno dos
and it's a medicinal chocolate caramel
bar
i would say i probably would have a
weakness for chocolate caramel i know
you know i'm probably carrying a good
number of pounds of chocolate collard
and when you blame it on the chocolate
this one i love the name of this this is
hashies
hashy's bar
uh
it's medicinal chocolate almond bar very
good this was next over
we have a deodorant purchased at a local
health food store it's hemp oil
deodorant it's made with the seeds of
the marijuana plant some people like to
distinguish the thc content but it is
from cannabis
and then last but not least another one
of my old products from back when i uh
sold hemp paper from 1990 through 1997
tree free eco paper this is 50 hemp and
50 straw and i imported about 60 tons of
this in three containers back in
1991.
so there you have it hemp paper it's
also
mixed with cereal straw that's the end
of our sharing segment for tonight