so here we go we got a few different
things here this is actually a box and a
bottle set it's old it's about5 years
old it's uh made in New Jersey and it's
Rend Our Father dialyses cough medicine
good for coughs cold bronchitis whooping
cost asthma hay fever and all
afflictions of the throat and lungs and
it's so been according to the literature
that's falling apart that it's been
coming with it's uh been found to bring
relief to the most stubborn cases among
friends and their children and it's
found in all cases to be a health
Builder and strengthening remedy and
wonderful medicine within the reach of
all so no one should be denied its
restoring compounds according to this
falling apart literature that comes with
it but Dr eliss I mean father excuse me
Father eliss cough medicine's also
embossed on the back with father lisses
and down here at the bottom it says
what's in it and I don't know if you can
see that we're going to oh that's really
good you're doing a good job uh it
contains opium Indian
cannabis
heroin alcohol and
chloroform so father deysi will give you
a good dose of mixture of opium Indian
cannabis heroin alcohol and chloroform
sming good what notice it says right
here it's used by father alissi for
years and it also says over here never
known to fail it's never been known to
fail so I'm sure it has so what does a
bottle like that cost that's full you
know our foundation got it for a little
bit over $500 and it's sealed and we
will never open this because it's part
of our Museum a shot never mind we're
turning you down we're not opening that
money no this is a museum piece we're
not opening right next door now this is
1905 Circa 1905 father dialyses magic
cough remedy right next to it we have a
tincture B from the 1880s we've seen
this in the past it's got the label
underglass or lug next to it my f one of
my favorite supplements hemp seed oil uh
I order this through hemp oil Canada and
it's very Nifty as we were talking about
you can get 300 gallons of oil and the
byproduct of that is this flour and high
protein flour Prairie Emerald H flour is
protein en wrench gluten-free whole
grain flour that imparts the Nutty
flavor of hemp into a wide variety of
baked goods hemp flour is an excellent
source of protein containing all the
essential amino acids hemp flour is very
high in dietary fiber and a good source
of energy for people on the go so there
it is hemp flour next we see hemp
nuggets now these have been hul these
are actual hemp seeds that have been
roasted and the outer crunchy little
coats been taken off and it's a lot like
a cross between cashews and walnuts or
pecans it's got this initial cashew
buttery flavor and then it kind of after
flavor of of pecans or walnuts and and
Tim you want to talk about you got our
our thing of hemp seed hemp seed milk
here this is really good stuff you
introduced this to me a few weeks back
and and you've been bringing it on the
show and I got to take one home a few
weeks back and I really enjoyed it put
it in the refrigerator cooled it down
and and I I just really I liked it it's
got all of the Omega-3 uh it's got 2800
milligram of Omega 6 it's got all 10
essential amino acids it's got 4 gram of
digestible protein essential vitamins a
B12 d e ribin and folic acid which is
very important vitamin BS are important
the essential Minerals Magnesium
potassium phosphorus iron and good old
zinc so I got to tell you it's it's it
tastes good and it's good for you you
know how about that and then we have the
ginger and hemp granola that's a new one
out there I just found uh out in a
health food store ginger in Granola you
know we just buy this stuff out there
once I see it and bring it on the show
here so you folks out there know about
the diversity of products that are
available out there and so uh go out
there and sample some hemp products if
not these try some others you'll be
amazed at how good they are for you