right here from England we have a bottle
of chloridine chloridine was a typical
actually this is from Australia a
typical uh compound that was used I'm
just going to read what it says it's
used for uh it affects great relief in
all cases of diarrhea disent chalera
fevers neuralgia bronchitis asthma cro
cramps influenza and as a sedative
medicine for the use in a great many
compx PS sounds very familiar doesn't it
yes it does now this is a bottle of uh
uh medicine it's actually full of a 100
little capsules from the manufacturing
chemists they uh are the successors to
Bell and Company and this is canaban
Bell it's an extract of cannabis strict
9 and zinc phosphate canaban Bell a
nerve tonic and stimulant for the
treatment of mental and physical
exhaustion depression insomnia neuralgia
Etc one tablet after each meal and at
bedtime gradually increase your dose to
two four times a day as directed by your
physician we got these Nifty little
green taets in there in the bottle and
it's there's a hundred of them in there
and they're about a hundred years old
now this is from England this is an
apoca can canister it uh probably would
hold about a half oun oun or so and it's
got a Nifty little uh mark on the bottom
on L and it shows some wear with age on
the inside a little bit and so there you
have it then this one is from the
Columbus pharmacist company and it's
nervine improved Elixir nervine improved
Elixir so I'm going to pull it away and
read from the bottle it uh contains
cannabis indicia right up at the top and
uh it's useful in the treatment of
congestive conv Ive and reflexive
neurosises insomnia
neurasthenia
uh affections due to derangement of the
nervous system epilepsy nervous Insanity
dmania hysteria and uterine congestion a
dose is uh one
teaspoon four times a day there it is
for hysteria yep hysteria and uterine
congestion