okay this is uh this is one of the
original uh pieces of hemp uh this is
medium density fiber board it was made
out of hemp that was grown in Spain
imported through France uh we imported
this I think in 1992 we imported a bail
through CNS specialty Builder Supply
Bill Ki David seber Barry uh Davis I was
on the board of directors there uh we
had to discover what we could do to use
this and so we had this bail of hemp
that we had to bring in through the DEA
and uh uh we had to prove that there was
no THC in it whatsoever and we were able
to do that so now we got the hemp and
now we have to discover what is it that
you do with a ba hemp to turn it into a
actual real live board and studies said
that that is stronger than steel this is
uh what we did when when we we had to
actually go through all of this standard
industry tests for this and uh for this
board uh and what we discovered was that
it met or surpassed every standard in
the industry and so it's Mo the modulus
of rupture on this is something like
1,500 which is 10 times average and so
when we had it tested on CNN because we
actually did have this tested on CNN it
broke the machine that tests things like
this there was you know so it we had we
we discovered all kinds of fanciful
things that you can do with him from an
industrial standpoint and so this is
when in my archives and you always have
showand tell down here here Paul and so
I I'm glad you brought that in I I I'd
bring a piece of History this is
actually one of the very first hint
boards ever made and I was on the board
of directors and I actually discovered
how it was that we could cut this up in
order to make it turn it into boards
because when we sent it to Washington
State and we discovered we they were
using long fibers and they put it
through their their fiber masher and at
Washington State University have a the
best the most uh Advanced composite uh
Manufacturing research and development
facility in the world it was funded by
the United States government but yeah it
was after World War II they they funded
that and so that's where we took it to
have them uh test the fibers and when
they put all those fibers into the
machine it froze the machine up in just
a few seconds and and they'd never had
anything do that to their machine before
rather than be upset they were rather
excited because they'd never had
anything do that before and they wanted
to know what this stuff was all about
and so we went on to uh several year
research and development uh process and
I believe that if you ever wanted to to
uh uh license this you could go to
Washington State University and and
purchase the license because they own
the license for this and and uh uh you
could learn how to make it and the
formula is available simple as that it's
it's out there