you want to talk about the breadth of
different patients and the type of
patients you see in this I know you had
practiced as a cardiac surgeon for about
40 years so you'd see people who needed
a heart transplant or I know in one case
we were seeing patients in Spokane and a
fellow said you had taken a bullet out
of his heart about 10 years before that
so uh but in in this case you're seeing
patients that are different from the
typical cardiac patient
no question that
um
to have your hand inside a chest around
a beating heart is an extraordinary
experience
and I think it was one of these
experiences that kind of lit the fire if
you will for me uh and for the future of
the use of something like cannabis
and I wonder if I could just say a few
words of Paul about one of the things
that arises to the surface please
especially when we see people in the
clinics
we are seeing many many people who are
coming in with problems associated with
pain
and this is a very important subject
that needs to be discussed in the
medical field as well as the Cannabis
field
people who are become uh
over users of Narcotics and opiates are
frequently seen in our clinics and it's
in large part because of the
inappropriate
giving of Narcotics to patients by
physicians and we see this constantly
and here we have this incredible
medication which can be used properly
can be very helpful in getting people
off of the use of Narcotics and opiates
and this is one area that we work
diligently on
yeah I've seen the vast majority of
patients that come through with chronic
pain issues who have been Addicted by
their Physicians to these things from
Oxycontin to Morphine to many forms of
synthetic narcotics
I would say about 80 percent of them
completely get off of those narcotics by
the time they come in for their renewal
the next year that's cool that's
accurate and it may be 10 have
dramatically reduced it and the other
maybe five percent five to ten percent
have have continued it but cannabis has
been used by literally hundreds of
thousands of people to help quit their
Addiction in fact you know we show these
medicinal bottles on our TV show all the
time and one of the things that it says
on the bottles is it's for the
habituates of opiates
chloroform
cocaine alcoholics with delirium tremens
to help them get off all of those drugs
so it's been acknowledged as an aid in
that for many many years and even
nicotine yeah yeah nicotine we've got
Alpha nicotine
frequently
you can attach yourself
to something that moves you uh beyond
the average
and I think being a part of medicine
enabled me to do this first of all with
the thing I loved so much was was taking
care of human
hearts
and then when that times slip slided
away I could come in and continue to
work with humans and their hearts but in
a different way by advising them about
how they can take care of their bodies
how they can avoid taking and eating the
wrong things and the wrong medications
and I think I've been able to realize a
a second coming if you will