great
you
in sy
we 76 against
5052 what we done is rem the
dutti
access
need
12000 signatures put on the b for vote
the people
november people ask why we more we got
remember just not just us voting the
mainstream voters so we did as little as
we was
necessary
dony have 76 days 76 days to get
123,000
signatures tell you when this initiative
came out spored by mr william kurz who
fought for you by
tost county qu b was
a bill his to vote b was money out his
pocket that he needed to put food on his
table with and stood up and susan elliot
stood up and the courts agreed and they
sent it back and thurston county was too
embarrassed to fight on so bill return
toe
7 it's do a lti take a of people of pati
to get signatures but we cannot depend
on our people alone we need
professionals out there to make up the
difference between what we can do
ourselves and what they able to do
professionals we need money but we
getting it for bucks and 12s hour i
was
wash
do
med grow liv on t grow if accessing
patients and want to be there next july
if authorization clin and you go on the
road and take care of people that don't
have primary care physicians that don't
have access to these people that don't
have the
resources we got save us all and keep us
open now once done
got tell you the money interest came out
heart and you can see it in
5052 it's time to stop f it's time to
come together and do what the
legislature has failed to do
1998 that's to cy our best practices as
they exist now we have patients come
into our plac because they are clean
because
respect because
safe we don't want pati to be for under
5052 to and get medic at2
store pesticides are not good medic we
must keep medical can safe and separate
sep from
recreational i don't want patients to
st
inad what and i don't want any patient
to go store and get medic because
somebody else got there before them and
bought it just to get high when that
happens you cannot your medicine any and
this is why we must keep medical sep
recreational please check out
the nor
can
17 hot speakers wills in your if you own
access if a grow if you
got get us your email you can volunteer
your information on the we will mail you
we
nov
usv
wash
we
we than you