these are all newly acquired freshly
open Nifty little things this one is a
corn the first two are corn removers
this one is from James and it's ether
and cannabis indicia says right there
closes in on that and then this says
it's a nonproprietary
formula of cicc acid or aspirin and
cannabis indicia which it says is poison
and that's the formula and it's uh
medicated elastic adhesive Ecto plast uh
uh corn rings to ripe out corns and and
other nasty things this is a couple of
different uh chloridine and neuralgic
medicines but the this one has morphine
extract of cannabis indicia
nitroglycerin peppermint just a little
bit of peppermint in there to add a
little flavor I think you know it's a
Nifty little label multicolor uh it's
from independent pharmaceutical company
of Worcester Massachusetts we're looking
about 1890 it's embossed on the back
with ipco the name of the company and
Nifty little poison thing here next door
we find Shin's neur neurologic medicine
it is
uh canabus and opium and other Nifty
Things From schins in Philadelphia this
also is a neurological medicine and it's
from Park Davis of Detroit Michigan and
it is opium extract in cannabis and a
lot of other little things in there and
that's from Park Davis and this last one
is the tonight's P resistance it's uh
powdered extract of Indian cannabis from
Park Davis and uh it's about half full
you can see we might call it Keef this
is Circa
1880 powdered extract of cannabis
powdered hashish and like I say it's
about half full it's got a thing on the
back this one's a pretty nifty one has
has a nice writing on it it's owing to
the character of this drug and it's a
powder equal the medicinal value and
it's a narcotic like opium it relieves
pain and spasms but does not diminish
the appetite or check the
secretions that's from uh Park Davis and
that's what you call really cured huh
yeah that's been cured uh definitely
aged aged cannabis now I'm not ever
going to open this this is a valuable
antique but uh my understanding is that
it degrades at about 10% a year and
since it's about gone 120 years old uh
it was gone a long time ago it's time
has passed