one of those is a hempcrete balls to
what you have here is the inner core
portion of the stock which is similar to
some of what we have here in this bag
the little woody portions that you see
in here and then we mix this with a line
binder and water and this becomes a non
structural component of the wall
insulation or you can compress them into
blocks to have construction structural
components of the wall it's breathable
resistant to mold resistant to fire and
you can learn more about that at hemp
dash technologies com and so that's
carbon negative this is a carbon
negative is what the tests have shown
for our colleagues in the UK now this is
one of the reasons why we want to be
cultivating industrial hemp in this
country is it so that we can start to
coordinating those stocks to create that
heard that will need to go into this
building application and not only can
you use this heard in hempcrete but you
can also use it in a hemp block here's a
little bitty piece of a pressed board
and this also is using the hemp heard
and then press this is made in Canada
nice just a little bitty press block
there keep all this organized by the
feedback and then right here we have a
hemp insulation so this is a pink
insulation replacement and you can get
this in various sizes and of course it's
cut to be 15 or 16 inches depending on
what you need it can come with or
without a fire retardant depending on
your needs in building code so here we
have I think these are both made in like
a needle punch machine as a non woven
matting this is a very thin piece so you
could use this as what is essentially
made into this briefcase right here is
this type of matting that is in molded
and infused you could also use this as
something to go underneath a counter
tops or as perhaps soil retention and
last but not least what we have here is
the bast fiber on the inside so this is
the outside of the stock and these are
the long bast fibres that you would use
to make those non woven Madden's and to
make the hemp insulation so I said last
but there's one more item here you have
him fast fibers yep hey bird fiber you
want to tell our audience the difference
between the two yeah so this is the
woody core on the inside this is the
hemp heard you can see this in all
cannabis plants they all have the long
bass fiber on the outside and that bast
fiber on the outside is what our
colleagues like in China are using to
make the amazing textiles such as what I
have on right now this is hemp or iam
from South Africa and then the inner
core here is the woody portion but you
could also use this in type of
applications such as gasification to
create heat in greenhouses and in homes
so this is a variable or animal bedding
amazing for animal bedding we just
cleaned out our chicken coop and we had
the top part with straw and underneath
we had the hemp hurt and so surprising
in Canada our minus 30 whether how the
hemp heard was still really light and
fluffy and it was able to remove the
straw quite quickly well thank you