and we need to free the people who are
in prison for pot we need to free the
children who are held hostage by CPS
away from their loving families
and we need to restore the rights of
those who have been stunted by felony
drug convictions
fairness equality social justice equal
opportunity
just injustice is here and it's
happening
now the human solution is going to come
up and give a message and they may talk
about Sean abanda who is fighting today
for her 11 year old son marijuana
changed her life and she educated her
community and her son and when he
corrected
the school that was giving
misinformation they took that 11 year
old in kept him in custody
raided his mother's home took her
medicine and her son and she's fighting
for him and that's today and even in
Colorado where I remind you marijuana is
legal
Angel price Lane was taken from her
parents when she was 11 months old
because her father said he
recreationally smoked marijuana
occasionally I remind you again it was
legal
within a month that baby was given to a
19 year old who had three other kids and
she died that month a blunt forced to
the Head repeated blunt force to the
Head
there are people who are losing their
jobs there are people who are losing
their children and there are people in
prison
and it is our right to be here to speak
and to to exercise those rights but it's
also our duty to be the voice of those
people who can't be heard because they
are in prison or they are held
their children are gone
so we need a bill that automatically
causes review of anybody serving time
for pot we need protections for parents
so that responsible use is not a reason
to take kids away
and in the four states in DC that have
legalized recreational use and in the
more than 20 states that have medical
laws nobody has protected prisoners yet
so make it a part of every cannabis
conversation Justice equality equal
opportunity and join me join normal
normal women of Washington Equal justice
and liberty for all oh