we had two bills this year SB of uh 5012
and hb1552 for industrial hemp we
suggested the most minimal possible
regulations that we could suggest in
order to maintain the Integrity of an of
an industrial hemp crop with the
sophisticated markets that exists today
and to be compliant with the new
legitimacy of industrial hemp research
act that was passed on a federal level
in February of 2014. however our minimal
regulations were too minimal for the
Washington State Department of
Agriculture who have inserted themselves
into the regulatory process and
requested multiple amendments to our
minimal regulations that they then
projected with a fiscal note of nine
hundred thousand dollars in order to
administer an industrial hemp program
here agriculturally for our state it
will cost nowhere near nine hundred
thousand dollars for them to administer
a reasonable compliant Industrial Hemp
program in our state but they wanted
their hands in the testing of hemp they
wanted their hands in the testing of of
uh of the hemp in certain Labs the
reality is that the liquor control board
does not oversee marijuana testing the
marijuana producers take their own test
sample they bring it to a third party
authorized testing facility and their
lab set all through our state and
everything is done by third party
authorized folks and with producers who
take their own sample the wsda the
Washington State Department of
Agriculture insisted that they had to be
present to see an industrial hemp sample
collected now I want you to know in
Canada they've had legal Industrial Hemp
since 1998 it's a booming industry
we buy 90 of the industrial hemp seeds
and hemp seed oil and other derivatives
that come from the proteins of the hemp
plant from Canada Health Canada which
governs the industrial hemp program in
that country does not oversee the
testing they do not go out into the
fields and collect tests in fact it's
actually a revenue generator they
authorize professional agrologists to
become licensed field Samplers and the
farmer pays a couple of hundred dollars
in many cases less to have a third party
come out and take their test once a year
collect a sample of plants and then take
it to a third-party testing facility and
health Canada doesn't deal with that
they don't bear the expense of that they
don't Supply the human resources and the
mass spectrometers and the gas chromatic
graphs required for all of that testing
that's hundreds of thousands of dollars
the liquor control board doesn't do it
either here and here we're talking about
marijuana not even a non-drug oil seed
and fiber crop but the Washington State
Department of Agriculture decided nope
we need to see the tests that the sample
actually being collected we need to test
that sample ourselves and invest in
hundreds of thousands of dollars of
cannabis testing equipment and therefore
it's going to cost almost a million
dollars Which is far too much for an
industrial hemp crop that we don't think
is going to earn any money so right now
even though we have two live bills even
alive still in our special session they
are both stalled at the House
Appropriations Committee level and the
Washington have Industries Association
is working overtime providing economic
data and other evidence to prove to them
that their projection of Regulation is
far far more expensive than it needs to
be why it is and how much money there is
to be made with industrial home
so we would really appreciate it if you
folks would join and all you need to do
is go to join hemp.net to become a
supporting member of the Washington hemp
Industries Association it's only 50 a
year to become a supporting member we
have got to clean up carbon carbon
emissions here we have got to clean up
heavy pesticide use heavy water use
heavy fertilizer use we are ruining the
land we are ruining the soil we have
already all but destroyed the American
farm and the farming industry Industrial
Hemp will re-energize that and will also
bring Health not only to our lands and
our soils and our Waters but to our
biosphere to our climate
I also am very honored to sit on the
board for the center for the study of
cannabis and social policy as well as
the normal women of Washington and I am
involved with compliance and law I've
had a dual career over the last 20 years
or so in complex civil litigation and
compliance and I wanted to make sure
folks realize that in this SB 5052 that
has passed that has Stripped Away many
of the rights that patients have been
enjoying in the state of Washington
since the voters spoke overwhelmingly in
1998 to to legalize the medical use of
marijuana
it used to be that folks that held
medical marijuana authorization patients
who depend on the staple plant medicine
to manage a variety of medical
conditions and quality of life issues
everything from glaucoma to Multiple
Sclerosis to wasting syndrome to chronic
pain syndrome to a variety of terminal
illnesses
they used to be able to grow 15 plants
themselves those who had to those who
could now if they voluntarily register
which many folks do view as a HIPAA or a
privacy right violation that we would
need to register for our medic our
medicine put our names on a list those
folks will be able to grow six plants
now not 15. and if you don't volunteer
to be on the registry you'll only be
able to grow four plants as a patient
instead of six now the reason for 15 is
of course for those of you who depend on
this safe whole plant medicine for your
conditions or for your quality of life
oftentimes 15 plants are required to
produce the actual quantity of medicine
that would be needed to manage a health
condition most folks who have a serious
illness don't consume by smoking
marijuana they consume it by eating it
or ingesting it requires more plant
material collectives used to be able to
have 10 members they'll go down to four
members now that this law has been
passed additionally
we've been able to go to these medical
marijuana clinics to get our medical
marijuana authorizations those who have
qualifying conditions medical marijuana
clinics as we know them will be
dissolved by law in two and a half
months July 23rd of
2015. that's this year that's this
summer all medical marijuana clinics as
we know them will be dissolved by law
and guess who is left to authorize your
use of marijuana for medicine your
primary care provider I'd like you to
ask yourself How likely is your primary
care provider to issue you an
authorization for medical marijuana this
is actually a place where activists and
patients and people who believe in the
freedom of this plant need to work with
their clinics need to work with their
medical providers need to work with
their Primary Care Providers to tell
them not only is the huge need here and
to give them information and hard data
that they need easily found on multiple
websites across the the World Wide Web
also let them know there is money to be
made
you are going to have to work on that we
have to work on the economic aspects of
industrial Health all the time we have
to dangle the carrot of money in order
to get people to buy into it it's also
how we're ending the drug war with money
proving that these billions of dollars
have done nothing but let the black
market flourish while we have continued
drug uh addiction
amazing statistics of drug addiction and
crime superseding most other parts of
the world right here in the United
States the last thing I want to tell you
is that medical marijuana dispensaries
as we know them will be dissolved by law
unless we can get some sensible
legislation or initiative pass by July
of 2016. so next summer right now
eligible existing medical marijuana
dispensaries are being asked now to
apply for a medical endorsement not from
the Department of Health from the liquor
control board a medical endorsement from
the liquor control board and those that
actually make it through The Gauntlet of
compliance issues which will no doubt
move and each compliance Target will
change as the process goes on they will
then be allowed to be rolled into
existing recreational marijuana stores
we don't have a ton of those many
patients tens of thousands of patients
across our state are impoverished
disabled they live in rural areas they
need safe and legal access to this whole
plant medicine that they have come to
rely upon that doesn't have side effects
that does improve their quality of life
that does treat their condition so we
need to be vigilant we need to work with
our Primary Care Providers we need to
contact our legislators you guys don't
don't let anybody fool you we live in an
amazing country and an even more amazing
State and and our legislators on a state
and a federal level they work for us and
most of them are fully aware of that and
they want to hear from you and it's so
easy to do so please take the
empowerment given to us by the folks who
created our country by the folks who
draft to the constitution for the state
of Washington and for the United States
and let's use our voices use our phones
and start being brave and letting our
light shine thank you everyone for
showing up today