these antique medicines you'll see
things for delirium trimens now that's a
side effect of of qu alcohol alcoholism
you see it says it's for getting off
opium and nicotine and chloroform so it
helps with that too uh here is a Eli
Lily bottle we have a couple of Eli Lily
bottles in the collection here here's
another one this one is extract Number
96 and right next to it is extract
number 17 so Eli Lily had a variety of
different medicines and we you show some
others on some other shows here we have
a hypnosedative with cannabis it also uh
has chloroform and bromide which the
chloroform alone of course will knock
you out this is uh uh for migraines now
here it shows they were using cannabis
for migraines and they mix this with
Aspirin basically uh uh extractive
cannabis and aspirin pill from sharpen
Dome of Boston and then right next next
door we have another sharpen Dome
cannabis extract bottle this is from
Mulford company in uh Ohio it's a nice
collection all of these bottles date
from 1870 to
1910 this one is about
1905 and I like this one because they
call it American hemp and it's cannabis
grown here in the good old us OFA and it
it has really interesting list of things
I won't go through right now here is one
of my favorite and I eat these regularly
they're shelled hemp seeds from uh
Canada and they you can find them in a
lot of different stores once you press
your hemp seeds and take out the oil you
have a high protein flour left and
here's hemp flour you can make uh hemp
protein drinks hemp patties and burgers
all kinds of things it's really good and
here's one uh a couple of different
versions of hemp milk this one from
Living Harvest this one from Manitoba
Harvest they're all made up in Canada
because we can't grow this stuff in the
United States the The Drug Enforcement
Administration doesn't think we can
handle it but we're going to get octop
passed and we're going to be able to
grow it right here in the great state of
Oregon that's right that's right and we
need your help out there so get ready
we're going to need you to come and
volunteer because we you know we going
to create new jobs we're going to create
new Industries we're going to put Oregon
on The Cutting Edge of some exciting new
environmental and economic developments
that will benefit fit our state a great
great deal I could totally see us
creating an industry here of wood
products too oh it's all we've got all
the pieces in place for that we have the
workers who are being off you know who
have that knowledge yeah we can put
people to work at the state anything
made with petrochemicals can be made
with hip seed oil so uh I look forward
to