40 different corn plasters that have
come across my into My Collection Here
What they do is they put it directly on
the corns and Leave it there for several
Days then they Find that loosens the
corn or the the mole or uh uh wart off
and then you just Scratch it off And it
Comes Right off with your fingernail
This is a 10 that was Just picked Up and
then Next Door Here from uh London from
Liverpool actually We have a Bottle New
cann of tincture Bottle Cannabis indica
from Liverpool Now Paul mccartney's out
there and you'd like to Get this Just
Give Me a Call budy Right Next to that
We have i'd be happy to Give this to
Paul McCartney uh Here We have a Park
Davis product neuralgia and uh it looks
pretty potent it's got morphine and
Cannabis and capsicum Which will make it
Burn As it Goes Down then Next to that
We have powdered Cannabis This is
powdered hashish a powdered
extract Next to that We have a fluid
tincture and a Couple Other larger
bottles that We shown in prior weeks All
of these are from eli Lily these Last
Four are all eli Lily and Who is the
senator Fred That's trying to Protect
it's fr That's protecting tennessee The
senate majority Leader and in congress
the leading drug Warrior the congressman
Whose committee propri the funds for the
drug zar Office is sa of İndiana Who is
considered the congressman from eli L
yeah and he's the rabid drug Warrior The
One Who he's from eli L but