this is uh as you can see uh Indian
cannabis uh a fluid extract of Indian
cannabis from uh wyth and brothers right
next to it it is a cannabis compound
called kill a cough it's a really neat
bottle it's a if you like bottles and I
do this one is a chloroform cannabis
mixture and uh uh it's called kilof for
cough as a cough medicine next to it we
have this that also came in this it's
also Kirk Call's cough medicine it has a
little package here with instructions in
Swedish Bohemian Spanish Italian
French uh and several other languages so
uh this is also uh uh cannabis and
chloroform basically that just knock you
out right doctor you take cannabis and
chlorop form boom you're knocked out you
won't be coughing then we have this one
from Eli Lily a one pint bottle of fluid
uh extract Number 96 cannabis uh Eli
Lily had about uh eight different
cannabis preparations several of them
pure some of them were fluid extract uh
I mean powdered extract of hemp which
was basically hashish then we have this
little V package of hemp oil we've taken
it and L this lamp to demonstrate the
energy potential of cannabis and then of
course our hemp wine