let's start over over here with the new
nutritious hemp milk which is very very
tasty it comes in plain vanilla and
chocolate I don't have any plain here to
show it's actually distributed from here
in Portland Oregon uh and uh but it's
made up in Vancouver British Columbia or
up in the British Columbia Vancouver
area anyway so this is really a tasty
new very nutritious item out there that
has all the Omega 6 and three that most
of our diets are lacking so that's
something to look at next over we have a
uh uh Park Davis bottle and Park D this
is a a pint bottles uh of cannabis
tincture one of the half dozen par Davis
cannabis you can see cannabis right
their products then right here is the
pride of the THCF
medical uh collection this is our oldest
medicinal cannabis bottle from the 1840s
from London and cannabis was introduced
into British
pharmacology in uh 1839 by William oanes
he's a Scotsman who brought it back from
India and he called it cannabis indicia
and so here's one of the early bottles
that they they used to store it in and
it's a real big bottle I'd say that's a
uh holds a gallon or so it's big 1840
our oldest bottle next door we have a
1880 cannabis tinure bottle from here in
North America they call call these
things lugs or uh label under glass
because they put the label under the
glass and then put glass on top of it
and that's one of the terms for these
type of apocy bottles uh a lug bottle
it's got a Nifty little cap and You' see
that in your farmacist and then this one
here the last one that we'll bother you
with tonight is a reproduction that was
done by the British
pharmacological Society in
1972 and