we have a film clip we're going to run
it this is from the magic weed a
production out of Great Britain from uh
2005 enjoy yeah Japanese immigrant
Farmers have increased production of the
one cash crop which has long been a
virtual Philippine
Monopoly the invasion of the two big
hemp producing countries China and
Philippines was the start of hemp
rationing Hitler was also aware of the
Strategic importance of hemp which is
used in the making of canvas and ropes
both of which were an essential part of
his war
effort in 1941 when the German Army
invaded Russia it blocked Britain's
supply of Russian hemp Germany managed
to develop her own hemp production but
the cultivation of this fiber which had
become so necessary in war time was
still banned in Great
[Music]
Britain in 1942 the German troops
reached the center of Russia the land
continued to produce hem which enabled
Hitler to move confidently to the next
stage of his plans for the
right to safeguard its own supplies of
hemp Great Britain urged India to
increase
[Music]
production meanwhile war was spreading
to
Japan within little more than a year
Japan successfully employing once again
the deceit and treachery which had so
well served her in the past had taken
the final desperate
PL when Japan bombed Pearl Harbor
forcing the United States of America to
declare war Americans realized they were
cut off from their hemp supplies the US
Navy was totally dependent upon hemp for
rock resistant ropes for their ships and
for many other
components the American government then
decided to redevelop the the hemp
industry marijuana was legalized again
and Farmers received seeds a propaganda
film called hemp for victory was then
made to encourage this war effort
[Music]
the Allies Air Forces were completely
Reliant upon Him parachute straps packs
and belts were made out of him no other
available fiber was so strong and so
reliable under combat
[Music]
conditions after General MacArthur had
forced the Japanese to withdraw from the
Philippines and production soon reached
pre-war levels of
again after the war Years A New World
arose From the Ashes of the old India
gained
[Music]
independence thanks to automation India
doubled its hem production and increased
its exports to America and the rest of
the world in peace time the United
States once again banned the cultivation
of hemp and cannabis but at the same
time imported millions of tons of hemp
during the postwar economic boom to
supply its Industries well this is the
port of New York a sprawling pattern of
activity covering more than 1500 square
miles it's 650m Waterfront an Ever
Changing mirror reflecting the work of
the world and its needs and tastes grain
from Canada and fish from Portugal and
Norway tires from akan
and hemp from
[Music]
India during the postwar years in France
hemp growing and processing went through
a revitalized Industrial
Revolution what is interesting to
underline is the fact that in France hem
culture went on in spite of American
prohibition while prohibiting marijuana
in the USA they prohibited H too and so
you couldn't grow it anymore in France
hemp growing went on France was a very
Ral Nation at the time and remained so
until the 50s they continue to cultivate
H there
today what happened was that synthetic
fibers went on to become a huge
development and even in France in a
country where Ham growing was still
legal H began to widely decline
until the H textile industry finally
died at the end of the 60s