we have another film clip we're going to
run right now this is an interview I did
with the driver of the hemp car Greg
Kyler he came through here about three
years ago the hip car was running on a
hundred percent hemp seed oil there was
no petroleum in the gas tank no
petroleum oil lubricating the engine it
was a hundred percent hemp driven car
and that's what we need to go back to in
the future and we'll be talking a bit
more about that just a moment hope you
enjoy this film clip
yep so how did you come to think of this
the hip car idea and this this national
tour you're doing well I was I wanted to
come out to the west coast and some kind
of environmental fashion and I've been
researching deals for a while it's never
really cared about came across can't
boil a transportation fuel and put two
and two together you know when was that
when did you ever back in October of
last year October last year right around
there and started asking you know how
come they took a look into the plant a
little more my nod not a drug still
falls under the DEA band so put two and
two together and decided that I had to
do it with your oil and so you're
getting hip oil from Ohio yeah it's
literally name from China on some from
Canada and then it's some of it comes
into a high or it's made new biodiesel
the John Ross chapter at the Ohio
and this retired swearingen of apple
energy who practices the oil for us into
biodiesel uh-huh what can you tell us
about the car to just normal car without
completely unmodified Mercedes these old
1983 turbo diesel any diesel engine can
rot burn any vegetable oil but you'll
get a longer engine life turning into by
people so that's what we're doing what
about your tour you started wearing
watching and DC july 4th big rally they
have their happy fourth of july at the
rally and took off from there I'll July
4th day we covered LLC today it's August
21st or 22nd Yeah right honor that's
about seven weeks we've been on the road
and uncover it at 6,400 miles six
thousand four hundred miles and how many
cities are you going to and tova make
we're going to about 50 cities in how
many days is that I sent about a little
over 90 days 50 cities in 90 days that's
ambitious yeah and that's a hundred
percent hemp fuel yep and what kind of
mileage do you get 27 miles to go on
just like the car came from the factory
floor and so it's being shipped to you
along the yet we have 12 like draw
points and we have our fuel ship ahead
and we pick up as much as we can carry
okay that was grand kryger with the hemp
car and that was running on a hundred
percent hemp seed oil now we're talking
you know the price of oil has gone
through the roof lately demand in the
United States continues to grow slowly
but the demand in India the demand in
China is doubling every year so they're
saying by the end of the year that the
price of oil is going to be a hundred
dollars a barrel well hemp seed oil can
compete at those prices and hip is
actually three times more productive
than any other seed oil crop so the
price of biodiesel come way down when we
can grow moderately high THC plants hemp
plants for biodiesel and that's what our
political committee is going to start
concentrating on a hip for biodiesel
initiative so we'll be talking more
about that in the weeks to come