sharing session tonight our our Show and
Tell we have uh several of our Museum
items from the hemp and cannabis uh
foundations uh collection of about 200
different medicinal canvas items and we
always bring out some things like this
this is hemp food that you can pick up
on the Internet or at health food stores
these are HED hemp seeds and HED hemp
seeds taste a lot like a cross between
cashews and walnuts and so if you like
nuts then I recommend HED hemp seeds
they taste really good you can get them
at health food stores right next door we
find a cannabis tinure this is an
alcohol extract from the 1890s from the
company sharpen Dome sharpen Dome was in
business up to the 7s I believe then
right next door to that we have two
different bottles one from the 1890s
another one from 1910 that uh are from
Eli Lily and both of these were
different types of tinctures they have
different numbers on them let's see this
is tinure Number 96 this is tinure
number 17 whatever that means anyway
next door we find from Mulford and
Company another cannabis tinure which is
a really Nifty thing so we have a whole
set of bottles with cannabis tincture
then this is one of my favorites it's
from specific medicines and this was a
bottle of American hemp they didn't even
call it cannabis in this case it means
the same thing folks hemp and cannabis
this is American hemp and what you'd
find in here are a bunch of marijuana of
flowers just like your you go to the and
and buy uh uh some flowers in the black
market back in the day which is like
1890 to 1920 you could buy these over
the counter at your Pharmacy American
hemp and it has the the the wording on
the side of these bottles is really
amazing we'll have to to go over that
again someday now this is a cannabis oil
extract it's a recent product these are
cannabis uh hemp seed oil and hempseed
oil is very nutritious it has all the
good fats that Wipe Out the bad fats and
once you press hip seeds you get a third
30% oil and what's left over is this
stuff hemp flour which is very high in
protein and very healthy now the thing
about hemp seed oil is it is the most
productive seed oil crop and not only is
it healthy for you but it will run any
diesel engine and so if we could run our
diesel engines on hemp seed oil then we
would have such a supply of this hemp
flour that it would wipe out world
hunger and I think we're going to do
that in the next 20 or 30 years once we
end adult cannabis prohibition finally
from the 1870s or 1880s we have a
cannabis tincture bottle that you would
have found in an old epoc are or
drugstore way back when