this is a circa nineteen twenty bottle
from eli lilly cannabis then right next
to it we have eighteen ninety bottle
this is actually still full and this is
Louise balsam for coughs to cough
medicine this box is in like five
different languages and it comes with
this insert that's in nine more so this
was a very useful medicine here's
another one from 1910 specific standard
medicines out of Illinois the Lloyd
brothers they sold many of these
medicines this is also a partially full
bottle this is an open box it still has
the the full bottle still inside right
next to it this bottle was dug up this
is a embossed bottle that says as you
can see dr. D H James's cannabis indica
so this was another medicine this is a
combination medicine it's a cannabis
with what else is it got lecithin and
lime and iron it has a little bit of
strychnine in it too I don't know why
they put that in their butts for nervous
prostration nervous exhaustion nervous
disability nervous excitement hysteria
and all depressed conditions of the
nervous system you read that right on
there so it was a widely used medicine
but most importantly we're still burning
our hip flame of freedom this is hip
seed oil burning a wick of hemp fiber
and this is why marijuana has made
illegal folks right here it's all about
money and power and energy they created
the whole marijuana myth to protect the
petrochemical pharmaceutical
military-industrial transnational crony
corporate elite ruling class and their
wealth [ __ ] yeah those those guys too
there you go and so here it is the hip
flame of freedom continues to burn
brightly here on cannabis common sense