I'm an occupational safety and health
professional I've worked in various
Industries including Aerospace
manufacturing nuclear pellet
manufacturing uh nuclear uh weapon
demilitarization Etc uh as a safety
professional over the years I looked at
various material safety data sheets I
found there is no threshold limit value
for marijuana there is no permissible
exposure limit for marijuana there is no
amount of marijuana they can consume
that will cause
death
ever since I read the book marijuana is
safer so why are we driving people to
drink by Steve Fox Paul arm andano Mason
vert with forward by retired Seattle
police chief Norm Stamper I've been
trying to spread the message that
marijuana is safer than
alcohol I see a lot of people in the
audience wearing safer
shirts you can see that some people make
their own safer shirts using stencils
that's part of what I do is I
legalizing marijuana is more important
than
me and as you can
see when you take the selfishness out of
it it can
grow some of the best pot I've ever seen
was not grown for selfish
reasons was growing for people who
needed
it ever since 5052 passed we have a
limited amount of
time where we can still grow our own and
share with Grandma it's okay Jared do it
so please call your lawmakers and tell
them to undo
5052 look at our 76 no we have a table
here we should have the initiative ready
to go soon
you don't have to collect as many
signatures on a referendum as you do on
a petition so that's nice they do have
to be printed on 11 by 17 double-sided
paper uh 20 signature sheets we may have
some three signature sheets or four
signature sheets with mail in
capabilities but yeah we need to undo
5052 call your lawmakers participate in
the
referendum we want hom grow thank you