we're going to start with something we
had last week as well it is a bottle of
Father
dialyses cough medicine here it is
Father deal it's actually a full bottle
this is Circa 1908 1910 it's right at 98
to 100 years old and this bottle
contains uh a cough remedy that's been
shown never to fail according to the
little letters on the side of the bottle
and it's opium
uh cannabis
indicia uh heroin alcohol and chloroform
and it's guaranteed never to fail it
probably just knock you out you be you
you want to make sure you don't take too
much or you won't even breathe you know
no less not cough but uh it is an
antique and it's part of the THCF
Medical Museum that you can see pictures
of some of this collection on the web
right next to it we have a uh under
glass bottle this is a a from AOC area a
drugstore Circ of the
1880s we have about a dozen bottles like
this in our collection next door we have
the Cannabis hemp oil seeds this is seed
oil highend the omega-3 6 and9 the LA
GLA and LNA oils that are essential to
our lives and cell formation I take six
or eight of these a day for the good
healthy fats now if you press hemp seeds
and get the seed oil out after you press
it you'll have this leftover hemp flour
hemp flour is a protein enrich
gluten-free whole grain flour that
imparts the Nutty flavor of hemp into a
wide variety of baked goods so we
recommend that then next door we have
hemp nuggets these are H hemp seeds they
taste like as we said earlier cross
between sunflower seeds walnuts and
cashews
they are good