um my other organization is a vote
victory over the enemy hey i like which
is the unregistered voter in the state
of california oh okay what we have to do
is upgrade our standard of voting we can
send people to the moon and we're
sending satellites into outer space
i believe that our system of voting in
this country is very uh adequate very
old it needs to be renewed and revised
and updated
i think that the vote voting should be
more important than christmas
okay i think that we should spend a lot
of money on educating the people look at
it this way the government
is in favor of the united states public
to vote
i feel that it's our duty to show them
or to find a way to help the government
find ways
to help people vote and i think with
television
the telephone
computer optics
and
and satellite dishes and all this
technology that we've got we should be
able to sit home
and vote on all these important issues
and i'm sure the government wants
everybody to vote
it's uh it's our constitutional right
and they and they stand behind it i
think that they should get behind us and
help us to get out there
and make voting a very important issue
it is important even if you are not in
favor of say the california marijuana
initiative of the hemp initiative
that's fine we would love for you to
come out and speak your opinion we want
you out there voting we want you to take
an active part in this country
if you do then i think this will solve
the problem