my name again again is Russ Carol I'm
head of the crop and soil science
department at Oregon State University
and what I'm going to do is spin off
from the product side of this and talk a
little bit about some of the production
uh realities as far as we know them at
this point in time uh here in Oregon and
what that may mean for hemp industry uh
in the state of Oregan and so trying to
align expectations at this point so
crops new crops alternate crops are
nothing new to the state of Oregon uh
we've got at last estimate over 220
different crops that are being grown
crops and natural resource uh products
across the state there's over a hundred
of those crops Commodities that have a
farm gate value of over a million
dollars so unlike other parts of the
nation where the Growers are faced with
very few cropping Alternatives we have
many choices in the the state and unlike
growers in some other parts of the
nation if you ask a grower here you
bring them something and say what do you
think about chory the questions they'll
ask are uh where can I get the seed what
do I know what do you can you tell me
about the production conditions how much
is it worth and when are you going to
pay me and from those four points people
can if it's something that is workable
they can pretty well figure it out and
see if it makes sense in our production
environment what I've done in the back I
don't know if everybody picked it up but
there's a handout that has far more
technical detail than most of you are
probably going to be interested in but
for those that are interested in
thinking about producing hemp I'd ask
you to pick a copy of that up and uh
take a look at some of the information
that's there the short story is that
hemp is a warm seasoned crop it would be
very similar to Sweet Corn soybeans
sunflower if you think about the wamit
valley and everybody goes well we grow
corn in the wamit valley but it's sweet
corn it's not grain corn there's very
little grain corn grown here very few
sunflowers very few soybeans and that's
because of the temperature regime that
we all love uh in Western Oregon and
across Oregon
we have a Mediterranean climate uh
rainfall comes during the winter months
and during the summer we have cool night
temperatures and moderate uh heat we
rarely of late we've been getting up
into the 90s and hundreds but generally
we expect that the summer temperatures
are going to be in the high
80s uh something like a corn plant uh
the optimum growing conditions for a
corn plant is if the nighttime
temperature Dr drops below 50° the plant
goes into physiological shock because
it's not designed to grow with its
physiology at temperatures that low uh
and the top end temperature for
something like grow corn is uh 86° so
it's got a fairly narrow range uh we
think that hemp has a wider range in
that we've not growing hemp here we've
not grown current varieties but we can
look at the information that's available
from other parts of the world and what
we find in most plant biology plant
physiology is that you don't change the
plant significantly there may be things
at the edges and that's what we're going
to have to look at the plants that are
well adapted uh to colder night
temperatures shorter growing Seasons uh
but at this point looking at the
information we can find from both Canada
and from Europe and trying to translate
that into into an Oregon context we're
going to be really hard pushed uh to
grow seeded hemp here in the mamit
valley uh the maturity the because of
the temperature regimes that we've got
you're going to be looking at
maturation uh in late September October
and if you're trying to uh mature a crop
dry a crop down you know what late
September and October is like fiber crop
may be much easier
depending on the varieties the the
maturity of the fiber occurs when the
male flowers on the plant have matured
so it's much earlier in the growing
season and there you'd be looking at
things in July August which make much
more sense uh so we may be able to
easily grow fiber crops the seeded crops
to getting both seed and fiber may be
more difficult and then the other thing
we have to think about is we enjoy our
dry Summers but if you're trying to grow
a crop uh during the summer and actively
grow that crop as the industrial hemp
would be growing you're going to need
water um and if you think about the corn
the green beans uh other crops that are
out in the valley in the summer months
they're being
irrigated and so you're going to have to
figure out if you're going to grow the
crop on large scale where are you going
to get the water from
and then the question that other large
commercial the current large commercial
Growers are going to ask is what's it
worth what are you going to pay me and
they're going to look at the production
economics of that do I put my water on
green beans do I put my water on sweet
corn which are very high value crops
versus something like
him so there are you know we need to
think about some of of those
possibilities now there are other parts
of the state we very successfully grow
corn in Hermiston Ontario you're further
Inland they still have a Mediterranean
climate but those are heat pockets as is
Southwestern Oregon so we very
successfully grow corn in the Hermon
area they set National yield records uh
for 300 325 bushel corn so you could
grow hemp in that environment very
easily but you're up against 300 bushel
corn at $5 a bushel at this point you're
up against potatoes carrots green beans
so again The Growers there are going to
look at what is this crop bring me
versus the value that I'm going to get
out of it in Rick's area we have grown
dry land corn in parts of the Columbia
Basin there's a experiment station
called the morrow experiment station and
they've grown Dryland corn uh for the
last four or five years and they're
getting about
3540 bushel corn you may have seen some
of that that Brian tuck had
out but again if you're getting 300
bushels in the irrigated area and you're
getting 3540 bushels in the Dryland area
you know again align expectations for
what you're looking at as far as uh
yields in those possible
situations so I guess as I think about
this we can do anything on small scales
if somebody is interested in growing a
crop in this state we've got a pliable
enough environment that you're going to
be able to grow what you want you're
going to have to figure out where you
get the water from you're going to have
to figure out how you can plant it early
and what you could do as far as
protecting uh the seed so that you can
get it planted and C capture early
season uh growing heat units uh there
are ways you can uh look at it but don't
assume that you're going to be able to
uh immediately once we've got it legal
to grow that it's immediately going to
move out into large scale production so
think about those things align
expectations appropriately and we'll be
in good
shape