aren't we in a pickle really it's a
limited to 0.3 and isn't there we don't
doesn't the department of side need to
be pushing the feds to kind of
mellow out and allow a broader
definition
so um the point three percent of THC
definition is actually not in federal
law the in federal law
um they don't define Industrial Hemp
from Cannabis as we've talked about
however it is in our state statute so as
the department of AG
it would have to be a legislative action
not an agency action
um I believe that the 0.3 percent in
you guys can probably talk about this
more better than I can but I believe
that that's
um kind of an industry standard for
industrial hemp because it cannot be
construed as having any value of the THC
to to use for drug purposes or
well yeah so just just a little quick
history and the standard was developed
in Europe and then in Canada and so it's
sort of been a de facto International
standard we didn't come up with that as
like you know unique we kind of said
okay this is what's working and the
Canadians and Europeans have been able
to develop a hemp industry around that
standard now does it limit you somewhat
uh yeah I might you know I mean is there
a variety of hemp that you know has half
a percent THC that might be better yeah
it might be and that might be something
we need to take a look at down the line
will we ever see a situation where
farmers are going hemp at five or ten
percent THC I seriously doubt it because
you're talking about psychoactive
varieties that somebody could pull out
of the field and you know smoke so I
think that you have to make a
distinction there between generally the
internationally it's it's recognized as
above one percent you get into varieties
that then have psychoactive potential
when you're talking about the THC so but
um I you know I wouldn't disagree with
you that it might be nice to have a
little bit higher or have the
flexibility to be able to say hey maybe
you know Ohio them through tents but it
is kind of what what it is
there's a number of crops that have
other
levels so something like canola has to
be below
two percent uricic acid so it's it's not
versus industrial
rape seeds so it's not uncommon to have
these kind of biological limits in there
are seed certification systems both in
Europe Canada here in the U.S that once
you've got varieties
that are known to have these low levels
to maintain those is not a problem you
can do cross breeding among the
varieties that are low
in the THC levels and you should be able
you know there may be the occasional
variety that would be useful or may have
some useful characteristic through
traditional plant breeding you can
oftentimes
take something like that breed it into
your low
lines and breed something that has the
new characteristic using standard
breeding techniques
uh when I lived in Northern Illinois
before I moved here there were still
acreage and some of them at State Park
of hemp fields that was left over from
World War II do we not have any research
data on growing hemp for those years
that might help us as we look at this
new era of gloriousness yeah we to
answer your second question the first
the we do actually the the picture that
Errol showed of the 15-foot Hall tall
hemp plants in Arlington that was
actually a USDA researcher named
Leicester Dewey who grew up in Arlington
Farms which is now where the Pentagon is
located in our
Virginia and uh he's he we've actually
got his Diaries uh you know he had
published a lot of research on it so we
had a lot of historical stuff and I
noticed that Rick has a great book here
too by Chris Conrad called hope Lifeline
the future there's some other books out
there it's not you know super technical
on the growing side but there is a lot
of historical information out there um
and
there are bulletins there were the USDA
and others other states did research
bulletins back in the 40s so that kind
of information is available
report there was a USDA and research
service reading program in Wisconsin had
been here in Oregon
down in Corvallis and Albany and they
pulled it out in the late 1930s and
moved it to Wisconsin because conditions
were better there
unfortunately as we went through this
whole craze in the 40s and 50s they
dumped all the germ plasm so
historically where material was put into
a national germ classroom repository
there's none of that
present these days but there are
international seed sources
has any thought been given through the
organization as they have
foreign
carbon
yeah so the carbon sequestration is
definitely uh you know I mean that's
that's a that's a fact and the the
building with uh hemp herd where they're
basically locking it into you know
mixing it with lime and then and then
that actually sequesters carbon and the
research they did over in the UK on that
shows that there's actually more carbon
captured in the construction process
than what's not released so it's a
carbon negative construction process so
that's pretty incredible and actually I
think that's going to be a huge market
for hemp once we get it grown here it
doesn't make any sense to import a herd
is sunlight and bulky it's just burning
towards that from overseas or whatever
it makes no sense but once you're
growing in here you can build homes you
know and uh right here and they're
extremely good thermal properties
there's another other benefits it's uh
because it's using alignment the mold
you don't have any problems with mold I
don't know if that's a big issue here in
Oregon but I think with your letter
climate that it might be a big
significant thing so so there's some
real advantages there and as far as the
fuel goes I just think that uh the the
jury's still out I mean there's two ways
you can get fuel from Health that I know
of anyways but maybe there's more so I'm
not an expert I don't claim to be an
expert on the field but I know the hemp
seed I think it's too high value to be
realistic as a mainstream fuel sources
maybe somebody's going to do it on their
Farm or something but then the biomass
conversion you know there's been
research some research on that but that
still isn't fully commercialized except
like with maybe sugarcane and Brazil or
something so they haven't gotten there
yet but that's definitely potential
so seed is a part of the statute in
Oregon and it directs the Department of
Agriculture to write rules about the
handling of seeds as well as the growing
um and selling of seeds so we have
regulations already in Oregon actually
of course seed dealers any any
agricultural or vegetable seed producer
or dealer has to be licensed by the
State Department of Agriculture and that
will fall under a similar licensing
process so that will be something that
will come out in the rules
develop them
um
the second the third question I'm sorry
was um about potential
cross-contamination
um and we have OSU sitting on our panel
and we'll hope that they can give us
some guidance there
um because the statute sets the limit at
0.3 percent that's one of the things
that I mentioned we'll have to talk
about
um what are the tolerances and and how
we will determine that and we don't know
I don't think
um I've seen some research or heard that
the cross-contamination having two
Fields next to each other could actually
damage potentially both not only
um you know the THC level that you might
be shooting for for medical purposes but
also
um keeping the other one under point
three but I'm not a researcher and don't
know that
um so it will certainly be something
that we'll have to look into
um
I don't right now this tattoo doesn't
direct us to have control areas
we'll have to work through that that's
uh gets into quite a bit of different
other laws in terms of
right to farm and that kind of stuff we
do have the Farm Bureau sitting on our
world's advisory committee they're
they're usually involved in those right
to farm issues and so hopefully they can
advise us
it's typically down you know in a
situation like this is there are
generations of seed that are produced so
you start with something called breeder
seed or Foundation seed and there would
be very specific isolation requirements
for where that seed could be grown and
then as you go through the generations
those tend to ease up a bit but
oftentimes the commercial crop is not
harvested for subsequent seed use and so
you could have what would be called
Foundation registered seed the certified
seed would be sold commercially produced
so even there if there were some small
level of contamination it's not going to
carry into the next generation of the
crop but would have to figure out what
are the isolation distances that you
need to have and then it would be up to
those people to work with their
neighbors to make sure if they're
producing early Generation seed that
they didn't have medical marijuana
those areas to try to keep the THC under
control