so uh just a little about Whole Foods
Market you may be familiar with us we
have a few stores here in the metro area
when we evaluate a product we we run it
through our core values so at this point
I think we have eight eight core values
we sell the highest quality naal organic
foods does hemp qualify yes we create
ongoing win-win Partnerships with our
suppliers we have awesome suppliers who
provide us with hemp we support team
member excellence and happiness H makes
us happy excellent we Serb we serve and
support our local and Global communities
well uh looks like the state of Oregon
wants us to support them we create
wealth through profits and growth I'll
go into a little bit more of that and
yes hemp eal hemp can be profitable we
practice an advanced environmental
stewardship hemp is a sustainable crop
is non- genetically modified we satisfy
delight and nourish our customers
affirmative hemp and we promote the
health of our stakeholders through
Health eating education yes hemp is also
healthy like my little organ hemp uh
logo there yeah I did it on PowerPoint
this
morning why hemp well you you probably
all know this preaching to the choir
here hemp functions as a nutritional
Powerhouse uh it's a complete protein
I've been vegan and vegetarian for parts
of my life I'm not now but when I was
hemp was a major source of protein it's
a much better source of protein than
almond or other nuts uh and it's a lot
more digestible and healthy than soy um
also has healthy fats complete profile
fatty acids it's got Vitamin E for
immunity and plenty of dietary fiber
tastes good too and this is also one of
our displays from our last hemp history
week promotion featuring products it
looks like
from Living Harvest and matova harvest
lots of hemp leaves so um you've
probably seen stuff like this this is
sort of the market justification there's
a lot of stuff you can do with hemp we
you know those tables out there from
hemp Industries Association and their
allies kind of show that um so you have
hemp seeds hemp
stalks when um I Heard uh Congressman
Lum hour mentioned uh about a half a
billion dollars I I think that's uh
radically underestimated just from how
much I know we sell and then going out
to our competitors uh seeing you know
two pound bags of hemp seeds at Costco
now um going to farmers markets and
seeing hemp everywhere I I estimate that
number is a lot higher um and that does
not even scratch the surface of Market
potential when you look at all the
things you could do with it did you know
that cars currently have hemp uh parts
now a lot of imported cars I didn't
until
recently so hemp at Whole Foods we got
about 90 brands that currently use hemp
ingredients mostly from uh Canada um
about 300 products on on or off we don't
really have very good data at Whole Food
so it's our estimate as my friend
Christina would know uh right now it's
about 25% annual growth um so that's
that's a multiple of uh three or four of
our own company growth it's one of our
top growing Trends right now and um it
has been like that for the last 3 to
four years and it's also the core
ingredient in growth brand so you got
all these awesome uh companies that are
utilizing hemp a couple more recent
items including a really great veggie
burger from a uh Kansas called Hillary's
she's got a hemp Burger um I saw a hemp
tofu that we're working on instead of
soybean tofu it's going to be a tofu so
um we've got a lot of products that we
can D be derived obviously soap and
cleaning products is a big big thing
non-dairy beverages hemp as a nutmilk um
you know for cereal for B making uh
cereal snacks and bars Nature's Path has
done a fabulous job with marketing hemp
in their products uh vegetarian meat and
protein sources so not just um you know
for protein shakes uh as an alternative
to whey or soy uh but also like I said
in uh meat Alternatives and uh you know
burgers and hot dogs and tofu Etc I've
actually seen hemp yogurt um not sure if
we've commercialized it yet it wasn't
that good but we're working on
it uh essential fatty acids and culinary
oils um and then you know St I don't
necessarily selling groceries textiles
and apparel um and then finally talking
to our construction team about utilizing
hemp creete uh we actually did a
promotion on a hemp as a concrete Source
in Colorado this summer during our hemp
history week um and they were showing
off like you know it's like cinder
blocks made out of hemp I have no
idea um so see these are some of the
brands that we've worked really closely
with uh I think we're doing H first
threee promotions now for about three
years and every year I think we've
gotten better at it um that's big uh
thanks to uh Christina vasei and the
Broner hooks but also these other brands
Living Harvest Manitoba Harvest natur's
path and newa and that is a display um
like they say everything's bigger in
Texas that is a Texas siiz temp display
out of the B Store in Houston uh really
great grocery team leader there um who
really gets behind the
stuff and this is a picture uh from the
USDA I believe this is uh in Arlington
in Virginia and those are hemst stocks
and so I can't wait to go visit Rick's
Farm to see him standing by 15t tall hem
stocks next
year Rick I'd like that exclusive on
your
product we'll talk about that so two
2013 our hemp history week promo about
880 events uh this is more than even
just the Whole Foods uh up to 300% sales
lift I don't want to bore you with
numbers here but I think we do over a
million in sales in like two weeks on
hemp products that included hemp and
then all the other stuff that you guys
today about 20 States um 10,000
signatures it's just it's growing you
know it's uh it's going to happen and
then uh internally we just did a lot of
PR we um the last years have had some
really good uh blogs social media um
insource signage marketing demos a lot
of customer engagement folks really get
behind we're really excited about it you
know our team members building displays
uh doing demos and uh talking to
customers about all this stuff so leads
me to uh say to you folks what the hemp
are we waiting for
and um that is a I don't know if you
call it a sprig of hemp from Colorado I
did get to attend the first of legal
domestic industrial cultivation of hemp
in South Eastern Colorado it was an
incredible experience and that hemp did
taste good so thank you so much