and what have we learned from Colorado
and Washington and what have these two
states done especially well or poorly
from what you've
seen sure I think that uh in Washington
uh the bill was fairly poor it doesn't
allow people to grow their own it does
it Limits The Possession to an ounce if
you have uh over 28 gram in Washington
you're have a misdemeanor if you have
over 40 GRS you'll go to jail so this is
dramatically better than that and uh in
Colorado they have a particularly
onerous system of Regulation that
requires video cameras on the grow site
from seed to sale with a video feed to
the state store it's definitely over
regulated uh we've seen prices of $7 and
$800 an ounce in Washington and uh
several hundred an ounce in Colorado
we're not going to wipe out the black
market those prices folks I think uh
initiative 53 will do that and uh a $35
an ounce tax is certainly reasonable and
I think it's a lot
better