you're representing this this new
initiative drive up in in Washington
state to basically remove all penalties
from Cannabis possession and and uh use
sales transport cultivation all the laws
against cannabis right what's the
process you got to go through in
Washington now what do you do well the
initiative process we need to get
251,000 valid signatures from voters
okay but the reason it's going to work
is the language follows uh initiative 61
from 1923 in New York that ended
prohibition Statewide 10 years before
the rest of the country and it just
doesn't conflict with federal law
because we don't create any uh
regulation or any language at all that
that could be preemptive federally MH
and it just simply removes State
penalties civil and criminal so uh a lot
of people say well you know they change
the laws all the time up there but what
we're really doing is we're creating an
opportunity for the legislature to step
up and listen to the citizens of how
they want that's right uh cannabis
regulated and taxed and what what length
of time do you have to gather those
signatures in we are going to file our
initiative in January uh we should have
our paper hit the street in February we
have until June 30th you have a a a time
period where you have to clear things
like through the state attorney general
or through the you know whatever
Department we will file early January
then uh they have 14 days to research it
okay we filed this already as initiative
1068 in 2010 MH uh we grew as an
organization and uh it it was all
Grassroots we didn't have any paid
gatherers uh some paid gatherers were
out there working for us some were out
there using us uh for their own benefit
and didn't turn their signatures in but
we're going to avoid that we've got uh
over 6,000 people this year that have
expressed an interest in helping out and
if that's the case and only half of them
uh step up and make a commitment then
that means we need 100 each for uh over
5 months period so basically if
everybody gets one signature a day and
only half the people that commit do it
we're on the ballot so you have a
five-month period you have to get this
in okay we're shooting for 420 uhhuh so
is that an initiative that's directly to
the people or is that an initiative to
the legislature I know in Washington
there is this other process there that
it gives you a little bit longer period
of time to collect signatures it does
give you a year but then the legislature
can also uh create a competing
initiative right like okay the citizens
say this but we say this so you really
split the vote that way with an
initiative to the people you're really
give the chance to say this is what we
really want and uh the numbers will show
it the the the response from the public
as time went on and they became aware a
lot of people didn't even know we were
out there but when they found out we
were out there it's like where have you
been I want to sign this m and they want
it to pass so if people want to contact
the campaign what's the best way for
them to do so yeah sensible
washington.org is our website uh there's
right now our website's in transition
from the barebones that we have left
over from uh last year we are working on
a really awesome new website that's
going to have a lot of information it's
going to be directed at the undecided
voters I mean we know that our True
Believers are going to support and vote
for us and we know that the the people
that absolutely will never support us uh
there's no Spence sense spending any
time on them yeah so we're going to aim
for the people in the middle that are
worried about their children how will
this affect their children they're
worried about the economy how is the
$150 million we a year we save from not
arresting 14,000 people in Washington
going to affect the economy and how is
having them back at work instead of
prison going to affect the
economy this will also cover hemp
Industrial Hemp so we're expecting that
the hundred million uh Market that
Washington Imports to make products here
uh can be grown here and that'll be
green jobs here in America right here in
Washington mhm all right