so what is the actual state right now Dr
rebec of medical marijuana here in
Oregon
well what's going on right now is that
um a person who wants to use medical
marijuana and another words has a
disease
process uh which includes wasting
disease of AIDS multiple
sclerosis
glaucoma and uh some people even use it
for various and sunry types of pain
problems and um there is
virtually uh in in particular in regard
to pain pain is so subjective that
there's no way for somebody to
measure uh the degree of pain or the
intensity of pain or even the relief of
pain or anything else there just there
just no way to do this but if a person
says I have a bad back or I have a bad
this or a bad that and I'm in pain and
uh that uh smoking marijuana helps I I
don't think that anybody should deny
them the right to use that now what's
going on in Oregon at the present time
is that people who who are using
marijuana for medical purposes have to
get some sort of a letter from a
physician which
says uh marijuana will alleviate the the
problem pain or whatever it might be for
this individual this letter is sent to
the uh uh Oregon Health
division uh Dr Grant
higginson is the person who uh who is
the U I guess U he's not the director of
the Oregon Health division but he's a
number two person there and and the
number one person is not a physician but
he is so he is the one who to whom these
letters are addressed and he is the one
who will issue the equivalent of a
marijuana user's license now the strange
thing about it is that it is still a
federal offense to in many respects
about the use of marijuana so no at the
present time nobody knows what's going
to happen but this hasn't prevented
people who get uh benefit from the use
of marijuana from using it there are an
estimated 100,000 people in the United
States right now who admit to using it
for medical purposes and there are
probably as I understand at around 10
people 10 million people excuse me who
who uh use marijuana recreationally
now this is I think the so-called
recreational use of this is a kind of a
poor term because I don't think people
smoke tobacco for recreational purposes
I I I I I I I don't I don't know why
people smoke tobacco but whether it's
for recreational purposes or whatever it
is this is a sort of a strange uh
terminology that that is
used uh so it's like when they use
alcohol that's social drinking or
something right well I suppose that
that's that's true I've never heard of
the social recreational use of alcohol
yeah recreation use of alcohol and the
social use of marijuana so the the the
terminology here is very very obscure or
muddied or whatever the right word is
imprecise at the least absolutely now I
think one of the strangest things about
this is that the federal government
raises marijuana yes in Mississippi the
federal government has it
harvested and processed to make
marijuana cigarettes and there are eight
people in the United States who have uh
letters of permission from the U Drug
Enforcement
Administration to use marijuana for
their medical
purposes now if eight people can use it
for medical purposes for relief of their
medical problem why can't nine or 10 or
a thousand use it so it it's it's a very
very strange
situation and uh a year and a half ago I
was one of six doctors who testified at
the American Medical Association
Convention uh
for
for the American Medical
Association to uh stand behind the
rights of patients to use marijuana for
medical
purposes and this was passed by the
house of delegates of of the American
Medical Association in
Dallas um
the headquarters of the American Medical
Association
has I don't know whether the word is
they've sat on their hands or sat on
their heads or whatever they've done but
they haven't done anything about it and
uh we six doctors have uh written a
letter to the Journal of the American
American Medical
Association uh as the equivalent of a
letter to the editor asking why hasn't
the American uh Medical Association
taken a stand on this well the first
letter we wrote uh they sent back that
we're sorry but we're rejecting it
because we have too many other things to
print in the magazine or something like
that and then about 6 weeks ago the
American what what is it The Institute
of medicine Institute of medicine The
Institute of medic Academy of Science
from the National Academy of Science
came out uh very highly publicized
throughout the United States that there
was considerable evidence that marijuana
was good for certain medical medical
problems and
um uh the American Medical Association
has been strangely quiet about this but
in view of the Institute of medicine we
six doctors again wrote a letter to the
American Medical Association and the
Journal of the American Medical
Association
say The Institute of medicine says that
it has some benefit in medical purposes
and why should um why should people who
use it be thrown in jail for using it
for medical reasons so um as somebody
pointed out a few minutes ago we are at
the cutting AE edge of this and uh with
the vote U I guess the last two
elections we had for medical for us
medical marijuana yeah November of 98
here in Oregon and Washington and uh
Arizona Arizona they voted on it for the
second time they originally voted in uh
1996 along with California to legalize
medical
marijuana and I think I think if I
understand right there are Six States
who have passed initiatives is that what
it is or yes six and then uh that's not
counting the District of Colombia where
uh the United States Federal Congress
has not allowed that vote to be counted
exit poll showed that it passed with
72% but uh an amendment to an
Appropriations writer by Georgia
Representative Bob bar uh defunded the
county of that vote and said that the
District of Columbia cannot count the
vote on medical marijuana that was on
their ballot well so Dr Beck I mean
Florida state is there every day you
know we find out new information about
drugs that existed for a long time I
mean it's not like the book is closed
you know once they come out with a drug
at the first place well I think it's
very interesting that we know
from historical records that that can
cannabis has been used for literally
thousands of
years and nobody has ever reported any
bad effects from the use of it yeah and
and when you compare that to Tobacco or
to alcohol MH uh there's absolutely no
comparison between between tobacco
alcohol and marijuana they're just
absolutely none
whatsoever and and uh the statement that
um that marijuana is a gateway drug to
heroin or cocaine or whatever uh this
was uh verbally thed by The Institute of
medicine that said there was no evidence
whatsoever that this was the case so um
I think I think the main thing that
we're doing is supporting General
mccaffery and a whole bunch of DEA
agents who are making very high salaries
and don't want to give up the the the
game as you might might say so the
people that are making money uh on the
marijuana issue are the DEA agents and
the people who grow and sell
marijuana uh and don't uh don't pay any
taxes on any aspect of of the money that
they make and if they're
caught they get sent to a federal prison
where it costs at least $40,000 a year
to keep them in prison so I guess the
federal prison
uh the guards in the prisons are
probably also recipients of a lot of
money from the marijuana business so
it's really a straight strange
absolutely bizarre situation that that
uh this has gone on and I can't
understand why some of these uh
politicians in Washington DC and
elsewhere can't see this or understand
it or whatever the right word is I don't
I don't understand it