we roughly estimate that about a third
of the people are receiving letters of
recommendation and approval for
primarily emotional or mental problems
and that cannabis is a unique
psychotropic in this context in that it
has effects on both cognition and affect
that also are inextricably connected
with any different kinds of physical
functioning for example with anorexia
people get inadequate nutrition because
of their anxiety causing a suppression
of the appetite and that when they
receive cannabis the nutrition is
improved because the peristalsis and the
spasm the spasm is relieved peristalsis
is promoted so also evacuation which
then produces improved mood and improved
functioning with regard to cognition
this also includes the people with
thought disorders and you might find
this kind of unusual but there are
certain aspects of cognitive functioning
that cannabis helps like suppressing or
decreasing obsessive thinking and also
paranoid ideation and paranoid
delusional thought interestingly the
short-term memory-loss people experience
when they acutely medicate with usually
inhaled cannabis they can't hold a
paranoid delusion long
and the same goes for
obsessive-compulsive disorder because
they can't keep up this string of
pathologic associations also the
modulation of effect also affects the
cognitive behavior with decreased
anxiety this decreases the pressure for
this abnormal type of thought I believe
that a new category is warranted the
cannabis fits and that's easement if you
look that up in the dictionary you'll
see several meanings and one of the main
meanings is giving ease not the property
legalistic kind of the passage or going
on to some property and getting certain
rights but easement as a calming effect
and this is what I believe cannabis more
closely approximates it's not the same
as a benzodiazepine which produces
sedation and ironically depression Allah
there is no free lunch pharmacologically
so people do not like the
benzodiazepines and other sedatives for
these kinds of reasons and cannabis
helps restore emotional response civet e
in a normal way and this also goes along
with people with their paranoid ideation
and disturbance of interpersonal
relationships with certain people with
thought disorder they note that they are
more able to relate to others which then
improves their self esteem and their
social functioning in there you're never
going to find this written anywhere
because of the
the psychiatric literature being
horribly biased and I've looked through
the APA publications going back maybe 70
years and it all is painted with the
anti-social element and causing calling
it the dysfunctionality or character
defect or other kinds of pejorative
condemnatory terms and it's all bill
pushing it's all medication and to that
end we really don't know what is
happening and this extends not just to
psychotropics but I'm going to read you
a short letter to John a kitzhaber MD
director Center for evidence-based
policy mmm Oregon Health and Science
University and this is who I suggest if
you want to contact to embarrass a
little bit on February 25th I happen to
view a panel presentation by your
organization on c-span on the cost
benefits study of different
pharmaceuticals contracted by AARP the
sum total of that that panel was they
could not develop any cost benefits
analyses because in analyzing in the
pharmaceutical literature they
discovered it was all promotional rather
than objective and scientific so
everything masquerading as science is
not so based upon California clinical
experience with a range of chronic
conditions our findings indicating the
significant advantage over other
pharmaceuticals conventionally utilized
because of improved quality of life and
fewer adverse effects consequently we
request the opportunity to discuss our
findings with you attached is
a list of conditions and guess what the
response was so I'm glad this is going
over to cable TV in the Portland area
and hopefully on some of the out there
and the viewing audience and can give
the senator a call and ask them to
include cannabis and their studies and
especially about the mental health issue
I would be fascinated to hear the
response but I won't hold my breath
may I interject just very briefly
there's research I'm sure you guys are
all aware of about the synergistic
effects of the receptor effects of
opiates and cannabinoids where they
basically are hitchhiking with each
other and small much smaller doses of
both medications create the same benefit
with of course much less side effects so
these are really remarkable findings and
and I really regret that there aren't
physicians who are just monitoring the
reduction in the prescription patterns
of their patients if they doubt that
cannabis is useful you think that's new
if you read marijuana medical papers in
the Ohio State Medical Society meeting
on cannabis in 1860 a doctor from
deliver from Ohio reported that using an
alternative alternating courses of
opiates and cannabis for treating
chronic condition conditions reduced
dependence on opiates 1859 this was
written and so you know this is
something new now we're talking about
the takeover by big farm and ruining
policy through their special interest
money and furthermore the fact that this
whole system this MA
can I use the my fake oh why not
monomolecular mercantile madness this is
all patent office driven if you look
back to what it was before the single
molecule ascended to its role in current
commercial medicine you'll see that it's
all secondary to what can get patented
and then they claim that the newly
patented materials increasingly better
blah blah blah but then you see what's
happened to the literature it's gotten
thoroughly corrupted and perverted so
that you don't know what's happening and
here we have now a drug seeking drug
hunger in public convinced they need all
sorts of combinations of patentable
materials and this and that's really
sickening our society and when they
started directly advertising to the
public for psychotropics especially ask
your doctor social anxiety disorder all
these these kinds of influences to
influence you and their bottom line any
other questions