it's not only good for our health and
safety it's good because it creates jobs
and by legalizing hemp
in particular we create a whole industry
because hemp is really a gold mine of
resources
and as a doctor and as a nutrition um
wonk you know i can
testify that there are incredible
nutritional
values to hemp there are a whole set of
fatty acids that are really critical for
our health that are not otherwise widely
available so there are very important
nutritional and food values to hemp as
well as potential as fuel
its value agriculturally is especially
important in this day and age of climate
change where we have drought we have
heat and all that
and where the costs of fossil fuels are
skyrocketing fortunately with hemp it's
a really stable crop you don't need uh
you don't need to irrigate you don't
need fossil fuel based pesticides and
you don't need fossil fuel derived
fertilizers either so it's you know it's
a really important crop especially in
this day and age of climate change and
likewise it's a really important
resource for manufacturing and henry
ford in fact you know made entire
automobiles out of hemp mercedes-benz
still uses hemp as part of the um
i think the panels in their
manufacturing process so you know not to
mention its uses in fiber
as well so they're just a whole bunch of
manufacturing uses for hemp it can be
grown locally it can be grown by small
farmers
so this is a valuable resource that that
the american people should not be
deprived of because of obsolete laws