we have a little interview with the
other chief petitioner Paul and I are
both chief petitioners on the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act but our other chief
petitioner is dr. Phillip Levesque a
professor retired professor of
pharmacology and toxicology that taught
up here at the current OHSU also taught
at Georgetown University and a number of
other universities around the world so
without any further ado here's an
interview with dr. Levesque down at our
Portland Saturday market booth you're
welcome to come down and sign our
petition the Oregon cannabis Tax Act and
today we have one of our chief
petitioners at our booth dr. Phillip
Levesque dr. Levesque is a retired
professor of pharmacology and a lobbyist
for AARP the American Association of
Retired Persons hello doctor tell us why
you decided to be a chief petitioner to
regulate the sale of marijuana to adults
and allow doctors to prescribe it
through pharmacies I practice medicine
and Molalla and I found out either
directly or indirectly that many of my
patients were not only used in my
prescriptions for the control of pain
but they were also smoking marijuana so
I did an investigation of my own and
found out that marijuana has been used
for thousands of years and very
effectively for a whole variety of
different kinds of problems would you
tell us what your credentials are I have
a PhD in pharmacology and I'm an
osteopathic doctor I taught pharmacology
and toxicology for approximately 30
years all right well we really thank you
again for being a chief Tichenor we need
people with your types of credentials to
sign on is there anything you'd like to
tell our our television audience sign
this petition and get this back on the
ballot we had two votes to make
marijuana
available for medical purposes it's time
that the hip hypocrisy quit and we make
it available not only for medical
purposes but also for recreational
purposes which it is being used for
right now but a person who uses for
recreational purposes and is caught by
the police can lose his home his car his
bank accounts any of his assets that he
had this will correct that well thank
you again appreciate it all right thanks