when the Vietnam guys started coming
back uh to the VA and they would send
him to a psychiatrist and the psychiatr
would say to you well so you've been
playing Cowboys and Indians over there
someplace and uh now you want some sort
of sympathy or something a prescription
for Valium for two weeks and you'll be
all over it guess what happened it
didn't work they got them hooked to
valum they popped them in the nose for
the Valium but at the same time they
they they give the veterans morphine
like drugs anti-depressant type drugs
Valium like drugs and and uh it causes
uh the veterans to turn into alcoholics
or suicide or some sort of crimes or
another and the Veterans Administration
is literally destroying right now 2.5
million people who who fought in Iraq
and Afghanistan 2 and a half million and
and they're just they're wrecking them
absolutely we're talking about medical
marijuana
and PTSD and and PTSD AB absolutely and
and I estimate that they're probably
about 1 million of the veterans of
recent Wars who have
PTSD uh and at least half of them above
a scale of five and those are the ones
who are desperately in need of of
marijuana therapy those those are those
are the ones the ones who are less than
five can probably get by on something
less than marijuana but marijuana is the
best drug we have found so far for the
treatment of PTSD and within the last
month I just wrote a
article that that marijuana prevents
PTSD suicides and I got about a thousand
comments on from all over the country
well you know I was in the military but
I didn't see combat but I I uh uh do
know as a marijuana user that uh when I
smoke marijuana I don't have dreams yeah
and when I quit using marijuana after a
couple of days I start to have some very
vivid dreams so
obviously marijuana will that that is
that is one of the worst symptoms of
PTSD and you probably wouldn't imagine
what the second most important symphon
is what's that not being able to talk
about what was your worst experience
uhhuh tell me about your worst
experience bam uh uhuh uhhuh so did you
feel that way after World War II I know
you went through a lot of very traumatic
experiences in fighting your way into
Germany meeting up with the Russians
there my first day I was I was u i was
committed to
combat I I got uh I got in an artillery
artillery barrage that just blew the
hell out of this little town where I was
and the next day they hit me with a with
a mortar barrage and when when we
crossed the Ry River I got strafed by
German planes I got strafed by American
planes we lost 150 men in less than an
hour out of how many 150 out out of our
Battalion and Battalion is what about th
about a, so 150 out of a, that's pretty
heavy attrition rate 15% in an hour we
had
the my Battalion my division had the
worst casualties crossing the Ryan River