thank you for tuning in joining us today
is the leader of California's normal Del
garinger and he has quite a fight on his
hands dealing with a variety of changes
that are occurring in his State and with
it being one of the largest states in
the United States I think maybe it is
the largest Texas might be in there uh
he has uh the need to find more members
and the need to get a message out to the
rest of America uh thank you for joining
us today um now the politics that
California normal focuses on focuses a
lot when it comes to at least the hemp
movement on the medical aspects isn't
that correct well we have with the
recent victory in San Francisco with
proposition P has put that to the
Forefront the question is what public
figures do we have out there who are
willing to pick up the ball when 80% of
the people of San Francisco say it's
time for a change on the issue really
it's amazing how our politicians have
been pussyfooting about it but I was was
very happy to see that the city
officials of San Francisco including the
leading candidates for mayor mayor egnos
and former police chief Frank Jordan and
other City officials have expressed
nothing but support for proposition p
and not only that we found that by
putting proposition P out there we were
able to give them an issue that they
felt good about supporting that they
didn't have to run and hide from now I
think it's time to bring that out to
some of the other uh leaders in
California particularly in the
legislature and in Congress and get the
ball
rolling now uh you've come out to uh
nation's capital uh shortly after was
only been like 3 4 days since prop P
passed hasn't been very long it's been a
week yeah going be a week so you've
arrived here just as quickly as the
message that that message that that that
proposal being passed sent to to our
nation's capital
how do you think Congress and the Senate
is starting to react to this you think
it's going to take the attention of
national candidates and it will be it
remains to be it's up to us we're going
to actually have to go to Capitol Hill
where I was the other day and I'm going
again on Monday and I think other people
have to be doing that too talking to
their Congress people and urging them to
take a position on this issue in fact
one of the key leaders in all of
Congress and among the Democrats on the
issue of medical marijuana is an
important legislator from California
Henry Waxman from Los Angeles who has uh
I must say had a very good record in in
voting against uh repressive drug
legislation uh he's been in a minority a
very small minority of people who have
opposed who've actually voted no on
these crime bills that come down like
the latest ninus crime Bill uh and he is
also uh the head of the health and
environment subcommittee that deals with
uh how what Got Drugs how drugs get
regulated FDA drugs and Health and Human
Services which is making the decision on
medical marijuana I think it behooves us
to tell to to to tell Mr Waxman I hope
his constituents will tell him that they
would appreciate it uh if he started uh
call holding hearings on the issue of
medical marijuana uh because I I think
by doing so uh he would have the
opportunity to really uh uh score some
important some important points that
have to be scored and uh affect some
change very quickly because there will
be popular support for this and there's
no reason that he shouldn't uh undertake
it so we we hope that people will talk
to Waxman and others urging this kind of
thing okay now you and I being together
from California I'm not native there I'm
native from Indiana but I spent the last
four or five years living in the state
know that uh smoke a joint lose your
license seems to have some importance to
that state and we are we got to deal
with that that's right it's on the
agenda California has got to act on
smoke a joint lose your license by
October 1993 or we start losing Federal
Highway funds can they do what can they
do well we've got two options we either
an smoke a joint lose your license which
is an automatic six-month driving
license suspension for any drug offense
any drug offense including personal
possession of marijuana regardless of
whether it's on the road or not
or we can reject it by a joint
resolution of the legislature and the
governor okay now the legislature does
not care for smoke a joint L your
license as does the majority of
California public and all informed
opinion in California the Sacramento B
the San Jose Mercury have editorialized
against this uh there's nobody I've
heard yet who's spoken up in favor of it
other than I believe the Orange County
Board of Supervisors so then why is it
still in existence but we have
because the legislature has to get
agreement from the governor on what to
do now we have a governor who announced
that he was in favor of Rec
criminalizing Marijuana and so the
universal assumption has been well gee
Pete Wilson is going to veto any attempt
to pass an override resolution to smoke
a joint Los your license uh we think
that Pete Wilson's position is very ill
informed he really hasn't thought
through the costs of this proposal
because you're going to have thousands
tens of thousands of marijuana offenders
who now you know get a ticket for
smoking a joint in the park are going to
be coming you fighting driver's license
suspension I mean they're going to get
lawyers they're going to get trials
public defenders I mean this is going to
cost the state tens of millions of
dollars and it is so stupid everyone
realizes it is so stupid to give six
months driver's license suspension for
somebody who has a joint in their purse
uh in the airport and and yet you can
drive drunk and get only a four Monon
driver's license suspension in
California I mean which is worse really
yeah but if they enact the uh the tax
situation that they've got on the uh
marijuana or oh with the tax issues is a
separate issue whether they should also
put a penalty tax on that's been beaten
back and I don't expect it to come back
we we did have to fight it uh Senator
Davis had a proposal in which he's head
in for many years to put a controlled
substances tax on so if they catch you
with drugs of any kind they could say
all right well you didn't pay the tax
and the tax was going to be $500 per
ounce $500 per ounce of crack $500 per
ounce of LSD $500 per ounce of marijuana
but they W $500 was not really what
you'd pay because that was the tax only
if you paid it in advance if they caught
you not having paid it which is what
they fully expected then there would be
a penalty and it would be $55,000 an
ounce you see and Ed Davis admitted
himself this is just another way of
expanding the state's forfeiture Powers
all right so that if there's a lot of we
can get the guys money uh and this
passed the Senate unanimously in
California uh a lot of senators voted
for it knowing it was a bad Bill
thinking that the assembly would knock
it down which it has in previous years
unfortunately it got loose in the
assembly it didn't go through the same
legislative channels it did last year
and it almost passed but we were able to
alert the the important decision makers
about that and it got scotched at the
last minute and I don't think it's going
to make it but this shows the importance
of watching
your public policy makers your decision
makers your city council these proposals
come up and if you aren't aware of them
I mean they can sail right through but
when you say something you can have an
impact okay that's it too you say we
have an impact okay I'm calling you from
Los Angeles and I want to know what can
I do to stop this what can I do as an
individual well from Los Angeles uh
first of all if you haven't done so
already please write to your state
senator and your State Assembly
okay look them up in the phone Booker
from your Board of Elections if you
don't know who they are and write to
them saying to vote against smoke a
joint lose your license and to support
an override and then what and also write
a letter to Pete Wilson which was going
to be ignored and probably put in a big
pile of letters and Wade or something
like that but do it anyhow that's right
because if they get lots of tons of mail
I mean nothing else it does make a state
well let me say state legislators don't
get all that mail on a lot of issues I
mean 101 the gay rights issue got a lot
of mail but often they'll only have you
know four or five letters on a
particular Bill what else can we do
that'll make a difference all right the
other thing you can do is go out and
when you meet candidates uh like at
candidates nights you know when the your
local Congressman comes in town and has
a public meeting ask him his stand on
that law on smoke a joint lose your
license ask him his stand on medical
marijuana uh you know you might even ask
whether people have a right Americans
have a right to smoke marijuana in the
privacy of their personal lives okay uh
I wouldn't ask them to take a position
on legalization no politician is going
to say yes to that at this particular
moment so let's not waste our breath but
let's focus on what's at hand it's
medical marijuana it's smoke a joint
lose your license and we'll talk about
more of that when we come back right
after this with us today is the head of
California normal Dell garinger Dell we
have some elections coming up in 1992 we
always have elections coming up but the
candidates in ' 92 are the ones that
we're focusing on primarily now as an as
a voter who's concerned about getting
the prop the propositions that we need
taken care of and into office and
implemented I want to be able to find
out how my candidate votes I want to be
able to find out his background I want
to be able to find out how I can make a
difference when I get ready to cast my
ballot well join California normal and
California normal reports makes a point
of giving you the information about how
people voting and we've been following
people that very interesting votes have
been occurring in California and people
are not very aware of them I think the
smoke a joint lose your license vote was
a particularly interesting one this was
a vote that was taken by Congress to
force the states to change their laws it
was specifically aimed at marijuana
decriminalization by Bill Bennett and
and Senator alfons deato and
representative Jerry Solomon well-known
right-wing reactionaries from back there
who voted for it in California well most
of all the Republicans did with the
exception of Tom Campbell who's running
for Senate um a lot of the Democrats did
too though uh including some supposedly
very liberal ones a notable one being
Barbara Boxer who is running for Senate
also the same senate seat uh from San
Francisco and Barbara Boxer fancies
herself to be an advocate of civil
rights and personal freedom and
abortions rights and our right to
control our own body and she makes a
very for show of being pro-choice but
when you ask her about marijuana she
says well you know I don't think it
should be legal and I don't think people
should go to jail but it shouldn't be
legal to use it and uh she defends her
vote on smoke a joint loser L your
license uh and on no particularly good
rational grounds she's basically a
prohibitionist she doesn't like drugs at
all she said she'd like alcohol to be
illegal if you know if if that would
help things out well it sounds more to
me like she's is trying to stop personal
rights right well we tried so we so we
told I mean the obvious contradiction
here is here's somebody who says she's
pro-choice she's pro-abortion she's not
pro-choice and we confronted her with
that at a couple of fundraisers for her
where we approached her and we the
people in in her campaign are people who
are very are friends of ours okay they
agree with us on these issues uh they
don't know that Barbara Boxer had this
position until we went up to the in the
Democratic convention in Oakland and
talk to them uh to fundraisers and talk
to them said do you know how Barbara
Boxer is on uh marijuana in fact an
incident that happened just a couple
months ago before the recent tragic
death of Bill Graham Bill
Graham had a fundraiser uh for Barbara
Boxer up at his beautiful Marin home
which is a psychedelic Museum of uh uh I
I'm I'm just thrill that I was able to
see and I'm I'm glad I met Bill Graham
too before he before he passed away uh
but I went up there along with Ed
Rosenthal and Eric harlo we paid hundred
bucks to get in we had we got a nice
party there too and we went around and
circulated and talked about things I
went up the barber boxer introduced
myself tried to tried to tried to make
overtures and she said well she didn't
agree with us on the marijuana issue
blah blah blah and so we went and talked
to Bill Graham and Ed Rosenthal button
hold him and we told Bill Graham the
story and Bill Graham said what Barbara
Boxer doesn't understand weed why that's
an important issue I'll have to tell her
about it and sure enough the afternoon
went on Barbara Boxer gave a speech in
which he went on about civil liberties
and everything else said wonderful
things I I had to agree with everything
she said in her speech she never
mentioned drugs uh went on to a
fundraiser auction first prize in the
auction four tickets to the New Year's
Eve Grateful Dead concert Barber boxers
holding up these tickets and hey now
come on this is the hottest tickets in
town everybody's got to go to the
Grateful bed she seem to have two
different Coates is what you're getting
well yes well anyhow after all of this
happened Bill Graham finally came up to
say what he had to say and it was very
simple he said well look I really agree
with 99% of Barbara boxer's position but
I have to say there's one thing I
disagree with her on you know I don't
want to talk about drugs but it's been
500 years since we came to this
continent and people still aren't free
to plant the seed that's right so now do
we have some kind of Lobby going in Cal
do we have a well is normal involved
with the lobby I try to do that and I
have friends and and there's a network
of people who who work on particular
representatives in some it's all it's
all volunteer but we have phone trees
which need to be developed especially I
would say in southern californ uh so
that we can get we can get calls through
to a legislator's office if a key vote
is going on and saying hey we care about
this vote because that's an important
thing to do if if smoke a joint lose
your license comes to a vote we want
people phoning the Senate Judiciary
Committee on the day of that vote and
we'll to let people know when that comes
but yeah because often times the people
that are making these statements and
making these policies have a mult a
million dooll budget to work with for
their campaigns and are able to have you
know press releases put together for
them and so on and the people who are
opposing these particular viewpoints are
coming from their heart they Working
Class Heroes and are working on a budget
so we need to find some way to work
together what do you suggest when it
comes to that state of size of
California how would you pull us
together uh that's a real tall order and
we're a a long way from having a single
organization as you're aware there's a
network of of groups in California that
I think we're just going to have to keep
developing for a while uh I see you know
many different people working in many
different places it's on really it's a
county bycount basis and different
Counties have their expertise and I try
to handle Sacramento Affairs and you
know press relations and stuff like that
for the and keep people informed through
the newsletter uh as for you know more
developed organization time we'll bring
that it won't we may not even need it
but it is important for us to to get
actively involved now how is it that
normal makes it its policies when it
comes to supporting various uh groups
and various uh proposals and amendments
going through the state how is it that
you make your selections there's an
awful lot going on out there there's not
that many issues that are strictly
marijuana there's usually about two or
three bills a year in the legislature
that really deal with marijuana usually
it's status quo all right and basically
we get in there to try to oppose bad
stuff and there every year there's a bad
Bill a couple years ago for instance
there was a bill by when Vamp was still
attorney general they wanted to
establish 10 plants as the absolute
limit for personal use cultivation so
anybody who was caught with more more
than 10 plants is an automatic felon not
eligible for diversion regardless of
whether they're a medical patient or
whatever and everybody who knows
anything about cultivation knows that's
completely unrealistic and not what
personal use is and uh
basically we're the only people who know
about personal use the legislature
doesn't and neither does law enforcement
and so by going to the legislature and
just talking to the people who are
sponsoring this bill and explaining well
look this has nothing to do with
personal use you're going to get into
all sorts of lawsuits on this sort of
thing this is unreasonable uh debunking
the statistics they had a cop come in
and try to say that one plant grows a
kilogram of marijuana well yes one plant
on a government marijuana farm with no
helicopters above it may grow kilogram
of marijuana but we know that's not the
way marijuana is grown we said that we
convinced the committee it wasn't hard
to do because we did have the facts on
this so bills like that you know don't
come around that often okay um now when
it comes to uh focusing your energies
too you have to be very select in the
type of people that you send as front
people and at the same time you're also
focusing on groups and the muscle behind
that uh who does uh does most of the
structuring throughout the state I know
you you had it up uh how is it organized
is it done by large cities is there a
lot of people like an LA it's a network
it's a network of people uh that we
phone okay um not all of whom are
official members of California normal
which has a very indefinite struct uh uh
indefinite structure is not right we do
have bylaws but the we're probably going
to have some reorganization of our own
just as National normal is but we've got
about a minute
and if you had the opportunity to say
one thing that was most important to the
California citizens as well as those
people across America who are seeing
this what would be your statement well I
think you have to really demand of your
Congress people and your elected
officials to stand up for your right as
an American citizen to smoke marijuana
it's real simple and we've got to State
it in those terms and raise the issue
whenever you encounter them whenever you
confront them ask them to State their
stand you know we've been trying to get
you on the show for a long time and it's
been a pleasure I like to have you back
again just as soon as we can work it out
and it's been a pleasure to have you
tune in if you have a chance to make a
difference in your community do it go
out and find some change that you can
contribute to and make somebody's life
just a little bit happier until we get
together again keep happy keep strong
keep one eyes