when I was about 12 years old I decided
that I wanted to be a a forensic chemist
and a forensic chemist has turned out to
be a toxicologist but it wasn't called
that at that time they were my my
training professor was the Oregon State
chemist for many many years and he
treated me as a toxicologist and then
when I got to medical school I became a
PhD of pharmacology and toxicology and
you taught pharmacology and toxicology
the number of medicals I taught
physiology pharmacology and toxicology
for about ten medical schools I was
invited to to East Africa Uganda and
Tanzania where I trained the first
doctors in Tanzania uh-huh University of
Georgia I was I was I was recruited by
the University of London to teach in
Africa and and so just like I say I
trained the first doctors there and I
was a I was a medical school professor
for 25 years the last three years I was
a full-time student while I was a
full-time professor and that was at the
doc osteopathic college in Des Moines
Iowa and the strange thing about it was
that I got my osteopathic degree when I
was 50 54 years old and I was older than
most of the teachers that's when he
started being an individual practicing
osteopath yeah I had guns associated
with Paul and a town hall meeting yeah
we were at KATU channel twos Town Hall
and I was in the hot seat it was just
before the vote it was the week just two
days sir yeah two days before the vote
in 1998 where we were urging people to
vote
yes on measure 67 for medical marijuana
and no on referendum measure 57 for to
recriminate later in 97 had passed in a
bill to wreak romera wanna and we got
90,000 signatures to stop that from
going into effect a year later we got
another 120,000 to put the the marijuana
legalization on the ballot so we went
into this town hall of course there was
one side of the studio where people
largely in favor of marijuana on the
other side of the studio were people
largely against marijuana and you were
right in the middle of the crowd well
there was against marijuana whole thing
was there were so many people Pro ah and
I was on crutches yeah so I had to sit
down the other way and what was the name
of that attorney who was running that
you know who I'm talking about
Oh Jack Oh Jack's right oh now that's
the one in why yeah I can't remember his
last yeah but Jack he was the emcee for
a number of years yes that's right that
and so he wanted to know if anybody on
the other side wanted to speak and so I
raised my hand and I said thank you
everybody around you thought you were
about to launch into something about how
terrible marijuana and I says marijuana
has been used for 5000 years as medicine
and it has never killed it I noted it
and I as soon as that show was over I
came to advise you to co-host this show
we started this show in 1996 in late
1996 and then you came on at about show
number 75 or aged something like that
yeah and we have some clips of some of
these earlier shows Paul moaning yeah
you had Paul Loney on as a guest host
and he stayed on to about show 125 or so
yeah then when we switched over from
this private studio that Lanny Swerdlow
had started the first dozen the first
120 shows you moved over to when we
started record shows here as well right
and you stayed at it for quite a while
well the first the first applications
that I wrote were in
your homes yeah for about three
different homes yeah yeah and home what
happened is if people start coming to
the TV show before the show to get you
to sign their papers and it's hard to be
overwhelming in terms of the people
coming just before the show and I so he
decided to move it over to my home for a
while that became I I had my kids were
young then they're they're young adults
now but they I roll around on the floor
and pick up all the food scraps toys and
stuff but eventually we opened an office
Broadway and 45th and we offered that
office the day we opened it it was too
small so we kept going and