hi i'm elvi musica and i'm sending a
very special message to the people of
florida especially south florida because
they stood behind me 26 years ago when
this loss had had me incarcerated after
i had already lost my better eye to lack
of marijuana
with your help and your support i
won and shortly thereafter became the
first woman to receive medical marijuana
from the federal government as my
medicine for the last 26 years
now i use it for arthritis for insomnia
for depression for all of the things
that strike us as we get older i don't
have any any pharmaceuticals in my
medicine cabinet my medicine is
god-given cannabis hemp marijuana please
vote yes on two and help the thousands
of people who desperately need you now
as you helped me back then thank you
vote on two