it really blows my mind to understand
that this war started a hundred years
ago her started their false propaganda
the lies renamed the plan hemp renamed
the plant cannabis and called it
marijuana because he lost a lot of
Timber to the Mexicans he wasn't too
happy with them but California started
the law in 1913. several States followed
quickly and before you knew it the
conglomerate of the industrial complex
had managed to pass a bill because the
marijuana Tax Act of 1937. it was proven
unconstitutional by 1969 and and Nixon
you didn't have much time to keep this
law going so he gathered his
conservative friends to give him advice
and find nasty things to say about this
plant but they found the opposite as
usual they found it is not have it
forming it does not lead to other drugs
it doesn't do any of the things that you
said that they said they do and so he
didn't like that report he tore it up
through it
report and but here's the tragedy so
actually the only federal law you law
enforcement listen carefully because you
two cannot use uphold our constitution
too that lie which disrespects my fourth
and fifth amendment rights that light
has kept me from getting a job since the
80s so now I live with a miserable
income and you got to support me that
same lie has put over 20 million of us
on their arrest at one time or another
now how many of us are are there here
how many people smoke marijuana in this
country what is the percentage of what
you arrest is it one percent is it ten
percent is it four percent well whatever
you think it is multiply that by 25
million and you might get a clue a hint
why are we forced to follow this is the
federal law they try to put on the
states and everyone else to follow the
legacy of a man who left the presidency
in this grace for lack of honesty this
needs to end that is one of the main
reasons I'm asking everybody to vote for
80 to both to help the people in
Colorado in Michigan and send a clear
message to the administration this will
not be tolerated any longer we have not
that's why there are millions of us
Breaking Your Law every day has no
respect for us it doesn't deserve
respect
now change it please change it vote on
80. if you live in other states help
those ones in Colorado and Michigan and
definitely con contact your legislators
and your president and remind you remind
them that this man changed these laws
all by himself with no help from the
Congress or the Senate it was just an
order that he gave that we're living
under this lie and this lie has to end
five generations of lies and
misinformation has rendered us a nation
very very incapable of making rational
decisions mostly because our system is
not satisfied the endocannabinite system
that opens our mind and expands our
thinking and allows us to be real human
beings