hi there let's review a little history
here I know that marijuana camp cannabis
has been a vital part of our society
before the Industrial Revolution it was
eighty percent of the world's Commerce
that was a good reason for them to try
to eliminate you as a grower because
that was the material that built homes
made beautiful clothes for me to wear
fine paper that does hold up much better
than the trees were killing and it does
not destroy the awesome in fact it real
oxygenates the planet so they stay made
a prohibition way back then but in the
United States it actually began 101
years ago in 1913 by 1913 it was totally
outlawed in the state of California and
the hearse press was spreading their
lives and misinformation which is the
only basis that was used for this
prohibition by the time 1937 came around
several states had joined that
prohibition and kept out into the list
by 1950 we began to realize that what
they had really Albert out Lord was this
wonderful thing called cannabis the
greatest medicine known and the oldest
medicine known to humanity which has
never killed anyone people began to use
it recreationally and try to write lost
regard to make changes since nineteen
sixty there was a morphia and then came
normal the most exciting thing that's
happened is in the 90 students for
sensible drug coalition are incredibly
brilliant young people who are making a
difference and young people all over
this country have been educated thanks
to the entrepreneurs and the internet
and the fact that so many wonderful
books especially the Emperor wears no
clothes came back out in 1988 88 was an
incredible year for marijuana because
also the DEA son chief administrative
law judge had had a chance to review the
medical evidence and said that it was
the oldest medicine to known known to
humanity and for a government to come
between a patient's
offering and the benefits of this
substance was unreasonable arbitrary and
capricious that position came three
weeks after I have been acquitted in the
state of Florida because I had been
using it to maintain the site on my left
eye by then we had destroyed my right
eye completely both through ignorance
and misinformation I had thought
marijuana was not saved and I had loud
all the cutting in my better idea I was
totally blinded in 1987 and in 98 I came
to court with it so I did the support in
Florida was amazing amazing amazing you
covered my trial you covered all the
things that happened prior to that and
you supported me norm can't four is now
the director of normal did it pro bono
since then I have discovered the history
of the prohibition and can never stay
home because in 1990 I met one Jack hair
who wrote the Emperor wears no clothes
and who made me very much aware that we
were arresting 250 to 300 thousand
people a year but nothing has gotten
better in spite of the hundreds of
thousands of us who work endlessly and
have been working for generations to
change these laws in spite of that the
lies continue they still have the same
arguments the difference is that now
because of the youth learning from us
especially in the nineties because all
the dedication that comes with that
youth because of a sense of
responsibility that comes as a result of
using marijuana because once you enhance
your awareness level by opening those
receptors and you didn't use before you
become more aware of your responsibility
towards yourself and the planet and it
is for that reason that I am saying now
that she knew and now that you've had
hundreds of thousands of us who have
been arrested repeatedly yeah we we have
joined this war we've been forced to
fight this war on us that they call the
war on drugs drugs are not going to jail
200 200
nobody see 25 million of us have been
arrested 2,000 every day still today you
cannot afford this prohibition at a
moral level at a medical level at a
financial level so it's up to you to
join us hundreds of thousands of us who
have been working at and remember most
of us were not necessarily willing
victims we were hammered with a war on
drugs and have no choice but to stand up
for our self preservation and survival
and in instincts which of course can not
be outlawed you can no doubt myself
survive self preservation and survival
and that's what you're asking us to do
if you maintain this loss please join us
and this nightmare whether you're in
Alaska whether you're in New York
whether you're in Oregon where you're
going to make it legal for anyone over
40 or whether you're still working on
the medical marijuana it is all urgent
the message needs to be loud and clear
the substance Control Act is the hammer
that shot that coffin for us back in
nineteen seventy when richard nixon
hired a team of his own friends to tell
him marijuana should be decriminalized
that it was no danger to anyone and he
decided he was not going to reward the
hippies know what were they called and
bit NEETs who had stopped his forum
vietnam and he appointed elvis presley
as his first drugs arts the hell i went
ignorance blinds us is what that proves
repeatedly but you have broken through
the dark night of ignorance when you
made california legal back in 1996 the
dark knight of ignorance has ended the
dawn of days here and it's all to you to
bring it into its full beautiful sight
we need to end this prohibition at all
levels hemp should be a vital part of
our economy our farmers should be making
money not being thrown in jail and you
need homes that are much harder to burn
down these days especially in dry areas
like the Arizona Calif
even a lot of fires in Florida there's
just fires all over that could be
alleviated a great deal by building
properly and not use so many chemicals
everywhere for everything one in every
three of us is expected to have a cancer
actually I have been to a medical
conference where some of the most
brilliant people stated very clearly
that today each and every one of us has
a chance to acquire a cancer and most of
it has to do with substituting this one
fight with over 50,000 petrochemical
products so please the wants of us who
keep our immune system by using this
plant stand a better chance of not
getting the cancer although there's
plenty of it to go around to all of us
so please help us alleviate help our
planet help the people and stop this
madness Florida is trying to make sure
that other people have a right to call
debated possess their medical marijuana
and of course we're with them in spirit
I am there in the spirit of gratitude
they are the ones who made it happen for
me and I know so I know they're
compassionate people if given the
opportunity education is the key to all
the answers that's what all the elders
have taught me and most of them were
younger than I am in fact my elders turn
out to be kids from 18 to 25 to took to
that road and we did every state in this
country repeatedly for two or three
years and then join the help you co mo
he joined us actually with the cannabis
Action Network and we continue to travel
the country for another year or two
after that all with the purpose of
educating America and learning and
teaching as quickly as we passed it on
to you and it has paid off I got you on
my side thank you what surprised me was
the reception that we got us we traveled
it wasn't like Oh what are those hold
people talking to us about me there were
all ears because they were not getting
education and we had that they were
getting there that was a poor excuse for
education I was very sad to travel and
hear the stories this kids could tell a
horrible parenting day
I don't tell 10 years ago when your
daddy gave up the Bruce and started
smoking pot only now they had to take it
back to him so he could throw him in
jail for actually taking care of himself
for once and for all I mean I had to
deal with this and try to teach this
children that not to give up that they
can change this is a bad story but they
need to share it with legislators they
need to put an end to it that brings us
to a very interesting part of this
prohibition in the States we have ended
medical marijuana prohibition we have
dropped in overdoses by pharmaceuticals
and I mean a whopping 26 percent we drop
plus 26 plus percent considering that
seventy-eight percent of all deaths that
are drug-related are with legal drugs
and prescriptions I think you need to
take note in the states for medical
marijuana is a reality we have dropped a
26 plus percentage of drug overdoses
this is an adult drug this is God's
precious herb gift I take it in a spirit
of Thanksgiving every day cannabis does
have accepted medical value thanks to
you again 24 states have accepted it
already and more will after this
election no doubt in my heart about it
thank you thank you thank you all of
them may the true spirit of love be your
guiding light and end this madness