you're not good for
nothing don't let them tell you
so your life has a
purpose and I think you ought to
know
makes the flowers
grow oh
grow I wondered why you're here but now
I
know
makes the flowers
grow I'm a dainty Little
Flower alone in the
snow and you've got the
power to fertilize my
soul
ship makes the flowers
grow oh
makes the flowers
grow I wonder why you're here but now I
know
ship makes the flowers
grow you nourish my
body and the sun warms my
bones I know
karate I should I studied it for eight
years
[Music]
sh makes the flowers grow
everybody oh
makes the flowers
grow I wondered why you're here but now
I
know
makes the flowers
grow
makes the
flowers grow
[Music]
thank you