[Music]
of all the world.
Dear, you are the
one. My favorite
human under the
sun. What brings
tomorrow, we never
know. So, you'd better kiss
me before you go.
There are the
flowers. There are the
trees. There's you and me,
dear. Among all
these. Sooner or
later, there is
goodbye. So kiss me once more,
dear, in case we die.
Death could be
waiting outside of this
room, anticipating.
Yours and my potential
doom. We could be
walking trip on our own feet.
Not even to
mention all the psychos we
meet. Sooner or
later, there is
goodbye. So kiss me once more,
dear. In case we die, take it,
Kathy. I don't really have a solo for
this. Neither do I. Take it.
H I wish I could think of something
cool. It's almost over. You can just
take it now. I can take the rest. Oh,
no. I can't. I'm just strumming.
Are you screwed that way? Take it out of
the key.
Death could be
waiting outside of this
room,
anticipating yours and my potential
doom.
We could be
walking trip on our own
feet, not even to
mention all the psychos we
meet. Sooner or
later, there is
goodbye. So kiss me once more, dear.
In case we
die, kiss me once more,
dear. In case
we
[Music]
die. Thank you guys. Thank you very
much.