what groups or organizations or
individuals
have inspired you in your life
well my
listen if it wasn't for an extremely
good mama and the freddie mediaville
maximum security prison i'd gone wrong a
really long time ago
so my mom has probably kept me on
straight and narrow more than anybody
else
but uh
when i uh
as i got older i became desperate for a
role model
and uh
so uh i
looked for the people who i thought was
just the right things
uh
there are signs
uh so uh i decided and quite frankly if
you wanna know the truth i decided to
just decide you need the new hero and
there's no reason to worry why i
shouldn't be it right you know
well every every generation between win
its own freedom and our past generation
had such icons as as faulty as the word
is john wayne and uh you know a clint
eastwood as being a
sovereign individual human beings
but this younger generation doesn't have
many heroes
i mean
ben diesel is not
like who shot liberty now
uh when when but somebody who's just
trying to do right
has to stand up against some unspeakable
villain uh who who threatens uh the the
very
freedom and soul of these protagonists
um
you know i guess i guess my heroes
nowadays are next to lessons
and that chinese gentleman
in front of that tank
square yeah
i know
yes
on a major problem