could you tell our audience a little bit
how how that came about and how you
actually first taught Willie Nelson
who's now a big proponent of biodiesel
about hemp bioaves we'd always heard
that Rudolph diesel had manufactured his
diesel engines run off sea dog we really
didn't understand quite grasp that this
was in the early 90s uh late 80s and
then it fella from Nevada Las Vegas
Nevada came through town driving a
little Volkswagen diesel and he's
running it off Burger King oil and so we
had just uh derived some hip oil out of
hemp seeds hemp seeds are 30 to 40
percent oil by weight you got 100 pounds
of hemp seeds you can drive 30 to 40
pounds of pure oil out of it and so we
had some of that and he tested it out in
his engine and he says this is the best
seed oil that I've ever driven this car
on and so we had cedor When Willy came
in to do a benefit concert for me we
poured that hemp oil into my Mercedes
diesel and drove it about 110 miles
across Kentucky
and it was the first time in I guess 50
to 60 years that any vehicle that had
been driven on Dent oil on the United
States roads but Willie told me later on
that 12 years later actually no I mean
now about 10 years later he says
Gatewood he says that afternoon we did
that it taught me what it was all about
and that's the reason I started my
biofuel company was from what we learned
that afternoon driving your Mercedes
across there
we're also smoking about the biggest
Hooters probably wrote in Kentucky at
the time and there was a caravan of us
we went from uh the Hyatt there and
rough Auditorium through Frankfurt the
state capitol which is about 80 miles
and then all together 120 miles all the
way into Louisville which is largest
city in Kentucky and then he did a big
benefit concert for you there that night
that's right