been practicing law for 30 years been
protecting the rights of the marijuana
smoker for since that time I ran in 1983
for a Commissioner of Agriculture of
marijuana on a legal marijuana ticket
let me tell you in 1983 that didn't go
over too damn hot I said galbert how do
you expect to win I said well there's
more marijuana smokers than are
Republicans in the
state if I can just get them to the poe
we can do that since I've run I've run
ran in 91 95 for governor ran in 99 as a
Reform Party candidate for governor
spent $20,000 and got 15.3% of the VOE
as of third party in Kentucky that was
pretty
phenomenal uh ran as an independent for
congress in 2002 got 27% of the vote as
an independent on a $20,000 budget you
know so um I've running this time as an
independent for governor of the state of
Kentucky and let me tell you I was
mighty impressed to hear these words
from meline because she's got it exactly
right marijuana is just a symptom of the
issue the real issue is are we still
Sovereign human
beings that's what the American
Revolution was all about marijuana is an
iconic issue because it shows just how
far the government has gone in
overstepping its bounds in policing
private behavior and impinging on the
whole idea of what America itself was
all about you know before America we
were all property we belonged to the
king or the queen or the warlord or
whoever had the most gunpowder in the
valley and they said hey come in here
off with your head there you went there
was nothing there you had no rights you
were property you belong to whoever had
the most gunpowder but when our founding
fathers decided they're going to set
this country up and wrote the
Declaration of Independence they
recognized in in essence that we we were
all created by our creator and endowed
with inalienable human rights among them
life liberty and pursuit of happiness
for the first time they gave each of us
our
sovereignty for there the first time any
ruling party had ever conceded that the
individual was a sovereign
thing and they wrote the Constitution to
try to to try to instill the the the
legal system to protect it and since
that time it has been in great peril by
people who seek to subvert it and make
slaves of us to their
will and believe you me the man ain't
racist he doesn't care what color his
slaves
are and the whole idea of having piss in
the cup to hold a job in America is
athma to what America itself was built
on
yeah I've been that this I was 24 years
old and a Milkman in 1971 when I decided
I was Grist for the mill I was going to
end up in prison or dead at an early age
because I didn't understand the system
and if if I as long as I was ignorant of
the system I was going to be a pawn in
their game so I decided I had to learn a
system and the best way to do that was
to go to college become an attorney and
if I was going to do that put in all
that work I might as well become
governor of Kentucky and change
marijuana laws and try to live Kentucky
back into
prosperity
wo we were the world's largest producer
of cannabis for over a hundred years we
called it hemp you know people said
what's the difference Gatewood and I
said well you know hemp and marijuana
are both cannabis in the same way that
Danny DeVito and Dennis Rodman are both
adult
[Applause]
[Laughter]
males you
know yeah but the Kentucky was world's
largest producer so we ought to return
to to it and let our Farmers back into
the niche of producing energy to solve
our energy problems instead of giving
all this marijuana giving all this money
over to to the oil producing countries
you know we calculated that if you could
plant 7% of the US agricultural land in
hemp you wouldn't have to import another
drop of
oil but you know what what's happened is
a great a great synthetic subversion
where those people who make synthetic
products have used the criminal law to
to criminalize Farmers from producing uh
competitive natural products in both
Petr chemicals and
pharmaceuticals and a great deal of our
problems today could be directly
Associated to the people I refer to as
the Petr chemical pharmaceutical
military industrial transnational
corporate fascist Elite son of a
[ __ ] who have never said a pledge of
allegiance to the flag of the United
States of America or to the Republic for
which it stands they're not warm and
fuzzy about us or our children or
grandchildren and and they see the
Constitution and the Bill of Rights as
impediments to the implementation of a
new world order in the global
economy and that's just where it's at
they you know they want to flatten the
world to make us all you know a global
economy and to you erase National
boundaries uh but you know they can't
afford to give every other human being
on Earth the same constitutional
Privileges and rights that we enjoy and
recognition of sovereign human beings so
they're going to have to take ours away
from us in order to make us a flat Earth
I ain't going down without a fight
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah so in 1983 like I said I started my
political campaign I got up I started
getting up every day in 1971 so I've
been at it 40 years and I've run for
governor several times so I I have a
pretty good idea about what politics is
all about I gave the the reform the
keynote address at the Reform Party
National Convention back in 2000 and uh
you know so i' I've been there I've
observed the politics and after 40 years
I'd have to be pretty dumb not to have
come up with at least one good idea in
those 40 years and I I do tell the folks
in this race right here if I was ever
going to lie to you I would already have
been elected but you
know but but but descriptively speaking
uh descriptively speaking Kentucky
suffers from electile
dysfunction what's happening is that the
the both parties have their horns locked
up like two bull elk fighting over
territory while the business of the
people lays dead in the dust and neither
party can produce a candidate could
disengage from the partisanship long
enough to work with the other side to
get the job done and my running mate
who's a a beautiful lady with six kids
two of them adopted one of her natural
children of special needs so she knows
where the rubber beats the road in those
women and children's issues uh she and I
are running totally as Independence no
party affiliation whatsoever we don't
want one we don't want want all that
baggage we don't want all that all that
corruption we don't really we don't want
it we don't want it you keep it that's
just a monster to be fed once you get to
the trough you know we're going to start
returning any of the surpluses of the
state over back over to the people but
the first thing I'm going to do when I'm
governor of state of Kentucky the minute
I'm sworn into oath is I'm going to have
the commander of the National Guard land
a helicopter in the in the front the
capital and bring me the keys to it and
that's the last time any one of those
figed military helicopters is going to
hover over the fields and Gardens of the
people of the state of
[Applause]
Chucky this is America not Afghanistan
and we're not an occupied territory and
we're not going to treat our citizens
like we are one in the state of
Kentucky they got a pretty good idea
that I mean it I wrote an autobiography
here not too long ago uh that I gave a a
copy to meline and uh this this is my
autobiography it's called the last free
man in America meets the synthetic
subversion and that's me holding M60 on
the front cover of it and so he said gab
why you holding that M60 I said cuz I'm
a serious
man you can you can get that order one
off of a my website at Gatewood dcom but
we have a hell of a chance of winning in
November our primaries are this coming
Tuesday we're not in the primary we're
totally
independent and what interest you may
have in what how I do out there in that
race is that we're going to take a giant
leap we're going to take a giant leap
we're going to go all the way to find
out whether America still has a pulse or
not and we're going to do it
constitutionally the United States
Constitution does not provide you the
right to life liberty and the pursuit to
happiness that's in Independence
Declaration of Independence that's not
law so you don't officially have a right
to that under federal
law but Kentucky has a constitution also
just like all the other states do but it
just so happens that ky's Constitution
is the most Pro people Constitution ever
written that I people back in 189 he got
so tired of being raped by the railroad
companies that they wrote a constitution
that protected the people and kept
corporations from being running rough
shot over
everybody and even now that's beginning
to fracture as our legislature keeps
selling out to to the uh to the uh folks
that I call the petrochemical
pharmaceutical military industrial
transnational corporate fascist Elite
son of a
[ __ ] so uh what's going to happen is
that the very first section of ky's
constitution ensures that it citizens
constitutionally are
endowed with the right to life liberty
and pursuit to happiness that's the
number one section in Kentucky
Constitution so I feel obliged to make
it the number one basis of policy for my
relationship of government to the people
in state of Kentucky I'm going to get it
off of their B
I'm going to take it out of the bedrooms
and the bloodstreams and the brains and
the bladders the billfolds and back
pockets the internet bulletin boards and
put them back in the little box where
they
belong I'm going to make government not
a burden on the people I think it's the
role of government to uplift Enlighten
educate and endow
people with an appreciation of Life
appreciation of the social compact
there's civil
duties there civil responsibilities
and make sure that we have address them
as Sovereign human beings capable making
their own
decisions and we're going to get medical
marijuana in the hands of every sick and
dying person in the state of Kentucky no
permit
[Applause]
needed I'm going to take it out of the
hands of the 10 and 13 and 14 year olds
who are doing it Just for kicks we're
going to give them over to the old age
homes to all the old old folks in the
old age homes
hey increase the appetite put a smile on
their face and think about the increased
vegitation by the Young Folks hey let's
go see
[Applause]
that so if we can do this if I can win
this it's going to be bigger than
Ventura it'll be next to Obama's
election because there is no there was a
an independent elected governor of Rhode
Island in this past one the first one
elected in 150 years but he had been a
state senator he had been a federal US
senator from state Rhode Island so he
had that base okay we'll be the first
truly independent ticket ever to uh ever
to uh win governor in state of Kentucky
uh in the last 150 years so uh we have
uh I've got a website called Gatewood
domcom um I I'm a criminal defense
attorney Al lexton I handle criminal
cases and I'd like to represent a
lottery winner or two if any of y'all
know who you are out
there if you're if you're a big dog and
and you're hanging out on Millions
here's a good place to uh to give me a
fee and let me get on down the road on
this campaign if you can drop something
5 10 20 bucks in on Gatewood domcom I
appreciate you doing it I'll send you a
copy of my
book uh an ex-governor of the state of
Kentucky said it was the best statement
of freedom in America he'd ever read on
the same day an 18-year-old girl from
the middle of the mountains called me
said she had read twice previous week
and it was the number one seller at
Joseph Beth top independent bookstore in
America for 11 month 11 weeks so uh I
left out 100% of the sex and 80% of the
drugs but it's still a kickass
read folks uh I'm I've I'm I'm out here
at the bequest of and the generosity of
somebody that I'd certainly like to uh
give a shout out to that's Mr Paul
Stanford here
in
he was swell enough to let me appear on
his program last night and uh we're
going to throw a little fundraiser over
to Clinton stre Clinton Street Theater
what time at 3:30 so to 5:30 so um you
know I've understand you all got some
business to conduct at meeting and I
just I hope I didn't take up too much of
your time gatew galbert I appreciate you
all time and attention thank you
so