and the question of himp the question of
cannabis is the most Vivid illustration
of how this government has overstepped
its bounds in policing the private
behavior of citizens when they told us
we couldn't plant a hip seed in the
ground they severed us from the natural
cycle that is what they seek to do I
call it the synthetic subversion where
they want to replace all the natural
products on Earth that used to be grown
out of God's Earth and God's seed and
replaced them with synthetic products
and knocked our farmer out of the
agrarian society and The Agrarian market
and made the ghost towns of our small
cities and Villages across this country
we need to ReDiscover a cast crop one
that will allow our Farmers to go back
to the land one that will allow our
Farmers to compete with the
petrochemical pipelines you plant us 7%
agricultural land in him you would have
to import another drop of oil we can
replace the spills in the Gulf we can
replace the uh environmental catastrophe
that the petroleum pipelines have cast
upon Mother Earth and instead let our
Farmers grow hemp as a fuel crop in 1991
Willie Nelson and I poured Hall into my
Mercedes diesel and drove it across
Kentucky in my bid for governor that's
why he started his biofuel plant listen
folks you all have been hand a a torch
Jack ha bless his soul passed away I'm
getting olded up here you know we cannot
make care of this ball much longer you
have to become educated you have to
learn the truth you have to reach out
there and grab the responsibility of
maintaining your freedom every
generation must rewin its own freedoms
and those very sacrifices right up to
the very last second I've been talking
to you on your behalf cannot continue
anymore what really counts is your all
commitment to what sacrifices you're
willing to make in the future to
maintain your freedom and it's right
there in front of you I encourage you I
encourage you to learn the law I
encourage you to learn the political
process I encourage you to reach out
there and take responsibility your own
Freedom Live Your Life Like a Warrior
God bless you all thanks for having me
out here Seattle