hey thank you guys thanks for everybody
showing up if we don't show up we don't
blow up so we encourage everybody to get
out to all the events represent and make
sure that we can hold the people who got
this industry moving that we can all
transition into this industry these
green rushes are moving in they're
trying to like wipe us all out for
pennies on the dollar that's been their
plan they really have no heart and soul
into cannabis so when you go out there
and spend your hard-earned money at
cannabis support the stores and support
the locations that support the people
who brought you here it's been a long
road for all of us
my wife was part of the first collective
garden in San Diego in 1996 our
collective got a raided in San Diego in
1999 where I was arrested for 448 plants
we've done a lot of things everybody's
done a lot of things we put a lot of
energy into this and we need to get
something back you know we really need
to hold on to our medical laws we'll be
seen what happened in Washington is a
disgrace to medical and it's really a
disgrace to all the efforts that
everybody put in the same people who
fought against this tooth and nail
Inslee and all the rest of us who fought
against cannabis now we'll go to the
death to protect the tax dollar so that
our plan really worked our plan was to
like get them addicted to the money and
then we'll be able to legalize so
they're all addicted it's spreading
across the country states are lining up
they all want to cash in on it but we
still need to show up at these events
and let our voice be heard to make sure
that the small guys and the small
farmers and the crafts farmers don't get
wiped out the big talk now is a race to
the bottom well we saw the race to the
bottom come in years ago because there's
big corporations already out there who
are ready to lose 30 to 50 million
dollars to create market to capture
market share so when you go out there
make conscious choices on what you buy
buy organic buy clean buy local just
like we do here in the Pacific Northwest
and Oregon we need to do the same for
cannabis it's not about the dollar the
lower the price the probably the crop
your weeds your
getting so support your local growers
organic growers and keep on showing up
at the events and you know show up on a
regular basis and you could really make
a change in the cannabis movement so
thank you so much for everybody coming
out today I want to thank normal and
parents for pod and Paul Sanford in
their group and everybody for keeping
Oregon on on you know going I want to
thank and ideas for kind of be in the
backbone here and Madeline Martinez and
all of these people who have really
brought us here today and got us through
legalization so thank you so much for
supporting cannabis and Oregon and show
up and blow up