I would like to dedicate this speech to
Aaliyah she's an 11 year old child in
the great state of Kentucky she has the
same rare illness I have unfortunately
for that child she isn't unable to get
the oil she needs we know it's my story
that it's important that this oil become
legal folks my illness it's rare and
incurable the doctors give you a
prescription for medicine that shut your
kidneys down when they're done with that
they give you a brain shunt surgery that
most people don't even survive and if
you do you have to keep having those
surgeries over and over to replace the
shunt I said no to that surgery three
years ago I use only cannabis oil it is
absolutely all naturally keeps my spinal
pressure down just as well as the stuff
the doctors are giving people that is
not working very important that we get
this federle legalized folks kids are
dying people are dying for this oil
every day I get messages from people
around the country they need it
legalized we live in a state that we've
got the blessing here that we do have at
least some type of freedom here we need
to set an example folks we're the ones
that need to set an example for the
other states I'm going to go ahead and
read what I wrote today simply because I
have a brain disease so I don't have
really good memory plus I take two grams
of cannabis oil a day so I'm going to
here goes i'm going to read what I wrote
hello I have three important words I
want to share with you all we all matter
I would like to say thank you all for
showing up to support cannabis there are
so many people who are depending on all
of us to be their voices people ask me
what is it going to take to get better
legalization
and and I tell him this number one
eliminate the fear factor by setting a
good example just what I was talking
about we're blessed to be living in a
state that is allowing us to have some
freedom where cannabis is concerned we
need to use this freedom to show
compassion and grace so other states
will see that the laws in their states
are unfair and that people will greatly
benefit from medical cannabis we also
need to show others that people use
cannabis are great and very responsible
people number two education let me see a
show of hands of all the people out here
that are using it for stress or pain
relief okay it's the stories you
people's stories it's the average Joe
these are the stories that are gonna get
to change we need they I can say here
tell my story 50 times there's not very
many of me yet to rare brain disease
there's millions of you use your voice
to get it done we also need to start
sharing these success stories with
doctors and the lawmakers they hear
stories of like I said from me but
they're not hearing it enough from you
people number three start a revolution
of kindness okay show unity in your
community show up to as many of these
events as you can get involved in
changing minds okay let's change some
freaking minds here number four vote for
candidates that are going to help our
cause not hurt it okay this starts here
in our own communities and our state
officials number five start pressing for
cannabis to be federally studied by
accredited doctors we need some deaf
studies done
for those that don't know my story like
I told you I do have a rare brain
disease but I'm kicking its ass using
cannabis oil okay one more thing I would
just like to quote my human rights we
hold these truths to be self-evident
that all men are created equal that they
are endowed by their creator because
damn it anyway let's make it legal