and
what he didn't tell you is for the last
nine months i've been a cancer survivor
guys
so if anybody tells you that rick
simpson oil don't work look you're
looking at it guys they told me i was
going to go away in september i'm still
here
i plan on being here for some time
coming so as long as i keep getting rick
simpson oil i'll be around guys
but i'm really here to talk about the
cannabis common sense tour we did a a a
great job on the west coast tour of it
and we're going to be taking off on the
east coast coming this up this summer so
keep a lookout for it man if you don't
know anything about it it's a way that
we put money on the books of marijuana
activists that are in jail for marijuana
crimes so it's a great tour it's going
to be a great cause come out and get
behind it guys