and we're offset is true it's about
family it's about getting people out of
cages and I was almost one of those
people i sat in a cage for seven days
after my facility was raided in Medford
on May 23rd 2013 I'm the former
executive director of Southern Oregon
normal my facility operated for almost 5
years next to the federal courthouse I
[Music]
was raided along with my husband at the
time on a Thursday before Memorial Day
yeah that's what we heard a year later
when we were due to go to trial we had
some really fine attorneys you've heard
Leland Berger speak here today he
represented my husband Dustin Russell's
was my attorney
we took a plea bargain in all of the 29
and 28 felonies were dropped against
myself and my husband in exchange for
one Class B felony the charge was
delivery of more than one ounce of
cannabis to another medical marijuana
card holder for no consideration and
there was no such charge that was a made
up charge to get those felonies to go
away
fast-forward to three years - felonies
been expunged as part of that plea
bargain our guns and ammunition we're
returned and that was also a first in
the state of Oregon I continued to lobby
with compassion at Oregon and you've
heard the Anthony Taylor and a couple of
other people talk about that today and
in now the five years since that
happened we've done things like
qualified PTSD as a qualifying condition
we didn't just do that for our veterans
we did that for people like myself who
suffered from childhood traumas
for women who've been raped
that's a trauma for children that have
been beat sexually molested women who
have lived with domestic violence
all of those are PTSD and you all now
qualify under the LM MA if you receive
Oregon Health Plan or food stamps you
now only pay fifty and sixty dollars
instead of two hundred we did that
compassionate Oregon did that and
veterans you only pay twenty dollars for
your application fee instead of two
hundred we did that if you want the
program to stick around you want to keep
your medical program you better keep
your patient card you medical growers
you better keep your medical patients
you better convince some of those rent
growers to get back on this side of the
fence because without a medical program
and people registered that patient
program is gonna go away you've heard
him talk about that little golden box on
my table over there at Delta and I'm
please please I'm begging you
drop your coins in it drop your dollar
bills in it it'll be circulating
throughout the crowd today if you know
what the doubt market is you'll see it
there on Sundays if you don't talk to me
about it privately if you need your
medical card signed you talk to Paul
Stanford or myself we've got a clinic or
two to refer you to I'm the owner of Jim
strong medical consultants and that is
dedicated to two of my mentors Jim Greg
and Jim Clark who are no longer with us
and to me
to me they represent what the Oregon
Medical Marijuana program should be
forever
tomorrow is Jim's birthday here's that
box my lobbyists Anthony Taylor is one
of the hardest working men in Salem and
he is there to fight for the patients
and the program and I ask all of you to
fight for this life plant is saved my
life and I have been cancer-free for 15
months I ask all of you talk to somebody
every day about this plant because it
will change your life like it changed
mine
thank you everybody let's have a great
March