it's a beautiful day in potland Oregon
it's so great to be here uh just a
follow up on what Russ said we are
seeing such great uh tremendous success
all across the country uh last week St
Louis Missouri decriminalized marijuana
Springfield Missour decriminalized
marijuana Maryland just legalized
medical marijuana Rhode Island just uh
legalized medical marijuana dispensaries
Washington and Colorado legalizing
marijuana uh for you know all adults uh
here in Oregon we have a bill
3371 that uh we hope to get referred
into 2014 that will legalize marijuana
for all adults allow home grow it's a
great provision I encourage you to check
that out we got PTSD added as a
qualifying condition under the medical
marijuana act that passed the Senate uh
uh reducing marijuana penalties for 29
grams to uh 112 G so it's no longer a
felony it's a misdemeanor that's likely
to pass this year Oregon's likely to
have
a an unprecedented success at the Oregon
legislature this year and it's done
because of activists it's done because
of people like you you call your
legislator and not more than call you
legislator you just you just tell your
truth you know everybody out here has a
truth about cannabis and about how
cannabis doesn't hinder your life it
helps your medical condition it makes
you more creative it it doesn't impair
your life in any way you keep spreading
that truth to person after person your
friends and family and that that message
just spreads and the truth shall
eventually set us all
free right brother so uh keep coming to
marches like this support urb's design
420 radio normal Oregon green free
national green friends everybody out
here is working for the cause campaign
for the restoration and regulation of
hemp support everybody we're today day
like this we're United on May 4th and uh
also I want to mention if you got a
smartphone or anything text uh NCC to
420420 and a couple of you win some free
t-shirts today some free swag so uh text
NCC to 420420 get you some free t-shirts
and uh you know on a beautiful day like
this you know may the fourth be with us
all thank you so much