and this hero died before he could see
the freedom which he fought for most of
his life our elders are dying every day
and with them goes a knowledge that may
never be recovered forced some for their
entire lives to hide what they know
instead of sharing it with others for
fear that others May seek to end their
lives to keep this information from the
general public education is the only way
to get the freedom we seek for this
plant and ourselves
understanding will only come when the
people open their eyes to the
possibility that they have been misled
by the media and certain corporations or
government organizations about the true
purposes of a naturally occurring
substance which had had a symbiotic
relationship with all life on Earth
until the
1930s discrimination and Prejudice
towards the cannabis plant and those who
choose to us utilize its broad
applications will always exist if fear
and ignorance are the only tools being
used to fight our oppression
if you know me or have seen me around
I've usually got a camera uh that's kind
of what I do as an activist uh I go
places I meet people uh I participate in
the global cannabis Community because
this is a global
Community uh which we are trying to
represent here today as respectful and
informed group of concerned citizens
that want their opinions to be
recognized I have had a tremendous
opportunities over the last decade or so
which allowed me to travel to great
places and meet even greater people I'd
like to thank the people and
organizations that helped me to reach
out and educate
others although I've been involved with
many organizations and groups looking to
forward the movement towards true
cannabis Freedom you know
like where it's growing on your parking
strip like
roses uh I believe that individual
activism is the real key you don't need
to sign up with only one group of people
you can find your way into multiple
channels of this beautiful plant and its
abilities I have always preached that
there are three types of uses for the
Cannabis genus plant type Industrial
Hemp medical cannabis and recreational
marijuana uh if you think you know your
pot you just might not uh seriously
though there are a ton there's ton of
information about the plant and it's
uses in its multiple forms so please do
some research and tell your family what
you've learned strike up a conversation
about something you know about cannabis
that the person you're talking to
probably doesn't know and they will find
an interest because you have the Hot
Topic talking point right now okay