and we love our dark skin we are not
ashamed we are not embarrassed
we are not humiliated by the racism in
this country because the people that are
pushing it out there they're the ones
who should be ashamed of themselves all
of us are disgusted by racism [ __ ] that
[ __ ]
one of the things that I need to talk
about today is not only the
decriminalization which we're
continuously fighting for marijuana use
in this city in this state it's supposed
to be legal but we still have to worry
about where we can legally use where we
can legally medicate my son is right now
on RSO oil for his seizures he has
grandma's seizures the only thing that
helps him and his wife who has epilepsy
is the use of the cannabis and the oils
that it produces but having access to it
is the biggest problem for them because
you know what if you can't afford to get
it as a medical patient and keep up all
the bureaucracy and policy behind that
then being a recreational user you're
still being criminalized and especially
a child with brown skin who has seizures
who might cease during a car while he's
driving he might have a seizure at the
time that he's walking his kids to the
park and you know what's my biggest fear
is that happening that happening and the
police hurting him taking his life
because they don't know that he's having
an attack they don't know that he's
having a health issue at the time
because of how we see people that
utilize marijuana in this country one of
the things that he has to deal with not
only the seizures but having to deal
with racism every day he is in an
interracial relationship
his wife was told one day by a child
that she grew up with that she was a
breeder now because she had mixed kids
by my son how humiliating for not only
them as a couple that's trying to live
in the year 2017 2018 in America to be
humiliated by racism but to know that
they are pushing that on their children
I advocate for a lot of children and one
of the things I tell them is that the
things that are happening
right now they're not they're false and
they don't have to carry on the same
traditions and values and policies that
we've been taking into consideration to
reform they need to break these systems
[ __ ] reform it's time for reconstruction
and when we talk about reconstruction we
know that it doesn't take rocket science
to make outside public consumption a
thing we know that it adds to the value
of public safety because people don't
have to hide what they're doing when
they're trying to deal with the girls of
today all of these hills that we're
dealing with all of the things that are
creating PTSD in all of us if you didn't
have PTSD before the Trump inauguration
there got it now I was in the hospital
watching it on morphine dying coming out
of a surgery and I knew that we were in
for a fight I got out of that hospital
ready I got out of that hospital I
connected with the ACLU I connected with
indivisible Oregon I connected with my
community and we kept moving because the
fact that we're getting tired of
fighting it doesn't mean that we're
losing it just means that we have to be
more innovative in the way that we do
our outreach everybody should be on the
frontline nobody should be behind we
don't have saviors in this movement we
have allies we have comrades we have
people that feel the same way that we do
and the only thing that is in between us
is legalities people think that's
speaking out freedom of speech that
that's violent people see it as violent
if they don't control the conversation
we have right now with the legalization
in the state of Oregon the opportunity
to change that conversation this
industry is making money that money can
be used for education and I'm not
talking about only the education in our
schools I'm talking about political
education when our numbers and our
neighbors understand the value of what
we're talking about when we need to
continue to influence policy when they
become the allies in this fight we will
win when we invest in elected officials
that understand the priorities when we
talk about public safety and marijuana
use
and not having our children be chased
and chased and shot for having a joint
or a pipe in their pocket when they
understand the value of integrating what
they believe is a better future
into where we're talking about having
access liberation then that's when those
things will change put your money in
this industry where our future needs to
be
give our children access to the guidance
that they need give them a blank slate
let's make something that matters happen
we don't have to propagate the falses of
the people that we elect that come to us
with lip service voter mouth volume out
if you don't trust them don't give them
a chance we in this industry we
understand we're second chances look
like and we haven't got them from an
elected leader
we haven't gotten them from a political
relationship or legislation they just
keep putting our ideas and our thoughts
and our necessities on the back burner
no more I'm trying to see a revolution
I remember when new approaching Anthony
Johnson when all of that was happening
and I was standing on the front line as
the candidate for Multnomah County
because I understood it to be a health
necessity I understood that having
access to it that it would decrease the
necessity for our courts to deal with us
on a criminal level and would encourage
our health departments and our health
resource operators to utilize it as a
leverage where there is no opportunity
for those that do not have access to the
health care that will make us healthy we
know our Esso works it's on the record
it works
we know that legal consumption is done
properly through our through our process
don't let somebody who's never used we
tell you how to policy it how to
legislate it how to make it right we
know it's normal for us we don't want to
be normalized by the [ __ ] politics
so let's create where we need and let's
do it together smoke