so I want to talk to everybody today
about a couple things the big things I
want to talk to people today about our
prison incarceration compassion and
making this a better place for us not
only here in Oregon where it's really
really really really wonderful and I
hope you all realize that right now
I've got enough marijuana in my pocket
to send me to prison for the rest of my
life in certain places in the United
States okay so I want you to understand
that you're living in a place right now
where marijuana is very very legal
there's a lot of people in this country
who don't have that they don't have that
ability and so what I want to talk to
about today and one of the people I
really want to talk about is Bernard
Noble does anybody here know Bernard
Noble is raise your hand if you know
Bernard Noble is I got you rust I got my
team over here I got Raphael over here I
got anybody else anybody else here who's
done five plus years in prison anybody
you back there come up for a minute I
want you to come up it's important and
you don't have to I'm not going to talk
I'm not gonna say anything about you
specifically but I want people to
understand something here we've got this
man here has done over five years in
prison understand that Bernard Noble
Louisiana 13-year minimum mandatory
sentence can anybody tell me how much
marijuana
mr. noble had on him when he was
sentenced to 13 years in prison from a
mandatory minimum miss Johnson come up
here that much marijuana this sent a man
to prison for 13 goddamn years okay a
lot of lawyers worked really hard a lot
of people worked really hard a lot of
advocates worked really hard can anyone
tell me how much time mr. noble actually
served seven years seven goddamn years
in prison for an amount of marijuana can
you hold that up for me miss Johnson
dadah marijuana marijuana sent a man to
prison for seven years in this country
right now okay that's what we're living
with in America this this bottle right
here this is 30 years to life in
Mississippi this is what stops people's
seizures this is what
people from being in chronic pain all
day this is what stops people from
hurting every day of their life and for
some of us out there it just makes us
feel good after work so we don't have to
drink three shots of whiskey okay so I
want to be really clear we live in an
amazing place in Oregon any one of you
who's 21 years of age or older or 18 and
older and a medical patient can walk
into a store and buy this this was given
to me today by someone who has the right
to make it because Oregon has homegrown
we have the right to grow your own
medicine or recreation as you see fit
and we fought really hard for that
privilege not every state has that every
state will have that that will happen
that day will come back because that day
was not that long ago we will end
marijuana prohibition entirely in this
country one day at a time one person at
a time one prisoner at a time I want you
to understand though I want you everyone
in here to think for a moment this
gentleman spent five plus years in
prison okay what I want right now from
everyone here is something really simple
and it's silence I want everyone here to
take 30 seconds and I want you to think
about what it would be like to spend the
next five years of your life in prison
for the amount of marijuana that I'm
holding in my hand okay I'm gonna time
it I'm gonna shut up it's really rare
that I shut up so starting now thirty
seconds of silence
you just did 30 seconds the man who just
walked off the stage did five years
Bernard Noble did seven years four
months and a couple days and he still
he's on parole he's still getting drug
tested every month he's still in the
position that if he screws up in the
slightest if he so much as runs a red
light that man's back in prison over two
grams of marijuana so I want everyone
here today to think about what it would
be like to spend that amount of time in
a metal cage over a plant because that's
what we're still dealing with in America
every single one of you here today has
the right to walk around as long as
you're an adult with an ounce of
marijuana in your pocket and no one gets
to say much else to you and that's a
wonderful privilege that we live in such
a place but it's not finished just
because it's done here doesn't mean it's
done everywhere else I don't know if you
noticed or not but my accent ain't from
here I'm originally from North Carolina
my family members died in prison okay I
had friends and family who in cages they
went there for years and years and years
for an amount of marijuana that honestly
people in stores here throw on a counter
and can sell to you I want you to
understand that we have it really really
good we have it amazing in Oregon we
have a system here that rivals any in
the US are we going to make it better
yes there are problems with it everyone
here knows if you're involved in this
fight that it's not perfect but I would
I want you to understand is that when
people come here from Mississippi when
they come here from Louisiana when they
come here from Idaho when they come here
from the south when they come here from
other countries where marijuana is the
death penalty they come to a place that
allows them freedom that allows the
compassion and allows us to live in a
better world because we get to share
with those people thank you very much
I appreciate all of you okay I'm gonna
do one last thing and I do it every year
I have to do it and it is this this is
my lighter I don't know if you've ever
seen it it's my business card it's what
I give out to people it's my way of
making the world a better place
because it's free legal advice it'll
keep you out of 99% of your problems
what we're going to do is we're gonna
walk through it it says one simple thing
am I free to go officer if I am being
detained
I do not consent to any searches and I
want to speak with my attorney prior to
answering any questions once again am I
free to go
officer if I am being detained I do not
consent to any searches and I want to
speak with my attorney prior to
answering any questions I can't fix
every single one of your problems but
what I can do with this is keep the cops
out of your life out of your car out of
your home out of your lives out of your
children's lives and make the world a
better [ __ ] place