so 2015
July 1st
it's legal we did it we actually did it
it's done we're gonna make it better
Russ talked about all the areas that
we've got to make better and Russ has
actually got my banner thank you thanks
for us
um
I've gone in the course of my career
I've been doing marijuana politics
marijuana policy and marijuana law for
the last 15 plus years
um I've gone in the course of my career
from doing almost exclusively criminal
defense every day I would wake up and
deal with somebody who had gotten busted
somebody who had to talk to the police
somebody who had a friend in jail a
parent in jail a child in jail
there were so many people every day who
came to me because somebody was in jail
was in custody was facing Court was
facing jail was facing prison was facing
trial I can tell you today I have less
than 10 criminal cases right now
okay
that's a big change most of the work I
do at this point isn't for people who
are looking at going to prison it's for
people who are looking at opening a
business paying their taxes being an
above-board member of society who can
walk into an establishment and say yeah
I'm in the marijuana industry that's
what I do
um and that change in the last 15 years
has been Monumental I remember when
people even mentioning the word
marijuana people would walk away from
you people would literally distance
themselves from you in public the other
day I was on a flight I was coming back
from Colorado it's coming back from The
High Times Cannabis Cup
um and someone on the plane said hey
I think someone has a skunk on board
and called a flight attendant it was an
it was a very nice older lady she said I
think there's a skunk on the plane
and the gentleman behind her started
laughing and about half the plane
started laughing because almost everyone
on that flight was coming back from
Denver from the cup to Portland and they
and the flight attendant looked around
and she said no it's illegal to have
marijuana on the plane but I'm sure that
everyone who had marijuana back in
Denver left it in Denver and we all went
yes flight attendant of course we left
our marijuana back in Denver
and so I want to explain to this very
nice lady that's what marijuana smelled
like and we all went about our day and
laughed nowhere Marshall jumped up
nobody was in handcuffs nobody was on
the ground being searched nobody was
detained from the flight none of those
things happened and 10 years ago
all those things would have been
happening
okay
um so I want to tell you today I I am so
happy to be here I'm so happy to have
spent time effort and energy with all of
you wonderful people getting to where we
are and I'm so thank you and I'm so
happy that moving forward we're gonna
make things better legalization's gonna
come legalization is going to get better
each and every year and it's going to
require each and every one of you who's
here today to do the same thing that
we've been doing for years and years and
decades and that's fight and then stand
up and say you know what we're
responsible productive members of
society we choose to use marijuana we
may use that instead of something else
we may drink a beer and have a joint
sometimes but for everybody who wants to
be a responsible adult marijuana
consumer this is what freedom is going
to look like it's going to look like a
world where you don't have to look over
your shoulder it's going to look like a
world where you don't have to call me at
3am and have someone bail you out of
jail because you had an had 29 grams
instead of 28.3 that was a money last
year okay a felony that meant that you
were a felon for a very long time in the
state of Oregon you were on probation
you were paying fines you were paying in
a cup
as of July 1st you can have a half pound
of marijuana in your home and I agree
with Russ 100 okay I think marijuana
consumers should be treated equally I
think we should have the same rights and
that's going to take some time but you
also need to remember there are places
in this country where eight ounces of
marijuana will send you to [ __ ]
prison
okay and we're gonna be in a place where
that's not gonna happen and what we've
got to do is we've got to work here to
make it better and for those of us and I
don't know if you know this but given
I'm wearing a seersucker suit you might
have guessed them from the south I'm
originally from North Carolina
there are places where marijuana is
still deeply illegal the amount of
marijuana that you're allowed to possess
in this state can send you to prison for
the rest of your natural life in the
state of Mississippi
okay no parole no probation no nothing
you're going to prison and you're
staying there for the rest of your life
so for everyone who's lived here
everyone who's grown up here everyone
who's worked so hard here whenever you
talk to someone who's not from here make
sure you explain to them that it's
possible it's workable you can make
changes we saw Oklahoma and Georgia both
pass medical marijuana bills this year
let me repeat that Oklahoma
Georgia both Southern States states that
we did not expect to see any traction
and they're not perfect bills don't get
me wrong I I don't want to pretend they
are but change does not come in one Fell
Swoop okay things are made day by day
this Plaza was not made by every single
one of these bricks instantly
materializing in front of us okay this
Plaza was made by people one brick at a
time putting these bricks in place and
the only way that we move forward the
only way that we make this happen is
that each and every one of us Works each
day to make things a little better every
day I wake up and I deal with marijuana
law there's not a day of my life that I
have not thought about or dealt with
marijuana okay and I'm not asking
everybody here to do that I'm not asking
everybody here to be an activist every
single day for eight hours a day but if
you can be an activist for five minutes
a day even something as simple as
calling your elected representative when
you're listening to Russ's show
something as simple as sending an email
once a week you know what and if you
can't do that donate some money put it
on your credit card make it an automatic
deposit make it an automatic every month
you don't have to think about it what is
it worth to be able to walk down the
street have an ounce of marijuana in
your pocket and never have to think
about a Cop arresting you ever again
okay
that's important finally there are still
things that can get you arrested there
are still crimes most of the people I
represent most of the cases I deal with
they are high level cases they are the
sort of cases that most of you will
never contemplate will never consider
but frankly if you've ever bought
marijuana on the black market or you've
ever received marijuana it had to come
from somewhere someone had to grow it
someone had to make it and there's a
bunch of people who've been taking a lot
of risks over the years and a lot of
those people are the people I represent
and the people I still represent so one
thing I want to remind everybody of is
how to be safe how to stay out of
trouble I'm sure most of you have seen
one of my cards or one of my lighters or
you've seen Paul's card you've seen
Paul's lighter and I just want to remind
everybody of what it says because
frankly even if you do have a legal
amount of marijuana in your pocket it
doesn't mean you've got to consent to a
police search it doesn't mean you've got
to talk to them or deal with them if you
don't want to
I always tell people remember to be
polite and we're going to go through it
so
am I free to go officer
if I am being detained
I do not consent to any searches
and I want to speak to my attorney
prior to answering any questions
I give these away I put myself out of
business every day and that's my goal
one day I hope to not have to do this
for criminals I hope to be doing this
for law-abiding citizens who want to
make the world a better place and share
with their community so remember this if
you need a lighter grab them from the
table I give them away for free