global warming is a real thing and so is
legalization in Oregon and I have to
admit that it hasn't played out the way
that I hoped it would I was hoping that
they would follow what the law as we
wrote it not rip it to shreds and
especially not endanger our medical
marijuana program and so here's my
challenge for every one of you today I
follow a lot of you on facebook and I
see you out there complaining about what
you don't like about how things are
playing out and I want you to know that
you have the opportunity every time you
post one of those things on Facebook you
can send it to your representative and
let them know how you feel too you can
send it to the committee that's making
these rules most of what you have never
smoked a joint in their lives much less
have a clue about how the plan works for
the rest of us let them know to stop
posting it on Facebook send it to your
representatives nobody cares on facebook
facebook is not real people your
representatives are real you can find
them in the time it takes you to write
one of those posts and you can send that
note via email or my favorite thing to
do call their office number on a Sunday
guess what happens you go straight to
voicemail nobody put you on hold you
leave your message that says save our
medical marijuana program save the
60,000 plus people who are registered
save our children who need this medicine
and stop the over-regulation and
ridiculousness that they're trying to
pull with legalization I'm pissed off
still and I've been fighting this fight
for 15 years and I'll find it for 15
more until these people get it right and
you guys can do help me do that and it's
going to take all of us I don't care
what organization you're with out here
or who you don't like and who you do
like every single one of us can contact
our representatives and once we start
doing that just like how we got Ellen
Rosenblum we have a voice there are tons
of us tons of us and I wish that
everybody who ever smoked weed was here
right now because it's time for things
to change
I'm so happy to see people like Jennifer
valiant Jesse spawn Berg running for
public office and being vocal about
their cannabis use it's time to remove
the stigma that we suffer as cannabis
consumers i'm pretty set up how do you
guys feel about that are you pissed what
are you going to do about it that's
right this fight is not over nor will it
be until everyone is free I want to see
everybody out of prison I want to see
nobody going back to prison I want to
see parents being able to choose what
kind of medication they want for their
children for themselves and for me as a
STONER for 46 years I just want to go
home after work and smoke a joint
instead of drinking a beer and I think
that's okay and it doesn't make me a bad
person I'm a good person I just happen
to like weed I work hard I pay my taxes
I make my car payments pretty much on
time so you know I'm just like everybody
else and so are plenty of other stoners
out there so you guys if you don't do
anything else in the upcoming year when
you post those posts on Facebook copy
and paste them and send them to your
representatives send them to that joint
committee and let them know that we're
not going to stand for this over
regulation five thousand dollars for a
dispensary license four hundred dollars
for a liquor license that's
discrimination and I'm sick of it my
name is Ana Diaz I'm a proud stoner join
me and let's be free at last thank you