I am the vice president of a Civil
Rights group called The Human solution
International we are a group that
believes that nobody should go to jail
or die for our plant so today I brought
with you guys some of my members from
Washington we've got Tony here and Adam
and Al together around the nation
internationally we are working to end
prohibition
2014 by delivering support right to the
front lines of where this war is
affecting us the most regarding our
defendant and our prisoners right now in
the United States of America while we
call it legal in all these states we
still have over 50 people serving life
sentences for marijuana and they will
never get out we also have defendants
right here in Oregon facing time jail
time prison time we have a we have two
chapters now in Oregon so I'm going to
invite you guys to get involved I'm
going to invite you guys to please come
out to the courtrooms when we have
hearings when people are at risk of
going to jail I'm going to invite you
guys to know that we have people right
here in your state that are in jail for
marijuana one being my dad's business
partner Chris Williams okay if you guys
don't know who I am my name is Kristen
Flor and I am the vice president of the
human solution International because my
father he died a couple years ago a very
tormenting and nasty nasty nasty death
in federal custody Shackled to a
hospital bed because our plant is still
federally illegal so while we celebrate
all these laws we have a nasty federal
law that will shackle us and put us in
prison for the rest of our lives just by
following these laws because they
contradict each other when my dad died
he died with broken ribs undiagnosed
colon cancer liver failure all kinds of
nasty things happened to him why they
kept my mom in prison as well and all
they did is own a company and follow the
state laws Montana his business partner
right here he went to trial the jury
didn't even know he was a caregiver how
many people he helped because they don't
allow state laws in federal court my
dad's other two business partners
testified against him so how are we
going to end prohibition
2015 well we are not going to snitch on
each other we're not going to cooperate
with the government and give them our
information in fact we're going to stand
up for each other we're going to go to
the courtrooms we're going to wear these
ribbons these ribbons that you see me
wearing that means that nobody deserves
to go to jail for a plant we're going to
wear them in the courtroom so the judges
the prosecutors and the jury sees them
we're going to know about our jury
rights that's your power to say not
guilty if you think a law is bad and
you're a juror you have a right not to
only judge if the law has been broken
but to judge that law and if you think
it's a bad law you can say not guilty
and refuse to send somebody to jail for
a victimless
crime that's something they won't teach
you in schools that we have to teach
each other so we're going to end
prohibition through one court support
two jury nullification and educating
about it and number three we're going to
defend our prisoners we're going to
educate about our prisoners and let
people know that they're working as
slaves for the top 1% of our nation in
private prisons and they are killing
them if they can't work for them and
they're paying them less than 152 cents
an hour so I'm going to urge you guys to
get involved with the human solution we
just started a chapter in Kenya Africa
we're very excited to be in prohibition
on a national level so please join our
go to our website
www.ts n.org find out how you can help
volunteer start a chapter come to a
couple chapter meetings we have Becca
and we have um Mindy and they started a
chapter here and they're meeting every
month you can come out and find out
what's going on in your community you
can read the Oregon Leaf right now the
human solution delivers all the news
from the Fright lines in a new magazine
that's just been delivered all across
your state in the Oregon Leaf you can
find out all the current news right
there you can go to the calendar on on
our website and find out what defendants
in your area need your support and you
can show up you can also we have a
chapter down in Southern Southern Oregon
Joy Graves who's one of our defendants
is also leading that chapter so you can
visit our website see what see what's
going on in Oregon and um other than
that know your jury rights also I can
also encourage you guys not to just come
for our defendants but you can actually
join as members and have be a card
carrying member we have a man by the
name of Mr Tommy Chong that we all know
very well who is a card carrying member
of the human solution International so
um I can encourage everybody that tell
everybody that nobody nobody ever
deserves to go to prison for our plant
and to pay attention and to help end the
war right from the front lines thank you
you guys and it's really nice to meet
you and I'm excited to be in Washington
in Oregon thank you