how y'all doing out there Portland
Oregon so let me start off by telling
you a little bit about myself I have
muscular distrophy I was diagnosed at
the age of three in my first electric
chair by the age of five I was known as
a pothead people ever understood that uh
I needed certain things to make my days
go well when I uh learned that I wasn't
a pothead I was a medicator I was free
from the
world
so you know we have uh women children
men out there that are dying because
they cannot get this plant they cannot
have free access to the meds they need
they are not able to get themselves out
of bed they are not able to maintain a
family life because the government says
we are wrong you all feel we are wrong I
don't I think we all deserve the right
to be free and to uh take the medicine
we need to help us relieve our
lifestyles and pains whether it be PTSD
Tremors stomach aches whatever if you
know it's your medicine you deserve the
right to use
it
um it's just uh to me it's just really
sad that that people are dying and
people have to fight for it I if you
cannot have access to your medicine
what are you going to do you you go you
fight you fight you fight just to tell
be told you're going to die it's not
right you know we we have the access we
need to make it right for everybody so
I'm going to wrap it up make it real
kind of quick and simple medical social
recreational whatever it is you all have
the right to choose if you need it or
not and on that note let's get ready for
this great March