hello Portland wow thanks for having me
I believe this is my third year speaking
and this summer marks the fourth year
that my daughter is in remission thank
you to cannabis oil cannabis oil
provided my seven-year-old daughter who
was fighting cancer the chance to end or
two and a half years of chemotherapy
without a single Tylenol not only that
she didn't lose a single pound and she
had a smile on her face the entire time
she fought she finished chemotherapy
about a year and a half ago and just
recently we hit one year off treatment
when we hit that mark our oncologist
came and told us that because McCalebb
replaced brain radiation in high-dose
chemotherapy with cannabis oil she has a
lower chance of a secondary cancer
relapse because of cannabis out of every
child that has ever endured leukemia
treatment my daughter has a lower chance
of a secondary cancer that means 10
years from now my child's not gonna have
a brain tumor from the radiation to
treat her leukemia and to me that is
extremely important that every child in
our country has that option so it's
great here that we have legal cannabis
in the state of Oregon and we can smoke
our bowls at home if we're 21 and older
and our children can be on a medical
program but that's not the way it is
across our country and our fight is not
done so please if there's anything I can
everyone to do is to not think our job
is done because our job is nowhere near
done our job is not done in our own
state and our job is not done across our
country and across the world if I can
urge you guys all to use your voices if
you find out somebody has cancer seizure
is epilepsy Alzheimer's any medical
condition heard him to get on the
medical marijuana program keep our
medical marijuana program in Oregon it
saves lives if we get rid of it my
daughter cannot have her oil she has
been taking cannabis oil for four years
she has straight A's she's doing amazing
in school she's surpassing all of the
expectations she's just like a normal
child and another importance is this is
not just CBD that I'm talking about my
daughter takes THC psychoactive THC
there's something called a tolerance
it's okay i promise you morphine gets
the kids higher than the cannabis oil
and I didn't have to experience morphine
or addiction or any of that that comes
along with opioid pain medication that
they treat children with in our state in
every other state we need to shy away
from opioid pain medicine thank you for
having me for another great year thank
you for attending and marching and
uniting for this great cause