I am Doug McVeigh I'm the editor of a
thing called drug war facts at drug war
facts dot org please do check it out on
the web
it's your premier source for information
on drugs drug policies here in the
United States and around the world I
also do some I'll do some radio work you
may heard me on KBOO I have a show
called free culture radio also have a
thing called century of lies it goes out
once a week and I gotta tell you it's a
pleasure it's such an honor to be at the
global marijuana March this has a long
history I don't know if you know aware
of this but before there was the global
marijuana walk global marijuana March a
little bit of a mouthful there was the
million marijuana March and before the
million marijuana March as my friend
Paul Stanford and I were discussing
yesterday there was the made a pot
parade now May Day the first of May is
May Day some of you many of you may be
aware but in case you're not
May Day is the International Day of
worker solidarity May Day is an event
around the world where tens of thousands
hundreds of thousands of people gather
and rally for individual rights has been
for decades since well before the
marijuana movement started doing
something on this day some people wonder
well you got something on 4/20 why are
you doing May Day yeah whatever
4/20 is a day of enforced reality if
y'all really want to go out and have a
party on Hitler's birthday y'all have
fun I'll stay home or I'll cover an
event that's actually going on but May
Day now that's something special in this
country we have lost sight of that labor
unions not being what they used to be we
have sort of lost sight and people like
myself who are proud to call ourselves
socialists may not necessarily see a lot
of us out here but there are Mayday
events and for me this this is our
Mayday this is our day to reach out in
solidarity with others and say we are
your neighbors we're your friends were
your family members we smoke weed we
like weed we think that pot should be
legal and we ask you people to join with
us in calling for that it's not so we
can have a party
have a party anytime if it weren't for
legalization and drug policy or form
work I'd have a lot more time for
partying all right I'm doing this
because it's important because it's
about freedom because it's about justice
and it's because it's what's right
social justice is where it's at
there's a thing called harm reduction
where you try to reduce the harms that
people do to themselves and you manage
the risks that people expose themselves
to drinking drinking alcohol maybe just
one drink an hour so that your body
metabolizes that's called harm reduction
not taking a shot of whiskey to wash
down your opiate that's harm reduction
because you could kill yourself doing
that smoking marijuana to relieve your
minor pains rather than taking an opioid
that's harm reduction okay simple
concept when we give out clean syringes
to people who insist on injecting drugs
people who inject drugs are people -
they're our friends they're our family
members they're our sisters and our
brothers they're our parents they're our
spouses
they're our partners they're our friends
they're people so we can either leave
them to get sick and to die or we can do
something about it right now
Portland there are a handful of people
who've been working for a little while
and it's getting a little bigger trying
to put something together called a
supervised injection facility I know
little off-topic this is a weed thing
but you know we got here because the
drug policy reform and we got here
because people are willing to break the
law to do what they think is right now
we have a syringe exchange that's run by
the county in this area Multnomah County
a wonderful thing but we need more
because the overdose crisis and because
really resources just being outstripped
so a lot of folks are working to get
this area to consider a supervised to
consumption facility a safe consumption
space a safe injection facility the city
of New York is running close King County
Seattle is trying they're trying to get
this done in San Francisco they hope to
have it in fact by sometime this summer
down in San Francisco Portland it's our
turn
we've been a leader in all this stuff
we've been a leader in marijuana
legalization in medical marijuana and in
harm reduction for a very long time it's
because people like you come out to
events like this and let elected leaders
and officials and just these I'll be
nice people in places like Studio on the
square we let them know that we really
are serious that we want this stuff to
change and we're not going to go away
until it's happened and frankly we're
still going to be here because it's
still not going to be perfect and
there's still a lot of work to be done
sure we have medical but god help you if
you live in an apartment or federally
subsidized housing sure we have
legalization of course do be careful if
you try and consume out here because
it's illegal to consume in public and
there are very likely people who would
have you arrested so you know okay I'm
gonna get through and wrap this up in a
second so here's the thing marijuana
legalization is a great thing drug
decriminalization is absolutely vital
harm reduction is important all this
stuff is why I do what I do I volunteer
several hours a week doing radio
production I manage a few hours of
working for a few different groups
patients at a time oh yeah
before I leave I need to remind you
patients at a time terrific resource
still working on medical cannabis still
working to educate health care
professionals and the public have a
conference coming up May 10th through
12th it's going to be in Jersey City but
hey some flights are cheap if you got a
chance and we'll have some video after
the event you can check it out again my
name is Doug McVeigh drug war facts org
you can find a lot more information and
all this stuff I've been talking about I
want to thank you all for being here you
are beautiful
happy May Day