let's unite today under one Banner
normal normal Women's Alliance organ
greenfree THC all of the
organizations Green Leaf loves everybody
the wellness center cannibis we're all
out here doing the same damn thing
trying to end prohibition like yna said
I'm tired tired tired of seeing my
people go to jail I deal with women
every day and men that cry because their
children are taken away from them you
know you think medical marijuana is
enough but it's not enough to protect
your parental custody rights they will
take your baby and just like L Reinhardt
is that what her name is Lindsay
Reinhardt she came over here and spoke
here for freedom and they took her baby
from
her how can you think medical marijuana
is enough it is not enough when our
people are being incarcerated when our
economy is suffer uing while other
Count's economies prosper from
industrial H it is
ridiculous and you know what the biggest
complaint as we moved forward with our
um House Bill
3371 was we didn't get complaints from
the state police we got complaints from
the local sheriff saying where's our cut
so this is time for us to do it you
contact your representatives and you let
them know that it is time to move
forward with house
3371 to allow us to build colleges and
not more prisons let's send our kids to
college let's stop sending our kids and
our future to prison you know I'm the
grandmother of six children three boys
three girls and I'm proud as hell and
you know what I fear every day that they
are being
disproportionately not only um
incarcerated but racial profiling is a
huge problem Across the Nation our
prisons are filled with blacks and
whites poor whites and brown people like
me and I'm tired of
it you know just because we bought
bought brought marijuana to this country
God dang guys we try to do something
good y'all love it when you're getting
high don't put us in jail
now right help us out folks and I want
to thank Russ and Aiko this guy who took
over Oregon normal and it lives on baby
Scott Poney Lee Burger all of you guys I
love you all come to the Cannabis Cafe
let's go
party girl