how high are you I mean hi how are you
my name is radical Russ Belleville I'm
the co partner in Delta nine house
Portland's 420 friendliest air B&amp;B and
I'm also the host of the marijuana
agenda podcast check it out on iTunes
and all other outlets I've traveled all
across North America these past thirteen
years fighting for the end of adult
marijuana prohibition and I'm happy to
say it is a beautiful day to be here in
legal pot land Oregon yeah so maybe
you're thinking though marijuana is
legal so what do we got to March about
that's a good question
when this March first started in 1999
there were no legal states and there
were only five medical marijuana States
when I started doing this March in 2005
two out of three people nationwide
opposed legalization of marijuana today
support the legalization of marijuana we
have nine legal states we have 29
medical marijuana states we have 17 CBD
only states we're down to just four
states in America that have absolute
cannabis prohibition so we've made a lot
of progress but folks legal ain't equal
legal eight equal we can still lose our
jobs for smoking legal marijuana we can
still have our gun rights denied for
smoking legal marijuana we can still
have our children taken away for us for
legal marijuana and we still have no
public place where we can gather with
other adults and smoke legal marijuana
so folks legal ain't equal in our
personal lives and legal ain't equal in
our business lives I'd like to quote my
friend Jody Emery in Canada who said we
thought legalization meant the existing
marijuana industry would be
legal but that's not what's happening
we're finding a legalization industry
that's squeezing out the family farmer
that's squeezing out the minority
distributor that's right folks
blacks and hippies did the time but
whites and yuppies are making the dimes
and that's something we need to change
we heard a lot as we were trying to
legalize marijuana about treat marijuana
like alcohol treat marijuana like
alcohol but legal alcohol can take
business deductions on their taxes that
legal marijuana can't take legal alcohol
doesn't have to worry about its bank
accounts getting closed but legal
marijuana does and legal alcohol doesn't
have to worry about federal interference
but legal marijuana does legal aid equal
especially on this Cinco de Mayo when
right down there at Tom McCall
Waterfront Park the place is packed with
parents and children at a place that is
sponsored a three-day outdoor drinking
festival sponsored by Modelo and
speciale Corona extra Negra Modelo and
cerveza Pacifico that you can drink
right out in the open in front of kids
but right here in Pioneer Courthouse
Square for our marijuana festival
marijuana is invisible so legal ain't
equal we also insisted that legalization
should not harm medical marijuana
we've said it three times in measure 91
so what is the state doing denying
out-of-state patient cards steep
reductions in growth sites invasive
tracking and inspections complex
regulations and exorbitant fees that are
driving growers out of the program these
drastic changes to the medical cannabis
program are unconscionable this state
charges $200
that's the highest fee in the 29 states
that have medical marijuana for a second
abled person to join a medical marijuana
program that's always run a surplus
always run a surplus and then the state
goes and diverts money from that surplus
to balance the budget of other failing
bureaucracies then has the gall to come
back to our growers and say they got a
pain
what is it 40 bucks a month for some
invasive tracking program they're so
messed up that they're driving growers
out of this program we are marching
today because we got it legal but legal
a equal legal ain't equal of the olcc
they're so afraid of pot that they have
devoted only twice as many resources to
the minor decoy operations the stings
try to get underaged buys twice as many
to alcohol as looted of marijuana but
there are 10 times as many alcohol
outlets as there are marijuana outlets
and then they're shocked when they come
back and find in the past five decoy
operations 100% compliance in the
marijuana side but they have nothing to
say about the fact that in the last five
alcohol decoy operations one out of
every eight teenagers was successfully
able to buy alcohol with a real ID with
a red box around their head that says
they're not legal treat alchemy rowana
like alcohol we had a treat alcohol like
marijuana we seem to be doing a much
better job of controlling it and legal
ain't equal to the Oregon Health
Association either Oregon Health
Administration they're so fearful of
gaming the system that they've turned
the system into an expensive game that
most growers don't want to play anymore
then they're upset when our patients who
can't find any return to the unregulated
untaxed underground market that OHA was
passing these laws to try to eliminate
in the first place and most of all legal
ain't equal to the Oregon Legislature
how else can you explain a Clean Air Act
that bans indoor smoking because we
proved secondhand tobacco smoke was
harmful
but then it's amended by the legislature
to include cannabis vapor which has
never been proven to be harmful a Clean
Air Act that offers an exception for
cigar bars to allow to backhoe smoking
but doesn't allow an exemption for
cannabis smoking legal ain't equal and I
say what the hell good is a right if you
got no place to exercise it we're
marching today because we want our equal
rights we deserve to be treated with the
same decency and respect as any cigar
smoker any beer drinker any whiskey
chugger any chewing tobacco user we
deserve equal rights
if society's figured out how to
accommodate the beer drinkers and
accommodate the cigar smokers they
should just apply those rules to us as
well any place I can smoke a cigar I
should be able to smoke a joint any
place I can do a shot of whiskey I
should be able to do a dab are you with
me thank you for coming out today I'm
radical Russ Bella you can check me out
radical rest com delta-9 house.com
and the marijuana agenda thank you
everyone