when you picture a cannabis consumer who
is it that comes to mind I hope that
that image that used to be one of lazy
stoner stupid hungry all of the all of
the awful Serio types that are
absolutely not true I hope that those
that image of who a cannabis consumer
for you has changed because I know for
me it certainly has we are not lazy we
are in fact more motivated than nearly
anybody on the planet I was reading an
article yesterday saying that people who
consume cannabis and exercise exercise
for longer I mean we're really finding
some cool trends and this the stigmas
are being shattered about who cannabis
consumers are for me as a mother as a
woman as a business owner as someone who
volunteers with nonprofits and advocates
for education choices and all of the
cannabis legalization things
particularly social consumption which is
on the topic that I'm particularly
interested in as well I implore all of
you to support the social consumption
movement going on there is a place to
sign up over there but I know for me as
a woman in this world right now I want
to scream from the rooftops that I am a
cannabis consumer I don't look like the
typical cannabis consumer although today
I may in my cannabis dress which I wear
proudly
but in other areas of my life I don't
look like a cannabis consumer and I go
out of my way to tell everybody that I
am because I think it's up to each of us
right now to go out into the world and
say this is my medicine and I know so
many other people that are finding
healing relief from cannabis as well
[Applause]
my teenage self would have never
believed what I would do when I grew up
I pinched myself nearly every day my
name is Samantha Montanaro and I'm the
co-founder of toca tivity the global
cannabis community for women we have
women's communities that organize events
in the United States South Africa Spain
and Canada and soon 135 other cities
around the world
something that I have learned from this
women's community is the ultimate love
that cannabis brings to the surface and
how cannabis can be a vehicle for us
being our best selves women when they
get together and consume cannabis
together there is this this swirling
magical energy that is really truly
magical and I think we all regardless of
gender feel that when we consume
cannabis it is such a beautiful plant
and it is my life's work from now until
forever she advocated for the walls
coming down around cannabis for equal
access and really for global
legalization
[Music]
we have an opportunity right now to be
pioneers each and every one of you by
just going out into the world and saying
I'm a cannabis consumer or by sharing on
your Facebook but hey there's this is a
place where you can sign a ballot or by
going into your dispensary if you're not
Atkins cannabis consumer and going in
and starting to learn about what this
plant has to offer we all have an
opportunity to be a true pioneer in this
space right now there's more than enough
room we have a long ways to go until
everybody's out of jail there's so much
work to do and we need every single
person on board so I I really implore
you to join me and so many others here
you can find out more about what we do
at taupe activity comm and again my name
is Samantha thank you so much for having
me here thank you so much to all of the
absolute legends whom I have adored and
been humbled by your advocacy in your
leadership has made me a leader and I
will continue to take my leadership and
turn other people into leaders as well
thank you so much for everything and
what an honor thank you