hello everybody how you doing today I am
so so grateful to be here today with you
this be absolutely beautiful day in
downtown Portland um to free the plant
we have a lot of work to do um our earth
is hurting our people are hurting this
sacred balance of the feminine and
masculine is off it's really off and I
don't know about you but I believe that
cannabis is the key to restoring balance
to restoring equity and to restoring our
health with cannabis legalization we
have an opportunity to do things
differently I see this as an opportunity
for us to free our people who are
sitting in jail still right now as other
people profit off of this plant we have
an opportunity to create a solution to
our dependency on plastics on toxic
chemicals and on all sorts of things
that don't seem to make sense for us
anymore
hemp is a solution to many many many
things we have a chance to restore
equity for men and women for people of
all skin colors from all over the world
we have an opportunity to actually
create programs with equity built into
them I am envious of the other places
that are putting those policies into
place right now and I want Portland to
do the same and Oregon to do the same
for us to get you know give assistance
to the people that were in jail and
whatever else give them an opportunity
to be working in cannabis through
supportive programs grant programs and
just assistance I believe that this is
our duty finally I think that cannabis
legalization is an opportunity for
empowerment for women and men for us to
step up and take charge of our own lives
and our own health and our own people
why do you love cannabis I know I love
cannabis because it heals me for so many
different properties I have scoliosis
osteoarthritis
I'm a mom I need cannabis for so many
reasons on a daily basis and I think one
of my favorite things about cannabis is
it helps me work through challenges
emotional challenges if I'm ready to
work out something it will bring it up
and it will help me work through it
cannabis aids in our pain emotionally
and physically and until we realize this
I don't think the plant will be free
cannabis helps me see my truths and
cannabis helps me face my fears
we all deserve love happiness health
equal rights and access to clean
medicine my son carmine is here today
and I want him to live in a world where
he's free from shame around using
cannabis as medicine