I'll be doing out there today are we all
ready to march all right let's talk
about what today is all about all right
serious money today is about cannabis
today is about making it legal for
everybody not just us here in Oregon
that have already legalized it not just
Washington all the other ones who've
already got our legalized we want it
legalized globally all right this is the
day when we all get together and we
march as one unison to make this plant
legal for everybody all right so let's
keep that in mind and here's my other
thing the medical marijuana project here
we're all at risk if you need it for
medical reasons if you need it to make
your daily life happen we're in jeopardy
you all may not see it but we are
they're taking it from us day by day
minute by minute we're losing everything
we have you don't feel safe with that do
you want to pay these rising prices that
we have do you feel that you should have
to pay for your medicine pay for life no
everybody should have the right to have
life the freedom of the journey to live
is what we're here for all right so I'm
one of those that like to make it short
and sweet because that's how I do my
thing let's put our hands together let's
route it out let's enjoy this March for
everybody that deserves the right to
enjoy a plant called cannabis all right
so Portland Oregon let's line up when
it's time I let March for our freedom of
life all right here here Portland Oregon