this song is called medication
recreation
educate
to medicaid and recreation
no medicine
can't do
nothing quite like this
so please
give me my
cannabis
y'all see i smoke the kind of weed that
you see in your dreams straight outta
high times man you should see this green
cbd's lnns and that thc in your best not
forget about that thcv yes or these are
the things that your body may need to
help us get rid of your pain or maybe
through your disease so sit back with a
sack of the finest trees rolling up and
give your body what you know it needs
cannabis
educate
to medicaid and recreation
or medicine can do
nothing right like this
so please
give me my
cannabis
y'all know i hit that green carpet with
all the pot stars at the hot tops
cannabis cup and do you know where you
are smoking with my friend okay in that
vip and it's time for all dabs i guess
i'll take two or three yes and then
we'll smoke that j and pass along those
medicals have you seen this place man
these things are so incredible just
think about it weed as far as the eye
can see so come on and legalize and give
the people what they need
educate to medicaid and recreation
no medicine
can't do
nothing quite like
this so please
give me my
cannabis
very wanna
educate to medicaid and recreation
no medicine
can do
nothing quite like this
so please
give me mine
thank y'all very much my name is justin
james bridges you can check me out at
justinjamesbridges.com
free the weed