hey everybody welcome to the biggest
event the whole month of may in fact
Mays marijuana month have you heard that
medical marijuana month too we have a
lot to celebrate and one of the biggest
and most impressive reasons that we're
here today all comes together in this
one gentleman down here in the center
picture dr. Phil Leveque now a lot of
people have done a lot of things for
medical marijuana but very few have done
what dr. leveque has done for the state
of Oregon and for the world the whole
the whole globe believe me because he
was not just a spokesman he was a doctor
that believed in us he believed in
patients rights he believed in ending
pain ending the ability or the
disability to reach what you need to get
the wet the medicine that you really
need and he saw from a young age that
cannabis was that medicine he was born
in 1923 his dad was one of the great
loggers of Oregon and when his sons were
were young he told dr. Leveque and his
brother don't go into logging it's all
over got to find a new industry so that
was in the 30s so he did he went to
college and he got his degree in
biochemistry he joined Patton's army
thinking that he'd be able to help on
some fantastic level because of his
chemistry degree but instead they said
hey dude you're missing a couple of
fingers on your right hand you can't be
an officer so instead they made a joint
he joined the infantry and became a
scout and is one of the scouts that
actually lived from Patton's army he
crossed the Rhine his stories go on
forever and in fact this is his book dog
face soldier dhokla vex own book is
being Reata dright now but there are a
few copies that are available so he
wrote his memoirs of the war but when he
came back from the war he went to work
he was a doctor he got his degree the
people that he trained under new
about cannabis medicine because there
the old guys they've been using cannabis
medicine forever they never even
questioned whether or not they should
use it and so they so he discovered that
and still he would say right now should
he be here that there's a bottle of
cannabis medicine somewhere in his barn
from back then because it worked so well
he decided to keep it so he was a born
in the wool you know dyed-in-the-wool
cannabis Crusader from a young age he
had a lifetime of incredible experiences
he taught in Africa he was the first
manda to at first doctor to teach
surgeons brain surgery in Sierra Leone
in their brand new hospitals so he'd
made a lot of really great that you know
dedicated moves for all of us but when
it came to cannabis he came back to
Oregon he's had a practice and he soon
discovered where his real calling was
and this is it he put his all into he
got together with Paul Stanford Paul
Loney and a lot of other very important
folks and worked at the th CF clinic the
very first clinic in the state of Oregon
and he helped veterans he had over a
thousand veterans were his clients of
course he they were near and dear to his
heart but all of us were he testified
over four hundred times as a
toxicologist pharmacologist he had a PhD
and that he's one of the only
toxicologists in the country with those
credentials and we were lucky enough in
the state of Oregon to be able to have
him be with us represent us speak to our
legislature go to our hearings and he is
one of the greatest assets to the
medical marijuana program worldwide
that's ever existed and so it seems
almost fitting that last year on global
cannabis day he left us and passed on to
New Horizons better journeys no doubt
and so I am so honored to be able to be
the
one that says we dedicate this stage
right here global cannabis day global
cannabis march here in Portland Oregon
this stage is dedicated to dr. Phil
Leveque this is now the dr phil Leveque
memorial stage thank you guys so much
for coming you know being here is really
what it's about and every single one of
you is absolutely important and precious
to us so thank you very much and I'm you
know from doc what does doc have to say
don't smoke in the rain that's right