hi my name is brave michaela and i
kicked cancer's butt
with the help of cannabis oil
i have finished treatments six months
ago thank you all for the love and
support peace love here
hi thank you so much for being here
today my name is erin purchase and i am
michaela's mom
i am also a cannabis activist
i've been an activist long before she
got cancer that's how i knew to give her
cannabis oil 10 days after she was
diagnosed
i think it's important that all patients
get this oil right when they are
diagnosed because we never even lost she
never even lost a single pound going
through chemotherapy and never had to
take a tylenol and had a smile on her
face every day i think it's important
that every
child and adult have that right and in
order to do that we have to get our
doctors on board and in order to do that
we need to change the law at a federal
level congratulations oregon for
legalizing at a state level that's great
if we can get more states to do that
maybe we can overturn federal law it is
very very very important to my family
that we overturn this federal law and
researches began
michaela has a very rare form of acute
lymphoblastic leukemia
it has a low survival rate
75 percent i didn't have to worry about
that because i had cannabis oil
most most families don't have that and
they have a lot of anxiety as they're
going through treatments not only do
they have a lot of anxiety they're
dealing with a child who's suffering
with a feeding tube in their nose and
they have to stay in the hospital
sometimes over a year
we had 14 days in a hospital and the
only reason my daughter ever had to stay
in the hospital was because they gave
her forced me to give her drugs that put
her there she had two allergic reactions
one of them almost killed her because of
their medicine that she did not need
in order to prove that she did not need
it we have to change the federal law
also
at a st at a county level on a local
level you are all very important because
oregon has legalized cannabis
but they have also imposed a lot of
regulations that affect patients like
michaela
they have limited our medical marijuana
grows now inside city limits to 12
plants that's two patients we went from
being able to grow from four patients to
two
they have not passed that bill yet but
they're very close to passing it
come to salem we're there mondays and
wednesdays right now of 5 pm we need
your help we need your support we need
you to tell them we don't want to change
things like this
another thing you can do is go to your
county and city
commissioner meetings i've been to
clackamas county commissioner meetings
every single month and i'll tell you
what
as you guys are rushing out finding
warehouses they're imposing regulations
to zone you out
get to your county commissioner meeting
stop looking for a warehouse stop
looking for commercial property and get
to your legislators and your
representatives and start talking to
them about what you want to do
not only what you want to do for
the marijuana industry but you what you
want to do for our community because if
you don't support your community they're
not going to support you
please support your community get out
there make a difference
present yourself appropriately and
support this plan and let's get
somewhere because i don't want kids to
suffer and i just proved that they don't
have to she's done
she's in remission she's alive
more people need to know this more
doctors need to support this more
politicians need to be on our side let's
support the other industries the other
movements the other civil rights
movements
it will help our industry make it
further
um i want to say thank you so much to
sony girl gardens i'm now working with
them they're giving me the opportunity
to speak on your behalf
we um they also made the oil that saved
my daughter's life
and for that i can't thank them enough
so thank you jen and mike mullins
jennifer valley and mike mullins and
stony girl gardens you guys mean the
worlds to me thank you