you know I am the only candidate running
for Clackamas County Commissioner that
voted in favor of measure 91 I think
it's important that all of us who voted
for measure 91 get involved in our
communities at every level city county
state doesn't matter we all really need
to be involved and and talking to Oregon
Health Authority especially because
they're the ones who are running our
medical marijuana program straight into
the ground right now I am running for
Clackamas County Commission because when
we legalized marijuana fifty-seven
percent of clackamas county voters voted
in favor of it but not one of our
Clackamas County Commissioners did and
they decided to go with their vote when
it came time to make regulations they
didn't consider the fact that they were
on the losing side of that vote and
instead of opting out of legalization
they decided to zone it out and they
made it nearly impossible to start a
cannabis business in clackamas county
and that made me mad enough to want to
run for office and let them know that
they were wrong so I hope you'll all
support me in my run and I'd like to see
you all out there at the Oregon Health
Authority meetings have a great day
let's get to margin