here to go out there and to make a
difference talk to your legislatures
because now they're going to be running
for office they're going to be coming
asking you for their for your vote
and that's you know they want your vote
so you're going to have to ask them
where do they stand on cannabis right
to ask them how do they stand where they
stand with cannabis
they're not gonna stop us they're just
gonna incarcerate us and it needs to end
yesterday
marijuana is not going to re-legalize
itself
and if you're not registered to vote
then you're not going to be part of
making a change
stop pretending that the drug war is
working we need to stop pretending that
dare is working because none of them are
working
none of them are working
so please do what you can to support
ending cannabis prohibition
as we know it
but you know it's real important to
support the octa the i-24 the sensibles
the whatever comes upon you for freedom
man and for what your rights are i mean
a lot of these they're so close you know
they're all on this train they're
different
they're all part of different groups but
they're all on the same train and they
get on that train in the morning and
they cruise forward and that's what we
got to do our train in our community is
one train and that's the cannabis train
and we all need to get on the cannabis
train
and chug a lug for freedom