i was so happy that i got my medical
card
now i don't need one
no i don't need one
so i'm gonna tell y'all
why we enjoy
that beautiful
and nyquil don't help me sleep all i
need is a puff of a good green tree i
smoke help alleviate my pain i smoke to
open up my super brains
help me manage my life's problems
take me from here
she's so relaxing she's my prescription
she grows on branches she helps me deal
with the extent
she takes all the stress far away from
the brain go for my suitable
he'll take
i
ladies and gentlemen
on guitar
courtesy of my man justin
make some noise for mr reynell hall
y'all
in town from los angeles give it to him
right now
just the bridges
yes
hey y'all
last time i saw this guy he needed a
wheelchair to get around he's not
walking it's my man justin bridges y'all
justin james aka the mad dab
he told me a little bit ago he said man
i haven't done any pharmaceuticals
in two years it's all been massage
therapy and cannabis and cannabis and
cannabis and cannabis massage therapy
and cannabis
and cannabis and cannabis massage
therapy and cannabis and cannabis and
cannabis it was massage therapy and
cannabis tell us
how to do it
took a little bit of cannabis and then
you see it makes me what yes it opened
up my mind and then i'm free of the
chair and i'm walking again and yes i
sit back and yes i'm just grinding with
friends and yes we wrecking flipping
going off ain't gonna be spitting if we
always coming through and yes we always
gonna be hitting it and yes i pass it to
the left and maybe to the right but i'm
gonna tell you one thing yes i'm dabbing
it all night but uh huh and yes we have
enough fun we gonna keep on coming
through it yes we joined under the sun
to just show what yes we all being
blessed by this one plant that we all
love never rest never hold up and this
war was not over until all our prisoners
out of jail and yes you know what
soldier that's right it's time to work
yes free everybody cause we need a
little weed and we keep it going
and uh
in cannabis
and cannabis massage therapy and
cannabis and cannabis and cannabis
massage therapy and canada
and cannabis and cannabis
thank you brother
he let us use the guitar so our show
will roll cool thank you for that too
bro
congratulations we gonna tell your story
worldwide brother i promise you that
okay i love you lk
i love you okay in the building yeah
baby yes laurie duckworth i love you
baby t.a.c foundation in the building
what's up y'all yes
keith and christy man i know y'all not
here but i love you my guy had a heart
attack in california
he owned an oregon cannabis connection
newspaper man y'all need to pick that up
and got all the latest details on what's
happening in your cannabis community man
that's what's up give yourselves a round
of applause for being here today on this
beautiful day
we're in portland's living room