you know I'm really excited that uh
marijuana is legal in Oregon and that
12,000 people won't go to jail this year
for cannabis
yay so as we are working toward
implementing that law we've come across
some problems um and that the measure 91
committee decided that measure 91 was a
good first draft and they want to do
something different and so we've had a a
Time of coming together and really
communicating what our community needs
because the measure 91 committee did not
follow what measure 91 said measure 91
said that om should remain untouched it
said it three different times but
because it wasn't a constitutional
amendment put the sign down buddy
amendment they changed it they took it
as a good first draft and they're doing
what they want so right now tomorrow M
day SB 844 is going to be adopted
there's some discussion if it's already
been adopted or if it's not adopted I
think that it's pretty as close to
adopted as it's going to be until they
actually take care of it and then
they've got- s amendments too so they're
trying to alter it sentence by sentence
literally like it's literally sentence
by sentence change this word adopt this
thing but what they've done is they've
messed up our grows you guys they messed
up our possession limit for our plants
and so that's a really big deal because
now a bunch of patients that were going
to have medicine from their Growers
their Growers cannot give them that
medicine for free because they're not
going to have a surplus of medicine to
be able to give away for free and there
won't be as many Growers able to help as
many of these Patients Out they've put
on some pretty strict reporting
requirements and they've put in some
things like um inspections for grows if
you designate somebody else to grow for
you then that person would be subject to
inspection there's a lot of things like
that that are very alarming in this
legislation and so what I would invite
all of you to do is to read it get
involved show up in Salem on Mondays and
Wednesdays at 5:00 the measure 91
committee meets and they have done a
really good job about listening to what
we have to say they recently called
themselves a monkey with a gun you guys
they called themselves a monkey with a
gun over our program we know what we
need so we need everybody here to show
up and tell them what we need now after
they're done with this 844 Amendment or
the SB 844 and the Amendments that go
with it they're actually going to turn
toward measure 91 and measure 91 they're
going to be looking at ret taxing and
the taxing structures that were laid in
place are going going to be gone they're
going to look at implementing moratorium
and they're going to look at
implementing moratorium without putting
it to a vote there some things that they
are not allowed to do in measure 91 but
because it's a legislative session
they're going to be allowed to do what
they want and so it's really up to us
we're the ones that voted it through
we're the ones that wanted it we're the
ones that have been screaming out to be
regulated now we have to hold them
accountable in this process C we have to
show up we have to tell them what we
think about what they're doing to our
grow limits we have to show up and tell
them what we think about taxing our
medicine or taxing recreational Cannabis
we have to show up and hold these people
accountable because if you think they
know what they're doing I want to remind
you again he called the there was a
member of the committee that stood sat
there and said we are monkeys with a gun
they are they're monkeys with a gun you
guys they do not know what they're doing
if you saw a monkey with a gun running
through this Plaza right now what would
you do you would try to disarm the
monkey and you would run you would not
just leave the baby the with unattended
with the monkey with the gun so we have
a baby which is our program which is
measure 91 and we have a committee
that's monkeys with a gun so what I need
everybody to do is come babysit the
monkeys they all have our baby and we
all have to me babysit the babysitters
the monkeys with the gun I need
everybody to show up in Salem m Mond
dayss and Wednesdays this whole next
month they're going into the last bit of
the session they are tired they're tired
you can visibly see that they're tired
we have definitely made an impact we
need to make sure that we're there the
whole rest of the session because last
time everybody got tired we wound up
with moratorium all over the state 126
counties 36 cities because people didn't
feel like going to Salem well if you
didn't enjoy not having access to your
medicine for the last year or you lost
your job because of moratorium maybe we
should all just show up and make sure
that despite our tiredness we hold these
people accountable so please come to
Salem submit emails make phone calls be
loud this is the time that they're
listening and read the information
there's the Oregon legislative
information system you can go on there
you can look up all of the legislation
you can read it for yourself you can
form your own opinions there's no reason
to be underinformative
growing in one place that's not enough
space it's not enough we we won't have
enough medicine and then if they want to
have the medical program stimulate the
recreational program until after outdoor
Harvest is done I really see a problem
with shortages so you guys please show
up and salale them tell them what you
think about what they're doing give your
thoughts and your opinions and then call
them back up and ask them what they
thought hold them accountable make sure
they understand what you're telling them
and any changes that you have to the
legislation Senator Buckley has
representative Buckley has been very
very clear that if you're going to give
your thoughts and opinions on the
legislation he and the other members
very much appreciate it if you're very
specific on the line item and that
you're talking about because then they
can address it more promptly um so yes
please show up in Salem please hold them
accountable and uh come to one draw too
they're good people get free hash thank
you guys