hi everybody and I mean hig a tie what a
spectacular day here in pollen door
again thank you mother nature bear with
me a little my PTSD is kicking a little
hard right now so just bear with me you
guys so do we have to say to our state
again what's wrong with all these
changes you keep making that continue to
happen and have happen to our cannabis
medical program in the last year or so
always somebody or something has tried
to change us leave our medicine alone
that seems to be the words that have
been said or used by most how many times
have you said it or heard someone else
say it gee do you think anybody's
listening and know that we can hear
ourselves saying it who's listening come
on state of Oregon our state had one of
the best medical cannabis programs to me
I am a multi-state medical cannabis card
holder now that medical has paved the
way for recreational recreational will
ultimately take over and be servicing
our ommp in the end this sounds crazy to
me disappointed disappointed is one of
the strongest words that this Oregon
Oregonian can say I like a lot of you
have had to make constant change in the
past few years social clubs closing
because of the Clean Air Act my markets
closed because they couldn't be
regulated by the state my friends died
because it was more important for them
to be treated with pharmaceuticals
then the choice of cannabis what else
must mean we give up well I'm not
willing to give up my medical cannabis
card and if they end this program they
will be literally ripping the card out
of my hand our hands my friends hands my
family's hands seems like paying it
forward or giving back Oregon can be the
ultimate reward in closing I would love
to take this time as Portland hem stocks
hospitality manager to invite you all to
him stock this year down at Waterfront
Park September 24th and 25th I hope to
see you all there I want to stay in
closing also did these people are
extremely missed ok John Walsh john
trudell Greg Pryor Jack hair and many
more and I want to thank them again for
all their efforts that they put into
these programs I'm ready to march with
my p4p group and I hope you are too come
check out our booth in the back thank
you and show great so nerism