they're
here to take
Daner they're here to make sure nobody
gets
hurt they're here to keep the peace let
s this
say bling do they tell you you'll gave a
smile on their
face but I seen the other side of the
boys in
blue yeah I see them with every times in
their I head
suits beating on Peaceful protesters
yeah man that's what I have
saying believe happened to you cuz it
happened to
me they
say go home and watch the
news but they got to mention they've
been bought off Media is lying to you
too cop see we're only doing our
job we're only filing orders we do we
told you man it comes down from the to
but I seen the other side of the boys in
blue yeah I seeing them marching them
horses in the crowds of people Two by
Two by
Two beating no kids pushing out women
yeah man that's what I have
seen believe it happen to you cuz it
happened to
me think for yourself before you speak
out loud they'll come down hard in a
bling of an eye talk about the truth oh
stand up for your rights you best being
ready for one hell of a fight but this
seem the way than things have got to be
so come now with me and let's take to
the
streets and I see the other side of the
Bo and
blue when I seen him they telling
running how we made them look
like
f they're losing all that proceive power
here man that is what I have
seing believe happen to you cuz happened
to
me yeah I seen the other side of the
boys in
blue when I see theide of the man just
people like me yeah
when I seen the fear in their eyes when
we dance all around them that is what I
have seen so come now let's take to the
streets who streets are
streets whose streets our streets