thank you guys for the syndicate it's
our last song if you want to support us
another way we're having a noun release
at the star theater on june 12th you can
come check us out talk to us more about
that we appreciate your rally we
appreciate you guys cause you're heading
in the right direction
soon enough we'll be crossing the bridge
with the joint in hand just passing it
back and forth from jansen beach it'll
be awesome
won't you light up in place
lost in her purple hands
life's just a masquerade
time slowly slips
um
she almost made it she was so
consecutive now she lies in the valley
just waiting for her heart to stop us
beating for the devil to take her soul
the good is
and when i'm stopping if your teeth
should let me bleed
is
once you light up in place
time slowly slips
is
i
thank you guys very much for the
syndicate enjoy the sunshine