write them emails make phone calls go
into their offices and put a face on
medical there were legislators that said
oh 90% of the medical people are fakes
they're just wreck users that just want
to smoke pie well I want to tell you
something I'm also here to speak for
patients like William kurs who has a
degenerative hereditary disease and I
got to tell you 90% of the patients that
I know in Washington don't get out they
can't afford to get out they are
physically unable to get out they are
too ill to get out so we need to put our
face in front of the legislators we make
we got to make sure that they know that
medical is legitimate that recreational
is not harmful but the two must go ahead
separately to protect the best interests
of the state and and of the people and
of the
patients make sure you're registered to
vote sign these initiatives and before
we get to the vote start on your
legislators I'm a voter I live in your
District I voted for you you represent
me and medical makes a difference to me
and my community tell them what the law
should be don't sit around and wait to
vote on it you are the government the
government is not you make them change
the law to represent what we want for
cannabis