these boys here that i read floor for
you you're in for a treat I've been
listening to him well basically my whole
life because their whole life anyway
because I've been listening to so they
were we little lads that they didn't
they've been playing in Milwaukee area
for God years now so before my voice
goes totally away I want to give this
over to probably the best band in
Portland right now bad habit at guys oh
yeah give a freestyle we're not coming
near will not be spitting the end I love
again we're a global care to be smart or
up again all your beautiful faces out
there go ahead and clip again I can't
care like I can't driving like that
these everybody wanna see me when I'm
going the top of the cap inhale pre stop
it y'all cuz i don't need no rings come
back to bite all true won't you take on
the bike keep bullshitting but be
friends right you did open your lucky
and I'm loving tonight when it's light
outside some fun with your private I see
the killer focus again drew hoping to
see these all buffers wanna see them we
don't put your hands down this is free
everybody in the half put your hands up
everybody yeah I'll put your hands up if
you're swooping on that ground use your
hands up everybody yeah ha put your
hands up all your beautiful people just
put your hands up everybody outside put
your hands up
whooping on the grand put your hands up
everybody cheers try to be selfish
sometimes I can't help you always want
seconds after my first hildebrandt no
matter how i'm doing like a roof
replacement gonna do i do it in the
first place is the worst case a hunger
that you ever seen like I never ate did
to forget what you're telling me or car
they say that'll reap the rewards but
when I'm seeing the [ __ ] stopped
beating for more than like they know as
fair as Kapena Shakur Rask anybody's
been world in a week me aboard not
everybody you meet asleep and adores but
sometimes I brought along even if you
wanna did you get it the beginning if
it's a guy you're living you got to
choice he's in the system but I can't
stop my mom made up on this wing for
yours take the bull by the horns at tell
them you want more everybody outside put
your hands up all the ladies now should
get your hands over horses outside put
your hands up everybody up everybody
outside put your hands up all the babies
outside put your hands up put your hands
up everybody put this my turn man saw
your specific every domestic everyday is
this affair agency set of hair or a
second the princess and and have a slap
on my record for better to making your
grandma the Vedic Mets killer set it and
track with
if you have to pretend if it never
really really do you let your come on
everybody applying me a square right
Nick huh chance up everybody outside put
your hands up all the ladies outside put
your hands up how y'all doing out there
luckily good we're just getting warmed
up so warm up trap y'all it's a
beautiful day to be doing outdoor show