all right what a beautiful day and I'm
really happy to be here who here
believes that everybody can have access
to cannabis
no matter your political affiliation no
matter your race no matter your
ethnicity no matter how old you are no
matter how young you are right everybody
should have access to cannabis now who
thinks everyone should have access to
the best cannabis in the world like here
in Portland this is without a doubt the
best cannabis I've traveled all around
the world and Portland has the best
cannabis in the world but when I was in
the South when I was in the southern USA
we don't have laws that are quite as
liberal as they are in Portland my
father spent seven years in prison for
an ounce of cannabis before he was going
to get into the top college in North
Carolina and ended up having to come out
and become a janitor and every year he
worked worked up with our family we
moved to another city and when I finally
got a chance to have cannabis when I
finally got a chance to experience it I
ended up getting arrested too I was
arrested a total of four times for
cannabis possession one time even for a
seat I was arrested to spend two nights
in prison two nights in jail what I
never got a chance to go to prison
so when people in our community and
communities that have been highly
impacted by cannabis prohibition are
very bitter
how to look at the cannabis industry is
something that is not for them something
that will not help them and we all know
that everyone having access to the best
cannabis there's something that will
help them so when I finally got a chance
to move to Portland and finally got a
chance to consume cannabis without
getting arrested I wanted to learn more
about growing I wanted to learn more
about the industry and it was the people
of Portland that opened up their doors
opened up their programs opened up their
their grow shops their knowledge to
teach me how to grow the best cannabis
in the world and we started loud
cannabis here in Portland Oregon
contributing to the craft cannabis story
he reportedly but if you're in the
cannabis industry if you're benefitting
from the cannabis industry you cannot do
it without understanding the history of
the industry you cannot do it without
contributing to the people who have paid
that sacrifice and I've opened up for
legalization actually happened we never
thought legalization was a real thing in
the south we never thought it could
happen but it's here and it's here
because of all of those people so each
and every one of us no matter whether
you're going to a dispensary no matter
whether you're contributing and buying
from your your local grower you have to
find a way to help alleviate some of the
issues that have been caused through
cannabis prohibition and one way to do
that is to work with the new leaf
project here in Portland Oregon
more than was the first city in the
country I want to say that one more time
Portland was the first city in the
country to open up some of these
cannabis tax to help people who have
been targeted by cannabis prohibition
you got to think about how monumental
that is for a city to open up and become
the first and it's happening all across
the country because of what Portland has
done and as a result of that
organizations like the new leaf project
that my wife Jeanette Ward is running
and I'm helping with and so many other
Portland City citizens are supporting is
opening up and helping with expungement
opportunities is helping to give grants
to black owned and minority-owned
cannabis businesses it's helping to
contribute to that history and alleviate
that history that has been caused now
there is a long way to go without a
doubt there is a lot that we have to do
well what I want everybody here to think
about is I leave the stage here is how
am I going to contribute to helping
these issues that have been caused by
cannabis prohibition am I going to
support the dispensary that is helping
to make these movements like green how
am I going to help support the cannabis
that are helping to contribute am I
going to help by just helping the
everyday Portland citizens out here on
the street everyday by giving them a
joint right whatever you may be how can
you help everybody here through the
cannabis legalization movement and I
want to thank all the Portland citizens
I would not be in this cannabis industry
without this amazing city and without
the amazing fighters here in Oregon that
helped to open up legalization so thank
you very much everyone here who was
helped with that and thank you everyone
who will contribute to making a better
cannabis legalization picture in the
state of Oregon