oregon has led in innovation nationally
we protected our beaches
the bottle bill land use
40 years ago
oregon was the first state to
decriminalize marijuana
and i was an impressionable young
legislator actually voted on that
legislation
and there was another
debate that occurred during that session
it was led by a conservative republican
pig farmer
from hermiston oregon
a remarkable gentleman named stafford
hansel
who had a distinguished career as a
long-term state legislator
he was active in administration he
helped protect the land use system
but stafford gave what i think was one
of the most compelling speeches
i've ever heard in my life
here was a
conservative
republican
didn't smoke drink
swear who got up and led the state
legislature through a tutorial
he pointed out a package of cigarettes
that killed 400 000 people a year
that was legal
he had a bottle of jack daniels i think
it may have been the only time he'd ever
held the bottle of liquor
and he pointed out that for some people
alcohol was toxic
and it contributed to the deaths of tens
of thousands of people on a highway
each year
and then he had a baggie
with a marijuana cigarette
and he pointed out that
people didn't die from it
that it wasn't as addictive it wasn't as
destructive
and that it was illegal
and he proceeded to defend
a bill we had on the floor of the house
that would have
authorized
two plants for personal consumption
i'm told
by knowledgeable people
at the capitol at that time
if the 19 of us
who voted for it
had been joined by the people who voted
no but smoked dope
then it probably would have passed and
oregon would have been the first state
to legalize adult use
at the same time oregon was having this
discussion about a more rational
approach to marijuana
we were watching at the federal level a
war on drugs being launched in the nixon
administration
and it had a much different approach
to marijuana
the legacy of that
war on drugs
was classifying
marijuana as a schedule one drug
the consequences of that our legion
first and foremost as you know
classifying marijuana as being as
dangerous as heroin or lsd is simply
false
it's false
telling people
that it is more dangerous
than cocaine
or methamphetamines schedule two
the meth
epidemic that is destroying rural and
small town communities
suggests we've got our priorities
upside down
it also suggests to me part of a need to
reappraise what is can only be described
as a failed war on drugs
we're spending 25 billion dollars a year
we are arresting
three quarters of a million people a
year for something that most americans
now think should be legal
and there are as you're well aware some
of the most egregious
racial disparities
targeting
young african-american men
greater than any other sector of the
population
even though their use is no greater
maybe even a little less
than white young men
and there are people
doing time
now
as a result of the consequences of this
act
we've been involved in congress
in the effort to help
rationalize
our drug treatment
drug approaches
part of it
is to make sure that the federal
government is not interfering in medical
marijuana
part of
the lie
in federal statute
as a
category with schedule one narcotic it
has no
therapeutic value
not
true
and luckily
voters starting in california in 1996
as the first state followed by oregon in
the next election we now have 21 states
and the district of columbia
representing over 106 million americans
who have
access that's legal
under state law to medical marijuana
a million americans now are legally
authorized to have access
and i have heard countless stories about
the difference that it has made in their
lives
part of what we're doing in congress and
i will tell you i'm encouraged
because we now have 13 pieces of
legislation
most of it bipartisan
to try and bring
some sense
into this upside down world
that is marijuana regulation in the
united states
we have legislation and bipartisan
support to stop the lunacy
of making
marijuana legal marijuana businesses
be all cash enterprises
what's the logic here
if you care about money laundering if
you care about tax evasion
or just burglary
forcing
perfectly legal enterprises to
pay their taxes with a shopping bag full
of twenty dollar bills
doesn't make any sense at all
or
because of a quirk in the tax law
forcing them to pay two and three times
higher
tax rates again for perfectly legal
businesses
is wrong
but i will tell you some of you are
familiar with a rep a conservative
republican tax advocate
grover norquist
grover was with me
at a press conference for my bill
to allow
legal marijuana businesses to deduct
their business expenses that's how far
we're coming
that's how far we're coming
wednesday
on the floor of the house i had an
amendment
that would have allowed our veterans
to be able to talk
to
their va doctors
about marijuana
why should our veterans be treated as
second-class citizens
in those
states where medical marijuana is legal
why should they not be able to talk to
their primary doctor
about whether it's right for them or
wrong
we weren't successful
but we got
195 votes
including two dozen republicans
who said
this doesn't make any sense
and i was told by one of my republican
co-sponsors of the legislation that he
was convinced that there were 12 or 13
republicans who if they better
understood it would have voted
with us
we're on the move
in the united states congress
we passed an amendment
that allows
research agriculture institutions
to research industrial hemp
which passed
with a significant yes vote
we now have a dozen states
that are
poised to allow
industrial hemp production
and we have signals from the
administration that these are part of
the
the smaller fish that the
administration's not going to fry that
we'll be able to proceed with this
and it's about time
some of you have been involved
with trying to promote
not just the use of legal hemp products
which of course they are and they're
sustainable and they're beneficial
it's just that oregon farmers and
ranchers can't grow it
kentucky tobacco farmers can't grow it
it's got to be imported
from outside the united states
but we're turning the corner on that
we have to do a better job i think of
breaking the stranglehold of this
pernicious classification
that prevents
research
into
marijuana
up on the hill
i met with neurologists
people who are dealing with problems of
our children
they talked about those with violent
epilepsy these parents are willing to
move
their families to be able to have access
to medical marijuana that will prevent
these violent seizures
but the scientists
cannot get marijuana to study what works
and why
that's an outrage
oregon was a leader
40 years ago in decriminalization
oregon has a chance
to be the explosion that breaks the dam
on marijuana policy nationally
it's great what we have in washington
and colorado
it's great that we've got 21 states in
the district columbia with medical
marijuana but we're on the
just on the cusp right now of changing
national policy once and for all
it'll be great in alaska if this summer
they legalize adult use
but alaska's sort of up there and out
there
i don't think the land of the mid
midnight sun and sarah palin is going
is going to start a national trend
it's great that medical marijuana is on
the ballot in florida this year
700 000 signatures
but given the florida constitution will
require a 60 percent less yes vote to
pass and
that's questionable here in oregon
we have an opportunity
to cast a ballot for a rational
marijuana policy
that will be followed across the country
it'll open the floodgates in california
in 2016
and we can get down to business
we can tax it regulate it keep it out of
the hands of the kids
and stop interfering with people's lives
i'd ask you to study it
get involved
sign a petition
and spread the word
so that we can have success
this november oregon can do it thank you
very much