this next one is for a lost friend of
ours okay thank you very much brother I
love you man love you for everything you
did for us and this next one is for you
brother
come on ganja lady one but did you kill
to Medicaid and recreation Oh medicine
can't do nothing quite like this so
please give me my cannabis
you know what's not to kinda bleep that
you see in your dream straight out of
high times but you should see big-screen
TV DS le mins and the THC then your bets
now forget about that THC be guess javis
on the thing that your body may need
help get rid of your pain or maybe your
your disease don't sit back with a sack
of the finest tree but would never give
your body what you know with me gunjan
anyone get you came to medicate the
recreation
medicine can do nothing quite like this
please give me my canopy
nothing shaking on shakedown street used
to be the hard time seeing in city ain't
got no harm just got look around nothin
shakin on shakedown street be the harder
time baby shitty ain't got no just I'm
look around nothin shakin I'm sick time
will be the hard time see this city
ain't got no harm just I look around
Michigan I'm sick time just be the heart
of time city ain't got no
just a look around gunga anyone is you
came to medical care every shine Oh
medicine I do nothing quite like this
here we might can I be
you know what hit that green crop it
with all the pop stars at the hot tubs
cannabis cup and dude you know where you
want smoke it with my friend fanm VIP
there the time for all that I get some
take two or three yes the dimples moe
catch a pass along side the Bulls I
believe this place Mandy thing that's
our grand a month to think about it we
as far as the eye can see so come on
illegal I to give the people what they
need dungeon anyone
you came to medical and recreation let
us undo don't think why like this so
please give me my cannabis cannibals
ganja anyone educate to Medicaid a
recreation don't medicine can do don't
think quite like this so please hear me
mine can I be