john lucy law 420.com i represent
anonymous as well as occupy as well as
the global cannabis movement so what i'm
here today though to do is something
really simple i'm here to help you
protect your rights so i'm going to read
a little bit of information that's on
every single one of my business cards
back in front that you need to know when
you deal with the cops or you deal with
anyone who's trying to get you in front
of the cops and it's really simple and i
want you to listen and repeat it back to
me so we're gonna do a little call and
response everybody know how to do that
everybody got that okay
remember to be polite okay that's the
critical part of this don't be a jerk to
the cops just be polite
they hate it more than anything when you
know your rights
so
i do not consent to any searches
i do not wish to answer any questions
i invoke my right to silence
and i wish to consult with my attorney
we're gonna do it again you know why
because if you remember this you'll
probably never pay me a dime
i do not consent to any searches
i do not wish to answer any questions
i invoke my right to silence
and i wish to consult with my attorney
if you can't remember that i've got
wristbands they just say i want my
lawyer
cards are over there if anybody needs
them you guys have a wonderful day
unfortunately i've got a client in
custody i got to go over to the jail and
take care of it i love you guys stay
safe
that's how john lucy does guys he's
always working he's always working for
freedom and supporting the many many
great and wonderful activists patients
and people that we have in this cannabis
community