thanks folks hey thanks for coming out
for the March we finally did it we've
got legal marijuana congratulations and
thank you for making it happen staying
at the fight for so long you know I've
been saying in a long time that cannabis
prohibition has never really been about
drugs it's about control and money and
power and the continued centralization
of Economic and political control I
truly believe that marijuana the whole
marijuana myth was created to stop the
use of biofuels and fiber they made up
that whole myth and so finally the truth
is coming to light but we're still
experiencing blowback we still have the
legislature trying to shut down the
medical marijuana program they've been
successful across the river in
Washington with uh Senate Bill 5052
which Governor Inslee signed into law
just last week
they have to stop that I hope they can
organize a referendum they need 120 000
signatures in the next 75 days or so
good luck to the folks behind that
hopefully we won't have to do a
referendum here in Oregon we have a few
friends in the legislature but we have
to stay active with them as well and
contact them and let them know what we
don't like it looks like
the community's done a great job last
week in reaching out and stopping some
of the worst aspects of the dash six
amendments to Senate Bill 844 but it's
still working its way through there and
uh we got to keep an eye on it
anyway we're about to go on a March I
want to thank you guys for coming out
here it's uh another year is this a 16th
year 16 years
it's been going on so
uh thanks again have a great March it's
been a great show and help us restore
hemp