it's good to be here in a place where
you know the voters understand the needs
of both the patients and the
recreational people and we all
understand that for recreational is this
the most benign therapeutically active
substance protecting your neuro in the
cannabinoid systems is just to deny us
the access to this wonderful herb is
really sacrilegious it is a war against
the creator's work work it is a war
against the people here I am I have been
legal authorized by the federal
government for 27 years I had to prove
to FDA DEA and nida that cannabis is the
most efficient the most reliable and the
safest part of my treatment as it turns
out today it is the only part of my
treatment haha and I am out a niche for
most of my friends have a medicine
cabinets full of nasty drugs that cause
them to take all their drugs which they
have it on their brain deliver their
heart and everything else they're trying
to protect that marijuana does well gee
is a wonder the pharmaceutical on the
health industry just don't want it to
change they will lose fifty percent of
their business at least the day cannabis
takes its rightful place in our society
I applaud you for having made so much
progress but you know the jobs far from
over I don't know why we're not having
million marches all over this country
behind Bernie Sanders he's the only one
has come up with a plan that just might
work to end the federal law on us this
needs to change we need to get behind
this man it's the only hope i have seen
lately changing laws as long as the pets
they know my doctor still doesn't have
the right to practice his Hippocratic
oath in other words he's not allowed to
have the First Amendment of the
Constitution and neither are you not
really we can rent in
Raven oh but we can't even light up
after all those approvals I don't feel
free to light up right now I don't want
to have so you know how cause your
problem this is disgusting this is
ridiculous and to charge someone that
wants to start a cannabis business
$5,000 when someone can open a liquor
store for 500 there is something really
messed up about this we have come a long
ways but obviously we're not done with
this job we need to change it federally
you need to get rid of the clowns who
oppose us I thank you jennifer for being
up those meetings for saying what needs
to be said I'm for running for office
now thank you so much to all of you who
keep doing things like that it's the
only thing that's really gonna change
everything remember remember that it
freedom isn't really free so you got to
make sure it gets untangled from this
bureaucracies and that your own
legislators still make you suffer come
on with this bureaucracy I lost sight
that I had maintained for 37 years when
you got greedy and wanted more money
than I could pay you for my license to
one or my prescription that's ridiculous
like my daughter said man-made booze God
made pot who do you trust let the true
spirit of love always be your guiding
light but don't sit on the job don't let
another Nixon come in and tear us all
down we're about the will learn 1980 are
we gonna let it all go back to hell
again we're on our way there we are at
the top of the hill let's make it all
the way and put our flag nice and high
the ham flag the ham flag and start
taking care of our environment remember
that the green leaf is here for the
healing of the nation's remember that
and remember that hemp can and will save
the planet get rid of those papers
stinky paper mills do the right paper
with the right crops that we can harvest
at least once a year give our workers
jobs please get back to the hemp you've
already voted it in let's really work of
making it
change thank you love you