I love the global Cannabis March because
it's my activism or my cannabis activism
anniversary the first Global Cannabis
March I came to was in 2001 I came as a
volunteer for what was PDX normal at
that time and I registered voters and I
created a mailing list of people who
were interested in getting information
about cannabis legalization little did I
know that by suggesting that maybe we
send these people a letter I would
become the Secretary of what was Oregon
normal and a founder of Oregon normal
and be here 14 years later still working
for cannabis freedom I am honored to be
here and I think that one of the things
that it's really important that we talk
about today is to remember to be
grateful for those who have come before
us and to remember that gratitude is the
attitude to have moving forward there
are a lot of things not to like about
what the government is is trying to do
around implementing measure 91 and I
Echo mine's sentiments that we need to
St press our legislature hard this year
to implement measure 91 as it was
written that means they leave the
medical marijuana program
alone but here's the thing A lot of
people are getting really mad about that
and they're all up in arms and I would
say to you this measure 91 they say
doesn't go far enough it's like how many
plans can you legally have now any of
you that aren't patients none so four
looks pretty good to me right I mean I
think I could probably grow four decent
plants and they would turn out I mean I
don't know I'm not that good at it but I
can grow some weed too so if everybody
can grow just a little then isn't that a
good thing instead of going to jail
instead of losing your family instead of
losing your job I would say yes so how
did that come about well it came about
from years and years of people add
advocating for cannabis Freedom before
many of you ever even knew it was
happening and I would say we need to
thank those people we need to thank
those organizations that stepped up
first that came out first and showed us
the way and led the P the way to where
we're at now which
is inches from legalization we're two
months away from being able to smoke a
joint at home without having to worry
about getting busted how cool is that
it's the coolest so remember to have
gratitude for organizations like normal
like students for sensible drug policy
like um
crrh the THCF CL clinic and people like
meline Martinez Paul Stanford Scott
Gordon Aiko and all of those who have
come before us who made it possible for
us to be where we are I think that if we
remember our history moving forward we
could move forward more quickly because
we can learn from the mistakes that were
made in the past my name is Anna is and
I am proud to be a stoner join me and
let's end cannabis prohibition once and
for all thank you