good afternoon Portland it is so good to
be here with you guys this is the first
time I have been able to be at a march
here in Portland i'm usually up in
seattle so thank you guys very much i'm
here today I'm from voices of the
cannabis war I also am a host for K
booze Prison Pipeline KBOO does that
mondays at six thirty and voices of the
cannabis war is 9 a.m. on sunday
mornings on blogtalkradio i'm here today
to talk for people who can't be here to
speak first of which is Kristen floor
kristin is one of my wonderful dear
friends and she was supposed to be here
today to speak family emergency and she
can't be here but I have the opportunity
to give you good news so Kristen if you
don't know her father died in federal
prison he was shackled to a bed he had
been in for four months of his sentence
when he died there cannabis he was the
first caregiver in Montana so all of you
out here who are dispensary owners can
caregivers recreational growers
federally you're still at risk and
families like Kristen suffered her dad
died her mom also went to prison Kris
Williams is still in prison the good
news is is this last week sherry floor
was standing on stage in Seattle for
their march she has now been about two
weeks as she can finally have her
medicine she will never get her husband
back she was in prison when he died she
wasn't there for him but she's finally
getting some of her freedom back now
when people get out of prison they're
not done they still have a record they
still struggle to get jobs as many of
them are still on paper they can't even
have all of their rights back when they
first get out and so many of them are
still there many people to tell me Oh
Mindy they're not there people people
don't go to prison for weed anymore
that's not true Cooper curving he got a
life sentence two years ago out of
California the
guys here I have letters asking the
President to let these guys out
president Obama has been letting people
out left and right we've been hearing
about it all over the news but you can
count on less than two hands how many of
them are for pot they are lots of other
things and I'm grateful for them but
they're not our weed prisoners antonino
best Garrow whereas he's over here
longest-serving prisoner for marijuana I
believe he's in for almost 40 years he
got an 80 year sentence Cuban war hero
his daughter wants him home desperately
Paul free again he wasn't even in the
state that they accused him of at the
time all these guys are in for
conspiracy they didn't even have weed on
him please come to my booth over there
sign some letters get the President to
send them home i also want to urge you
don't get complacent we are not done in
organ i cannot smoke pot in my house i'm
a renter i could still get drug tested
at my job there's still people who are
losing things as well as we cannot go to
schedule to we must be schedule schedule
2 is not enough it won't get him out
thank you very much