it's the most productive crop produces
more fuel from its seed oil and its
biomass and ethanol more fiber from its
stems
for
canvas rope lace linen paper and
building materials
and more food from its seeds the best
protein known to man
so to take the oldest and most
productive crop and to prohibit that one
is evil and we're here to protest that
to restore hip to its rightful place in
our economy
if you look right up there
where that mark emery sign is being held
that's the starting point of the march
so we're going to start when we come
back congressman earl blumenauer will be
here to uh to give our keynote speech
and a number of other speakers and music
for a few hours this afternoon
again i want to thank you all for coming
line up for the march and help us
restore him