Thank you Thank You Portland hey welcome
everybody with a beautiful day out here
you know what I love about Portland is
you can have a cigarette outside you can
go to a sidewalk cafe and have a beer
you don't i hate about portland pots
legal but you can't smoke it anywhere
now i don't know if you know this but in
addition to my fact abysm work
emotionally I work with the northwest
cannabis club we're right down here on
Powell hey I got some members out there
right on Powell here by the aladdin
theater 13th and Powell open seven days
a week from noon to midnight this is a
place where anyone 21 and older whether
your medical or not can come in and
socialize and enjoy your cannabis you
can vape in there we've got vape rigs
for you we got bongs we got pipes we got
the whole thing but in my work there
what I found is I talked to people and I
and I find out why you coming to the
club why aren't you at home why aren't
you hanging out in your own space
parents don't want to smoke pot around
their kids so just like a bar or a cigar
bar they need a place to go socialize
away from their mind or children because
they're responsible parents we have
other people that come in you know what
the housing situation is here it's tight
I know people that are literally living
in trailers and come in to our nice club
because they want to entertain their
guests and they want to socialize and
I'll tell you you know the days of
reefer madness are going away but
unfortunately we need more people in the
state house so it goes away more the
organ cleaned or Clean Air Act one is
the method that they're using to
regulate us they want to say that there
can be no smoking anywhere well you know
we're supposed to be free to associate
with each other if it's legal for me to
smoke a joint at home why should it be
legal for me to smoke a club socially
somewhere
so I'm only one voice but I see a lot of
voices out here and here's the thing
that I want you to do I know you're
already registered to vote you know what
laws you want there to be in effect do
you know who represents you either
locally or in the State House have you
ever contacted them have you ever seen
them at a public gathering seen them out
of the county fair with or eating hot
dogs whatever they got going on have you
been to their offices have you written
an email or made a phone call these are
the things that all the individual
voices can do to effect change you know
there's money at play in this there's
there's money in keeping it illegal you
know there's there's a lot of fines that
go out people you know you smoked out in
public you can get a ticket and you know
what the court system it's just a grind
so we need to create safe access where
adults can meet and greet and entertain
each other responsibly and socially and
not be feel like criminals we shouldn't
have to hide in the closet anymore so
when you get the chance come on down to
13th and Powell and see us down at the
club daily from noon to midnight comedy
on the first and third thursdays of the
month and medicated Monday every Monday
and treats Tuesday we've packed that
place we pack the patio and it's a
beautiful facility you're not sitting on
the couch at daves garage so come on by
but talk to your legislators and tell
them what the law should be next session
it's going to be big thank you all Thank
You Portland