our founding fathers imported him into
the United
States they got the in for up out on the
street I can get on out the town but
this is Town's my
home nobody so leave my
ass this a losing battle now that the
truth is out even the politicians I fig
this thing out you can go ahead and in
help might help you loosen your and
legalize the and drop all the r cuz if a
losing battle
the test so it's time to exercise our
rights and put on a h Fest and we're
educa the youth soon rule the land it's
just a matter of time and it's time to
take his
stand win going on just keeps right on
going like with the com Mission and the
you can thow us all in prison but you
cannot win the
fight
country people got suffering
and this has proven that it is a for
hey Mr politici
find the wake
up yeah