uh I bring you warnings from Washington
you know
502 uh passed they said it was
legalization we have exchanged criminal
prohibition for an economic one they
have grabbed the power of the plant away
from the people there is no home growing
unless you are a medical
patient if you
are if you're a licensed grower into the
state system you can't even sample your
own product
this is an iron gpon cannabis that we
have got to move past we have got
initiative 648 in Washington this year
it's going to legalize hom growing at
the medical limits for anyone 21 and
older without tax fee license permit and
most importantly registry if it's a
legal product you shouldn't have to go
on a government list in order to have it
okay we fix a couple other things too
thank you
you right now under 502 if you're under
21 hey I'm over 21 it's legal I can have
an ounce if you're under 21 you go to
jail the first step the first arrest
should be a ticket if you're under 21
over 18 you go see the judge if you're
under 18 you go with your parents and
figure out what's up maybe your folks
don't know what's going on but if we're
going to have it legal we don't want to
be arresting young people people and
putting them into jail with thugs and
criminals and
molesters when we need just to get them
into court with their
parents going to fix it so I got to tell
you last legislative session uh when 502
passed they didn't they they said oh we
won't affect medical at all we won't
affect medical the first thing The
Liquor Board tried to get shoved in
there was to put medical into a system
that does not even exist yet
this is problematic because so many
patients depend on their medicine I see
what's happening in Colorado they've
mixed the systems there I think that's a
bad move Rec should be recreational
medical should be medical when patients
need their medicine and go into a place
and find the wreck users have bought it
all up or driven the prices up so high
that they can't afford their medicine
what have we
done we have got to do this right in the
coming 10 years this country is going to
be legal but what will that legalization
look like will you be able to grow for
yourself or will you be forced to go pay
an exorbitant tax and face ARR rest if
you don't or should you be able to grow
your own share with your friends and
family just like you do the Bounty of
your
garden I know this is Oregon this is the
global
March tell your friends in Washington
sign
648 and something else you know we're
going to get some video out of today
this is kind of like and the and the
March it's a great piece for about a 30
second sound bite on the
news what happened in Washington was our
lobbyists claiming to represent our
industry they were representing their
own special
interests our people wore red shirts we
sat in the legislature upstairs in The
Gallery at the end of the session right
up to the last few minutes they couldn't
decide on how to kill
medical we stopped them and we stopped
them by not just getting the sound bite
in the video we registered patients to
vote we got patients that had never
talked to their legislators before to
write them emails
make phone calls go into their offices
and put a face on medical there were
legislators that said oh 90% of the
medical people are fakes they're just
wreck users that just want a smoke pie
well I want to tell you something I'm
also here to speak for patients like
William curs who has a degenerative
hereditary disease and I got to tell you
90% of the patients that I know in
Washington don't get out they can't
afford to get out they are physically
unable to get out they are too ill to
get out so we need to put our face in
front of the legislators we make we got
to make sure that they know that medical
is legitimate that recreational is not
harmful but the two must go ahead
separately to protect the best interests
of the state and of the people and of
the p
make sure you're registered to vote sign
these initiatives and before we get to
the vote start on your legislators I'm a
voter I live in your District I voted
for you you represent me and medical
makes a difference to me and my
community tell them what the law should
be don't sit around and wait to vote on
it you are the government the government
is not you make them change the law to
represent what we want for
cannabis