all right who like who here is in favor
of freedom
all right and who here likes to have a
job
who here likes to have a place to live
who here likes to have health care
well you know so far we can't rest yet
we passed measure 91 but the rest of it
now we have to work on if you want to
have your job if you want to have your
house if you want to you know have go
see a doctor you know you have to say
stop the discrimination against cannabis
right
it's like end of discrimination that's
what we're all about here you know it's
that's why we're here people say why are
we marching we passed measure 91 and
we're here to end discrimination right
that's the only way we're going to do it
because right now you know your landlord
can tell you no if you're living
government housing they can tell you no
where do you smoke right they say not in
public where do you go
and then they're then they're trying to
pass bills they want to pass bills that
say you can't even have a cannabis club
right check out my shirt right
we got it yeah boo on that
yes Nikki
all right Nikki knows what I'm talking
about Nikki's got a great Club folks
check her out Joe
yeah so the other spot that's right I
got those got the great t-shirts can't
miss those nice and pink
so again oh I see a black one all right
that's great so again you know they
don't want us to smoke anywhere that's
what it sounds like they're saying hey
you know if you live in certain housing
you can't smoke there if your doctor
tells you you can't smoke you can't
smoke because you're fortified you know
I said oh I'm not gonna treat you for X
Y and Z if you're a marijuana consumer
how is that fair right we vote for
freedom
we have to keep working freedom and I'll
call the folks and Salem and say this is
not enough why they're busy down there
attacking the Oregon medical marijuana
program we've got to remind them we got
to have more we need to have we need to
have our rights to consume in a club
in private we need to have our rights to
have housing they can't discriminate
against in uh federally funded or
state-funded housing and jobs
you know right now you can be fired if
your employer says after July 1st I
don't care what you do on the weekend
you know that's great but if your
employer says hey if you smoke marijuana
on a weekend you're fired Monday morning
who wants that right it's not what we
voted for we voted to end prohibition
and we didn't allow we know it's not
just to end public prohibition we need
to end private prohibition that's what
we're facing you know people are being
discriminated against because there are
consumers they choose us no you're not
going back in the closet Lori's not
going back in the closet Nikki's not
going back in the closet I'm not going
back in a closet nobody here is going
back in the closet
all right so remember that you know and
you got to tell your friends and family
this is not over you know come July 1st
it's not over and you know what what I
said on a night measure 91 pass that
great night is this is just the
beginning
just the beginning right now we really
have to push for our freedoms because
they want to push back we're seeing
already down in Salem when you know when
the Oregon League of cities and the
counties are trying to say no you can't
you can't have a dispensary there you
can't have a grow there I mean they're
trying to say that if you're grow if one
little piece of Aroma escapes your
property you can't grow
yes you know you know we they don't say
that about chicken farms my next door
neighbor has chickens I can smell the
chickens that's okay
yeah why why is it marijuana smell okay
I mean come on this isn't you know this
is not what we're about here in America
right as long as we don't hurt somebody
else it should be okay that's what we're
a country was founded on
so we need to believe that folks and
keep pushing keep pushing for your
freedoms you know we can't rest now we
can't stop we still have to prove
ourselves it's what I tell say folks
every day come to my office you know
yeah it's hard right now because we have
to prove that our industry is a good
industry we're not going to harm others
and we're especially not going to harm
children we are a very good industry
we're very proper and we're you know we
have to go above and beyond say the
alcohol industry the tobacco industry
yes I mean why is why can our college
football teams here in the state Oregon
State and Oregon have official beer
right why you know that doesn't make any
sense at all folks that's that's what
that's kind of the hurdles that we're
facing right now we have
exactly they're not 21. so we have to
keep keep that out there all right so
I see Scott give me the nod so I'm going
to end up as Nikki knows and Laurie
knows with my famous little things I
want folks to repeat after me
this is what you have to say when an
officer comes to you
am I free to go officer
a little bit louder am I free to
I do not consent to any searches
I wish to speak to my attorney
and I wish to remain silent
thank you folks