really nice to be here I'm just privil
feel so privileged and proud to be here
with all of you today um it's it's
really great my name is kimly McCulla
I'm the legislative director with the
ACLU of Oregon I want to tell you a
little bit about the ACLU before I get
into everything else just so you know
because not everybody does um ACLU has
been around for over a hundred years
we've been on the front lines of pretty
much every civil rights and civil
liberties issue in the country um we're
nonpartisan nonprofit organization we
work on Free Speech racial racial
Justice prisoners rights human rights um
Humane police practices privacy
religious liberty Reproductive Rights
LGBT rights immigrant rights and much
much more we believe these rights are
fundamental to a free society and that's
why we fight every day across the
country in the courts and in the
legislator legislator and Al also
through public
education as I'm sure you all agree the
war on on marijuana is a failure it has
needlessly ens snared hundreds of
thousands of people in the criminal
justice system at a tremendous cost more
than half of all drug related offenses
in the state of Oregon are for marijuana
over the last decade Oregon police have
arrested and cited more than
95,000 oregonians for marijuana
possession that's the equivalent of
arresting or sighting every single
person in the entire city of Hillsboro
in 2010 we spent over $50 million
enforcing marijuana
laws what's more the war on marijuana
has been enforced along color lines even
though black and white oregonians use
marijuana at about the same rate black
oregonians are roughly two times more
likely to be cited or arrested for
marijuana offenses and some areas of
Oregon are actually even worse than that
in Lane County it's 3.5 times more
likely for doing the same thing at the
same rate as everybody
else last November Oregon voters said
enough is enough our money and resources
should be spent on measures that
actually keep our communities safe like
investing in investigating serious
crimes and reinvesting in public health
programs including drug treatment rather
than wasting time and money clogging our
courts and jails and destroying lives
and families the people of Oregon voted
to Legal ize and regulate marijuana at
the same time what the voters absolutely
did not say is let's throw medical
marijuana users under the
bus people who are sick need access to
their
medication let me say that again people
who are sick need access to their
[Applause]
medication the ACLU was right there with
you fighting for the medical marijuana
program and we will continue to fight to
protect
it yeah the voters also did not say
endanger our privacy and over regulate
marijuana yet some of the proposals that
have been made in the Oregon legislature
this session would do just that if
enacted into law as the legislative
director for the ACLU I'm down in the
capital every day I've been fighting
very very hard to ensure the privacy of
our medical patients the privacy of our
recreational users and to make sure that
these new regulations don't just simply
create another method of criminalizing
marijuana
use I'm also absolutely dedicated to
work with representative Frederick um
and anybody else who wants to get
involved to expunge all nonviolent
marijuana related convictions from
Oregon
residents it makes absolutely no sense
to legalize marijuana and not clear the
records of people with marijuana
offenses no Oregonian should be serving
time in prison for marijuana and no
Oregonian should have to suffer the
collateral consequences of having a
conviction for marijuana for one more
day I want to tell you now unequivocally
your voice is extremely important and
it's very powerful in Salem when I'm
down in the capital I hear legislators
regularly talk about the Communications
that they get from the people of Oregon
it actually does make a difference when
you sit down and write a letter
particularly when you write it in your
own words so please look up your
legislators look them up online email
them tell them what you think tell them
to enact fair and safe guidelines for
measure 91 and hold them accountable
tell them the honor the will of the
voters who said it was time for a new
approach to marijuana to honor the
privacy of oregonians who use marijuana
to expunge marijuana convictions and to
protect the medical
program I also just I have to do this I
want to encourage you to support the
ACLU we need your support um membership
is as little as $5 for students it's
really easy to do just look us up online
ACLU of Oregon that helps make our voice
stronger we will continue to fight this
fight because we believe the criminal
justice system is broken we want to end
not just the war on marijuana but the
War on Drugs more
generally the drug war has failed to
improve Public Safety and Health it's
placed an unprecedented number of people
behind bar bars and it's severely eroded
our constitutional rights all that
search and seizure law all of those ways
that the government invades our privacy
so much of that has been done in the
name of Fighting the War on Drugs
instead of actually helping the American
people so together I believe we can end
the drug war we can reverse the tide of
mass incarceration and protect our
constitutional rights thank you