I met a group of people out in
Harrisburg Oregon who decided that they
they they would like to
import hemp excuse me from Spain through
France and so we did and we had to get
the dea's permission so we imported this
hemp and then we took that hemp and we
made Boards out of
it it's really a nice guitar and this is
a really old piece of wood that the wood
is older than the the guitar so what's
going on is I've got this piece of wood
that's 20 years old and it has an age
today right and it was made out of hemp
fibers that we imported from Spain
through France and we were able to prove
through this piece of wood right here or
actually medium density fiber board that
we could actually create medium density
fiber board and that because of that we
have the ability to
change the the dynamic in the woods okay
now we proved this 20 years ago but
because we do not have anywhere in the
world we do not have enough adequate
Supply to actually do it I mean nobody's
growing hemp fields in United States
unless you run out in Nebraska and get
some of the ditch weed I mean it is
everywhere you know it is you've seen it
and that's what's going on you know we
we just don't have a real Supply if we
ever had a supply I mean tomorrow we
could be producing Boards out of hemp we
could be turning all the herd in the
inside of the stock into Visos and and
making you know know chairs for
astronauts that will never break you
know we could do things that you
couldn't you could even imagine but we
we actually can't because we got a big
imagination so one of the reasons that I
keep fighting and I've been doing this
for over 30 years is I believe I believe
I believe