welcome back to the global cannabis
March this is a really big day for all
of us every year this 19th anniversary
should really be a kickoff for something
great too because cannabis has come so
far in the last year let alone last 10
years or 19 years you probably know that
there are a lot of people that made this
happen through the years that are not
here today
unfortunately everybody's not been able
to see this wonderful thing come to
fruition a lot of folks may ask also
well what the heck are we doing hey man
you know Oregon you guys can smoke weed
why are you even marching that's because
they're not from here and they don't
understand the struggle we have been
working tirelessly
I mean seriously since the 80s with
people like Paul Stanford Paul Loney
and of course dr. Phil Levesque dr.
Levesque passed away three years ago
today on global cannabis today the most
perfect day of course for him to decide
to go through another door what he did
for Oregon and for the United States and
for the world is hard to put into any
kind of synopsis it truly is he was a
brilliant man that absolutely did not
ever ever give up to his dying day when
when he was a kid and he graduated from
high school he went to University of
Oregon and got a bachelor's in chemistry
and what did he do after that he went
and joined the Army in 1944 and became a
scout in the army one of the most
dangerous jobs there was so thanks to
him and Patton's army crossing the Rhine
he was able to secure and liberate
Americans and and people that had been
you know accosted by that terrible war
for years and he came home alive what he
also came home with was a terrible bout
of PTSD and he couldn't talk about the
war for decades decades not to his kids
not to his wife not to anybody when it
finally broke free about 30 just over 30
years after
the war then he was able to start
reaching out and helping other veterans
in Oregon that meant helping veterans
get off of narcotics and the terrible
drugs that they were going that they
were used using even alcohol in order to
combat the demons that they were
suffering from PTSD so doctor Levesque
through his work in Oregon and fighting
through with the legislature was one of
the guys that made it possible for
veterans to have access to the right
medicine that would make them healthy
and not kill them so in 1998 doc fought
real hard 99 you know that it became
legal for medical marijuana patients by
2004 dr. Levesque had five thousand
patients he was the doctor in Oregon had
signed more cards than anybody else so
that put him in the spotlight the target
for problems with the authorities
problems with other doctors other
doctors that wanted to keep their
patients drugged up and under their care
and instead doc was freeing them from
the terrible you know drug addictions so
that got him in trouble
in 2005 he actually lost his license to
practice and after that he became even
stronger voice for legalization and for
medical marijuana patients he never
stopped one day under any circumstances
they beat him down but they never never
got him down and he always came back
stronger than he was so what I would
like to do is dedicate today and this
stage again to dr. Phillip Levesque and
I know if he was here he'd have a lot
more to say about what it means to him
to work with all of you guys and you
know that really you are his legacy all
of us are and it's up to us to keep this
momentum going stronger we don't need to
reschedule we need to descale let's get
this thing over with
okay so let's do it for doc Levesque and
for Jack Kerr and for everybody else
that we have lost that were the big
fighting warriors we have to be there
warriors you guys it's up to us now okay
anyway and so only one last thing about
doc and those of you that know him know
that his last words would be don't smoke
in the rain and if you have to ask don't
ask