as a consumer you have the right to know
how your medicine has grown what's in
your medicine so you need a folks asset
you know as you if you don't grow your
own medicine ask your grower what's in
it you know as a consumer you have the
right to know it's your medicine so
stand up for it and ask what's going on
with my medicine
so yeah and the folks and also normal
we're out there lobbying to improve our
laws you know because you know right now
the dispensaries are starting to be
rolled out which is great
congratulations to everybody who got
their license all right so but you know
folks we need to have it so that if a
school moves in next dispensary
dispensary has to close that's not fair
is it
that's right it's not fair if you're
there paying your taxes paying your
employees doing everything they're
supposed to do and then the school moves
in you have to close that's that's not
American folks and one of my clients
told me you know that sounds more like
Russia so again that part has to be
fixed talk to your legislators you know
as Scott said we're voting in November
and all these legendaries they're not
coming around asking for your vote and
staying here and ask them you know what
are you going to do to improve my access
to Medicine
how are you gonna fix this law you know
are you going to stop these moratoriums
because again because they're going to
be back next year folks asking for
another moratorium we can't let that
happen you know tell them it's time to
stop being scared it's time to come up
with the reasonable regulations we all
support that everybody here supports
reusable regulations that's all we're
asking for you know and the other one is
why do we have a dispensaries have to be
a thousand feet from another one you
know bars could be next to each other
you know that's not that you know why
dispensaries have to be a thousand feet
from each other you know that's just
artificially increases the price of
medicine you know and once again that's
not America folks that's Russia you know
we're here in America so uh again talk
to your state legislatures this is not
fair you know why are they doing this to
us you know we need to make sure that
free competition can take place you know
and there are Growers can be protected
as they grow medicine okay they don't
have to worry about artificial weight
limits talk to your state legislatures
about that you know educate them most of
the state legislatures aren't very
educated and you heard Congressman Earl
blumeier talk about him
he got educated now it's time we have to
educate the rest of them we can't leave
it up to counter women always educate
folks we have to do it that's our
responsibility is to get out there and
educator like Anna's doing it with
patience for pot that's great normal
woman's lines that's great you know
there's Ico out there making videos of
this
you know
all right and so
um you know and part of my other life as
I you know represent processors and
Growers and producers and dispensaries
but also represent folks who get into
trouble out there and so I always like
to wrap up my little uh talk
here we could stop by the police or they
were approaching what you have to say
folks so remember
you know don't say nothing he's right
don't say anything but there's four
little sayings that you always have to
think of and I'll say them and repeat
after me and Michael knows these I know
that Russ knows them let's use them
quite well the other day so
the first one is am I free to go officer
I do not consent to any searches
I wish to speak to my attorney
and I wish to remain silent yeah
all right thanks folks
thank you so much Paul Looney
the real message right there folks is is
we don't have to be bullied by the
police when you're pulled over
especially if you know your rights and
how to handle the situation
sounds real easy
if we read up on it study up on it put
ourselves in those situations we can be
protected