hello everyone I'm so excited to be here
with you today on such absolutely
gorgeous day for the 17th annual global
cannabis March my name is Kimberly
McCullough I'm the legislative director
with the American Civil Liberties Union
just for some of you who may not know
who the ACLU is we are a nonpartisan
organization debt is dedicated to
advancing civil rights and civil
liberties our national organization is
almost a hundred years old and our
Oregon affiliate is celebrating our 60th
anniversary this year we work on a broad
range of issues many of which intersect
with the ongoing need for drug reform in
1973 we supported legislation to make
Oregon the first state to decriminalize
possession of small amounts of marijuana
in the 1990s we beat back attempts to
recriminate craft the successful ballot
measure that created organs medical
marijuana program we're grateful to have
also been part of the measure 91
campaign and we continue to be involved
in this work because we want organs
experience with legal marijuana to be a
successful model for other states and to
lead to federal reform but I don't want
to just talk to you about marijuana
today I also want to talk about the
decades-long drug war that has ensnared
millions of people into America's
criminal justice system our society and
our government made a huge mistake when
we decided to regulate certain drugs
like marijuana through prohibition
criminalization decriminalization and
stigma instead of dealing with drugs as
a public health issue we set in motion
machinery that deeply eroded fundamental
rights crucial to our democracy tore
families apart and locked people in
cages well we've made incredible
progress legalizing marijuana in Oregon
the truth is that so much of the drug
wars machinery is still operating the
impact it's made and continues to make
will take a huge amount of work to
rectify
so how do we get there how do we get to
finishing drug reform or two more drug
reform that we need we need to shift the
narrative and change our culture instead
of talking about being tough on crime we
need to talk about being smart on crime
and being smart on crime means that we
know that dealing with drugs as a
criminal issue doesn't make any sense
criminalizing drugs makes us less safe
it pushes people that need help into the
shadows it disproportionately impacts
the poor and people of color and it
gives power to cartels who are
terrorizing our neighbors in nations to
the south as we shift away from
criminalization we need to instead focus
on public health our laws and our
efforts should be aimed at promoting
health in our society what's good for
people who need medicine what helps
people who have addictions and what
actually keeps us safe and free we can't
become complacent we can't think that
merely decriminalizing marijuana in
Oregon is enough because the damage that
has been done is so deep even here in
Oregon we still have marijuana reform
that needs to happen criminal penalties
for marijuana related crimes are still
too high even though alcohol is a much
more dangerous drug criminal penalties
that remain on the books for marijuana
are still much higher than the same
types of penalties for alcohol in
addition employees in Oregon's two can
still be fired for using marijuana even
if they're a medical patient and tenants
in Oregon can still be evicted from
their homes because they use or possess
marijuana in their homes all of this
needs to change and we have to be also
vigilant in protecting our medical
marijuana patients as I mentioned
earlier the ACLU has been at the
forefront of drug reform for a long time
and we're not stopping anytime soon my
sincere hope is that you won't stop
either so I understand that the March is
about to start if you guys can have
head up that way towards the beginning
of the March let's go get them