I'm here to talk just a little bit about
The Hemp stock
we've been denied the permit to to put
on him stock this year some you probably
know
so we asked the court to review the
decision-making process of the Park
Service
it sounds to me like hearing Madeline
here today hearing her say don't smoke
marijuana
put your joint down that doesn't sound
like the Madeline I know it sounds to me
like her Free Speech rights have been
tampered with
just like Paul Stanford's were
told what to say from the stage now by
the city
but we filed a
suit for a reader review and we argued
it
last week
had a few a little flurry of
brief writing after that we should get a
decision next week whether there will be
a Hemp stock 2015 or not
but the reason it was denied is because
some people smoked marijuana down on the
waterfront
so that's probably why Madeline is
having to warn you guys the city can
crack down on us anytime free speech in
the state of Oregon however we have a
constitutional amendment
constitutional provision it's not even
an amendment
and there's a similar case
under the federal law out of out of
Ferguson
it seemed that the police officers in
Ferguson were telling people to move
along Move Along Move Along keep moving
you can't stand here and talk about the
shootings you can't talk about
government you can't talk about anything
just keep moving keep moving
so they sued in federal court and just
quite recently last year
the federal court said no you can't make
people just keep moving along
the reason is it doesn't work
it's not narrowly tailored to solve your
problems it just stops them talking and
you can't stop people from saying what
they want to say
I'm hoping that that's the same result
we'll have next week and that we'll all
be volunteering and planning for him
stock meanwhile keep speaking
because that's what got us here thank
you all