certain people have made these things
possible in the cannabis community we
have so many cannabis warriors that have
come before us that don't get nearly
enough attention and all of us gets come
out here and march around and we have
our cheers and our chance and our flags
and we need to do it all the time but
years ago there were only a few people
that had the guts to do this and we need
to give them mama John a day like today
rain or shine they would be here dr.
Phil the Becca's one guy he's still
alive and well and 91 years old and he
is one of the premier people not just in
the state of Oregon but throughout the
United States that has helped make today
happen that has brought this in front of
the people that has been an honest true
brave warrior to the extent that he lost
his entire career and is no longer able
to sign a prescriptions and he did that
for us he gave up his right to be a
doctor basically for us that's his
sacrifice jack hair is another guy that
a lot of you people would have seen here
today if he was still here Jack was this
terrific warrior that never never gave
up under any circumstances and what
would you say today you'd say so the
seeds of Education everybody that's here
we are not preaching to the choir you
guys need to take everything home and
tell 100 people that's what Jack would
want you to do we got to keep the
momentum up prohibition is an ugly ugly
thing and we need to yank it out of the
ground like a root and make this a
better thing for all people in the
United States if we get those 800,000
people stop them from getting arrested
and jailed every year think of the happy
times everybody have a Christmas think
about all the people that would have a
fulfilled life and it's so it's about
medical but it's also just about life
liberty and happiness and Indian
prohibition so I'm in closing I'd like
to say one please turn into salem news
com we're everywhere
around the world we have a hundred and
twenty five riders in over 100 countries
so you are well represented by looking
at Salem News and seeing what's going on
for your community and industry around
the world and direct from dr. Levac he
would like me to tell you to not smoke
in the ring