one love one love to all the media
that's here today and thank you some of
the media that's been helping um with
the movement of legalization you know
and i mean we really appreciate the
writers out there and those that come in
share your broadcast with the people
continue to do that y'all
you know please continue to do that
cause we love you
you know they uh
they used to call this portland now we
call it potlin y'all be planting roses
as well we be planting pot man y'all
should
tangerines can i have a sample please
i'ma be like
yeah the smoke up in your dressing like
the wind
can't wait to taste the flavor of my
bubble gum i tried it at the cafe i
loved it now i'm going some ak-47 to
that california orange but got a strain
i caught my ankle to help you keep your
bang up yeah
the lights is
i took some super silver hazel
look at all these trees
used to call it portland now we call it
potlin y'all be planting roses while we
be planting pies man don't you see my
spot man room full of hot lamps comments
when you see these but that's gonna be
like all damn look at all these trees
and my weed ain't got no seasoning
tangerine can i have a sample please
is