greetings from northeast portland and
from the capital and from salem listen
i'm not going to talk long i know you
all have been here for a long day
already i just wanted to update you on
what's going on in salem right now now
as you probably know it's a passage of
91 was just the beginning of a process
laws don't spell out all the procedures
required to make them work and some of
that's being hammered out by the Oregon
Liquor Control Commission as well as
some of that some of it in the
legislature in fact yesterday the olcc
put together a group of committees that
are going to look at rules and licensing
and quality and financing and extracts
and infused items and growers are going
to look at all those different issues
but I want to tell you I'm not going to
talk about those i want to i know that i
was asked to speak because of a bill I
introduced in the beginning of the and
start the process of cleaning up some of
the effects of the so-called war on
drugs unfortunately that bill 3372
probably isn't going to make it through
the process this time fortunately
another bill will okay it won't do
everything I had I had hope but as Mick
Jagger would have been talking about the
legislative process he he said you can't
always get what you want so what are we
trying to do well it's important to
recognize the extreme criminalization of
certain marijuana related activities has
done more harm to our communities then
the drug itself ever could combined with
measure 11 and put a lot of people
behind the bar behind bars and gave a
lot of people felony records for actions
that will not be criminal in the future
a stint in prison is not the end of one
so-called debt to society a felony
record can follow you for the rest of
your life closing doors to housing and
employment disrupting families and
dragging the whole community down we
should have learned that from the
experience of alcohol prohibition in the
1920s and 30s but we had to run the
experiment again it seems and now as we
come to our senses and creative system
in which cannabis is legal but regulated
in the future we also need to do
something about the harm that's been
done by the prohibition in the past and
that's why I introduced a bill I
introduced a bill to create a path to
the expungement of
records of nonviolent marijuana related
records and and the reduction of
sentences for similar offenses for
people who are still in custody or under
supervision it's this is a high priority
priority for me to do something about
this because while I won't deny that
crime affects our community and I won't
deny that incarceration sometimes it's
an appropriate response to criminal acts
I also believe that has been used too
often where it makes no sense at all
creating criminals out out of people who
are doing no harm we need to fix that
for the future and also reach back and
fix what has happened in the past now as
I said 33 to 72 is not going to make it
but details matter a lot in the
legislative process and we just couldn't
work out through the details in the time
that we had I understand however that
there will be another bill coming
through the committee on implementing
the Senate the Senate and House
Committee on implementing measure 91 in
the how in the district and the capital
that's called the Joint Committee on
marijuana just so that you know yes it's
a joke and everyone seems to like it I
am always set for some of the folks here
I urge you to use the online Oregon
legislative information system olas look
that up Oh L is to keep informed about
what the committee is doing and I hope
you'll pay more attention to this make
more attention to more than this one
issue because make I want you to make
this issue your gateway issue for more
involvement in our policy making process
our system works better when people
watch and take part and that means you
and I want to also just thank you for
coming out and and being so active in
the campaign last year and stay active
we need to have you to continue to
listen to what's going on to watch to
talk with everyone know who your
legislators are do you know who your
legislators are how many of you know who
your legislators are all right if you
don't you need to look it up and find
out who that is and go and talk with
them let them know that you're out there
let them know that you're watching and
that you want to have some things
changed as I said I don't think my
particular bill is going to make it
through but I believe we will get a bill
that will come through in some form
work that will make certainly make
things a little better for the folks who
have been incarcerated who have records
anto who are presently incarcerated
maybe we'll get some changes and that'll
only because become because you decide
to work for it so thank you very much
take care