thank you so much to Scott herb Thrasher
he's put on a lot of work here this is
all his work today and with some help
from volunteers and also he is the
director of Portland normal which is the
organization in this state that is for
consumers and that's a voice that often
gets lost especially these days with
so-called legalization in this state I
personally have didn't have much of a
speech plan because I spent the last
three months my life wasted on a
swindler who is going to invest in me
but that's what we have now these days
is these sharks circling these people
who haven't been involved in cannabis at
all and don't really care about the plan
are now circling to try to make money
and so I just want everybody to be
conscious of that and aware of it and
and aware of who you support when you do
buy products and that it's people who
really do care about this plant I as he
said I've been involved in Seattle I
actually moved here year and a half ago
because I fell in love with a grower
down here but I've been a cannabis
activist in washington state since 1995
and you know what's happening up there
is not pretty and it's you know
so-called legalization but you know who
thinks this is legal do we think this is
legal because the feds certainly don't
the feds think you're all criminals
still and they the reason that our
regulations are so ugly is because of
the feds up in Washington it's like they
treat it like plutonium or something
when it's a plant that helps people
actually had a friend contact me this
morning who said that he had a friend up
in tacoma who had a five-year-old who
has a serious illness and really needs
cannabis and he's actually calling visit
this is an estate that supposedly legal
and you can go to the store and buy it
and he can't fight they can't find help
for their five-year-old and that's
what's sad is that it used to be easier
to help children but with all the
regulations that are getting piled on
people and the way they're just getting
rid of men
a call the troop growers aren't there
anymore and you can't find these
products that actually help people so
down here I actually had the fortunate
the fortune to spend some time down in a
Applegate Valley last few days with some
just incredible growers who put a lot of
time and energy into making extracts
that they can give to people with with
cancer and children and they told me a
story about a friend whose dad had they
been getting oil to for free and the
doctor said I don't know what you're
doing but keep doing it so we know that
it works and these are people that you
know the state and the feds would love
to run out of the business so that they
can put more and more regulations on
this and track where every single seed
and plant goes because God forbid that
it get out to people that we share it so
it's so crucial that we keep home grows
and then we keep medical gardens because
these are people who are trying to get
genetics out to people the genetics that
help people instead of just trying to
get the highest th e and and there are
the people that can be shut out because
they don't have the money that it takes
to follow these regulations that they're
really expensive everybody wants cheap
pot but it costs a lot of money the when
you're when you've got so many
regulations on you have to keep to buy
this expensive software put tags on
every plant pay all these ridiculous
taxes 280 doesn't allow businesses to
deduct expenses at the federal level the
federal the feds are taking half of the
profits from people so it's really
expensive to get in so this fight is not
over while you're here walk around to
all the booths and sign up for things
it's okay to sign up for all of them
there's a lot of groups out there but
there's a lot of issues there's going to
be a lot of groups you know people talk
about we all need to get together and 12
under one umbrella and that's fine if
you have some common al
but there's there's so many issues out
there I wrote I was thinking about all
these there's let's see there smoking
lounges there's County bands there's
280e there's edible limits
over-regulation pesticides patients
small growers are so many issues to
focus on and all the different
organizations kind of have a different
niche so be part of it signed up for all
the lists and if there's one that really
speaks to you get active get involved
because this fight isn't over and and we
get complacent when we think it's legal
but it's not there's still people
serving life in prison for pot and even
when they're it is legal and it seems
like it's a good thing oh we can all
come out here and smoke pot together but
behind the scenes with the industry
there's regulations going on that that
don't help they actually hurt you know
all these cups that we enjoy going to
this is just one example and actually
organs doing it much better the jobs in
Washington I'll tell you that much but
one of the regulations in Oregon is that
you know the people who get a
recreational license can only give
samples to other people with
recreational license in order to try to
sell it that means that when a cup comes
along next year a recreational grower
can't give a sample to the cup that it's
not legal they'd have to actually go to
the store and buy it to submit it to a
cup and I brought that up to the LCC and
they they claim that that's not what
they intend to do so maybe we'll see
some changes but it's little things like
that that they're just so concerned with
tracking every bit because it might hit
leaked out god forbid somewhere and they
don't think about like the actual effect
on the industry the people who have been
in this so long and know what's best for
the plant and for patients and they're
worried about it might go to another
state well you know what if it's going
to other states at least they're not
getting in Mexico right so there isn't
that horrible you know let hopefully we
have to continue the fight to legalize
it federally that
just the number one thing right now I
think and so like I said go around sign
up thank you so much for coming remember
seattle hempfest third weekend of august
largest cannabis protest evil in the
world and we'd love to see you all there
thanks again Scott