how many folks here want to have a job
how many folks here won't have a place
to live well guess what our state
legislature they don't care if you have
a job if you're a marijuana consumer
they don't care if you have a place to
live your marijuana consumer far as
they're concerned you can be hungry and
homeless living on the streets if you
use marijuana that's why we march folks
the city of Portland as was mentioned
earlier they asked as why are you guys
still marching I thought we fixed
everything and it's like no people you
know we have consumers right you mean
you have businesses out there businesses
can now sell but where can you use it if
you're a renter you cannot use it in
your home if your lanterns and want it
most employers they'll fire you if you
turn a positive and a urine test for THC
metabolites they don't care whether we
smoked a month ago they're going to fire
you that's why we're here folks that's
why we march and we march for our
brothers and sisters who can't march
publicly in cities around Oregon even
where they have to hide their belief in
a marijuana plant that marijuana plant
is the best plan for them remember that
that's why we're marching for folks that
can't March is there you know there
would be blackballed by the local
jurisdiction that they did can we march
because we need to have our rights to
gather in public and use marijuana when
we want to you know it's again our state
legislature says you guys can't smoke
marijuana if you're a renter guess what
it's legal so you can't but it's not
legal folks I'm sorry measure 91 you
know which I helped draft oh you know it
was a partial stepped we are not there
yet and don't let anybody ever tell you
that we have legalization we have the
best model in the country when it's only
part way belt now we have to make sure
that we have a place to live a place we
have social clubs and that the fact that
the city of Portland you know they don't
charge they're charging outrageous sums
of money if you want to get into
marijuana business you know again it
falls right into the say legislature and
the
bureaucrats they would only like to
regulate a few large industries dealing
with marijuana we have to tell know that
this is truly a cottage industry
everybody has a right to grow and sell
marijuana with minimal fees not
expensive fees sorry just remember that
when you're out there when you're
talking to your friends saying why did
you spend a beautiful Saturday in the
streets of Portland well you could have
been home gardening or doing something
else because we had we're losing our
rights folks you know they say oh you
guys you have legal marijuana you can go
into a store oh and here's my favorite
if you're a patient you can buy tax-free
it's like well what good does that do if
the patient is low income you know
wouldn't be four they were getting it
for free you know and taxes only we're
going to be twenty percent who's paying
for the other eighty percent you know so
that doesn't make any sense right so and
it was Anna was talking about not just
write and call your lettuce I just go
visit them when they have a town hall
and they all love Gabby's little town
halls go talk to them tell them who you
are they need to see real people because
right now you know down in Salem they're
seeing the big business folks and we
can't let marijuana become big business
here in Oregon we need to show the
entire world that we grow the best
marijuana in the world and we have the
most freedoms with it so and if Anna is
still out there I'm sure she want me to
help lead folks in this little thing we
have to say so back here in my poster
you know these four things when you have
an officer comes up to you you still
need to remember these even though
marijuana's somewhat legal so I go
repeat after me am I free to go officer
there we go he's got it right he's got
the one right there on this thing so am
I free to go officer I do not consent to
any searches
and I wish to speak to my attorney yeah
and I wish to remain silent