hi everybody
um
glad to be here today
um I've been an activist like you said a
lot of people might know me from the
cafe I was there from most of the time
it was it's had it had a location
hopefully we'll have a location sometime
again but a lot more people know me from
Facebook where I started
basically as soon as I got on Facebook
back in 2008 was very about the same
time I got hooked up with Oregon normal
through going to the meetings where we
gave away clones and medicine to people
who couldn't afford
to buy it or you know have their own
Growers and stuff
um
so I got very involved with that and I'm
very happy for the chance to talk here
today but
well
I think it's important not only to talk
to your legislatures
but also to talk just to your family and
your friends who are not you know out
here today you know preaching to the
choir is a wonderful thing to do
and
um you'll do it you know a lot if you
get the chance to speak to people a lot
most of the people you talk to will be
people who agree with you but there's a
lot of people out there who listen to
reason as we can see passing the measure
91 here 56 percent
was a big victory for you know
our movement and the world and
especially when several months before
the year before we were told by the
marijuana policy project that we
shouldn't seek to legalize in 2014
because it was an off-year election and
people wouldn't come out and things
wouldn't happen because of um
experience they had in the past with gay
marriage and
um which is a great issue and I'm glad
to see that moving forward and and it's
another issue that has Unstoppable
momentum but when you look at
consistent pulling across the country
which puts support for medical marijuana
at 80 percent and higher among the
general population
um
it's um time for the politicians to just
get with the program and the way to make
that happen again is to contact your
legislatures write letters uh emails I
got
um this
sb844 which Aaron was talking about a
minute ago where they're making changes
to the medical program I've emailed back
and forth with Peter Buckley and some of
the suggestions that I made actually
made it into the latest amendments uh
structure so they listen they're trying
to do things right and they know that
um there's a lot at stake
and they're listening and it's very good
to see that happening here and to
provide an example for the people who um
will come after us and um because in
2016 we'll probably see legalization
initiatives in California
we'll get the whole West Coast
um legal
for uh for adults it'll be great and
also and Nevada possibly Massachusetts
Rhode Island and Maine are talking about
doing it through the legislator Ohio
supposedly has half the signatures they
need to get it on the ballot for 2015
passing legalization in Ohio and in an
odd year would be
almost
Unthinkable but it may happen
um but while all this good stuff is
happening and we're giving a good
example
um people are still being executed
um around the world for cannabis
trafficking crimes it last weekend in
Indonesia one of the nine people who
were put in front of a firing squad was
Cannabis trafficker and he was killed
for it and then every year Indonesia
Malaysia
Saudi Arabia a couple other different
countries there's about nine around the
world that still execute people for drug
crimes and the drug war just has to end
that's you know the the violence we saw
last week
in Maryland uh around the Freddie gray
killing
um is you know made possible by the no
knock raids and other
exorbitant measures that have been just
become every day events for the police
to put on there have been SWAT raids and
no knock raids and people just shouldn't
be dying for this plant that can save so
many people and which
um we're finding out now the hemp side
of things we can make batteries for a
small fraction of the cost graphene
level batteries that will hold a
tremendous charge for a tremendous
amount of time at a much much cheaper
cost than it would to make it from the
scientifically otherwise derived stuff
um but things are going in the right
direction it's good to see Brave
Michaela up here and but keep in mind
that last month
in Kansas
um an 11 year old boy was in a drug
education class and they were talking
about how these people should avoid
cannabis and it was had evil ill health
effects and this 11 year old stood up
and said no it doesn't it saved my
mother's life and he went down to list
all the good things that cannabis does
for people well
um
that ended up with him being taken away
from his mother so Shona Banda
who's a woman in again she's in Kansas
she saved her life she had Crohn's
disease and was on the brink of death
and discovered that cannabis oil could
save her and now she's instead of being
bedridden and not being able even to
hold her kid when which she was
at the time she's you know an activist
and
um
and she had to she's lost her kid for
the time being
um so this stuff is still going on there
are people dying and there's the
legislation that's coming out there's a
lot of legislation coming out
in places like Oklahoma of all places in
Georgia
um
but there's CBD only laws which
um people want because their CBD is very
helpful with seizures and stuff and it
doesn't get you high but that keeps out
the THC which does so much
for so much the whole plant medicine is
really the way to go
and anything other than that is an
excuse for the police to be able to
still keep arresting people
um
thanks for letting me speak today I
wanted to give a shout out to LK who's
here and who told me
um he used to introduce me to people in
the cafe he would say if someday your
kids aren't getting arrested for smoking
weed this is going to be the guy you
want to thank and
um that's like the biggest honor I've
gotten from anybody and that's just for
you know posted on Facebook and
um not shutting up about it uh we're not
done with this fight keep it up uh
contact your legislators tell people
back in your home States if you moved to
Oregon like I did
to talk to their legislatures 80 percent
80 support and politicians are afraid to
support it still in places thanks for
your time and look forward to the March
later on have a great day