what I would like to talk about today to
all of you is that
we need to look at the bigger picture we
need to understand that in order for
what we're doing here at the state level
to be truly successful we need to make
changes at the national level we need to
back representative blumenauer in his
project and we need to reach out to
States outside of Oregon and let them
know that there's hope for them that by
descheduling cannabis and by allowing
states to decide how cannabis is going
to be regulated Across the Nation we
open up doors for all of us that would
eliminate the moratoriums that we're
seeing on medical cannabis
um dispensaries here in Oregon right now
138 cities have enacted a moratorium for
a year on dispensaries because they
don't think that there's enough
regulation under the new rules I don't
know about you guys but I read those
rules
come on
there's plenty of rules there to
regulate cannabis to keep it away from
kids to make it safer access for
patients and I would suggest that
although we do need to fight that battle
we need to fight the battle at the
national level even more because once
those restrictions are removed
you'll see that explosion that
Congressman blumenero was talking about
and on we're on the we are on the verge
of that explosion legalization is coming
the law enforcement may not like it
there are people that don't like it but
it's coming whether they like it or not
how it comes about will be up to us we
do have the capability of having a huge
impact on what that's going to look like
the reason that these moratoriums are
happening and the reason that the law is
a little tighter than we would like it
is because enough of us weren't there
talking about it we didn't go talk to
our legislators and let them know what
we really wanted so guess who was there
law enforcement
that's what they like to do to us throw
us in jail so
please as you're moving forward if
you've never done anything as an
activist before in your life besides
come to one of these marches I would
suggest that maybe you take one little
step it doesn't have to be huge it
doesn't have to be a lot but you need to
be heard by someone other than this
group of people right here and you can
do that by sending an email to your
Congressman it's really easy to do and
you can find information so that you can
be an informed speaker about cannabis
just by Googling cannabis and the
disease of your choice or cannabis and
penalties or cannabis and children or
all of those myths that we've heard all
these years have been disapproved every
single one of them and we need to spread
that word across the entire country
bigger than Oregon bigger than anything
we can see here and we won't see changes
that we had not even imagined and on the
verge of those
um changes we see groups like the normal
Women's Alliance who is working this
year to start program that deals with
women and pregnancy and children with
special needs and mediation and
arbitration for women who end up in
prison for cannabis laws because they
answered their boyfriend's phone who was
making the dope deal women are also part
of the group that are marginalized in
this cannabis prohibition because along
with people of color women are going to
jail who haven't even used cannabis like
I said just for answering the phone
families are getting torn apart and that
needs to stop and you can do that by
contacting your Congressman by
contacting your local representative by
e who is just starting we have a booth
over here and we would love to talk to
you about what we're trying to do we
want to become a resource as cannabis
legalization moves forward parents are
going to need to go someplace to talk to
figure out how to talk to their kids
about cannabis and that's what parents
for pot is about the normal Women's
Alliance is another group of women who
share you my duty have come out of the
Cannabis closet and I would suggest to
everybody here that if you haven't done
that find a way to do it you guys can
only do it with one person even if they
only tell your best friend who never
knew that you smoked weed that you smoke
weed it's a step in the right direction
and it's going to be the rock in the
pond that's going to move ever outward
until finally we are free
I don't want to hear that word free
because that's what it's really about
it's not about getting high it's not
about I like to eat my brownies it's not
about I want to smoke a joint it's about
Freedom it's about personal freedom I
shouldn't have to have a drug test
because I work in an office neither
should you yes we should be able to do
what we want when we go home at night as
long as it doesn't hurt anybody else
and I don't know about you guys but the
only way I heard somebody if I'm smoking
a bull at home is if I accidentally burn
their fingers
well everybody who comes here gets
excited about the March and we're
excited to be marching at it gives you a
really great buzz when you go home from
this and you're thinking about what
happened here I hope that you will take
the opportunity to reach out to your
representatives to speak to them and let
them know how you feel about cannabis
laws to let people who are running for
office know that if they do not support
our ideas they're not going to get
elected my name is Anna Diaz I'm a proud
Stoner join me and let's end cannabis
prohibition thank you