thanks for having me up here it's great
to be up here it's my first year I was
the coordinator for the March down in
Medford for five years
I'm the former director of Southern
Oregon normal I was the executive
director for five years up until June
1st of 2012.
May 23 2012 my facility was raided by
Madge that's the Medford Area drug and
gang enforcement in Jackson County
under the direction of the state of
Oregon
my husband and I were arrested and we
were in Jackson County jail for seven
days under 550 000 bail each
we were charged with more than 25 class
A felonies
we knew our rights because we had great
attorneys
my attorney was Paul Loney
you can see his Banner right over here
my husband had Leland Burger many of you
know my great friendly limberger
they're both Normal attorneys I suggest
you support normal
because they've been around for a long
time
Southern Oregon normal is no longer in
existence that chapter closed
there's Portland normal now
I'm signing up today
Russ bellville's executive director
there I believe
he's one of my mentors
I had several mentors along the way
after I stepped out of the Cannabis
closet after 24 years in health care and
leaving the corporate corruption
I push legal pills on geriatric patients
and held their hands as they died
it was a shame with the nursing Society
did to those patients knowing that
Oxycontin killed them and the plant
could have saved them
I watched my husband Drool on himself
when Oxycontin came out because he was
one of the test patients that got to try
it out
our children played in the yard while
their dad drooled in the chair
I said no more I talked to his doctor
and we started him on cannabis he got
off all the narcotics except for one
he was on six
he had back surgery and used cannabis
and one narcotic
he still uses that one narcotic to this
day
and cannabis
he's a functioning father and
grandfather
he grows our medicine
he does not rely on the government to
pay over twelve thousand dollars a month
on Pharmaceuticals under the Oregon
Health Plan like they used to
our resources in this state are wasted
because our federal government refuses
to take this off of the scheduling as a
one it's wrong we have to change it so
all of you've heard today about the
legislators
we're active there in Salem we've been
there for weeks now Anthony Taylor and
Anthony Johnson and myself have been
there many of you have been watching the
hearings on
your monitors
your phones whatever you've been doing
to watch thank you whatever you've been
doing to communicate thank you we need
more of you to communicate they are
listening to us Monday they are going to
pass 8 44. Senate Bill 844 is going to
get passed the governor has written a
letter Kate Brown
expressing her opinions about how she
feels about the seed to sail
tracking
many of you can read that letter
yourselves on dip for
if not you can contact me on Facebook
and I'll forward you that letter
right now as it stands
when you harvest you can keep all of
your weight
there are also is now
no definition to an immature plant
no
you can keep all your clones no limit on
clones you guys that's huge those are
big wins for the medical marijuana
community
keep your weight
unlimited amount of clones
another big win for us is cities are not
allowed to ban us they can only Zone us
on your medical marijuana facilities
they cannot ban us that's huge
we fought hard
the city I live in Medford Oregon
you suck
you suck hard you raided my facility and
you shut off medicine to over 3 000
patients
some of those patients have died since
you shut my facility off
from cancer this week we lost Jesse
who is an advocate for PTSD and even sat
on a panel at Southern Oregon University
with Peter Buckley and Paul Stanford and
myself
advocating
to get the law changed and change the
law we did and we qualify PTSD in this
state
May Jesse rest in peace
I have five weeks to go and my felony
will be turned over to a misdemeanor
it's been 11 months of bench probation
I was able to keep my patient card and
my son became my grower
we even got our guns back
in two more years
I get to have my record expunged and I
can get my concealed handgun carry back
too
I want to give you all hope
that lose hope at times
don't ever lose hope there is hope in
this plant there is life in this plant
this plant cured Michaela
and this plant cured me
don't lose hope in this plant
this plant is love
this plant is life
have a great March and have a great day
thank you for welcoming me to Portland