can I just say Portland is absolutely
beautiful
today hi I want to first I want to know
if anybody's asking the patients what
they
want I don't think so cuz they can't be
cuz if anybody was the number of plants
would a grower can grow would not be
dropping in numbers or the amount of
patience a grower can grow
for
wouldn't be dropping in numbers there
are too many patients that depend and
rely on topicals
Edibles inhalent FCO or
RSO it takes a lot of plants to be able
to provide it we all and we all know we
can't or shouldn't stop taking it or
what ails you can and will
return there will definitely be a rise
in six patients I don't want to a I want
to know if any anybody still asking the
patients what they
want want to ask the patients what they
need or do we just don't
care well I'm a patient and I
care that's why we've opened the other
spot it's a recycled refurbished and
reused place where we as the community
Gathering and safety we we also provide
a Gathering Place for many Community
groups such as
ogf
crrh hamst Oregon normal cannabis
genetics preservation
Society human solution
International parents for
pot and
gals so so as you can hear this this
community place let me say again
Community is where
activities and events are constantly
going on we have our can ofer cause
coming up July 18th we will shut down
the street on Harold in
72nd we will have music vendors artists
barbecues and kids fashion shows hope to
see you all come out the proceeds will
benefit bit parents for pot
International or
national that is just one of the things
that the other spot does pretty soon
there will be nowhere for anyone to
go and medicate and be social under one
common roof these places like the other
spot don't exist then our sociability
dies we and Me Myself Believe that there
needs to be 50 more of these
places to go and medicate and be
social there's certainly enough medical
dispensaries out
there but where the Clean Air Act comes
in there will be nowhere for us to go
and medicate in out of public view so we
as patients will continue to break this
law so it is important for you to
support
places like to that supports you and
your efforts in this community this
place is not my place but it's our
place please don't talk to talk please
walk the
walk if you feel that there's anything
that you can't give that's not true pick
up a phone make a phone call write write
a letter
while you're sitting behind your
computers send an email to your
representatives go to the capital show
your presence there's always something
you can give or do please be
proactive I want to thank my husband Big
Mike he doesn't get enough of that
I want to thank Jesse and Mary for
taking this
ride and I wanted to thank my family and
my friends for all the continued
support thank
you