yeah you feelin good well I'm really
excited to be here as super glad to be
back here again for those of you who
don't know about the ACLU we are one of
the oldest civil liberties organizations
in the country National Organization is
almost a hundred years old now and we've
had an organization here in Portland and
in Oregon for six over 60 years and we
have been working on drug war issues and
on marijuana issues for a very very long
time back when we were fighting for a
decriminalization of small amounts of
marijuana a long long time ago fighting
for medical marijuana and then fighting
for fighting for recreational marijuana
and and really the fight continues so
I'm the policy director I work on
legislation at this at the state
legislature I also advocate in in the
city the city of Portland and cities and
counties around the around the state so
you know at the ACLU we really believe
that the drug war and and and the war
against marijuana that has been going on
for a very very long time it's one of
the most important civil liberties
issues of our time really one of the
most important issues it's important
because it has to do with people's
access to medicine which is incredibly
important to all of us and it also has
to do with our our personal autonomy
right the decisions that we make about
our own bodies and what we do with our
own bodies and how how we do things with
our bodies that doesn't hurt anybody
else right we're not hurting anybody
else will we make decisions about using
or not using marijuana and so it's it's
a really crucial issue that we'd be able
to have that freedom right not only that
the drug war intersects with so many
other civil liberties issues that are
important to us right there's there's a
huge intersection with racial justice
when we look at the way the drug war has
really disproportionately impact
communities of color in this country and
also frankly all around the world right
and then there's such a huge
intersection obviously with the criminal
justice system and with the fact that
we've been locking people up and
and you know for manufacturing marijuana
for selling marijuana for using
marijuana for far far too long so you
know we have come really far and I'd
like us just to like take a moment to
actually like acknowledge that at least
here in Oregon we have come really
really far and we should like seriously
power ourselves on the back all of us
for that fight right it's absolutely
amazing but we also need to acknowledge
and recognize that we have so much
farther to go right here in Oregon you
know we at the ACLU we dream of an
Oregon where insurance pays for medical
marijuana right where people have access
to marijuana and not being able to
afford it is not gonna stop them from
being able to access their medicine
right we dream of a world where medical
patients and recreational users don't
face discrimination in the workplace and
in housing and where we actually have
protections against that kinds of just
kind of discrimination right because
what people are doing for medicine and
what people are doing in their free time
shouldn't have anything to do with what
they're doing on the job right and where
they get to live so those are huge
issues that we need to fight here in
Oregon but we also have a responsibility
to fight for legalization in every
single state in this country and not
only that we need legalization
everywhere in the world and we really
need to take take take responsibility
for the fact that the United States
really has they took the drug war
international right and we we brought
that mindset to places where that
mindset did not even exist right and so
we have a responsibility not only to
change things here but to change things
in the rest of the world so I'm just
really you know I'm honored to be here
I'm honored to be part of this amazing
community of people who advocate for for
our rights and advocate against can a
biga tree we do have a lot of work to do
and I'm just here to tell you the ACLU
of Oregon will be here we will continue
to fight with you and and I'm just
really really honored to be part of that
fight so thank you so much everyone