hey Portland how are you
hey we've been yes all the time every
time we do an initiative we want you to
vote Yes yes yes all the time for
cannabis but I gotta tell you we got
some problems up in Washington they're
the very problems I talked about on this
stage this time last year and that is in
Washington state our legislature has
just passed a law that will end medical
access as we know it and require that
patients that don't grow for themselves
obtain their medicine from the state
licensed recreational shops that allow
any of up to 200 pesticides in that
product now that may be okay for a
recreational consumer that may be
healthy I don't know what the levels are
but I'm here to tell you
pesticides are not medicine for any sick
person
we have filed referendum 76 in
Washington state but now it's not yes we
want to tell them no the legislature has
passed this law no
the governor signed this law no
putting patients in with recreational
consumers to compete
for with with somebody that wants to get
high so that you can be well and at an
exorbitant price we say no they want us
to lower our plant limits which are
already half of what was originally
recommended for any patient to provide
for themselves on down to four to six
plants we say no we have legalized the
ounce for anybody to have
but now they want patience to be on a
registry and we say no and the reason
for that is because we register one
thing in Washington State
sex offenders and we're not sex
offenders there is no reason there's no
valid reason
to put patients on a registry anymore
you know in Oregon you guys did it
before medical and that helped establish
your your legal framework we have been
fighting since 1998 to get improvements
for patients and we've gotten forward
we've gotten forward and now we seem to
be going backwards
the fight is on for medical
you know compassion is where
provider will just give medicine to
someone in need
I don't see that happening in a in a
for-profit business
and when you whatever you pay you are
paying an exorbitant tax you're putting
this tax on the very people that can at
least affect it
you you put this tax on and people are
going to have a choice of getting less
medicine or going right back to the back
alleys and black market and that is
where we were it is not where we want to
be and we refuse to be there
we must keep medical legitimate
I've already had commitments of
thousands of dollars a piece all right
I'm in for a thousand Buck Paul Stanford
has said he's down for a thousand
dollars a thousand dollars a thousand
dollars a thousand dollars we're going
to add it up our patients are energized
our paper to uh get this referendum on
the ballot will be out uh May 17th 18th
right around there we'll go live and our
patients will do a wonderful job
collecting signatures and educating the
public on why they want to vote no
on referendum 76.
but we won't be able to do that alone
we need our community we need all the
Growers that grow medical we need all
the access points that provide for
patients we need all the authorizing
Physicians that do a wonderful job
picking up the slack of the other
providers that refuse to provide
authorizations for our patients in need
we need a thousand dollars from each one
of these entities and we need it for
every quarter through this campaign it's
going to cost about 240 thousand dollars
to collect the signatures if we do
nothing
will cost less than that but we need
that money
502 which promised us they told us they
told us over and over and over again 502
will not affect medical medical patients
will not be affected by 502 and now they
want to put us right in that system it
was all a lie it was a grab for power
and money and control they have gone
from arresting us to taking our wallets
right out of our hands
no no on r76 will save safe access in
Washington state it is going to
Galvanize our community as it never has
before and it will enable us to have our
discussions as a community moving
forward so that we can create reasonable
regulations that codify the services we
provide to patients now
we have an estimated five to eight
hundred access points across Washington
can you imagine how many people that's
serving right now
the 502 system has roughly 60 plus
licensed stores and they're not all
opened yet
they can't even serve the recreational
demand they have now how are they going
to serve thousands of patients that have
almost daily needs
I I don't understand what the thinking
was but we're gonna straighten them out
we're going to get this done we're gonna
get it on the ballot we're gonna pass it
in November and then we're gonna stand
up as a community and tell the
legislators what to do right we need
this to be right we need medical to be
separate from recreational if you don't
do that Friday is going to come and the
patient's going to have a Payday and
he's going to walk on down to that store
and be willing to pay that high tax
because he's sick and he needs his
medicine and you know what's going to
happen he's going to find out that
Johnny's got a party tonight and he
bought up all that supply of that very
strain that he needs to be well simply
so Johnny and his buddies could get high
no no on r76.org
I'm sorry
r76no.org is our website and we'll be
going live probably Monday or Tuesday
it'll be public information it'll be
volunteer opportunities and sign ups and
donations let's get this done in
Washington and I pray to God you guys
keep your eyes on the legislature watch
every single thing I don't know how you
ended up with seed to sell but
it seems to be going backwards
free the plant free the people promote
the economy
save cannabis save medical cannabis
our
76no.org thank you all for your support
get it done keep it legal make it well
thank you thank you thank you