I'm from Washington State I know we're
in Oregon right now but some people from
Vancouver might be visiting today if you
know anybody in washingon tell them we
did legalize recreational but the
lawmakers in Washington think that means
that we no longer need to be allowed to
grow 15 plants I think that's ridiculous
the lawmakers are acting like children
I'm ashamed to be a Washingtonian now
that this law is on the books the fact
that our governor signed this law on the
books makes me ashamed to be a
Washingtonian so look for
r76 this will undo what the governor
just did and it will maintain medical
marijuana in Washington state the way it
is it will let us keep growing 15 plants
it will allow the farmers markets to
keep happening and providing the highest
quality most affordable medicine to
patients who need it tell your friends
about real legalization in Washington
state we need volunteers to help with
the
r76 referendum thank you