you also testified before the DEA in
1988 I did indeed and now what what came
from that and who did you speak with
when you were there I testified in front
of a a judge Francis young very
intelligent man and the feeling of the
people that I was working with normal
and uh that that it it was he was going
to brush it off okay we were going to
finish our testimony and 15 minutes
later he was going to say forget it he
didn't do that he um agonized over this
for a long time and his DEC he was he
was only to make a recommendation to the
head of DEA he couldn't make the
decision and he recommended
wholeheartedly and he had heard people
all over the United States from all
different kinds of illnesses and said in
effect for God's sakes help these people
and what kind of response did he receive
the had of DEA in effects said drop dead
why do you think that is cuz they're
stupid okay now I we only have a couple
of minutes left and I was wondering you
commented that people of an older
generation than what I am have a problem
at times being able to re re rethink
restructure their thinking on this plant
what do you have to say to them okay we
were told and and I came from an era
that if somebody if my government told
me uh go out and stand in the middle of
the traffic I'd probably do it because
they would never tell me anything that
was
harmful and it has taken me a long time
to realize this isn't this is no longer
true maybe it never was but I thought it
was and so
therefore um it's difficult you you you
just it's like a religion you may go
away from the religion that you were
brought up as a child but it's always
there oh go with your gut feeling if you
think you're right go for it thank you
very much