kind of response did you get when you
went public did you get harassed the
police department come down on you did
it was amazing the way I describe it and
have described it for many years as it
rained marijuana on our house Wow the
people the article that I read about
finding on the doorstep and i laughed
was totally true we found it in brown
paper bags and our doorstep we got it
through the mail postage paid we also
got it in the mailbox we live in a rural
area and we have a rural mailbox founded
in the mailbox funded on back porch and
had many people deliver it to us Wow
okay and we'll be right back after this
we're talking with maina today and may
now what I understand is that you began
a crusade in your state to real
eagle-eyes him for medical purposes that
brought forth on October 10 1979 and a
history-making policy within your state
isn't that correct and true he chooses
the true share that we when we decided
to go public we decided that we needed
to be legal and so we contacted the
legislature to see if there was a
possibility that Michigan could do this
and found that someone else had been
there before us and it was in the
process so we joined the process Keith
went with us in early October and then
again late in October he was very ill
and we went without him and it went to a
hundred to nothing in the Senate and I
forgotten what the count was in the
house but yes indeed it did go and now
does that mean that in Michigan if the
people can start using it for medical
purpose doesn't mean that one once the
bill is passed then it has to be signed
and it was signed on october 22nd 1979
by the lieutenant governor of the state
of michigan
and that was the Dare son died so given
breath he he never received legal
marijuana and then after that it was
over a year before the state received
the marijuana the federal government
stands in your way and they're not
cooperative but Michigan in 33 other
states did pass marijuana laws and
indeed the area we live in received the
marijuana in fact i received it
personally from the state and the doctor
that took care of Keith had encouraged
me to work on the legality of it and he
got a license and as time went on he
said to me may I had I can't do this
anymore and I was hurt and now for what
I understand to an ollie was the
government slow in getting the hemp
marijuana into the state but during this
time while it was coming in you were
also getting hemp to other patients and
other people not after got legal okay
not after cat legal before it got legal
when Keith died we had a great deal of
marijuana okay and I knew what it would
do and I would not throw it away and I
did not I did not play games about it
and yes then the doctor said to me he
would send me patience I have to call
him our patients and say you know if
someone was saying doctor I'm going to
quit I'm you know dying can't be worse
and he would send them to me and well
now didn't you feel like you're breaking
a law didn't that now I understand that
people of your generation have an
ingrained thought when it comes to him
rain washing its cough yeah that because
it's illegal it shouldn't even be
discussed let alone considered and now
yet you okay I'm in a different category
I yes it's illegal and I found on my
children using it but we're talking
about life and death we're talking about
people
it's not even a quality of life which is
important but it's life and death and
people there are many people who will
die and I know of several who are have
survived because they were able to use
marijuana a dad told me just last year
this year that his son had cancer and he
refused to take the treatment and so one
of his buddies got him stoned so he was
so happy he really didn't care what he
was doing unaware that it could help the
nausea and so he continued his treatment
and young man is alive and well today
now you shared with me that there was a
vet Vietnam vet who was paralyzed I up
to him this year no could you tell that
okay he's a representative of disabled
veterans in southern Illinois and he
told me he had several vertebrae's
damaged during the war and he did some
rehab in a hospital in in Colorado
before he left his physician took him
aside and said I do not want you to take
the drugs that the Veterans organization
of the hospital is going to prescribe
for you he said I want you to take
marijuana use marijuana smoke and the
young man what he said he got to the way
he was incontinent with his bladder and
his bowels and was paralyzed he said in
five years he got so he could walk five
miles he could also take a few steps
without the walker and that his
incontinence was under control now I
understand that aids suffers people who
are dealing with that that disease can
find relief with absolute with him
there's an organization called Mars
marijuana AIDS research service and it's
to help them apply for legal marijuana
it's not going well it's going better
than it others have but
it's very slow there's so many of them
and the government is saying they don't
have the resources and you commented
that people with epilepsy epilepsy I I
did a national television thing a few
months ago and I received many many
phone calls from people with various
illnesses and one of my recent one was a
young woman with epilepsy and she was
from New York State couldn't drive
because of the seizures and had tried
the prescribed drugs and eventually
somehow someone talked her into smoking
marijuana and she was seizure free for
two and a half years and I if I remember
right she said two years in her State
and she could get her driver's license
back so she was back driving now when
this is used for medicinal purposes
people think that you should do is that
just smoking it you just going to the
hospital room and say okay doctor I want
a joint or two and you have your friends
beginning off the street and fired up is
that the only way they're gonna be used
that the best way you know it's the
fastest way okay but for someone a
cancer patient I've talked to many you
know and they have cancer because they
smoke tobacco and they simply cannot
tolerate any any other smoke in their
lungs so we can make brownies we can
make suppositories by making the butter
and and putting them in a capsule and
the nurses told me for children poke
holes in the capsule so that you don't
have to wait quite so long for the
castle dissolve before the the
ingredients get in the bloodstream and
also tea and I'm thinking the tea for
people my age you know we could drink an
herbal tea without a blink of an eye
okay and I was told this summer by a man
was dying of cancer that the pain the
nausea and the appetite and that the the
tea got into a system in like five
minutes some of the other things the
brownies
the suppositories vs bastards are
wonderful because you don't throw them
back up again that's true and the
digested foods brownies and such now you
said children now realizing that hemp is
an illegal substance for Americans to
use it's kind of unusual to hear someone
encourage that we give this to children
if you have a child dying and they are
giving you no hope whatsoever and this
is hope I have no problem with that at
all do you know of any children that
have benefited I know of one child it to
my knowledge and I and this was about 10
years ago and the child was so emaciated
and there was simply no other place in
his body to a poke a needle and they had
to stop treatment and to stimulate his
appetite they made him brownies and teas
and he was able to go back and continue
his treatment and to the best of my
knowledge the wild is alive and well
today Wow very interesting we'll be
right back after this we thought we were
I i distributed what we had and then
when it became legal ID I no longer well
I didn't have any more and I didn't try
to get any more but it was legal and so
I still worked with the doctor but I
didn't work directly with patients shoes
in the marijuana but eventually he
stopped using it and I was angry and
hurt and and he said to me may I cannot
spend more time doing paperwork than I
do taking care of patients and I have to
discontinue using it and and we had 34
states where it was legal and now every
doctor in every state not all of them
received it but the bills are dormant
because the federal government made it
so difficult horrendous for the doctors
to you so what I understand to of people
who have glaucoma and are applying right
the hemp for
paramedic absolutely from what I
understand the paperwork takes anywhere
from a year to two years yeah it's
horrendous and the Mars project is
attempting to they have cut it down
until a doctor can do it in in about 50
minutes now for I understand you also
testified before the DEA in 1988 I did
indeed and now what came from that who
did you speak with when you are I
justified in front of a judge Francis
young very intelligent man and the
feeling of the people that I was working
with normal and that that it was he was
going to brush it off we were going to
finish our testimony in 15 minutes later
he was going to say forget it he didn't
do that he agonized over this for a long
time and his to see he was only to make
a recommendation to the head of DEA he
couldn't make the decision and he
recommended whole heartedly and he had
heard people all over the United States
from all different kinds of illnesses
and said in effect for God's sakes help
these people and what kind of response
that he received they had a DEA in
effect said drop dead why do you think
that is because they're stupid okay now
I you only have a couple of minutes left
and I was wondering you commented that
people of an older generation than what
I am have a problem at times being able
to rethink restructure their thinking on
this plant what do you have to say to
that okay we were told and I came from
an era that if somebody if my government
told me go out instead in the middle of
the traffic I'd probably do it because
they would never tell me anything that
was harmful and it has taken me a long
time to realize this isn't this is no
longer true maybe it never was but I
thought it was and so therefore it's
difficult you you you just
it's like a religion you may go away
from the religion that you were brought
up as a child but it's always there and
I'm not sure that I would ever be able
to smoke a marijuana cigarette okay now
you've talked about Mars and there's
probably a variety of people who are
watching this show who'd like to have
the chance to find out more about your
organization or the organization Mars
it's got address and phone number I
don't have it it's through act a CT
Alliance for cannabis therapeutics and
they're based here in Washington DC I do
not have an address or telephone number
but i'm sure that through normal high
times has an ad in it there are many
places that they can contact them any
final comment to our audience oh go with
your gut feeling if you think you're
right go far thank you very much it has
really been a unique learning experience
having me on our show and I hope that
the information that she brought forth
is something that you can digest and
share with people around you and you
grow from there are a lot of people out
there who are suffering medically and
need the benefits of the medicines that
are derivative um who that derive from
the hemp plant we encourage you to write
your Congressman we encourage you to
write your Senators and we encourage you
to become more vocal in your community
to bring this message forward thank you
very much for tuning in we look forward
to seeing you the next time thank you
very much may like to have you back on
the show thank you I'd love to come back