get registered and
vote by 1972 I have gotten involved I
was 32 years old got an argument with a
guy got into an argument with a guy
about how much he charged me for some
pot and he said it was a N9 and I said
it was a six we got into a fight we made
up this book this book became the best
seller in the United States in the
Underground Market in 19 1973 in 1974
and people walked up to me and said Mr
her I was 33 years
old Mr
her did you know that they used to make
paper for
marijuana and I looked down on my
lid and I just could a picture how they
made
paper I was from Buffalo New York
originally they don't do that back
there
so next thing is somebody come K come up
19 20 year old kid going to college he
said you know they used to use hemp for
sales and
clothes
marijuana I had barely ever heard the
word hemp before in my life and usually
with a hemp
Thro it just kept growing after I wrote
this book people thought I must know
something about p i at that time 1973
early 73 I probably couldn't identify a
pop plant if I stumbled
up in 1973 I met a guy named captain
edare he owned a head shop in Los
Angeles called heads and high then van
eyes another one
in when by himself this guy in
1972 decided that when they were
collecting signatures to put California
marijuana ship on the ballot he decided
the unpaid volunteered initiative he
decided to open the store 24 hours a day
7 days a week and he give people 50% off
if they bring in off a water pipe off
a
p you're back on
hello
so here we were with
this Captain Ed in 1972 opened the store
around the
clock and did something no human being
had ever done before that I have ever
heard he collected 140,000 signatures
from his two stores in the San Fernando
Valley one third of all the signatures
that were collected in the state of
California to put the marijuana
initiative by volunteers on the
ballot that hundreds of petitioners came
out of the store would go out come back
he'd give them some bucks off something
he'd smoke them out if they have place
to sleep he'd sleep them in the
backro it was a hell of a thing you
couldn't believe it worked it wasn't us
steel and it wasn't
the US government or the Army this is a
rag tag bunch of people that basically
look like we do right
now fact a little bit more right tall
hats
anyway as I'm telling you the
story in
1972 he opened the store he made it his
business more than the other 200 head
shot in California 300 record stores
from the chains that all had carried the
petition he got more signatures than all
the other four 500 stores in the state
that carried the petition out of one
store he got more signatures than all
the other stores in the state
combined he made Believers out of people
that never never thought they could
believe in the power that one person can
bring
forth for those of you out there that
might know Captain out of there at some
point in his
life he was the most remarkable person
he took me a polyester kid a Salesman
brought me in turned me into a hippie BW
a
beard and we would go to marijuana
Ms for the C marijuana in 74 in 72 let
me tell you about
California in June when it
qualified the ballot for the ballot the
initiative had
9% of the
vote about 81% against it and
10%
undecided as July and August and
September and October came the numbers
went up
small 10% 12%
15 and Halloween just before the
election in November
1972 with the ever popular Richard Nixon
running for the
president we had 19% of the vote
everybody thought we would get
slaughtered everybody had discounted the
marijuana movement the be for the
hippies that have collected the
signatures a no money movement nothing
behind
it they got 34% of the vote and that
blew politicians away in state after
State Oregon Alaska California
decriminalized marijuana because of that
vote and they only started with 9% you
remember when they qualified in June it
was put out a ballot by hippies that
knew when you went out to petition as a
volunteer there's no nothing wrong with
making money petitioning but if you
volunteer that you're going to go
collect signatures go collect the
signatures your word should be as good
as your money if you can't collect them
put up some money to the organization
that is collecting them and let them use
your money about 50 cents 60 cents buys
a
signature you put up $10 you bought 20
signatures you bought some stand in
front of a
supermarket and collecting your
signatures for you it's a decent way you
put up the money somebody else
collection the
signatures we've got the greatest story
in the world to tell besides P getting
you
well besides it being one of the
greatest medicines and the safest
medicine on Earth there is nothing safer
you can put in your body than marijuana
you will live longer if you smoke pot
every day of your life than people that
do know drugs at
all you live 8 to 24 years longer than
people that use alcohol and
tobacco you'll enjoy music more you'll
stress out less less you'll come home
from
work smoke the B and equal that
executive two week vacation the port of
Artic where he's always [ __ ] fighting
with everybody and they charged too much
for this and they did
that
water you guys me some
water what you
got I'm
position well if you were one of the
thank you
D if you were one of the volunteer
petitioners back in
72 you know who Captain Ed was
he yeah I know Captain I know you
do we had we came back in 74 Ed store
collected another about 25 ,000
signatures but they failed to make the
ballot by 40,000 which they later
admitted they Mis counted but wouldn't
put us on the B 10 years later the
government of Oregon did the same to the
Oregon marijuana this year in
1984 they said we missed the ballot by
300 I had come up here with a bunch of
Californians and helped collect the
signatures to put Oregon on the ballot
they said we missed by 300,000 300
signatures I of about 75 80,000
collected about 2 weeks from the
initiative time they said hey you know
what we miss counted you get you got
enough SE to get on the battle too late
to PR PR put you on some tough [ __ ] you
guys are
off that's pretty short
trip we often didn't have lawyers to
fight for
us let me tell you in 1973 and 7 before
as those
people came up to
me and told
me that we could win the
battle that we could get the signatures
and I thought we could do it voluntarily
I've tried probably 15 times in various
States mostly California and missed the
ballot until with Dennis Peron last year
or three years ago we collected the
signatures we got on the balance we won
a very liberal very very liberal medical
marijuana in California if you got
headaches you got stress you got
backaches you got attitude you can get a
note the hardest part about getting a
note in California is the federal
government has threatened doctors with
the loss of their license they haven't
taken one away but they scared the hell
of the doctors
many few doctors will give you notes if
I had 20 speakers I'd make people listen
to
so when you think of all this work that
people been doing the reason you can sit
here and smoke a
bowl if you have to
today is because it's decriminalized in
Oregon it's decriminalized because about
a half a dozen or dozen people here
including Bill
Ki
masas voter power these people that you
just barely
know went out and collected
signatures when the Oregon legislature
Rec criminalized and govern kenh or B or
whatever his name is signed it we were
at the rainbow gathering we went out and
collected signatures we left the rainbow
gathering stoned out of our mind on July
5th you know what we were doing on July
3rdd when they signed it in July 4th
when we decided to come to stay in
Oregon not go back to California and
collect the signatures put it on the B
stop the law from going into effect you
only have 90 days to stop a law from
going into effect it's called a
referendum seldom seldom used but we
went in 90 days we collected the
signatures
stop the law of Oregon from RE
criminalizing marijuana down to a
seed where they can take your education
your car your kids go right home with
you they find a joint in your car now
they must write you a ticket if they
find a joint in your car under that new
law they could take you home and search
your
house so we went and we decided we have
no time to talk it over we only have 90
days from one a law passes on a
referendum to stop it only a few States
have referendums is one of
them they said we lose even the PTI of
for us said we were lose then we put out
a medical initiative that might
pass might pass but Rec criminalization
was here it was a fact that it came up
to a vote 8 months nine months ago in
November
98 a lot of people thought we were going
to lose early on in that thing we wound
up winning by
66% and I was happy to say [ __ ] the
orium they put you in jail take away
your rights it's a sloppy newspaper for
a
State marijuana in case you ever had to
defended hemp don't forget is the
greatest single plant on our
Earth think of about 3 and2 million
plants in one plant is greater than all
the other plants that grow on Earth
combined that's just one at a time like
a king kong
over a retinue of of other plants or or
beings or animals but like a King Kong's
King Kong one plant to make all the
paper all the fiber all the fuel nobody
wants it to but isn't it nice we have
something to stop fossil fuels to stop
poison
Plastics we have another way of living
on Earth but it takes you to register to
vote it takes you to register to vote
and to vote and if you move re-register
and get everybody around you to register
and re-register and re-register and vote
on issues there might be things you
might not want to vote
for or
against but you'll find the lesser of
evils and at least a choice and one day
you'll have things on the ballot like
initiatives that you're interested in
and you can actually do something you
can vote and cancel out some goopo type
brain who wants to vote in a synthetic
future for
[Applause]
mankind
so you live longer if you smoke pop than
if you do no drugs at all give me some
you live 8 to 24 years
longer need to 24 years longer as I told
you before with people that use alcohol
and tobacco I often tell this driving
story you're driving down the freeway
and you're
straight and you go to mue
exit you go
well let me get over there and you cross
three lanes you get over you see it
every
day if you're drunk you go to Mr free
AC get
over you blindly cross another couple
Lanes but if you're ston out of your
G and you go to pass your freeway
action what I usually see
is
who
you get off the next section to stop at
the Burger
[Music]
King you drive safer on your marijuana
everybody knows it 99% of all the
Studies have shown it over and over and
over again and they've never been able
to replicate their negative
study we're right you live longer you
can make all the paper fiber fuel food
richest for protein on Earth healthier
than any other single food on Earth if
we don't stand up and fight to shut
those guys up they can't shut us up in
corner they can't shut us up in schools
they can't shut us up at all if you
stand and tell your parents tell your
brothers and sisters and uncles and
aunts friends and acquaintances and the
guy sitting next to you on the
bus I have never stopped or gotten tired
of telling the story of how to win your
freedom you register and vote and you
vote and you vote you learn about this
subject I learned about this subject I
wrote a book about it I know some of you
read the emperor wears no
[Music]
[Applause]
clothes 600,000 copies 11 New Edition
every time I write it we write it new so
that it has everything that was in it
before plus everything that was updated
to
now the information
is is irrefutable marijuana is the queen
and king of the
earth it's the healthiest and best thing
for you but it leads you to fight for it
it can't get up and fight for it's
giving it it's
knowledge it's given us it's
incredible
advantages the finest paper from
corrugated
box the finest
fuel the best
oil the number one protein Source on
Earth and and the highest loline leg the
essential fatty acids the body must have
of all the fruits on Earth and it can
clean your blood better than anything
else on Earth this is a plant that is
illegal and the only people that needs
is us and all of the US that we know to
be taught this information over and over
again and in a refutable way so
guys I ask you to join me and
registering the vote there's a couple of
initiatives floating around
California excuse me in Oregon right now
to get on the ballot for marijuana they
are not my preferred words but I signed
them if
I they belong on the ballot if we have
nothing else to put on the ballot
because it gets the information out we
can teach this information
comprehensively and there are 80,000 of
us in prison in America in jail in
America a million and a half on parole
and a for
marijuana we want to get them all out of
prison all out of jail we want to Wi the
records clean until that happens we
haven't won this war nobody can rest on
their Laur if you have a soul we care
you're going to do or give something
every day bit as it might be big as it
might be to the marijuana movement I
have my friends have and because of it I
think a lot of us are a little bit Freer
here in Oregon in California than we
would have
[Applause]
been
so for Captain Ed wherever he
is for me Jack
her I want to thank bill
coni for having this event against the
police
[Applause]
powers
all of you should
think that a lot of people were scared
to stay or come
here because you're
here bill is going to have a tough
year he got lots of friends you're going
to have lots of friends you need lots of
money so I don't know what the solution
is is support Bill he ask for support go
out of your way because he has supported
this movement in this state so well for
15 16 years but I know him you just
can't do better than bill coni for
helping Save the
[Applause]
Planet I have a booth over there next to
bills it's about three over from the
elephant above the elephant here I'd
love to see you there talk with
you remember to go register and
vote and then remember to teach all your
friends that are 18 or older register to
vote right now and ask them the question
till they get tired of you order are you
out of the
[Music]
house I love you take care
[Applause]
guys
WK
you