okay i'm dan to the cannabis liberation
society we've been in existence about
four years
we're working on legalization
we don't talk about it i mean sure we
talk about it but i mean now we're doing
more we're actually working on it we're
actually there's two petitions in the
state of oregon for the re-legalization
of the state i mean for the
re-legalization of cannabis
but we need help big time there's some
things cooking uh you need to talk to
some people in the booze and find out
what's going on but the main thing is we
need help i went to the county fair this
year we worked the last three years
we've been at the county fair we've been
fighting off the the officials are
trying to run us off we've been insulted
but here's a pin this is a pin that i
picked up somebody gave to me at the
county fair this is being handed out
it's got a marijuana leaf with the
symbol on you know the slice across it
it says say no to drugs
report marijuana there's one 800 number
here and it says oregon state sheriff's
association
so
i had a great idea i only have one but i
need to find out where to get these
because i thought did you really make
great pins for sending our petitions
uh
and then i thought you know we could get
enough of them legally even maybe like
auction them off or you know sell them
for a fundraiser to help fight them you
know use the weapon against them and
then i got to thinking remember they say
there's nothing more minor than the
the sword i don't know i see i blew that
didn't i the pen is minor in the sword
okay
if that's true
then we have a we have two of the best
weapons and when you're in a war is the
the better weapon you have the better
advantage you have we have two of the
strongest ones first of all we have the
pin
and like i said we could use their pin
against them and then the other thing is
we have truth now that's a a radical
concept of the truth and i've always
thought that the truth could uh they
don't need to be close they can stand
naked so the thing is well let's get
behind legalization i talk to my fellow
activists and they tell me oh well uh we
just don't have time we gotta implement
the medical
okay let's implement the medical that's
fantastic and that's been it's great
we've made great strides
but we've got five states that pass the
medical let's go for
let's go for legalization you get no
amnesty without legalization that's the
bottom line it seems to me it's a
no-brainer legalization is what we
should be working on
and i don't mean talking about it like
i'm doing i mean
working on it like i and a lot of other
hard-working people are there's no money
in legalization so you won't find much
money in it but we're scratching we're
back there this is registered to vote in
front of our booth we've got a sparkly
windstock and we need help
we need help not only money-wise we need
help and personnel wise we need help and
equipment uh anything you can donate do
you think to get help we need computers
we need uh people that have might have
computer permit they can loan out let's
get more people online communication is
the key if we can get online more people
online
uh i think that you know that's another
idea of that but anyway
i better get more people some more time
here thanks for coming
feel free to talk to us anytime you want
and let's
vote for freedom
register and vote
thank you