well one of the things we were
discussing just a little while ago was
Henry Ford's hemp car right grown right
he made an external body uh with hemp
fiber and oil and some other seed oils
you I've got videos on our website and
have for 10 years where they swing a
sledgehammer at it it bounces off and it
doesn't scratch the the body of the car
it's kind of a uh Prelude to fiberglass
but perhaps a better alternative mhm
like hemp glass yeah exactly
so Ford was a was a total Pioneer and we
cover pieces of his life in the film one
of the things that Ford did around that
same time that he built groan is he
actually created an ethanol facility in
the US wow and he was turning hemp and
other products into ethanol uhhuh now
there was a guy at that time named
Rockefeller right Standard Oil Standard
Oil good friend of Andrew melon exactly
Secretary of the Treasury for several
administrations right so and this is all
during the time of you know Hurst and
this whole this whole sort of global
power play was starting to be created
well Ford had a completely different
idea not only did he grow his car but he
wanted to grow Fuel and his ethanol
facility got about 25% of the fuel
Market in the Midwest and you know
Rockefeller said we've got to do
something about this guy so Rockefeller
started funding something that became
known as the women's Christian
Temperance Union ah I've heard of them
yeah yeah this was what Circa
1930 or 25 well right before prohibition
so 1915 or something like that exactly
and and as you recall you know soon
after that the women's Christian
Temperance Union got together and they
created this push for people to stop
drinking alcohol right which then turned
into exactly which most people don't
know that the amendment to the
Constitution that was called prohibition
was actually funded by Rockefeller
not having to do anything with drinking
alcohol but to make sure that Ford would
stop producing alcohol ah you know that
kind of ties some strings together there
that have flung Loosely in the wind in
terms of uh eventually leading to to
marijuana prohibition you know and and
the whole biodiesel issue is something
that we've talked about on this show at
length