[Music]
and
[Applause]
[Music]
War's
over when's everybody going to learn
over telling you're about to
burn War's
over unless you caught up in a line that
same old Line's
over so let's all party and get
high thousands of thousands
[Music]
just did not sink in their
head so many give so many more
take this turn off just a have
to's
over when's everybody going
to the drug war is
over until found
War's
over unless you caught up in a line same
old's
over so for Christ sake Let's get high
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
oh what about it a't you heard the story
yet you're going to help change it to
add to the
[Music]
de I'm getting way deep concerned and
Ain't No Lie
we all come together soon and we all B
to
[Music]
die War's
over don't you be
ating War's
over cuz there ain't nowhere to
run War's
over unless you caught up in that
light War's over so yeah roll one up and
get high
[Music]
[Applause]