put your hands together welcome to Stage
my good friend Mr herb
Thrasher
yeah Portland H St what's going on out
there appreciate Ango dude he he does so
much for this community he's up from
Sacramento he's at all these him
festivals you guys have seen him for so
many years and he comes up and gives us
his time and I appreciate him and I also
want to take a second to appreciate all
the hempstock core staff here running
this show come on guys we all go through
so much this event right here has been
going on for about 10
years and it gets run because people
volunteer people join together people
are Community we are a cannabis
community and we make events like this
we make Seattle Hempfest we make Olympia
Hempfest and all our Hempfest events
like this great and you guys are awesome
and I just hope you guys when you guys
see the core staff riding around on
these golf carts picking up trash thank
them dude I'm telling you they're
volunteers all right are you guys here
for HST what's
up that's right that's the spirit we're
talking about that's what we're looking
for right now so Hempfest man how many
guys out there support hemp anyone have
any hemp on right now wearing hemp yeah
we got a lot of vendors out here selling
hemp so guys make sure sure you guys go
by there the vendors that are selling
him give them an extra thumbs up man cuz
we really need to start supporting him
this is a huge industry that we can
drive to the forces of the mainstream
movement that's right socks belts
wallets come on dude you guys know we
don't smoke hemp shoes it doesn't matter
underwear it's all good man hemp so we
guys definitely keep supporting him
learn about hemp find the companies that
are selling hemp and support them I mean
if companies like if you walk into a
store and you see a product right next
to a hemp product and if the hemp
product is $2 more $3 more than the
other product don't buy the other
product because of that come on guys
let's spend a couple more bucks it's
hard to get him here it's hard to
produce hemp it's hard to manufacture
hemp you know hemp's illegal too I know
you know dude I know you know and so uh
let's just keep supporting hemp let's
keep doing what we do keep supporting
these hemp Industries you guys know I
started a company over here herbage
designs.com and one of the reasons I
started this company is because I wanted
to sell him but I also wanted to start a
company that didn't sell B bongs
pipes dab pieces you know I love all
those pieces I'm a huge bong smoker I
love bongs I love dabs but man we need
industry we need business we need
creative people out there which the
Canabis Community the music industry all
these guys are creative people we need
creative movements within this industry
doing industry mainstream products let's
get I I would love to expand my company
by buying your products so we can get
into mainstream stores and take this
industry to the community I love you
little girl Brave
all you guys definitely need to look up
the brave Michaela story she's a sweet
little heart right here she has been
driving so much for the just this
industry teaching people teaching people
what it's all about so you guys
definitely keep supporting Brave
Michaela look at her story let's see
what's up how about moms out there do we
got any
moms yeah hello moms you guys support
your kids and I hope your kids out there
you guys need to educate your moms
that's who we need to start educating
moms I mean if if the dad is like if Mom
is happy when when the when the
household's happy if the mom's happy
everyone's happy that's right and so
moms if we can keep educate mom support
you
guys so keep supporting educate your
moms that's who's going to drive this
Force if you guys look back at
prohibition alcohol prohibition moms and
women are who changed it look up the
normal Women's Alliance that's a growing
growing chapter right there a lot of
people are joining normal Women's
Alliance a lot of women are now
definitely joining this movement which
we've needed for a long long time and
thank you sweetheart so much man we are
freaking so thankful for everything you
guys are doing and it's awesome and so I
also want to talk about 420
radio.org that's right some of you guys
know me as herb Thrasher I support I
have a live radio show on Friday nights
420 radio.org we're a 24-hour Network so
you guys come over there stop by check
out information we have the Russ Beville
show you guys know Russ does anyone know
Russ Belleville out
there I know everyone out there is
probably cussed him at one time but
you've also hugged him 10 other times
cuz he's huge for this movement he's got
a great show Monday through Fridays and
then we've got disco show we've got a
reggae show and I so happen to be
metal I like rock dude does anybody like
rock that's right man this movement
isn't all about Bob Marley I Love Bob
Marley yeah we be jamming but we also be
J that's right dude Grateful Dead I love
the dead but also love 6 feet under I
love the Sarah who we're about to hear
and all kinds of great metal bands and
so all you metal head out there all you
rockers it's time for you guys to start
stepping up into this movement too for
so long it's been others man and it's
time for the metal movement to start so
you guys support herb Thrasher flower
hour on Friday nights 8:00 420
radio.org appreciate all you guys and
everything you guys do