I'd like to
[Music]
rest
on stars. I'd like to lay my weary bones
tonight on a
bed. California stars. I'd love to feel
your hand touching mine. Don't tell me
why. I must keep working on. Yes, I give
my life to lay my head tonight on a
bed of California stars. I'd love to
dream all the way on my
bed of California stars. Jump up from my
star bed. Make another day underneath.
California stars they hang like grapes
on vines that shine and warm a lover's
glass like friendly wine.
and give this world a dream a dream with
you on our
bed of California stars.
I have to rest a heavy head tonight on a
bed of California stars. I'd like to lay
my weary bones tonight on my
bed of California stars. I'd love to
feel your hand touching mine. Tell me
why I must keep working on my life to
lay my head tonight on the bed.
California stars I'd love to
dream all the way out of
it. California stars jump up from the
star and make another day
underneath. California stars they hang
like grapes on plants that shine and
warm a lover's glass like friendly wine.
Guess I give this world to dream a dream
with you on our
bed. California stars.
[Applause]
[Music]
Yeah.