we're going to do a couple more songs um
but I want to say this before that I
want you to check out if you can
remember this all right Hempstead
projectth heart.com but you can't Google
it yet you got to go to that little
address thing up there right but
Hempstead proart
dcom because we want to we're anyway
some of us work of this attitude that
it's time to seriously consider hemp as
Alternative Energy with its own identity
that we know where we're at with the pot
and the medical marijuana but hemp is
Earth medicine it's medicine for the
Earth and we want to see we want the THC
people all right to start saying and
making it known in a coherent
non-argumentative way that it's time to
consider hemp as Alternative Energy all
right so this and it's not not an
organization just go out there and make
it heard the same way the medical
marijuana people made themselves be
listened to
the same way the gays and the lesbians
made themselves be listened to we want
the hemp people to make themselves be
listened to all right so if you would
check that site out all
right and if you agree with what we're
about then then act on it all right and
if you don't then that's what it
is