we've been on the front line for
struggling for freedom of the pan and of
the consumers of cannabis since maybe
like 17 years now and it would it was
nothing there we kind of built
everything from zero with no money this
is actually what we did and I won't just
give a brief little update about what's
really going on in South America you
know and this can ever think this big
contradictions worldwide you know about
that there's also contradictions even
here where you guys are ending
prohibition right big contradiction
contradiction that we can't even smoke
in the pot even if it's legal huh let's
see so that's one so um let's go for
South America like Chile this year the
authorized destroying for medical
patients for 500 plants that this was
made by a foundation called aya and the
government of one of the counties of
santiago chile and after that they are
continuing to discuss the commission's
in Congress the change of the law a lot
number twenty dollars and that's the
name of the law and they're changing it
for authorizing six plants per residents
and about half kilo of dry pots in each
property that's what they're discussing
now but it's not done yet there's
they're they're trying to finish it but
it's not done this isn't cheating they
have a great community I would break
cannabis community in cheated they make
like every year they make the expo weed
which is a three-day event and the last
one they had around 70,000 70,000
personas attendee for the three-day
event they also have the global
marijuana march
which is we have here on my right mr.
dana p 0 which is they responsible for
that if you want passport and past five
years and making the march so
successfully so this marching sun devil
gather around more than that about
300,000 personas this year in May and in
Argentina the same March gather around
200,000 so huge huge massive event
people that they absolutely feel better
by consuming this herb but there's
there's not much culture about it I mean
people want freedom but they don't know
the history they don't know all the uses
of hemp so we're in the in the process
of educating all these massive amounts
of people that are waiting for the
hell's freedom but we're lack of culture
yet we have to go through a big process
of Education and that's what we're doing
alright well let me go get to uh yeah
Gaston just just I wanted to finish with
this that here and you know we've been
we've been here in America for a few
weeks now and we've been observing
what's going on and I want to salute how
to say congratulate all the hard-working
activists that have made this ending a
provisional reality but I the messages
that were not done yet we have to keep
on continuing with the rest of America
to liberate the rest of America of three
thoughts concerning the pant because
what you guys do here is very important
for the rest of the world maybe you're
not really cautious about that but
whatever happens here has a big impact
worldwide so I was here last year one
you guys were with
91 and you succeeded so I want to
congratulate all the hard-working
activists and tell them that they will
thank you for the hard work but we're
not done yet we have to continue and
spreading the word thank you thank you
so much so we don't have actually
there's no help in South America only
other white a project of just a research
project we used to have a head but we
don't have it anymore and what I want to
say about about this new era that's
coming that I've seen here also the
United States you know part of the
contradictions is we should take the
human barriers that make these limits of
THC in hip we should just move them away
that's part of that task that is already
we have to keep on doing that because
that those those were part of a
different a different time a time of
prohibition now it's a different time
and we should go forward and taking
those artificial barriers and leave the
plant grow as it is naturally and take
all the benefits of it tell us what you
know um I represent I've been
representing the growers a lot because
we have a homegrown movement but you
know what i want to say is that that's
not really important because that's not
safe access for all of us we got to go
forward in trying to find a different
way of getting access besides the whole
goal
I think you guys are a big example for
the rest of the world I think many of us
are going to be inspired by Oregon and
by United States in general but Oregon i
think that article law is really good
and you guys have been following the
information right all the the money has
been that's right