I tell a little story I've told it a lot
and uh I'll tell you guys it real quick
and perhaps you'll understand then why I
do what I
do many years ago I went to this little
[ __ ] hole in Southeast Asia called
Vietnam and it uh screwed up my head
real bad so for about 15 years I didn't
really give a [ __ ] about my wife or my
kids or my or anything else and then one
day I had a
realization that if I didn't change my
life I was going to die and so about 17
or 18 years ago now I got sober but I
would devote the rest of my life to
promoting the sacred plant at every
level both as a medicinal and as a
industrial product and that I would
dedicate myself to helping those less
fortunate my wife and I started a
Ministry and 2000 in 2002 we were rid
where they got 658 kilos I believe
nobody was arrested we figured we were
safe the next year we planted over a
th000
plants which we harvested safely and the
following year they came in and raided
us and then the following spring they
came and raided us again the reason I
tell you this background is
because I've based my entire defense I'm
facing four life sentences
$17 million in fines an additional 40
years and the part that really makes my
balls ache a $600 spatial
assessment they get to 17 [ __ ]
million they can wait on his
anyway uh we have based our entire
defense on the religious freedoms
restoration act which allows for the use
of marijuana as a holy
sacrament and for 2 years I've been
trying to get this in front of a judge
and the federal government the judge
even my own attorneys have all conspired
against me at every level to keep this
argument from going in front of a a
court there was a recent decision by the
Supreme Court called the udv decision
which is incredibly critical because it
has to do with the church drinking what
they call wausa tea which comparing
marijuana to that tea is like comparing
ice water to battery
acid the Supreme Court said in the 90
vote leave them boys alone now if they
can let people French Kiss rattlesnakes
drink cyanide drink a tea that they
Import in 50 gallon drums from Brazil
then I am having a lot of trouble
wondering why they are so hesitant to
put a marijuana case in front of the
judge they they tell me it's because I
would be what they refer to as a Gateway
case which means that if I won and you
guys all joins my church we'd all be
sitting here smoking pot right now
instead about wondering about looking
over your shoulder you'd be able to do
whatever you wanted they couldn't stop
it and that's why my case is on hold now
it looks like they're going to probably
dismiss all of my charges but they're
going to do it under bad warrants so
they don't ever have to address the
religious
issue for those of you that are
disappointed this is where the story
gets
interesting my wife who was as bald as a
baby [ __ ] bird and weighs less than
100 lb I think we're going to be there
in like a month or four months ago told
me that she had to do something before
she died to make things right oh yeah so
she went down and she started her own
Ministry because I couldn't do it
through the one that we had started
together because of the legal problems I
already
had she turned around at that time
ensued the Attorney General of the
United States the Attorney General of
the State of California the governor of
the state of California all of the de
agents and the National Guard the
highway patrol and Sheriff agents
involved in her [ __ ]
raids right now she has I'm not sure but
somewhere in the neighborhood at 35,000
plants planted back in our garden and so
far they have come in and done
nothing I cannot tell you what an honor
it is to have Jack career for a best
friend but that peels by comparison the
honor I have of having lenda for a
wife she personally is taking this to
them in such a way they will have to
address the religious consequences of
this and once it's settled it will be
legal across the
board I Know Jack sometimes has a little
trouble getting the message out because
of his stroke but in a nutshell what he
said was hemp will save the world if you
will study the history of hemp and
marijuana you will find that it is the
Mainstay product that has sustained this
world for over 25,000 years that we can
prove in black and white I said this
last month in Seattle at the Hempfest
and I say it to you now I promise you if
we will all stand up just one [ __ ]
time together we will never have to
stand up
[Applause]
again
70% 70% of the
Republicans in a national survey in
admitted that they smoked pot and had no
problem with marijuana as a
medicine that's 70% of the people that
[ __ ] hate us you
guys can't we get the rest of us on
board with that you know let's stand up
let the people that we elect know that
they are our servants and that means
that they kneel at our feet not rip out
our throat and bite our hands we pay
them used to be Serve and Protect now
it's screw and prosecute it's right in
the Constitution have any of you ever
read that if it's a victimless crime
there can be no jail time how many of
you people sitting out there today know
somebody in jail that didn't hurt
[ __ ]
anybody huh come on put your hands up
most of the
crowd read the
Constitution the other thing Jack said
that's imperative is you have to know
your rights you have to to understand
the laws and you have to understand your
rights under the
laws and the best thing that we can do
is vote the NAACP the NRA the multitude
of national organizations that create
voting blocks control elections