[Music]
yeah Johnny harp take it to me
baby so listen close
y'all I'm smiling
crying and biting my time I keep singing
man I'm bringing the dopest still Rhymes
and though our leaders are all liars
ain't no need to be paining just pass
the jug of wine and y'all
see you know I got to thinking while
we're drinking and we're shrinking the
sound Chief and CH come on hey let's
pass that the
W owners of this country they're tearing
it all down to the ground now they ain't
making a single sound but thinky silence
me cuz who knows someday I just might be
famous but more likely end up looking
like a damn
ignoramus blow the glass and will grow
the grass the good Lord done gave us
it's all that can save us now all I can
save
[Music]
us we position for a mission that we
must
undertake to gain favor now don't waver
cuz there's so much it stay
and though our leaders slowly bleed us
man how much are we going to take y'all
for Joseph and Mary's sake when are we
gone away cuz who knows someday we all
might be famous find 10,000 like minded
caises to claim us blow the glass and
we'll grow the grass that the good Lord
done gave us it's all I can save us
now all I said who knows someday we all
might be famous fly right by the moon
and go Circle you're in us and blow the
glass and grow the grass the good Lord
done gave us it's all I can sa
[Music]
us now I'm going to back it down just
the notch
[Music]
now listen close see you ever been to a
drunken brawl you know the kind where
the cops get called there's always
someone getting hauled away to jail yeah
huh you ever see a stoner picking a
fight to maybe crack a couple skulls on
a Saturday night yeah me neither I doubt
you ever will they been lying to you
sudden now please dig my little truth
y'all somebody tell me what's the fuss
of
about was just the band here is w't burn
one down and then we'll eat and then we
[ __ ] all asleep May dve the truck 10 mil
beneath the speed limit I don't get it
tell me what's the about oh
[Music]
yeah I got to know
you know I really hoped when I wrote the
song that the message should be real
strong so some folks they might one day
understand now
yeah that alcohol has killed so many
more than green but ever will look who
keep on score you know a matter of fact
you can't do de on we they been lying to
you dig my little truth somebody tell me
that what's the
first with just a band of I want to burn
one down and then we'll eat and then
we'll [ __ ] sleep dve 10es the speed
limit I don't get it
tell and somebody tell me that what's
the first about you know we're just band
for Spokan let got to burn some down and
then we'll eat then we'll [ __ ] we'll
probably fall asleep maybe TR the CH 10
the speed limit I tell
me what
[Music]
the Yeah
said who knows someday just might be
famous right by the moon go Circle your
in us and blow the glass and we grow the
grass the good Lord done give us it's
all that can s us
[Music]
oh I'm Tommy G from the 509 these are
the legends after 11 we thank you
hemstock thank you so much for having us
and we're looking forward to coming out
and party with you guys stick stick
around we're going to all right