all of the groups and and the thing to
do if you want to get involved is to get
involved cuz uh you know those of us who
uh who stand up those of us who who are
willing to talk truth to power those of
us who go to legislature and say I'm not
a medical marijuana patient but
sometimes I use cannabis to enhance
various uh various experiences sensory
experiences those of us who are willing
to do that can't do that alone and if
there's one thing that's true about our
movement today today it's that there's
too many chiefs and and not enough and
not enough Grassroots so please doesn't
matter which group you get involved with
as far as I'm concerned there's a row of
uh nonprofits over here behind the stage
stop by check it out get involved