hempstock thank you so much for being at
this wonderful sacred event it's always
a demonstration of two things it's a
demonstration against the
laws and it's a demonstration that we
can come together peacefully over and
over and over with no problem because
the only problem with the whole cannabis
thing is the laws cannabis prohibition
as we know is fixing a problem that
doesn't
exist and uh we had Hemp Fest this year
was our th
anniversary it was a hard
year initially we uh had a five-month
battle with the city over the permit
they didn't want to give us a permit to
have the event because they building a a
bridge a sky bridge over the road and
into the to the park and it's a real big
event with 150 100 250 I think thousand
people we had this year 280,000
something like that it's a big footprint
event and there's not a lot of places in
Seattle to have Seattle Hempfest and so
we had a five Monon long permit battle
and we sued the city of Seattle and we
won and we won a third day you know the
city said you're too big for that Park
and we said give us a third day and they
says well why and we said because if you
give us a third day that Friday is going
to pull enough off a Saturday that that
there's going to be enough room for
everybody it's going to work real smooth
and they said well where's your science
behind that and that's just a theory and
and that's not proven and when uh we won
this year we won the third day as well
and Friday was our most attended day and
Saturday was totally smooth and we were
right and hopefully that's going to have
an impact on next year but every year is
a struggle every year got to fight for
it Freedom doesn't come easy comes with
a lot of responsibility and you know at
Hempfest one of the reasons we've gotten
20 years down the road with such a big
event is that we try to take a safety
first approach we we're not always
perfect you know we make mistakes we aim
to please our aim is not always perfect
but we try to learn from that we try to
always do a better job and and that's
gotten us down the road Road and here
Portland hemstock you know I've watched
this event grow and flower and Blossom
you know and wow this this year is just
so beautiful it's just such a beautiful
location with such an iy Ambiance and
like Hempfest it's right by the water
energy which is always good and uh the
weather couldn't be better it's really
beautiful it's kind of perfect weather
to grow a big stand of pot plants
in and uh and it's always a
blessing I think often of Jack her
friend of mine that I knew for a long
time Jack only missed one Seattle H Fest
and that's the first year that he had
his his first stroke but but you know
most people would their career would
have been over right then it would have
been done and he would have had an
incredibly illustrious career and uh and
and and all these books and his
incredible work if he'd stopped right
there but not Jack Harris not the kind
of guy was he came right back the next
year and and he came to him Fest and he
you could hardly understand a word that
he said after his first stroke but he
got up there on the stage in front of
everybody he was so Driven Man he wasn't
going to let that stop him and he was up
there and sometimes it take him 15
minutes to get his five- minute speech
in and then Jack was back the next year
and he was speaking a little bit better
and he's back the next year and he's
speaking a little bit better and pretty
soon man he was Jack was speaking pretty
good and he was taking hemp oil every
day and he was taking uh Rick simpsons's
pot oil every day I know cuz I saw him
take it and uh and everybody's got to
die but Jack Herr really bounced back
man and he was one of the most driven
people I've ever seen Jack really if you
think about it he sacrificed his life
for the can of's movement he did because
he literally went until he dropped man
and when he dropped the first time he
got up and he kept going again and the
second time he dropped he never got back
up but that guy is the true hemp Warrior
of all time and he was a great friend
and it's it's always going to you know
it's always going to be something we
think about when we're at hemstock uh of
how much we love Jack and all the people
at Seattle hempest this year on our main
stage and a couple of our other stages
we had something really cool we had
these these thin transparent prayer
flags on this really thin meshed cloth
that had pictures of all of our fallen
folks of of all the people in the
Hempfest family over 20 years who've
passed away while they were working on
the cause while they were a member of
Hempfest of the family um and we try to
really honor all those people and the
thing that always strikes us as man I
wish they could see how far we've gotten
right now they'd be so proud of all of
it of everybody's work um so I want to
thank all the volunteers with hemstock
and everybody you know there's a lot in
the Cannabis Reform movement in the LI
legalization movement for the last 25
years that I've been actively involved
in it um there's been this kind of Kum
by a camaraderie this kinship everybody
got along and everything was Rosy and
and wonderful because the nuts and bolts
dynamics of legalization were so far
down the road it was IR irrelevant at
the time you know it's like it's like
would you argue about crossing a bridge
while you still have 20 miles of woods
to get get through probably not but when
you get to that bridge you're going to
be arguing about how the best way to get
across that thing is we're at the bridge
of legalization now and man are we
arguing about it and people have
different initiatives out and different
ideas on how it should happen there's a
lot of infighting with the movement
within the movement and it's just
important for the community to remember
that we're a part of this incredibly
beautiful artistic peaceful wonderful
gentle community and all the activists
have to realize that that we represent
this huge Community that's bigger than
us and to try to keep as much unity in
our community as we possibly can while
we increase the peace uh thank you so
much uh Seattle hemp fest.org you may
see me walking around I got a book out
this year called prot testival um check
it out it's kind of cool thanks