uh industrial use you know i don't see
any harm and uh
there's a lot of good uses for it uh
you know people fight it because of the
uh
well from
the backbone of it through william
randall person's paper industry i guess
that's where it first started but
i don't mind the industrial use i mean
mix rope fine rope find clothing find
paper whatever
anything you can make out of a
hydrocarbon you can make out of a
carbohydrate there's no reason to be
burning fossil fuels when we don't have
to if you can grow him
properly
it is a material that contributes to
sustainable agriculture
because the tonnage of carbon removed
from the air in the form of carbon
dioxide
is high
relative to the amount of carbon removed
from the air by other plants
like trees this is a modified 1983
mercedes-benz turbo diesel and the only
thing that we've done differently is put
lots of wonderful stickers on the car
and put
biodiesel fuel in the tank
that's it
no modifications
also mercedes-benz right now has a model
420m series believe it or not that's got
uh hemp composite plastic dashboards and
door paneling
and um they're discovering that it
biodegrades when it when it breaks upon
impact it doesn't break sharply so it's
less likely to injure a person and we've
uh let's see we've been on the road for
six weeks now
got six thousand miles on the car that
that's totally on him
and uh we've got uh another six weeks to
go roughly before we end our tour in d.c
there's a lot of problems that have to
be solved and this can't solve a number
of bits it's fiber strength is up on the
on the order of 5000 psi
so you get a fiber strength that's
equivalent to some of the toughest
strongest woods
when you process hemp fiber
using a hydrogen peroxide process
you can control the pollution more
effectively than using chlorine
processing which is used for paper
the hemp that comes out of this process
can be made into oriented strand boards
oriented strand board is the largest
growing sector of the materials industry
for construction
oriented strand board can be made with
hemp fiber having a modulus of 6000 psi
about twice the strength of ordinary
um
uh particle boards this makes
hemp fiber
bonded with its own natural
binders
a suitable material
for underlayment
sheathing and
roofing
the substrate in houses and housing
construction
you