hip Industries Association we are the
national nonprofit here in the US we've
just had our 22nd annual conference so
that's 22 years and Association fighting
for the rights of industrial hemp in
this country and also facilitating the
rights of so many others as we it was
reiterated in the panel before saying
that the rest of the world is really
looking to what is happening with
cannabis movement legislation view
what's happening the United States
thankfully is a hip industry we have our
international partners to really help us
take this sector to the next level if we
look at something like building material
this is from Chris's booth this is a
block he made it hip technologies which
is my principal and the company that we
are members of the HIA which as I said
is a national nonprofit this is a burn
test he did on a block he made in one of
our workshops so imagine how long was
this here just one minute so one minute
burn you can imagine her house we have
it end up going up in flames if this was
to happen so just for instance of one of
the materials there I am based in
Manitoba Canada i am from joplin
missouri where i've just completed my
15th season of sampling for the hip
regulation based on THC it is something
also that we're we are looking and
fighting for the change in the arbitrary
THC level in the plant itself if thin
candidates also point three percent in
the GPU at point two percent THC
and in addition to that we have a
derivative testing requirements so that
means that all the head foods at come
from Canada into this country have also
been tested for THC word and that's at
10 parts per million where we're saying
since 1998 we have been sending healthy
head foods into this country from plants
that have been point three percent THC
and nobody has ever failed a workplace
drug test from consuming hemp foods from
plans that are point three percent so we
know we have that level of efficacy to
move forward to help shift the change in
the THC requirement unfortunately right
now well unfortunately we do have the
bills in congressional in Congress and
the Senate and the House of
Representatives to legalize industrial
hemp but that is written two-point-three
percent so if we want to make this
change at something also that we've got
to really consider what we've got to
change in our federal legislation right
now to help facilitate that in the in
Australia the root percentage is one
percent THC and that's because it falls
under something called the poisons act
and not anything to do with the outside
of really different with THC percentage
but these are regulations right now we
do have around 27 28 states somewhere
right in there it could have changed up
on Friday for all I know
24 states that have legalized the
cultivation of industrial hemp in the
United States in accordance with section
7 606 of the farm bill and this year we
had eight states cultivating industrial
hemp underneath that farmville
legislation so that's really great
bringing farmers back to the farm I
wonder if they've ever faced we have
seen a lot of youth farmers coming back
so that's really empowering coming from
working with farmers in Canada and now
seeing the shift of people in their 30s
and 40s and even younger getting excited
about staying on the family farm because
they have the hope and opportunity to
cultivate cannabis and industrial hemp
very cool