and so we believe things like this will
help stop deforestation this is a hemp
fiber board produced at Washington State
University uh by their wood science labs
and they've shown that it's the
strongest fiber board they produced it's
actually stronger than steel and so we
think that uh once we cultivate
Industrial Hemp we'll slow or reverse
the deforestation and environmental
degradation our plant planet's been
suffering and uh uh that the industrial
hemp will transform our economy and stop
the uh
uh the use of petroleum as to Wi degree
as it is used today we believe that
that's really the the key crucial
element of cannabis prohibition the
reason they we were sold the marijuana
myth back 70 years ago is to protect the
petrochemical industry and and uh uh
this will reverse that and so it'll also
allow adults to grow their own and uh
just as people can produce their own
tobacco or alcohol products