Make Some Noise if you like
weed what about if you like
marijuana I love them both it's time to
legalize cannabis you know it used to be
legal till 1937 the founding fathers
Jefferson washingon all those guys they
grew it they smoked it the Declaration
of Independence was originally written
on hemp paper cannabis right better
paper than trees better fabric than
cotton and you can smoke it and talk
about
[ __ ] life liberty and the pursuit of
happiness write that down that's why
John Hancock signature so big cuz he was
high as
hell you feel me you have to be high to
fly a kite in a
thunderstorm Ben Franklin smoked a lot
of
weed right the national bird is the bald
eagle what bird did Ben Franklin want
for the national bird the turkey he's a
stoner being the eagle flies graceful
free and Majestic above the clouds yeah
but you can eat a turkey
brother and there's John hanock [ __ ]
I'll sign for that I'm
starving marijuana makes you a better
cook anyway I'm a good cook cuz I smoke
weed I don't have any money I will
invent [ __ ] to eat right right if we got
bisqui and peanut butter we got peanut
butter rolls coming in 10 to 12
minutes I looked in the pantry one time
we had marshmallows margarine and Top
Ramen I'm making ramen
treats Ramen treats they were hella good
don't use the flavor packet that'll f it
up it's not
Savory I know you guys know what Top
Ramen is Portland hell yeah I had an
upscale crowd one time I said to Ramen
they just stared at me I had to break it
down I was like well y'all know a couple
noodles right uhhuh well I can't afford
a freaking cup
I'm just trying to get old
noodles some of you know what I'm
talking about you ever been so poor you
went through your couch
again if you had a couch I go through my
friends couches I just invite myself
over steal money off the
table
H
brilliant work Stone not hard that's
what I always say if you smoke a lot of
weed if marijuana is no longer a hobby
if it has become a lifestyle you have to
take steps you have to be proactive like
this when it's time to renew my driver's
license picture I get high as hell you
feel me I pull into the parking lot of
the DMV and I Hot Box the [ __ ] out of my
car and then I go take my picture
because I want them to think that I look
like that all the goddamn
time right so when they pull me over
what seems to be the trouble you can go
sir you understand