nice to be back in Portland doing this
particular event we go back a long ways
doing things together in this day don't
we yes we
do for many many years I live very far
from here down in Florida and you
invited me to come and speak to your
legislators and you invited me to come
and do some television shows with you
Paul and you invited me to come and get
some signatures with you John S and
there are so many others that I'm not
even going to start the list but the one
thing I've learned is that people in
Oregon are the coolest of them
all and there are beautiful cool people
all over the planet and the more you
know about cannabis the more you're
going to join them and and understand
who you really are you're the largest
minority in the United
States there are there is no segment of
our society
no religion no color no Creed no
Financial background that escapes it we
all love
cannabis and those who never smoke
cannabis well you got to feel a little
sorry for them because they're they're
not in connection with their inner being
for the simple reason that there are
receptors in their brain that have not
been open for them to understand who
they really are but the most the more
you know about this ancient tribal herb
the one that was given to you on the
third day if you go by the Bible that's
the one the Judea one we accept mostly
in the United States on the third day he
said behold I've given unto you every
seed bearing or remember everyone not
just the ones that DEA
[Music]
likes you are a part of something that
goes beyond time and marijuana has all
always been in your system even if you
never took a puff because it's been in
your system generation after generation
after generation and the fact that too
many people don't have it in their
system now I suspect contributes a great
deal to all the immune deficiencies that
are striking so many different parts of
our
bodies I think you all know that I
received I smoked 10 joints today and
Uncle Sam is my supplier you know that
right there are five of us in the entire
country who actually walking are walking
around with a prescription not a
recommendation you all keep saying your
doctors are prescribing marijuana and
all the federal government will come
very hard on them if they attempt to do
such a thing but there are five doctors
that have been approved by FDA DEA and
Ida to write prescriptions for us you
know
why because we were forced to exercise
our instincts of
self-preservation our you're not doing
the same if you're taking care of your
illness because we understood that a
man-made law could not possibly wipe
away our common sense when it came to
survival or to maintain the lovely the
beautiful gift of sight that I am BL
blessed with however limited it may be I
see stars and I see the colors you wear
and when you're close to me I see you
smiling and I know we're working
together and this Earth brought me to
you because the person I was before I
smoked it or used it is someone I don't
even
recognize I don't know I was a different
person growing with a different set of
values one that said you know you get
the house you get the nicest clothes you
look really sharp all the time and all
this kind of crazy stuff and then you
you realize one day that the thing you
need most is your health in my case my
sight and there is a crazy law that some
crazy people have created that says I
don't have the right to
self-preservation or to maintain my
sight well I argue that in court because
I knew no government had the right to
demand blindness out of me or you or the
kind of suffering this prohibition is
maintaining yeah I [ __ ] the law and I
won I [ __ ] the law and I
want we got to fight it I am not any
Freer than you are as long as you're not
free I'm not I'm glad that I was a part
of all of these different organizations
that are here in Oregon that when it
comes time to vote for something
important you put your personal
differences aside and you come to the
plate and we do work together and we do
make things happen oh well there was the
Hat we'll throw off the hand to all this
wonderful people to all of you in Oregon
we hope to help you and to support all
your efforts yes John I definitely want
to see dispensaries where patients can
enjoy and relax with each other's
company while they medicate and yes I do
want to sign your petition meline I
think a national petition is well
overdue I worked on one in the '90s and
didn't quite get it to the justice
department like I wanted well I actually
did but I didn't leave everybody's
address is there anyway I want to thank
you for letting me do this take care of
yourselves make cannabis legal in every
way you possibly can educate your
legislators to the fact that when a
man-made laws contrary to the law of
nature it has no validity anytime
anywhere under any circumstances and let
the true Spirit of love always feed your
Guiding Light thank you