Bringing up Elvie Musa, one of the only
living members of a government program.
She gets marijuana from the federal
government in the mail each year. Elvie,
welcome to Salem Hempfest, darling.
We're back. We're back. We're back.
And I'm looking forward to the day we
come back here to celebrate that laws at
last are a thing of the past when it
comes to our issue.
I wish it was as simple as just going uh
waiting for the mail. No, unfortunately
they make me go to Florida at least once
a year. Hang out there for a month or
two. It's at the height of winter. I
don't mind that too,
guys. I get to pick up my marijuana
grown in Mississippi. Cannot be mailed
to me to Oregon. Even if I have doctors
here, I have there I have to go. Anyway,
we're all working on so many issues all
around the country. Rhode Island of
course being the latest state that
already has medical marijuana and has
dispensaries and they are very happy
there. Yes, they are. We now have 15
states and when these elections are
over, no telling how many more. That's
right. Also, there are several things
going on with initiatives in my state of
Oregon. We don't have
dispensaries and it's hard to find your
medicine when the mites get your
grower's crop or when for whatever
reason you just can't be found. Uh and
then if you're traveling, think of the
convenience of stopping somewhere, you
got your card with you, you can stop and
choose a medicine that will suit you for
that particular part of your
journey. It's all very wonderful that we
get together. Now we got a good
administration and we got a holder who
we certainly have educated right here in
Seattle right all these years from the
justice department. He is uh handing out
rules and making decisions for us. It's
more important than ever that we get in
touch with our legislators and see what
we can do. Time for hair.
Um, we definitely passed it in Oregon so
that marijuana is a schedule two, not a
schedule one drug. So that's against the
uh the lie that we are propagating from
Mr. Nixon's time still onto now and
which could be wiped out with one
executive order. Your president needs to
hear from you. There are people trying
to help and Gasper on the radio has
gotten uh Ed Rosenthal to finance a
project in which some of the legal
smokers and I will go to Washington with
Marilyn Matrix which one of the
co-founders of patients out of time and
trying to explain to our legislators
that we cannot continue to uphold this
prohibition is causing too much pain,
too much heartache. There are so many
medicines right now that are being
patent using parts or some of marijuana.
Marijuana is medicine and everyone knows
that now. But the most exciting things
that are going on as Rick Sinum showed
us at the beginning of this year with
his tape run from the cure. However, now
there's a newer take that really goes
into all the leads about cancer and
cannabis and there is no way to ignore
this scientific evidence anymore. So, we
really need to present it and make it
clear to our legislators. We need our
health back. We don't need to have this
many cancers. We need to have plenty of
pure hemp seed oil like they do in
Finland. And cancer is prevented because
it leaves a coat protecting your immune
system. Manitoba here makes wonderful
non-narcotic hemp seed oil that we
should also take. I am concerned about
California under new law. I would like
to see changes. However, when it puts so
many more restrictions on the bad laws
we already have, making them worse,
there's no way I could go for that. I'm
sorry.
Pay attention to what you're doing and
keep it moving. Keep it going strong.
Remember that you are part of the
largest majority of people. That's
right. In the United States, there is no
segment in your community that doesn't
have pot smokers. Whether you only hang
out with judges, doctors, nurses, any
other professionals, or whether you
don't have a professional uh goal at
all, but you are an entrepreneur and you
do well with your life, or whether
you're doing nothing, chances are you
know people who smoke if you don't smoke
yourself.
Okay, it's time for me to leave you, but
I got to remind you that as I travel,
and I have done every state in the
United States and several countries. The
only opposition I ever find is from the
pharmaceutical industries, the insurance
industries, and most of all, the
corrupt prison system. Somebody misqued
me and said the press. I love the press.
They've always been good to me. It's the
prison. Let the true spirit of love
always be your guiding light. And I hope
next year we come to celebrate. Thank
you. Thank you, Vivian. Keep up the
music. Show your love.