[Music]
think about hemp hemp Industrial Hemp
see I think that the medical marijuana
movement will get a lot further if they
will reach out and help explain the
realities of hemp the larger issue of
hemp hemp medical marijuana hemp hemp
helps everybody hemp helps the earth
hemp is Earth medicine and I don't see
enough awareness being given to hemp as
hemp we're too busy using the medical
marijuana for our own enjoyment and to
help heal the pain and these different
things but we're ignoring hemp hemp will
help the planet practical reality if
we're going to talk about medicine all
right we're talking about medical
marijuana is medicine for the people but
hemp is medicine for the Earth and if we
if we forget the Earth then we're only
going halfway there that's right that's
just some
attitude Industrial Hemp you build your
home out of it you can make a clothes
out of and hemp and hemp the CBDs in
hemp all right are a larger medic they
serve a larger medicinal purpose for the
human body than even the THC does and
people need to kind of look at this
because we're talking about diabetes
we're talking about epilepsy we're
talking about cancer It's very effective
against breast cancer all right we're
talking about a real deal here but
nobody's paying any attention to it all
the attention is being put to the THC
aspect and I think it's time to
recognize the entire
plant for the Earth for us