big up to Jack big up to Jack man big up
to Jack man make some noise for Jack
Herrera
[Applause]
BR truly without the book hold on second
one second Papa truly without the book
The Emperor wears no clothes very few
people really know what's going on right
now this is a this is an awesome book
every ganja smoker should have this book
in their house so when someone's up in
your house telling you man this and then
G you smoking you pull out the book and
say read and then come talk to me all
right for real we can chat to me after
you read the
book because they're going to get their
minds
blown so go out and support this
book I would also advise everyone in
this creation to read the words of his
majesty the autobiographies of Hal
salasi and the collected speeches of Hal
salasi you will be astounded you'll be
amazed your whole life will change and
you will see what Rasta far is dealing
with and what R far is truly really
about yes I he's a wonderful man he's
the most wonderful man I ever seen and I
ever known yes I and I love my father
and I love my mother and there is no
disrespect to them neither my
grandfather neither my grandmother
because highly SAS is from the end of
days until no more time see and he's
from creation and living upon this
[Music]
Earth Music
Man smoking
[Music]
session
that's I'll we are
time I'm the
true come up
Port
[Music]
up culture it in a Boll it in a you put
it in a Philly in a dut
you smoke it in a pip on it in a no
matter you do you just love the gja the
West CO to
Arizona New York back to West
Virginia Canada British
colia Mexico South
America Amsterdam across the water
Scandinavia
PR will from Jamaica and watch me
brother give me a one job Papa escort
service give me a proper one drop for
real right
now from
Jamaica
gwaii
alas China India
Africa promote
gja whole world
over
when we come it es
service when
[Music]
we lovely
lovely I want hey hey Make some noise
for Pony Boy and L
marijuanos I don't know all the bands
and all the groups that played so this
is this is not like I'm forgetting
anyone this is just I'm going to Big up
for know Make some noise for the herbo
y'all for
real Make some noise for human yes I
this is a really wonderful show and if I
knew everyone's name I would name
everyone right now for real and I would
like to know everyone personally I think
that's the best situation to travel the
world and to make Breen and sis with
everyone yes sir