you know the main thing i've been
concentrating on the past few months
is measure 80 and we need everybody out
there
to register and vote for measure 80.
it's to legalize marijuana and hemp
we are going to create tens of thousands
of new living wage jobs
and thousands of new companies
and several new industries with him
and marijuana our initiative allow
adults
to grow their own without a license fee
or registration our initiative will
allow
people to grow hip horticulturally and
marijuana horticulturally
where you can breed your own strains
you'll be able to sell
seeds and starts without a license fee
or registration
if you want to sell the buds then
you don't have to get a license to grow
it process it
and sell it but it will
free it and no one will be going to jail
for marijuana anymore
you know there are dozens of people over
a hundred here in the united states
right now
serving a sentence of life without the
possibility of parole
just for growing marijuana they never
threatened another person they never
owned a gun
they never stole anything and they're in
prison
for growing a plant that's the first
agricultural crop
it's been grown by people at least
twelve thousand years
maybe 30 000 years the first cloth
the first rope the first paper
were all invented from marijuana
the whole thing about the low thc hip
let me tell you it's bs
hip higher thc hip
will make more seeds and more oil and
marijuana prohibition is not
about marijuana they created this myth
when they made it illegal everybody knew
what hip was they couldn't have
criminalized him
so they said they had a deadly new drug
called marijuana
and so uh and we know that it's the
oldest agricultural
crop and it produces more oil for fuel
and food
more protein more fiber
more medicine than any other plant on
this planet
yeah they've taken the
first crop purposely sown by humans
the one that produces more fuel fiber
food and medicine than any other
and they made it illegal and the reason
is because
economic and political control
you know it's about the petrochemical
pharmaceutical military industrial
transnational
fascist elite ruling class
we will legalize marijuana but we need
you
guys to register and vote you don't have
to vote for everything either
you know you don't have to vote for all
those judges if you don't want to
it's up to you but we need you to
register and vote for measure 80.
you know if you have not got a ballot in
the mail in the past
year you need to re-register because so
many people get thrown off the rolls for
being inactive voters
or if you've moved since you last voted
you need to re-register now we have
booths around here
for our initiative that you can register
at but you can also go online
to oregon oregonvotes.org
and register right online so you need to
if each of you
got 10 other people to register and vote
and everybody out here that's at least
18 registered and voted
we will win this election and restore
freedom in america
you know there are a lot of trends going
on right now
things are happening technology has been
growing exponentially
you know we've seen it in the internet
and we're seeing it with genomic or bio
biological tech
biotech where they're creating
new organs they've got nanotechnology
tiny microscopic machines and
artificial intelligence all of those
things are converging
in the next 30 years the possibilities
are terrifying if we don't expand
natural individual rights to include
freedom of thought
freedom of consciousness and the right
to get high
the future of freedom the dystopian
possibilities
are grim things like the terminator
and the matrix are just the tip of the
iceberg
so marijuana is a bellwether issue for
the future of freedom
it's about freedom of thought and
economic and social justice
so register and vote