[Music]
got
when is my brother to be
[Music]
free the Red Man over theit
the all
[Music]
over they took away creat
land an home to the
red them way above that their
res go them to come B to Star
[Music]
look what's going on down in
Mexico
the couldn't take no
more too many years driven in
poverty time for human rights and
dignity
lard still in prison
when they going to make that final
decision they set him up that's PL to
see time to set
[Music]
oh
a
[Music]
n
when is my brother going to be free
[Music]
[Laughter]
[Applause]
thank
you yeah man Native American rights are
the same rights you know seems like the
little people on the bottom are always
struggling to get up a lot of people up
on top making money to keep us down
doesn't
work you know they say that we control
it all we got to do is register and vote
on it no matter what you decide to vote
for you know you may not be interested
in international politics or you may not
be interested in war but hey if you
haven't voted yet it's time to get
registered in
vote you know because you know the next
couple years going to tell the whole
story can't help it man I used to be one
of the people who said don't do it but
you know after you've been in the jail
cell a couple of times you realize you
really have to stand up because there's
somebody in behind bars right now that
you know
you know and uh they're waiting for you
to decide so let's do it