Oh my god.
[Music]
At the times
when I am
weakest, I shall thank God.
Most of
all, when I'm
lonely, try
to one who
answer when I
call. I know
John shall protect me.
Oh
mighty. Though I
small, I shall praise
God
everlasting more than
any. Oh
girl, there's so many times them save me
all day. My sister gone away and
everything I take away. What I do
I'm put on my knees and free
I left my sister down and I take it
away on my knees and I woke up this
morning I couldn't even see no one was
there to look at me.
Oh, she was
gone home. So far away, just how long
and how far I can't
see. But there's one thing I
notice deep down
inside. Cha cha never leave I
[Music]
alone. At the times when I'm
weakest, I trust in the Lord is the one
thing that keeps me on.
My
brother told what I
said my
[Music]
lip
money at the times when I am weak.
I
shall most of
[Music]
all see my brother all left me and my
sister gone away and everything I got
somebody take it away. What more could I
do and what more could I say? Blow down
the
money. Put my chest in the wub. I know
they rocky and very la. I have to
ch get me inspir
Sh. No one in this world
could one in Zion. So watch
my left
sister
everything I do what I say on my
knees and
[Music]
everything I
say I feelings
I am
weak. I shall thank
John most of
all when I'm
lonely. John the
only one who answer.
Thank you. When
I know John
shall protect me.
Oh, they
mighty though as
small I shall
puree
lasting more
than over.
[Music]
Oh yeah. Yeah.
Namaste
namast give thanks and praise.
[Applause]