now this is the whole reason marijuana
is illegal Yep this is hemp seed oil
with a hemp Wick and it is an illuminant
hemp was an original illuminant before
they Ed whale order oil before they were
using petroleum hip seed oil was one of
the first uh illuminants used by
Humanity to uh light the first lamps and
this is the whole reason it's illegal
because you can pour this hemp oil right
into any diesel engine turn the key and
drive it hemp oil produces three times
more seed oil than any other plant on
the planet it also produces three times
more fiber and here's some HP twine uh
this is uh uh produced in China hemp
twine from China so the main reason
marijuana is illegal is because of hemp
oil and hemp fiber and marijuana laws
were created to stop the oil companies
from competing with hemp fiber with the
introduction of new Machinery that made
hemp Fuel and fiber much less expensive
much less expensive to process much as
the cotton genin had made cotton much
cheaper to process 100 years before this
new Machinery the decorticator had made
uh hemp fiber much cheaper so the uh
Fuel and fiber companies uh put together
a misinformation campaign we know as
reer Madness and came up with this name
marijuana based on racist lies as the
name marijuana proves I mean it's based
on anti-hispanic and uh people of color
racist propaganda that was prevalent in
the 20s and 30s and so uh uh here is the
whole reason that marijuana is illegal
it has nothing to do with drugs drugs
are a smoke screen it's really about
Fuel and fiber exactly and there's a
very we're going to do this every week
folks uh I I just love the hemp candle
idea so this is our flame of Freedom
that uh we're going to be talking about
each and every show