again
the during times of
shadow in the background of
burst the sun waits for the
moon to torch the
night torch the
night and the the broken
neon and Faded
light the lucky
motel at the corner of
nowhere and the
past where memories go to
forget to
forget laughing to
erase her name is
Lacy she makes his crazy kind are
crazy his name is
one she can hear
her she wants one but doesn't want
to Sparks of the
Stars strong
he he is like
flame as her fire
weits she is a
pulse a pulse
in the charging
light as a passion of storm lightning
carries
Thunder
she's a good
girl coming to understand that sometimes
this is what good girls do
in the breath of
s in the magic of
moon they held them together so not to
feel so alone so
alone so
alone during times and
Shadow in the background
reverse the sun waits for the moon to
torch tonight torch
tonight in the breath of
s in the magic of
moon they held them together so enough
to feel so alone so
alone so
alone
wo