we made a lot of progress since last
year's hip stock you know they didn't
want us to have it again here today but
we're here and we're going to comply
with whatever rules they make us comply
with we're not going away we're going to
continue to push the envelope until we
can grow hemp without regard to its THC
content but with regard to the most
productive seed varieties the varieties
make the most protein and oil the
varieties that make the most fiber we
shouldn't be judging scene and fiber
production by THC content I think that
high THC cannabis makes 20 times more
seeds than what i call dwarf him the low
less than three ten to one percent hemp
and that makes twice as much fiber so
until we can restore him the battle is
not over and we'll keep pushing this
envelope we should be able to have an
adult smoking area right here in the
park just like the alcohol events can
have their alcohol area here in the park
alcohol as we know is much more
dangerous than marijuana marijuana will
decrease your lifespan for most people
you have less stress lots of powerful
antioxidants you live longer how could
they say something so beneficial is bad
we have to educate them they've been
missing for him to this huge
misinformation campaign we call reefer
madness after that crazy movie the
federal government funded back in 1937
so we're here until we remove the stigma
the fall stigma surrounding marijuana
and I want to thank you all for coming
please go to our vendors show them some
love you see something you like pick it
up you know follow the rules
and we'll be back here for him stock
again next year I want to thank all you
guys for coming again and help us
restore him thanks again