I will say that in Washington of might
be surprised for you folks to know we do
not have legalized industrial hemp
cultivation Oh legalize marijuana so
we've not yet passed industrial hemp
legislation in Washington and me we do
have an argument as to whether or not it
should already legal based upon our
state definition of marijuana which
which has the qualifier of having a more
than twenty three percent THC so that's
an interesting thing we have going on in
this state on a federal level so jealous
of Oregon because yours that your
federal senators Wyden and Merkley have
priming co-sponsored the industrial hemp
farming active 2015 refiled after 2013
but that's a very small and simple act
that would remove industrial hemp from
the Controlled Substances Act all five
of your federal representatives have
co-sponsored the sister bill which is HR
5 25 in the US Congress so Oregon should
be very very proud of itself on on so
many levels of I want to mention just
that there are so many industries that
industrial hemp effects obviously we
know about the nutrition but even just
from the seed we would get into
cosmeceutical nutraceutical and
industrial oil and all of the
derivatives protein powders and even the
byproducts of this eve industry which
are holes which can be used for any
number of applications including fillers
for biocomposites but we're also talking
about apparel textiles paper that
industry alone to be able to use hemp
blends in in our paper and our recycled
fibers but now we're even moving into
course of building materials
nanotechnology supercapacitors biomass
used for bio medical purposes things
that we never saw coming 25 years ago
when i first became interested in the
industrial hemp movement so we also have
a future here of planet cleaning and
once we can legalize the both species of
cannabis will be able than i think to
move on to expand the way we deal with
agriculture and the healer
the land and the water and the biosphere
and start to marry more permaculture
techniques and move beyond this
sustainable concept and move into
regenerative concepts and industrial
hemp and permaculture techniques can
bring the planet into this healing that
will be required for us to be able to
deliver the the next seven generations
into into a healthy world so
congratulations Oregon you're doing
something right on a state and federal
level