yeah I just got my medical card renewed
just this past week and found out that
my doctor is losing his medical license
because the Oregon State Medical Board
decided that he was driving too many
prescriptions for this kinda stuff and I
imagine they might have been getting a
little pressure from the pharmaceutical
industry which is losing money to the
founder for seriously isn't it awful but
you know we're gonna win in the long run
you know but in the meantime here's
great doctor Ben he's not allowed to
practice medicine that next week because
he's fighting a battle that we're all
fighting and you know so keep up the
good work folks get up from the folks we
put on this fence and keep it in
people's mind that there's still a lot
of lot of work to do
our Portland's a great time to do it and
I'll tell you that
[Music]