give it up show your love for Paul
[Applause]
stord thank you Ango hey thanks all of
you for coming out and making this a big
success you know uh in our clinics
around the country so far we've helped
almost a 100,000 people become legal
medical marijuana patients we've done
that in nine states we're looking at
handing into other states too and you
know medical marijuana is a wonderful
thing especially for the really sick
people who desperately need it it
definitely leaves so many different
conditions and seeing the patients come
through our Clinic is is really a a
spiritually gratifying thing they're all
so grateful and they help us put this
whole festival on and help uh expand the
movement in a lot of different ways but
marijuana medical marijuana
is not the end and it's not the end of
the trail for cannabis and hip we need
you know hip produces more fiber more
protein and more oil than any other
plant on this planet and what we've got
to do is legalize that and the worst
thing about the current situation is
thousands of families are broken up
parents are thrown in jail kids are put
into foster homes all over marijuana
when you you know it it doesn't cause
the Terrible Things That alcohol can
cause when somebody's abusing alcohol I
mean a marijuana abuser would be
somebody who smokes it all the time and
goes to sleep and he's definitely not uh
harming many people except for himself
and you know we should have the freedom
to grow the plant that produces more
fiber protein and oil than any other
plant on this planet and solve a lot of
problems so we have a proposal to do
that right now we have a couple of
proposals that uh we just gathered
signatures on we're going to get a
ballot title uh for the Secretary of
State the process here in Oregon now is
you need to get a th000 signatures to
get a ballot title and the ballot title
is what actually appears on the ballot
we're going to poll two different
versions of our Oregon cannabis Tax Act
and depending on which one gets best in
the polls we're going to move forward
with a bill for 2010 to completely
legalize marijuana and in adult
marijuana prohibition allow any
individual to grow their own it would
put in the past we had filed a previous
bill that would have put marijuana in
the same stores as alcohol or liquor in
our previous polling we showed that was
a real mistake we got to keep marijuana
separate from alcohol and so we're
putting marijuana in marijuana Only
Stores now so you won't go to the same
store to get your alcohol and near
marijuana and so uh uh it would also
allow people to open like coffee shops
or marijuana bars or vapor
bars it will just really make our
economy boom and open the door for
tourism in this state and we need your
support to make it happen you know so in
the coming months you'll see a new
petition probably around Christmas time
and just we urge you to get people to
sign that petition and then we're going
to have to win the election but first
we're going to poll and see where we
stand in terms of the the two different
wordings we have anyway we appreciate
all of you folks coming out you know uh
if you can support all the vendors they
help us put this event on pick up a
little bit of trash we want to leave
this park nicer than we initially found
it and register to vote that's one of
the most important things you can do
we've got to get rid of The Stereotype
that we're just lazy Stoners and we got
to get out there and show that we can
take charge of the political process you
know back in the 60s Tim Larry said uh
turn on tune in and drop out well he
changed his tune in the latter part of
his life and I really liked what he was
saying then it was turn on uh tune in
and take over and that's what we got to
do we got to take over and the only the
best way to do that is Through The
Ballot Box in this Society currently and
so I urge you to register to vote
partake of the political
process and enjoy human and the Human
Revolution I want to thank Los Banos
thank John trell thank human and thank
each and every one of you for coming out
and remember help us restore him
tonight Paul Stanford everybody