[Music]
Feeling crazier than hell.
Got this time on my
hands and got you on my
mind and got nowhere else to
go. The fires burn hot and
cold. There's some place in between the
melt and the
freeze. This need for reaching for
you. You were all I could be.
Now I'm here wearing
alone. We were one. Now I'm a
ghost falling from my place in the
sun. This dizzy is out of
control. The world keeps
spinning. I heard a vibrating
echo. Sounded a lot like
you amongst the truths I saw.
You were the one that I
found. Now I'm needing the remembering
close of memories of you holding my
hand. Remembrances of laughter
singing. Songing the nights with
belongings. Sweetnessing the shelter of
each
other.
Reality. The
reality of safe feeling.
[Music]
With all these times of missing
you, I'm never not going to love you.
these days without you to hold my
hand. Feeling crazier than
hell. This crazy goes on and on.
And this confusion of me, crazy together
or crazy
apart. When crazy is
crazy, it's not always in our
heads.
Sometimes it's in our hearts.
[Music]
feeling crazier than
hell. Got this time on my
hands and got you on my mind.
and got nowhere
else to
[Music]
go. Hallelujah.