i am as you heard running for vice
president of the united states of
america
i am going to win this election with
your help
the
the most qualified person to be
president of the united states that i
know of is a fellow by the name of
governor gary johnson from new mexico
governor gary johnson has actually done
this while he was governor he stood up
in 1999 and said the obvious the
nation's war on drugs is not working and
it must be changed the man has courage
he has insight he has integrity and he
goes for it support governor gary
johnson for president you will not go
wrong
and if that's not enough and it should
be
but if that's not enough understand
that you can elect romney you can elect
obama
they're the same
i call them robomny they're the same
if we do elect that either of them there
won't be any medical marijuana
dispensaries in our country within a
year or two from now
none
it's out of control we need to elect
governor gary johnson it's the only
chance for survival for medical
marijuana dispensaries in our country
in addition
something hugely important
we as a candidacy have endorsed the
initiative here in oregon initiative 80
to treat marijuana like alcohol we need
to get this word out and we can do it
alone you can't do it alone but together
we can get this done measure 80 has got
to pass
that's not loud enough i said did you
hear me measure 80 has got to pass
same thing in washington we've endorsed
both of those initiatives same thing in
colorado we've endorsed that initiative
there as well we're going to put it
right to the federal government the
people of these states demand that they
be allowed to choose the way to treat
marijuana and i say let's treat it just
like my drug of choice let's treat it
just like wine that's the answer to go
for
i'm not sure you're convinced that's
what we need to go for
and for heaven's sake let's treat hemp
like cotton let's just treat hemp which
has valuable uses in industrial uses all
around the nation we are actually
squandering this opportunity we're
importing a billion dollars worth of
hemp every year from that radical
country north of us called canada and
we're cheating our own people while
we're at it let's treat him like cotton
for heaven's sake let's get this done
visit our website garyjohnson2012.com
garyjohnson2012.com you will like what
you see and if you do and when you do
take it personally pass that link on to
your email world if you take it
personally endorse this candidacy vote
away from romney and vote for somebody
that you actually can vote for
understanding that the lesser voting for
the lesser of two evils you still get
evil don't you vote for governor gary
johnson someone you can vote for tell
your friends tell your acquaintances
tell your family to do the same thing i
i'm here to tell you help is on the way
vote for 80 vote for these initiatives
in colorado and washington and for
heaven's sake you'll always be proud to
have voted for governor gary johnson and
judge jim gray go get him thank you all
let's make this thing