Bo
[Music]
when everybody got to
learn War's
[Music]
over we going to
burn War's over
[Music]
unless you caught up in that old
line War's
over so let's all party and get
[Music]
high thousands of my
de these words just did not think in
their
head so many give so many them they just
take until it's something turn off it's
just a have to
bake War's
over when everybody going
[Music]
to the drug War's
over till then we're all going to
burn those
[Music]
unless you're caught up in that old
life
over so let's all party and get high
[Music]
a
[Applause]
[Music]
about it you heard the
story you got to help change it to the
[Music]
I'm that you know it ain't no
lie we come together soon know we all
about to
[Music]
die War's
over don't you be acting
[Music]
D's
over cuz there ain't nowhere to run
War's
over unless you caught up in a
line War
over so let's come together and beehive
[Music]
oh
a
[Music]
[Applause]