I'm John Lucien law for 20 and some
marijuana law firm founded here in
Portland Oregon back in two thousand
seven we've been doing this for a long
time and we're going to have to keep
doing until it's completely legal like
they said so what I want to tell
everybody is we've made giant steps
we're getting there there's still a lot
of people out there who are suffering
we've got people who are still in prison
people who are still in jail in this
state and in other states we've got
people around who are getting arrested
still you can be 18 19 20 still get
arrested you can be growing more than
one plant and get arrested you can do so
many things that will allow you to get
arrested or otherwise have to deal with
the police and so until the day comes
when community community policing where
the police your friends again where the
police are trying to help you where the
police are trying to give you directions
rather than see what's in your pocket
until that day comes I want you to
remember something and those words are
very clear they're all my lighters throw
my cards they're on my website they're
on just about everything I own to the
point that I think I could repeat it in
my sleep and so what I ask everybody to
do help yourself out learn this phrase
this will save you I've had clients who
say themselves easily ten twenty thirty
thousand dollars by just saying these
magic words and they really are magic
words the Supreme Court of the United
States says they're magic words and they
will get the police to leave you alone
and if they don't and they do violate
your right so you've got recourse but if
you don't say these words you can be in
a lot of trouble so what I want
everybody to do is say with me am I free
to go officer
if I am being detained I do not consent
to any searches
and I want to speak with my attorney
prior to answering any questions those
are magic words good luck thank you they
aren't magic words but what's important
about this is that the police they
oftentimes can be your friends and I
don't want to disparage them because
there's a lot of good cops do a lot of
good things and take care of us and they
help us out in a lot of ways but when it
comes to marijuana when it comes to drug
use when it comes to those sorts of
things the police are not your friends
okay and so what you've got to do is
you've got to stand up and it's not easy
even if your voice shakes even if your
body shakes even if you cry even if you
have to sit down when you deal with the
police you have to assert your rights
because if you don't assert your rights
you're going to end up in a jail cell
you can end up in a cage they can take
your kids they can take your job they
can take your house they can take your
card but what they can ultimately take
them for so many people is so valuable
and something I'd fall for many years
for is your freedom I've watched my
friends die in cages that's not
hyperbole I've watched them I found out
that they're dead from a letter from the
department of justice okay I don't want
anyone here to ever suffer that I don't
want anyone here to ever watch them try
to take away their kids because you
smoked a joint and they claim that
you're an unfit parent what I want to do
is I want to live in a world where
marijuana is treated appropriately where
there's going to be some regulation
that's never going to be the case we're
never going to live in the Utopia that I
wish we could live in but if we can live
in a world where when you smoke
marijuana it won't destroy your life for
a year five years 10 years 20 30 40 or
injure life that's the world I want to
live in guys thank you