I know Agra that you've been working on
hemp fuel projects for many years and uh
could you talk about how Pharaoh hemp
here in the Midwest could uh solve our
energy problems well I don't know that
feral hemp the feral hemp genetics could
solve our energy problems but the feral
hemp is a small amount of the of the
plant growth in the area we took a feral
Hemp stock and and grew that
agriculturally well we want to grow 500
acres of hemp under a center pivot and
we're looking at what kind of
preparations do we have to undertake in
order to grow a crop of a size that can
make a difference and assuming a
hundred-fold increase you need uh five
acres a year before that of seed crop
dedicated for seed not making food out
of it and five hundredths of an acre the
year before that which is like 20 foot
by 20 foot and
the year before that two foot by tufa
which is really one plant
and so we're four years away from being
able to grow industrial hemp
on a scale it can make a difference