once again vot look they could do this
in California you know we could do it in
Oregon and we could get it going in
Washington we could take this thing all
around the
country get that majority and keep
it and stop being the silenced
majority you know there's a few people
out there in the land speaking against
all of us and you know what there's only
a few of them really but they're the
ones with the airwaves we are the
silenced majority we're not a minority
we need to get out there and support it
and make it happen because we can do it
man talk to everybody you know talk to
your local police officer talk to your
minister talk to your husband your wife
your kids your mom your dad your grandma
your
grandpa and you know because once the
truth is out who's going to keep this
thing illegal like this who's going to
stop you know I mean when's it going to
stop yeah when does it
end so meanwhile what are we here for
we're here to have a good time
[Music]
RIT yes I love you take
with with me up
so we
[Music]
can we be rocking in the
gr just
rolling time you get yourself up on this
hill one way than and let your heart
through the f i me was thinking for this
feeling so what the what the anyway hey
me
a yes I you check
wh P me
up so we can R
[Laughter]
[Music]
this just a roll
w
[Music]
all
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
he
[Music]
time to get yourself up on this H one
way
and let your heart the p i me we
this
anywayy yes Che
wh
up so I can
[Music]
this us
up with be rocking in the
the
you rolling
[Music]
oh
h
[Music]
oh yes