you know this event is about ending
marijuana prohibition we have a big vote
to do that here in just less than 6
weeks now we need to make sure everyone
here is registered to vote that means if
you haven't had a ballot back in the
mail sometime in the past year you need
to go over and register to vote we're
ready to do that you just step right
over to the booth over in the next
section register vote make sure get your
family and friends to register to vote
I'm going to tell you why you should
vote for measure 91 because it's much
better by far than the initiative that
is in effect now in Washington you know
Washington's law does not allow you to
grow any marijuana whatsoever and if you
have more than an ounce you are a
criminal and so this law will allow you
to grow marijuana in your home and
possess marijuana that you've grown in
your home that makes it far superior by
itself but in Washington they actually
have three levels of Taxation as well in
Washington they tax the grower they tax
the processor and they tax the seller
and in each stage along the way that
increases the price and so this law will
only tax marijuana once and it's a set
fee tax
$35 an ounce that by that's just a
fraction of the tax in Washington the
tax in Washington is about
$350 an ounce this is about one10 that
tax it's a lot less than the tax in
Colorado as well also you'll only have
one licensing fee if you want to grow
you want to process you want to make
extracts concentrates you want to retail
each business will have one annual fee
of only
$1,250 which is not chump change but
it's a lot less than the current
dispensary law that we have which has a
$44,000 per
location tax or an annual license fee so
I really see that marijuana will easily
be selling for less than $100 an ounce
maybe in some cases half that now the
tax on trim and con on trim and uh Shake
is only $10 an ounce so and there's a
one-time tax when it is purchased so
that's only a125 a gram so we'll be
seeing marijuana selling for $2 or $3 a
gram it will be very very easy to see
that happen so cannabis needs to be
cheap and plentiful and this is the best
bill yet to make that so
so you know I urge you again to vote Yes
on measure 91 you know there are a lot
of businesses here and Boo and there's
twice as many over on the other side the
only reason we're able to put this on is
because they come and they help share
the bill to be able to make this thing
happen so we need to support our local
cannabis businesses so I urge you to
visit these guys thank them show them
some love if you see something you like
go ahead and buy it from them but we
need to support our local cannabis
businesses and this new measure 91 will
allow a lot of mom and pop businesses to
spring up you know it will allow uh
economic boom here in the state of
Oregon and put us on The Cutting Edge of
exciting New Economic
developments you know I I know the only
reason marijuana was illegal was because
it was about money and power and greed
it's about the petem IAL pharmaceutical
military industrial transnational
corporate Elite crony capitalist ruling
class creating a myth about marijuana
that somehow it is bad but we know it's
not bad marijuana is actually good for
you you know when I was a kid my mom
thought marijuana like alcohol kills
your brain cells well now we know that
marijuana actually protects your brain
cells from trauma it will enhance your
longevity it will help you achieve
homeostasis but that's just about us
individually marijana will also help us
achieve balance for the whole planet
because we don't have to burn petroleum
for our fuel we can replace petroleum
with HP it makes more than three times
more seed oil biodel fuel than any other
plant at the same time it makes four
time times more fiber for paper building
materials rope canvas lace and linen
than any other plant at the same time it
produces more protein digestible protein
that we can eat so it will solve so many
ecological problems and instead of our
money going to the Saudi chics and the
Nigerian despots and Exxon and mobile
and shell and into their Swiss bank
accounts the money will be going to our
Farmers who'll be spending in our
communities and the wealth will be
shared around instead of seeing the
further centralization of economic
control that's been going on since they
prohibited hemp this will spread the
wealth and we'll see a decentralization
and all of us will benefit from that
when the farmers can start spending that
money in our local communities instead
of to those petrochemical megga uh uh
corporations
so we're going to have a uh the next
singer as many of you might know is
Lucas Nelson and the promise of the Reel
they are an incredible band last night
they backed up Neil
Young during his set and Willie Nelson
during his set at a protest benefit in
Nebraska outside of Omaha and that was
against the Keystone Pipeline carrying
the highly toxic Canadian tarand Oil
down over our main water resource in the
midwest the ogala aquafer where it could
poison the water of the whole
Midwest so last night Lucas Nelson and
prise of the Reel were working to stop
the petrochemical monster corporations
from polluting our Earth to tonight
they're here to support the replacement
of petroleum with industrial hemp and
that is what we want to see
folks you know everything petroleum
touches is toxified everything that uh
you know when when that Exon vales
dumped the load of petroleum in Prince
Williams Sound 25 years ago in Alaska it
poisoned that whole sound for
Generations if that had been hip seed
oil would have enriched the the the
ecology the birds instead of being
killed would have been able to eat that
and got nutrition you know so we need to
replace
petroleum and hemp can do it that's the
real goal here remember drugs are just a
smoke screen it's really about
petrochemicals and that's why they
prohibit it and that's why we have to
Legalize It
again I want to encourage you to support
all of these businesses out here and
even the ones that aren't here support
our community thanks for coming out and
showing your support tonight we have a
great show for you this band is hot it's
kind of you'll see you'll see so thanks
for coming and help us restore
him