hustling pool hustle on down
hustling Street Ragman and Ragueneau
paper bags full screen age alert
intended Charles on sidewalk playground
about to be where Junkman's hit the
shadows
Delia's young beautiful sister deal
themselves around beautiful brothers not
so beautiful anymore so much older than
the day before
hey everybody tired being poor
message in the scroll message on the
wall
Ruffini man it's got something to say no
something's wrong
we're gonna be cool our time open spaces
on shopping center wall middle class man
middle-class land clean enough to be a
boundary of a nice place to keep white
eyed child control climates these little
shops all laid out everything for sale
my cash plus price not devotion but pave
it is spend some money buy some more
Beauty man's got something to say
message in a strong message on the wall
put on blinders to all the senses who's
worth more than money they spend
rice paper building corporate corner
alright finance big businessman suit not
stained by spider blood blood or money
sophistication hot I'd stayed indicate
you vinyl office I'm under himself
spoils of war or spoils of war says
junkman owner of the junk
Media man's got something to say as he
gave us one message on the web now boss
no more bosses something's gotta change
something's gotta change