[Music]
Portland how you feel
it we're coming at you from Southern
Oregon it was a long long
[Music]
drive but I heard the Ducks one it's a
Green Day
[Music]
oh
w
[Music]
oh
how y'all feeling
[Music]
when you see your brother man don't put
me down bo bo bo for you know that
little thought will stick for around bo
bo boom hold on to me until we walk at
the steps of
Zion Bo then you'll see your brother
I'll be marching like a lion you got to
fall
the positive vibration got to
follow to the rising of the Moon yeah
got you
follow the positive vibration got to
bring It Low your PDX this is Mikey
Stevens
[Music]
w
[Applause]
[Music]
and when you see your sister don't put
her
down Bo for you know children will be
running around
Rhythm hold on to her until she walks
the steps of Zion
then you'll see your sister shining with
her light on you
got the positive vibration got to
follow y'all are inun to the STA
Jefferson how you
[Music]
feeling and now mix me up
H oh yeah calling on the L calling on
the L yeah
calling on the line calling on the
line one time