it's great to be here i've been in a lot
of places but i can't think of a better
place than right here seattle hymn fest
beautiful
all right well as vivian said
i'm a travel writer
and for me high is a place
it's a good place it's a sweet place
it's a sweet place where my speakers
sound better
suddenly i'm a good cook for
conversations
are like stray cats
it's a place sometimes i want to visit
a lot of people want to go there
but you know
our government says we can't go there
why today there's 80 000 americans doing
time in prison because they wanted to go
to that place called high
now there are
times when our government can say we
can't go there and that's that's right
but if our government says we can't go
to a place there better be a good reason
we can't go there and there's no reason
we can't go too high
i believe
that the responsible adult
recreational use of marijuana is a civil
liberty yeah
no apologies necessary it's just having
fun
it's a civil liberty
now it's a drug
and i don't want to promote it we don't
need to promote it we're trying to
change the law that says people who want
to enjoy it
can do it
we need to acknowledge that it's not
healthy
it can mess you up it can be abused it
can be addictive
it's not for children
if you drive intoxicated by anything
they should throw the book at you yeah
if we want to get it anywhere we need to
acknowledge that
our government is fighting a war against
marijuana it's a perpetual expensive
losing battle based on lies it's costing
our society billions of dollars of years
it's locking up hundreds of thousands of
people every year 800 000 americans get
arrested for marijuana and then they've
got a record what i bring to the
equation
is a european perspective i've spent a
third of my adult life in europe and in
europe
a joint's about as exciting as a can of
beer it's just no big deal
now we have a drug abuse problem in our
country and europe has a drug abuse
problem in their country we can learn
from each other and we can do a better
job minimizing the harm that drug abuse
causes our society
in europe they've learned that if you
have a drug abuse or a drug policy it
should be motivated and assessed not by
how many people do you lock up
but by how does it reduce harm to your
society yeah harm reduction and in
europe they're into pragmatic harm
reduction and what they found is that if
you take the crime out of the equation
you can treat drug abuse as a health
problem and an education challenge and
you can help your society minimize the
harm that drug abuse causes
now the united states is really into
moral into legislating morality and
europe has learned that that does not
work it's futile
my european friends tell me that a
society has to make a choice
you can tolerate alternative lifestyles
or you can build more prisons
in the united states we're building more
prisons
and in europe they've learned
that you can you can tolerate
alternative lifestyles and the result is
we've got more people in prison than any
civilized country in the world
we lock up eight times as many people
per capita as europeans do
either we are inherently more criminal
or there's something messed up with our
lives
and today we can sort that out and we
can explain that to our society in
general now what shapes american drug
policy
fear it's all about fear it's reaper
madness generations of lies and fear
we've got to take the scariness out of
it frankly this group here is kind of
scary to people who are most afraid of
drugs
you're not going to solve the problem by
being more scary in their face
you're going to solve the problem by
explaining things to them in a way that
lets them not be afraid if we want to
get anywhere in this struggle we've got
to stop being scary and being reasonable
and let people know that there's not a
whole reservoir of people wishing they
could just ruin their lives with drugs
if only it was legal a lot of people out
there
think that if marijuana was legal
everybody would smoke it but i'll tell
you in portugal they legalized the
consumption of all drugs 10 years ago
and what's happened
nothing
it doesn't go up use doesn't go up
anybody who wants to smoke pot is
already smoking pot they just take the
crime out of the equation that's a
beautiful thing
a lot of americans who are afraid of
marijuana say it's a gateway drug
well in the netherlands they've not
locked up a pot smoker for 25 years
they've got a track record they care
about drug abuse just as much as we do
and they liked their system they took
the crime out of it and what they
realized is
their hard drug taking population is not
getting bigger it's getting older
young people can experiment with
marijuana and not be buying it from
criminals on the streets i'll tell you
if there's anything gateway about
marijuana it's illegality
because when it's illegal you can only
buy it from criminals on the streets and
they've got a vested interest in getting
you enough more expensive more addictive
and more profitable drugs if you don't
want marijuana to be a gateway drug then
legalize it
now this hymn fest is a lot of fun it's
a great celebration of the cannabis
culture but if we're going to legalize
marijuana we've got to get serious and
mobilize
i mean we're all understanding this
we're all hip to the fact that there's
nothing dangerous about the mature adult
responsible use of marijuana but our
government needs to understand that and
the best way to help our government
understand that is to support advocacy
groups that are fighting your battle and
my battle in the state house and in
washington dc
they are waging dogged struggles on
small budgets and if you're not
supporting them with a few books you're
not helping out
i'm a board member of normal i've been a
board member of normal for 10 years i've
got great respect for the work that
they're doing they need your help
these advocacy groups are not charities
they are services and they're doing our
hard work
now we're at a crossroads today we're at
an exciting crosswords where we can
actually make some difference
like prohibition in the 1930s imagine
what it was like in america when they
realized hey that drew that the laws
against alcohol are causing more
problems than the alcohol itself
courageous people stood up and explained
that to scared people and they realized
it's stupid to criminalize alcohol
in the 30s when they dropped prohibition
they didn't say booze is good they said
the laws against booze are causing more
problems than the booze itself
we're there today with marijuana okay we
can do that but we've got to communicate
mayor laguardia in new york city back in
the 1930s said that if you've got a law
on the books that you don't intend to
enforce consistently across the board
the very existence of that law erodes
respect for law enforcement in general
it demoralizes your police force right
now we got along the books that there's
no serious intent to enforce across the
board
if they arrested everybody here tomorrow
in seattle this city would be one much
less interesting place to call home
wouldn't it
i'm telling you i'm a hard-working
kid-raising church-going tax-paying
american citizen and when i work all day
and i want to go home and relax with a
little bit of marijuana that's my civil
liberty
is that right
it's not about hard-on drugs or
self-control i'm just proposing that we
learn a little bit from europe about
pragmatic harm reduction take the crime
out of the equation recognize marijuana
the responsible adult
recreational use of marijuana as a civil
liberty and then we can be smart on
drugs does that make sense
i hope so hey nice to see you all have a
great time and happy travels even if
you're just staying home all right