hey guys this LK I'm backstage at
hempstock 2012 with Jim Paige welcome
bro hey thanks good to be here very nice
I know that you've been involved with
trying to help get it legal here because
I know a couple of years ago you did the
OCTA tour and now you're here for
hempstock I want to thank you uh
anything you want to tell people that
you might know well I played the
original uh Hempfest up in Seattle too
and I've played most of those throughout
the years I've known Vivian for for ages
uh he's one of the most interestingly
direct action constructive people that I
know um I'm you know I'm from the 60s
generation you know and so I I kind of
came of age in in in the era when people
were challenging all kinds of
prohibitions you know and I'm a musician
which means I've been around all sorts
of substance abuses including mostly
alcohol and we know what that does I've
seen what that does I've seen the
casualties over and over for years in
the music community and in the civilian
Community associated with music and so
on and so on and so
on and you know it's a broken record to
say over and over again that that
cannabis smoking it eating it whatever I
mean the worst I've ever seen is
somebody might go to sleep you know or
they might start seeing little little
sparkly things and talk about flying
sausage or something that's it they're
not going to get into fist fights they
don't get loud they don't steal your
stuff I mean it's just it's completely
different and once you start to get into
the wise and Wares of the pro ition and
things were changed and locked away it
just starts to be kind of boringly the
same as everything else in this country
that gets hidden away and and keep and
kept out of our grasp so if we can get
actually close to changing it I think
that's fabulous if we
can I
mean I've learned to expect the worst
but I would love to see the best you
know I personally think that people are
better than we than we're allowed to
think smarter than we're allowed to
think more generous than we're allowed
to think okay I think we can do this
I I'm always prepared for that big let
down but I think I got my fingers
crossed on this one it really looks good
it really looks good yes I I know that
uh measure 80 would here in Oregon we
have the opportunity to make it legal
for recreational use amongst adults we
were the first state to decriminalize
and look where it came so if we can pass
this and make it legal in Oregon no no
telling where it's going to go to uh I
hope I think you might have already
answered this but I always ask everybody
this one question if you could say
anything to the marijuana Community what
would you say um I would say uh walk I I
I what would I say I would say keep
going I I I would say don't make a fool
of yourself I would say don't don't you
know don't be confrontational but keep
going keep going don't let people shut
you up okay don't let people put you
down don't let people tell you how
stupid you are any of those things keep
going cuz it's a totally sensible thing
to do let me ask you question okay when
it was decriminalized so to speak here
in or in Oregon did the murder rate go
up
no that's
it actually actually uh uh violent crime
actually came down yeah so uh anything
that you think your fans would like to
know where you going to be in the future
or well I'm playing all over the place
um I got I always do a a West Coast tour
up and down uh the coast like twice a
year once in the spring and once in the
fall and so I'm I'm looking forward to
to November is the next thing and one
thing I'd like to say which people talk
about a lot and I've said this before
but it's true um you know I'm not an
advocate of any particular use of
anything but cannabis is it's it's an
unlocking agent among other things
and can I be blunt yes okay the first
time I took acid
okay way back when the funny because
that acid makes you laugh okay it make
it doesn't allow you to it makes you
laugh okay you will laugh and the thing
that is the most funny that I remember
is pomposity pomposity is the funniest
thing on the planet once you learn to
laugh at pomposity the game is almost up
you know because they can tell you what
to do and what to think and where to sit
down and and when to shut up and
everything else with their big uniforms
and their Badges and their pompousness
once you start to laugh at so all I'm
saying is that some of these things are
unlockers they unlock your creativity
they unlock your sense of humor and they
allow you to see the ludicrousness of
certain kinds of superiority okay I
don't know how to fix guitars so I bow
to the authority in that sense of the
word of a guitar repairment when mine
gets broken that's the only definition
of authority that I give any any
Credence to the other one you you're not
an authority you've just got a gun you
can put me away for 10 years that's not
Authority that's P that's Force that's
all that is so if we can get things
square and straight with our terminology
and we can learn to laugh at the right
time and we can understand that
unlocking our brains can be dangerous to
some other people now we understand why
they don't like us I think we'll be fine
we just keep going we allow people to
slowly but surely understand that we're
not endangering them the murder rate
isn't going to go up the world isn't
going to fall apart the Earth isn't
going to get hit with asteroids the
dinosaurs aren't going to come back all
of a sudden it's going to go on you know
we might even get some constructive
things done okay very nice guys again
this okay back stage at hempstock 2012
with with Jim Paige one of the most
wisest men I ever heard after just
hearing this interview I I want to thank
you for everything you've done in the
past and what you'll do in the future
and it's just an honor to interview you
sir thank you so much