hi how you doing my name is Dan Herer
and uh
if any of you have lost a loved one you
know that sometimes speaking about them
gets a little tough so bear with me
my father
inspired people
he helped Inspire the people that
started this event
s in California
helped to change laws
help to protect people's rights
fought for the wrongful persecution and
prosecution of innocent victims of the
drug war
he went from state to state around this
country
and uh
he taught everybody that he could spoke
to everybody Rich poor old young
not only did he try to teach them but he
also listened to them listened to what
their fears were and listen to what
their hopes would be
a lot of people say you know
your father left you a great legacy
with his book with his words with the
people that he inspired
but in all honesty
I think the Legacy that he left
was what I see in everybody at every one
of these events around the states that
I've been to
you are my father's True Legacy
through his words
and hopefully
how he's inspired you to show up at
these events
participate create new health Commerce
that will create changes in the future
because you are the roads to the Future
and the bridges that we must create and
cross
to educate the other side of this
movement and that is the uneducated
a year ago this weekend
my father stood on this stage
and expressed his feelings for the
future
that without hemp as our future we would
have no future
I look out across this field
and I see hope
I see hope in the people that he loved
and cared for whether he had ever met
them or not
and you
you are the future of this movement
you are the future of the ways these
laws are going to change from state to
state
and I am proud to say that I am his son
hell yeah I'm either I'm even prouder of
the legacies that he's created within
each and every one of you
God bless you all God bless Jack Herer
foreign