I am not
afraid No I am not
afid I am not
afid No I am not
afraid
for As Long As Walk this I know that
Protect me
as for as this I know that Will prot me
as
Earth
The
to Money
Will
shall Evil tries to take down Nothing
can prent from do work All
The The
for this I know that Protect me As Long
As Walk upon this Earth
for As Long As this I know that Will
Protect me
as this
Earth
People
This Is Us Now The Evil is leaving The
taking their Gold Thousand Years of
Peace be left alone so Forward with J to
the
ofous i Right here for Living posi and
No Fear for As Long As this I know that
Will Protect me As Long As Walk upon
this Earth
yeah for As Long As this I know that
Will Protect me As
Long
k
Walking down the streets the babon
system I look around every do I see Fear
in the Eyes Fall The Good People but
there is no Reason to Fear me I I live
only for Love Here to prot to un as All
vibration behind
Protect me As long Walk this Earth sing
it with US If you believe It For As long
as I walk upon this land I know that
Will Protect me as as I walk upon
Earth is
protecting
a