I've been in this um marijuana
legalization movement like he said since
about
1964 long before most of you were born
my prayer in my entire adult life has
been to see marijuana legalized in the
United
States before I have to leave this
planet and go on to the next one like we
all
must that's my dream and my prayer
and I'm not going to Harang you about
why marijuana should be legalized it
would be like trying to tell some angels
why they should have
wings one thing I know all of us would
rather live in a world where we aren't
treated as criminals where the police
had no business with what was going on
inside our [ __ ]
heads what do the police have with what
goes on in our heads it's our business
so one day I pray this will be over with
in Michigan I'm a medical marijuana
patient registered with the state I got
my card on
me
yeah in Detroit where I
based we're going to vote for
legalization in the city of Detroit this
November and I think we'll probably
win years and years years ago we
established in an Arbor Michigan in
1972 a local ordinance that made
marijuana possession or sales of any
sort subject to a $5
ticket and that's been in effect there
for 40 years now I think they raised it
to $25 kind of a in nod to
inflation but it's still just a ticket
that's as good as it gets before you
have pure legalization which I hope
we'll have here in Oregon so I've always
wanted to go to the hempstock Festival
I've never had the opportunity before
and then Paul Stanford invited me this
year and said we're trying to pass our
measure number 80 to legalize marijuana
in Oregon and really I wanted to be part
of that so I'm glad to be here today I
spend a lot of time in Amsterdam where
you just buy your weight over the
counter you don't even have to be
sick you can buy some weed just to get
high on they got really good weed and
the prices are something you can live
with it's a beautiful thing we got one
coffee shop here in Portland I had the
opportunity to visit last night the
World Famous Cannabis Cafe here in
Portland and that's a good start I think
it's the first one maybe in the USA am I
right yeah well I live in in a coffee
shop culture every day I go to the
coffee shop get high drink coffee see my
friends listen to
music and have a good
time it's a civilized way to
live so I'm praying that yall are going
to pass this legislation in November I
just wanted to have one preachment and
that is the necessity to register to
vote because if you AR registered to
vote and then you don't actually vote
then these other idiots are going to
continue their
tyranny the other side they vote every
[ __ ] time they very rarely miss a
vote all of them vote and that's why we
get our ass kicked all the time because
we forget to vote or we don't think it's
important or they Hoodwinked us into
thinking it wasn't
necessary it's always good to vote man I
love democracy this is a great way to
live a democracy you got to vote but you
got to use it in order to use it you got
to register to vote in a timely fashion
so that's the one piece of grandfatherly
advice I can convey to you this
afternoon other than
that I was reminding Paul Stanford
yesterday when we were on his television
show I was with the Great American poet
John trudell and I was
reminding my brothers that it was poets
who started the marijuana legalization
movement Alan Ginsburg Edward Sanders
they were in the very Forefront of this
movement way back in 1964 and
1965 I was right behind them coming out
of
Detroit and you had people here in
Oregon like King key who spearheaded
this idea for many
years so you get to remember
poetry comes into this at the basic
level