[Applause]
[Music]
[Laughter]
w don't them know that we
know in know the struggle we'll fight
every time don't them know that we
know all these times we'll fight for her
rights don't that we
know in other struggle we Bight every
time don't him know that we know that I
and I will never give
[Music]
up
PR
nice no College mind I'm surely no
Professor I'll take this down we got to
make things better here is my question
that I'm on must is there a place where
I might a place where peace and unity DW
is there such a place no man I can't
tell and that's for Freedom that I
mention you don't lose your focus don't
lose your attention don't know that we
know in another the struggle we'll fight
every time don't time know that we
know you know these times we fight for
right don't time know that we
know another struggle we'll fight every
time don't need them know that we know
but high and I will never give up
to
[Music]
give
up we'll never give
up we never give up like my boy Michael
fron used to tell
Casper you never give
up you never give
up you never give up like John trell
used to tell
[Music]
me yes
sir
[Music]
it I'm in no
hurry big up to the DU tronic
crew
[Music]
respect
yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
he
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
la
[Music]
[Applause]
hope win