alright thank you so much in guy oh it's
great to be here at him stock I
appreciate the warm welcome and
introduction I am just happy to have
played my part to help legalize and
regulate marijuana here in Oregon but
let's give it up for T'Pol Stanford one
of the Giants of the movement and I'd
like to say that all the activists who
are working today we all stand on the
shoulders of giants and Paul Stanford is
one of those giants so really appreciate
all the work he's had to do and you know
I got involved in activism because I saw
my african-american friends treated more
harshly than my white friends for
marijuana offenses back in Missouri and
the first time we got a
decriminalization measure on the ballot
because we couldn't stand to see young
students have their lives ruined for
marijuana within the city limits to come
in Missouri we lost we only got forty
three percent of the vote but then we
got right back on the ballot again and
we got more than sixty percent of the
vote the next time we made the ballot
decriminalizing marijuana in the city
limits of Columbia Missouri and
legalizing medicinal use for any patient
so the patient finds themselves in
Columbia Missouri they can possess at
the 35 grams a medicinal cannabis
legally and now that movement in
Missouri is looking as moot as moved on
to decriminalize marijuana and st. louis
dee chrome eyes marijuana kansas city is
now looking to pass a statewide medical
marijuana legalization measure in 2016
and I think this movement of just step
by step person by person city by city
state by state is how we're going to
legalize marijuana fully you know here
in Oregon we had to decriminalize
marijuana all the way back in nineteen
seventy three the very first state to
decriminalize marijuana and then we have
to wait until nineteen ninety-eight to
legalize medicinal cannabis and then in
2004 we tried to legalize medical
marijuana dispensaries it didn't pass
I 2010 we try to legalize medical
marijuana dispensaries again it didn't
pass and then the legislature legalized
medical marijuana dispensaries in 2013
you know then 2012 Paul and measure ad
campaign team got a legalization measure
on the ballot that would have legalized
you know possession for adults
cultivation for adults it got forty
seven percent of the vote you know and
it didn't pass but it laid the
foundation for measure 91 each step of
the way we get closer and closer to true
equality and true freedom and then after
we pass measure 91 we say we're not done
there you know we're going to further
decriminalize marijuana we're going to
further reduce marijuana penalties and
we passed the first in the nation
expungement provision that can help up
to 78,000 people get marijuana offenses
off their record when down we've
accomplished that we're still not done
you know we got to equality for
employment true equality for housing
education to have adult smoking sections
and a festival where they celebrate
alcohol numerous times a year and we're
going to do that not because of me not
because of Paul not because of any other
activists you may hear about we do that
because of people like you all right
step-by-step person by person you share
your stories about marijuana how
marijuana helped you medicinally how it
helps you relax how it's a better choice
for you than alcohol or how it works
well for you and alcohol but you're not
a bad person you do not deserve to be in
prison do not deserve to be arrested and
you deserve to have employment
opportunities just like everybody else
so person by person speak the truth
about cannabis and the truth shall
eventually set us free so thank you very
much everybody keep up the good work I
really appreciate it I appreciate the
time to be here and I look forward to
him stock being bigger and better years
to come