as you just heard my name is Sid Mauer
and I am a former local news anchor from
Eugene Oregon and still really new for
me to be talking about this and standing
on a stage talking about cannabis
something that I of course like many of
you have worked on hiding for many years
before this so um what happened to me
was I was forced to take a drug test and
was fired due to in active THC
metabolites in my system most of you out
there probably understand that when you
consume cannabis it interacts with your
body differently than almost anything
else and traces of it even when inactive
stay in your system for up to 30 days so
even though I was completely one hundred
percent sober at work I was penalized
and fired for personal cannabis use in
my own time what's more is my news
director and assistant news director my
immediate bosses fought for me to keep
my job so in case anyone out there was
wondering if it was something else going
on it wasn't i was told verbatim that it
was my drug test that came back positive
for THC metabolites that led to my
firing and instead of just being quiet
about it and kind of pretending like
that didn't happen trying to maybe go
back into the news or back into the
corporate world I was so frustrated so
frustrated that I had to speak out
against it it was completely legal for
an out of state attorney corporate
attorney to fire me but it wasn't right
legal but not right and that is why I'm
speaking out against it so a little more
backstory on my on my situation like
many news stations out there my station
was very very comfortable with drug
testing people I am not exaggerating was
saying that I had a co-worker who
tripped and was drug tested I had a
co-worker who bumped her head and was
drug tested and for my situation I was
in rush hour traffic and I tapped the
bumper of the car in front of me and was
forced to take a drug test so even
though i left two scratches on a bumper
in front of me was completely sober and
that wouldn't have led to me getting
fired because i used cannabis in my
personal time i was fired and like i
said this is completely legal and i
truly believe that the only
that we're going to see any change any
movement in these unfair policies is if
we continue to educate and expose people
to the truth about cannabis if this
policy was in place to keep people safer
it's sailing there's no reason to
believe that someone who uses cannabis
in their free time is that all unsafe or
less safe than someone who say consumes
alcohol in their free time so let's take
a minute to think about my situation had
I used alcohol or had I use even a
harder substance like meth or cocaine
days before my accident I would still
have my job but because it was cannabis
and like I said it stays in your system
for longer I lost my job we need to
explain to businesses that this is bad
business practice it's not keeping
anyone safer and it's actually sending a
really negative message to employees
right top employers like Microsoft for
instance they don't drug test because
they respect their current or
prospective employees there are so many
reasons that drug testing is wrong
exactly policeman aren't drug tested and
in fact the FBI for instance has stopped
drug testing certain departments because
they weren't getting the application
turn out that they needed it is known
that using cannabis in your free time
does not increase your risk as a worker
therefore this policy should not be in
place it'd be different right if it was
a reactionary thing if there was a time
in history where we can point that
cannabis was legal and a bunch of people
were just coming to work stoned and
causing you know just terrible dangerous
accidents all the time guess what that's
never happened that is not the news
story that I was in the news business
for years and never once was there some
crazy incident about someone coming to
work and causing accidents because they
were stoned on cannabis this instance or
this policy was put in place because
Ronald Reagan decided that he wanted to
make a federal drug free workplace
policy basically and because of that it
spread and we are where we are today so
like I mentioned I am speaking out to
educate people and expose people I
truly believe some people really just
don't understand cannabis and that's why
they're against it so if there's
anything that I could explain to you is
talk about it come out of the cannabis
closet if you don't talk about your
cannabis use how is anyone supposed to
understand that it doesn't make you a
bad person it doesn't make you more
dangerous more lazy or any worse than
someone who chooses to use alcohol or
any other substance in their free time
so please keep talking about it if
you're looking to find out more about me
at Sid Mauer you can look at me on
Twitter and Facebook and I'm blogging
for marijuana politics which is a great
website if you're looking to follow
anything and everything on cannabis news
so thanks again for listening to me