[Music]
Yeah, Hemptock. Good to be here. I
played that Seattle Hemp Fest for years
and years. Started out as a little place
up there in Starlight Mountain. Smaller
than this, even way up there in the
Cascades, you know. Be getting cold this
time of night. Be hunkering down in your
sleeping bag and your tent taking a
little nip of something to keep warm.
song from back in those
days. Well, here's a little song that
you might get along with. All about a
natural seed growing wine by the side of
the roadway. It's nature's a wonderful
weed. Been around so long, it's hard to
tell why anyone would think it's new.
Love it or hate it. However you relate
it, I'll leave that up to you. But isn't
that righteous? And isn't that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough for
me. Now history's locked in a cardboard
box and it's hard to take a look with
sidetrack thrills and fantasies all
written all over the book. Everybody
tells you what to think and they've got
their reasons why. You got to pick
reality up by the scruff of the neck and
look it right in the eye. And isn't that
righteous? Isn't that good enough?
Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough for
me. Now, the same people that are
spreading the fear, the same people that
scare me the most. You know, some of
them look like they just assume like to
hang it from a lamp post. They talk
about what it does to your brain. Well,
I just have to react cuz Hitler never
touched the stuff. And that's an actual
fact. And isn't that righteous? Isn't
that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough for
me. Now, George Washington was a father
of our country and he had a hemp
plantation. Betsy Ross used it to make
the flag that flew above the baby
nation. They wrote their declarations on
paper from that same hemp fiber press.
And I don't know what they smoked when
they were taking a break, but I got a
pretty good guess. That isn't that
righteous? Isn't that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough for
me. Now it'll calm you down when you're
too uptight. You know, it just might
make you smile. Use a seed oil in your
engine. little lubricate the miles.
Glaucoma and chemotherapy, they say it
smooths out the track. So next time you
meet a cancer patient, ask them what
they think about that. And isn't that
righteous? Isn't that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough for me.
I don't know why some people get so
upset when you say to legalize it.
They'd rather build more jails, arrest
more people, and spread more crazy lies.
It's like talking to a brick wall, you
know? They just don't get the facts. I
think they ought to try a little that
Betsy Ross. It just might help them
relax. And isn't that righteous? Isn't
that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? Isn't that
good enough?
Ratches is good enough for me. Now, this
is just a song about a pre for common
sense. You know what I'm saying? Just a
little common sense, a little bit of
slowdown on a pick them up and throw
them away and lock the door kind of
thing. You know what I'm talking
about? I don't know.
I So, I I guess I've just about had my
say now, so I get beyond my way. I know
some people don't like the kind of
things I've got to say, but I got mine
and you got yours. is we give what we
can take. So next time I need a
breather, well, I might just take a
little smoke break. And isn't that
righteous? Isn't that good
enough? Ain't that the way it ought to
be? Isn't that righteous? And isn't that
good
enough? Righteous is good enough. Yes,
righteous is good enough. Righteous is
good enough for me.
Thank