so come about 1910 this guy named SCH
sidin according to research by Don
worter started inventing a machine that
was like the cotton gin it dropped the
labor involved in hip to 100 fold from
its previous price it went from I think
uh uh 50 cents a pound to half a cent a
pound and hip became incredibly
inexpensive and when that happened the
petrochemical industry was just starting
to synthe ize petroleum to be like hemp
seed oil and other vegetable oils to run
diesel engines and so at that time
petroleum wasn't the predominant fuel
most people grew uh their fuels you know
their their uh illuminance they called
it for their lamps before
electricity and they'd eat the stuff
left over and with hip they called it
GRL which uh was a pretty basic food
that uh was very high in the essential
fatty acids just like it is today it's
very healthy food but the petrochemical
industries realized that HP was their
main competitor that hemp produced three
times more seed oil than any other plant
out there and that's still true today
according to uh a study out of notra
Dame that was published in a magazine
called the Midlands naturalist back in
1975 this article is called uh feral
hemp in Southern Illinois
according to that study the wild hemp
that was growing on the Riverside in
Southern Illinois produced four tons of
seeds when you take four tons of seed
and you press it you get 300 gallons of
oil now that oil is not only very
nutritious it can also be put right into
any diesel engine and with no conversion
to the diesel engine it can run your
diesel engine now the other seed oil
crops right now our
soybeans uh sunflower seeds and canola
our rape seed you you know it's grape
seed and then when they present they
call it canola oil each of those produce
100 to 120 gallons of oil per acre and
you know that's mainly what we're
driving today when we're driving
biodiesel Vehicles we're driving those
seed oils and it you know it runs the
diesel engin just fine as most of us
know but HP is three times more
productive and the byproduct for
making oil from hemp is three tons of
high protein you start with four tons of
hip seeds you press it you get 300
gallons of oil and four tons of high
protein hip seed meal yeah so that's not
the only thing you get you know just
think if we just with that alone though
if we grew all of our fuel from
hemp all those barrels of oil
for every barrel of oil there's 50
gallons there's going to be a half a ton
of high protein hip seed meal left over
to wipe out world
hunger and then there's another
byproduct the fiber byproduct you're
going to get about 25 tons of HP herd
fiber HP herds also make paper there's a
bulletin from the USDA back in
1916 USDA bulletin 404 by Lester Dewey
it's called hip herds is a paper making
material and that report said that hip
produces four times more paper per acre
than trees well that's a waste product
when you're growing hip for seed oil and
that waste product can make most of our
paper needs and our building materials
you can glue that stuff together the
same way they glue together wood fibers
today and then the other byproduct not
just is the herd fiber but also 6 to 8
tons of Bast fiber that's the highest
quality plant fiber you can have
it's made to it's used to make canvas
rope lace and linen and in fact a lot of
the antique Linens and laces out there
are made from marijuana stems from hip
uh
fiber and so your average acre of hemp
is going to produce 300 gallons of oil 3
tons of high protein hemp seed meal 25
tons of hemp Bast fiber for paper and
building materials and 6 to 10 tons of
him uh herd fiber actually the herd
Fiers is the 25 tons the bass fibers is
the 6 to 10 tons but the bass fiber can
be used to make canvas rope lace and
linen and I think it's the seed oil
that's the real key here and that when
we legalize marijuana and allow
unregulated Industrial Hemp to become
predominant again the petrochemical
industries are going to lose their
Market hold we're going to see a
decentralization of the economy we're
not going to see the money being sent to
the chics and the oil companies uh the
despotic governments around the world
that depend on it in Nigeria and the
Middle East we're going to see the money
going to the farmers and to the local
economy and that's the key that's what
the petrochemical industry does not want
they want us to keep pouring our money
into their industries that are capital
intensive takes so much money to drill
for oil of us can compete and it takes
billions of dollars tens of billions to
refine petroleum into all the different
products we use to make from it today
but hip seed oil and hip you can you get
a a seed oil press for
$2,000 and any farmer can get all the
oil he needs to run his tractors feed
his family and ship the rest to to
support the local energy market and I
look forward to the day when that's
going to happen you know what we are
really here working for today is to end
adult marijuana prohibition we want to
end adult marijuana prohibition we want
to make it legal we want to see it where
it's legally sold to adults over the
counter we want to see it where adults
can grow their own with no license
whatsoever I mean why you know you don't
need a license to make your own beer or
wine it's only when you start selling it
that you need license so we want to see
unlicensed personal cultivation we want
to see unregulated hemp right now you
look at the industrial hemp Market out
there and in Canada and Europe they're
limited to less than 1% THC in some
cases half of a percent THC in their
plants what they do and that's why the
petrochemical industries really allow
that and support it because what they do
is they breed out the THC and by
breeding out the THC they breed out the
flowers by breeding out the flowers
They're breeding out the seeds and
that's the food and the protein that hip
should be making and when we restore it
to its natural place we're going to see
a boom for all of our Farmers for all
our local economies and the
decentralization of wealth as it should
be I think
so that's the dream and that's what
we're working for to restore industrial
hemp and to help medical marijuana
patients and I think you know we've got
our clinics and they've done a lot to
help us get this thing going but I look
forward to the day when our clinics are
put out of business by legal marijuana
and unregulated Industrial Hemp and
that's what we're working for we're
working to make it where our clinics
basically don't have a job anymore
because people can grow their own
without a license and uh that'll be a
happy day and we're going to keep
working toward it