we have no home grow in Washington State
get her down here anybody 21 and up
getting out the four plants that's real
Eagle ization when you can grow it and
give it away that's real Eagle ization
if i'm still in washington state forced
to go to a store that has any of 271
pesticides on it which is where they're
trying to drive all the medical patients
it's not really legalization you know
our movement has come up quite a way and
we made a lot of ground with medical but
it seems now that now thats recreational
legal and everybody sees a big pot of
gold that medical seems to be taking a
backseat seems to be getting rougher
treatment seems to be seen to be not
legitimate and I thank goodness for the
Oregon program that is so well at scotts
in your society here that it is still
apart as a matter of fact of leads
recreational you have got to go to the
to the medical shop right now until we
can get our other people licensed
washington did that exactly the opposite
way they gave licenses out to the rec
people people that were medical we're
not as accepted and less down the road
and right now they are trying to shut us
down I work in a place called Northwest
cannabis market up in Seattle this is
the place were 20 to 30 vendors seven
days a week quote our medicine in front
of legitimate patients with cards across
earth and across our two markets in the
a.m Seattle and white center we just on
the fifteenth of September shut down our
Seattle market we have had 2.5 million
patient visits to our market
how do they want to serve our needs they
want to eliminate your choice they want
to shove you into the store they want to
tax you that's all it's about it's not
about what's best for you or what's best
for the people or best for the state
it's our money and a power grab and I
say to all of you in any other states
Ohio can you hear me don't forget the
people that got us here our growers are
experts they know what they're doing you
know this new crowd they're going to do
great because they got lots and lots of
money behind them but I don't want to
legalize pot at forty and fifty dollars
a gram taxed I want to legalize pot so
it goes down to about two bucks a gram I
want it to be free I want to grow my 15
plants and I want to give some to you
into you into you and I'll tell you
something when anybody can grow in
Washington State that will be the best
protection for any patient because it
will not only not be forced to go to a
store where poison is not medicine they
will be able to get their cannabis from
anyone they choose it may be your
neighbor it may be your friend maybe
your coworker but I save you again until
you can grow your own and give it away
for free to any other adult without
dad's fee license permit registration
for now the new thing is they want to
come in have a liquor board inspect your
medical grow the Weed that you grow
privately for yourself for your own
consumption they want to come in your
home and look boy I say get the hell out
of my house and get the hell out of my
cannabis and get the hell out of my bag
really gonna say
is a long way to go I I don't know what
we've done in Washington I praise what
you've done in Oregon and i look forward
I mean everybody up there is either
going underground or they're leaving the
state and I see a lot of great
Washington growers down here in Oregon
now and follow the public can only
benefit from that so please be active if
you live in Washington get on the phone
get on your email get in your
legislators face and say what are you
doing we don't need to grab every
freakin dollar from the people that can
least afford it we need real
legalization thank you per line