Madison Oregon we got we got the
Southern Oregon Sun growers guild man
and it says it's pretty cool people get
together to cooperate on testing and
hiring a lobbyist it speak for outdoor
Sun girl good organic herbs to make sure
it's it's you know remains legal man
there's there's so many things that
could be done to just hardly [ __ ] this
you know let's hope you guys like this
is an emerging thing all over the
country man just feeling like we got to
find justice and then we got to figure
it out right away man in so many ways
you know with the trouble with the
police man I don't know they feel like
they're in a war zone learning and we're
not it's just a drug war I think you
have to go away as long as I can soon as
we say go away so let's say go away what
do you say put me down for one of them
Edelbrock or their two made in there
look even worse that a big bass here
brings down every year brings fear that
I'll have to sell the farm but have it
be a little easier but make you sound
have a farm paid off in just a little
while gonna be your own if he grows why
[Music]
I've always tried to be
favorite
[Music]
yeah
seems the agricultural of the eye
now with the regulations to come the
can't afford a lawyer like a corporation
a graph of the gamble of the ox [ __ ]
down to bargain farmers out there
[Music]