We're getting involved in this idea of
what we call Hemstead Project. Hempstead
Project.com. All right. But you can't
Google it. You got to put in that little
address thing up there on the computer.
But hemstead
projectart.com. Uh, and that's really
about we want we think it's time to
start focusing energy on hemp
specifically as an alternative energy
and economy and and something that's
healthy for the earth. So, we're we're
looking at trying to encourage people
that agree with that to take any kind of
act on it however they know how to act,
but to not be silent. Do anything do
anything that you can because it all
adds up. Uh well on the hemp said thing
one one of the things we've done on the
site is we put links so that people can
go and find out about hemp because I
think a lot of people don't really
understand what hemp can do you know I
mean as a resource from food uh people I
don't think people really understand. So
if people would go look and and at least
check it out check out the facts about
what it's really all about and then if
they're in agreement on that act on it.
Yeah.
I always ask everybody this one
question. If you could say anything to
the marijuana community, what would it
be?
Get out there and put these efforts into
hemp. The same energy and effort that
was put into medical marijuana by the
marijuana people, THC people, I think
that same energy should be put into
hemp. I think by putting that energy
into hemp, it's more consistent because
when we go for the medical marijuana,
that's just for us. When we go for the
hemp, we're now repaying the earth
because it's for the earth as well as
for us because it's healthy for the
earth. We've used medical marijuana and
wanted it because it's healthy for us.
Well, the same thing applies. Hemp is
healthy for the earth. So, I would like
to see the medical marijuana put some of
the same intensity and energy into now
getting medicine for the earth that was
used to get it for ourselves. Yes. Yes.
I agree. I' I'd like to see uh hemp
around the world. I think that it could
be solving a lot of the world's
problems. Well, this is what I'm saying.
See, a lot of people think it this or
that, have opinions about it. So, what
I'm what we're suggesting, go check out
the facts about what can really be done
with it. All right? I mean, from food to
clo, go check out the facts. See what
can really be done with it. Because
we've got to take it from being just an
abstraction hemp as an add-on. You know,
if we're talking about glo global what
that global warming, climate change, all
of these things we're discussing and
talking about, hemp has a tremendous
impact on being able to to to help to
balance what's happening, you know. So,
yeah. So, we're asking people research,
check it out, and if they're in
agreement to act on it, and if they're
not in agreement, well, then they're not
in agreement.