[Music]
[Applause]
I love the way you hurt me without
trying and the way you speak to me with
your
Embrace sometimes when you're asleep and
I am
crying I can just make out the smile
across your
face crashing cars Ling you and busting
fences destructive things that I've been
known
to so if I never do come to my
[Music]
Heart Will
Go I'd rather be a brok heart that's
run along
road to take me
down then a heart that's never broke but
knows it's
coming we were Bor to love and
[Music]
loveing
known so if I never do come to my
senses re Heart Will Go On You
[Applause]
[Music]
can't go
on can't go on
dying can't go on feeling
can't get over you there's no use in
trying I
never but I
[Music]
want
May
better another of
you maybe I'll have the time to sit
and and that's what
I'll when
I'm I'll go back to crashing
cars you and buting
fences
dtive that I've been known
to so if I never do come to my senses
heart will
[Music]
[Applause]
go thank you