is white te yes I
for isect
[Music]
alone for all of my life I've always
been prising the most high and
throughout my life
I've always
[Music]
been for all of my life I've always been
praising
the
my
always I would never run
away no matter what WI
as Bobby Crum to the ground I knock on
make I focus I
Med life always prising
the and my
[Music]
I all my life I've always been raising
the true all my life I've always
been I give thanks and praise for the
blessings that we share yeah we still
the people and Bing over the
heav theming still I give thanks and
praise cuz I know I be standing there
yeah is calling and I know that
I
fall still iing
the and
my
always for all
my I've always
beening and for all my life always
[Music]
been I teach better kind
of I bring them more
[Music]
postivity you can't feel sober anymore
if all your drink is R sure so mind
where you get
[Music]
your your life remember to
for all my life I've always beening
the and throughout my life I've always
been yes
I my life I've always been praise and
Jo throughout my life I've always ha
and for all my life I'll always be prais
and through my life always be
in for all my life