i want to tell you all a little bit
about a plant i know that can save the
world
it grows long and tall and has flowers
that can make your mind swirl
it's a funky plant with a vibrant that
is resistant to rain and mold
is the strongest plant fiber known to
man the best road you'll ever hold
where the pine is covered up the wagon
trains with a canvas made of him
and washington and jefferson the good on
that front was said to make the most of
it the first stars are strikes were sewn
on him the first constitution
too issues around the world for food
fiber oil
medicine and fuel and if we're pregnant
we won't have no need
for any of the oil we can make paints
and links or run our cars growing back
the next trees and it'll fix the soil
the muslims choose to see we can put in
a mouth with omega 6
and three we can feed the world with the
tree of life
and live sustainably but if we cut down
on the trees
we won't have no every girl feels a
helping stand
we can't make our papers but the house
from
a better world than my ancestors
foreign
well the flowers the female ham plant
makes the best medicines on earth
helps cancer and ace patients eat their
food helps those with depression
overcome the blues
look over everlasting all the insomnia
stress and rules for psychosis being pms
all the studies have been done on all
the doctors and people they can't make
money off this plant you see
because it's free it goes from a seed to
water free life we honor
you know the future is grown in our own
backyards
but if we cut down
my children world than my ancestors
so in this modern day and age when we
seem to lack spirituality
this one single plant can bring us back
10 000 years in history
to the shiva piranhas the jesus the
christ to the buddha the pagans the
goddess the light you can be with all
the animals they want with all the trees
is
bye