you've made history here in Oregon with
legalization last year it was just
coming on the verge of it and I'm so
glad to be back again and you know the
future really looks bright is all these
clubs and stuff that are forming there
like community centers and that's what
this movement is about unity of the
people through nature and a plan man and
you know when we're talking about
history not only talking about history
of people like Jack hair and any lap in
prison and stuff like that but people
like ray crystal who I shared this stage
with last year man now he's gone but
that brother did so much for this cause
you know and Paul helped out brother out
Paul's done so much for this cause to
and it's really important to remember
that and when we talk about cannabis
history man we're talking about tens of
thousands of years of history according
to the latest archaeological evidence
we've been making hemp fibers for 32,000
years this comes in the forums of tools
used for breaking up the fibers of him
we have evidence of hemp cloth 12,000
years old you know what I mean so this
is something that was spread out
throughout the whole agent world oldest
evidence of burning cannabis inhalers
fumes actually comes from the Ukraine
from 5500 years ago from a
proto-indo-european these are the same
people that domesticated the horse even
the domestication of the horse was
thought to come about through the use of
hemp rope and so these same people that
were making hemp rope domesticating the
horse they burned cannabis they spread
the use of cannabis throughout the agent
world and you know I don't care where
you're from in this world man your
culture has a connection with this plan
whether it be in China where they've
been using cannabis seeds and fiber for
food and cloth for probably four or five
thousand years and burning it for
probably like 3,000 4,000 years you know
the oldest pharmacopoeia is from China
the pens at South ought to be 2700 bc
4700 years ago cannabis is probably the
first medicine currently they think that
cavemen may have been using cannabis to
fight off parasites so this is coming
from scientists people like dr. guy
Jeffries from GW Pharmaceuticals he
suggests that cannabis played a role in
the Great Leap Forward this is when
humanity was discovering things like the
the making the wheel and how to control
fire so cannabis may have played a role
in that novel ability to think and
create a new ways and in Mesopotamia in
Assyria and Babylonia they burn cannabis
is in the temples under the name kanamu
and also anointed their skin with it and
this led over into the Hebrew use of it
where people like Moses use cannabis am
the Hebrew name of cannabis and the holy
anointing oils and incense is man Moses
would cover his body in cannabis and
myrrh and cinnamon oils then burn that
on the altar of incense and actually
speak to the Lord the pillar of smoke
over the incense altar and then in
Persia sorest her man one of the great
prophets of the ancient world used
cannabis and infused wines that was the
main source of enlightenment in the
Zoroastrian religion in India man going
back to the Stone Age longest
continually worshipped God on earth
Shiva is the Lord of cannabis also Lord
of yoga you know what I mean there's a
whole movement of ganja yoga going on
right now because that's how yoga was
originally performed you can go to India
right now see sad news and other holy
men partaking of the Holy chillum in
honor of Sheba before sitting down to
their yogic practices and Africa manage
spread all over Africa pygmy said that
they've been using cannabis since the
dawn of time and that God gave them hemp
so they'd be healthy and happy so all
over the world people have recognized
this powerful medicinal plant man first
medicine first sacrament and and
probably first recreational to you know
what I mean because it is about feeling
good feeling positive and getting back
into that vibration of nature you go to
any bar here in town I bet you at
closing time you see this fights outside
of that bar I bet you that never happens
once in a medical club or a recreational
club with cannabis just good vibes and
that's what this plan is about that's
what it's bringing to this planet right
now in this important time we can use
hemp to heal our planet stop cutting
down our old growth for us we can move
away from fossil fuels with hemp fuel we
can feed the world with the most
nutritious plan on the world hemp seed
and hams coming here
Bergen as well man there'll be a huge
teehalt hempseed you know what I mean we
can heal our economy what's happening
here right now in Oregon think about not
only these clubs with all the
advertising dollars graphic artist
dollars all these sub-industries people
making concentrates people growing it
we're talking about the billion-dollar
crop that jack herer preached about for
20 years taking place right now and this
time and this here and you people in
Oregon are leading that battle man I'm
hoping next week when I go back to
Canada we have legal weed there on the
federal level man got an election on
Monday the guy leading the poll says
he's going to legalize cannabis will be
the first country in North America to
have federal legal cannabis so we're
making the future right now and then the
future as Bob Marley sitting this great
future of ours don't forget the past man
so pay respect your ancestors who
brought this plant down through the ages
listen to their wisdom listen to their
love and take that with you and spread
it around the world god bless you all
mad make way for the tree life