well the shest way to empty a room is
for an old guy to start telling his life
story so I promise you I won't do
that I wrote the cultivator handbook in
1968 I wrote it because at the time we
were engaged in a terrible war in
Asia uh DEA didn't exist was the FBI
enforcing drug
laws Richard Nixon our criminal
president
as the man in the White House and I've
been growing for a couple of years and I
realized that if if we were going to be
free truly free in this country we had
to be able to grow what we want to
consume whether it's marijuana whether
it's our own garden of vegetables
whether it's opium whatever it is you
want to grow if it's a natural plant if
it's a free gift from God that is your
right now those rights
don't exist unless people like Paul
Sanford and and Oregon normal enforce
those rights in our name you know when
somebody like Paul Stanford goes to his
state representative and says I've got
an organization with 200 people in it
who vote they're going to yawn at him he
says I got an organization with 2,000
people in it and they vote they might
pay attention if he says I got 10,000
people in they're all registered and
they all
vote then the politicians listen so as
much as I hate belonging to
organizations and those who know me will
tell you I don't belong to many I think
it's incredibly important that you give
Paul and meline and the other folks here
from Oregon normal and from the HP
cannabis Foundation your support by
registering and voting and showing up
whenever is possible to to to to to let
your numbers speak where your voices may
not be
heard so I want to thank you all for
coming today I want to thank you for uh
being the generation that's going to
make it finally happen you know I'm
probably your grandfather's age your
grandmother's age I've been working at
this for 40
years you guys work at it for another 40
years but I'll guarantee you before one
or two more years is out this whole
scene is going to change and then you
work to make other get rid of these
other oppressive laws that are taking
away our freedoms work at it don't let
them do it show up vote join the
organizations that are making a
difference in your lives God bless you
all and God bless Jack
harar