we can stop the madness of marijuana
prohibition
there are people out there that are in
jail today like Mark Emery we saw his
wife here a little bit ago he was in it
yesterday to five years simply for
selling a seed
and if you go to Malaysia
there are people in Malaysia that are
sentenced to death just this week they
sent us the guy to death for just about
three pounds of marijuana and there are
people on ready scheduled to hang in
Malaysia for 300 grams
I think I'm carrying around about that
much right now you know so
anyway
we've got to stop this stuff you know
people are being incarcerated it's
ruining their lives we're losing our
children
even medical marijuana patients have to
go through hell you know in Washington
state the medical marijuana law just
right over there across that river is
just an affirmative defense
and you know that the medical marijuana
law is great it's helped a lot of people
and sick people have an option now but
it's not the solution
it's a step
and what we really want to do is just
completely legalize marijuana and hemp
and that's what we're working for
you know in California there is a
historic vote proposition 19. back in
1974 there was a vote in California that
was also called proposition 19 and
coincidentally it was also a marijuana
vote it was the first marijuana vote and
he got about 40 percent of the vote back
then but this year's proposition 19
looks like it's going to win
if we can get our voters out we will win
there we also have an initiative here in
Oregon that will help medical marijuana
patients that's ballot measure 74.
one of the chief petitioners was just up
here Anthony Johnson so we strongly
support ballot measure 74. we urge you
to get out there and help us get it
passed and mobilized and register and
vote because that's really one of the
keys here as we know in this system is
to register and vote and get our voters
out you know the polls show that ballot
measures 74 here in Oregon can pass by a
good majority but if you go to the the
list of the people who are likely voters
people who say yeah I'm definitely going
to vote it's a lot lot closer we're only
ahead by a couple of appoints where the
the polls show we're ahead by about 10
points overall but among likely voters
it's much much closer that means our
unlikely voters need to get off their
Duff and get out there and vote and get
their friends to vote
because that's the only way we're going
to make a difference here
you know we need to work for Global
cannabis freedom and that's what this
event is about we want to end adult
marijuana prohibition and restore
Industrial Hemp for all the many things
that Industrial Hemp does key among
those is energy
we think that when marijuana is legal
we'll be driving most of our cards on
hemp seed oil most of the time on the
world's most productive biodiesel
resource and the byproduct from that
is food an acre of hip according to a
study out of uh University of Southern
Illinois that was published in Notre
Dame back in 74 an acre of hip wild hip
feral hip here in the United States will
produce 8 500 pounds of seeds per acre
when you press that you get over 300
gallons of oil per acre that's six
barrels of oil per acre just from a cold
pressing of the seed and the residue out
of that 8 500 pounds of seeds is 6 000
pounds of high protein hip seed meal
so if we start driving our cars on hemp
fuel the the waste product will Wipe Out
World Hunger
it's really a miracle plant I believe
that Hep and cannabis are the greatest
gift from our mother earth from the
Creator
and it's our job to bring that back
and it's going to take us all educating
our fellow Americans and getting out
there and boating so I urge you if
you're not registered to vote go over to
the THCF Booth over here and register to
vote
we have a petition over there that will
legalize marijuana here in Oregon in
2012. we're Gathering some sponsorship
signatures on that so if you are a
registered voter here in Oregon go right
over to the THCF Booth which is right
over there
corner
and sign that petition
you know I I want to in closing urge you
folks to work for Global cannabis
freedom to help those people in Malaysia
who are sentenced to death and they're
going to hang and their families are
left there to deal with that to help the
people like Mark Emery and Eddie Lepp
who've spoken on this stage
to so they aren't incarcerated aren't
left in jail we need to work for Global
cannabis freedom
to help our mother earth the Web of Life
all the plants and animals on this
planet we need to restore balance to the
energy industry and hip will do that the
way we can help that is to work for
Global cannabis freedom
and for those of our brothers and
sisters who have fallen on the way like
Jack Herer who last year suffered a
eventually fatal heart attack right here
at our hipstock Festival gave his last
speech right here on this stage and for
Dr Todd bakeria who helped push medical
marijuana and spoke for the first two
years on this stage
for all of our brothers and sisters
who've Fallen along the way
I urge you to work for Global cannabis
freedom help us restore hip
it's the healing of the nation thank you
thank you Paul Stanford