Paul this is for you if you're out there
Paul wanted to hear this song U it's
called heima Nagasaki Russian Roulette
and it's about uh well you know we're
always America's always posturing and
posing and saying you know those those
people over there they want to get a
bomb they want to get nuclear stuff
going in their own country you know
whether it's Iran or whoever it is and
the same time America is the only
country the only country in the world
that's ever used an atomic we
and it did it preemptively on a civilian
population twice
twice they did it in Hiroshima and they
did it in Nagasaki so this is called
hirosima Nagasaki Russian
Roulette they dropped the bomb in 45 to
win the World War no one had ever seen
such a terrible sight before the world
watched with eyes wide to see where it
would lead as the politics of power
passed around the sea it was a time to
remember that we never can forget
toim russan
rouette they arose like the saviors of a
modern human race with radiation Halos
that hung above their face were the key
to the sure cure and treatment of our
ills a hot shot of cobalt a pocket full
of pills speaking always of the enemy
who lur across the seas while they moved
in Among Us like a carrier
disease hold up in the heart was hidden
secretly away the warheads and the
submarines await to make their play and
the military masterminds improve on your
designs while the soldiers get all doped
up and stumble through the lines and the
leaks in the water and get carried by
the time to call it National Security I
call it attempted home
aside Governors and Statesmen on
Congressional pay quick to please the
hand that feeds careful what they say
they call out experts to assure us and
to wave their magic wands this is the
power of the future they say and the
future marches on and then they gather
up their favors and political gains
while the spills fill the rivers and
settle in the
pl I know the minds behind them they are
riddle full of holes they are not to be
trusted with their hands at the controls
their eyesight is Twisted with the glory
of their careers heaped Praise of
flattery his music to their ears and to
listen to them talk about how it hasn't
happened yet stck plan he receive nasaki
ring r
l
[Music]