there is a Canadian seed growing
Association they been producing Their
Own Foundation seed they've been
producing foundation and what you
normally have in seed development is you
have breeder seed you have Foundation
seed you have uh registered seed and
certified seed those four classes so
there's a 4-year period in the evolution
of any certified seed the the uh the
national seed protection act provides um
the the legal framework for handling the
genetics of seeds inside of the United
States and it's consistent with
International treaties now the Canadian
regulations that they're operating by go
far beyond the the restrictions of the
of the seed variety protection act um
because under the uh seed protection act
um a farmer can save seed enough to
plant their own
acreage of a of a tier one of tier one
of tier one seeds there are many
heirloom seeds that there is no
restriction on it um I have a lot to
learn about the nature of those laws and
those are the rules I believe we going
going by Colorado is going to be doing
it its own way Colorado is not Canada MH
um and color I'm from Colorado yeah and
we value our autonomy and our
independence greatly and uh we've gotten
advice from some of the best Minds in
the world mhm um and this is a very very
exciting time