[Music]
my
name is
[Music]
during times of
shadow in the background of
burst the sun waits for the
moon to torch
tonight torch
the
night in the broken
neon and Faded
light the lucky
motel at the corner of nowhere and the
past where memories go to
forget to
forget laughing to
erase her name is
Lacy he makes his crazy kind of
crazy his name is
want she can hear
it she wants
want but doesn't want
to Sparks of the Stars
burnings strong heat he is like flame as
her fire awaits she
is a pulse a pulse in the charging light
as a passion of
storm fiery rain lightning carries
Thunder
[Music]
o
she's a good
girl coming to understand that sometimes
this is what good girls do what good
girls do in the breath of
ss in the magic of
moan they held them together so as not
to feel so alone
so
alone so alone during times of shadow in
the background of first the sun waits
for the moon to torch the night torch
the night in the breath of
ss in the magic of
moan they held it together so it's not
to feel so alone so alone so alone
[Music]
we