as long as people are just being locked
up for cannabis then we've got to change
those laws and we've got to restore him
for energy folks that's the real key
here the whole reason marijuana was
prohibited was to stop this to stop
hemp fuel being used now this is hemp
seed oil with a piece of hemp twine here
this is next week's wick right here and
you can burn this in any deal in June
with no conversion to the engine today
you pour that right into your diesel
engine and turn the key and drive and
that's the reason it was made illegal
it's the petrochemical pharmaceutical
military industrial transnational
corporate elite crony capitalists ruling
class that have brought us hemp and
cannabis prohibition