you know it was about two years ago that
uh Jack two years ago yesterday that
Jack Herer gave his last speech from
this stage Jack har wrote a book called
The Emperor wears no clothes right here
in Portland back in
1985 we call this stage the Jack Harrer
stage and uh uh you know today is also
911 so it was 10 years ago that a lot of
people died
back on the east coast and so we're
coming up on
420 and we just want to remember couple
other people Dr Todd Miker also got to
talk from this stage he wrote a book
about cannabis and Ben mzelle a famous
uh Wisconsin activist spoke on this
stage last year and he passed away
earlier this year from cancer so I don't
want to give anybody a bummer here at
420 but uh we're here to Mark important
occasion you know we want to see hemp
restored hemp is one of the oldest crops
grown by people everybody agrees that
marijuana was among the first few crops
that people started growing at least
12,000 years ago and it produces more
food protein that meets human
nutritional needs better than any other
protein out there it produces more fuel
biodiesel fuel from its seeds and
ethanol from its leaves and stocks and
from these hemp stocks and this is the
official Hemp stock of Hemp stock here 3
years old it from the stocks it produces
more paper more fiber more building
materials than any other plant
so uh we're here to legalize him and
we're doing it through an initiative
petition there's a petition Booth right
over there I want to urge you guys if
you're registered to vote to sign the
petition if you're not registered to
vote now now is the time we've got to
take control it's your duty you know you
can't stand around and say when are they
going to legalize marijuana because
they're never going to do it we're going
to have to do it you know it's going to
take us all working together you know no
doubt about it it's not going to happen
you know unless we all get out there and
represent and educate so I urge you to
sign the petition if you can get some
signatures on the petition there's some
petitions over there
and uh you know I want to hope you are
you guys ready for
420 well you know it's it's less than a
minute away according to my clock so uh
you know we're here for freedom and
liberty too you know our right to our
freedom of Consciousness to be happy
here on this planet is one of the other
things we're fighting for you know right
now there's really a rapid growth in
genetic technology and Gene information
there's rapid growth in nanotechnology
as they miniaturize all sorts of things
there's a rapid growth in artificial
intelligence within a lot of our
lifetimes lot most of of you guys out
there uh computers are going to be
pretty darn smart and if we don't
protect individual rights then the
future is dire you know things like the
Matrix and the Terminator are
possibilities so we have to protect our
right freedom of Consciousness and
expand natural individual rights and I
think marijuana is a bell weather issue
on that the the fact that they've taken
the oldest crop the one that produces
more fuel more food more fiber and more
medicine than any other plant and they
made that one
illegal it's
wrong so we're going to have to get
active I'm counting on you happy
420 and uh
we'll be back restore him