my name is Anna Diaz and I am from the
normal Women's Alliance and I'm also one
of the founders of Oregon
normal and I'd like to talk to you today
about
legalization cuz it's time has come so
we got some really great news from the
doj it sounds like maybe they're going
to honor State's uh rights to
legalization in Colorado and Washington
and even in Oregon the legislature is
already talking about
creating a law there rather than letting
it go through the initiative process so
clearly the powers that be are starting
to understand that legalization is
something that the people want and
something that the people have requ are
requiring and that's really good news
the bad news is our people are still
getting busted yeah just this summer my
good friend Lori from Southern Oregon
got raided for providing safe access to
patients just this last week 14 private
residents in or right here in Portland
got busted I haven't heard all the
details yet somebody left me a note that
said well maybe they should have gotten
busted for shipping 50 lbs of weed to
Texas and New York and my first thought
was don't people in Texas and New York
need weed
too it is time for prohibition to end
and it is time for everybody out here
that's having a good time to step up and
contact your local representatives and
your federal representatives and tell
them to stop sending us to jail stop
taking our babies stop destroying our
families and allow us to consume
cannabis in peace like we're doing right
here right
now and you guys are the ones who can
make it happen I'm just one person and
I've had some kind of impact on this
movement if every one of you stepped up
you could do the same thing I'm not
anybody special I'm just a person who's
pissed off and if you're not pissed off
about what's happening in CA with
cannabis in our community today then
you're not paying attention cuz even
though we are are are so fortunate that
we can be out here enjoying the freedom
of weed right here right now our people
are still getting busted our people are
still going to jail and it's mostly
people of color and people who are
younger so you kids who think it's
really cool to sell weed so you can pay
your rent you need to help us legalize
too because you can get a real job in
the Cannabis Community you can get
benefits you can have a 40-hour work
week and get paid to do that same thing
if we legalize if we can grow industrial
hemp in this state the jobs that will be
created and the sustainability that it
will provide for us
is infinit large I can't even put it
into words it's so huge I was unemployed
for 2 years trying to find a job here if
we have jobs through industrial hemp and
the Cannabis businesses that can be
built once we legalize I probably could
have had a job the first day so today I
ask you all as you're out here enjoying
yourselves when you go home think about
what a good time you had think about how
great it felt to be free because doesn't
it feel great to feel
free I can't hear you doesn't it feel
great to be
free Okay so let's make it happen call
those Representatives email them send
them a postcard drive them crazy make
them know that they know who you are and
that you support cannabis legalization
don't vote for anybody that doesn't
support cannabis legalization if you're
from Washington there's a petition here
you can sign today that promotes real
legalization sign them all let's
legalize my name is Anna Diaz and I'm a
proud Stoner join me in Arana
prohibition thank you