nice to be in oregon
or you're about to do something really
smart
and that is to get the police and the
authorities of our company society out
of our lives
so we can get high and enjoy ourselves
without having to worry about these
goons and their uniforms
this uh
i've been doing this for a long time we
had our first hippie gathering in
detroit where i'm from in 1967
just like this
well we didn't have as good of a sound
system or a state
but then what happened the police wrote
down on it so they're always
in ann arbor when we used to have
pre-concerts every sunday
we used to pay off the police
to not come on to the
site they could have they had to stay in
the parking lot
and take care of the parking traffic
because we thought if they came in
to the free concerts they would just
kill everybody's high
and they'd be walking around their
helmets and their guns and their radios
and all that horse [ __ ]
so we had to pay them off to keep them
outside but today this is a new low for
me when the hemp stock
organization
has to pay these guys to come in here
and hassle us
i don't get it
i think once you legalize it to get that
over with yeah
i'm all due respect to these guys i know
they serve a
important role as security guards in our
society but hey i feel secure as a
[ __ ] out here
you know what i'm saying i feel really
unsafe with this kind of environment
of uh armed
uniform characters
walking amongst us okay
i could talk about the police all day
but i'm not going to
i'm really a poet
i became activist because the police
wouldn't leave me alone i had to fight
back
so
that was 50 years ago
that's a long time ago
most you know ain't even 50 yet
so
i'm really ecstatic to be here
and i'd like to give you a few poems if
i could i don't want to
[ __ ] up your afternoon but hey this is
what i do and ask me to be here
like to start with a prayer
inspired by the music of john coltrane
what is jazz
but spirituals
played through saxophones
and trombones
spirit voices
through
metal tubings
and the terrible repetition of the
formal premise phys
trance-like at its best
or boring
when the spirit does not move
oh what is blue
but spirituals
with the line
removed
that is structurally
and in content just a prayer
to the gods of daily life
to ask the blessing
that the body of another
may lay warm in the bed
beside you at night and the rent be paid
and a meal
on the table
with the sheriff
far
away
from the scene of the crime
oh what is jazz but the registration
of the human personality
in relation to the spiritual
stripped
of literal meaning
but full of sound
important
direct as the voice of the gods
spiritual