in 2003 i think i met dr. Phil davec I
know a lot of you guys know dr. Leveque
if you don't this is dr. Leveque says
closest I could get today because he
just couldn't make it so this is almost
life point he's really a tall guy anyhow
if he was here he'd have all kinds of
advice to give to you um all good advice
doc lévêque was one of the main guys it
helped the law of initiative in 1998
become a reality he had problems with
the Oregon Medical Board because he
signed more patients authorizations than
any other doctor in the state of Oregon
so good for him he helped 5,000 patients
before they took him out in 2004 so he
had five good years that he helped all
these people a thousand of them are
veterans and we hear from them every day
we hear from them at Salem News calm
because he's a regular writer for us so
he's a really special guy he turned 90
years old I just a couple of months ago
and he's still going strong so you'll
see him around and he writes for us two
three four times a week so catch his
stuff on salem news com he covers PTSD
and a lot of toxicology he is a forensic
toxicologists and a pharmacologist one
of the only ones in the state of Oregon
and so though he can't sign applications
anymore he can still talk about what he
knows to be true fact which is that
cannabis cures and he knows the true
such as we all do so I just wanted to
share that with you that doc does wish
that he could be here and on his behalf
I'd like to say what he would of course
leave you with don't smoke in the rain
anyway you guys are in family and we
always think of the cannabis community
as a community and I want you to look at
each other and realize you know this
isn't a bad this is you know we don't
want to look at each other as people
that we only run into at places like
this because it's a cool place to hang
out we do this all the time you're an
activist if you believe in Indian
prohibition then you need to believe it
24-7 so look at each other as your
brothers and sisters we need to take
care of each other keep each other out
of harm's way don't let anybody that you
know get arrested give them good advice
so you know turn them on to the best
information that you've got and we've
got a lot of resources at salem news com
so please feel free to use us in that
way as much as you possibly can but we
have a lot of people that have really
sacrificed a lot that are serving time
in prison today that have been for many
years but you know we've got Reverend
Roger Christian Hawaii three years in
federal you know detention this stuff
needs to stop and gawk Lebec also he is
a sacrificial lamb he sacrificed his
whole career for us for us so let's do
him the favor that he is doing for us
and give it your all do what you need to
do sign your petitions and make sure you
vote and speak up you guys you know that
it really makes a difference it makes a
difference speak the truth anyway thank
you very much