well things been so smooth here so many
great speakers saying something good
things guys I wanna be part of the day
[Music]
Sunday afternoon City Bob everywhere
weeks done
while it says
[Music]
on the riverbank
get things coming out
where'd you go
Colorado Washington to California to
they got a great little organ freedom
[Music]
keep it
you can over-regulated
[Music]
turn it up in the Sun down in the back
row
[Music]
here people come speak and give a wisdom
around a
lawyers doctors engineer's farmers and
people that see bring it on we need
Warner's freedom well
[Applause]
[Music]
again
the RBA let that sometime
[Music]
living in the city of dreams you put a
bird on me with my biggest part of town
he got that Portlandia thing about it
looking all around
in theory before like this in that
Marlin wing
[Music]
and stock 2016