[Music]
Hey, one more time. We're the syndicate
from Vancouver, Washington. We love
every single one of you. We love
marijuana. We love this
[Music]
festival. And we love Sublime.
When you grab a hold of
me, tell me that I'll never be set
free. I'm a pair of
eye creep and crawl. I slip into the
night.
[Music]
Two pints of
boo. Tell me, are you a bad fish, too?
Are you a bad fish, too? But ain't got
no money to
spare. I wish this night would never
end.
Lord knows I'm
weak. Won't
somebody get me off this? What is that?
It looks
magical.
Baby blue whale.
Really grab the reef when all diving
fails. I swim, but I wish I never learn.
Thank you. What is
too
rich? Dive deep when it's 10 ft
overhead. Grab the reef underneath my
bed. underneath my
paper can
[Music]
cause time and
go. Lord knows I'm
weak. Won't somebody
[Music]