it's great to finally be able to see
legal cannabis and to buy some legally
as an adult you I've been growing my own
so I haven't really gone to any of these
dispensaries before this is the first
time I've ever bought marijuana over a
counter at a cash register and uh it's
what we've been working for for many
many years and I'm just happy the day is
finally come you know I asked for a Jack
Herer joint here uh thinking I I re
recognize that name he would be so proud
to be here today there's no doubt about
it he petitioned hundreds maybe
thousands of hours here in Oregon his
book was written right here in Oregon
for the first edition so this is uh an
exciting day well I I figured I'd
probably be doing this in about
1972 uh but it's taken a few years
longer uh I've been going to Amsterdam
for a very long time and and buying
recreational and social marijuana over
the counter and and sharing it and we've
got a long way to go before we're at
that level uh but it's really great to
see a a good start here today uh it
feels great you know it's a real surreal
moment uh you know talking to you about
the uh progress that we've made and
really the long hard fight over decades
uh yeah I think about people like LK Jim
Greg Jim clar you know people that uh
put in decades to this fight who aren't
with us who weren't able to see a day
like today day and uh it means a lot uh
for a lot of people um when I was in
high school I first want to debate about
marijuana legalization back in like
1995 uh in college I helped
decriminalize marijuana in Columbia
Missouri and my goal was to help
legalize the state by 2020 you know and
Colorado and Washington legalized in
2012 and then Oregon Alaska and DC in
2014 and so to have a day like today
it's really a day for celebration a day
for reflection um but I know in my heart
that despite the improvements we still
need to make here in Oran that we're
going to remain Vigilant and we're going
to have a law that can be the model for
the rest of the country and we can stop
this insane and barbaric practice of
arresting and jailing people for
cannabis all across the country so today
is is a great day each step of the way
has been very surreal a lot of people
have been waiting a long time to see
this happen it's historical moment that
we're all finally able to enjoy and it
is showing the freedom that we all
should have and the right that we all
should have to recreate not only
Medicaid it's unbelievable we thought
that this day would never going to come
to reality actually but we're really
happy and we're happy for the people of
origon you know uh that uh you went
through the ballot and you succeed and
this is the result so we're really
excited to be here it's the way it
should be it's too bad it's taken so
long and the commuting is going to kill
me down from Canada but it's a true
pleasure to be able to act like a normal
person and get the product when you want
it I'm so
exciting free fighting for legalization
this is a worldwide process then soon or
later we'll come to every single place
in every single spot in the world
because it's a medicine and just insane
that has to be illegal so we're really
excited this is a a key moment in
history I guess it is
it's yeah I think that here in Oregon
we're going to show you know the cities
and counties in eastern Oregon that are
ban marijuana businesses that you can
have regulated sales create jobs
generate Revenue the sky is not going to
fall and that's going to carry over to
more States and more and more states are
going to both legalize Adult Ed cannabis
but also medicinal cannabis as well each
of those states that comes into the
legalized realm that adds additional
senators and representatives uh
who represent people who are living in
states that have legalized marijuana of
some sort so um I think Congressman
blumire think believes 5 years um I
think within 10 for sure we're going to
repeal a federal prohibition it's going
to be left up to the states and that
Oregon with uh home
cultivation uh keeping medical no per se
DUI low taxes relatively low barriers to
entry we're going to have the best
policy in the country and unless States
look at what we've done and even improve
upon what we done but I think of many
ways we're going to be a model for
everybody and then the United States
looking at a global sphere United States
has been the one pursuing the the Global
Drug War the global war on marijuana and
once the United States ends prohibition
I think we can we can expect most of the
world to do the same you know the
biggest thing is to educate people
educate your politicians educate your
family educate your friends that
marijuana is a good thing uh we need
hemp for our environment we need
cannabis for many different physical
issues so uh uh the more alcohol we can
replace with cannabis the better off
we'll all be