and it's uh it's all about uh all the
beneficial uses of cannabis and hemp and
marijuana and you know Oregon I'm sure
you all know this just legalized the
cultivation of hemp one of the first
states to really go that far so give
thanks give it up for
Oregon
I want to tell yall a little bit about a
plan I know that can save the world it
girls long and tall and has flowers that
can make your mind swirl it's a funky
plant with a fiber that is resistant to
rain and it's the strongest plant bber
known to man the best roope you'll ever
hold well the Pioneers covered up the
wagon trains with a canvas made of him
in Washington and they GRE all theirs in
said to make the most of it the first
Stars and Stripes were swn on him the
first constitution to ises around the
world for food fber oil medicine and
Fuel and if we break this we won't have
no need for any other
we can make and R our cars going back
next seon fix the so the see we put in M
witha 6 and three we can feed the world
with the tree of life and live
sustainably but if we cut down all the
trees we won't have nowhere to bre grow
fields and help instead we make our the
house from it got gr Wild and Free
Living the way that we ought to be going
to leave my children a better world than
my ancestors are
Lefty wo
wo la
la
woo
will the flowers of the female ham plant
make the best medicines on Earth helps
Cancer and a patients eat their food
helps those with depression overcome the
bluea epilepsy nause neosis pyos pink
PMS all the studies have been done and
other doctors agree but they can't make
money off this PL to see because it's
free it grows from a SE water and free
like we are to be you know the future is
growing in our own
backyards but if we down on trees we
won't have nowhere to Brea we go him
inad we make our the house got wild and
fre the way we are to be to my children
a better world my
ancestors
wo
w
so in this modern day and age when we
seem to lack spirituality this one
single blank can bring us back 10,000
years in history to the Shiva piranhas
the Jesus the Christ to the Buddha the
pagans the God is theight to Comm with
all the animals be one with all the
trees to realize the god of Secret
inside me is the we got to take care of
the earth the earth is the mother that
gives birth and we can hear all listen
with a single green plan we can start
right now we down all the trees
weere
house wild the way we are be my children
world
my wo wo
la la la la la la la la la la
la wo
wo
you
w