I've seen we had 66 out of Kentucky 120
counties
to get your own children I guess
sending out one hundreds of millions of
dollars and the American public is
sending out billions of dollars in tax
clean income to the international
criminal syndicates in South America
Mexico for a plant hi granddaddy used to
grow by the thousands of acres and I'm
going to redirect that money out of the
hands these international criminal
syndicates and I'm going to put them
into the capital tax coffers of
Frankfurt so I can lift the people of
Kentucky out of poverty and out of the
mezz rain out of these last place
hey
this money but I'm going to redefine the
role of government in policing private
behavior in the state of Kentucky yeah
are you gonna please say you don't leave
here go out to give your cards they can
set up random go [ __ ] in front of you
make you get out of your car bring a dog
to sniff you your car and always
belongings take blood out yard make you
pee in a bottle stick their hands where
the Sun don't shine I don't know Jackie
room as me another fellow I was telling
stop running for governor he said well I
before your against you which ever
helped you the most government that
tells you that the solution to a present
a problem is double in the prison
population over next 20 years has its
head stuck where it's never going to
discover the thousand points of light of
George Bush these people's idea of
future full employment is to make half
of his prison guards male have prisons
this man is an alien he's not a
conservative he's an alien he and Ronald
Reagan both they are willing to imprison
a whole generation of people to keep
intact the petro chemical and
pharmaceutical monopolies in this
country which he's well vested in each
point and I think he's a vampire I don't
think he's an American I think he's a
vampire willing to suck the life out all
those victims or remain entire Foreman
in a fire for position but let me take
this opportunity right here wherever
this gets shown limitation I am pleased
and honored to be in presence that one
was brave man in the United sterile this
gentleman that I had his author Emperor
wears no clothes and so much more than
just an author researcher and a
dedicated diligent activist and a man
who I know for a fact is responsible for
tens of thousands of people just kind
being able to come out of the closet
stand up out of the darkness to stand up
out of oppression and despair and lives
of quiet desperation and be able to
point to the source of knowledge and the
truth and the point of light that this
man right here is personally responsible
for putting together I would not be
where I am today were it not for Jack
hair and I know that a lot of people
would not be walking tall with dignity
of a sense of pride in a sense that they
do no wrong by communicating with mother
earth through the earth and in other
fashions and this man right here is
responsible for as much of it as I know
what I'm sure the people deserve credit
to a belt amount but this man right here
is one of the most brave people in the
United States today and I hope someday
that this country people when it will
reward you appropriately what he's done
for freedom and individuality and civil
liberties and mother earth in this
country I want to take it up to the
right now oh that mean does that mean I
just regress for us my life as you know
I was going
let me show you something you can take
back in right-handed better photos this
is mr. Henry Ford in 1941 with popular
mechanics magazine showing off his car
made from hemp all is that when the
whole car itself with me and you and it
says so right there a popular mechanics
1941 is that nice one more deal in the
car that's an irritation never notice
like oh man that is that is that
everybody else is not the case of a
blind hog snuff now anchored here once a
while eh the elegance you know I think
Edison Edison said the genius is one
percent inspiration and ninety-nine
percent perspiration who was man right
eaters readies national oh yes yeah he
certainly has well I'll tell a lot of
the features okay this may I wrote a
book that i read that was one of the
really in Michael Aldridge and written
some of the greatest work on him long
before I really understood half though
he wrote in 77 it contains Asia utterly
and i am the Kentucky Yahoo's marijuana
peacebuilders to tell you a new job
here's my adolescent that man and the
perspectives you two he is not some of
you needs to come to me to learn about
him I learned a lot of my him from him
born in Jack make you crazy they know
marijuana does not need you to crime
they know marijuana does not lead you to
harder drugs but marijuana is a system
of control that they can exercise over
you because you step out of line from
their corporate policies this is the
million marijuana market and today there
are demonstrations just like this in
every major city across the world I
think that the laws against marijuana
are the most vivid illustration of where
this government's overstepped its bounds
in policing private behavior the
petrochemical pharmaceutical
military-industrial complex as utilized
the lawmaking powers of Congress to get
through legislation which is
criminalized the farmer who's gone into
competition with these synthetic
manufacturers hint is the number 15
we're the number one fuel the number one
food and number one medicine so the laws
against marijuana are the most important
step that this government special
interest have put together and put on
two people to remove them from the
natural cycle of things
we smoked pot no pot no pot unless
people actually get out in the streets
and actually demonstrate and actually
push the envelope this first amendment
has no life I've been to these things
when we had a 50 people I've been Adam
when we had 20,000 and I'm always
empowered by seeing one person stand up
and try to give life and vibrancy and
existence to the bill of rights in the
society we live in a police state
there's no doubt about it you can lead
this demonstration and don't get in your
car and get out on the road and they can
set up a random road block in front of
you and make you get out of your car
bring up a dog listen if you your car
and all its belongings take blood out of
yarn make your pee in a bottle and they
think you got something that is a police
state I'm going to live in a police
state our fathers and our grandfathers
did not fight and die on the beaches of
Normandy me won't Eva so that you would
have to pee in a cup holder job in
America there is a peaceful solution
call these realm
now let's take back America there's war
and we're in know we can win so let's
take mine
I was a dream so we'll either and you're
ready to receive it now let's take back
having come when the war is over and we
want let's remember how we do this so we
don't have to do it again better get
some people solution aunties
now let's shake
you
pardon me I don't think marijuana was a
problem back in 1937 it certainly wasn't
a problem is certainly not a problem
today and it's all over the place so I
don't know how I could possibly been a
problem in 1937 except for the fact that
when they passed that law for the first
time federal government took over the
right to tell you what seed you could
plant in the ground and what you could
do with the product of that see then put
it like this some people who don't know
me give me a reputation for wearing to
legalize drugs I do not want to do that
I'm in the business of trying to license
and regulate cannabis as a crop tomatoes
are legal alcohol and tobacco is
licensed and regulated and I've seek to
license and regulate take it out of the
black market status just cannabis now I
would take the law enforcement dollar
which we would save of the currently
recurrently spending on detecting
arresting prosecuting and incarcerating
people who associated with cannabis
plant if we change laws we'd save all
that money I would go after the hard
drugs I'd go after the synthetic drugs
to crack the cocaine heroin those kinds
of synthetic drugs man-made drugs which
destroy the spirit and overcome rights
of determination and self choice because
they're addictive and destructive to the
body but the most insidious is the
prescription medicines courage there are
pharmaceutical medicines as and their
impact on society and paralyzed entire
portions of Kentucky including vast
regions of Easter
which have no economy and Admiral jobs
and are the main sources for illicit
oxycontin or settle or tavern and these
pharmaceutical companies are out there
spending billions of dollars encouraging
as many people as they can to take this
poison and they know that it is
addictive and they know that's a huge
black market that builds up around
people's necessity of continuing to take
this addictive medicine with their
doctor stops their treatment so there is
a big black market up there and the
pharmaceutical companies are unaware of
it professed an opinion tablet they
could create oxycontin so you can't
crush enough extorting so they're aware
of this and that they didn't do that
this talk because they didn't want say
pretending to happen but some because
they do is they had a big addiction
situation and they're going to sell it
out long locks continent if ever I was
addicted to it
I'm the question of him the question of
cannabis is the most vivid illustration
of how this government has overstepped
its bounds in policing the private
behavior citizen when they told us we
couldn't plan an empty tin the ground
they favoured us from the natural cycle
and is what they seek to do i call it
the synthetic version or they want to
replace all the natural products on
earth they used to be grown out of God's
earth 'god seed and replace them with
synthetic products and knock down farmer
out of the agreement society in the
grant market and they do go south of our
small cities and villages across this
country we need to rediscover a cash
crop yeah one day we don't have our
farmers go back to the land one day a
little high our farmers to compete with
the petrochemical pipelines you plant us
seven percent agricultural land in it
you wouldn't have to import another drop
of oil we can replace the spills in the
Gulf we can replace the environmental
catastrophe that the petroleum pipelines
that gas squad mother earth understand
let our farmers grow in and they do crop
in 1991 Willie Nelson I port if only to
my Mercedes diesel and throw it across
Kentucky and my bid for governor that's
why he cited biofuel prayer visit folks
you all have been handed a George jack
herer blessing so passed away I'm
getting old up here you know we cannot
make it so much longer you have to
become educated you have to learn the
truth you have to reach out there and
grab the responsibility of maintaining
your freedom every generation must
remain its own freedoms and those very
sacrifices right up to the very last
second I've been talking to you made on
your behalf cannot continue anymore what
really counts is your old commit
it there what sacrifices you're willing
to make in the future to maintain your
freedom it is right there in front of
you I encourage you I encourage you to
learn to law encourages upon the
political process I encourage you to
reach out there take responsibility your
own freedom live your life like a
warrior god bless you all thanks for
having me out here Deanna
hey this is Willie and you're going to
be voting for a governor in your state
kentucky pretty quick so think about gig
would galbraith because he's my friend
I'm knowing a long time he and I believe
the same way about a whole lot of things
and I think you believe a lot of the
same things that he does so hear him out
Gatewood forgot thank
I met gate when I was very impressed by
him you know we both loved cannabis and
we would smoke out at the normal
conferences together for a few years but
in 1990 not September he called me and
said willie nelson wants to meet you so
I hung out with Willie and we got him
some herb and he would have me roll
joints about every 45 minutes a roll
another one Paul roll another one Paul
and so I did then he invited me to come
back to Kentucky in October that this
guy gate what gah breath was running for
governor so I flew back to Lexington
Kentucky and had a press conference
there with Willie Nelson and Gatewood
gah breath in then they drove gate woods
red mercedes benz station wagon powered
entirely on hemp seed oil they took
pressed hemp seed oil discovered that it
can be used as a diesel fuel they poured
it right into the engine were able to
drive from Lexington about 50 miles to
the State Capitol in Frankfort we
stopped at the State Capitol the
Kentucky legislators went crazy over
Willie Nelson and we drove on about
another 80 miles on to Louisville
Kentucky and Willie Nelson did a benefit
that night in Louisville Kentucky we'd
always heard that Rudolf diesel with
manufactured his diesel engine run off
seed oil we really didn't understand
quite grasp that this was in the early
90s late 80s and then the fella from
Nevada Las Vegas Nevada came through
town driving a little Volkswagen diesel
and he's running adult Burger King oil
and so we had just derived some hip or a
lot of hemp seeds hemp seeds are thirty
to forty percent oil by weight you got
to underground temp seeds you can drive
30 to 40 pounds of pure oil out of it
and so we had some of that and he tested
to the doubt in his engine and he says
this is the best seed or that I've ever
driven this car on and so we had seed or
when Willie came in to do it
fit concert for me we poured that in
foil into my Mercedes diesel and drove
at about 110 miles across Kentucky and
it was the first time in I guess 50 to
60 years that didn't vehicle there have
been driven on it boil on the United
States roads but Willie told me later on
the 12 years later actually no I mean
about ten years later he says gate woods
he says that afternoon we did that as it
taught me what it was all about and
that's the reason I started my bio fuel
company was from what we learned that
afternoon driving your Mercedes across
there and we also spoken about the
biggest Hooters probably road in
Kentucky at the time and there was a
caravan of us we went from the hyatt
there and rough auditorium through
Frankfurt the state capital is about 80
miles and then altogether 120 miles all
the way into Louisville which is largest
city in Kentucky and then he did a big
benefit concert for you there that night
that's right you know we need we need
help in health care of camp as a cash
crop out there for the petroleum
purposes now you get twenty two barrels
of petroleum off an acre of hemp when
you grow cannabis in an industrial
textile direction our farmers need that
niche in the energy market and that
would furnish according to state
calculations sixty-eight thousand new
jobs for seed hemp is planted in hills
like corn sometimes by hand empezar
dioecious plant the female flower is
inconspicuous but the male flower is
easily spotted in seed production after
the pollen has been shed these male
plants are cut out these are the seeds
on a female plant
tempra fiber is ready to harvest when
the pollen is shedding and the leaves
are falling in Kentucky hemp harvest
comes in August here the old standby has
been the self r a creeper which has been
used for a generation or more
hemp grosso luxuriantly in Kentucky that
harvesting is sometimes difficult which
may account for the popularity of the
self rake with its lateral stroke in
Kentucky hemp is shocked as soon as safe
after cutting to be spread out for
reffing later in the fall
my god
walk out
just so heartening to see the the
progress that you know of course
proposition 215 in California 96 and
what you folks have done here in Oregon
I mean it's just it's just fuel my fire
to see you all actually succeed it's
something I've been trying to do in
Kentucky for many field for 40 years we
need to lift Kentucky out of poverty is
one of the most poverty-ridden states in
the country we find 47 48 49 and 50th
and all the standard living in Texas our
children are poor we're broke bankrupt
we can't fund the retirement for our
teachers or public employees that we
need to find rediscover something that
will generate some money in state of
course we were the world's largest
producer of cannabis for over 100 years
and so you know I want to go back and
touch on the history and heritage of the
state and get us to return to cannabis
as a cash crop hey we're the first a
decent Mississippi to actually license
and regulate the hell out of it we will
live Kentucky out of poverty I'll fill
every hotel room and motel room at state
seven nights a week Saracen boom walnut
these won't be people come in there and
drink whiskey and punch holes in your
walls these people come in and sit down
row 1 and order room service the United
States Constitution does not provide you
the right to life liberty and pursuit of
happiness that's in Independence
Declaration of Independence that's not
law so you don't officially have a right
to that under federal law but Kentucky
has a constitutional so just like all
the other states do but just so happens
that Kentucky's Constitution is the most
pro-people Constitution ever written
that I our people back in night 1890 got
so tired of being raped by the railroad
companies that they wrote a constitution
that protected the people and kept
corporations from being running
roughshod over everybody and even now
that's beginning to fracture as our
legislature keeps selling out to it to
the earth to the folks that i call the
petrochemical pharmaceutical
military-industrial transnational
corporate fascist to meet some of a
[ __ ]
so what's going to happen is that the
very first section of Kentucky's
Constitution ensures that its citizens
constitutionally are endowed with the
right to life liberty and the pursuit of
happiness as the number one section in
Kentucky Constitution so I feel obliged
to make it the number one basis the
policy for my relationship of government
to the people in state of Kentucky I'm
going to get it off of their bikes I'm
going to take it out of the bedrooms and
the blood streams and then brains and
bladders the bill folks in fact pockets
the internet bulletin boards have put
them back in the little box where they
belong I'm going to make government not
a burden on the people i think it's the
role of government to uplift enlighten
educate and endow people with an
appreciation of life appreciation as a
social compact their civil duties there
are civil responsibilities and make sure
that we address them as sovereign human
beings capable making their own
decisions and we're going to get medical
marijuana in the hands of every sick and
dying person in the state of Kentucky no
permit needed I'm going to take it out
of the hands of the 10 and 13 and 14
year olds you're doing it just for kicks
we could give them over to the old age
homes to all the old old old folks in
the old a jones hey increase the
appetite put a smile on their face and
think about the increased vegetation by
the young folks hey let's go see Dad
okay folks here we are standing on the
corner of a Manowar and Versailles Road
it's Keeneland
a lot of traffic on those going to our
large amount of traffic coming through
this intersection I've got a sign here
them holding up you can fix a sign of
your own we'd like you to get signed
buzz but if we can't get you one make
your own sign make sure it says Gatewood
governor independent you stand on the
corner you get traffic coming one way
with the light changes you turn around
and you can trap it going the other way
and Fisk is made people's can't see that
image Gatewood governor independent I've
been out on quarters like this for about
25 years started at four grand for a mr.
banco through an 83 i started doing it
at that time because they 128 years
give up its way with material
it's a dream so believe in and get ready
to receive it now let's take my America
the war is over we wanted let's remember
how are we done it so you don't have to
do it I'm escaping delrin i'm an
independent candidate for governor we
don't want a political party my running
mate nah hey dear if you're gonna use
your outside boys over and join the
other children over on the playground
we're trying to get some serious
conversation going on here okay so you
go with the other kids over there you
know people say galvers you're a
perennial candidate that's what
kentucky's got perennial problems if the
people would beat me the first time and
solve the problems I wouldn't I had to
run again but they didn't and they have
it and they can't because neither party
can produce a candidate that can
disengage from the partisanship long
left work with the other side to
actually get the job done the leadership
of both parties had their horns locked
up like to whitetail buck fighting over
territory while our business lays dead
in the gust and and both of the parties
are the blame for what we've got here
neither party has presented any
solutions to it dee and I are not asking
you to vote against your party or vote
for the other dreaded party we're asking
you to vote for an independent governor
who does not care who gets credit for
doing what's right for the people if
you're a democrat or republican or an
independent if you've got a solution to
Kentucky's problems you can come to
Kentucky their governor's office where
we stand and we will do our best and we
will give you all the credit for it and
you come up with a good idea mr.
Williams had a great idea the other day
and I complimented him on it and I said
David I said when I'm governor and
you're President and Senate we're going
to put that idea true but you know folks
I got to tell you mr. Williams can't win
this election mr. Wynn's cannot win this
election
I'm sorry to say I'm start saying well
ma'am listen isn't one for an extremely
good mama and if ready daddy bill
maximum security prison I got wrong a
really long time ago so my mom is
probably kept me on straight narrow more
than ideal but uh when I uh as i got
older i became desperate for role models
and so I looked for the people glob dogs
just the right things there are five so
I decided quite frankly be one of you I
decide to just decide you need the new
hero and there's a reason for why
shouldn't be it right
gatewood supported our initiative drive
did so very publicly he be very happy to
see the turn of events since then but he
was an amazing speaker and one of my
mentors yeah your friends course we
don't like it just hush up about we
watched him run nine races in 29 years
and every time this is the most
efficient vote bidding process in the
world it was classic Gatewood I knew
there if they have he ran for Congress
back to back in two thousand get a
photographer in two thousand two argued
he said he was done after the 2002
election but there he was the next year
running for attorney general literally I
was drafted into this race Gateway was a
sound byte machine thank you brother
percentage of brands out there I'll
never forget that early May Day I spent
with him in 2007 while he was running in
the Democratic primary for governor
thank you dear i love you all to a
street corner charmer Kentucky's gonna
be a fun place to live and I'm governor
who raised Kentucky's conscious you know
we cannot have it
the partisanship is killing me engaging
and intelligent but also right here just
lucky enough to never be taken seriously
by the mainstream this was the time he
was arrested during Lexington's fourth
of July parade
yes he was an independent cuss the gate
wooden hours because they're down this
way chose Kentucky will miss you
you