when I'm watching the Super Bowl and I
see that uh uh they're saying people
like me are in addition to like mowing
the lawn and having some nachos also
murdered a family in
Colombia I I take offense to that who
else takes offense to
that I did not murder a family in
Columbia and it is the people that are
propagating those EDS that are
responsible and they're going to keep on
they're going to be I can't even imagine
how many families are going to die
because of our drug war in
columia War on Drugs give me a break man
attention drug war generals out there we
are fighting back man and unlike
you unlike you drug war generals we are
nonviolent we are peaceful you cannot
and will not stop us because we are not
criminals we are Americans we're going
to make that mean something and we're
about to take our country back and put
it in the hands of the people who
founded this country the hands of the
people whose blood and sweat and tears
and backs paav the way for us to be here
today the problem is that in our justice
system we've got too much emphasis on
the system and not enough emphasis on
the justice and I ain't going to make it
man that's exactly why we're here today
at Seattle hempest that's why you came
out and we'll be vocal day after day
after day year after year after year
until we've overcome and Justice finally
prevails