well you inspired so many people with
your book which you know is uh you know
you had a book first no on raing
cannabis right yes and that was like a
judging years before high times two
years before High Times Like 1970 or so
or 73
73 okay and then when I first met you
there was a I'd seen an article in the
yippy newspaper overthrow called the CMI
white paper and that was kind of about
three pages long and laid out kind of
the gist of what was the outline of your
future book The Emperor where was um
what's name uh what's uh the guy from
New York Dana yes he took them for
himself he said oh that's a wonderful
information I should have
it put it in overthrow is that how that
got published there and
I I got really bad you got mad at for
that well I think you he deserved it few
people did I know that uh then in ' 85
you wrote the first edition of your book
right here in Portland in River City and
it was H for a while it was the CMI Omi
white paper the California marijuana
initiative the Oregon marijuana
initiative and the first few editions
were like newsprint editions they were
handed out right the first first edition
and the second edition
were 110 page book uhhuh the third and
fourth edition that got 990,000 copies
for the campaign for the organ marijuana
initiative in 86 and that was a
newspaper yeah yeah I remember every
neighborhood they handed those out in I
think Omi W that was one of the every
and it only one
cities and what do they call precincts
yeah 15 PR those were the ones and those
were the it's handed out twice and three
times and four times it got handed out
MH because the guys
were
they
90,000 people and about
30 of them 30,000 of them got once twice
three times and four times we One Knows
by 60 or
70% right so how many copies have been
sold now and how many languages is your
book The Emperor wears no clothes
printed
in there was a number one seller in 100
magazines uhhuh and it's in about 600
700 50,000 copies in the United States
and about 500 or
600,000 copies overseas overseas a lot
of and then there is about 10 or 15
companies Japan
Korea uh
Hungary
uh uh
Czechoslovakia Poland Russia so it's in
all these different languages they pay
me uh well I guess your uh your
copyright's only as good as your ability
to enforce it