Hi, my name is Jack Herb from an
organization called Hemp and uh which
has helped eliminate or end marijuana
prohibition.
We're going to show you a movie called
Hemp for Victory that was made by the
United States Department of Agriculture
in 1942 for encouraging the war effort
to grow 350,000 acres of cannabis of
hemp of marijuana cannabis sativa over
the next each year for the next three
years for the war. More than they had
grown in the preceding 50 years in the
United States combined, mostly importing
their hemp from uh the Far East and
Russia.
While this movie is on, you may not
realize that hemp was the most important
product in America and in the world. For
thousands of years, all commerce was
carried by hemp and sales. Indeed, the
word canvas, as you'll see in the movie,
comes from the Arabic word and the Dutch
word for uh hemp, which is canvas.
Canvas is a Dutch pronunciation of
cannabis.
the movie you're about to see. For the
last 20 years, the United States
government says that no such movie was
ever made by any department of the
United States
government. that um we know that from at
least 1981 on that reporters for
magazines, newspapers have been told and
you'll see a you'll see actual letters
denying that this movie was ever made by
any department of the United States
Department of Agriculture or by any
department of the government.
uh Carl Packard, Maria Pharaoh and
myself, Jack her uh after going all
through
the US Department of Agriculture Library
of Beltsville, Maryland in the May uh
April and May of 1989.
went to the Library of Congress, motion
pictures and film strips to see if we
could find any documentation that this
movie that the newspapers were telling
me that I was they couldn't run as being
affirmed by the government that the
government said that they'd never made
this movie that I was showing to
television reporters and there were
other people activists all over the
country who were showing this movie and
were being told that this movie was
never made by the United States
government.
Uh Carl Marie and I went into the
Library of Congress through the motion
pictures and film strips and we did a
search with their librarians as we had
done at the Department of Agriculture
Library in
Beltzville. And we found no trace of
this movie in their electronic searches,
in their cataloges or in any of their
card files. And we were convinced that
even though we believed the movie was
totally genuine, that there was no
record and that these people weren't
deliberately lying, they just didn't
have somehow somewhere it had been
omitted. Finally, as we were about to
leave the building after leaving the the
room where the film strips and motion
pictures were
housed, we thought, well, well, let's go
back and give it another try. And we
asked the Mrs. Katherine Longby, I
believe her name is the librarian, to
assist us again. And we said, "What if
we had come here 30 or 40?" We didn't
really know what we were going to say
when we got back into that room. We
said, "What if we had come here 30 or 40
years
ago and in the 1940s or 50s and asked
for the movie Hemp for Victory?" You
would have gone to the electronic
searches or the current cataloges or any
of the other things that you've used
today, the card cataloges to file. Where
where would those cataloges be? Do you
throw them away? And she said, "No,
they're over by the copier. you keep all
the old cataloges and you can go over
there and look. But um if they would
have been here, they would have showed
up on the if it would have been in any
of those books, it would have shown up
already today in our searches. Now, I'd
like to show you a typical letter that
was sent out denying that this movie was
made by the United States Department of
Agriculture or any other division of the
United States government. Listen to it.
To Mr. Jim Evans, dear Mr. Evans. This
is now this is from the United States
Department of Agriculture, the Oregon
State Office uh from John Val Calcar,
the information
officer. Dear Mr. Evans, we contacted
the Washington DC office of the
Department of Agriculture and also the
federal audio center and and have been
unable to locate any film with the title
Hemp for Victory that was produced by
any department of the federal
government.
Now you're reading the certification by
the photo duplication service from the
chief of photo duplication service of
the library of congress and it said that
there is now in the collections of the
library congress a publication entitled
the national union catalog volume 28
motion pictures and film strips 1953
through
1957. I further certify that the
attached photo copies are true copies of
title page and page
367. And in testimony whereof, I hear
unto subscribe my name and cause my seal
the Library of Congress to be affixed,
which you can see. Ladies and
gentlemen, next you see the front page,
the National Union Catalog, the uh title
page,
1953-57, volume 28, where we
discovered hemp for victory. Motion
picture, US Department of Agriculture,
1942, 14 minutes, black and white, 16
millimeter. And then summary explains
that the war cut off the supply of East
Indian coarse fibers and stresses the
need for American grown hemp for
military and civilian uses. Portrays
foreign practices of hemp growers in
Kentucky and Wisconsin. And this went
out to um in supposedly into the
archives under hemp US also to the US
Department of Agriculture. They give you
their number there. US Office of
Education and Visual Education Service.
All of which this disappeared from.
Next, we have the certification from the
same chief of photoduplication service
of the library congress that there's now
in the collections of the library
congress publication entitled
educational film guide annual edition
1945. I further certified that the
attached photocopies are two copies of
the title page, the reverse title page
and page 331.
in testimony whereof I here unto
subscribe my name and cause the seal of
the Library of Congress to be affixed
this 12th of July
1989. And now as you can see on page
331 under
677.7 hemp twine and knots is hemp for
victory 14 minute 16
mm and um it says here a USDA production
shows how the war cut off our supply of
East Indian coarse fibers and the urgent
need for American grown hemp for our
army and navy as well as civilian use.
portrays farm practices of hemp growers
in Kentucky and
Wisconsin. The proof now is that this
movie does really
exist. Now, the government for years
have been telling all of our media that
this movie didn't exist and all of our
activists were
being impuged on their integrity. We
think uh let the movie speak for itself.
You'll please watch all 14 minutes of
this film because it every bit of it is
memorable. Right up to when you see the
parachute webbing that George Bush
jumped out of the over the Pacific with
was made out of marijuana that saved the
poor boy's life.
[Music]
Long ago, when these ancient Grecian
temples were new, hemp was already old
in the service of mankind.
For thousands of years, even then, this
plant had been grown for cordage and
coarse cloth in China and elsewhere in
the
east. For centuries prior to about 1850,
all the ships that sailed the western
seas were rigged with hemp and rope and
sails. For the sailor, no less than the
hangman, hemp was indispensable.
A 44 gun frigot, like our cherished old
iron sides, took over 60 tons of hemp
for
rigging, including an anchor cable 25 in
in
[Music]
circumference. The Konos Stoga wagons
and prayer schooners of pioneer days
were covered with hemp and canvas.
Indeed, the very word canvas comes from
the Arabic word for
hemp. In those days, hemp was an
important crop in Kentucky and
Missouri. Then came cheaper imported
fibers for cottage like jute, cy, and
manila hemp, and the culture of hemp in
America declined.
But now with Philippine and East Indian
sources of hemp in the hands of the
Japanese and shipment of juke from India
curtailed, American hemp must meet the
needs of our army and navy as well as of
our industries. In 1942, patriotic
farmers at the government's request
planted 36,000 acres of seed hemp, an
increase of several thousand%. The goal
for 1943 is 50,000 acres of seed
hemp. In Kentucky, much of the seed hemp
acorage is on river bottom land such as
this along the Kentucky River Gorge.
Some of these fields are inaccessible
except by
boat. Thus, plans are a foot for a great
expansion of the hemp industry as a part
of the war program. This film is
designed to tell farmers how to handle
this ancient crop now little known
outside Kentucky and Wisconsin. This is
hemp seed. Be careful how you use it.
For to grow hemp legally, you must have
a federal registration and tax stamp.
This is provided for in your contract.
Ask your AAA committeeman or your county
agent about it. Don't
forget, hemp demands a rich, well-
drained soil such as is found here in
the bluegrass region of Kentucky or in
central Wisconsin.
[Music]
It must be loose and rich in organic
matter. Poor soils won't
do. Soil that will grow good corn will
usually grow
hemp. Hemp is not hard on the soil. In
Kentucky, it has been grown for several
years on the same ground, though this
practice is not
recommended. A dense and shady crop,
hemp tends to choke out
weeds. Here's a Canada thistle that
couldn't stand the
competition. Dead as a dodo. Thus, hemp
leaves the ground in good condition for
the following
crop. For fiber, hemp should be sewn
five pecks to the acre. With drill, the
closer the rows, the better. These rows
are spaced about 4
in. This hemp has been broadcast. Either
way, it should be sewn thick enough to
grow a slender
stalk.
Here's an ideal stand. The right height
to be harvested easily, thick enough to
grow slender stalks that are easier to
cut and
process. Stalks like these here on the
left, they yield the most fiber and the
best. Those on the right are too coarse
and
woody. For seed, hemp is planted in
hills like corn, sometimes by hand.
Hemp is a dishious plant. The female
flower is inconspicuous, but the male
flower is easily spotted. In seed
production, after the pollen has been
shed, these male plants are cut
out. These are the seeds on a female
plant. Hemp for fiber is ready to
harvest when the pollen is shedding and
the leaves are falling. In Kentucky,
hemp harvest comes in August. Here the
old standby has been the self-rake
reaper which has been used for a
generation or
more. Hemp grows so luxurantly in
Kentucky that harvesting is sometimes
difficult which may account for the
popularity of the self rake with its
lateral
stroke. A modified rice binder has been
used to some extent. This machine works
well in average
[Music]
hemp. Recently, the improved hemp
harvester used for many years in
Wisconsin has been introduced in
Kentucky. This machine spreads the hemp
in a continuous swave. It is a far cry
from this fast and efficient modern
harvester to the Armstrong model of
Yore. But here's one kind of harvester,
at least that doesn't stall in the
heaviest hemp.
In Kentucky, hand cutting is practiced
in opening fields for the machines.
In Kentucky, hemp is shocked as soon as
safe after cutting to be spread out for
ringing later in the
[Music]
fall. In Wisconsin, hemp is harvested in
September. Here the hemp harvester with
automatic spreader is standard
equipment. Note how smoothly the
rotating apron lays the swave
preparatory to wetting. Here it is a
common and essential practice to leave
headlands around hemp fields. These
strips may be planted to other crops,
preferably small grain. Thus the
harvester has room to make its first
round without preparatory hand cutting.
Here the machine is running over corn
stubble.
When the cutter bar is much shorter than
the hemp is tall, overlapping occurs.
Not so good for reading. The standard
cut is 8 to 9
ft. The length of time hemp is left on
the ground to rest depends on the
weather. The swave must be turned to get
a uniform rest.
[Music]
When the woody core breaks away readily
like this, the hemp is about ready to
take up and bind into
bundles. Well-rtted hemp is light to
dark gray. The fiber tends to pull away
from the stalk. The presence of stalks
in the bow string stage indicates that
retting is well underway.
[Music]
When hemp is short or tangled or when
the ground is too wet for machine, it is
bound by hand. A wooden buck is used.
Twine will do for tying, but the hemp
itself makes a good
[Music]
band. When conditions are favorable, the
pickup bander is commonly used. The
swath should last smooth and even with
stalks parallel. The picker won't work
well in tangled
hemp. After branding, hemp is shocked as
soon as possible to stop further
ringing. In 1942, 14,000 acres of fiber
hemp were harvested in the United
States. The goal for 1943 is 300,000
acres. Thus, hemp cannabis attra the old
standby cordage fiber is staging a
strong comeback. This is Kentucky hemp
going into the dryer of a mill at
[Music]
Versailles. In the old days, breaking
was done by hand. One of the hardest
jobs known to
[Music]
man. Now the power breaker makes quick
work of it.
[Music]
spinning American hemp into rope yarn or
twine in the old Kentucky River Mill at
Frankfurt,
Kentucky.
Another pioneer plant that has been
making cordage for more than a century.
[Music]
All such plants will presently be
turning out products spun from American
grown
hemp. Twine of various kinds for tying
winding armatures and upholsterers
work. Rope for marine rigging and towing
for hay forks, der and heavy duty
tackle. Light duty fire
hose. Thread for shoes for millions of
American
soldiers and parachute webbing for our
paratroopers.
[Music]
As for the United States Navy, every
battleship requires 34,000 ft of rope
and other craft accordingly. So, here in
the Boston Navyyard, where cables for
frigots were made long ago, crews are
now working night and day making cordage
for the
fleet. In the old days, rope yarn was
spun by hand.
[Music]
Today even the rope walk is
mechanized. 160 fathoms to
[Music]
go. The rope yarn feeds through holes in
an iron plate.
[Music]
This is Manila hemp from the Navy's
rapidly dwindling reserve. When that is
gone, American hemp will go on duty
again. Hemp for moing ships, hemp for
toll lines.
[Music]
Hemp for tackle and gear. Hemp for
countless naval uses both on ship and
shore.
Just as in the days when old Ironside
sailed the seas
victorious with her hemp shrouds and
hemp
[Music]
sail hemp for victory.
I received a letter of vital importance
from a member of the narcotics bureau.
I'm going to read this letter to
you. My dear Dr. Carol, the suppression
of the use of marijuana and of the
forces lurking behind it are the most
important jobs this department is now
engaged in. At the outset of this
letter, there is one vital fact I would
like to submit. There is a powerful
agency. I speak of the school parent
associations of this country which can
be invaluable in stamping up this
scourge. Their help, their eternal
vigilance could be the deciding factor
in our fight against it. The weed
marijuana is grown in every state in the
union. Recently in the city of Brooklyn,
New
York, a field of marijuana was found
behind a tenement court. The weed was
here being cultivated, regularly
stripped and dried and sold in schools
and at government army posts in and
around New
York. The dried leaves and berries are
ground up and made into cigarettes by a
simple hand machine. The deadly narcotic
is thus quickly and easily prepared for
its
market. The sale of marijuana is even
more difficult to detect and halt than
the traffic in drugs such as opium,
morphine, and
heroin. They are hidden in fake jewelry
cases, in the heels of shoes, women's
shoes especially, because the drugs can
be secreted in false heels.
Hollow shavenishes are another medium.
Books with false centers are often used.
Watch cases are convenient hiding
places. The value of drugs thus seized
is enormous. Recently, a huge supply of
heroin was taken. It was concealed in an
apparently harmless shipment of 35
barrels of olive oil. The deadly drug
was burned in the incinerator of the
Bureau of Engraving and Printing. And
more vicious, more deadly even than
these so destroying drugs is the menace
of
marijuana. No doubt many of you do not
believe that these things do happen, but
they cannot happen to you. You may also
believe that the facts have been
exaggerated.
Let me tell you what. The Library of
Congress
themselves has accepted these
movies or has recommended acceptance as
you can see in the
letter from the assistant chief of the
MBRS division gift to video cassettes.
His name is Paul C. Spear S PR.
And uh he says two half-inch video
cassettes were brought to the MBE RS
division. On Friday, May 19th, 1989,
their bearer Jack Herror Hemp Pack,
California Marijuana Initiative, Van
Eyes, California of the Help Eliminate
Marijuana Prohibition Hemp Pack
Political Action Committee wishes to
donate the tapes to the libraries
collections. He spoke with Mrs.
Katherine Long. The tapes are duplicate.
Each contains the following hemp. Hemp
for victory produced in 1942 by the
United States Department of Agriculture
14 minutes and reefer madness excerpts
produced in 1936 originally 167 minutes
but this material is excerpts only. I
recommend that we accept them and that's
from Paul C. Spears assistant chief of
that gift division of the motion
pictures and film strips.
Now, I'd like to ask you to
send $20 to the Help Eliminate Marijuana
Prohibition Hemp Pack, 5632 Vanise
Boulevard, Vanise, California, sweet
210, zip 91401, Van Eis, California. Our
phone number is
8183775886. And we'd like you to know
that we'll send you a copy of Hemp for
Victory with all the documentation you
just saw, as well as a copy of the book,
The Emperor Wears No Clothes. And please
use this information. Send away for more
of this information. If you'd like one
of our t-shirts, they're
$12. They're the Hemp for Victory
T-shirt. And um we have new t-shirts
coming out all the time. What we want
you to do is support normal, support
hemp, and get this information around.
Uh we're really a grassroots
organization. But we have one big
message, and that is that your
government, for whatever its reasons,
lied about the number one product
probably on earth for paper, fiber,
fuel, and food. Whether it did it at a
conscious level or unconscious level,
they've been sending people hundreds and
hundreds of thousands to prison and
taking away their their
properties, their children, their cars
for
marijuana. that in any sane society they
would reward people for using in
comparison to alcohol and tobacco.
The national drug control strategy
proposed by President Bush and Drugs R.
Bennett isn't worth the environmentally
disastrous and unnecessary sulfuric acid
and dioxin laced wood pulp processed
paper which it is printed on.
Specifically, the continued prohibition
of hemp marijuana cultivation prevents
our society from utilizing nature's
premier renewable resource for the
majority of Earth's paper, fiber, fuel,
food, paint, and medicine. Ironically,
at the time of George Washington, he and
all American farmers were required to
grow and could even pay their taxes with
hemp. Why? Because hemp was the used for
the majority of colonial Americas in the
world's paper, clothing, towels,
diapers, lace, sales, canvas, Dutch
pronunciation of cannabis, rope, paint,
varnish, lighting oil, and more. In
fact, as recently as World War II, with
Philippine and Asian hemp cut off by the
Japanese, the US Department of
Agriculture in 1942 produced a 14minute
black and white film, Hemp for Victory,
encouraging and instructing patriotic
American farmers to grow 350,000 acres
of hemp per year by 1943 to be used for
civilian and military shoes, rope, fire
hoses. Even the parachute webbing that
George Bush held on to when he bailed
out over the Pacific was made from
cannabis hemp. Hemp uses the sun more
efficiently than virtually any other
plant on our planet. In fact, on a
planetwide, climatewide, and soilwide
basis, hemp grown annually would produce
approximately 40 times the biomass that
is living organic matter of the next
best annual rival biomass crops that be
can grown on Earth, such as corn, kunaf,
and sugarcane.
Today, we have the ability and the
mechanized technology to use hemp
biomass and other biomasses for energy
farming and produce all of the
clean renewable fuel we would need for
all of our
cars, homes, and industry with a net
reduction of carbon
dioxide. Theoretical computer models
have shown that reversing the greenhouse
effect will only be possible, if
possible at all. If hemp and other
biomass waste are used again as they
were until 130 years ago for making the
overall majority of Earth's paper,
fiber, fuels, paints, varnish, and now
everything from plastics to dynamite. As
for
marijuana, the blossom of the hemp
plant, US government clinical studies,
as well as studies of the Jamaican,
Costa Rican, and Greek marijuana using
populations, indicate statistically that
you will live more than a year longer if
you smoke marijuana every day than if
you use no drugs at all and 8 to 24
years longer than regular tobacco and
alcohol users. In 1987, US government
statistics reported 395,000 Americans
died from tobacco. 87% of all lung
cancer cases were caused by tobacco use.
Also, the National Institute of Drug
Abuse, that's NIA, reports 125,000
Americans died in 1987 from alcohol use.
That same agency and the Surgeon
General's mortality statistics report
zero Zero deaths ever due to marijuana.
And as of October 1988, no case of lung
cancer has ever been attributed solely
to marijuana
use. Therefore, we at Hemp are seeking a
marijuana hemp armistice. That is an
immediate nationwide moratorum on the
personal medical and industrial
suppression of hemp. and for the
president and congress to immediately
appoint a hemp advisory commission to
oversee and expedite reintroduction of
hemp to American agriculture, business
and medicine.
Our justifications for this moratorium
commission are that with few exceptions,
none of the American public, especially
our politicians who should have known
when they made these laws, the judges
who should have known when they enforced
them, and the police and even the
teachers who should have taught them and
all the rest of us in the first place,
knew virtually any of the preceding
history, facts, information, or the vast
potential of hemp as Earth's premier
natural renewal. able resource biomass
and life
extender. If I have to go to jail for
fighting for that or give of any other
part or you should, you should be proud
to. I mean, such a sweet thing as
marijuana to go to jail for put there by
people that don't even know this
information. Haven't the foggiest idea.
And yet chemicals,
petrochemicals, fossil fuels are totally
legal. and hemp. One of the greatest
things that we, if not the greatest
natural growing thing on earth, is
illegal. Every damn politician out there
be should be ashamed of themselves
forever if they continue this now that
they know this or they and don't check
it out if they've heard it and they
don't believe it. Check it out. But if
it's true, you better change your ways
because if a world would accept you, I
wouldn't want to live in that world. And
if the world doesn't accept you, you
should you should be proud of a world
that would teach you how to behave like
adults. Like you want kids to behave
like to be responsible to control their
uses. We expect you to control the
abuses of the power of legislating
stupidity, ignorance, and the end of my
planet. That's all.