I want to remind you we're all here for
the Oregon cannabis tax act because it
is time to re-legalize cannabis hemp in
this country
we just had a decision from the Oregon
Supreme Court that said all you medical
marijuana patients are second-class
citizens you can be fired just for what
medicine you're taking boo hoo that
sucks that's why we need to legalize it
we will always be treated second-class
citizens until it's legal for everyone
he's right you know and your job now you
have a job get yourself registered if
you're not registered to vote and when
it comes up I want you to sign the
petition and once that petition's signed
and we put it forward and it's enough
names and we can get it on the ballot in
the fall vote this sucker in
ahead The Walking Blues
it was so bad that you just Walk and
Walk and Walk
I have
foreign
fill her off of my shoes
this morning
I feel around with my shoes
know that feeling baby
I've been mistreated
even this morning
I have to go rather blind
I've been Mysteries
I don't mind dying
that's how bad I feel
one walking
dead
now you know people tell me walking blue
ain't so bad
worst old feeling
I ever had
people tell
Walking Blues ain't so bad
I ever had
I'm going walking
all right
okay
foreign
Blues ain't so bad
it's the worst old feeling
I
am
so bad
I ever had
go and walk
yeah
foreign