start I started drafting this thing
started drafting it way back in uh
1988 so uh I didn't dream back then I'd
still be working on it all these years
later but we finally put it on the
ballot and it is a
transformative proposal it would make HP
and marijuana completely legal you'd be
able to grow your own without a permit
license or registration you'd be able to
sell seed and starts of all varieties of
cannabis without permit license or
registration you want to sell the
flowers you'd have to get a license and
you'd have to process it so there'd be a
a process around selling the flowers but
you know I really believe that the only
reason marijuana is illegal is because
of hip Fuel and hip
fiber the word marijuana was based as we
know on on racist propaganda from theet
chemical industry they realized that
with new technology that made hemp
cultivation a lot cheaper that the price
of hip products were going to fall
dramatically just as with the invention
of the cotton gin the price of cotton
had fallen to a penny on the dollar the
price of hemp was set to do that with
the invention of new decorticating
Machinery so they came up with a new
name for hip everybody knew what hip was
they came up with a new name and they
got it from Mexico from a revolutionary
war song Poncho V led the Mexican
Revolution in 1911 and they had a song
called lukar Racha you guys might have
heard it when I was a kid I remember
Bugs Bunny used to sing it
laara laara anyway in that song I Won't
Tor you anymore my singing But in that
song they said the Cockroach smoked
marijuana well when the Mexican
Revolution happened
happened they nationalized the oil
industry and the Mexican petroleum
production is still nationalized and run
by the government well the Oil Barons in
Pennsylvania and Texas did not like that
so they took this word from this Mexican
Revolutionary War song and they created
a whole misinformation propaganda
campaign about it and said that there's
this deadly new drug called marijuana
causes people go crazy and kill their
family and friends so based on that
baloney they were able to prohibit hemp
but
hemp is tied to our
civilization in fact if you go back over
12,000 years ago all the new
agricultural civilizations in Asia were
growing hemp hemp was originally from
high up in the Himalaya Mountains in
present day Tibet Nepal Kashmir
Afghanistan and by at least 12,000 years
ago and perhaps over 30,000 years
ago people learned to cultivate it and
they spread down and form civilizations
all across Asia and the ones we know
about today we call Mesopotamia along
the tigress and Euphrates River Valley
in present day Iraq our prehistoric
China along the yellow River the Wang
haa in
China and in those communities they were
growing hemp and it's a common crop it's
the oldest crop known to man and We Know
It produces more fuel more fiber more
food and more medicine than any other
plant on this
planet and the prochemical people
realized that that it was going
to displace with new technology it's
going to displace a lot of their
economic fight you know petroleum is
what economists call Capital intensive
takes a lot of money or capital and they
take tens of millions hundreds of
millions of dollars some cases billion
dollars to go out and drill for
petroleum and it takes tens of billions
hundred billion dollars to refine
petroleum into all the different
products we make it if you can grow
very inexpensively and you get a cheap
oil press and get at least 300 gallons
of oil per acre and the byproduct of
that is 3 tons or 6,000 lbs of high
protein hip seed meal so HP prohibition
is really about Fuel and fiber and the
continued centralization of Economic and
political control it's about this plant
that makes more fuel fiber food and
medicine than any other
plant and so our initiative would
completely restore that hip cultivation
will not be limited to low THC strains
low THC Y is there's no reason
to grow low THC H it produces half as
much fiber and 12th as much seed oil and
protein what they've done with low THC H
is they bred out the flowers by breeding
out the flowers they bred out the seeds
and the seeds are where the oil's at and
that's what they don't want us to have
because you can take hip seed oil or a
lot of other vegetable oils and pour it
right into any diesel engine and turn
the key and drive it yeah now hip is
three times more productive than the
next most productive seed oil crop those
are canola or rape seed soy beans and
sunflower seeds each of those make about
100 to 120 gallons of oil per acre where
HP makes at least 300 gallons of oil per
acre given the economics of biodiesel
today we should see hip biodiesel for
less than a buck a
gallon and the petrochemical companies
don't want to compete with that so our
initiative frees that and it's ballot
measure 80 you know it's on the ballot
this
November the best thing you can Poss
possibly do is register and vote if you
haven't been registered in the past you
haven't registered because you don't
want to participate in the political
process you didn't think there was
anything worth voting for well this year
there is something worth voting for
there's ballot measure 80 and you can
vote to end marijuana prohibition and
let our brother sisters out of jail and
restore hemp for fuel fiber food and
medicine and completely transform our
economy
[Applause]
you know they say the energy industry is
the world's largest
industry and it uh the money that comes
from that goes into the pockets of these
Saudi Arabian chics Nigerian despots
Exxon Mobile shell British Petroleum and
they put it into their Swiss bank
accounts when our farmers can get that
energy money for hip biodiesel fuel that
money will go into our local communities
and Revitalize our towns and reorient
our entire
economy that's what it's all
about it's
really it's really a conspiracy from the
petrochemical pharmaceutical military
industrial transnational corporate Elite
fascist sons of a
you know my father was in World
War II he was on a PT boat out in the
Pacific fighting the fascists we
defeated the Nazis in Germany and drove
the fascists out of power and
unfortunately our government has all too
often emulated those fascist policies
you know my father did not fight the
fases so we would have to pee in a cup
for employment we need to end the crazy
War on Drugs and restore him for fuel
and fiber so register vote and help us
pass measure
this November and change the world for
the better thanks