we are born of Nature and in nature we
will die oh and if we don't make it it's
not because we didn't try know it's not
because we didn't
try they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
M they have all the money we have the
will and I would rather be a match than
a paper dollar bill yes I would yes I
would they have the guns all we are is
flesh and blood but we will multiply our
numbers and drown them in our flood yes
we will yes we
will they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
my and they have all the power
that's what they say but we will turn
those tables take their power away yes
we will yes we will we will not be
dissuaded and we will not turn around we
will face the barricades and we will
tear them down yes we will yes we
will they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
my
you can call me a fool that's all right
with me I will live to see this good
round world breaking free yes I will yes
I
will they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body
my they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
my thank you