this is W he Go's 100th birthday this
summer in July and the interesting thing
about that is he basically defined the
art of The Ballad The Ballad when it
refers to the ballad when it comes from
um the concrete situational life that
you live
[Music]
in so he was a pretty important
character in our um
alternative
culture so I took um I took his most
famous song which is this land is your
land and I rewrote it and it goes like
this
[Music]
gather around me you're my sad story I
know you think you've heard someone sing
it before me but it's an old song I had
to change
it times ain't what they used to be as I
went walking a super highway below the
gray ha and so did Skyway I was arrested
for H hiking on the
freeway they said it don't belong to me
no it ain't my land and it in your land
could be a rich land but it's a poor
land cuz of the few that hold it in
their tight grip hand so that it don't
belong to you me when I was younger and
in my schooling I learned and followed
by all the
rulings I never dreamed that they were
only
foing How Could my teachers lie to me
but as time passed and I Grew Older and
the world around me got a little colder
well then a voice Came Calling at my
shoulder said it don't belong to your
men know it in my land and it in your
land could be a rich land but it's a
poor land cuz of the few that hold it in
that tight grip hand so that it don't
belong to your me that's right
[Music]
from the boardrooms of
Corporations to the back rooms of
desperate situations it's a confused and
disunited Nation all the way from sea to
shining sea from the Urban War zones of
the busted street lights to the toxic
wastelands on the bad test sites from
the open strip mes to the facut
forests oh it's a sad side to see I see
the downsize I see the layoffs the
corporate welfare politicians payoff I
see the bread lines that never make the
headlines cuz they are so entertaining
on TV when they can reduce you you're
just a number when they can knock you
down and they can plow you under and
then the only thing that matters is the
dollar then you know it don't belong to
you me know it in my land and it in your
land could be a rich land but it's a
poor land cuz of the few that hold it in
that tight grip hand so that it don't
belong to you or me there was a time
when the song was greater
but that was then and this is later and
there's a hole in my heart just like a
crater and they say it's going to be the
death of me so let's take this song back
let's take this country take back our
future it's our duty let's stand up tall
so that everyone can see then this land
will be long to you and me and it will
be your land and it will be my land from
California to the New York island and
the red foot Forest to the G stream
Waters this land will be long you and me
[Music]