right now this
song this uh you know I'm kind of on a
memorial thing
tonight I think it's important to do it
right
now this song uh this song's for
Jack you know good
buddy and uh we love him
dearly and uh this song's for you Jack
[Music]
I Miss
You Lord knows I miss
you I miss
[Music]
you oh how I miss
you I remember the
[Music]
time you laid it on the line
it was such a fine
time
yeah I miss
you Lord knows I miss
you I miss you
[Music]
oh how I miss you
I remember the
day the other
day The Day You Went
[Music]
Away wasn't nothing we could
pray it just had to be that way
so go on Jack I Miss
You Lord knows I miss
you I miss
[Music]
you oh now I miss you
thank
you God bless Jack ha