[Music]
well here's a little song that you might
get along with all about a natural seed
growing wild by the side of the roadway
it's Nature's a wonderful weed been
around so long it's hard to tell why
anyone get new love it or hate it
however you relate it I'll leave that up
to you but isn't that
right isn't that good
enough ain't that the way
be is that right is that good
enough rightous is good enough for
me history's locked in a cardboard box
and it's hard to take a look with
Sidetrack Thrills and Fantasies all
written all over the book everybody
tells you what to think and they've got
their reasons why you got to pick
reality up by the scru of the neck and
look it right in the eye and isn't that
R isn't that good enough
ain't that the way it ought to
be isn't that
rightous isn't that good
enough righteous is good enough for me
now the same people that are spreading
the fear the same people that scare me
the most you know some of them look like
they just ass soon like they hanging
from a lamp post they talk about what it
does to your brain well I just have to
react cuz Hitler never touch this stuff
and that's an actual fact it isn't that
isn't that good
enough ain't that the way it to
be is that rightous and is that good
enough righteous is good enough for me
George Washington was a father of our
country and he had a hemp Plantation
Betsy Ross used it to make the flag that
flew about the baby Nation they wrote
their declarations on paper from that
same hemp fiber press and I don't know
what they spoke when they were taking a
break but I got a pretty good guess and
isn't
that isn't that good
enough ain't that the way ought to
be is that
right is that good
enough rightous is good enough for me
[Music]
it'll calm you down when you're too
uptight to just might make you smile use
the seed oil in your engine it'll
lubricate the miles glaucoma
chemotherapy they say it smooth out the
track so next time you meet a cancer
patient ask him what they think about
that isn't that
right isn't that good
enough ain't that the way it ought to
be isn't
that and is that good
enough righteous is good enough for me I
don't know why some people get so upset
when you say to legalize it they'd
rather build more jails arrest more
people spread more crazy lies it's like
talking to a brick wall you know they
just don't get the facts I think they
ought to try a little that Betsy Ross so
just to help him relax and isn't
that is that good
enough ain't that the way it to
be isn't that righteous and isn't that
good
enough righteous is good enough for
me so I'll be on my way now guess I've
taken just about enough of your time I
know there's a lot of people out there
that don't like my state of mind but I
got mine and you got yours we give what
we can take so next time I need a
breather well I might just take a little
smoke break and isn't that
R isn't that good
enough ain't that the way it ought to
be is
that is that good
enough righteous is good enough for me
Isn't that righteous
isn't that good
enough ain't that the way it ought to
be isn't
that is that good
enough right is good enough for me