[Music]
so this is uh this is called Tent City
and uh It Was Written originally about
about Nicholsville but
it it also speaks for dignity Village I
suppose goes like this
[Music]
too cold for Rainbows too cold for sun
too cold for
downpour but we going to get one You
Better Run for Cover rally around that
flag and got a raincoat got a plastic
bag come sit down by the
fire it'll do some good we're going to
keep it going long as we got firewood
[Music]
cold to sit down too cold to stand too
cold to say hello but I can shake your
hand this is where we live now so come
on in long as you ain't looking for
trouble you're welcome friend pull a
sleeping bag
over fatten it down try to keep it level
so you don't roll out on the
ground Living in America
intensity Living in America
intensity Living in America intense City
Living in America intense City yeah and
it's just trickling down ain't
it yeah too cold to be living in tense
too cold to Camp try stay
dry everything gets D too cold be living
outside you can tell it to the cops
ain't got no other place to go and the
weather won't stop take a letter to the
mayor deliver it for me tell him it all
I can see him down here keeping good
company yeah to
cold but what you going to do God lives
somewhere and you know it's true I can't
pay the
mortgage can't afford the rent after
food and bus Fair my money is just about
all spent take a message of the
man whisper it in his ear tell them
until we see some changes we going to
stay right
here Living in America intensity
Sacramento Living in America intensity
dignity Village living Liv in America in
t City Nicholsville Living in America in
t City all over the place
[Music]
[Applause]