[Music]
the song is R Vivian MC PE who may or
may not be
here he's going to be here sometime or
other he was here
[Music]
yesterday it's good to be here to come
all the way down from
Seattle on I
five yeah it's a long ass
drive down to Olympia
Tacoma Centralia
you finally hit in Vancouver you know
there that and and and there's the river
right in front of you and that big
bridge it said big sign that says
welcome to H
hemstock with an arrow pointing over to
the right which is actually the left if
you know what I'm
[Music]
saying let take our culture back take
our culture back get the monkey off of
your back and take off C back well now
we've been here for a million years
music filling up the people's ears and
we always sang our own song Until the
music business came along and I don't
know I could be wrong but I ain't about
to just tag along behind somebody with a
bank roll hanging out telling me what I
can sing about let's take our coach back
take our coach back get the monkey off
of your B and take our Co
[Music]
back
Hollywood spectacle and prominade think
of all that money just wait to be made
and all you got to do is go you'll be
sitting up pretty on gangsters Road and
I it ain't smart to be misled by some
beavers and Butthead you can have your
hip Seattle slacker just give me a good
computer ha let's take our culture back
take our culture back Wikileaks take
government off your back and take our
culture
[Music]
back
you got to get inside to break it out
you got to be outside to know what I'm
talking about two heads and a million
eyes and we can cut this thing right
down to size now culture is a Weaponry
in all our great humanity and survival
is a Counterattack so let's take our
culture back let's take our culture back
take our culture back get the monkey off
of your back and take culture B right
[Music]
[Applause]
now