I wrote this song A long time ago and uh
it's called hushim Nagasaki Russian
Roulette and some some uh rap group
Collective back in h Connecticut or some
place like that got a hold of it through
another Channel and they rewrote parts
of it so that it was Hiroshima Fukushima
electric roulette or something like that
and they turned it into a rap song it is
so cool I mean I don't know if
you can hear it anymore was up there on
the web for a while it's very very cool
um
and it kind of it's It's a song that
kind of it disappears for a while and
then it becomes relevant again when
something happens like you know like
Japan like the nuclear reactor over
there so I I do it
today go like this
[Music]
they dropped the bomb in 45 to win the
World War no one had ever seen since a
terrible sight before the world watched
with eyes wide to see where it would
lead as the politics of power passed
around the seat it was a time to
remember we never can forget they were
playing Heim saki Russian rul
[Music]
they Rose like the saviors of our modern
human race with radiation Halos that
hung above their face with the key to
the sure cure and treatment of our ills
a hot shot of cobalt a pocket full of
pills speaking always of the enemy who L
across the seas while moving in Among Us
like a carrier disease
[Music]
down deep inside the bunkers of the
concrete and Lead Einstein's disciples
working steadily ahead building heavy
metal power plants to fire the city
lights and all you hear is the
underground coming in the night and the
walls of tight security Circle all
around where they spill out all the
poison and they bury it in the ground
[Music]
hold up in the harbor hidden secretly
away the warheads and the submarines a
away to make their play and the military
masterminds improve on their designs
while the soldiers get all doped up and
stumble through the lines and the leaks
in the water get carried by the time
they call it National Security I call it
attempted homicide
[Music]
Governors and Statesmen on Congressional
pay quick to please the hand that feeds
careful what they say they call out
experts to assure us and to wave the
magic wands this is the power of the
future and the future marches on and
then they gather up their favors and
political
while the spills fill the rivers and
settle in the
[Music]
pl I know the minds behind them they are
riddle full of holes they are not to be
trusted with their hands at the controls
their eyesight is Twisted with the glory
of their careers the Heap Praise of
flattery is music to their ears and to
listen to them talk about how it hasn't
happened yet stuck play he suck MO
[Music]