Grass
fire. Grass fire.
[Music]
[Applause]
Yet between the
blues there are good days and bad
days with everything and nothing to
lose. While the setting sun never sits
and the night has no
limits. The void between freedom and
free.
dealing with the unnatural
reality. A need to see, a need to
be.
Grassfire. My
DNA needs THC.
Grass
fire. In a world that
yours, that's the way this fire
burns. Like a grass
[Music]
fire in the unnatural
society. Been trying to
maintain while the same appear to be
clearly
insane with no way to explain.
[Music]
Outlasting the great
lie. A sparking spark does my
mind.
Grassfire pulling the
sky. Breathing in sativa's design.
[Music]
Grass
fire in a world and
yours. That's the way this fire
[Music]
burns. It's a grass fire.
The void between freedom and
free. Dealing with the unnatural
reality. Need to see. I need to be
grassfire. My
DNA needs THC.
[Music]
Dreaming of long times past. All that
those times brought. Looking to the
heart of tomorrow. Grass fire in a world
that yearns. That's the way this fire
burns.
[Music]
High fire.
Where
are the fire?
[Music]
I fire.