[Music]
there's a
shadow over
sisterland with a Smith and Thomas
pointed at her head pointed at her head
money and Authority have their own way
of talking their own way of talking when
it comes to the Man versus what the
woman said versus what the woman
said Shadow there's a
shadow there's a shadow shadow there's a
Shad over sister land
[Music]
somewhere sometimes a woman lives the
memory of the little girl's pain
dragging through the Mind dragging
through the mind every day a compromise
just to do the time just to do the time
silence is a mess silence is a mess when
nothing can be said nothing can be said
there's a
shadow there's a
shadow over
sisterly goddess brought the Chalice
Dominator made the blade God slew The
Serpent and the woman's bed was made
[Music]
tethers of chains tethers of jewels
economic bondage runs by those rules the
laws of Justice are business decisions
gender and class cut with surgical
Precision religious
definition in the politics of man church
and state together hand in hand there's
a
shadow there's a
[Applause]
shadow there's a shadow shadow over
sister l
Mother Earth as goddess is woman meets
the god of men violent prayers
rationalizing Madness partnership comes
to an end land Lords
landlords
landlords ownership prevails ownership
prevails ruling class industrial male
ruling class industrial male ruing
industrial male there's a
shadow there's a
shadow over sister L over sister L God
has brought the Chalice Dominator made
the blade God slew The Serpent and the
woman's bed was made and the woman's bed
was made and the woman's bed was made
a
[Music]