[Music]
famine in the
Plenty patience Burns
quick waiting for the
rich but the rich won't
hurry the rich eat
us so the rich don't
worry in the sun
Shadows water melts into
Cal running rivers of want want needs
Justice For Justice is just ice in those
rivers of
[Music]
want the stars in the night have seen it
all what isn't remembered takes time to
Weep the soul isn't empty yet it feels
that
[Music]
way in
the patience
[Music]
Burns waiting for the
rich but the rich won't
hurt the rich eat
us so the rich don't
[Music]
worry all those Stolen Moments searching
to
beong the scent of Heaven
PS the prayers of the
prey feeling something
missing a constant
of every
[Music]
day
confusion in the happy
place the great lie is one with all the
little
lies edges of breaking dreams
cutting into other
[Music]
dreams Burns
away waiting for the rich but the rich
don't
hurry
the so the
rich famine in the
Plenty patience Burns
quick waiting for the rich
but the rich won't
hurry the rich eat us so the rich don't
worry famine in the
Plenty patience Burns
quick waiting for the
rich but the rich won't
[Music]
hurt