the devil need
baby can't you
see leave
meaby better leave me be
baby can't you see
baby the Devil and me
baby been around too long
baby nothing's all right
baby my light went wrong
baby the dark makes night
baby it's nothing you done
baby it's the way I run
baby me b
Stones through the glass
baby cracks in the wall
baby clouds instead of sun
baby crazy like a man
baby love sharper than the knife
baby confusion a trayal of my life
baby regret in the palm of my hand
baby what I don't remember
baby I can't let it go
baby something to what I did
baby what I don't want to know
Baby history of my stories baby
ending tattered
glories
baby baby look at you
baby you've been through a mill of your
own
baby you've seen some sad times
too
baby still there's a good life for you
baby bab no real need to rush
baby just be careful what you do
baby I can see in your eyes
baby you've been a victim before
baby of people like the Devil and me
baby the Devil and me
baby baby can't you see
baby it's nothing you done
baby it's the way I run
baby run
baby run run
baby
meab
he