feeling
crazier than hell
got this time on my hands
and got you
on my mind
and got nowhere else
to go
the fires
burn hot and cold
that someplace
in between
the melt and the freeze
this need for reaching for you
you
were all i could be
now i'm here
wearing alone
we were one
now i'm a ghost
falling
from my place
in the sun
this dizzy
is out of control
the world keeps spinning
i heard
a vibrating echoing
sounded
a lot
like you
amongst the truths i sought
you were the one i found
now i'm needing
the remembering close
of memories of you
holding my hand
remembrances of laughter singing
songing the nights
with belonging
sweetnessing the shelter of each other
reality
the reality
of safe feeling
got you on my mind
with these times of missing you
i'm never not going to love you
these days
without you to hold my hand
feeling crazier than hell
this crazy just goes on and on and on
in this confusion of me
crazy together
or crazy apart
when crazy is crazy
it's not always
in our heads
sometimes
it's in our hearts
feeling crazier than hell
got this time on my hands
and got you
in my mind
and got nowhere else
to go
you