so we thank you for uh being here
tonight
give us this day
our daily yeses
yes to life
yes to living
yes to caring
yes
to giving
to creating
yes
to thinking
to clarity
yes to balance
yes
to seeing
yes to being
yes to yeses
give us this day
our daily yeses
chaos confusions
chaos
desperations despairs
despairs
desperations
program to believe
belief program
manipulated minds
minds manipulated
behaviors reactions
reactions behaviors
fearful thinking
thinking fearful
inside
outside
altering thought
thought altering
diseasing perceptions
perceptions diseasing
forgetting medicine
medicine forgetting
clear thinking thinking clear
coherent coherence
coherence coherent
prayers given
givens prayers
peace and love
love and peace
reality created
created realities whatever sees
sees whatever
we do
do we
give us this day
our daily yeses
yes to see
yes to yeses
yes to being
yes to
yes balance
clarity
yes to thinking
yes to creating
yes to giving
yes to caring
yes to living
yes to life
yes to yeses
give us this day
our daily yeses
yes
give me