right there
I am
can I get the gym bag or McDonald's
during times of shadow
in the background of burst
Sun waits for the Moon
to torch tonight
to torch the night
and the broken Neon
and Faded light
the lucky Motel
at the corner
of nowhere and the past
where memories go to forget
to forget
laughing
to erase
her name
is lease
she makes his crazy
kind of crazy
his name is want
she can hear it
she wants one
but doesn't want to
Sparks of the Stars
burnings
strong
he is like flame
as her fire awaits
she is a pulse a pulse in the charging
light as a passion of storm
fiery rain
lightning carries Thunder
thank you
she's a good girl
coming to understand that sometimes this
is what good girls do
what good girls do in the breath of size
in the magic of moon
they held them together so as not to
feel so alone
so alone so alone
during times of shadow
in the background of verse the sun waits
for the Moon
to torch tonight
torch the night in the breath of songs
in a magic of moon
they held them together
so as not to feel so alone
so alone
um