hello
thank you
from the heart there are times I turned
out crooked
and times I turned on down
there are times I just kept trying
and times I just went without
there are times I felt like screaming
and times I probably did
there are times I can't quite remember
and times I can never forget
there are times love is a shadow
and times love is a change
there are times Love Is The Life
and Times love is to blame
oh
from the heart there are times when a
smile is a smile
and times when it is not
there are times time buys
and times time bought
there are times
I went way out there
and times I never came back
there are times of great feeling and
times I don't feel a thing
shadow
and times love is a chain
there are times love is the light
and times love is to blame
there are times I keep waiting for
and times that are never going to come
there are times I could have done
different
and times different isn't there
from the hood there are times the
balance is balance
and times the rush is too extreme
there are times it's all I can do to
live
in times I'm glad that I do
foreign