[Music]
High
we give us this
day our daily
yeses yes to
life yes to living
yes to
carrying yes to
giving yes to
creating yes to
thinking yes to
Clarity yes to
balance yes to
being yes to
seeing give us this
day our daily yeses
[Music]
chaos
confusions confusions
chaos despairs
desperations desperations despairs
programmed
belief belief
programmed manipulated
Minds Minds
manipulated behaviors
reactions reactions
behaviors fearful
thinking thinking
fearful
inside
outside outside
[Music]
inside thought
altering altering
thought diseasing
perceptions deceptions Pro
diseasing forgetting
medicine medicine
forgetting clear
thinking thinking
clear coherent
coherence coherency
coherent prayers given
given
prayers realities
created Created realities see
whatever whatever
sees we
do do
we our daily
yeses give us this
day our daily
yeses yes to
see yes to
being yes to
balance yes to
Clarity yes to
thinking yes to
create yes to
giving yes to
caring yes to
living yes to
life yes to
yeses give us this day
our daily
[Music]
yeses
yes give me
[Music]
yes give me yes
[Applause]
give me
yes give me
yeah give me