in the rhyme of
match these Embers of
torch seding the
light what you do to
me this temptation of heat
craving your
liquid that deep
fire than sweet rushing
flame and embracing of
stirring your name is the
spark fire starting this
ra
blazing through my
heart much is said about
love but love seems too change
with no way to
explain our Wilding of
gentle the reality of
dream the closing of
close melting Destiny and Faith what is
meant to
be this unraveling of of
need drenching of
desire and it all
started with your
smile and embracing of
stirring your name is the
spark fire starting this
Ro blazing through my
heart about
love but love seems to T
with no way to explain to explain our
wild a gentle
in the rhyme of
match these ambers of
torch sweding the light what you do to
me
this temptation of
heat craving your
liquid that deep
fire then sweet rushing Flame
oh