I
lightning there is
thunder during times of
shadow in the background of
bur the sun waits for the night
to torch the
moon to torch
theight in the broken neon and Faded
light the lucky
motel at the corner of nowhere and the
past where memories go to forget
to
forget laughing to
erase her name is
Lacy she makes his
crazy kind of
crazy his name is
want she can hear
it she wants want
but doesn't want
to Sparks of the
Stars
burnings strong
heat he is like
flame as her fire
Waits she is a
pulse a
pulse in the charging
light as a passion of storm
fiery
rain lightning carries Thunder
how
she's a good girl coming to understand
that sometimes this is what good girls
do what good girls do in the breath of
ss and the magic of
moan they held them to
together so as not to feel so
alone so
alone during times of shadow in the
background of
first the sun waits for the
moon to torch the
night torch the night in the breath of
ss in the magic of moon
they held them together so as not feel
so
alone so
oh