this comes in a matter i think the
finding new ways to approach this thing
exactly mere you know these are the
mother talking about the stuff they do
but these are the people that created
the Inquisition yeah I'm anything that
they were doing doing we're not being
realistic and pragmatic if someone act
of cruelty or stupidity or just plain
old cold-bloodedness happens and we're
shocked and surprised by it then shame
on us exactly yeah yeah so so it's
really to me a matter because
everything's about energy all right and
they're focusing their energy we can
call it whether it's the hate stuff all
the discussion but they're focusing
their energy in such a way all right
that it's being effective for them and
and and but it's it also because they
can hit us and push emotional buttons
and pull the stores out of us then they
distort our energy you know and so to me
I think what's really ahead of us is
it's not even a matter of our organizing
them it's a matter of out thinking them
thinking differently outside of their
definitions and inside of the bar yeah
outside the box because see we're
talking about alternative energies
because the whole marijuana thing all of
it but really this everything is about
energy and when I look at it is well we
are individual alternative energy
sources if we looked at ourselves as
alternative energy as well as we do hemp
or whatever else you know and understood
the value of that and then use that
power of our creative intelligence use
that power of our creative intelligence
clearly and currently we can out think
these people but it's not happening
because because we've been imprinted and
wired to have these insecurities these
doubts and these reactionary fear so
they they know they can push in your
motion button so they're spending so
however many of these things are half of
that just put out there just to push our
emotional buttons it's not to recruit a
new people have been rebelling against
the oppressor class since there's been
an oppressor class and I look within our
my own lifetime we were young idealistic
our stuff we want it all to be good in
fairness and that you know and so we did
all the stuff we went out there we took
all that out there basically that the
generations had done before and the way
that they did it now and so what's
missing if our intentions are good our
motives are good our idealism is good
and yet the
stay on top of us in what's missing and
I think what's missing is we weren't
using the palm of our creative
intelligence clearly and coherently see
we were just picking up all behavior
patterns and organizing the same way
under the same definitions at the
generation before had in generation
before heads we never challenged we
never we never approached it from the
concert the perspective of well maybe
life is about responsibility and not
freedom because I've responsibility has
it's got a definite meaning to us
whereas freedom is an abstraction all
right i mean it is because i can say i
believe in freedom but then that means
that that the racist liar that lies
about hemp the only thing then what they
have the freedom to do that if i had you
know since it's an action right and
we've never really approached this thing
whole thing from the sense the
perception of responsibility what we
have a response it because if we want to
be free being free is connected to
responsibility alright being oppressed
his concept is connected to this
abstract hill logical all right no
definition of freedom