[Music]
last night in he
dream I interrogated
God why is it the Good Die
Young what's the reason to
this we talked we argued we
cried I never did getting
answers but God knows I tried
[Music]
the
answers already know a question for the
question who is it took the creation
story claimed it and took it
apart glorifying obedience and fear
stamping uncertainty Into the
Heart rampaging through the
mind and then there's that original sin
and something about the devil to pay and
that Golden Rule do unto others
obviously isn't really a
rule the lord giveth the lord taketh
away the violence gets
violent God just sits there with nothing
to
[Applause]
[Music]
say
I've read it said in the beginning was
the word and the Word was God I've never
read it said in the beginning was
thought and the thought is to think but
that has to do with
anything last night and he dream I
interrogated God why is it the Good Die
Young what's the reason to this we
talked we argued we
cried I never did get any
answers but God knows I
[Music]
Cy
oh