there's me there's the other me
there's another me and then there are
the more means
we've all got a domino to play so we
been trying to work it out we don't know
how your life turned or what all that
means but me and amis we're not going
back we've already seen what we couldn't
do
any skeletons in our closets are our own
private stash of bones that's free with
no choice there's no scream like the
next screen reducing the present get to
nothing while yet eternity is now not
then who's divided into once and you
know how many does that mean there's
love that loves there's love that fears
there's love that possesses there's love
it needs proof where's the love that
accepts love that likes love that cares
there's no forgetting some realities
destiny through it us and fate wasn't
much help with his way of loading the
loan but it was up to us to carry it and
we didn't have any sane
if the land where the law is king using
fear like glue pretending pretending
isn't pretending each and every one of
us have seen the Lord not a one of us
likes the way we fall sometimes straight
is a way of walking which snake isn't an
option because we've been accused of
some things we did some things we didn't
do and we heard I forgive you
are looking for a me there will answer
to me so far there's no one who will
ah