one two three
in the rhyme of match
these
embers of torch
sweeting the light
what you do
to me
this
temptation of heat
craving your liquid
that deep fire
this sweet
russian flame
and embracing of stirring
your name is the spark
fire starting this roar
lazy
with no way
to explain
are
the closeness of close
melting destiny and fate
what
is meant to be
an unraveling of knee
this drenching of desire
and it all started
with your smile
and embracing the stirring
your name is the spark
fire started in this
through my heart
no way to explain
in the rhyme of match
these embers of torch
sweetie in the light
what you do
to me
this temptation of heat
craving your liquid
that sweet fire
the deep
russian flame
so
you