[Music]
then Happy fell
down broken into pieces of
light
fragments of shattering
law glimpses of what what once was
overwhelmed by what is what if and what
could have
[Music]
been at
first it didn't seem like
much but then each Stone
thrown had an accumulative
effect whether they hit or missed each
throwing
Stone became a part of the wall they
[Music]
built then Happy felt
down broke it to pieces of
[Music]
life then Happy fell down
turning
quarrel into
ritual losing
balance turns
habitual someone else's truths are
someone else's
lies during those Wars of
scars Old Wounds keeping time waging
battle in the minds
[Music]
then Happy fell
down BR it
[Applause]
[Music]
down there's When Love is
Blind when it opens its eyes it can
disappear the reality of what is
happening happening is not
diminished by their unwillingness to
comprehend it is
them who
[Music]
diminish happy F
down broken into pieces of
light F down then happy fell
down
[Music]
[Applause]
BR
[Music]
down broken to pieces of light
broken let happy fell down
[Music]
w