give us this
day our daily
yeses yes to
life yes to
living yes to
caring yes to
giving yes to
creating yes to
thinking yes to
Clarity yes to
balance yes to
be yes to see
yes to
yeses give us this
day our daily
yeses chaos
confusions confusions
chaos desperations
despairs despairs desperations
Behavior
reaction reactions
Behavior manipulated
Minds Minds
manipulated fearful
thinking thinking
fearful inside outside outside inside
altering thought thought
alter perceptions diseasing dis dising
perceptions forgetting
medicine medicine
forgetting coherent
coherence coherency
coherent peace and
love love and
peace realities
created Created
realities whatever
sees sees whatever we do do we
give us this
day our daily
yes yes to
yeses yes to see
it yes to be
it yes to
Clarity yes to balance yes to
creating yes to
thinking yes to giving yes to
caring yes to
living yes to
life yes to
yes give us this
day our daily yes
oh
give
me
me me
W wo