feeling
the feeling
of something gone wrong
how do you define
what you can't explain
into dragging on
hunger gnaws on law
and in self-defense
long keeps gnawing back
sometimes the thoughts
don't know what to think
and where i've been
doesn't remember a thing about me
something strange going on
everything that had unraveled
and now it's raveling back
into all i thought
i'd escaped
those places i don't want to go
but don't want could care less
about any of that
not with its own need
for a fix
looking
at what's been done
all i did
was go along for the ride
in a shadowing of light
flung to the edge collided with reality
and reality didn't even
those dreams
marked by scars
the rampage question is
who would want to scar a dream
maybe
its scars
need dreams too
riding
a shattering or breaking
into an echo of silence
that bitter taste
looks
for someone sweet
feeling
the feeling
something gone wrong
how do you define
what you can't explain
in a shadowing of light
flung to the edge collided with reality
and reality
didn't even blink
you