all right
away
spoken anger
silent hurt
some kind of wheel
inside her head
going around
and around
inside her heart
heated Passions
chilling effects
when they first met
she couldn't forget
times only purpose
was for them together
they talk together
Edward James
together
with their dreams
she needed a friend
she needed a man
inside her head
around and around
and around
as newness stretches thin
turns out he didn't understand
part of the man let her down
part of the man couldn't give
part of the man he never was
part of the Man a part of her life been
all through this before
inside her heart
pouring around
and around
thank you
heated passions
showing effects
now here she is acting tough again
turning herself off fast
curtains dropping in place
giving away nothing
in rise
spoken anger
silent hurt
some kind of wheel
inside her head going around and around
and around and around
and around
chilling effects now here she is acting
tough again
the curtains dropping in place giving
away nothing nothing
in her eyes
foreign