there's me there's the other me there's
another me and then there are the more
means we've all got a domino play so we
been trying to work it out
we don't know how your life burn or what
all that means for me in the means we've
already seen what we couldn't do and
we're not going back
any skeletons in our closets are our own
private stash of bones there's no screen
like the last stream and it's green with
no choice reducing the present is to
nothing all eternity is now
not then who is divided into one and how
many does that make there's long that
lungs there's loves it fears there's
love that possesses there's love that
needs proof where's the love that lights
love that cares
Joe's not forgetting some realities
destiny threw at us and faith wasn't
much help with this way unloading the
loan it was up to us to carry him you
really have any say
you
in the land where the lie is king using
fear like glue mechanic pretending isn't
pretending each and every one of us I've
saw the glory each and every one is what
the boys but we don't like the way we
fell and sometimes stray is a way of
walking when we can't stay because we've
been accused some things we did is
something we didn't do and we are I
forgive you then lied
to be enemies
I've been looking for me they will
answer to me and so far there's no one
who will
there's me there's the other there's
another me
and we've all got a domino to play so
we've been trying to work it out