uh you know cuz we're in
a we're in a situation in we're in a
dimensional reality now we're pretty
much you got to pretty much improvise as
we go along you know and to and to
really be able to effectively improvise
as we go along we need to be able to do
it with respecting the
clarity respecting our our intelligence
you know we need to be able to do it
with Clarity because they're
with our minds they their mind
us so that we can't see we don't know
anymore so everybody's just afraid
that's it that's reality reality is a is
fear you know everybody's being mindfuck
through that fear so no you know and so
everybody's going around reactionary
these be reactionary Behavior patterns
they're really are the same thing that's
going on but they've convinced
themselves they're doing something
different am I making
sense all right see so see so if there's
going to be any real change right but we
got to understand to respect our
intelligence see and and we need it's
very important it's very very important
that we learn how to like ourselves this
is the most important thing of all cuz
see if you don't like yourself then what
the good you're going to do for the
rest of the world when it really comes
down because I don't like
my no
offense meant but see gu what I mean we
need need to think cuz there's too much
muddled going on here that's getting in
the way of us having the lives that we
that we are entitled
to and especially with what's coming see
not my generation I'm of the generation
we're booking we're going you know we we
we get to go on and do our other the
rest of our stuff but what's come in
here it's very
important that the next that we need to
understand to like ourselves to respect
our intelligence cuz we can talk
spirituality all we want we can talk
good guy stuff all we want but if we
don't like ourselves what does it mean I
mean seriously seriously and now back to
the part about liking
ourselves see and and to me don't like
ourselves see it's if we're full of fear
doubt and insecurity and we just think
we're up you know then that means
we don't like ourselves but but what my
point being if you look at at reality
with
it somebody put that in our mind see
what see somebody said it to us somebody
told it to us we didn't think that up
ourselves am I making
sense all right see so so and it's very
important for us to understand that
somebody that wanted to control us and
feed off of us put this fear see and the
fear starts with we don't like ourselves
because we don't think we're good
however they put it in there however
however ver whatever version of that
virus we carry but our intelligence is
the antibiotic
anyway whatever goes
on keep clear
mind
know I power is
very
power power comes from
us and how we use a clear mind
yeah cuz I don't know sometimes I get
confused cuz I am multi-dimensional
sometimes and I
am I am crazy you know and and and I
don't trust any of you normal at
all no
offense because you don't understand
what power
is power is in your
heartbeat all right power is in your
heartbeat
power is in your heartbeat it sends
electrical energy and your brain
transmits electrical energy through what
is called thought that's power all right
that's power we are our own
power all right
this all the rest of
it whatever it is
right but
power comes from
us money is about Authority not power
politics is about Authority military is
about Authority so all these religion
it's all about Authority all right but
we've been but we believe see we don't
think any anyway we've been programmed
to believe that these things represent
power but in reality they represent
forms of authority power is an entirely
different thing see but in the in in the
land of Deceit slight of mind and
illusion and delusion we get confused
used okay