oh
spoken anger
silent hurt
some kind of wheel
inside her head
going around
and around
her heart
heated passions
chilling effects
when they first met
she couldn't forget
time's only purpose
was for them together
they laid together and were gentle
she told him her prayers
she needed a friend
she needed a man
inside
her head
going around
eyes
as newness stretches thin
turns out he didn't understand
the part of the man
let her down
part of the man couldn't give
part of the man he never was
part of the man
part of her life
been all through this before
inside her heart
going around
and around
chilling effects now here she is acting
tough again
turning herself off fast
curtains dropping in place
giving away nothing
nothing
in raw
spoken a
silent hurt
some kind of wheel
inside her head
going around
and around
chilling effects
now here she is acting tough again
turning herself off fast
hurts dropping in place
giving away nothing
nothing
in her eyes
so
you