[Applause]
[Music]
cast out from a dreamer's
dream I lied to
myself for Canyons of
gold where there were no
Canyons there was
go out of
control false faces praying to God
against those who see the changing
this first I tried
fighting then I was crying when finally
I saw you were
one truth is relative someone's take it
up go
wasur baby baby baby I was hurting
baby baby I was hurting always always
always wanting
[Music]
you during first impressions our days
were
good close as we got then you slipped
away melting my eyes I saw you
fa I vainly traded myself to
illusion Bain lies desperately
pretending i t talking to someone I
couldn't see but they wouldn't show at
least not to
me when I tried tearing down those
rotating
walls turning into a continuing storm
worn Away by what I couldn't tear down
passion on fire bur to rain and into ice
baby I was hurting baby baby I was
hurting
[Music]
baby maybe I was hurting
maybe I was after what I didn't
deserve maybe what I got was what I
did anyway I remember a story I
live we are what we
learn even as we
deny today could be our day of pay for
the luxury or the torment and
self-denial anyway I'm feeling like
someone you used after someone else you
used like sometime someone else must
have used
you savage why I wasn't enough to love
heart keeps questioning my mind and
heated
debate can't help being
angry can't help being just as
sad but I see you're only another victim
and I'm only another victim
[Music]
too baby I was in baby baby baby I keep
hurting baby baby I keep hurting hurting
from always wanting you Andy baby baby I
keep hurting baby I was from not getting
you and baby I keep
[Music]
h
w