you know I mean I want to throw this out
there about hemp hemp what's called hemp
see we're after the medical marijuana
and we all talk about that and
recreational marijuana and all the
marijuana aspect of it but the hemp
aspect hemp is Earth medicine hemp will
make fresh oxygen for a sky that is
being suffocated hemp hemp will feed us
cloth us we know all the stuff hemp will
do it but not enough attention is being
ain't paid to
hemp we need to pay more attention to
hemp and recognize
it I mean
otherwise it's more you know there's
more to life than let's go get the
medicine that just helps us you know
let's get the medicine that will help
the earth and the planet too and us so
let's think about that
hemp not enough attention being paid to
hemp the word gets said a lot but not
enough attention being paid to
hemp no
offense