[Music]
oh say a
woman sister to the
[Music]
Earth life
Brer see the
woman she has a young
face an old
face she carries herself well Through
the Ages
she
survives all man has
[Music]
done in some tribes she is
free in some religions she is under
man in some
societies she is worth what she
consumes
in some Nations she is delicate
strength in some
states she is told she is
weak in some
classes she is property
owned in all
instances she is sister to
Earth in all
conditions she is lifebringer
in all life she is our
[Music]
necessity
see the woman
eyes flowers swaying on scattered
Hills Sun
dancing calling in the
[Music]
bees see the woman
heart lavender
butterflies fronting Blue
Skies Misty rain falling on soft Wild
Roses see the woman
Beauty lightning
streaky dark summer
nights Forest of Pines mating with new
winter
snow see the woman
spirit daily serving courage with
laughter her breath a dream and a
prayer see the
woman she has a young
face an old
face she carries herself well Through
the
Ages she
survives all man has
done the
woman say the
[Music]
[Applause]
Earth life
[Music]
bringer