last night in a dream
I interrogated God
why is it the Good Die Young
what's the reason to this
we talked we argued we cried
I never did
get any answers
but God knows I try
the answers already know a question for
the question
who is it took the creation story
claimed it they took it apart
glorifying obedience and fear
stamping uncertainty into the heart the
Rampage through the mind
then there's that original sin
something about about the devil today
Golden Rule do unto others obviously
isn't really a rule the lord giveth the
lord taketh away the violence
for God just sits there with nothing
nothing saying
um
Reddit set in the beginning what's the
word and the Word was God
I've never read it sin in the beginning
was thought
and the thought is to think
what that has to do with anything
last night in a dream
I interrogated God
why isn't the good guy young
what's the reason to this
can we talk
we argue we cry
I never did get any answers
God knows I try
oh