you know we should believe less and
think more right well anyway if you
don't think about
it well believe when we say I believe
I'm not trying to start any but
when we say I
believe actually we're really saying I
don't
know but we're not going to go out and
say I don't know this I don't know that
so we're going to go say I believe this
I believe
that but I think we need to really think
about thinking rather than than
believing all thing everything is energy
energy flows that's the way it is
thinking is energy it flows but believe
is a container so when you take the
energy of flow the flowing energy of
thinking and put it in the container of
believing it's got nowhere to go so it
just kind of intensifies inside the
container and creates all this stress
and freak out
think more believe less all right
that's
the I don't know where it came from but
hey it's out there you got it now
in the rhyme of
match these Embers of
torch seding the
lights what you do to
me this temptation of
heat gra craving your
liquid that deep fire then sweet rushing
flame and embracing of
stirring your name is the
spark fire starting this
Roar blazing through my heart is
about seems much is said about
love but love is too
t with no way to explain our Wilding of
gentle in the reality of
dream the closeness of
close melting Destiny and
fate what is meant to
be an un traveling of
need this drenching of
desire and it all started with your
smile and embracing of
stern your name
is Fire Starting Roar blazing through my
heart seems
to
no way to
explain
in the Ryme of
match these ambers of
torch seding the
light what you do to me
this temptation of
heat craving your
liquid that deep
fire then sweet rushing
Flame
a