feeling the
feeling of something gone
wrong how do you
define what you can't
explain into the dragging
on Hunger gnaws on
long and in
self-defense long keeps gnawing
back sometimes the thoughts don't know
what to
think and where I've been doesn't
remember a thing about me
something strange going
on everything that had
unraveled and now it's raveling back
into all I thought I'd
escaped and those places I don't want to
go don't want could care less about any
of that not with its own need for a fix
looking at what's been done all I did
was go along for the
ride and a shadowing of
light flung to the edge collided with
reality and
reality didn't even blink
those dreams marked by
scars the rampaging question is who
would want to scar a
dream maybe it scars need dreams
too writing a shattering of breaking
into an echo of
Silence that bitter taste looks for
someone sweet
feeling the feeling of something gone
wrong how do you
define what you can't
explain in a shadowing of
light flung to the edge collided with
reality and
reality didn't even blink
on