let's just say I don't know what I
organized but I was part of a lot of
things that went along yeah right and
that's really kind of the reality of it
just wandered around to different places
worth it it was good to wander too yeah
so you are now a recording artist and
you have a number of albums out there I
guess was it Jackson Browne who first
brought you into the studio how did that
come about well it came about you know I
spent a lot of time as a political
activist right and then for me as an
individual I came to understand that
that wasn't that identity didn't work
for me mm-hmm right because it limited
my perception of reality because I was
person I was participating in reality
from the perception of a political
activist and no matter how righteous my
activism it what no matter how righteous
might cause I'm limiting my ability to
see because I'm only seeing as a
political activist and and that has its
own limitations because I think there
are larger understandings that as human
beings we need to be able to experience
maybe alright so in that hole as all
that's going on through my head and
consciousness I started writing and and
and I started writing and in yes Jackson
took me and I was kind of like a
fugitive and and Jackson took me in and
into the world of music while I was
writing and then at some point I got the
idea while I want to put what I want to
put my lines with music but as spoken
word mm-hmm you know so then I wandered
off into that to see what it would go
and Here I am i remember it was must
been more than 20 years ago i first came
across a cassette of yours it was this
is an El Salvador cases in El Salvador
right that was really a powerful was
that one of your first ones it was the
fourth album fourth album we made tribal
voice which was the poetry with the
tribal music uh-huh and then three years
passed and then I met Jesse at Davis and
with Jesse had Davis made
graffiti make a graffiti man which is
now with the electric music right and
then we made heart jump bouquet and then
we made but this is nel Salvador I think
in 1987 were recorded that right we like
that Thun grass fire man that's why ya
na needs tiene mas jay-z well it's
reality yeah real so many things I
Messiah was backing that up more and
more every day we often talk about it
here how you know just in what was it 93
they discovered that our bodies had this
whole endogenous cannabinoid system
where we have these artificial
cannabinoids they kind of modulate the
rest of the endocrine system the body's
hormones and everything's what you do
need th see ya know that mother's milk
has endogenous th don't know that's why
my DNA needs th there's a reason right
then it gets said but you know what I'm
interested in I mean in a way is like
because what you're saying about the
this yeah I think that where's this
cannabis sense yeah canvas Congress I'll
see what makes cannabis common sense to
me is I think we really need to start
putting some efforts in to the
legalization of industrial hemp mm-hmm
if we put as much effort in energy into
the legalization of industrial hemp as
we put into hemp that we can smoke if we
put an equal amount of energy into that
because that serves and it meets a
larger objective of alternative energy
because I mean wow you know like us we
make the fuels and the food and all the
sir all right in it you know and I and
I've had this lingering curiosity in the
back of my consciousness as active as
the cannabis movement is in its various
levels and perceptions right that III
don't quite get why more energy isn't
put into that mm-hmm you know because it
would save the farmers and all I mean
there's so much that could be and
everybody's talk see and and people are
starting to sit back now that the
political system starting to talk about
well in order to meet our oil needs in
order to meet all these will do offshore
drilling
you know and people say and but and I
don't see it coming on in order to meet
some of these energy needs industrial
hemp yeah we often talk about this study
out of Notre Dame University in 1975 is
published in a magazine called the
Midlands naturalist and it's feral hemp
in southern Illinois according to that
study an acre of hemp will make four
tons of hemp seed and four times as hemp
seed will make 300 gallons of biodiesel
fuel or oil so to me those of us who
come from the hemp community say this
should be the alternative form of energy
that we're putting up it out put as much
effort into to getting medicine for the
earth as we put into getting it for
ourselves see we have the energy to do
it it's just it up to focus in the
consciousness because what I see as the
imbalance we're talking about the
benefits of him or marijuana should
additionally all right for us but it but
it also serves the same medicinal
benefit for the earth you know and it
does but we're not putting an equal
effort into what it does for uh for the
earth as we're putting in to what it
does for us and because what I don't see
it really happening in anywhere to a
large degree but what we really need to
have is we really need to have a
stimulation of the inner of the energy
consciousness energy John our theme was
industrial have man we yes the antenna
should be yeah stream of energy the
environmental crisis being what it is I
think it's a neck I think there's an
opening somewhere to inject it in as a
alternative part of the alternative
because they're talking about
alternative energy yeah I can read and
write a sheep and everybody i think
that's about right it's the alternative
energy i agree with right well that's
all going on this whole idea and maybe
it comes out of our consciousness about
saying no consider this this is about
alternative energy mm-hmm you know
because they are talking about drilling
offshore no you know and everybody's
starting to eat
up to people that wouldn't accept it 15
years ago it's it's you know because
what's happened is the industrial ruling
class they're cutting off access to the
drug oil and people are going through
the withdrawal and they're making them
pay the higher price and now they're
willing to sell their children so to
speak or chelle would sell the family
jewels so to speak you know writing to
get the next fix the offshore drilling
ET boon pin all as Ardoin transfer well
it always you must know and but I I
think that see what makes sense makes
sense what Alec cannabis come what makes
sense makes sense and I think that it
that you see I'm not the person that
does but that can that does it but
someone usually if it started gets
injected if in our consciousness and we
start thinking away that this should be
put to that alternative energy debate
thing that's going on and I industrial
industrial him they don't want that but
I don't think that's the key and it's
being said for this for the sake of it
because you know there are a lot of
people especially farmers the song about
fun there's a lot of fun there's a lot
of people that would be supportive of it
but it's got to be if we could put the
money for these Detroit a and money
that's going over say it's an
arbitrator's pockets but putting in
finally you're gonna say I need to put
the energy into the idea all right put
the energy in all right and then that'll
help to feed other energy and see what's
going on is the word sorry for energy
against dust and we're putting against
them yeah that's exactly what's going on
they're putting their their energies
more coherent what they're going to do
against us there they're very coherent
about what they're doing alright in
order to keep the downtrodden the Donald
down try but it's about energies laws
and voting and all that stuff these are
mechanisms but in the end it's about
energy so the only defense we're ever
going to really have in the long run
what kind of energy do we create with
the creative power of our intelligence
what kind of coherent energy do we
protect ourselves with yeah because and
anyway so to meet you handle it family I
think it's in our best interest if we
really put thought into the industrial
what we call industrial hemp as a part
of the alternative energy right
consciousness that's going on right now
right and then it helps the medical
marijuana use for the humans and it also
helped for that yeah you can feel the
plan got me good because I I think in a
lot of ways we're having a hard time
getting past because the way we have to
fight the struggles we have to fight to
get it legalized for human consumption
all right i think but i just think an
equal amount of energy needs to start
going for its earth medicine protects
you you know you don't have to but you
don't have to insecticide it and all
that stuff right yeah that's right it
grows more Buffalo in faster more
protein fiber and oil than any other
planet planet one of the things we say
here on the show quite frequently is
that the real reason that marijuana's
illegal has nothing to do with drugs
it's not about drugs it's really about
money and the continued centralization
of economic and political control it's
about the political powers that be that
protect the petrochemical industry and
the wood based paper industry that whole
corporate monolith that wants to you
know centralized control to a tinier and
smaller group of people and we don't
even have to centralized control things
are working just great for them yeah and
they have been for a long time that was
easy so so they don't need to centralize
or do any I've actually all they're
really leave all hit ball bearing
institutions are concerned about is
keeping the status quo yeah I don't
think they're actively at this point I
think they've got everything where they
want it and it's working just fine I saw
a great bumper sticker the other day it
said everything considered the war in
the environment is going extremely well
yeah that's right we good it but for you
this other thing about its marijuana is
not a drug all right and and we jokingly
refer to it I do we do sacrifice right
no it's a plant the nerve it's an herb
it's a plant it's not a drug the earth
does not grow drugs this is basic
reality the earth does not grow drugs
all right a man creates drugs out of
things the earth grows so marijuana is
not a drug no its plant and and and I
think that that's an important
distinction that we we need to
understand because it's a part of our
humor and a whole part of our
consciousness is dope this is right you
know it's kind of different but in
reality than agree we might look at the
like the Cheech and Chong kind of humor
not to complain about them but it is
self danica but but at some point we
need to really have that understanding
also because it helps us you know
because we know the marijuana
prohibition has got to do with the
threat that opposes to the petrotech the
petro chemical society yeah you know
because if you do experience all of
these things out of it you don't need
all this oil if you can you know if you
can make paper out of it then you don't
need to cut down the forest if you can
make wood for houses then you don't need
see it's it's a serious see that's what
this is really all to the whole industry
all about that whether you smoke a joint
or I smoke a joint is it irrelevant it's
about this all right and whether we
smoke get to smoke a joint or not
becomes a way of keeping this down
mm-hmm we're fighting this thing right
you know an artificial construct and I'm
just saying somewhere along the line is
we evolve this thing if we throw in with
throwing our energy of consciousness and
alliance with in what I call industrial
hemp looking out for the earth in a
larger context it will be beneficial all
around for all of us