you
there are times i turned out quickly and
times i turned on down
there are times i just kept trying and
times i just went without
there are times I felt like screaming
and times I probably did there are times
I can't quite remember and times I can
never forget there are times love is it
and times love is a dream there are kind
love is the light
love is 21 times the fist
there are times a smile is a smile and
times when it is not there are times
time buys and times time box
there are times I went way out there and
times I never came back there are times
of great feelings and times I don't feel
a thing there are times love as it can
and times love is a chain there are
times love is the light
times I keep weaving in times that are
never going to come there are times I
could have done different and times
different it isn't there
there are times balances Dallas and
times to rush is too intense there are
times if all I can do to live and times
that i'm glad that i do