[Music]
I have loved
you
since the
Stars met the
sky and the
moon first lit tonight
and the
sun brought
bright to the
[Music]
day I have loved
you since dream learned how to
dream you have been part of my
reality my Saving
Grace when saving needs save
I have loved you
[Music]
since doves first found their
songs with coyotes first Howl at the
Moon in each heart in each
heartbeat from the
beginning of the first I love
[Music]
you I have loved you since
in the
attracted it is
decided in the DNA of
time I have loved
you
since my first
breath since the Stars met the
sky and the moon first lit the night and
the sun brought bright into the
[Music]
day since dream learned how a
dream you have been a part of my
reality my Saving Grace when
saving needs
save in the
attractive it is
decided in the DNA of
time I have loved
you since my first breath
[Music]
Dayo
woo cool