Johnny Damas and me
and the Mongrel dog the Mongrel dog
we've been laying real low laying real
low in the shadow of the road shadow of
the road the road to success the road to
success we stood face to face face to
face we went head to head head to head
over the idea of money the idea of money
the idea of money and Nest away it's
done and that's the way it's done and
that's the way it's
done speaking in tongues speaking in
tongues phrases and traces traces of
words traces of words something still
doesn't settle still doesn't settle
still doesn't settle
still wild wine on a coyote Moon a
coyote Moon high on a hill high on a
hill a reckless wind knocks a reckless
wind knocks rattling the night rattling
the night over his shoulder over his
shoulder watching the door watching the
door ready for flight ready for flight
needing to run needing to run needing to
run
in the Nazi Babylon in the Nazi Babylon
in the Nazi Babylon Lucifer Dances With
Angels Dances With Angels dances with
angels and the dead and the dead carry
the living on their backs on their backs
on their backs in the Nazi Babylon in
the Nazi Babylon in the Nazi Babylon
ruthless and arrogant ride pil pony ride
pil pony ride pil Pony using hatred as a
shield hatred as a shield in the world
where to give also means to take also
means to take someone's must yield
someone must yield in the Nazi Babylon
in the Nazi Babylon in the Nazi
Babylon
Johnny doas me yeah Johnny and me from
the story of love the story of love and
prove that you love me prove that you
love me a broken heart I couldn't
recognize couldn't recognize and mongel
dog the mongel dog the mongel dog went
mad in the arms mad in the arms mad in
your arms of many lovers many lovers
many lovers they wept in the high they
wept in the high Baby Don't Cry Baby
Don't Cry Baby Don't Cry love baby Ride
Like the Wind fly Ride Like the Wind fly
baby fly fly baby fly fly baby
fly and the man who is a ghost is a
ghost is an ally of mine an ally of mine
he saw the whole thing he saw the whole
thing from where I can see from where I
can see too bad for Johnny and them yeah
poor Johnny and them from what I can see
from what I can see this can't happen to
me can't happen to me I don't carry it
well don't carry it well and the man who
is a ghost is a ghost is a ghost is an
ally of mine an ally of mine he saw the
whole
thing Johnny Damas and me and the Mong
dog we've been laying real
low
hey