feeling
the feeling
of something
gone wrong
how do you define
what you can't explain
and they're dragging on
hunger
goes on long
and in self-defense
long
keeps gnawing back
sometimes
the thoughts
don't know what to think
and where i've been
doesn't remember
a thing
about me
something strange going on
everything that had unraveled
and now
it's raveling back
into all i thought
i'd escaped
those places i don't want to go
but don't want could care less
about any of that
not with his own need for a fix
looking at what's been done
all i did was go along for the ride
i didn't ask
where we were going
in a shadowing of light
flung to the edge
collided with
reality and reality
didn't even blink
those dreams
marked by scars
the rampaging question is who
would want to score a dream
maybe
its scars
need dreams too
writing a shattering of breaking
into an echo of silence
that bitter taste
looks
for someone sweet
feeling
the feeling
of something gone wrong
how do you define
what you can't explain
writing a shadowing of light
flung to the edge
collided with reality
and reality
didn't even blink
you