last night in a dream i interrogated god
why is it the good die young what's the
reason to this we talked we argued we
cried I never did get any answers but
God knows I tried the answers already
know a question for the question who is
it took the creation story claimed it
then took it apart glorifying obedience
in fear
rampaging through the mine stamping
uncertainty
into the heart and then there's that
original sin and something about the
devil to pay
and that golden rule do unto others
obviously isn't really a rule
the Lord giveth the Lord taketh away the
violence gets violent and God just sits
there with nothing to say
Oh
I've read it said in the beginning was
the word and the Word was God I never
read it said
in the beginning was thought and the
thought is to think what that has to do
with anything
last night any drinking interrogative
God why is it the good die young what's
the reason to this we talked we argue we
cry I never did get any answer
but God knows I tried