so
oh
during times of shadow
in the background
a burst
the sun
waits for the moon
to torch
to torch tonight
the lucky motel
at the corner of nowhere
in the past
where memories go
to forget
to erase
her name is lacy
she makes it crazy kind of crazy
his name is
she can hear it
she wants one
but doesn't want
sparks of the stars burning
strong heat
as a passion of storm
fiery rain
lightning
carries thunder
my
she's a good girl
coming to understand
that sometimes this is what good girls
do
what good girls do
in the breath of science
and the magic of home
they held them together
so it's not to feel so
alone so alone
during times of shadow
in the background verse
the sun waits for the moon
to torch tonight
towards sinner
in the breath of sod
in the magic of moon
they held them together
so as not to feel so alone
so alone
you