there's me
there's the other me
there's another me
and then
there are the mormys
we all got a domino to play
so we
been trying to work it out
we don't know how your life turned
or what all that means
but me and me
we're not going back
we already seen
what we couldn't do
any skeletons in our closets
are our own private stash of bones
that scream with no choice
there's no scream like the next screen
reducing the present into nothing
while eternity is now
not then
who's divided into what
and how many
does that mean
love that loves
love that fears
love that possesses
love that needs proof
where's the love that accepts
love that likes
love that cares
there's no forgetting
some realities destiny threw at us
and fate wasn't much help
with this way of loading the load
when we didn't have any say
and it was up to us
to carry us
ah
wow
in the land where the lie is king
using fear like glue
pretending pretending isn't pretending
at least one of the me's
have seen it all
each and every one of us want the glory
but not one of us
likes the way we fall
and strain
is a way of walking
when staying isn't an option
because we've been accused of some
things we did
and some things we didn't do
and we heard i forgive yous
delight
so me and the means
are looking for me
they will answer to me
so far there's no one who will
hey
you