hemp is about earth medicine we got our
medical marijuana issues that serves us
as people but we really need to think
about him because hampus earth medicine
and hemp will benefit all of the human
beings not just the ones that are
dependent on medical marijuana so we
need to start thinking in terms of the
energy of hemp any rats alma sabo
give us this day our daily yeses yes to
life
yes to living yes to carry yes to giving
yes to creating yes to think yes to
clear it yes to balance yes to be
yes to see yes two yeses give us this
day
our daily yes
ah
Oh
confusions chaos chaos is confusion
desperation experience despairs
desperations program belief belief
program manipulated mines mines
manipulate behaviors reactions reactions
behaviors fearful link thinking fearful
inside outside outside inside thought
altering altering thought perceptions
disease II his easing perceptions for
getting medicine medicine for getting
coherent coherence coherence coherent
clear thinking thinking clear prayers
given given prayers peace and love love
and peace realities created created
realities see whatever whatever sees do
we give us this day our daily yeses
yes to yes yes to see yes to be yes free
balance
yes to creating yes to thinking yes to
Claire
yes to carry yes to giving yes to living
yes to life yes to yes give us this day
our daily yes
Oh
you