this is we went on midnight oil in 1988
big deal man so you know everybody
want to be part of the band but but the
reality was it was poor pay in our there
was a hard doorman it was you know they
were very grassroots matter they were
doing hard toward and we did like 32
cities you know in 40 days or something
like that but we got we started losing
band members 70 members of a band
started we started moving losing band
members along the way time we got the
Midwest there were three of us Peter
Garrett said well back to your call it's
gone and I'll them so so anyway we
hung in there
but that's how we did this other
necessity because it was we needed to do
what we needed to do because we needed
to do it you know Amy's that make sense
so we all will just go for it you know
there's no I can't
this needs to be done you know so anyway
I don't know what value that has but it
has some value someone you really think
about it
Oh
so
bring me
Oh
see the woman
she has a young face
in all face
she carries herself well through the
ages she survives
sometimes she is free
in some states she's property on
whose own classes she is worth what she
consumes
in some nations she is delicate strength
she is told she is weak in some classes
she is poverty and she is sister to us
in all life she is our necessity in all
conditions
she is like see the woman eyes flower
swaying on scattered hills Sun dancing
in the bees
see you
lavender butterflies 25
see the woman beauty
streaking summer nights Forrester
parades
mating with new winter snow
see the woman's spirit they serve
encouraged would laugh her breath
hey dream addict Raya