waiting for the rich
but the rich won't hurt
the rich eat us
so
the rich don't work
in the sun's shadow
water melts into ice
running rivers along
one needs justice
but justice
is just ice
in those rivers of one
stars in the night have seen it all
what is it remember it takes time to eat
the soul isn't empty yet it feels that
way
all those stolen moments
still searching to be
long descent of heaven pulls
the prayers
feeling something missing
a constant
of every day
confusion
is a happy place
the great lie
is one
with all the little lies
breaking dreams
and cutting
into the edges
of other dreams
quick
waiting for the rich
but the rich don't hurry
the rich eat us
so the rich don't
but there is
so the rich don't worry
the rich
don't worry
so the rich don't
salmon in the plank
quick