no compromise it's
either it is what it
is so anyway we really appreciate you
all being here and
[Music]
uh
higher
high fire
you
high
fire in between the
Blues in between the blues there are
good days and bad days with everything
and nothing to
lose while the Setting Sun never sits
and the night has no limits
[Music]
the void between freedom and
free dealing with the unnatural
reality a need to be a need to
see
grassfire my DNA needs
THC grass
fire in a world
that that's the way this fire burns
[Music]
it's a grass
fire in the unnatural
Society been trying to
maintain while the
same appear to be clearly
insane with no way to
explain outlasting the Great Law is
sparking
does my
mind grass fire pulling the sky
breathing in sativa design
[Music]
grass
fire and a world that
year that's the way This Fire
Burns it's a grass
fire the void between freedom and free
dealing with the unnatural reality
a need to be a need to see Gras by my
DNA needs
THC dreaming of long times gone and all
that those times brought looking to the
heart of
tomorrow grassfire in a world that
yearns that's the way this fire burns
oh
high
[Applause]
fire
High you high
[Applause]
[Music]