cannabis grower and I have a question
for George we are having a problem and
curing our cannabis to where we're
trying to find a fine line between not
letting it mold but yet letting it get
too dry we keep them in the glass jars
and we do burp the glass stars because
we have had some that did mold and so to
prevent the molding you know we are
burping the jars but then we find that
if we burp the jars too much that it's
getting too dry so I was wondering if he
had any suggestions yeah you probably
have mold on it it's probably got mold
before it goes into the jar and
generally what happens you probably have
some kinds of mildew the big one is the
powdery mildew and it botrytis isn't so
bad but that's botrytis sanara but you
can have a this powdery mildew and this
year it's been horrid we have one year
in Spain where it was horrid two years
and now it's not so bad you have to
start controlling it early on because
it's a systemic thing and it could start
in your plants already right and you
have to kill it before it gets in if you
want to do it organically because
there's a what is the bacillus subtilis
is just one of the Pasillas you know
bacterias and serenades one of the
products that they use right and you
have to put that on your plant before
the mold comes and then you have to keep
that up before the mold comes and then
after that I you know keep mold other
plants that are molding away because
this year it was horrid everything had
planned a mold I have crape myrtles
where I was growing this year in
California and they had it my plants got
it I kept ahead of it on some of them
did an experiment experiment on the
others and they didn't look too well uh
but anyway there's that point you start
there and then after that when you
harvest the plants you take all the
branches you know and you put them in a
bucket of a container like this full of
water with like say a two percent of
a solution of hydrogen peroxide rich in
peroxide yeah h2o2 and then you soak
them in there for a while it sounds kind
of funny when you soak them in there the
mold floats up to the top you skim that
off might take a couple of times and
then you skim that off and then you take
your plants and you lightly spray them
with water with water I don't know
exactly what it does to the trichomes it
may beat them a little bit but i would
use like a light spray not heavy spray
just to kind of rinse it off and then
you shake that and then you let it dry
or you can put it in a harvesting
machine or I mean a trimming machine but
then then you could put it into your
container you know but what that the
second control alloria gave was you know
when it had mold on it already and that
stuff it's hard to see you know once you
see it it's there it's inside the plant
you can't change that so one of the
things I've been playing with I was
planned with one of those green lights
you know you put on your head and walk
around in the green in the row room with
we were filming in a I'm doing a lot of
videos now and we were filming in a grow
room and I was looking around with this
green light and you can see the mold it
sticks out yeah and so the next thing
I'm going to do is get the UV see light
not UVB but UVC it'll burn your eyes but
you can shine it on the mold and it'll
kill it right on the plant you know so
that's a big tip please pay attention
yes there you go no master himself hey
here's what something I'd like to say I
just came from dinner with my friend
Jeff who wrote this book teeming with
microbes and it's an excellent book
wonderful book it's all about growing
organically you put a good biology with
your soil and you're going to grow a lot
bigger plants you're going to have way
fewer problems you're not going to have
gosh all of these invasions to the roots
and everything the money the the
microbes will help so much I've been
using the micro Sol enzymes for years
left that helps the nutrients break down
and
the roots those what other microbes can
well the thing is the thing is with the
microbes they they make the fertilizer
the the nutrients that are available and
they make them available in the soil
there's already a lot of things in the
soil that just are not available to make
it available is a big thing just because
something has a big in PK number you
know like 10 20 30 or whatever on the on
the label doesn't mean that the plant is
going to use it that plant it doesn't
use that always or uses a fraction of it
the main thing is to get the the stuff
used and anyway like I say give this a
shot and you'll be much happier and the
other thing is to you know people spend
a lot for fertilizers and stuff it's not
necessary you can you can grow a
10-pound plant in a 200 gallon container
with good soil and for further for your
flowering fertilizer you have two hands
two hands like this full of bat guano
should have gloves on because because
it's poop it's not good but you throw
that on there and that's it that's all
you have to give for the whole year
that's it you know so um if you feel
your head with good things you don't
have to put too much on your plants it's
a very good thing very good point the
big plant video that you produced you're
working on some others now you got that
one out there on how the best way to do
that i know i'm gearing up right now to
make my cuttings for this this april and
excellent you know i always try to make
them right around the first a year so
they're they're good three to five feet
tall when they go in in April you know
that's that's what you have to remember
this plants really really easy to grow
you know some people call it a weed it
grows everywhere you know everywhere
there's a memory how we grow too yeah
exactly huge 24 plants in an area and
it's just jam-packed and so now I cut it
back to nine I've seen you know three
plants fill a 60 x 30 greenhouse yes yes
yeah then totally possible there's
people are growing plants you know 20 20
pounds
you know it's very very possible it's
not that difficult the main thing is is
it takes time for it to grow that big
you know if it doesn't have time you
know the plants indoors they can grow a
meter high and that's it because the
light is limited and the pot is limiting
but when you have a plant that's that
has plenty of soil and there's time for
the biology to take place in the soil
for the for the roots to absorb
everything you're going to have a lot
bigger plant and like I say you're
taking your cuttings uh right after
Christmas first of the year that's what
you should be doing and you're growing
cuttings to you know I mean and but the
thing is your cuttings have been
acclimated acclimated to this climate
this is a sunset western garden bug zone
eight on eight a or B I can't remember
but uh you know that means the last
average day of frost is April fifteenth
I things okay so I'm in zone 14 where
I'm at in California right now I can
start a bit earlier but the main thing
is you could put these plants outside
you got to keep them from flowering so
that means they're going to need a
little light to keep it from flowering
because you know it's a day light
sensitive plant but the other thing is
they're going to need heat and that's
about it it can be raining cats and dogs
outside as long as they're warm enough
they're going to grow yeah and they
don't need tons light early on in the
year