and mr keystrop founder of normal i want
to welcome you back to the show again
thank you for taking the world's oldest
marijuana smoker
yeah
and we were just talking earlier that
just last year during the boston freedom
festival you were
had your first u.s marijuana arrest yeah
amazing because i've been
smoking out front for
we found a normal 37 years ago and i
think i wasn't as out front the first
four or five years but i went back
recently because i'm working on a book i
went back and was surprised at how
honest about my own drug use i was in
1977 so right somewhere back there i
came out front for some reason they
didn't bust me until last year at the at
the boston freedom rally and i think it
was strictly an accident i mean we
i was smoking a joint behind a booth
with the associate uh purdue associate
director at high times rick cusick and
we weren't trying to get arrested
otherwise i would have lit up a joint on
the stage we were just sharing a joint
so
once they arrested us they kept trying
to drop charges and of course we didn't
want them to drop charges
three different times they offered
finally the judge said if we'll just pay
the court costs and our lawyer objected
said no we don't want to drop charity he
said well i'll waive the court costs and
our lawyer objected
so at any of it the judge finally
figured out he said ah nullification you
know we wanted so we ended up going to
trial we both took the stand under oath
and said of course we were smoking a
joint what else would you be doing at
the boston freedom rally it's a smoking
process
you know it's why obviously only time
once a year i go to boston is to attend
the smoke out and at any event
they ended up convicting us
the people in the jury pool who were
favorable were too honest one of them
even said to the judge
judge if they lit up a joint on the
stand i wouldn't convict them
so all of the good people got taken out
of the jury post and the others didn't
have much trouble but to the judge's
credit he understood it was an
intellectual challenge he had no court
costs no fine no probation the
prosecutor went six months probation
because they knew they'd put us on drug
testing and we'd fail you know but uh
the judge said no no no time served we
we served 20 minutes when they arrested
the 20 minutes so it was i thought it
was we didn't get penalized for going to
trial most people in america do if you
search your rights and go to trial
tell me right you pay a penalty well you
know i went through a federal trial for
growing marijuana back in what was in 93
december of 93 and i was told if i
didn't take the plea bargain offer i was
going to get 10 years so i they offered
me five years that didn't really seem
like much of a bargain so i did go to
trial and i admitted i did everything
that the judge and the you know that the
prosecutor was alleging we didn't even
call any witnesses we did have one point
where they introduced my library that
turned out to be pretty beneficial to me
because when my uh defense attorney was
able to cross-examine the officer on the
stand he said pick up this book
marijuana your legal rights turn to page
219 and read the chapter headline the
cop picked it up he stuttered for about
30 40 seconds the judge said read the
chapter headline the
uh
my lawyer said read the chapter headline
he just kept stuttering finally it came
out it said juries can acquit defendants
even if they think they're guilty and it
was about six pages all about jury
nullification the prosecutor jumped up
objection objection
and the judge says oh you can't object
to your own evidence you can only object
to their evidence now you introduced
this evidence so you can't object to it
and it was kept in the record and i was
acquitted so well i would have done 10
years and i don't really know of any
other man to win on notifications i know
until
until about 1880 in this country defense
lawyers could argue jury nullification
they can say to the jury look if you
think the defendant did is charged but
that it would not be fair to convict him
of a crime which would be a marijuana
smoker obviously most americans know it
shouldn't be a crime
but you can't argue that because of a
supreme court decision i think was in
1880 and so now what has to happen you
have to figure out ways to try to let
the jury know that if they're outraged
by this particular application of the
law they do not have to convict most of
i think they do yeah we just they don't
let them tell the jury unfortunately
that's right and i got lucky
in the books
so the you didn't get so lucky eddie you
no actually uh have you been sentenced
yet no i get uh
sentenced december 21st and this in
federal court yes and to address what
you said about having the courage to
stand by your convictions and take it
clear to trial
two and a half years ago
when they had all four
the major components of the two warrants
i was looking at four life sentences 17
million dollars in fines in an
additional 40 years
prior to the udv decision which is a
major religious decision
uh
they offered me 30 months 18 months in
prison and six months and a halfway
house six months of
home home detention
uh i go back to the very real
possibility on december 1st being
sentenced to prison for the rest of my
natural life
they're asking for a 10-year minimum at
this time which of course at this point
in my life
is almost a life sentence it is a life
sentence uh what useful life i have left
uh as far as being a productive member
yeah i'm 56 now and uh i don't know
we've got some life after yeah 66 don't
you well yes but but the point i'm
making is is if i take 10 years out of
my life right now i understand it's been
in prison when i come out at 66 what
good am i going to be to myself for
anybody else certainly i'll still be
able to do
you know i'm not going to just die but
the other side of it is i might as well
uh
and it's there's a lot to keep fighting
for well the judge uh was emphatic
after she
abolished me for smoking growing or
being around any marijuana she then let
me come up here
and one of the points she was emphatic
about was that i let people know the
dangers of growing marijuana and the
penalties
and i will tell you quite frankly if you
grow marijuana
and the federal government catches you
you cannot have enough money you cannot
have enough power you cannot have enough
friends they will destroy you
my attorneys won this case three times
the first time all of the warrants were
thrown out the judge said do not put
your lying witnesses to the prosecution
on my stand about open field
less than a month later she turned
around and allowed the open field
warrant keeping the case going
the second time we did a flawless
presentation under the
religious freedoms restoration act
for the first five minutes the judge
came out agreed with every point we made
said that i was sincere that this was
religious conviction we made every point
that the supreme court called for she
said that we qualified for
she then spent the next five minutes
telling the prosecutor that he had
failed on every count
he had not shown compelling interest he
had not shown least restrictive means
according to the u diva decision
at that time that case was over i won
the prosecutor submitted
my attorney submitted at that time as
far as i know and i'm not positive maybe
you know better but as far as i know at
that time the judge is supposed to take
everything under consideration
instead
this judge took it on herself to become
the prosecutor
explained that diversion was possible
even though the udv decision said the
diversion in and of itself is possible
at any level and therefore cannot be
used as a sole compelling
reason for a decision
she used it for the so compelling
decision
held holding me over again
in trial when i should have won the case
and
when we actually went to trial
she tailored her jury instructions so
specifically and defined the crime so
specifically
that a gentleman that spoke to the jury
after the fact told me that one of the
ladies that he spoke to
told him with tears running down her
face that they knew i had broken no law
either state or federal
but that because of the judge's specific
jury instructions
and the specific definitions that they
were given they had no choice but to
find me guilty
and sadly in my jury pool as you alluded
to the guys that stood up and said hey
my mother died of marijuana or died of
cancer and used marijuana the last two
years it's the only thing that brought a
relief you're out of here let me ask you
something keith is there any way to kind
of exclude those kind of questions from
the jury say we're not going to ask them
about their marijuana use and you can
either i think a lot of defense lawyers
in fact don't
well first off in states the judge
usually does it not the defense lawyer
but in federal court the defense lawyers
get to do it but what i hear some of the
more experienced ones
will frequently waive their right to ask
questions for the very point you reign
they they sometimes think by the dress
and the way a juror acts that they can
kind of guess who's sympathetic and if
they ask the damn question and the juror
answers it honestly they're thrown out
of the pool so okay
a lot of lawyers think they'd rather
rely on their own instincts than ask the
questions they threw
i'm not sure how many people but at
least six to eight people out of the the
jury pool when they came in with 80
people
uh
nurses
yeah they threw them out threw them out
doctors threw them out anybody that had
any medical knowledge medical knowledge
got thrown out immediately in my case
they were pre-screened before they ever
came to the courtroom right