here's a song My Dad wrote called Bloody
Marry
morning well it's a bloody merry morning
baby left me without warning sometime in
the
night so I'm flying down to Houston with
forgetting her the nature my
fly as we tax it down the runway with
the smog and Haze reminding me of how I
feel just a country boy who's learning
that the pitfalls of the city are
extremely
real all the night life and the parties
Temptation and deceit the order of the
day well well it's a bloody merry
morning cuz I'm leaving baby somewhere
in
La well it's a bloody merry morning baby
left me without warning sometime in the
night so I'm flying down to Houston with
for getting her the nature of
my
n
aahah
as we taxi down the runway with a SM and
Haze reminding me of how I
feel just a country boy who's learning
that the pitfalls of the city are
extremely
real all the night life and the parties
Temptation and deceit the order of the
day well it's a bloody merry morning cuz
I'm leaving baby somewhere in
La well it's a bloody merry morning baby
left me without warning sometime in the
night so I'm flying down to Houston with
for getting her the nature of
my so I'm flying down to Houston with
my