[Music]
shal la la la la la la la la
my feet are dragging on the Redwood
floor I'm moving closer towards my
bedroom door
I've seen this movie in my mind before
I'm going to fade
[Music]
to
to I lie awake but I am falling
fast into the Open Arms Of Sleep at
Last we United in a s of I'm going to
fade
to
fade picture Fe like a
memory I'm glad to see it go away from
me Peace at
Last the greatest stap for free
and when I wake up I won't be
scared because I got my little baby
there peace that
last it's where I want to be
[Music]
the picture Fades like a
memory I'm glad to see it go away from
me oh Peace at Last
the greatest gap for
free and when I wake up W be
scared because I got my little baby
there oh peace
and it's where I
want
[Music]
sh
sh going to
[Music]
f
to fth
[Music]
BL
[Applause]