[Music]
[Applause]
la
[Music]
[Applause]
I was sitting in my Daddy's car
with a joint in both of my
hand smok till the smoke wouldn't stop
and the windows rolled down and I'm
rolling around in my
mind waiting for the time to
fly there's a fork in the road and I
know where to go but I'm scared to do it
and I'm stoned as you
[Music]
are fire and
far I'm a listening fool and I know just
where you
[Music]
are don't take me
back to where I came
from I don't want to go
from I'm only sitting and listening as
my baby Tred to take me
home I'm only sitting there listening at
my baby tried to take me
home all right baby let's get down
[Music]
[Applause]
there's
calm in your
eyes like a shadow
falling taking the piss from
mine you
got a way to
persuade well but I ain't going
nowhere no I ain't leaving
today I'm only SI and listening as my
baby tried to take me
[Music]
home I'm on to sitting and listening and
my baby and TR to take me
home I'm sitting there listening at my
baby Tred to take me
home all right
[Music]
n
a
[Music]
[Applause]
all right
baby
all
right sit right down take my joint
burn it down let's get out of here baby
I don't want to go
home I don't want to go
home I'm only sitting there listening
and my baby tried to take me
home I only sitting there listening at
my baby tried to take me
[Music]
home I'm sit and listen sitting and
listen sitting and listen my baby tried
to take me
[Music]
[Applause]
a come on baby get down
[Music]
n
[Applause]
[Music]
w oh