thank you all so very much for being
here this evening we're here for a
worthy cause but before that just let me
say Jack your spirit will never
die we'll miss you but you will live on
to do your work you know I want to ask
each and every one of you here today to
please please get out there and help us
Rel legalize cannabis and legalize H H
is medicine for our planet it's St
medicine for us you know I tell the this
to people every day we have these huge
meetings at Oregon normal 200 people at
a time coming to look for the medicine
that works so effectively for them but
they lose their jobs they lose their
children through child custody battles
divorces get ugly and they bring in
you're a medical marijuana patient you
don't deserve to have your kids that's
[ __ ] and I'm tired of it I'm fed up
with my people getting arrested
every
day
yes bull it is [ __ ] and we're going
to change that because we're going to
pass the OCTA we're going to pass the
Oregon cannabis Tax Act where people can
go and purchase their medicine without
having to look behind their backs and be
afraid of the man but it's going to take
each and every one of you to put the
join down step away from your bong just
for a little while write a letter send a
fact make a phone call don't just sit
there and take this [ __ ]
anymore that's right we're going to do
it and we're going to do it because jet
taught us well and he knew the power of
him he knew it could save our planet so
everybody remember this day remember he
gave his life to this movement and now
we owe it to him to Rel legalize marij
Marana you know I'm a Mexican I'm a
navaja and my people are blam for
bringing marijuana here and I got to
tell you I am godamn proud of
it that's
right that is it and I want to remind
you all that each of us has one small
voice but together we are a giant raar
that can shake the halls of Congress
please help me legalize him and
cannibis thank you all thank you so very
much