the voters of the state of Washington
passed an
initiative and the voters in the city of
Vancouver passed that initiative by an
even larger margin
54% said yes to the legalization of
recreational use of marijuana we're
pleased in the city of Vancouver to
support the voters of our community
we're going to have six up to six
businesses operating in the city I'm
happy to be here to kick off this
opportunity with Main Street marijuana
I'm pleased to see so much energy and
excitement around this from our
community so please enjoy do it safely
do it within the law support our local
business I'm proud of what these guys
have accomplished I know they want to be
good neighbors they've outreached to the
businesses and the neighbors here in
Uptown Village and I think this is a
great this is a great turning of a new
chapter for the city of Vancouver thank
you to and
everyone all right
[Music]
[Applause]