well about four years ago in
2010 uh Ben had noticed some lumps he
had on his posterior um being a former
naturopathic physician's
assistant he could kind of almost
predict that it might be cancer but he
wasn't quite sure he got blown off by
his family doctor he wasn't uh going to
give us a referral so he told them it
was a calcium deposit don't worry about
it but he was already growing some
marijuana for the purpose of um dealing
with his uh his uh heart condition um
kind of keeping his blood pressure at a
at a rate where it would give him a
little bit of
energy and uh kind of turn off the
gravity amplifier he'd been watching um
YouTube he saw the YouTube show on um I
guess the the Rick Simpson story ah and
when he learned about that run from the
Cure and so he uh he decided to apply
that just thinking you know this might
this this lump might be uh cancer and he
applied it and he thought well if it's
not let's just see what it does well he
had a golf ball sized well he found out
later it was a tumor uh and after
applying it topically for within about
two months it shrank down to the size of
a well down to a little pink spot I mean
I mean it it uh went below the surface
of a skin and disappeared So eventually
um someone must have called the police
thinking they smelled marijuana in our
apartment and uh and so we were raided
and he had he had shown the the police
officer what he had been using the
marijuana for that he was making
cannabis oil and he even uh even showed
him you know uh how he applied it before
he confiscated it before the the officer
Furlong detective Furlong confiscated it
um so we were arrested we went through a
year of um basically firing attorneys
trying to get someone who would
represent us and not force us to plea
out and then eventually um we just gave
up on that and went ahead and took a
guilty plea of manufacturing he wanted
to present a medical defense no one was
was going to hear it and they just
weren't going to go with it so we've
been we had been on probation for a
couple of years um during the the first
couple of months uh in
2011 he had gone to um finally got a
referral to an
oncologist who came back with a result
um after giving him a biopsy that it was
in fact angio sarcoma cancer it is a
cancer of the in lining of the blood
vessels which appears as uh tumors on
the skin above the the surface of the
skin
and
so while on probation Ben decided to
just try to get a hold of whatever plant
material he could um sometimes ditch
weed friends would Harvest some out of
the field you know in Iowa it just grows
everywhere um and he would make uh can
cannabis oil out of that sometimes he
had to go to the street to buy cannabis
oil but eventually you he was able to
acquire just enough for a you know a
couple of grams here or there um he
would ingest them and he was he was able
to keep the tumors from growing and some
of them would even shrink you know some
of the smaller ones especially now this
went on for well about two and a half
years and then in June
2013 well I'm I'm getting ahead of
myself uh he started growing cannabis in
a trailer in the backyard um his best
friend helped him and uh he had all uh
higher CBD strains I think he had um
canonic which I think came from some z7s
uh seeds um that he' ordered from Mr
Nice I think mhm and so he had uh he had
plants that were you know eventually
going to possibly you know if he could
acquire enough uh he could make enough
oil to maybe wipe out this cancer cuz at
this point it was at stage one they were
really small
tumors well and then 2013 June of 20
2013 um we were raided and they brought
about 20 SWAT agents uh in at 5:45 a.m.
to the house um banging on the door
screaming uh I was the first one to the
door and I
had about well about six agents pointing
you know some pretty high power
uh Weaponry in my face um so you know it
kind of scared the crap out of all of us
um I can imagine actually I've been in
that situation myself so well I know
what that's like yeah and and his
elderly parents were
upstairs you know it it uh kind of it
shocked them um there was just the five
of us living there so they ended up
Prosecuting all five of you though they
did the parents your son mhm both of
view yeah that's just outrageous yeah
you know that's what they do is they
they try to pile on as many charges as
they possibly can so they can then
manipulate you to do what they want you
to do like we're going to torture your
wife and your son and your parents if
you don't do exactly what we say to do
you know it's
disgusting you know that our law
enforcement has has turned to this it's
really the prosecutors and the police
are in charge of the whole system and
choosing how to charge you and uh uh
make you you know dance to their tune or
else right yeah it appeared that way
I they uh they didn't arrest his parents
but they did charge them with operating
a drug housee kind of makes it sound how
parents
Bon
they 70 they are um respectively I think
70 at the time they were 76 and 77 years
old that's so Benton I just got a let
our audience know you you've been the
recipient of some
beneficial cannabis oil here in Oregon
as a legal medical marijuana patient I'm
proud to say that you know we were able
to help you get that medical marijuana
permit and have helped you out with some
medicine in the past but yeah I know but
right now you're on a pretty big dose of
of uh RSO
oil do yeah yeah six grams a day that's
a lot that six grams is in fact I don't
think I've ever heard of anybody taking
six grams in a single day so yeah that's
a lot I figured you vaporized twice that
much you would think so but no no it's
not true maybe I wish I could uh well
half my right lung is full of tumors I
just found out so now that cancer is
metastasized to your lungs and where
else in my liver your liver and your
lungs and so you've just been convicted
when about 10 days ago
uh just about two weeks ago yeah about
two weeks ago and so fortunately you
with a bond the state has allowed you to
come here and visit Oregon a few times M
right yeah so they yeah they started
letting me come here so I could survive
to make it to the end of trial right I
could good point you want to go on with
the story Loretta and what happened sure
well when we were arrested um his
parents had bonded us out um but a
couple of weeks later uh because we'd
been on probation our probation
officers uh issued warrants for our
arrest again so back to jail we went uh
this time there was a $5,000 cash only
Bond held over both of us and so his
parents being you know broke completely
unable to get us out they couldn't do
anything about it we uh ended up staying
there well he stayed in for 40 days um
he was uh he was constantly trying to
draw to the attention of the medical
staff his tumors which were starting to
grow um without anything um and I've got
to say that I've seen some pictures of
your tumors
online and I just very sorry that you
have to endure such painful lesions they
they look uh like look pretty bad I've
seen seen some other people with saroma
back before they had the antiviral
agents when people were dying from AIDS
yeah kind of reminded me of that it's a
similar kind of cancer isn't it yeah I
imagine it's very simil I think it's it
might be the same form that ended up
killing so many AIDS patients as you
have a compromised immune system that
too my uh immune system is not quite as
compromised as it could they probably
should be actually but you've got this
this rare form of cancer so you want to
tell us about the trial uh
Loretta yes um well we it's taken
several months since uh we got out of
jail um we had uh pretty good
representation uh each of us um they had
a lot of different things that they
wanted to do um they wanted to try to
see if they could get all of the
evidence suppressed and the whole case
thrown out of court because we live in a
rural area in Iowa it's on private
property and so when the police had been
going through our trash to try to find
something they said they found a stem
and that was the justification for the
warrant they had been trespassing on a
private drive so we had upcoming motions
uh hearings for the Motions on uh
suppression to try to see if the the
warrant was even valid um all of these
different different things so it it's
taken well it's taken an entire year
since the uh original uh
raid um but we wanted a jury of our
peers and our you know fortunately we
had attorneys who were you know with it
all the way they were filing motions
they were doing everything they could
and
um problem is his good attorney lost her
license because well it doesn't seem to
make any sense she had been doing a lot
of work for him and I think that there
was somebody higher up trying to kind of
cut her out of the way and as you know
as I'll as I'll describe to you what
happened during the trial sort of the
control yet mind control or just wanting
to have another conviction no matter
what uh it seemed like uh it was not a
fair trial the judge would not allow a
medical defense um he wouldn't even
allow Ben to tell the jury that he had
cancer he wasn't even allowed to discuss
his condition um at all the jury had no
idea
what you folks were facing or the very
reason you were doing
this and then they also prosecuted your
son yes yeah and well his friend
originally but they they offered a plea
agreement to his friend and I guess he
took it because he was very he was very
scared uh he wasn't going to be throwing
us under the bus mind you he just he had
been looking for an opportunity to
become a States witness so that it would
give him an opportunity to when you know
taking the witness stand to to just you
know risk all risk getting thrown and
contempt to court to say look this is
what my friend was going through I was
helping him he has cancer he was making
cannabis oil well it seemed like the
state was pretty much onto the strategy
of our defense and they didn't allow
that it controlled uh every
aspect every aspect of the the jury
trial and it took a good 3 Days To even
select a jury because so many people had
already read um newspaper articles that
um the Quad City Times uh writer uh
Brian wellner had been following up on
our story since September MH of uh last
year and just there was just so much
control and uh you know constantly uh
keeping the jury in the dark they would
take them in the other room to address
issues going on with Ben's health um he
needed to take a lot of breaks and then
on the 7th of July uh right in the
middle of the trial he pretty much
collapsed he had um we had to rush him
to the hospital called an ambulance and
his uh potassium levels and his
hemoglobin had just dropped uh he'd been
sweating um profusely um just having
cold sweats for the last couple of
months because at this point he's at
stage four of his cancer um everything
metastasized when he was in jail so it
just kind of went from stage one to
stage three to stage four in a matter of
months so
he he's at this he's at the point now
where cold sweats and you know nausea
and things like that start to set in so
I mean this this happened
um you know without the jury having any
idea they were just shoved off to their
little deliberation room probably under
lock and key and not allowed to even
look out the window and see the fire
trucks that you know came pulling up in
front of the uh the ambulance pulling up
in front of the
courthouse and the judge was not uh very
understanding like he promised he would
be about Ben's condition
he uh he basically uh thought that Ben
was mingering that maybe he was faking
something to try to get out of this
trial which is not the case at all we we
got him to the hospital and they had to
give him a
transfusion and uh the doctor's orders
were no he's not going anywhere tonight
he's staying here we're going to watch
over him and the next morning they were
trying to address you know keeping him
uh keeping his pain medication
stabilized and all of those things but
the judge was insistent well he needs to
be back the next morning we need to get
on with this trial so it was just it was
inhumane it's incredibly inhumane yeah
I'm sorry I'm ashamed for our government
that's done this to you and uh you know
I wish I could offer you Sanctuary here
in Oregon I mean maybe we can put you in
a local church or something you know and
uh say you know no more you know they're
in the safe Zone you know they that's an
ancient concept that we should have
something like that I think especially
for someone going through that it's just
heartbreaking we appreciate it
too there's just no way we could bow out
of this fight now right now what do you
think they they mentioned an appeal Bond
right now you're here in Oregon on a
bond uh do you think it's likely you had
any communication that says you might be
allowed to continue to be on appeal Bond
well I'm actually not on a bond my my
wife is out on bond but I they let me
out of jail to avoid any medical
expenses I see I see so uh technically
until uh sentencing if they sentence me
to any jail time or any anything at all
they're going to try to put me in prison
I don't know if they'll wait until I
apply uh or appeal it before they try to
put me in jail otherwise if they put me
in jail then I can bond out from their
probably Casper I was just all the
support that seems to be rallying around
the case and all that you've gone
through I know in California they have
groups that show up at cour houses with
uh signs and make a lot of noise out
outside so you any
Community has there been there was noise
of it happening but we haven't seen a
lot so you're in a little area though
there's not any big urban area except De
Moine in in Iowa right so for its area
uh the Quad City's area is is pretty big
it's uh it's about Iowa City size maybe
bigger but the the community support's
been really really and why did you have
such a the problem with your attorneys
taking your case in the direction you
wanted I mean it's your
case um I was settled with him in the
last with a month to go before uh jury
selection and then I wasn't even
contacted by him for another two weeks
so we had two weeks to go to build a
case and first thing uh he wanted was to
try to deal with this on
a on a
a plea and I just demanded he'd never
ever enter into that train of thought
again and that's when we started
clashing but he he had plans on trying
to change things instead of being
straight with me and backing out when I
still had time to give somebody else
exactly the same chance he had to at
least support me or Letta how do you
think things are going to go for
yourself and your son and your your
husband here do you have any insight or
just hopes and prayers hopes and prayers
mostly uh yeah
it's it's been suggested that we'll have
um I well I I did talk to his former
attorney and she said something about
appeals Bond so I'm really not
completely you know educated about that
whole process we have talked other
people who have been through this
process before who think that we are uh
in a position to wait I really don't at
this point I don't think after all the
attention that this judge Henry
leam uh has has had which has not been
the right kind of attention he's he
certainly is not a hero now everyone in
Iowa and basically Nationwide since the
story went out on the Associated Press
It's Been Everywhere uh he they've had
to shut down the phone lines to uh his
yeah his lines and uh the prosecutor's
uh phone lines and uh there's just been
so so many people calling I think when
is your sentencing coming up you're here
in Oregon for just a few days like a
week or less than a week yeah it'll the
uh sentencing is on August 28th August
28th so you want people to contact this
judge and uh to be there in support of
you on August 28th obviously there is
there is also a group on uh Facebook
free McKenzie so it's
facebook.com/frequencyseries
that will be at the Scott County
Courthouse in dport Iowa I see so we
will have some people showing up maybe
with picket signs maybe just to show up
in the courtroom if you know if they'll
let them in so what's this judge's name
in Scott County Iowa Davenport Iowa yes
what's his name judge Henry leam Henry
laam all right