hello and welcome to the seattle million
marijuana march which is put on by the
folks with the seattle hemp fest we're
here to document
the march which leaves from seattle's
volunteer park and heads over to west
lake park over in downtown seattle looks
like a crowd of about 300 people here at
the start of the march
maybe a little more it's growing so
that's a good thing
and so we're about four minutes away
from the start of the march
now that the truth is out
even the politicians have figured this
thing out
you can go hit it in their own prayers
might help you loosen your eye and
all the legalize
wake up
because it's just a matter of life
but you cannot win the fight
hey mr politicians
there is a piece
we
it's a dream so believe
how we've done it so we
don't have to do
it again
so we don't have to do it again
america
it's a dream so believe
there was a peace resolution and a
peaceful revolution
and a peaceful solution to save america
and the peaceful
america
these videos
we are here today as part of a global
voice that is screaming we will not be
persecuted we will not be scapegoated we
will not be demonized or imprisoned any
longer this is a civil rights movement
and it's sweeping the world
as adults in a free society we demand
the right to make our own educated and
informed choices
on what we use for medicine
in industry
for spiritual purposes and for
recreation as adults
to our government we are saying we do
not need you in our living rooms thank
you
we do not need you in our bedrooms we do
not need you in our grow rooms and we
don't need you in our goddamn blood
streams that's for sure
we're saying
no more orphans no more clear cuts no
more ocean of tears no more pot war we
demand cannabis amnesty now for all
prisoners
these
we're living in some wild times man
nobody has ever lived in a time like
this in the history of humanity things
are changing fast
these are times of major transmission
for human behavior this change is
manifesting in so many ways that it
would be difficult to compute them all
one can only guess what the result of
this gradual metamorphosis will be but
there's one thing that is certain to any
discerning person
uh
and that is
as a people to have any kind of positive
impact or effect on creating a desirable
future for the generations that surely
will come show their global calamity we
got to come together right now
the people who will have the most
successful impact on the world will be
those who follow principles and ideals
based on values that are morally and
ethically right that are sound and
self-evident
policies of governments which condone
acts that are unlawful to the
sovereignty and autonomy of the
individual as a human being should not
be considered acceptable or tolerable by
the citizens of those governments
these include
these include policies that strip rights
of free speech choice of religion racial
and sexual equality and other rights
that do not interfere with or prevent
the rights of others
america has declared war on drugs
america's war is humanely unlawful it's
unacceptable unacceptable human rights
violations across the board have
resulted from the criminalization of
otherwise decent law-abiding citizens
merely for possessing using or selling
only those drugs which the established
status quo hasn't had the opportunity to
cultivate some sort of financial
monopoly on yet
but there's a lot of money to be made
from the war on drugs
war on drugs you know it's not even
possible you can't do that you can only
wage a war on people
so the concept is logically flawed by
design
we stand here on the 50th anniversary of
the universal declaration of human
rights but we have more people in jail
in the united states than any other
country in the free world
the vast majority of them are in for
victimless non-violent crimes many time
of them many of them are first offenders
previous to today the very proclamation
of a drug war was absurd
to have a war there must be two opposing
sides both taking some casualties it
would be more accurate to call the
previous years a drug massacre
by demonizing by criminalization people
who choose to recreationally use or sell
or buy or manufacture substances not
approved by the government we cannot
defend ourselves ourselves unless we
risk arrest and incarceration the loss
of our job in our home nobody has
statistics on responsible recreational
users of substances because those people
aren't creating any recordable problem
their lives are in society
the emergency room does not receive the
folks while they're casually kicking
back on their sofa driving the remote
control
my admittedly radical leftist claim of
cultural genocide of sorts i believe is
qualified by the gross discrimination
against and deliberate
i'll try it's a long speech i'll try to
slow down deliberate scapegoating of
people who use illicit drugs even
marijuana unarguably the mildest drug of
all and by most definitions an herb not
a drug an herb
one marijuana felony one marijuana
felony like throwing 100 plants or more
will result in the loss of all welfare
and other public aid
student loans and pell grants public
housing
gi bill
also the forfeit laws they're not
forfeit laws they're seizure laws
scorpion means you voluntarily gave it
up
they're taking it
house car bank account computers they'll
wipe you out man they can result from
one felony marijuana arrest mandatory
minimum sentencing guidelines prevent
judges
from stopping 20 to 30 year sentences
for marijuana offenses with no parole
possible
rapists pedophiles murderers for some
reason their crimes are not worthy of
such punishment and in most cases they
get much less sentences according to our
law
the drug massacre is over
now with the vast network of very
sophisticated and dedicated activists
many of them family members of prisoners
or ex-prisoners themselves there's a
formidable foe to the phony unwinnable
catchphrase war on drugs
there is a worldwide movement of
opposition based on humanitarian ethics
and common sense facing compassion and
seeking an all-out total war as we are
on addiction poverty and abuse
that's what we need to fight