ham dotnet is an internet service
provider
it is the whole of the web design for
sale that's website how many people see
on our website wwlp.com I introduce you
to my good friend and colleague Robert
lund a owner and operator of him net
[Applause]
hello Seattle right here in the middle
Westlake Center you guys are awesome
those of you tend to some of the marches
against prohibition last year I'm sure
you can appreciate the members we see
here today I love you today we've been
marching and speaking out against the
numerous and justices brought on the
American people by the war on drugs we
may be the first true people with
differing opinions on the issues but one
thing is common amongst us all the war
on drugs has affected the lives of
everyone of us enough so that you're
willing to get in the streets and March
and say that things have got to change
the drug war is wrong
we know the drug was wrong because it's
fraught with injustice forfeiture laws
are unjust because they allow a home or
car be taken without an individual be to
be charged with a crime mandatory
minimums are unjust because there's no
room to consider the circumstances that
go along with the rest the judge should
have an option the Legislature should
not be saying you go to jail for ten
years
because you are related or heard about a
drug bust and the cannabis prohibition
is unjust our laws are hypocrisy
parla it's hypocrisy that we can drink
alcohol we killed hundreds of people
every year
[Applause]
it's a [ __ ] receipt you can legally
smoke nicotine and yet it kills hundreds
of thousands of people every year and
yet I'll stand here is that you have the
right to do that you should as a free
American being able to consume nicotine
the drink alcohol and smoke pot so
what's the result of this unjust war
well for example there's a mr. gray who
was the US Marine for five years he went
off and served this country in the Gulf
War he came back with numerous
unexplainable illnesses uncontrollable
vomiting he went to the VA hospital 20
times they prescribed numerous legal
drugs none of them which could help him
so finally he turned like many sufferers
of the Gulf War Syndrome due to
marijuana and he found relief and how do
we thank him steal his [ __ ] house
[Applause]
another Justice is the Eastside
Narcotics Task Force we allow them to
engage in terrorist tactics destroying
homes and traumatizing children house
after house after house that's unjust
I'm just that will foster who grows
marijuana for his own personal medical
reason should be sentenced to 93 years
in jail
the trunk more needs to change 80% of
our forfeitures occur where no
individual 'its was charged with a crime
I think this is such an injustice and we
don't have to look farther than our own
law of Washington to see the problems
with this law so I'm gonna read the
three pillars of the Washington State
forfeiture law tenet number one and this
is in the hip voters guide if you saw
this last year number one in cases
involving property personal property the
burden of producing evidence shall be
upon the person claiming to be the
lawful owner of the property that's you
that's not the cops if they plan
something to shove you up to you to
prove it if your friend has a joint in
your car and they take your car it's
your responsibility to prove it there's
no due process in that and there's no
justice in that look at the next two
corners of the Washington state farm to
drill on number two is each seizing
agency sorry meant to the state
treasurer and about equal to ten percent
of the net proceeds of any of the
property forfeit is what happens to the
other ninety percent property and the
net proceeds not required to be paid to
the State Treasurer shall be retained by
the seizing law enforcement agency
[Applause]
and as an invitation for corruptness
it's no longer a balanced justice system
that we're supposed to have in the
United States the forfeiture laws and
the drug war needs to change
[Applause]
[Music]