Chris serves as a lead advocate at the
Coalition for medical marijuana in New
Jersey and the pennsylvanians for
medical marijuana he also serves on the
board of Philadelphia normal and normal
New Jersey and was the founder of
normals highly-rated podcasts back when
he was based in Santa Fe New Mexico
Chris tell us about new jersey and
philly
hello yes
hi pot is not just for California
anymore uh ya know we've had we've had a
long wonderful tradition with marijuana
on the east coast but really in the last
couple of years we've seen a whirlwind
of reform activity on the East Coast we
are bound to the legislative process we
do not have a ballot initiative process
that we can employ to change law or
bring up new law but I'll tell you what
this year we've seen something really
revolutionary happened in Philadelphia
so I am the bearer of good bad news I'm
sure you've heard about New Jersey's
medical marijuana law and I'm working
very hard on this with Ken wool ski at
the Coalition for medical marijuana New
Jersey Ken's been at these conferences
he attends the patients have time
conference he's a registered nurse and
the director of our coalition but i have
to tell you and we're getting to this in
just a second New Jersey is about to run
a revolution on medical marijuana and
it's not a revolution any of us are
going to be real happy with you know
talk about i'm going to talk about the
good stuff first right here on the
screen you will see the july issue of
philadelphia magazine they interviewed
women for the pot is back now all of us
are saying well where did pot go it
didn't go on vacation you know pots
always been around but it looks like the
media in Philadelphia in new york and
new jersey are just finally starting to
wake up with to the fact that they can
cover this that this is an issue that
isn't just in california this is an
issue that exists around them every day
what Philadelphia Magazine went out and
did was interview yuppies smoking pot on
the main line in Philadelphia after work
bankers a lot of women I hate to use the
term but sort of this the Stiletto
stoner kind of an interview is what this
turned into be myself and state senator
daylin leach were the only people quoted
with our real name in what was a long
feature length article here they also
sampled the local marijuana in
Philadelphia and did a write-up of that
which was good stuff but this was an
innovation I'll tell ya and it wasn't
very savvy the guy starts out the
article and he says I'm a cop but I can
get you know I look like a cop but I can
get great marijuana around Philadelphia
well I'm here to tell you if you don't
look like a cop you can get even better
marijuana around Philadelphia so
you know and actually it was the
Philadelphia Police that we worked
really closely with this year and I have
to thank Harry Levine for his support
you know we pointed out the racial
disparity on the arrests in Philadelphia
this year in the city responded
positively to this is the first sign
that really reached out to municipal
government and they sort of reached out
back to us and had a change so let's
talk a little bit about that pot is back
in Philadelphia New Jersey folks as you
can see on this magazine here New Jersey
passed a medical marijuana law that's
right there at the Statehouse that's our
senators Nicholas qatari of New Jersey I
had just had a meeting with him a couple
of weeks ago New Jersey has a new
resolution right now to support HR 28 35
New Jersey could be the first state to
so to pass a resolution to support the
federal medical marijuana patient
protection act of course it's sponsored
by Barney Frank he's a New Jersey boy he
was born in Bayonne we're in touch with
Congressman Frank to do some appearances
in New Jersey about the new resolution
that's the good news the bad news is we
passed a medical marijuana law this year
that is the most restrictive in the
nation and in implementing this law we
are up against one of the biggest
hurdles i have seen in the marijuana
movement thus far New Jersey is a unique
place to have a medical marijuana law
pass it is where four of the seven
largest pharmaceutical companies in the
world are based it is a state that has
unique state regulations that exist for
this medical and pharmaceutical industry
in order to work with the state and
these entities and the universities and
everything like that you might have
heard that they were going to give a
monopoly production contract to Rutgers
University this year but it wasn't
really just Rutgers University it was
Rutgers University and a couple of small
companies that already work on
plant-based pharmaceuticals through
clinical trials and they were really
going to try this and what's going to be
next for New Jersey there were looking
on the implementation of the medical
marijuana law they are proposing that
six alternative treatment centers serve
the entire state of New Jersey they are
still moving towards a centralized
production of medical marijuana what
will that mean well we as advocates have
our foot in the door but we need a
little help pushing behind us or the
door is going to close right on our foot
because other than us lobbying the state
government we have the heavies the
medical and the pharmaceutical industry
in New Jersey are about to sink a test
well into medical marijuana and it could
be approved right through the state law
you know if it weren't for the tenacity
of this Democratic senator from New
Jersey they would have written Rutgers
University into the law and we'd all be
turning around going what happened and
that is the truth of what's happening in
New Jersey right now it doesn't receive
the attention that it deserves and
because it's so quiet through this
implementation phase it's just what
these corporate interests want I want to
go back to the slide here that's us in
front of the Statehouse you know with a
few press conferences ken will ski our
patient population of New Jersey and Ms
patient who went on trial named John
Wilson we've garnered significant media
attention and we turned the corner on
the Rutgers University idea but our
governor chris christie republican
governor of new jersey think of him if
you've ever seen the Sopranos he's sort
of like Tony Soprano mixed with karl
rove you know that's that's what we have
is our governor in New Jersey this guy's
a former US Attorney he says he believes
in medical marijuana but he wants to do
it right
now the New Jersey State teaching
hospitals association was going to get
the monopoly contract on distribution
their representative Rick Goldstein no
relation showed up at the high times
medical cannabis cup and he found every
grower he could and he asked them if you
could only grow three strains of
marijuana what would they be and I think
you all know what that means
the
centralization the homogenous ation of
medical marijuana could start in new
jersey and
i think that the interest that we are
fighting against is that small business
and this movement and the ideal of
medical marijuana needs to be
reinstalled here
medical marijuana is a challenge to the
health care system of America overall it
requires doctors and patients to talk to
each other it requires doctors to go and
look up specific information it requires
a real relationship this is not the
health care that we have today where you
go in and you speak to your physician
for five minutes and get prescribed a
pill
they want to do that with medical
marijuana they want some sort of
consistent homogenized brand for this
that doctors are comfortable with this
comfort zone of the medical industry is
what we're fighting against but I think
that in New Jersey we are working hard
to meld these ideals it is inevitable
that corporate interests are going to
get involved with medical marijuana I'm
not going to be able to fight them in
New Jersey are nonprofits there as hard
as we work and as hard as our volunteers
work we're not gonna be able to fight
that interest in New Jersey and it's
inevitable that they're going to get
involved nationally the question is do
we have a place at the table or do they
try and take it over one hundred percent
and the models in New Jersey have
already been taken on in Washington DC
two ounces no home cultivation believe
me we're not happy about this law and
we're fighting to change it every day
but again the inevitability of corporate
interest seeing and counting their coin
on medical marijuana right now in New
Jersey is the reality how this is going
to play out i wish i could tell you here
at the conference today but we will see
it happen over the next six months now
let's talk about happy stuff
that is the District Attorney of
Philadelphia standing with myself and
the radio producer Marty Moscow lean of
radio times in Philadelphia he is the
first african-american district attorney
in Philadelphia's history Seth Williams
he's elected this year and we eased the
possession penalty for all Philadelphia
residents this year it was through one
set of data three meetings with city
officials and police and this gentleman
right here seeking the support of the
state Supreme Court
Philadelphia was the last County in
Pennsylvania that required every single
person who was caught with any amount of
marijuana from a joint to 30 grams to be
prosecuted through the court to make a
$300 bail hearing and to show up for
criminal prosecution even if they were
going to take a disorderly conduct plea
4,700 cases a year
seventy-five percent black men between
the age of 19 and 35 only ten white
women a month are cited for marijuana
possession in Philadelphia now I'm
Philly normal I can find more than ten
white women smoking pot we're walking in
the city for like ten minutes you know
but the truth is is that Philadelphia
Police only find ten white women a month
but they find 362 black men a month to
cite for marijuana possession less than
30 grams the procedure before was go to
court make bail the procedure now
starting in June is that you go into a
diversion program at the point of arrest
you are offered the diversion program
you no longer have to make bail you show
up in court you pay a two-hundred-dollar
fine and it is automatically expunged
from your record this is a tangible
change for the marijuana consumers of
Philadelphia this year and this has been
of positive benefit I cannot even tell
you how many people hug me at concerts
and thank me because they were in there
like I got busted last year but this
year it was so different so but you know
it's Seth Williams and Harry Levine
who's sitting out here i have to tell
you weren't harry's data and his work in
New York you know and knowing how to
pursue that and getting the data and
really highlighting the racial disparity
you know this is the key for us on the
East Coast this is where we found police
and prosecutors and city officials there
was no argument back from them there is
no opposition to the racial disparity
argument it's bad any way you look at it
it's a problem that people want to solve
and it's our job to give them the tools
to do that oh
yeah okay so New York this year just so
everybody didn't miss there was the
national normal ad ran in Times Square
that's me and Rick music and steve blum
from celeb stoner and Danny Danko from
High Times Magazine we went up there it
was running we waited the afternoon it
ran on this big screen so we had to wait
for the 15 seconds to take the picture
but national normal times square this
year had an ad millions of people saw it
this year and you know what it's not
like people are going oh my god there's
a marijuana leaf on Times Square people
see that come up and they cheer and that
is what is happening on the east coast
folks
we had a 1200 people march up south
street this year for the global cannabis
March it was an excellent parade I think
that was a video it didn't quite start
yet though let me see if I'm going to
destroy starting yeah it's okay if it
doesn't start it was our biggest March
ever there were no arrests at the at the
annual cannabis March this year I want
to let people know that while the focus
of reform activity is rightfully so on
California this year that New Jersey and
Philadelphia have seen tremendous
strides forward there is a medical
marijuana bill in Pennsylvania right now
HB 1393 we got it introduced in the
house in the Senate just three weeks ago
in Pittsburgh we had special hearings
where we skyped in Lester Grinspoon
which was awesome we had dr. Cyril Wecht
a forensic pathologist testified that in
over 38,000 autopsies cannabis was never
cause of death of course we know that
but it's important to hear that I you
know and I know it may seem passe to a
lot of folks who have already won these
battles in other states but this is a
discussion that never happened in the
Keystone State they never had a bill in
Pennsylvania ever before this year and
it's a discussion people want to have
eighty percent of Pennsylvanians support
medical marijuana from both parties it
is the most strongly supported
Republican public policy issue in the
state of Pennsylvania people think
amongst the Republicans and Democrats
that medical the medical marijuana bill
is more positive than any candidate for
governor any candidate for Congress then
the job of the legislature what we need
to do is run medical marijuana for
office and we're in every single seed
you know but that is that is really
what's happening you know in
Pennsylvania people need to wait you
know it's hard for people to handle this
look politicians get a thirty seven
forty percent approval rating on a pole
and they're popping champagne bottles
and trying to have sex with the interns
in the office eighty percent is
something that they don't know how to
handle it is the most popular public
policy issue the state of Pennsylvania
has ever pulled is this medical
marijuana bill politicians politico's
people in the Statehouse and the media
struggle with the popularity of medical
marijuana on this basis now it's our job
to make sure that marijuana law reform
whether that be decriminalization
realization or medical marijuana bills
we need to turn this corner with the
politicos in America especially the
state legislators this medical marijuana
is not controversial eighty percent
approval rating give me a break this is
the most positive political capital you
can have in America today if you want to
win elections you need to support
marijuana reform and that's the message
we're going to take out there the East
Coast thank you everybody
[Applause]