[Applause]
I first smoked pot 45 years ago when I
was a freshman at Georgetown Law School
in Washington DC and I've been a regular
smoker ever since. There is nothing
wrong with the responsible use of
marijuana. It was 40 years ago next
month that normal was formed. And at the
time, and so we've been at this now for
four decades. And our position then and
our position now is there's absolutely
nothing wrong with responsible use of
marijuana by adults and it should be of
no interest or concern to the
government. They have no they have no
business knowing whether we smoke or why
we smoke.
As Allan mentioned in his opening
comments, we really are at a tipping
point in this country. There are more
living Americans who have smoked
marijuana than living Americans who have
not. And with the increasing support we
have from the public now, we've made
more political progress in the last five
years than in the first 35. So folks, we
are very close to winning this. Closer
than it looks like when you're out
struggling on the street level. I
understand. But once change begins, it
happens more quickly than you
anticipate.
[Applause]