i first smoked pot 45 years ago when i
was a freshman at georgetown law school
in washington d.c and i've been a
regular smoker ever since there is
nothing wrong with the responsible use
of marijuana
it was 40 years ago next month that
normal was formed
and at the time
and so we've been at this now for four
decades and our position then and our
position now is
there's absolutely nothing wrong with
the responsible use of marijuana by
adults and it should be of no interest
or concern to the government they have
no they have no business knowing whether
we smoke or why we smoke
as alan mentioned in his opening
comments we really are at a tipping
point in this country there are more
living americans who have smoked
marijuana than living americans who have
not
and with the increasing support we have
from the public now
we've made more political progress in
the last five years than in the first 35
so folks we are very close to winning
this closer than it looks like when
you're out struggling on the street
level i understand but once change
begins it happens more quickly than you
anticipate
now i want to introduce you now to some
of the people who are
responsible for the progress we're
making i don't for a moment suggest that
these are the only important projects
around the country because frankly there
are so many of those we couldn't
possibly have everyone represented on a
panel or we wouldn't have time during
the three-day weekend but this is a fair
sample i think of the very good positive
progressive work that's going on on this
issue
um
the first person i'd like to introduce
uh is because we're here in his home
state john sajo is the executive
director of a group called voter power
they are the primary sponsor of
initiative 74 i believe it is is that
right john 74 in oregon which would
create a
state license dispensary system
where right now in oregon as healey
explained i'm sure
they have medical marijuana and you can
share it among your friends and give it
away but nobody is legally allowed to
sell it well with some luck in november
that's going to change please welcome
john sajo
thanks keith and uh welcome all you
normal attendees if there's any of you
that are my age or a little older you
might remember the last time normal had
the
annual conference in in portland was
and uh back then we also had a measure
on the ballot to legalize personal use
of marijuana i was the
main person on that and uh we've come a
long way that year we got 26.3 percent
yes vote and it was a real sobering
lesson and so it's exciting to be with
you all here now when we are on the
verge of not only being on the ballot
but winning the election so this is an
exciting time
i think
i assume you're all here because you
love marijuana and you would like to
legalize it
good
well let me tell you you know when i
started out as a young activist many
decades ago i looked at it and you know
tried to figure out well how do we do
that you know is it going to be do we go
to our legislatures do we go to congress
do we you know bring court cases where
the laws are thrown out and i i quickly
realized that the way we're going to
legalize marijuana is using the
initiative process and that has been how
most of the major gains have happened
that's how we got you know prop 215 in
california brought us the first medical
marijuana law now we have 14 states
plus d.c and most of them came with
initiatives so we need to embrace the
initiative process the people are far
ahead of the politicians on this issue
and that's how we're going to legalize
marijuana and this is an exciting year i
you know i'm not a hundred percent sure
but i think we have marijuana on the
ballot and four states and i think
that's the most we've ever had on in in
one time so that's another measure of
progress
now i'm just going to try to share some
things i've learned over the years about
using the initiative process and what we
need to know about it
first off it costs a lot of money and
up until recently most of the
initiatives were not funded by us they
weren't funded by
you know a grass roots movement they
were funded by a small number of big
funders peter lewis soros and sperling
and thank god for those
you know really wise rich men
but it's time for this movement to move
past that funding source and frankly
we're having to do it whether we like it
or not
we got on the ballot by doing it
ourselves and we did get a grant from
mpp and a grant from dpa but in this
initiative that we just put on the
ballot we raised the lion's share of the
money uh from small contributions and
and a few benefactors and one of my
messages is that if we want to legalize
marijuana we're going to have to pay for
it and it's not going to be cheap
and i'm hoping that we can go away from
this conference with everybody realizing
that we have the power just those of us
at this conference to do this but we
need to shift our spending a little bit
and we need to all make sure we spend as
much on legalization as we spend for
example at the governor hotel
and if we do that we'll be pretty close
to legalizing marijuana
so anyway part of my pitch to you all is
we need your help you know one of the
things that's going on with this
initiative is we barely got on the
ballot we're nearly broke and we're in a
very very difficult tough campaign we
think we can win and there's lots of
evidence that shows we can but we need
you to help us raise some money so we're
having an after party tonight at the
motish building which is about three
blocks from here we're passing out
flyers so so come on down and you know
we'll uh we'll be continuing the
conference after it stops here and have
uh speakers and and and things you can
uh bid on and all that all that usual
stuff but anyway we need your help so so
please step up
now what does our initiative do
our initiative you know we've had the
oregon medical marijuana act for 12
years and it's a it's a great law it it
has stopped patients from being arrested
for using their medicine
what it hasn't done is created a system
where all patients get medicine and they
get it conveniently we now have over
forty five thousand patients in oregon i
don't know if that's the highest per
capita among the states but it's right
up there
but we have a system that requires these
people to produce their own medicine and
it's a felony for anybody to sell it to
them and we've been struggling with that
for 12 years making the best of it and
we do pretty good you know there's a lot
of organizations that that try to help
patients but it just doesn't work you
know there's no question
uh that requiring patients to produce
their own medicine keeps marijuana
medical marijuana in the dark ages and
we look forward to a future where
patients can grow it themselves if they
want but where they can go buy it and
where they can buy advanced products
that research and development and
innovators like some of you out there
are going to come up with and that's
going to be a better world and we're
going to make it happen uh on november
2nd
there's some really exciting aspects of
this campaign now we we've done a lot of
polling and you know one of the things i
got to say is that uh
part of politics is our issue but a
bigger part of politics is realizing
that we're a little issue in a big sea
and right now one of the things we're up
against is the decline of the democratic
party in the in the national
sphere and the you know the republicans
are highly motivated they're out for
blood and they're all going to be voting
we polled on our issue
in right after the november 2008
election and we were polling at 59 32.
we polled in june and we're only ahead
46 41 and it's not because people have
changed their attitudes about medical
marijuana it's because young democrats
are not planning on voting
and so
one lesson there is the key to us
winning this election and i imagine it's
the key to prop 19 winning in california
is we have to mobilize the young voters
we have to register them and we have to
get out the vote so we're directing a
lot of effort in our campaign at that we
have petitioners out collecting uh
emails and registering voters we just
registered we just collected uh emails
from
about 5000 people at the state fair and
now we have an email list approaching
twenty thousand and we're gonna we're
gonna keep building on that to where we
can send out emails and remind people to
vote in oregon we are lucky because we
have only vote by mail we don't go to
the polls at all so we have about a a
two week window where people have their
ballots and we're going to spend a lot
of our resources on on getting people
that we know our supporters out to vote
and if we do that that will easily
overcome uh the fact that we're not over
50 in our polling numbers uh there's
been another test of of this campaign as
well
last month a new part of the initiative
process here in oregon was called the
citizens initiative review where
another non-profit organization
partnering with the state government
selected 24 voters
uh at random to demographically match
the state of oregon and those folks
studied this initiative for a solid week
we had many hours of uh testimony they
had expert witnesses we brought out
all kinds of people we brought
mary lynn mathery from patients out of
time and mike kravitz from uh veterans
for access to medical marijuana we
brought don duncan from asa you know the
other side they talked to andrea
barthwell they talked to uh
you know chris's police chief who said
all kinds of terrible things about uh
dispensaries in california uh but at the
end of that process where these 24
average citizens got to really get into
the trenches and study the details of
the initiative we won 13-11
and the lesson for that is that we can
win but it's going to be very close and
that's really what what we're up against
in this race and uh we're putting the
best campaign forward we can we got some
good things going for us
oregon has a voters pamphlet that you
can buy pro and con arguments in it gets
mailed to every household
we have an outstanding lineup in our
voters pamphlet uh we have 11 arguments
in including one from tom potter the
former mayor and police chief of
portland betty roberts former justice of
the oregon supreme court
christine olson former u.s attorney for
oregon so our goal was to have some
law enforcement people on our side and i
think we did pretty good there uh we
have eight other arguments from doctors
and patients the other side has only two
uh one from citizens against legalizing
marijuana and another uh from the cops
uh so i think we we're gonna win in that
arena that's gonna be very influential
we hope to raise a significant amount of
money over the next two months and use
it to get out the vote on the one hand
and also to put out our message that a
regulated system will work better than
what we have now and we'll make sure all
patients get the medicine they need and
you know wish us luck do what you can to
help
i think we're going to win this election
in november thank you very much