um next let's switch to the topic of
some uh Municipal initiatives and in
this case one that's been stalled
temporarily but we think only
temporarily matab Bell is going to talk
about an initiative in Detroit Michigan
Matt is a very active member in fact a
life member of the normal legal
committee uh he founded cannabis Council
a practice entirely consistent of
medical of cannabis cases and clients um
but more importantly what I've seen over
the last year whatever since I guess
about a year now since Michigan's had
that new initiative is Matt is truly the
go-to guy on these important questions
in Michigan but again instead of having
him talk about the medical use law today
I'd like for him to talk about what's
going on with that initiative that we
expected to be on the ballot this
November in Michigan
Matt uh thank you keth and happy normal
everyone it's good to be here um I'm a
lawyer in Detroit and uh there are some
activists in Detroit who uh approached
me and and uh said they wanted to do
something uh further to uh try to
decriminalize marijuana or move the move
the ball even a little bit uh Tim Beck
is the person who actually put the
language together and and then um had
the petitions printed came to me and and
someone else and asked for funding and
three of us just kicked in a little bit
to print it and toay pay some
circulators we didn't even need a th000
signatures for this so if if initiative
is available to you in your state or
your municipality or your county um do
it you know take a look at at the city
Charter the county Charter um if that is
available there are all kinds of ways
that we can do this on a smaller level
to make inroads and that's what we were
trying to do in Detroit the Detroit City
Charter allows citizen initiative and it
didn't require whole ton of signatures
so we printed some petitions that said
um this would amend the Detroit city
code to exempt adults possessing or
using marijuana on private property by
amending the uh the code section um and
to add this section none of the
provisions of this article shall apply
to the use or possession of less than 1
ounce of marijuana on private property
by a person who has attained the age of
21 years and then we reprinted the
entire controll substances ordinances in
the city of Detroit and just added that
section so it requires you to put all
the language there that might be
affected so better safe than sorry in
fact we uh printed them once and there
was some small uh heading that wasn't in
bold and it was completely reprinted
that cost a couple hundred but it's
important to have the details right too
um which anyway um what happened was we
circulated the petitions we paid
petitioners a dollar a signature and
um those were filed with the county
clerk I'm sorry with the city clerk they
were filed with the city clerk the city
clerk counted them um and they had
sufficient signatures under the law they
were good and then it was submitted to
the election commission to set the
language to go on the ballot and Tim and
I appeared at the election commission
hearing and instead of considering
language The Corporation Council one of
the three members of this commission
said uh we can't do this this is illegal
and I move it uh that it be denied and
we just can this and that's what
happened now they had written a legal
opinion which we only found that day and
obtained a copy of it saying that they
felt it was illegal for two reasons um
that it was preempted by federal law and
that it was advisory only in nature and
and neither of those is true or accurate
but uh so we sued them is what happened
this is a copy of the lawsuit that I
filed in Wayne County in Detroit and uh
we got an order to show cause against
the uh the city clerk and the um
Election Commission the head of the city
council and um we appeared at the
hearing and at the mandamus hearing the
judge said this violates the law and I'm
not going to order that it be placed on
the ballot and U basically make me kind
of um and so we're going to um
but not right away uh the timing is such
that the ballots are are being printed
already now and the politics are such
that while the court of appeals our next
step um might if they want to uh hear a
case in three or 4 days it typically
takes roughly a year and a half from the
date all the briefs have been filed and
are sitting in the court um before they
hear the case well at least a year
so um looking at that what we've decided
to do is we're filing a motion for
rehearing in front of this judge
explaining a little more how he's wrong
because um he didn't really um hear us
out all that much he had his mind made
up and we'd like to show him what a
stupid uh decision that was if you
excuse me that's a legal term you can
look it
up and we want to show him some other
things that um I didn't have and didn't
think were necessary like a copy of the
Detroit medical marijuana law that was
passed in 2004 four years before our
state law which was put on the ballot
and wasn't preempted and wasn't advisory
and um he asked me uh how you know what
what actual effect it would have how is
it not advisory and I said well you know
an officer wouldn't be able to write a
ticket under city code that he can write
today you know that's a big practical
difference and then he he made up some
some crazy analogies that um were not on
point and I explained that to him him
and he said good point and we moved on
and uh anyway uh we are going to be
filing a motion for rehearing in front
of the same judge and um we expect it'll
be denied but it'll our brief will be
much thicker and and more professional
ready to go to the court of appeals we
kind of thought it was a lay down but it
was uh it was all over before we got
there so um when we go to the court of
appeals uh we'll have all the legal
arguments already laid out in the lower
court which is uh better way for us to
do it and um the timing is such that it
looks like if and when we win this it'll
probably be either a special election
which will be rather interesting or um
it could be even two years from now um
in the uh the 2012 elections so um we
are slowed but not deterred and we're
going to move forward and the actually I
thought that first of all I thought
there was no way we were going to lose I
was so confident when I went to court um
although I I never get overconfident you
never I never say it's a done deal but I
felt very good about the case because
the law really is very strongly on our
side and um when we lost I I I was
surprised that I wasn't depressed or
dejected I was invigorated by um by more
of the Injustice that that's still
coming from the government and so that
had the reverse effect that I expected
but it was a good thing for all of us
and I'm reinvigorated and I'm willing
and ready to press on forward in this
and so we're gone but not forgotten or
we're forgotten now but not gone we'll
be back put it that way uh one way or
another so all right thank you very much