thank you keith thank you everybody for
being here and uh bear in mind that
that's our former police chief
that you heard uh taking that position
by the way john and so um yeah it's
great to be here today it's a really
exciting time uh and i'm very um
optimistic about prop 19 passing right
now let me start off by saying what the
state of california law is to give you a
grasp of where things stand right now
basically marijuana is illegal in
california there is a
qualified limited immunity that people
have if they get a doctor's approval
and that is an immunity that allows them
theoretically to have eight ounces or
six plants
and be immune from a rest if they have
the right paperwork otherwise they're in
court fighting it out and a lot of times
the problem is the paperwork the cop
doesn't believe doesn't like the doctor
doesn't believe it's
undone in time and so forth whatever
their issues are that they have against
the paperwork becomes a big factor in
this whole thing um but sb4 prop 215
created the limited qualified immunity
sp 420 created an opportunity for
collectives to grow in and
it also set up the safe harbor for use
but basically it created a legal defense
against sales of marijuana which right
now we have this dispensary system in
california which is not based upon them
saying it's legal to sell marijuana is
to say that if you get it busted that
you have a legal defense in court for
marijuana
it is a felony to furnish for people
below the age of 18 in california it's a
misdemeanor to possess marijuana to
transport marijuana it is a felony to
cultivate marijuana that felony can be
mitigated by a pc-1000
deferred uh entry of judgment which
means that the judge is nice to you that
you might be able to get out there
without having a permanently scarred
record other than having been arrested
because they can dispose of the pc uh
excuse me of your cultivation bust
as was mentioned earlier something like
56 percent of uh californians think
marijuana should be legal when you look
at the polling what we have right now
the
average of the last seven polls comes to
51.3 percent or who are in favor of the
initiative um as written so uh what this
means that is that our opponents are now
in the position where they will say that
they're not in favor of the drug war
they're not in favor of marijuana being
illegal they just think this is the
wrong initiative and then they will give
you two reasons of why they think it is
wrong or more they have you know they
can make up fake stuff as much as they
want obviously
uh so um so i'm going to pass on that
for a moment and get back to that minute
because what i want to go to next is how
do we arrive at prop 19 in the form that
is written right now the origins and
concept come from the fact that there
were four initiatives that were being
crafted in california last year
one of them was a california cannabis
initiative which was a full legalization
initiative the other was the california
hemp and health initiative jack harris
initiative uh the other one was called
the common sense initiative a couple
guys in long beach who just said it's
time to do something and they didn't
know they didn't have a group they
didn't have anything they just wrote
something that said it's common sense to
legalize marijuana so therefore we
should do it
basically with their initiative and then
we have proposition 19. now as you
notice only one of those is called
proposition that's because of the four
one made it onto the ballot my wife
mickey norris here
who's a co-publisher of the west coast
leaf with me
she and i were engaged in the writing of
three of those initiatives and what we
people said to us so which one do you
support and what we said is we support
the one that gets on the ballot
because the other ones you know it's
they're great ideas maybe but they're
not on the ballot and so it seems pretty
clear to me how you have to address that
kind of a situation however not everyone
felt about that way
and so i'm here to tell you that this
initiative is very very very very very
carefully written it was initiated from
material was put together by criminal
lawyers then it went to uh
constitutional lawyers then it went to
election lawyers there was a group of uh
citizens such as myself and mickey and
many of the leaders of the movement were
invited to participate and they said
they did not want to because they felt
this was the wrong year and if they held
off for two years then they would get
involved but they wouldn't get involved
now we took the different approach we
said if there's something on the ballot
i want to have something
input on what it's like and so then a
lot of people are resentful for us to us
because of well how come we were
consulting they weren't and the answer
is because we took the time and went to
the meetings and they didn't that's what
happened there and so those means were
extremely interesting because this
initiative was designed to do several
things one is to preserve the existing
medical marijuana laws the attorneys
have told us originally as long as you
don't mention
yeah
so they said as long as we didn't
mention the medical marijuana laws that
they were automatically preserved and as
long as we didn't put them in the
section it says these are the laws that
are changed it would not be changed but
we said that's not enough we put in the
purposes three times that it protects
the medical marijuana laws in california
and in the ballot argument it says one
time that we're preserving those laws so
the idea that it's changing those is
completely wrong was written to protect
the medical marijuana laws and in fact
to go beyond it because the current
medical marijuanas do not make it clear
that you can sell medical marijuana
whereas prop 19 says you can sell
marijuana if you if the city authorizes
it and so the question of the
dispensaries will be resolved
clearly that you can sell marijuana in
california for medical uses after prop
19 passes which is not clear right now
is still being fought out in courts
the other thing is that it's a modest
goal rather than legalizing unlimited
amounts of marijuana for anybody to use
all the time in any place and share with
anybody of any age they wrote something
that said it limits to one ounce
and you have a affirmative defense to if
you have more than an ounce and the
legislature can increase the quantities
available and the legislature can
continue to make further changes to
improve the initiative by reducing
penalties and reducing restrictions but
not by going the other way not by adding
new penalties doesn't give them that
authority it doesn't get and it and so
um
so and it also makes a very small
personal grow legal what that means
changed during the course of our
discussion originally it was a
reasonable amount then it became maybe
100 square feet then it went down to 50
square feet then it went down to 32
square feet and what we found out is
that the people who don't grow marijuana
think that that is a lot of marijuana
and so so richard came to the 25 square
feet and the legislature can increase
that um
initially i was very against that but i
think that with the affirmative defense
that you can defend bigger gardens and
so that's not really going to be a
problem that just means if you can stay
within 25 square feet you don't get
arrested uh and the other thing is that
it allows local regulations
without putting in a state law that
regulates the uh the sales of marijuana
this is what our constitutional lawyers
told us we had to do they said if we
made a law that california had to break
federal law that that would be ruled
unconstitutional immediately what we can
do is say that the state is stepping
aside and it's going to allow the cities
to do the same kind of regulation that
they do over the gas station the barber
shop the grocery store the drugstore the
liquor store the tobacco outlets the
same kind of regulation and of course
that offended a lot of people because
they felt like marijuana is not supposed
to be regulated it's supposed to be
something different
but our sense of what we got to through
the polls was this that the voters were
in favor of legalization but they don't
like the alcohol model because they
think it's not controlled well enough
they wanted more controls over marijuana
than over alcohol and we might say well
marijuana safer but that's not what the
voters want to hear they want to hear
that we have written a law that produces
more controls and so those controls were
put in there specifically to do a couple
of things one of them being that it
would
make 18 to 20 years old equi
excuse me sales or transfers to people
between the ages 18 and 21 we kept all
the criminal penalties for cells to
minors below 18 and 14. those remained
intact
same as they always have been there's no
new felony in this at all
but what it did do is it made it tougher
penalty for selling to people between
the 18 18 and 21
made it equivalent to the alcohol model
uh and it said that we have to keep it
away from kids and it did in kind of an
ambiguous way is that you can't it
doesn't legalize smoking around people
around minors
so it didn't make a new penalty it
didn't change the law about it it said
that it didn't specifically make it
legal to do that uh and so we basically
so you still have your misdemeanor uh
furnishing
charge uh but
and the medical is still protected but
if you're distributing people under the
age of between 1821 you might actually
have the possibility of prison time it's
not a guaranteed prison time excuse me
jail time there is no prison time i said
that completely wrong this is only jail
it does not create any prison time at
all
uh
and the other thing that people are
concerned about let me reiterate that no
prison time
because i know that's going to come back
and haunt me the fact that i said the
wrong word
that's the way that it works in this
movement okay so uh and the financial
argument raises the nights very well
although people don't really expect it
to pay off the way it sounds like it
will because they remember the lottery
and it didn't pay off the way they
thought it was going to the drug cartel
argument is extremely powerful because
the fact that 60 of the drug cartels uh
in mexico's money and i know the word
mark cartel's being abused here but i'm
just going to go with the common usage
the drug cartels in mexico about 60 of
money from selling marijuana that if we
take the california market away from
them that that's going to reduce their
ability to slaughter people in mexico
and to do that kind of criminality
that's going on down there and people
are really concerned about that
the other two things that are really
important to california is that they
don't want people driving under the
influence and they don't want people in
the workplace smoking pot and so uh what
we did is in initiative it protects the
employer's right to say what people can
do on the job it protects the federal
drug-free workplace laws which by the
way we can't change federal law anyway
it is you know
and then it also uh makes sure that the
the driving under the influence laws are
intact so it protects preserves those
because again you can argue that people
may drive safer on marijuana than other
things but voters don't want to hear
that they want to hear that people are
not going to be driving under the
influence of marijuana any more than
they used to so uh that's where the way
the law was written based upon polls
what we were looking for is the middle
ground
in other words uh and so we're getting
hit from both ends and so let's talk
about that for the next moment here
which is that uh we were got the
backlash we were expecting from the
right wing which is that they say well
uh this is creating a crazy situation
and and so forth and marijuana is this
great danger and and people begin
driving under the influence and people
are going to be smoking at work and we
have dealt with all that within the
initiative itself so most of their
claims don't have a lot of traction if
you actually read the initiative only if
you don't read the initiative now what
we were not necessarily expecting was
that uh dennis perrone and another group
a woman called dragon fart or something
like that is out there uh making up
false stories about the initiative and
spreading it around we were not really
counting on that because we were hoping
for this what we call
we're doing 51.3
with the um uh what they call the um
likely voters but we want the unlikely
voters out there too the young people
who aren't expected to vote and we think
it's going to be important for the
democrats and for the progressive agenda
in general to have this happen as well
and so um
anyway so just to basically say it uh
you know there are no new felonies it
doesn't do basically anything that they
say and so in the new issue of the west
coast leaf we have a we did an
investigation of the claims that were
made by those people you can't go on
forever though because they can make up
conspiracy stories like you wouldn't
believe and you can spend your whole
life trying to dispute their conspiracy
theories but we looked at the things
that they said were likely and we found
out that basically uh it was all wrong
what they had to say so then um
the historical context is that this has
been
that this is 38 years since california
had legalizing non-medical marijuana on
the ballot coincidentally or
inextricably it's the same ballot number
proposition 19 and right now the big
funders have not come through with the
money for it so we need to count upon
people like john said for here you know
if you could take one month's supply of
money that you spend on marijuana and
give a third of it to normal a third of
the problem 19 a third to prop 74 that
would be an extremely good use of your
money
and in addition to that i would say that
you have the uh the information here to
donate to the campaign and also the
west coast leaf gives you a full rundown
on how these things look and all these
arguments and i think that prop 215 is
the best thing that happened to
california
since i've been alive and if prop 19
passes it is going to far far surpass
anything that proposition 215 did and so
we need every one of you out there
telling people in california register
vote get people to vote absentee get
them out to vote but we have to have
them and we will need to win on november
the 2nd so please thank you for your
time and get everybody out
on behalf of uh legalizing marijuana it
makes it lawful not just a legal defense
this law says it is lawful for people to
possess cultivate and use marijuana and
that is the difference because that's
the beginning of the end of
discrimination which is all based upon
it being illegal thank you very much