welcome everybody to the uh Ready Set
grow uh breakout session here it gives
me great pleasure to have put this thing
together and I don't think even just a
couple of years ago this would even be a
possibility um to have people speaking
about uh growing for patients um the
right ways to do it the safest ways to
do it uh and people that are willing to
come out and talk about that uh and how
they how they're able to do that you
know legally and uh and the proper way
so uh without further Ado let me
introduce the panel here uh directly to
my left Miss Jill from uh TGA genetics
TGA seeds is Team Green Avenger
combination of uh subcool and Miss Jill
and uh dioxide a bunch of other guys uh
and gals that are helping out uh for the
medical patients uh they're seed
breeders they're Growers and uh you know
they really do it the right way they're
responsible for uh some really amazing
strains like Vortex uh Jil beam Jack the
Ripper Danny Boy and uh the list really
goes on and on uh they're even in my SE
Bank Hall of Fame uh which I put
together so uh yeah and it's really
quite an honor that they're here and uh
just want to introduce them so cool is
also the author of dank uh which is uh
an amazing book uh Inside the Mind of a
breeder and and what choice they make uh
to create the strains that they make and
uh beautiful pictures as
well okay uh we got Rafael Martinez uh
Jr who is a patient caregiver uh for the
state of Oregon and a major player with
work and normal and a great
dude I'm scy here uh that's rapael or
Junior and then eor ruz old friend of
mine he's taking the place of Kyle
kushman who actually sadly could not
make it uh up here for this uh seminar
but uh he is taking the place he's with
uh Safe Harbor of Maine which is one of
the first dispensaries uh on the east
coast in Maine uh they only allowed
eight dispensaries for the whole state
and I think it's one one per
resident no it's one per County it's one
per County and uh they already have the
caregivers they had the medical law
since 99 uh they have a grow your own
they have a caregiver system and now
they're going to have dispensaries uh
even some of them I think will be able
to deliver the medicine to patients in
their homes which is really exciting for
us on the east coast and Main's really
leaving the way it's like the California
of uh of our side
of the country and that's so that's
[Music]
Igor uh and to his left uh Jeremy Miller
Jeremy is not only the founder of uh
Olympia Hempfest in Washington he's also
a great grower and uh uh the breeder of
seeds of Truth uh which is his uh you
know medical marijuana seed uh outfit so
uh and if I've never been to Ali
Hempfest but I hear it's a great time
and I'm looking forward to hopefully
coming this uh next year so welcome
Jeremy uh let's get right to it uh we
only have a little under a couple hours
or whatever so uh I want to get as much
as we can out of uh everybody so I guess
we'll start at the beginning you know
germinating seeds is really how you uh
Embark upon
this uh Pursuit you know because you can
always buy clones from the dispensary
and that's a good way also to get
started sometimes but you could you
could come with a lot of problems and it
depends on who you get them from um a
lot of them can be susceptible to
powdery Milo or already have pests on
them and you know a lot of times they're
just not they don't have the Vigor that
you get when you pop seeds and uh so I
think uh I'm going to talk to sub cool
right now let him uh let him tell us
about germinating
seeds thank you Danny um there's milons
of ways to start seeds um we see a lot
of seeds start we have 20 strains
worldwide distribution so I see
everything you can possibly see with
seeds and the first thing I would say is
that people try to do too much to them
uh my favorite picture is uh we sort
seeds out back and underneath my
barbecue grill and working when it's 40°
and granite seeds will germinate okay so
it doesn't take anything to germinate
seeds uh a lot of times people will send
me an email that says hey I got your
seeds they didn't germinate I put them
on a heat mat I used this and that three
drops of this you know nature didn't
really need all that um we are big fans
of a product called rapid roters uh I
don't know which company makes them
they're a small cord plug we flip them
upside down we stick the seat in and
they germinate I mean that's that's
really what it's about uh I really try
to suggest that people not use a lot of
chemicals and products in order to Aid
germination because it simply is not
required um and that's really how I
germinate seeds and and have for a long
time one more small point a lot of
people like to put them in paper towel
last zipl bag that's fine but if you
don't have a light touch as you're
transferring the seeds from the plastic
bag and the paper towel you can tear the
seeds up you know you can smash them or
Nick them with your tweezers so I don't
think that's always the best way if
you're a big clumsy guy like me and your
hands aren't real delicate so you know
don't try to start moving seeds around
while you got resin all over them the
stuff you'll kill your
seeds all right and uh um Rafael do you
have any uh any seed germination tips or
anything you know you know I I kind of
have the same Theory as sub I don't
really believe in using a lot of um
chemicals when you do it on the old
clumsy hands I still use I still use the
seat bag you know and the paper towel
but I'm old school you know the guy I
learned from is older than dirt you know
my dad so he's taught me quite a few
things that I've learned and he's a seed
person with the in paper towel paper
towel but no most Comm water that's the
most common way that's pretty much me
all right and uh so what what's the
importance of of growing from seeds and
and and and and explain what a mother
plant is to people too I mean you don't
always have to grow from a seed only to
like just flower that plant and move on
you can keep those genetics and that's I
I try to go fast cuz I ran I'll try to
stick to point here I covered this down
in Colorado everybody's very interested
in it the problem with clones are
threefold number one is Mis labeling I I
I love it when someone walks up and
hands me a bud and they tell me it's
California Orange well I've been growing
californ orange for three decades and I
know what it tastes like so the Clones
were very mislabeled and that can be a
problem if you're trying to make
tinctures or medical number two is Milo
that you cannot see mildew uh my partner
out there just got a bunch of nice
clones uh hell OG cut these are cuts
that people tro and salivate over and
what happened was even with good
treatment amazing mythology methology he
uh he got a little spot of powy mildew
and then he spent the next six months
getting rid of it so if you take clones
in thinking that you're going to save
time it's a very good possibility that
you're going to bring something into
your grow room the main thing that we
all are scared of M mites are part of
growing cannabis indoors and out uh if
you have a good climate in your grow
room keep it 74° all the time don't let
your temperature swing you can keep the
MS down but if you bring say rulin
cutting into your house a year ago
because it is an amazing strain and you
really needed it to make a strain and
then you battle mes for a [ __ ] year
you know that's what you're opening
yourself up to when you start with seed
you don't have to worry about mites or
mildew or mole coming into your grow as
a grower from a 10 pack of of good seeds
you should be able to select three to
four nice females discarding the females
that are not nice or not what you want
and select a mother plant that you want
now this is how we do it quickly we grow
the plant at day 45 we know that what
the sex of the plant is she takes clones
she has nice delicate hands um then we
Bud the plant out we smoke the plant we
share the plant with our patients we're
very lucky here in Oregon that we just
give our pot to our patients we don't
charge for it so we give B away to
everybody you know we don't care who
find
joint there joints in the ashtray not
enough people smoking them because
they're not used to being here in orgon
anal guess um but okay so then we Bud
these plants out and she uses numbers I
like to use cool names this is Shaggy
this is one of our new space Queens uh
uh she squits oh I'm sorry so this is on
the cover of a magazine right now we
planted five seeds uh one of the seeds
her hermite right at five weeks it was
easy to get out of there people don't
want to talk about this but the dominant
state of cannabis is Herod ISM so as a
grower you just got to get rid of that
then we had two other ones one was
cheese dominant one was purple dominant
we selected this Peno which I Nam Shaggy
cuz I like cartoons and uh it's freaking
awesome I mean it tastes like grapes and
it tastes like cheese and it yielded 3
and2 o from dirt from one Single Seed
grown in soil and this is a special
phenotype that we won't get rid of right
it's got an amazing high and we found
this you can't do that if you don't
start the seeds so what I've done my
entire life and I urge you to do this if
you guys are out there growing Medic One
start seeds man it's like a box of
crackers Jacks and I I'm a seed guy
right but I'm not saying bu my seeds
okay there's there's plenty of breeders
out there right I mean I we grow other
people's seeds all the time looking for
something I grew DJ shorts blueberry I
didn't find what I wanted I grew this
kid from the UK seeds called a pine
Queen this kid's name is Sonic something
called Shima
times uh something else oh my God it's
like the third best pot i've smoked in
my life and so you can't find these
things if you don't start the seed so
I'm sorry it's so yeah absolutely and
from those seeds uh you can get a good
mother plant and from the mother plant
you get you can get an infinite amount
of clones I mean I wouldn't call it
infinite but I'd like to cover one more
small thing here um a lot of people
don't understand cloning and I really
feel it important to address this you
don't have to keep a mother plant and
here in Oregon where we can grow six
plants for each one of our patients I
can't have a room full of 5 foot pot
plants I just can't we take clones just
before we bud so I have 12 strains in my
grow room I take four clones a pretty
nice clone the roost the fastest we keep
um Jack's cleaner I don't know how many
people have heard of Jack's cleaner it's
the father of Jack the Ripper uh it has
been cloned for two decades I mean I've
been to prison so while I was in prison
other people kept cloning it and it came
back to me the plan is exactly the same
and this is what I want to explain I
think the word clone is wrong it's not
we're not making a copy of something it
is the plant we're taking a living piece
of the plant living piece of DNA and
then it's just growing again I'm not
going to stop calling them clones but
you're not replicating something so the
theory of copy versus a copy versus a
copy it's
false you're right you want Healthy
Growth you want really Healthy Growth
really good point you can't use a sick
clone but I would imagine most of us
growing here are not using big mother
rooms
right well uh yeah no it's great and uh
how about Jeremy uh why don't you tell
us a little bit about uh the situation
in Washington and uh also if you have
any tips on germinating seeds cloning or
mother
plants I uh I'm I'm very simplistic in
the way I gerate seed so I I think the
way that subol said was very adequate
you definitely seeds have bigger that
clones don't have so I mean if you're
starting from seed they take right off
really big so if you're starting in
water rapid R like subit suggested you
see those things just sprout right out
and take off like very vigorously
because the seeds have a just a vigorous
hybrid growth that the Clones don't
after a certain certain time they start
to lose a little bit they're still great
plants you won't see them quite as
vigorous as the seed stre in my
opinion um Washington State itself is a
little bit different it's Unique we're
able to grow 15 plants we're only able
to caregive for one patient so and um
the problem that we see with that is uh
Washington State um possession is 9/10
of the law so if I'm caregiving for
another patient then technically I'm in
possession of 30
months so even though the law allows me
to grow for another patient I still am
fighting it in court I have to prove
that I wasn't technically in possession
I was growing these for somebody else
and I wasn't consuming that medicine on
my own uh behalf so it's kind of it's
kind of strange Dynamics they're working
on a dispensary law next year Senator
Cole wals is working on a dispensary law
in Washington state um there's a lot of
aspects to this this proposed
legislation that really worry me I'm
asking a lot of people to kind of take a
look at what's going on and uh this is
our chance to really uh Define what's
going to happen here in the future in
Washington and I think that the
legislators don't take into account what
the stakeholders and the patients you
know really feel a lot of times they
just
make time for the big lobbyist for the
people that have money and uh I think
right in the next few years we're going
to see a lot of interesting backs in
Washington state for
sure yeah it sounds like it's turning
around very quickly and people are
getting more involved there's uh I mean
right now there's a lot of patient
co-ops that are operating in Washington
state there's a lot that's popped up in
Seattle this Spokane area I actually um
run one Tacoma area called Sac PL
medicine that's where we do all her
breeding everything for seeds of
true now what about uh we were talking
about the importance of seeds and uh
Vigor um what about uh you know
germination what's what uh what's any
any tips that you might have no I'm a
very simplistic germinator too I'll go
either with a paper to old school style
or I'll start them right in the
r two ways that I'll do it um mostly
I'll do it the old school paper towel
way because have time I don't have the r
be right there in front of and what
about cloning do you do a lot of cloning
or most we do do uh a lot of cloning of
the strains that we have to keep them
perpetuated you know um but we
definitely love love the seeds you know
they have a bigger that clone just don't
have and they come like a subset disease
fruit so all right well uh as subset
also uh Jill takes the uh the
Clones uh for them or the cuting rooted
cuting however you would want to refer
um uh so maybe you can give us a couple
of uh just step by step of how you how
you go about creating
clones well it's important that we start
out with utensils we have um sorry we
have sharp razor blades
and to take the and we take them at a
45°
angle Che
and we dip these in rooting hormone you
can use gel powder or liquid and we
prefer the liquid and I like to take the
the soft cuting and um usually off
towards the bottom they need to be
healthy nice green coloring and I like
to make sure that there is a um a root
bump that will be going into the the
cube so that I feel that that's a better
way to root the plant and we like to put
those immediately under fluorescent we
put them in we use a shoe box plastic
shoe
box you can buy them at the Dollar Tree
and we take two sides and we invert them
take the lids off and throw them away we
just take two big sides and turn them
inside you know together we stick them
under the light we keep the Clones very
damp we keep them you know warm we don't
want them to get too hot we keep them
about 78° it's a good temperature and in
about 3 to 7 days we have
Roots next
yeah that's great um the importance
being on the humidity and the warmth um
and consistency and consistency but if
you need to if it's cold and you're
doing a cloning uh get a cheap little
heat mat that you plug in and put that
underneath the tray it's really
important that the roots in that area
and the water that they sit in or
whatever it is never get too
cold this is this is going to sound
silly okay but I answer a lot of
questions question and the main thing
that I ask everybody that have a problem
with clones is do you own a thermometer
and you know I say what's the
temperature oh it's about no you have to
have a thermometer a feter is not the
way to Delta temperature and it sounds
silly telling you guys this but I can't
tell you the number of people that have
had problems for a month cloning I'm
trying to coach them through it they go
to Radio Shack and all of a sudden
they've got clones so you got to have a
thermometer and a humidistat to find out
what the temperature in the humidistat
is don't just say Well they're kind of
warm that's not all right uh eor uh you
got any any cloning
tips um well the rapid roter system
rapid roers everybody seems to be a fan
of that do you preo them um I I like
them because they're actually inoculated
in a lot of beneficial bacteria so it's
not going to get pollinated with stuff
that's going to hurt your plant um
that's not being yeah closer to M uh he
said so yeah what I said was the the
sponges are inoculated with bacteria
they actually also have a little bit of
a mineral charge too to help the plant
move forward there's other products on
the market as well such as easy roots
that cost a little bit less and it's
really similar it's also pH bucks so if
your nutrient solution isn't exactly
right on it'll balance it itself out you
could also um it also make sure that
none of uh the well that the medium you
can't oversaturate it it'll uh you could
pour tons of water on it and if the
surrounding surface will float it'll
just lift itself up off the water and
balance itself up I would do a
commercial for rabbit RS they they Rock
they're so much nicer than anything we
ever had and and you know we would also
probably all agreed to try to discourage
the use of rock wool in that in that
process I
mean plants do root well in rock wol uh
because it's able to hold air and and
allow oxygen to the roots and stuff but
it's a really kind of a toxic product
not kind of a it's a toxic product and
uh it's not good for you to be around it
and it's not good for you to throw it
out and uh so rapid rooters or easy
roots or any kind of organic alternative
you can find are much better and the
truth is you can just get the the you
know little cubs and fill them with soil
and keep it moist and warm and the plant
will root in that as well the the
moisture level and the warm temperature
are what's important for to get the
roots to pop and once they pop now
you're in the vegetative stage