[Applause]
next um we'd like to ask Dale gager to
talk for a second about a new bill that
recently passed the California
legislature I think it's still pending
before the governor but it would in fact
finally do what we thought we had done
back in 1977 which is to actually
decriminalize marijuana but as Dale will
fill you in in more detail it turns out
you know they're still arresting 60,000
or more marijuana smokers every year in
California so uh this is a major step
forward I think most of you know Dale
he's the coordinator and has been for a
dozen 15 years of California normal he's
a co-author of a book called marijuana
medical handbook published in uh 1997
and again updated in 2008 he's Vice
chairman of the normal board of
directors and was the 2004 recipient of
normal's Lester grinspoon award
recognizing outstanding work in medical
cannabis advocacy Dale garinger
please thank
you yes um we have actually for the
first time in many years good news
coming out of our state legislature in
Sacramento a bill to
decriminalize Petty possession that is
possession of less than an ounce of
marijuana to an infraction like a
traffic ticket has cleared both houses
of the legislature and is now on the
governor's desk uh uh and our good
friend state Senator Mark Leno deserves
credit for sponsoring this bill sp1 1449
it's called a a little bit of background
a lot of people think that petty
possession is already not a criminal
offense in
California this is not actually
technically the case technically
possession of an ounce or less is now a
very minor misdemeanor but one which
requires you to go to court
and which in itself is quite an
inconvenience and gives you a technical
criminal record for a misdemeanor for
actually just two years after two years
it's expunged but the mere threat of a
misdemeanor charge can be a big problem
for lots of people uh and as a result
many people don't even plead out to the
maximum fine which is there's a $100
fine there's no possible jail with the
current
misdemeanor uh marijuana possession um
but uh in order to avoid the uh
possibility of a record a lot of people
will will spend hundreds or thousands of
dollars to go to these treatment classes
which is a diversion program that can
avoid the technical misdemeanor
conviction well this is all a lot of
nonsense uh there's no other misdemeanor
in California with that does not have a
jail sentence attached to it uh you
shouldn't have to go to court for this
and this is costing the state quite a
bit of money in fact if you got 60,000
Petty possession offenders last year in
California that's 60,000 court cases uh
I don't know how much uh a court hearing
costs in fact the state court system
doesn't know either but it's somewhere
in the hundreds of dollars so the the
you you can tell right off the bat the
state is spending millions of dollars on
calling these people into court
needlessly
um Senator lener Leno managed to get
support uh from the district attorneys
and the courts California court system
for this bill in fact I think it is the
support of the district attorneys that
made it possible to pass the bill in the
first place because identical
legislation has been up to the uh State
Legislature three times in the last
dozen years or so and never managed to
pass out this is the first time it
passed out but given the fiscal crisis
and given that it does save millions of
dollars in quarter expenses and would
save marijuana offenders any criminal
record whatsoever for petty possession
there's a really strong case for this to
be signed into law we are crossing our
fingers uh Governor Schwarzenegger does
not have a good record on marijuana
legislation in fact he has vetoed every
bill that we wanted
uh while Governor however with the
support of the district attorneys and
courts and with the with the budget
crisis we have we think there's a very
very strong case now for the governor to
sign this bill we are urging everybody
to contact the Governor Schwarzenegger
you can do so via the normal or
California normal websites we shall know
by uh the end of the month what the
verdict is uh let me say that this if it
does pass that is signed into law it
will also have uh nice implications for
proposition 19 because uh uh without it
uh if proposition 19 passes petty petty
uh marijuana fences like using marijuana
in public or in front of children would
remain a misdemeanor under Prop 19 but
if the Leno bill passes it would only be
a fraction and there would be no cause
for criminal action so let's hope that
the governor signs sp1 1449 thank
you