good afternoon everyone my name is
Barbara Bowl and i represent
congressional district number four which
is lame county a central part of the
state congressman defazio area I'm
excited about what's going on right now
my commercial brokerage insurance
brokerages that we have office and
Portland Eugene so I get to see a lot of
businesses small businesses like
business I happen to believe that this
could be our Napa Valley our silicon
valley if we do it right and we really
or the main component right I think that
the rest of the country is looking at
Oregon right now we have our number
three there been some mistakes that have
been made in the other two states we're
hoping to avoid those we want to hear
from you we're going to start making
rules later on this year with the idea
that this becomes an economic engine and
one of the goals that that I have is
that in the coming year this next
biennium the organ liquor control is
going to deliver to the state of Oregon
1.2 billion dollars that's what liquor
wine and beer does to the state remember
we don't have a consumption tax so you
know I want to be excited to one day say
guess what the cannabis industry
produced 1.2 billion dollars to the
state of Oregon and maybe we can build a
library once in a while so thank you