hello and good afternoon I'm a Kimberly
strand I am a patient a grower for
patients and I also own the cannabis law
here in the willamette valley called
fujian lodge and the 420 lounge thank
you i will say to you that over the
years we've been in Salem for six years
with not one altercation not one problem
never a DUI not even a noise violation
cannabis patients our local cannabis
patients have a garden community garden
where neighbors can come and take the
food they need during the summer we have
coat drives and food drives we've
cleaned up the building that was
abandoned for almost a year by the
Eagles and have made it a beautiful
place for people to come and gather and
they want to say that the Clean Air Act
that you're not allowed to come and
gather with your friends and I will tell
you the medical marijuana patients do
not medicate in 10 minutes like a
cigarette smoker does so when you say to
a terminally ill person or a person with
body pains and aches that I'm sorry now
you have to go outside and it's 42
degrees and it's raining and we want you
to power smoke down your joint so that
you don't hurt anymore I gotta say I'm
sorry we're just not doing it i'm
holding a daily open act of civil
disobedience at pd and because honestly
we got an outdoor smoking area and
that's where the cigarette smokers go
and I say to them don't let the door hit
you on the way out I also tell them if
you want to quit smoking I'll give you a
quarter ounce of pot a roller I pay a
pack of papers and every time you want
to smoke that cigarette you sit down and
you roll that joint and then you smoke
that cigarette all by yourself and guess
what I have 12 to 16 people every year
quit smoking cigarettes on my roll a
joint program for the last six years of
PGN so when you say to me I want you to
go outside in the cold because we're
worried about your secondhand smoke I'm
gonna say we're not gonna participate in
that cuz when you would you say we're
gonna go outside they're not kind of let
you back in
just know it they're not going to let
you back in once you give in don't give
up we have a beautiful outdoor smoking
area we do and it will continue to be
for cigarette smokers at the lodge as
long as possible and I know I'm probably
putting myself in jeopardy because it is
a complaint based program at this point
however if you let them push you outside
and push you back in the closet that's
where you'll be we fought long and hard
so that patients of dispensaries would
have the right to medicate many of them
can't work a four-hour shift without
taking a 10 minute break to medicate it
and now they got it you want him to
drive home medicate and drive back no no
also the targeting of our elderly
cannabis patients for DUI I happen to
have a patient who got a DUI for a
rolling stop at a stop sign because she
was taken to doff assert the utensil
that she smoked her medicine out of and
he arrested her right there on the spot
she didn't get a ticket for her pulling
stop she got a ticket cuz she had a bong
in the front seat of her car within the
drivers reach she got a DUI she's 72
years old she spent the night in jail in
Dallas is not a friendly place so I'll
just tell you you don't want to get get
a DUI for marijuana in Dallas they don't
think she was not treated with respect
she was not treated with dignity and now
she's in their system and being told
that she can't even Medicaid for 18
months while she's on parole or
probation or whatever this class she's
taken that's her medicine and she's
being denied this is wrong on so many
levels when you want to talk about
compassion and caring and helping people
they don't know they really don't know
they don't have a clue you have 12
people making the rules for 78,000
amazing people who need this medicine
and unfortunately we can't get them here
they're sick it's too cold for a lot of
my patients to be outside they couldn't
stand here for these two hours so bless
you I know many of you are in a lot of
pain standing out there to listen to us
beat it
out there that we need your help we're
not going to be put back in the closet
again we're not going to be ashamed that
we are cannabis patients this plant I've
seen it do so much for so many people
including my own my own life my dad I
was a police officer he got the Purple
Heart from the city of salem 79 years
old he wants to rub my bomb on his feet
so he goes to his doctor and he says doc
I just got to be legal I don't want to
smoke it but my daughter makes this bomb
and I want to rub it on my feet my feet
hurt so bad and they said Jerry just
take this medicine just take this
medicine for three months then a couple
weeks my dad had all the symptoms of
Alzheimer's he went to walmart forgot
where he was and he wet his pants in
walmart and i had to retrieve him so if
you're approaching 80 years old they
want to dope you and drugged you and
roll you into the hallway so they can
clean your beds and don't you not be a
bother to them I got my dad off that
medicine and within a week he have full
cognitive he now lives in Florida's 86
looking at girls in g-strings ok this is
no you should grow old happy with pain
relief that you choose quality is what
it's about amen it is about quality of
life and by god we live in oregon and we
should have the right to choose our
medicine alright how we live how we
treat our medicine and how we die thank
you very much for coming and bless you
all