hello everybody my name is Lori
Duckworth I'm the former director of
Southern Oregon normal in Medford Oregon
we were in operation for a little over
four and a half years right next to the
federal courthouse before we were rated
on May twenty-third 2013 my husband was
the president of the organization and I
was the executive director we both
suffered from PTSD at the time of that
raid from childhood experiences and he
also had a diagnosis of chronic pain CNI
of seizures nearly a year after that
raid when we were prepared to go to
trial with our lawyers Lee Limburger
who's here today thank you Leland and my
lawyer Justin Rosa a local attorney in
Medford we took a plea bargain and they
state of Oregon dropped 29 Class A
felonies against me and 28 against my
husband in exchange for one class C
felony the charge delivery of more than
one ounce of cannabis to another medical
marijuana card holder for no
consideration there's not even a charge
like that anywhere heard of but we took
it so we didn't have to face trial and
possibly going to jail for the rest of
our lives we got our guns and I
ammunition back on our business closed
approximately a year after that I was
diagnosed with cancer this is my
medicine now I take 3 grams a day the
current rules and regulations would
prohibit me from being able to purchase
that in a dispensary thank goodness
we're good growers and we have great
friends that own extraction companies
that can help us out with that the
current rules and regulations that are
being imposed or proposed and i met with
very early today earlier they're going
to hurt the program they're going to
damage the program and this program
has been the stepping stone to
legalization in this state I would
suggest all of you pick up a Newsweek
that just came out and read the story in
it it will explain to you how people
come into this state and take advantage
of our program with the illegal ways and
means and this is what happens to our
program we cannot stop fighting we the
honest people that have been part of
this program and we work hard number 436
436 in this state 17 years ago we cannot
stop fighting for this program for the
protection the preservation of it the
patients are the building block of
foundation for legalization we deserve
better the children deserve better the
dying hospice patients deserve to not
die before they can access their
medicine and dispensaries with their
safety packets safety packets it's crazy
that's all they get for three months
while they're waiting on their actual
credentials to come most of them died a
hospice patient has to be deemed 36
months or less to be hospice it takes
three months to get their actual card
from the state you can walk into a DMV
and get your driver's license a
temporary and what two weeks later get
it in the mail why is it so cumbersome
just to get your own man p card when we
just bottom that fancy new what
million-dollar system a couple years ago
the AC mmm has been a toothless
committee we need to be putting pressure
on our governor and on our state people
in this building right here to listen to
the AC mmm listen to us we are 76,000
strong we need to keep fighting never
give up never lose hope and remember
where did all of that marijuana come
from that started legal as a
it was grown by the farmers under the
patient program please talk to your
local representatives be professional be
precise and always walk the talk love
thank you