I'll start with where I represent
represent south jackson county
everything from the green springs to
ashland talent phoenix into Jacksonville
into the Applegate Valley I'm the house
Democratic co-chair of the Ways and
Means Committee which is the Budget
Committee in the state and I've always I
have favored legalization for for many
years I think prohibition does has not
worked we have decades of evidence that
says prohibition does not work and it's
counterproductive but what really spurs
me on now is having spent the last three
or four years on the Budget Committee
signing my name's to budgets that cut
education for our kids that cut health
care for seniors that make our
communities less safe by cutting back
public safety programs I can't in good
conscience continue to do that work of
trying to rebalance a state budget
through cuts when I know there is a
source of revenue that is reasonable
that is rational it's the right policy
choice and it's strike economic choice
for our state and that's the
legalization of marijuana and a
legalization of industrial hemp and i'm
not sure if all of you understand your
followed this but in 2009 the
legislature passed a bill confirming the
state of Oregon's policy is to have
legalized industrial hemp in our state
the federal government still says we
cannot grow it but we've passed
legislation on industrial hemp that as
soon as the federal government comes to
a rational decision on that and allows
the production of industrial hemp our
state will be ready to move into
production of industrial hemp and that
is it that that proposal just so you
know passed almost unanimously
Republican and Democratic urban and
rural in fact the representatives in the
senators from Eastern Oregon were some
of the most enthusiastic backers of
having industrial hemp as a crop for our
state because it just makes sense makes
economic sense for jobs in their
community it makes economic sense for
the state so we will get there on
industrial hemp and we are going to get
there and legalization the I can liken
this to the effort through the
initiative system of when women got the
right to vote Oregon was the first state
to put that on the
out and have it passed by our people it
took three times to get on the bat three
times on the ballot to finally pass and
begin the law of the state of Oregon
this effort has been building and we
have people here have worked on it for
many many years has been building for
many years we're at a point now we're
making a major leap forward by having
this on the ballot for the voters of
Oregon to give their their view on they
will render their verdict next Tuesday
will know what it is and if it passes
where they sincerely hope it does we'll
work with us to make it work and we'll
keep putting pressure on the feds to
make sure that becomes the law for the
state of Oregon and hopefully influence
the rest of the country it's on the
ballot in Washington it's on the ballot
in Colorado as well we will watch how
those elections turn out as well and
we'll build off what happens here on
Tuesday no matter what but I just want
to be here today to again express my
strong support for legalization my
strong support for industrial hemp as
well my strong support for ending
prohibition having rational drug
policies in the state of Oregon and the
United States of America to move in
totally different direction and the
other the last issue I'll touch you on
this one that there where I think called
the press conference here today to
emphasize as well is expansion of the
medical marijuana program to include
post-traumatic stress and that to me is
a reasonable and again totally vital
step for the state to to take we have
people in the state right now Oregon can
and should be a leader in the research
of how marijuana impacts ailments across
the board we have we have the growers
here we have the medical community here
and we obviously have the people in need
here we should put that together put the
people who are suffering ailments
together the people doing research on
marijuana and the growers and come up
with the data so we can say with great
confidence that someone who is suffering
from PTSD with this strain of marijuana
or that stern of marijuana can expect
certain results some with chronic pain
with this strain of marijuana or veteran
or marijuana used in this way can expect
this results the medical marijuana
program in my view needs to be
professionalized and we need to make
sure that's having the best possible
outcomes for the patients who are on it
and went
that I will just turn remember to you