maybe we can expand on why it seen is is
a good thing that the OLCC regulates
recreational marijuana when presumably
they don't have any experience with
cannabis I'd be uh particularly
interested on the consumption side of it
as far as
monitoring yeah the uh OLCC you know
they they have experience with alcohol
they have experience with licensing
rules regulations audits sting
operations collecting Taxation and so
they have experience dealing with you
know a relatively similar product so as
all the government agencies goes they
just happen to be the best one for this
program the Oregon Health Authority with
some with some experience dealing with
medical cannabis really made it clear
that they only wanted to stick with
medical cannabis and didn't want to move
into adult use over 21 so we really
didn't want to have an antagonistic
relationship with a government agency
that didn't really want the regulations
starting a brand new regulation on
unfortunately there are startup costs
associated with that and and so when you
start off with the state saying this
brand new agency is going to cost $22
million a year um for whether that's
true or not that uh really puts you in
in a tough position to win the election
so the OLCC you know has experience with
these type of rules and regulations and
uh they are definitely looking to be
educated from patients consumers people
in the industry how Washington and
Colorado's gone and they're definitely
looking to have you know work groups
around the various issues to to educate
themselves and that's one of the reasons
why we give the OLCC a full year to
develop the rules and regulations so
they have time to uh to learn about
cannabis bring in experts and pass you
know Common Sense rules and
regulations yeah that's one of the
things that was impressive for me is
ensuring that you have an agency that
actually has some expertise in
regulations of uh substances this is U
from my perspective what new approach
Oregon was able to do is come together
with a existing facility so you will not
find us needing to actually start from
Ground Zero as Anthony says uh one of
the things that is very important to
myself and many people that serve in the
legislature is that we do away with the
black market or the Underground Market
and uh by having the uh taxing structure
that they have placed in in in order uh
to move forward actually will give us
that best opport opportunity to undercut
we've seen historically when you look at
what happened with alcohol when it was
prohibited and when it came back you can
actually have the impact of undoing uh
the cartel type of philosophies uh by
actually having a well-regulated
industry I also believe that the OLCC
knowing for uh my discussions from uh
the executive director they're not
waiting until this passes they're
already there as Anthony says working
and watching and seeing from those who
are actually implementing in Colorado as
well as what's happening now in
Washington to be ready for uh what is
going to come forward and the I guess
not saving grace but I think the the
part of having a deep breath and
ensuring that we move forward in a
positive light is that there is a
one-year incubation to actually have it
up and running uh but clearly I can tell
you right now that uh Steve marks who is
the executive director of OLCC uh has
been on the phone with me and he has
made it very clear that he's working
with the department of a as well as the
Oregon Health Authority because the
measure itself deals not only with the
recreational part but also brings
forward some of the stuff I've worked on
in industrial hemp and also where you
have the medical part and I think we'll
get into some of the questions that we
go into greater detail why it's so
important that this uh uh measure that
new approach organ has put forward
actually calls out that we're going to
maintain a separate uh system for the
medical and it's not going to be blended
into the retail such as what has been
discussed at the Maran
state so let's let's address that what
what will happen to the or Oregon
medical marijuana program if this passes
and if OMMP continues will there be
separate dispensaries for medical and
recreational
purposes well I guess starting off from
where we're at yes I expected they will
one om p is going to stay in place the
uh new approach measure
ip53 uh calls that out and distinctly
says it will stand alone uh the
important part of that is because I
think the needs are very important for
all of us to realize as to exactly what
that program was set up for and what IT
addresses uh I was fortunate to be able
to uh help move forward after the
measure passed back in 1998 we had about
10 years that ran and actually showed
how the medical marijuana program was
working working how efficient it was and
how it was actually helping patients to
actually get the relief they want uh
knowing that and knowing that the
citizens actually passed uh that uh
measure which was if I'm not mistaken
was um ballot measure 67 uh back in 1998
uh what we basically have seen is that
it has actually worked to the point of
where we wanted to give the patients in
Oregon more control more assurance and
protection so in in 2009 I was able to
get my colleagues to actually support
changing the scheduling of marijuana
from a schedule one which is identified
as having no Municipal purposes to a
schedule two and so we are one
of we are the only state that I know
that has actually taken the step to
actually recognize what the people of
this state have said that we believe it
doesn't have a medical purposes and use
and it should be uh uh clarified and
classified to be a scheduled to drug and
so that is something that for me is very
important and clearly as long as the
federal government is let's say behind
and coming up where the people of this
state and 20 other states in the
District of Columbia are at as it
pertains to medical marijuana U until
they make the change from a schedule one
to a schedule two we have to do
everything we can to protect our
patients in this
state we've addressed this a little bit
um maybe you could expand on what impact
this uh legalization might have on the
black
market well my goal is to put it out of
business I mean the reality is we have
an opportunity uh to have it an industry
become more legitimate and out from
underneath the uh the rocks and from
behind um you know closed doors and and
Alleyways and everything else to the
point of where you can actually have a
viable industry that's actually going to
be producing Revenue that can go into
the state general fund to pay for
education uh human resource issues
health and wellness as well as for uh
Public Safety needs and so I do in fact
think that you're going to see uh the
the let's say the turning away and the
drying up of the uh of the black market
as it stands today and that you will in
fact and many of the people I represent
in the district I represent uh are
looking forward of coming uh out and
being more public and being able to
actually be accountable for what they do
and not be behind the scenes and being
concerned as to uh uh who might be uh
knocking on the doors be it law
enforcement or the bad guys trying to
get in and uh take what they what
they're doing right now and this is
something that spans Beyond urban areas
uh I represent a lot of rural areas of
Douglas and Lane counties and I can tell
you that there are a lot of people have
spoken to me about this topic and they
think that this is something that's
right for the state and it will make us
all better for it and we'll have the
accountabil
and the responsibilities will be in
place and then we are actually will see
Revenue coming forward that will help us
as a state