so good evening everybody
um thanks for coming out tonight my name
is Rob Patrick and I'm the chair of the
Oregon Liquor Control Commission and
we're happy to host these meetings I
think this is meeting number nine of or
eight of the uh number nine from
Arlington so eight of these meetings
we've seen almost 2 000 people face to
face from all around Oregon
um the commission is happy to sponsor
these events to get out have an informal
discussion uh to see what's going on
around the state to learn about your
thoughts related to measure 91. we're
really trying to focus our conversation
on hearing from oregonians about those
things that we can control at the Oregon
Liquor Control Commission we don't
control the taxes
the what is lecture controls that we
don't control things like
um we don't we don't control the taxes
we don't control where the money is
going to go many of those kinds of
things will continue to get questions
about we'll try and redirect those
questions and we may cut you off on
occasion but we don't want to cut you
off
because we don't want to hear from you
but we're going to cut you off so we can
focus on those things like marketing
packaging how you're going to obtain
your license how all those things are
going to work those things that we as
members of the OLCC can really affect
you know this was a measure that was
passed by Oregon voters
56 of the people said yes 44 said no and
as I've told people at every single one
of these sessions
I voted no on measure 94.
and I I'm very clear and open about it
and I made no bones about it but I'm
also the chair in the commission and as
the chair of the commission I have a
responsibility to put this measure into
place
in the in the right Manner and in a safe
and responsible manner for oregonians
we're not here to step on the air hoses
we're not here to do those things the
voters have spoken so now is our time to
make sure that it's done the right way
and so
I want you all to be respectful of each
other as we continue to move forward
we're here to gain information from you
and we're here to gain information from
all sides but the but the measure has
been settled and we're trying to get
solicit those responses from from people
about now how to put it in place
so let me give you the basics related to
measure 91. the measure was approved by
voters in November of 2014. it gives
OLCC these five Commissioners the
authority to tax license and regulate
marijuana in the state of Oregon
there are four license types that were
allowed under the measure those license
types include the producer or Grower's
license the processor license a
wholesaler's license and a retail
license so there are only four specific
types of licenses that were allowed in
the measure
licensees can hold multiple types of
licenses unlike alcohol where you can't
accept maybe if you're like a brew pub
or something you don't get to produce
distribute and Retail the alcohol
generally
the rest of the basics the excise tax in
Oregon is paid at the grower level
unlike Colorado and Washington which
have taxes at multiple levels the tax in
the state of Oregon is paid only at the
grower level
the net revenue distribution is not
decided by the OLCC it can be changed by
the Oregon legislature but this is what
oregonians voted for in the measure 40
percent to the common School fund 20 to
mental health alcoholism and drug
Services 15 to the state police 10 to
cities for law enforcement of this
measure 10 percent to counties for law
enforcement of this measure five percent
to the Oregon Health 30 for alcohol and
drug abuse prevention those were
included in the measure that oregonians
voted on
the ACT does not affect the Oregon
medical marijuana program
while there has been much debate related
to the Oregon medical marijuana program
and whether these programs should be
combined and those kinds of things
the OLCC has no authority to act to
combine programs or affect the Oregon
medical marijuana program there's some
synergies in the program that we're
we're interested in as the OLCC that we
have some probably will have some
recommendations related to the
legislature we'll talk about some of
those things later but just so people
are clear on where we're at with the
medical marijuana program we will ask
you some questions related to the
medical marijuana program and the merger
not because we have any effect over that
but because the legislature knows that
we're out here talking to oregonians and
they want our feedback as well so
they're using us as a sounding board
of what's going on the ACT allows a
homegirl of up to four plants and eight
ounces per resident beginning July 1st
2015. the OLCC has no control over the
home girl Provisions we don't regulate
the home girl Provisions there's nothing
in the act that provides our ability to
regulate those provisions
the ACT prohibits consumption in public
you can't smoke in public you can't take
marijuana in public you can't eat
brownies in public you can't eat Edibles
in the public you can't do any of those
things in a public area okay there's no
provision for lounges or bars or those
kinds of things for marijuana
the ACT does not allow local governments
to tax marijuana I know that there are
over a hundred local jurisdictions in
the state who have passed measures that
are interested in taxing marijuana the
OLCC does not get to decide whether
those local jurisdictions can tax
marijuana that is something to be worked
out either in the legislature or that's
something to be worked out in the court
system but again we're not going to talk
the LCC is not going to talk about the
taxes we don't have anything to do with
that tax level
localities May opt out through general
election if 10 percent of the voters in
a give it jurisdiction in the city or
county sign up put it on the ballot they
can't opt out of having licensees in
their jurisdiction all right it still
allows you know the Homegrown personal
use and those kinds of things but they
can opt out but many people don't know
is that you can also opt out a liquor
though we don't have cities and counties
in the state of Oregon who have opted
out of liquor but that's just a fun fact
laughs
Federal considerations we have you know
Federal considerations related to this
and you're all aware of this and the
OLCC is very aware of this marijuana
remains illegal under federal law all
right so it's a business risk right so
we just point that out to everybody
however on August 29 2013 the U.S
Department of Justice issued guidance to
the states that have legalized
recreational marijuana
they've issued guidance under what is
called the coal memorandum
c-o-l-e so the call memoranda provides
the guidance to states that are putting
recreational marijuana into effect the
coal memorandum doesn't have the force
of law
it's merely an opinion of the U.S
attorney's Office under the current
Administration Administration to
Administration could change that so it
doesn't have the force of law if you'd
like to look at the coal memorandum in
its original form go to
marijuana.oregon.gov and you can
download or look at online
okay
Federal guidance this is the main points
of the coal memorandum
so the main parts of the cool memorandum
are to one prevent the distribution of
marijuana to minors
prevent revenue from the sale of
marijuana we're going to criminal
Enterprise
cartels
three prevent the diversion of marijuana
from where it is legal under state law
to other states
so we don't want it going out of state
no interstate commerce
four perfect State authorized activity
from being used as a cover for illegal
activity
we don't want to be growing things in
the recreational market then la la all
of a sudden they're all over the country
so that's what they don't want to have
happen
five prevent violence and the use of
firearms and the cultivation and
distribution of marijuana
six prevent drug driving and other
adverse Public Health consequences
associated with marijuana use
seven prevent the growing of marijuana
on public lands
and eight prevent marijuana use on
public property
there's actually the eight kind of
principal points of what the coal
memoranda says but again go to
marijuana.oregon.gov to take a look at
the original by yourself
in order to meet the precepts of those
eight points from the coal memorandum
both Colorado and Washington
and the state of Oregon is now looking
at right now and in the process of
preparing a request for proposal for a
seat to sale tracking system we don't
feel that we can comply with federal law
without having to see the sale tracking
system
all right
I already said Colorado Washington
require it and the reason they require
it is so the taxes are cold properly
collected and that the inventory does
not migrate from the residential Market
into a black or gray Market
so that's the reason we have the seat of
sale tracking system
it's designed for more effective Audits
and to satisfy federal guidelines
it's also for efficiency
we can't have people going to every
recreational marijuana grow and whatever
and you know individually counting every
single plant we'd have a fleet of
Auditors we need to be able to go
through and with the one with RFID tags
and be able to say how many plants are
here and what's going on and are they
properly where they're supposed to be
and those kinds of things it's for
efficiency not only for us but for for
the operations and that's what they do
in a lot of the manufacturing Industries
today
so we mentioned before there are only
four license types that were allowed
those four license types
well we have more for alcohol
they're they're very restrictive in what
they do so the first type of license is
a producer license
it's only able it's only able to
cultivate marijuana it's responsible for
the payment of tax at the first point of
sale
so for example the commission had an
educational session today we're going to
make some recommendations of the
legislature one of the things that we
she has a potential deficit on the
producer licenses we don't be able to
have this you know kind of Farm to Table
kind of thing that we have on the food
products industry under the way the law
under the way measure 91 was written you
can't be a grower package it for retail
and sell it directly to a retailer
you've got to have two licenses so that
doesn't seem to make a lot of sense to
some of us and so that's something the
legislature would have to change but
it's something that we as a commissioner
trying to look at
the processor license the processor
license packages and labels marijuana
items okay
also it would be the manufacturer you'd
have to get this kind of License to
manufacture edibles
and extracts okay
in addition to that we have a wholesale
license
those people that buy and sell at
wholesale so this is a required license
but as as markets mature wholesalers
come in
so that license is anticipated by the
measure
and the fourth and final license is the
retail license it sells marijuana items
that retail to adults over 21 years old
so that's the retailer that's the person
who's doing it
um
that's the one who sets up the shops so
but there are other licenses that the
OLCC is considering asking the
legislature about doing you know one of
the things is testing we want we're
interested in having testing but if you
were a testing facility there's no way
to get licensed to be able to hold the
marijuana out of the recreational system
so those are some of the tweaks and
things that as the OLCC does its work
and as we work with the industry and we
work with everyone to understand where
we work with local government law
enforcement those are all the things
that we want to make sure in the system
so that when your product's being
transported from your facility to the to
the test facility that it's in this seed
to sale tracking system so if somebody
gets pulled over by law enforcement or
something else happens you have a
manifest it's clear where it started
where it's gone where it's going and and
the plan through the system so that's
why we're doing what we're doing we're
doing it for everybody's protection and
transparency in the system
advertising packaging and testing these
are this is going to be probably one of
the biggest and hottest areas related to
where OLCC is going to be involved
the ACT gives us the authority to
regulate or prohibit advertising
we can regulate packages and labels to
ensure Public Safety and prevent an
appeal to minors
and we can adopt standards and testing
requirements
so this is an area where you know we're
in new ground really we regulate alcohol
alcohol is a federal it's regulated at
the federal level it all falls under the
Federal Constitution
so
the rules are kind of clear OLCC for
example we don't approve any of the beer
and wine and alcohol labels that's all
done at the federal level so we don't
have the internal infrastructure at the
OLCC or the trained staff that's
familiar with those kind of processes
currently so those are some of the
things where we're going to be able to
be seeking a lot of public input related
to those types of items
impaired driving
the ACT does not identify a specific
limit for driving a blood level in it
both Washington and Colorado in their
original measure past a blood level
limit for impaired driving
does not have that
but I can tell you as a D.A we prosecute
people on a regular basis all around the
state for drug driving so we currently
have a system in place to deal with drug
driving around the state but the ACT
does require the OLCC to examine
research and present a report to the
legislature related to impaired driving
in the state of Oregon related to
marijuana so what are we doing we're
working with the Department of Justice
investigation Division and the Oregon
State Police to gather the data together
to present that report so we're trying
to work with everybody local government
but the state police is really the main
place where all that where all that
information is gathered but we're
charged with that data collection and
implementation report
many people have asked what's the
timeline for implementation and I think
you've all seen stories coming out of
Washington and Colorado related to those
things we're trying to be very
transparent with the public about what
their expectations are
we're trying to keep within the spirit
this group is certainly uh very much
into keeping it to the spirit of the
measure and keeping into the timelines
but our commission also acknowledges the
fact that when oregonians signed up
and put their signatures on the
initiative measure to get measure 91 on
the ballot we also didn't have the
experience of having two states legalize
marijuana so we also feel like we would
be remiss as a commission and I think
the legislature feels the same way that
we would be remiss if we didn't learn
from the what's been fared it out in
both Colorado and Washington
so we want to keep with the spirit of it
but we're going to go slow we're going
to do it the right way and we're going
to do it in Oregon's way we're not just
going to you know
they're all every single one of these
states is different
January 1st 2015 personal possession and
home production become legal in the
state of Oregon
that's uh that was in the measure and
that's what's uh happening with personal
possession of Home production again the
OLCC does not regulate personal
possession and home production
March through 2015 we will begin to
notice rulemaking
um we're probably only going to be able
to put these rules in on a on a
temporary basis just because of the
timelines to hit our January deadline
with ultimately a final rules package
coming forward but through March through
October 2015 there will be plenty of
opportunity what we're going to do is
we're going to graph a set of rules
we're going to get an Advisory Group and
I'll go for more detail later but that's
what we're doing is Rule making March
through October our hope is that by
November of 2015 we will have a
temporary rules package in place so that
we can begin to tilt up the system
January 4th 2016.
this measure requires us to as the OLCC
to begin accepting applications for
licenses so that's what it requires is
April I mean January 4th 2016.
but what does that mean that means we've
got to start accepting applications for
licenses but that doesn't mean that
you're going to be able to walk into a
retail establishment and buy marijuana
across the counter January 4th 2016. so
late in 2016 is when we believe retail
sales will begin why do we believe that
well I think people watched what
happened in the state of Washington uh
they had this huge Spike because there
wasn't enough product in the market and
there was huge costs and then it's
flattened out it's done all kinds of
crazy things remember we're this is a
this is an industry well well nobody on
the commission does not believe we have
a mature marijuana industry in the state
of Oregon we certainly do we certainly
have a brand and a reputation worldwide
related to the marijuana that's
currently we
that marijuana cannot come immediately
into the retail system it has to be
grown in the retail system and tracked
in the seed to sale system there's got
to be a harvest cycle there's got to be
processing and packaging approval and
then then retail stores can come online
so that's why we're saying realistically
late in 2016 is when we begin to believe
something will begin to come online we
also intend to process those
applications in order of you know
Growers and then you know producers and
then retailers who certainly are trying
to do that so that we can be efficient
so that we don't have some of the same
pitfalls in Washington Colorado
all right
public engagement you're here you're
obviously publicly engaged but we have
the listening tour again I can't stress
enough how many people have gone to
marijuana.oregon.gov
okay well if you haven't take a look at
it okay uh volunteers with expertise in
the range of issues related to measure
91 so we're going to appoint a rules
advisory commission to do that
um we're going to include law
enforcement Insurance Chiefs DA's local
government cities and counties from
industry Growers processors testing
kitchen people in retail
the proponents of measure 91
and three other members of the public
that's kind of our intent
at this point we
questions
clarifying not discussion oriented I
promise you we're going to have time for
that yes I've got a question on uh the
board here you you mentioned everybody
and you have a D.A a real estate agent
an insurance agent you see no conflict
of interest with going ahead and setting
these laws in your case perhaps
Prosecuting them sounds like discussion
to be but go ahead and answer yeah can
you guys stick with clarifying right now
I don't I personally don't see a
conflict of interest these are
recreational marijuana laws and rules
that we're putting in place
um I don't see the insurance guys having
a conflict work you know we have no
direct financial interest in it so and
they will be stopped from let's say
selling real estate to people and uh for
the person that does sell real estate
and they will be stuck from selling or
having a list of people that can get
insurance from no
you mentioned that you'd be working with
the industry
is there a growers association involved
or is there a non-profit organization
that represents a growers association
like the wine industry the nursery
industry
there are several grower groups around
the state we've had several of them
testify before as invited testimony
before our commission as well as the
legislative committee most of those are
private groups you know beer the beer
people and the wine people have
something in statute that's distilling
industry the craft distilling industry
is asking for something statute this
time this point time though marijuana
does not have anything
in place at that kind of state level but
I know that there are loose groups of
Growers around the state that we are we
have been that are organized that we've
been reaching out to
um that that are identifiable and have
also reached out to us
won't affect the OMP program but I just
want to clarify uh specifically on House
Bill 2040 that bans medical marijuana
businesses within one mile radius of
schools that will have no effect on the
home MP program for say existing growth
sites what I would tell you is I don't
know anything about
that particular piece of legislation the
commission is really focused on we don't
have any control over the OMMP the only
people that could affect that is the
Oregon legislature so you're right to
look at those bills but that doesn't do
it we don't have any control over those
bills my question is on the in the
impaired driving
are trying to produce products that have
zero THC in them and and that is
essentially for those who are possibly
drivers and those who are possibly
children and how how does that affect
those folks that there is no THC which I
believe that's the active ingredient in
there so if there are only CBDs and
stuff that helps seizures on the Glam
all epileptic so we would like to be
able to control those things and not get
high and so are you folks setting up
some form of
you know clarification on that because
I'm sure there's a lot of energy well
most of that is under the most of those
are under the Oregon medical marijuana
program recreational marijuana cannot
have cannot be given to children at all
it's those over the age of 21. so most
of that will be housed in the in the
medical marijuana program which again we
have no regulatory oversight or ability
to to control that how many people are
going to be on that rules advisory
committee and if that's determined like
legislatively or if that's something
that you guys have within your power to
determine so the rules advisory
committee is at the commission level
it'll be director appointed
at least a plan at this point in time
and we had the discussion today we're
waiting to hear back from staff tomorrow
morning uh the the pitch today was
having a third about 13 members on that
committee but it's uh it's a it's
through the OLCC so that's and then
there's a plan to do a bunch of
subcommittees underneath that especially
for to get some really specific
knowledge
should there be restrictions on where
marijuana businesses can operate yes
there should be restrictions on where
they can operate red no I think okay
largely green but it's mixed they're
Reds and a few yellow scattered within
there wow he's holding his a friend no
and what we've heard from some of these
jurisdictions is that you know we don't
control jurisdictions you know and some
of the jurisdictions have asked the
legislature to take a look at allowing
them to maintain home rule because each
of us live someplace else
and some of the concern is is that from
the state level we'll start telling the
cities and the counties how to run their
communities and so that's where that
question kind of came from
should retail outlets be allowed to
co-locate with medical marijuana
dispensaries yes or no
should they be allowed to co-locate with
medical marijuana dispensaries very
predominantly green but let's this
gentleman wants to speak I understand
the co-mingling of both medical and
recreational but
I feel the problem is medical got such a
historical recreational for people that
are already owning medical dispensaries
they have an unfair advantage
so for the people on the recreational
side
you have to adhere by a different set of
rules and finding those limited spaces
that are still available is becoming
harder and harder
the same regulation a thousand people in
the school another dispensary
you're not giving the same platform she
said
one of the main concerns was already
brought up which is regulation Law
Enforcement wants one system to audit
we've heard them say that over and over
so that's something that you're going to
have to consider from their perspective
OLCC probably they're not going to tell
you right now but they probably feel the
same way they want one system to audit
and beyond that I think that if you're
going to have a thousand foot from each
other buffers where are you going to put
a recreational store in Portland
nowhere there's 117 dispensaries in
Portland out of 225 in the State uh
uh okay at least 110 of them are
licensed okay yeah so should there be
should there be a server type of permit
in marijuana just like there is an
alcohol green Yes red no yellow Maybe
okay okay
so Tom you've got somebody
I'm opposed to having them have a
permitting process okay another fee to
before it starts first of all the real
issue that we're looking at is surfing
underage
underage people I think that's really
the only concern in terms of the
training at this point and that's the
only thing we have research to back up
or anything to go on forward with and I
already heard the commission talk about
implementing a potential card check
measure against people who are found
bioaving and serving underage people so
there's already a policy where they can
hand down some consequences in terms of
people who are breaking the law and
serving minors and beyond that there's
really not any sort of standard set or
any sort of information to create this
test that bud tenders are supposed to
pass and it just really doesn't serve
any greater purpose I guess
I think there are a number of concerns
about getting marijuana served to me as
a consumer Beyond just whether or not my
gray hair says that I'm too old or too
young for it I want to know that the
person that's grabbing that butt has
washed their hands are they wearing a
glove do they know the difference
between indica and sativa they have any
idea what concentrates are how long to
wait for a cookie to take to kick in
there are a lot of concerns and I want
to make sure that the people that are
serving the especially the new cannabis
consumers that will be coming into and
the tourists we don't want to have bad
headlines like they had in Colorado
let's make sure that our servers are
licensed and trained
please don't confuse being served in a
bar with buying recreational weed
all right should there be limits on the
size of commercial marijuana grow
operations and that's number of plants
or canopy yet to be determined but
should there be some sort of limits on
the size of the growing operation
mostly red mixed but mostly red I would
say more red than green not similar to
farming
born acre Valley
the small farmers they're not
big in the state there's a lot of
farmers that are small and it shouldn't
be limited to you know you can only grow
five corn flasks or tomatoes it should
just be based on the regulations in
place and the rules you know as long as
you're meeting that you can
you can do what you want
there's we have no idea how many users
of recreational marijuana are going to
be
at this point we have no idea it's too
early to put that into place and how
large a grow operation needs to be the
grow operation will serve the clients
that they sell to and there's no way for
us to know exactly
what that will look like
and you know if we put a restriction on
it now that will limit the size of
businesses it'll limit the number of
people that they can serve and so on
would there be different requirements
for indoor and outdoor grow operations
should there be different requirements
oh really mixed
and a lot of yellows
it's important that marijuana growers
have a security system
should they have a security system
okay a lot of greens mostly greens
so that's one of the things when we ask
the first question that's one of the
things a lot of the audience would talk
about is the different requirements for
security with an indoor versus an
outdoor
you have a couple of follow-up questions
yeah so so one of the big questions
we've had one of the questions that's
going to be on our mind is we prepare to
put rules into place how many people
think that video surveillance systems
should be required on any marijuana
growth
video surveillance huh
well then you should have a recorded
video surveillance system
and there's a lot of Reds there are a
lot it's really mixed which is the issue
of uh testing
so should the OLCC require testing of
recreational marijuana for things such
as potency pesticides and molds should
there be a requirement for testing okay
that's pretty so that's pretty
overwhelmingly green people would be in
favor of requiring that the medical
marijuana program
adopt the same testing standard as the
recreational program okay that too
about so we appreciate your input on
that
yeah well standardized fantastic the
fellow up here the question he asked is
is the will the labs be standardized and
that's a lot of what we've heard is that
you're getting those of you are who are
having your product tested are getting
really different results depending on
the labs and I'm seeing heads knots
should edible recreational marijuana
products be available
yes okay that's what I thought so should
edible recreational marijuana packages
contain information on dosage and
serving sizes
yes okay simple okay so should should we
prohibit recreational marijuana products
that may be appealing to children
this is where yeah we get more mixed on
this one should there be standards
for what's required on labels like there
is on food you know and you know what
you're getting
so should there be standards set for
what's required on the labels and that's
overwhelmingly green thanks guys for
having this meeting
um I I know that the statute in measure
91 says there's not going to be the
public use cafes uh scenarios
um my question is specifically is there
going to be any kind of involvement for
a private club style scenario so the RCC
we don't believe currently has the
licensing ability or regulatory
authority to have a license for a club
oriented business so that would be
something the Oregon legislature would
have to tackle so if you're interested
in that you'd have to talk to the
legislature my name is Russ Bellville
I'm the executive director of Portland
normal and I want to thank you for
having these listening sessions uh I
would encourage you as a Liquor Control
Commission in the gray areas where it
isn't specifically dictated by measure
91 that an operating principal should be
what do we do with alcohol and so when
you have questions like how big or how
much should people be able to grow in a
commercial setting how much can they
brew at Widmer how much can they brew at
McMenamins is there a limit on them if
there is apply it to us
when we're talking about serving we're
talking about retail licensing we're
talking about packaging I don't think
these questions are too hard to answer
we've already answered them with the
most deadly dangerous drug there is
alcohol apply that reasoning to
marijuana
hi my name is Jefferson uh kind of a
response to that I think there needs to
be a strong Focus
on limits on growing precisely because
as someone mentioned there's no limits
on current plans but this isn't a corn
plant this is a specific Niche product
and Oregon's distilling in Brewing
Industries have become
the high points of the national scene
that they are by letting Niche markets
grow and if this is turned into
something where a Thousand Acre Farms
can produce tons than the local Growers
isn't going to have a place or
to compete so will there be a
a focus and emphasis on letting small
businesses
become part of the scene I wanted to
provide my perspective on just three
quick issues um and you don't need to
respond I just wanted to say so one is
is that everything that you guys are
doing please do it with the mind of
encouraging this industry and not
restricting or reducing it because we're
at a stage right now where we really
want to grow this industry so um you
know with the exception of necessary
restrictions we want to avoid any
unnecessary hindrances on the industry
the second thing is when it comes to
kids I think we shouldn't be irrational
or overblow the issue kids have access
to marijuana today they've had access
for marijuana you know 50 years ago I
don't think that putting um bright
colors on the label are going to make
more kids smoke marijuana I don't think
we need to worry about that especially
when we're looking at them being
available in adult-only stores so um
don't get blown away by this idea of
protecting our children we've already
established rules and limits that take
that into account and then the final
thing is um with regards to the
limitations on the plants canopies
acreage whatever I I think that we need
to take into account that we want to
encourage economies of scale cost
savings energy efficiencies and things
like this and not put unnecessary risk
restrictions that require us to do
things that require excessive energy or
that require excessive cost that would
be a burden on the industry
my name is Jackson McCormick I'm a
dispensary owner and I wanted to talk
about co-location and a couple ways to
address that I think the testing
standard is a way to address that and I
think the Oregon Health Authority would
be pressured heavily by myself and other
dispensary owners to have Labs adopted
adopt a standard because as you said
we've all experienced here the issue
with testing drastically differently
between facilities I think that would
solve the biggest issue of co-location
where the marijuana program already
requires customer specific historical
purchase information to be kept on site
that's more regulation than we're going
to be requiring in the recreational
Market I also don't think the seed to
sale aspect is really that influential I
don't think people are rushing to be
regulated and paid taxes and then are
going to sell their product in the black
market or vice versa I think that slows
down the process of the recreational
Market hammering down the black market
and eliminating it completely because if
we create a safe access and illegal
access that pays good taxes people are
going to be interested in all the
estimates so far indicate that the
purchase price in Oregon is going to be
ridiculously low so I just really LC the
intense focus on the seed to sale aspect
of the
um I have comment about the limiting of
the acreage or whatever for Growers I
feel it should be limited because you're
going to have a millionaire farmer out
in eastern Oregon with 6 000 acres and
then you're going to have a small person
down in Eugene with only two acres it
really will help to limit it because the
small businesses will then have an
opportunity to thrive my other question
is there's an open container law for
driving
will there be an open pipeline or
whatever you know so so currently there
is no open container law like there is
in alcohol I know there's a strong
interest in the commission addressed
that today as one of the items that uh
that the legislature needs to take a
look at so that we can have
clarification personal use is a kind of
a gray area you know there's right no
we're well aware it's my personal space
okay
I have an assessment and a question an
assessment is that you know this
industry is in you know it's real
infancy right now and
putting too many an onerous regulations
on the people who are going to be
building this industry and its Embassy I
think is a general guideline maybe it's
not the greatest idea in the world as a
question I am curious what the review
process is going to be over time
um because you know this is the industry
will be evolving so is there going to be
a review process say to review the
regulations and you know that big
changes accordingly you know change
course okay I would tell you that the
OLCC tries to regularly look at its
rules on a regular basis we have
hearings we have all kinds of things
related to changing alcohol rules to
meet the market we had to deal with
issues related to Growlers and we had to
deal with all those kinds of issues and
we were Market innovators that were
pushing the rest of the country so you
have the staff and a group of
Commissioners who are committed to
constantly re-looking at those things so
it's not just something we put on the
shelf and then keep going
I believe the creativity of both the
Edibles as products and the graphics
used to advertise them should not be
limited by if it appeals to Children if
you as a consumer purchase an edible
product you need to be responsible for
keeping it out of the hands of the
children just like alcohol
I understand the importance of not over
taxing based on
what's going on in Washington
but what I my question is is why is it
um just the grower it seems like burning
but what I would tell you is that's what
oregonians voted on and that's what the
proponents of the measure put forward
and we didn't have anything to do with
that at OLCC I'm not sure why they did
it that way they've never provided a
great explanation for me from that
marketing side and I know one question
we've come up with quite a bit is uh
basically advertising kind of over the
border and I guess I would kind of
encourage and kind of ask you all if the
OLCC plants are really communicate that
the Washington about how those laws will
interact as far as uh basically business
on the board advertising back and forth
so just so you understand
the the call memorandum specifically
tells us not to be involved in
interstate commerce between the two
states so you are probably not going to
see this commission trying to engage in
conversations with Washington about how
that advertising works uh the first
issue the first thing is about uh you
know size grows limitations residency
restrictions I think all of us are just
looking for a way to protect Oregon from
Walmart and Kmart and everything else
and give the opportunities to the small
business so I appreciate that you guys
are taking that issue seriously the last
thing then is uh with regards to the
testing would that fall under cost of
goods sold and would that be a tax
deductible
item
that that would be but as you guys are
all aware there's really specific
federal tax rules related to this we
there were some deduction things that we
had to deal with that OLCC is looking at
working with Department of Revenue and I
agree that you shouldn't be heavy-handed
in terms of sea to seal tracking but
clearly because of the coal memo and you
know you don't want a product diverted
into a black market and you want to be
able to track it for taxation clearly
you have to have strong robust seed to
sale tracking system but I would I would
offer a cautionary till
Washington that really approaches from
technology perspective and not a policy
perspective so that when you adopt um
seed to sale software
regulations or specifications for a
database that allows free open access to
other software competitors because
that's really going to create what
Marvin referred to as as the Silicon
Valley of of where and Oregon has a
unique opportunity to really create a
connoisseur culture for marijuana and
ADD to the technology perspective
but my question is mostly about Growers
later on when we get moving into this
how are we going to do breeding and Seed
sales even within the state and before
that how are Growers going to obtain the
seeds
so the OLCC is asking the same question
as part of the three plus hour policy
discussion we had this morning we have
asked the legislature to clarify that
because it's not clear from a policy
position even what the OLCC should do
related to that
you know are we going to assume
Immaculate Conception and that's one
yeah
that is what a lot of other states have
done but we we have asked the
legislature to clarify that from a
policy perspective because we don't want
to send our staff out there into this
unknown so we think it's fair to
everybody to at least clarify what we're
going to do
hi my name is Kelly and I'm a co-ower
owner of a lab and also work to help
running a dispensary since 2010. I just
come to give input from a lot of people
I've been talking to and the Oregon
residency thing seems to be a big thing
that's important to people here
um also with the Medicals and concerning
children a lot of us feel like there's
already something in place for that
concern which is Criminal consequences
and I know a lot of people in this
industry have kind of Taken offense that
we get the wrap that we are not
responsible adults around children
also when it comes to lab testing I just
ask that hopefully you get as much input
from as many Labs as you can instead of
just one or two
and then with that when you're
implementing the rules just keep in mind
just as much input from the public
concerns that is as there is for the
industry since we have the most
experience of knowing what's efficient
how this can work best
what kind of the issues relating to
banking are in Oregon because in
Washington the horror stories are just
crazy with what people have to go
through just to be able to put their
money that they made off of this
industry in the bank and so I was
wondering uh
the banking issues predominantly a
federal issue we just had the Arc of
Treasury as well as Department of
Revenue as well as mbank which is a bank
that is accepting
um which is accepting the positives
um we are in discussions mbake has had
some limited discussion with us related
to what they're going to require of
their customers we certainly realize
it's an issue we don't have the capacity
to LCC to once a month have Brinks
trucks roll up to the front door with
cash to pay your taxes so we have the
same concern at llcc as well so we are
trying to work on that but that is
predominantly a federal issue that we
can't control first of all I just want
to speak out in support of the canopy
limits because I believe that the one of
the main key purposes of this law is to
bring marijuana production into a
tightly well-regulated system and I
believe a key component of that is
co-opting the people that are currently
growing on the black market and so forth
and I can tell you that if it's if it's
not designed in such a way to co-opt as
many of those as possible they're going
to just keep on growing because they're
you know they're they've been doing this
for a very long time and so uh if
they're if it's not designed for that
purpose it's gonna you know it's going
to cause a problem and having smaller
limits will allow the little guy to have
a chance to be able to take part in this
industry in an economic way
and uh I would say that you know in
Washington they had 21 000 square foot
limits they had three tiers I can tell
you the 21 000 square feet of weed a
thousand to two thousand pounds of weed
is a lot of weed okay so you know
they're that it's going to be a good
size for area a thousand or two thousand
square feet of canopy is quite it's it's
a lot of weeds uh the second point is I
am a Clark County resident and I've
heard I know that this is a main issue
so I don't want to really push anybody's
buttons on this but the as a Clark
County resident I am a member of this
metro area and Clark County residents we
pay over 150 million dollars a year in
income tax revenue for the state of
Oregon and we're the eighth largest
county in Oregon State as far as tax
revenue and I would just I would just
really like to have an opportunity to
take part in the economic uh life of
this of this community uh so I would
hope any uh I know there isn't any
actual residency requirements in the
building that'll be up to you guys to
decide that but I would hope that maybe
I said it's up to the logic okay
um I would just hope that whatever is
decided that uh taking into
consideration the economic participation
of of adjacent counties I would say
would I would hope that you would keep
that under consideration
concerns I have just to kind of touch on
the point that the gentleman just made
was
if we're creating a seed to sales system
isn't that kind of contradictory to not
allowing canopy limits because if the
sea to sailing you're trying to track
you to make sure you keep it off the
black market but then you give Farmers
the ability to grow an abundant amount
of product that's supply and demand it
doesn't work properly I mean it's
inevitable that some of it's going to
get to the black market
the second concern I have is
commingling medical marijuana
dispensaries with recreational use
in my mind I I tracked this pretty
closely I've been part of the industry
for a long time and in my mind
the medical marijuana dispensary side
was able to be established before the
law was even molded on for recreational
use so anyone that wants to come into
the business going through the due
process of trying to do it with the the
legal parameters that were given we're
not given an opportunity I don't know if
you do co-mingle those two there's no
real reason for you to have any little
licensing application for the
recreational side
especially in the city of Portland
if there's that many retailers already
out there on the medical dispensary side
and it doesn't give the recreational
side the ability to tap into that market
what are we doing what are we here for
if someone buys let's just say a brownie
or even flour or whatever they buy are
they going to be able to look up where
it came from who grew it
if it's organic or any of that kind of
stuff it's going to be tracked all the
way through the system I don't know that
we're going to make that available
exactly to the person we're more into
tracking the product not necessarily the
product back
and will there be a tax write-off for
people who get outside software to help
pay for the software for seed to sale as
we read the bill or as we read the law
currently there will be those will be
the cost of goods sold and I was just
wondering how you guys were going to
decide who receives the license
so there's been a lot of questions
sometimes related to licensing there's
no limit on licenses in the state of
Oregon we always have to choose to do
that we don't do that in their alcohol
regulation we haven't we aren't down
that path yet but we certainly have
heard not to have any restrictions on
licenses everywhere we've gone pretty
much for the most part
what are the limits on THC per serving
and per package and what's the yeah
what's the maximum we haven't set those
limits and those are going to be things
that we're going to be having a
conversation with co-working about as we
go through the rules process I know in
uh in Washington I saw about 100
milligrams per package and I know
there's users that use more than that in
a day
um
I know that would be expensive I don't
know
yeah we're certainly looking at
we're certainly looking at setting a
serving size standard which is how we
believe we're going to have to inform
the public about it what that size is
and how much that is we're going to have
to you know be able to put out there so
we're not sure what that is I'd like to
say uh
keeping the existing medical
dispensaries and recreational
dispensaries distinctly separate gives
the recreational dispensaries a more
even
Lakeville
okay and uh
the limits on the personal growth
does it allow for enough of the Next
Generation to keep a Perpetual grow
going
and floor plans isn't going to last
anybody a year in less than 12 feet tall
my questions first was on a public level
of public transparency will you make the
public engagement statistics well all
this information even collecting will
you make that information public so we
know that actually what the people have
spoken is actually reflected upon your
actions and state and you know yeah I
think we're summarizing what's what's
been done so yeah we're trying to make
that available but we don't have a very
limited staff I understand yep and then
the secondary question you mentioned the
40-some items that you sent off the
legislature for recommendation I was
wondering if that was sent out to be
made publicity mail your email list or
system certainly and where we haven't
adopted it yet we're going to probably
adopted the commission meeting tomorrow
okay great adapters option it would go
out yeah after adoption it's going to be
it's a public document as it is but I
mean yeah exactly available yeah great
thank you so much uh the the basically
that my only statements are one just to
request to treat alcohol uh you know to
treat the Cannabis similar to alcohol
and tobacco and specifically or alcohol
oil and wine specifically
alcohol 100 plus times the most recent
study more harmful than marijuana
cannabis medical or otherwise and my
request is just strongly to reduce
whatever kind of bigotry is involved and
to sort of have as much fairness and
parity in whatever you're treating
whatever professional Recreation
uh and then the last is uh tourism to
make it available for tourism and then
fencing with the fencing it costs 40
Grand defense an acre 50 or more eight
to ten feet high with Cyclone fencing
which takes about 18 seconds to break
through that same 40 Grand would create
a security system with lasers and lights
and forget the whole nine yards Auto
tracking auto alarms much cheaper and
much more effective for an electronic
system than a hardware okay thank you
and I want to highly recommend that we
do ban Edibles that are appealing to
kids there's several products that can
be used that aren't attractive to kids
so I would like to see the Edibles like
the candy and the suckers and the gummy
bears and all that free band thank you
thank you very much