good afternoon and thank you everyone
for coming out this is a very important
beginning of a session for us it's all
important that we all be involved my
name is mike mullins and i'm with stony
girl Gardens stony only dispensary and
we have our PortMaster damn university
but today i'm not here to talk about my
businesses i'm not here to talk about my
right to party i'm here to talk about my
right as a patient to qualified medicine
and to have access to that medicine
wherever i live in the state of oregon
it's a shame that we now have gone
backwards and gotten back to putting
patients on the east side of our state
and in many other areas and denied them
access many of those patients cannot
afford to grow for themselves many of
them patients cannot do for themselves
whatsoever and depend on people such as
myself to be a caregiver in a grower
unfortunately we're hearing stories that
this has become so over regulated and so
costly that our patients are going to
lose access to qualified medicine
they've already lost access to the
places where they used to get their
qualified medicine Michaela would never
have gotten her medicine in hermiston
store if it were closed she's alive
today because she was able to access
that medicine we all know that first of
all cannabis is medicine and to attest
to that fact I can tell you that our
healthcare industries the largest ones
in the state of Oregon who provided the
health insurance for all of the people
who are in this building have already
approached us and are looking for an
integrated path to cannabis therapeutics
because their doctors know that cannabis
is medicine the fact is is that they've
already approached us they're already
looking for an avenue we've already
given them a five-year integration path
to be able to utilize this for their own
purposes to recommend it to the patients
as they are now doing through licenses
the fact is is that our lawmakers and
our need to know that they have never
been able to legislate the black market
and that's trying to do it now will
accomplish nothing but reinforce the
black market that we've worked so hard
to get rid of here in Oregon I would
like to say I'm very proud of Oregon we
are the second oldest state in the
nation to have a medical marijuana
program and have one of the most
successful medical marijuana programs
it's unfortunate that the lawmakers in
their fear
and are trying to push prohibition again
I only have one thing to say to our
legislators and that is instead of
taking this program back to Prohibition
and creating failure they should be
focused on building the success of
Oregon's future and the advantage that
we may have thank you