my edit my medical issue started with
comas surgeries seizures anxiety and yes
PTSD I started on 36 meds a day and I've
managed with the help of cannabis and my
doctors to only have one pill a day now
in cannabis that's my success we are all
individuals with different needs and so
please I beg of you to please leave our
medical alone we have managed so far to
be able to take ourselves off of
prescription drugs and get to some way
of having a life I along with my husband
meet Big Mike and another couple jesse
and mary opened the other spot a year
and three months ago for a place that
not only ommp card holders could partake
in their medicine but also get the
information that they need such as
attorneys current dispensaries
information provided by medical clinics
such as THC F which is now empower them
we provided birthdays anniversaries
karaoke boomers comedy shows we
unfortunately also provided that we have
in this community built on injury and
sickness we have also provided
celebration of life's i want to say i
miss you okay ray John Craig dr. Leveque
um some of the pictures are here all
those gentlemen gave a lot to this
community and people need to recognize
that gatherings for fellow patients also
we were much more than a place to go we
are placed they became family my husband
my son and my daughter are all also
patients and since the cannabinoids were
added to the Oregon Clean Air Act we
have had to close the other spot January
first
because we couldn't afford the five
hundred dollars a day fine nor did we
want to break the law please I also beg
of you please remove the cannabinoids
from the Clean Air Act it's not fair to
any of us you will also have patients
breaking another law that this fine
state has established and that's smoking
in public view if you don't have places
for these people to go they'll go to
your parks please please support things
coming up such as ham stock our festival
that we have here in September 24th and
25th down at waterfront in Portland
Oregon please support these social clubs
by PGN in Kaiser Northwest cannabis club
in Portland please don't think that one
day the other spot will not rise again
out of the community ashes thank you and
please vote and continue to have your
voice heard always showing good stoner
ism