but having 50 plus the fisheries bring
up all around the state defense that we
were putting pressure on the legislators
have to be able to come to the table to
say how do we control this now they're
invested and now we have to deal with
that this is the next step in that level
30 grow gardens is proud to have made
that Stephanie if the create
dispensaries you're going to save access
for patients we didn't want to own it
all these one to create the availability
of it now we're really really excited
about the fact of giving these seats
away to everyone in the state of Oregon
is beyond because we feel safer if our
neighbor has more plants in their
backyard it's not competitive for me as
a producer as a reader or at a grower to
be the only guy on the block we really
want everyone to be able to have this
opportunity to experience it give it a
try and we're going to make that
experience available and we feel that as
we need a much safer world