my name is Eric Llewellyn I'm part of
the crh I also am a board member for
parents for pot I'm also a patient and
that's what I'm here fighting for is is
the patient accent of this all us as
patients we we can't always get out in
life and do the things that we need to
do without certain medicines a lot of
people rely on this medicine without it
people can't live their lives go out
raise their families heck I couldn't be
here right now if it weren't for
cannabis we all fought for the right to
have it as a medical use we all need to
continue to fight to keep it medical and
help with those that can't get out to
grow it obtained it smoke it even
smoking like my fellow partner nikki
says people into place to be able to
smoke their cannabis and if they're
taking those places from us where are we
going to be able to do it safely how are
we going to obtain our medicine to
maintain life I'm just basically saying
that we need to continue to fight don't
stop the fight because we've legalized
it for recreational that's you know one
step we try to accomplish we
accomplished but now we they need to
stick to what they said and not touch
our medical thank you all for coming out
today