hey everybody thanks for coming this
afternoon to the state capitol to rally
about our efforts to continue to improve
on the reforms brought by by ballot
measure 91 and and to help protect the
Medical Marijuana Act things are
changing very rapidly and I'm not sure
that we're all on the same page
necessarily and I'm not sure that my
information is the most current
information but people should know that
what differentiates this lightning round
round short session from previous
sessions is that the legislature has
been responsive to our concerns they've
been in touch with the Health Authority
and the Health Authority has pulled back
on some of the rules they were going to
impose on medical marijuana growers the
senate co-chair at last week's meeting
announced that instead of march first as
a date for grandfathering that it would
be May first so so you know we are
seeing progress we are seeing
improvement we are seeing you know some
good technical Corrections we all left
those of us who've been coming here for
a while I've been coming here since 1999
will remember that last session we left
the building thinking that as long as it
was a private club and didn't have
employees there could be cannabis cafes
and then when the health authority
issued rules that said that couldn't
happen we contacted legislators and
there's an amendment of 15 11 that's
being proposed to amend the indoor Clean
Air Act to allow for cannabis cafes
thanks mostly to the good work of
Harrison Connelly a former Legislative
Council has been lobbying on behalf of
the world-famous cannabis cafe in
Madeleine Martinez
I was a little surprised to hear about
this rally since or you know just
because usually there's more kind of
advance notice it gives people an
opportunity to get in touch with their
legislators and legislators from the
what's now the Joint Committee on
legalizing marijuana and I just want to
encourage you all to to do that to make
those appointments and to schedule times
and to visit with people if it's not
likely going to be able to see anybody
today but you can certainly come back
while the legislature is in session or
in between sessions is an especially
good time to catch up with legislators
and because part of the problem is you
know I thought I'd say I've been coming
here since 99 and that I've been then
you know sandy Burbank was here Laird
funk sometimes John say Joe would come
down from the mountain you know and and
me and the only person in the building
that was being paid to be here every day
that was on our team was the was the
ACLU and it was like that more or less
for a long time Madeleine and others
were here in 2005 when we passed Senate
bill was it 1805 1705 whatever number
was the bill that expanded the Medical
Marijuana Act but last session suddenly
there was an explosion of lobbyists on
our issues and they were lobbyists for
the industry for different portions of
the industry for individualized
companies and some for organization
including the Sun grown growers guild in
the Oregon cannabis Association but but
the problem is that there wasn't anybody
here for the consumers for us and so I
went and met with folks at the Portland
normal and started a legislative
committee and a Lindsay Reinhart who's
are not here right this minute is is now
the voice of consumers in this building
so if you if you have if you
is that you think are important to
consumers that you want in front of
legislators get that information get
that information to to Lindsay um yeah I
think I think that's that's mostly it I
think that that you know the important
thing is I know that people get together
and rally when they're angry and upset
and there's a sense of outrage but I
want folks to know that in the first
place the legislature is being
responsive but the thing that you can
really do the thing that you can really
do is a lot many legislators on the 91
committee have a bad view of the medical
marijuana program they've been misled
about the medical marijuana program they
believe as a matter of fact good
overwhelmingly most of the medical
cannabis is cultivated was leaving the
state when that's not true they believe
overwhelmingly that anybody can get a
card and that and that most people in
the program or scamming the system and
they're going to continue to believe
that unless and until those of us who
are honest participants in the medical
marijuana program make ourselves
available to legislators and tell them
the truth okay cuz that you know this up
again you know some of these folks
there's a guy on the panel who's friends
with a guy who has ms they believe in
the medicinal value we've won that
argument they don't think we're making
that stuff up but they are concerned
about about the abuses that have been
publicized and they are going to make
reforms to change those and including
the reforms that they made already we're
not going to get that stuff back but we
can we can move things forward if we
present honestly who the patients are
who the growers are what's really going
on so thanks again for coming and as
always I'm around I'll be available to
questions today
you tell the people who are you are my
name is Leland burger I'm a lawyer in
Portland I practice statewide for with
Oregon County business compliance
counselor LLC and I'm also chaired
legislative committee for Portland
normal which meets on the first monday
of each month at eight o'clock at the
northwest cannabis cafe at thirteenth
and Powell in in Portland thanks so much