I had a friend of mine it's awesome
sufficient and for me for real and she
her doctor told her that if he continued
to use medical marijuana he wasn't going
to be able to give her her prescription
painkillers so she's gonna have to make
a choice and she asked me this is before
the merger 91 past she asked me she said
well measure 91 help in my situation if
it passes and I said no he won't give me
it'll help in the long run but it won't
help in the short run because he won't
change a thing for part of your concern
and when I left she had a cheered I mean
he's not a judge right she had children
on her cheek gonna laugh I mean it was
just really tragic so these are the kind
of thing to keep me going you know as an
activist it's been almost 20 years that
Jon Jon's got me started his fault but
almost 20 years ago and i miss Yun all
the way in for many reasons one thing
was I would ask John when was that and
he would tell me the date and how many
years ago was I mean he was up on
numbers and you know I don't remember it
anyway the organ legislature my opinion
has been a horrible job of implementing
the Oregon Medical Marijuana Program
since the any sense it began started out
by having an a credible director and
then didn't give her the facility what
you needed to do the job and then fired
if you wasn't doing the job and that was
just the beginning they stolen money
from the patients supposedly it was X
amount of dollars / how many patients
and babas to work out well the state is
making money on and the Morrigan medical
marijuana program and want some more
including a two hundred fifty dollar fee
for each drawer I mean come on this is
ridiculous we've got to fight so anyway
I got to get out of here so I appreciate
you coming I really appreciate everybody
to show it up we've got to do more of
this because
got to see the numbers it makes a
difference it's just like cart support
it makes a difference thanks a lot