I'm Scott hogland this is planet hemp I
sitting in a Mot and the Bible there on
the Shelf so I had a Satur to pick it up
and read a
verse well according to Genesis 1 verse
29 God gave every man every bearing a
seed which is on the earth plan I have
which Bears a seed Ed me up in a jail
and they took my herb away and threw me
in a
cage that makes me ask a question who
are throughout this program you will
learn how one of the world's oldest
cultivated crops can play a major role
in dealing with some of today's
environmental struggles as well as
increasing the wealth economy and
wellbeing of its
[Music]
population together and tell them this
[ __ ] ain't right learn first and then
[Music]
decide allow me to introduce Dr Tom
Maloney hemp goes back a long ways for
being used by
man Dr Maloney is the head of the wood
materials and engineering department at
the Washington State University it is in
his Laboratories that he and his
associates test building products
manufactured from
hemp next I'd like you to meet Ken
fredman president of American hemp
mertile in Seattle Washington Ken
Imports and sells goods made from him
including paper fabric food even
furniture and this is Paul Stanford
president of tree-free Eco paper in
Portland Oregon Paul sells the many
paper products that can be made from him
from envelopes to letterhead to
corrugated boxes to computer paper well
our papers made from non-wood fiber
primarily hemp but first let's clear the
air of a few misconceptions hemp and
marijuana are often referred to as the
same substance but this is untrue
hemp is a plant that grows um over most
of the world it's Latin name is Cannabis
sativa it is the same plant that the
marijuana comes from but it's grown
differently and they hybrid it so it's
very low in THC if you were to think of
an apple tree hemp would be the tree
itself the bark The Roots the stems the
leaves the whole tree marijuana would
then be the fruit of the tree or the
Apple
hemp is a crop that grows annually it
grows relatively rapidly uh depending on
location and Pacific Northwest from what
I understand is a good location for
growing the hemp plant you can get a lot
of material growing annually you can
grow it on uh land that might not be
good for Forest uh perhaps the biggest
hurdle tripping the hemp industry is the
mistaken idea that when when hemp is
grown marijuana is always
produced what a lot of people get
confused about what is hemp and what's
marijuana and I think another parts of
your program you're discussing that but
they're quite different I always tell
people I say well what is hemp I said
well just think about hemp rope that's
the hemp that you're really familiar
with marijuana is only grown on female
plants if male plants are grown only
industry usable material is
[Music]
produced besides growing only male
plants science has created a genetic
hybrid that produces no marijuana
whatsoever or non-industrial hemp would
be illegal marijuana the things that's
being grown in people's basements are
imported from Thailand um Industrial
Hemp is a different hybrid it's grown
differently it's grown for the stock all
the fibers come from the stock so they
grow it close together they don't grow
it for the leaves or the buds
it's the same plant but uh the plant
that produces the best and most fiber uh
doesn't produce the psychoactive
substance in any quantities that uh are
useful for drug production they've been
doing it for uh Generations in Western
Europe and for centuries in Eastern
Europe uh in fact in the United States
we had Industrial Hemp until 1937 and
scientists have dated hemp use back
12,000 years it is known to be one of
the first four cultivated
crops 12,000 years ago hemp was one of
the first crops that was purposely
cultivated by human beings in the first
agricultural settlements that uh sprung
up in uh uh the tiger Euphrates valleys
and in the Yellow River
Valley sailing ships used hemp to make
the sail cloth and hemp's been used and
making paper for centuries and
centuries this one plant was used to
make the paper that Bibles and even the
Declaration of Independence were printed
on hemp has been woven into garments
throughout history and across the world
Not only was the very first American
flag swn by Betsy Ross made from hemp
but so were the clothes and supplies of
the many soldiers that fought to keep
her
waving was illegal not to grow hemp and
some of the British colonies because
they needed it for their Sals and their
ropes and they needed enough of a
production to satisfy the
Navy but more recently in the 1940s when
the United States was at war in the
Pacific and many of our supplies were
cut off the United States government
produced a video called hemp for victory
this video was to encourage Farmers to
grow hemp for the war effort American
hemp must meet the needs of our Army and
Navy as well as of our Industries in
1942 patriotic farmers at the
government's request planted 36,000
Acres of seed hemp an increase of
several th% the goal for 1943 is 50,000
Acres of seed
hemp today when grown for paper
production it would take four acres of
trees to make the same amount of usable
pulp material as one acre of hemp well
hemp is the longest and strongest plant
fiber so it can make a stronger paper
than uh wood fiber wood fiber's maximum
length is about 7 to 8 mm where hemp
fiber can be up to 3 m long or hundreds
of times
longer that same one acre of hemp can be
harvested three times a year for hemp
only has a 120-day growing
season tree-free paper can be made with
um any combination of hemp pulp from 10%
to 90% to 100% the paperwork currently
producing is 90% hemp 10%
cotton and it's um got the obvious
advantages over a wood pulp because you
don't need to cut trees to make nice
paper it's also stronger than W pulp it
can be recycled more times according to
USDA bulletin 404 a waste product from
making canvas rope lace and linen that
waste product makes more than four times
more paper than trees according to a
Dutch study that was published in last
July of 93's Pulp and Paper magazine the
the total production from hemp both the
bass fiber which can be made into both
paper and textiles plus the herd fiber
those fibers together produce more than
eight times more paper than the most
productive tree
species another advantage to hemp paper
over tree paper is that no harmful acids
are used in the bleaching process it can
be bleached with hydrogen peroxide um to
avoid the chlorine problems from uh
paper industry
so it is an ideal product for paper it's
an annual plant it uh yields a lot of
Pulp and you can make paper with the
byproducts of the uh textile industry so
you can use all the plant and and make
each of them cheaper the pl all the
plant
yeah hemp is composed of very long
fibers up to 15 ft in length and
depending on how the hemp is grown these
fibers can be woven into fabric fabric
as soft as women's lingerie or as rough
as
burlap uh again as you know hemp fiber
can be used uh in the United States and
is being used and cloth products uh the
Chinese are doing a better job right now
on the lighter weight Fabrics um they
are spinning finer threads that the
hungarians will are able to do and will
start doing in bigger quantities
immediately there are um probably
hundreds of products you could do from
him the ones we're currently doing are
fabrics and almost everything you make
from fabric uh clothing bags
wallets uh hats things like that are all
being made currently futons it's a good
uh upholster
fabric fabric made from hemp is three
times stronger than cotton is more water
absorbent than cotton and is warmer than
cotton um it's a good alternative to
Cotton because it's grown without
pesticides it um stops soil erosion it's
uh pest resistant it's drought resistant
uh Cotton's a very
uh cotton has a lot of impact on the
environment it's grown with a lot of
pesticides there's some soil degreg
problems there's erosion problems
there's the the problems of harvesting
and things like that uh hemp is very
easy to grow um it's naturally resistant
to Pest and it's naturally resistant to
droughts and so you can grow it without
putting new chemicals into the
environment visual if you can a house
made entirely of hemp start with the
foundation the concrete in France they
have perfected a technique where you mix
hemp herd with lime that substance then
mineralizes into a material that is
stronger lighter and more durable than
concrete as one of the numerous products
where the hemp material could go would
be into this product line either as on
top of our foundation lie the building
materials made from trees hemp has the
potential to replace these
products long fiber is very intriguing
to many people because you can take that
and make in the long structural pieces
using that fiber because you got the
fiber length and the hemp fiber is very
strong and so well right now the demand
exceeds the supply and because of that
that's driven the price up in the long
term though when uh there aren't the
artificial barriers to the market that
exist today hemp fiber will be less
expensive within the walls of our house
we need Plumbing hemp can be made into a
biodegradable substitute for plastic
Plumbing
pipes and here's a sample of a a hemp
board uh there's some others here too I
I'm hold holding up one as uh it
something like what I just showed not
quite the same because some of this has
to be worked out yet exactly how to work
with these materials some of the
Machinery isn't quite right but that's
because we've been using wood machinery
and not hemp
Machinery now this board is not as good
as this one over here uh this is again
you probably can't see it on the camera
but it's it has a nicer surface uh it
looks better and I know the numbers
aren't on the back here but I do know
it's much stronger in this in fact it's
much stronger than the the traditional
MDF or Med best fiber board I just
showed you in a house fire people are
often killed by the gases from their
carpet as it burns hemp carpet releases
no poisonous
fumes this could be uh around doors
windows what have you where we use high
quality Lumber in the past which we
really don't have much of anymore no
matter what anybody says as long as this
is painted you would never know the
difference between this being a nice
Mill piece of Douglas for Oak what have
you if you want to have a wood grain you
can print it on overlay it and what have
you a lot of this is done already so
it's moving into a lot of the
traditional uses that where we used to
have Lumber oil from the hemp seed can
even be used to make paints and
varnishes it works in there it has
worked elsewhere it's been used some in
this country in the past but there is
the possibility of making this kind of
product with the fiber as well there's
all kinds of mixtures too you could use
a good long hemp fiber on the surfaces
and some poor fiber or particle in the
middle because it's for bending purposes
and the fiber gives you the bending
property so there's all kinds of
opportunities it's going to boil down to
economics like all of these things how
much does it cost to do it how much does
it cost to grow the material Harvest it
process it um and supply and demands in
there too if you don't have the wood
material if you want to keep making
these kind of products you use something
else all of us want it to happen as soon
as possible we could for the American
farmers and be good for the environment
be good for the consumer we get cheaper
hemp products here um very
quickly the same process by which we
make ethanol fuel from corn can be used
to convert hemp into a usable
gas for our cars and to heat our houses
there's a process which you can make uh
the same way you make ethanol from corn
you can make it out of hemp uh very
economically I think you can also make a
hemp seed oil can be used as a fuel
probably this would mean less dependency
on any foreign oils and would reduce the
price of gasoline in this
country but what about food hemp seeds
contain all the necessary and essential
fatty acids amino acids and protein
necessary for human life you can use it
as a cooking additive you can use the
hemp seeds themselves in cooking uh you
can cook in the oil it's it's very and
such a variety of foods can be made with
the hemp seed anything from hemp ice
cream to hemp peanut butter all of which
Aid in increasing the body's immune
system and actually remove
life-threatening plaque from Our
arteries it's very high in the essential
fatty acids uh high in protein low in
the bad kind of cholesterol high in the
good kind of cholesterol it's a it's
like flax seed oil as far as all the
health benefits just as it has done in
the past the potential is there for hemp
food to play a key role in ending our
world's hunger
problem probably everything can cure
world hunger if you do it right um it
could be part of the solution certainly
and it's it's a plant that you can grow
and and and be good for the environment
at the same time feed people it's high
protein um it would contribute to the
solution so what climate conditions are
good for growing hemp well hemp is
indigenous to central Asian region area
kazakistan
uh Pakistan the Tibetan region of China
and Kashmir region of
India hemp is like a weed it can grow
virtually anywhere in us any soil well
there are two main sources of hemp in
the US market right now uh Hungarian
hemp and Chinese hemp well it's grown in
Holland it was made legal to grow in
England I believe in June of this year
and there's some hemp farms in Canada at
the present time hemp can be planted in
areas that have been deforested or
Fallen victim to a fire you can grow it
on uh land that might not be good for
Forest uh stand so somewhere some parts
here in Eastern Washington where it's
not particularly great for growing
anything H hemp crop would grow well its
long roots anchor the soil in place to
prevent erosion and its nutrient-rich
foliage mixes with the soil to actually
increase the fertility for the coming
years this is why hemp is also a good
rotation crop for
Farmers judging from the exceptions our
products have gotten I'm pretty sure the
general public would not have any
objection or very little objection to
Industrial H being grown here the
politicians don't realize that nobody
even wants to talk about it yet um but
with the environmental issues becoming
more crucial with the American farmers
needing new crops with the paper
industry needing new pulp it should
happen very quickly the idea behind the
hemp movement is not to eliminate jobs
or eliminate Industries it is to create
more jobs and new Industries to
integrate hemp knowledge and hemp
products into today's society The
Logical way to use this to start with is
as a supplement to present wood material
in an operating medium NY fiber board
plan like I showed here or particle
board uh which is a little coarser
particle as a a supplement to that raw
material and uh so people become
familiar with the processing uh of the
material and it gets uh used properly on
the board and then eventually with
success you could move on to a uh a
manufacturing plant that would use the
hemp material
exclusively um I'm not optimistic it
might be 5 or 10 years before they allow
it and what we're trying to do is put
the hemp products under the nose of the
American consumers so they can see it's
a good product um and not be afraid of
it and start uh accepting it and
accepting the idea of growing it
here support your local hemp industry
Buy products see for yourself test them
against products that you use now which
do you like better then make a
choice it would appear that it has lots
of benefits and a lot of good things
that you can do with it and the secret
is economics like I said before and
developing a way uh to take it out of
the political and emotional scene so
that there's there's not a concern that
this you're growing a drug material
rather than ability
material but um it's just a question on
how much political resistance there's
going to be uh it could happen within
one year of them of the United States
government allowing it it might happen
sooner um under a permit
plan and I I think what's going to
happen is that cannabis will be taxed
and regulated and that hemp fiber and
Seed will be grown uh without regulation
and uh then 10 years will become a major
source of fiber for uh paper
making I'm Scott hogland this is planet
hemp think about it