well and whatever's going on in this
dimensional
reality will never outfight them it's
about outthinking
them it's about outthinking
them just think about that right about
out thinking
that Alternative Energy power power
Alternative Energy conscious life
thought the process of thinking
energy we are the alternative energy
that can make the change to happen but
we really have to understand what this
means we really have to get it and
understand it then we become that
power the power of the people got have
[ __ ] to do with the vote or any other
thing it's got to do with thinking with
a clear coherent intelligent mind use
the intelligence clearly in coherent how
much power do we have can if you can you
make yourself feel miserable with your
fears and your doubts and your
insecurities if you can do that you have
power simply put all right so it's just
a matter but that's power used
incoherently and chaotically so just
think some mental shifts here and use
that power clearly and coherently and
real change
this is the power of the
people like this cannabis Tax Act you
vote but you you the Voting is like
using it as a tool you know you just use
it as a tool but your power isn't
there the power isn't here