from from my experience
in the legislation i have found that we
really don't have anybody in the house
of representatives
who is there to back the wants and the
needs
of regardless of what your part of
cannabis is whether you're
industrial hemp medicinal marijuana
choice to use or sacrament i believe in
them
all they all have a place and they
should all come together
and we need to change what this
state for sure needs and to do that we
have to be here and we have to be on the
inside to do that right now
if we want all these changes we talk
about here at this festival
we need to get out there and vote and
you know get that ballot in the mail and
make you
make sure you register i want everybody
to be able to enjoy
what i've been able to enjoy for almost
40 years now
and that's cannabis in whatever form you
choose to uh believe in it in
um i'm also a
pre-transplant patient with host hsu
and so i'm kind of under their thumb of
being held out of the system
because i can't use it when i know that
it worked before
for me before i was evaluated and put on
the list so i've been on both sides of
the fence
i've used it medicinally to take care of
my needs
i know it works my life is basically on
the line
if i use and they find it in my system
then they'll take me off the list they
might as well shoot me right then and
there
and this is a type of bias that we don't
need
in our world much less our state much
less
this district everybody should be able
to do what they want
and long before that i was a farmer
and it's time that farmers are no longer
slave labor they need to be
paid for what they do and paid
righteously so
and our new transitional healthcare
bring
cannabis into it from a positive
section to where the oha
starts protecting any of the clinics
any of the growers any of the patients
from outside intervention if you don't
like what people are doing
and don't want to give them the best
health care they can
then you really don't give a if
they live or die
and those type of people don't belong
in any sort of political politic
uh position or uh office
uh i'm running for state office because
i think we gotta
really clean up what we got going here
and hopefully those changes just like
our model law did
years ago and those type of things drip
downward and outward just like it will
as more and more states come online
with whatever form of legalization they
choose to do