20 states that passed pro industrial
chemical legislation and more telling
ten states including or you have passed
legislation that remove barriers to its
production
let me read them California Colorado
Kentucky Maine Montana North Dakota
Oregon Vermont Washington and West
Virginia pretty wide range of states all
across the country now as I think most
of you know hemp products are perfectly
legal
today there is a retail market and no
products we think is about half a
billion dollars now I frankly think
that's understated we've watched the
estimate since I've been working on this
the estimates kind of go up about the
range of the market and I will tell you
that I'm convinced if we're able to move
forward with actual hemp cultivation in
Oregon and other states I think that
market is going to expand them there'll
be more competition for it and it can be
grown locally not imported from Europe
or Canada or come checked out or
someplace so it's the supply line is
shorter and the competition is greater
so I think that means that it's going to
have overall an opportunity to make hemp
products even more competitive than they
are now
additionally it's going to I think the
attention that is going to be directed
as a result of what's going on in Oregon
and other states we're going to watch
the expansion so I think there will be
more attention more involvement and I
think
to see even more commercial applications
so from my point of view it's gone from
less than a third of a billion to 1/2
billion and I think it's going to expand
dramatically you see some of the
products out there this is a hemp flag
journal Pulis and I arranged for it to
be flown over the United States Capitol
on July 4th now it's important to clear
up the misconceptions industrial yeah
I'll let you repeat after me
industrial him is not marijuana you want
to practice that in other groups it's
it's really frustrated there's less than
three tenths of a percent of THC it's
not a drug now we can argue about
outdated drug laws anyway I mean is
marijuana really worse than heroin and
meth but that's a debate for another day
we don't need to get into it I don't
want to get into it I want to focus on
him regardless of your view about other
drug laws this is Nigel and we need to
come together to help people understand
that and what the opportunities are I've
been listening to people who've been
cornering me for decades some of you
have been stalking me
but but the point has been rotated and
so we've been working as part of a whole
range of issues in Congress to get this
thing off the table get it passed get it
accepted now part of what's interesting
for me is that the controversy
surrounding marijuana is going to help
us sweep through some of the
misconceptions as you know 21 states in
the District of Columbia have legalized
medical marijuana over 110 million
people live in states that have medical
marijuana where it's illegal and this
fall to states Washington and Colorado
voted to legalize adult recreational use
of marijuana what happened is it set up
this is set up an interesting conflict
with federal law
again not debating the merits one way or
another destination but President Obama
famously said when when challenged is
the Department of Justice going to be
prosecuting Colorado officials for doing
what they're required to do in the state
constitution which over 55% of the
people told him to do and the president
said then he had bigger fish to fry and
that's true
and so we had this statement from the
administration which was logical and a
way to avoid an unfortunate conflict
between the state and federal
authorities we do have bigger fish to
fry the problem was that there were 83
independent US attorneys who were frying
those smaller fish so we sought and
obtained clarification from the
Department of Justice that they would
not essentially be prosecuting people
who are operating under the color of
state law and set up some conditions
whereby that would be respected well
this helps us even more because if you
can have a regimen in these states for
medical or recreational marijuana is
legal and you can do this to the
satisfaction of the Department of
Justice it would be a no-brainer to set
up a system where by him meets that
criteria and would not be prosecuted
it's it's very for me exciting to have
that guidance from the US attorney
laying out the priorities but even more
important for us and worrying the US
attorney Amanda Marshall has stated that
her position will be to rely on state
and local authorities to address
localized activities
and in a recent letter we make copies I
think from US attorney Marshall the
department expects that states which
legalized cultivation or use of cannabis
whether for industrial purposes medical
purposes or otherwise will establish
them for strict regulatory schemes that
protect the eight federal interests that
are identified they will take a trust
but verify approach and as long as the
state follows suit imposing those
controls it's not likely that they will
be there will be any threatens federal
act and federal action unless necessary
look at the actual language but the
point is if that's the case for
marijuana it certainly it informs the
guidance for him so it ought to be
easier more direct and virtually no
reason that there would be any
involvement and it's important for us to
give clarification to the men and women
who may decide to be involved that
they're not going to be interfered with
and I hope that it gives the assurance
to the state the state's been
extraordinarily I think forthcoming on
this with the Department of Agriculture
the state legislature
so we're amazing well-positioned well
actually have an opportunity here from a
representative from the State Department
today now you may have noticed the last
few months have not necessarily been the
shining moments for the United States
Commerce there have been some
controversies some dysfunction but for
me one of the highlights in a really
miserable period was watching in this
Congress the moments of bipartisanship
around the issue during the farm bill
debate together with a colleague from
Colorado here and published and one from
Kentucky Thomas Massie a Republican from
Kentucky who has agreed to be our lead
with the legislation in Congress we
could offer what we thought was shut the
simple common-sense Amendment that's
always a danger sign in Congress because
those are the first to lose that would
allow colleges and universities to grow
and cultivate him for academic and
agricultural research purposes
passed with bipartisan support
I think it's 225 votes and that
provision is still on the table for the
farm bill discussion we have now and
we're working for the conference
committee is and some of the stuff it's
going to be in the bill makes me cringe
I don't know that I'm going to be able
to vote for it but I think we're going
to be able to keep this provision and be
able to do something else that's very
important it's not just to give a clear
signal to Oregon Agriculture that it is
appropriate for them to go forward if
they cultivate it as they see fit it's
important to help them call me and for
us to be able to do the research that
OSU is capable of doing they do amazing
things there to help other Oregon
industries from the cheesemakers people
who root beer wine small fruits and
vegetables their forestry and they there
are not just American experts they're
global experts at OSU tremendously
powerful research capacity
people to research on him in terms of
how to grow it and product applications
that is a part of establishing a new
element for Horrigan industry we have
we're about to hear from an all-star
panel I think I've stalled long enough I
think we've got everybody here is going
to be here
although thank you cable access when
you're on your exercise machine and 2:00
in the morning and just know might know
what to do and you're tired of watching
speeches on the floor of the house on
c-span or even as you'll be able to
watch this and listen from our experts
I went I did want to acknowledge how
helpful the Department of Agriculture's
kekova has been she's the director I'm
talking through with her the nature of
this federal partnership wholefoods
a leader in adapting alternative
products to retail markets and helping
them become more mainstream thank you
hearing from Rick Rutherford and or a
good farmer I just met for the first
time from doofer who's interested in
doing a deep dive and cultivating yeah
well I think the stakes are high Florida
we want to be able to strengthen our
economy particularly what happens in
rural and small town or you being able
to have one more product that they can
cultivate that has a number of
applications I think it's a step towards
helping the economy in an area that's
been battered by the recession and as we
research grow and be able to have access
to them I think it's also going to know
small entrepreneurs you people who have
ideas for new products that can be more
affordable and accessible so I think
it's going to unleash other areas of
economic activity because this is a part
of an effort that we need to do here
to support it encourage this process
being set up with the with the state of
Oregon the Department of Agriculture we
want to learn from one another and we
want to inform the public so we can lay
the foundation I would like Orion to be
a leader as we move to the point where
it is clearly going to be authorized
under federal statute and we are doing
more for research and product
development but Oregon once again is
poised to be a real leader