the National Drug control strategy
proposed by President Bush and drugar
Bennett isn't worth the environmentally
disastrous and unnecessary sulfuric acid
and dioxin laced wood pulp processed
paper which it is printed on
specifically the continued prohibition
of hemp marijuana cultivation prevents
our society from utilizing Nature's
Premier renewable resource for the
majority of Earth's paper fiber fuel
food paint and
Medicine ironically at the time of
George washhington he and All American
farmers were required to grow and could
even pay their taxes with hemp why
because hemp was the used for the
majority of colonial Americas in the
world's paper clothing towels diapers
lace sails canvas Dutch pronunciation of
cannabis rope paint varnish lighting oil
and More in fact as recently as World
War II with Philippine and Asian hemp
cut off by the Japanese the US
Department of Agriculture in 1942
produced a 14-minute black and white
film hemp for victory encouraging and
instructing patriotic American farmers
to grow 350,000 acres of hemp per year
by
1943 to be used for civilian and
Military shoes rope fire hoses even the
parachute webbing that George Bush held
on to when he bailed out over the
Pacific was made from Cannabis hemp hemp
uses the sun more efficiently than
virtually any other planet on our planet
in fact on a planet wide climate wide
and soil wide basis hemp grown annually
would produce approximately 40 times the
biomass that is living organic matter of
the next best annual rival biomass crops
that be can grown on Earth such as corn
kunu and sugar
cane today we have the ability in the
mechanized technology to use hemp
biomass and other biomasses for energy
farming and produce all of the clean
Renewable Fuel we would need for all of
our
cars homes and Industry with a net
reduction of carbon
dioxide theoretical computer models have
shown that reversing the greenhouse
effect will only be possible if possible
at all if hemp and other biomass Wast
are used again as they were until 130
years ago for making the overall
majority of Earth's paper fiber fuels
paints farnish and now everything from
plastic to Dynamite as for
marijuana the blossom of the hemp plant
US Government clinical studies as well
as studies of the Jamaican Costa Rican
and Greek marijuana using populations
indicate statistically that you will
live more than a year longer if you
smoke marijuana every day than if you
use no drugs at all and 8 to 24 years
longer than regular tobacco and alcohol
users in 1987 US Government statistics
reported 39 5,000 Americans died from
tobacco 87% of all lung cancer cases
were caused by tobacco use also the
National Institute of drug abuse that's
nighta reports 125,000 Americans died in
1987 from alcohol use that same agency
and the surgeon general's mortality
statistics report zero Zer deaths ever
due to marijuana and as of October
1988 no case of lung cancer has ever
been a tri uted solely to marijuana
use therefore we at hemp are seeking a
marijuana hemp armus that is an
immediate Nationwide moratorium on the
personal medical and Industrial
suppression of hemp and for the
president in Congress to immediately
appoint a hemp advisory commission to
oversee and expedite reintroduction of
hemp to American agriculture business
and
Medicine our justifications for this
moratorium commission are that with few
exceptions none of the American public
especially our politicians who should
have known when they made these laws the
judges who should have known when they
enforced them and the police and even
the teachers who should have taught them
and all the rest of us in the first
place knew virtually any of the
preceding
history facts information or the vast
potential of hemp as Earth's Premier
natural renewable resource biomass and
life extend
if I have to go to jail for fighting for
that or give of any other part or you
should you should be proud to I mean
such a sweet thing as marijuana to go to
jail for put there by people that don't
even know this information haven't the
foggiest idea and yet chemicals
petrochemicals fossil fuels are totally
legal and hemp one of the greatest
things that we if not the greatest
natural growing thing on earth is
illegal every damn politician out they
be should be ashamed of themselves
forever if they continue this now that
they know this or they and don't check
it out if they've heard it and they
don't believe it check it out but if
it's true you better change your ways
because if a world would accept you I
wouldn't want to live in that world and
if the world doesn't accept you you
should you should be proud of a world
that would teach you how to behave like
adults like you want kids to behave like
to be responsible to control their uses
we expect you to control the abuses of
the power of legislating stupidity
ignorance and the end of my Planet
that's all