I am a travel
writer and for me high is a
place it's a beautiful place it's a
place where my speakers sound better
it's a place where suddenly I'm a good
cook where conversations Slither around
like stray cats and then once in a while
I like to go there and a lot of people
do now there are cases when our
government can say we can't go someplace
but if they say we can't go there there
better be a good reason and as far as
I'm concerned there's no good reason for
our government to tell us we cannot go
to that beautiful place right today
80,000 Americans are in jail because
they wanted to go to that place called
high I believe that the responsible
adult recreational use of marijuana is a
civil
liberty I'm not promoting marijuana it's
a drug it's not healthy it can be abused
it can be addictive it's certainly not
for kids and if you're caught driving
Intoxicated by anything as far as I'm
concerned they should throw the book at
you but that doesn't deny the basic
principle that enjoying marijuana is a
civil
liberty now our government is waging a
war a long losing expensive demoralizing
war against marijuana based on fears and
lies Li it's demoralizing our police
force it's eroding and corroding
necessary credibility among parents and
teachers to teach their children how to
get through the threats of hard drug
abuse in their young years it's wasting
billions of dollars and it's messing up
literally hundreds of thousands of lives
800,000 Americans were arrested last
year for marijuana they're not rich
white guys they're poor people and
people of color and people who cannot go
through life with bad burden this is a
Scourge on our society and it's time
that we have a new approach now I inject
a European perspective to this and in
Europe a joint is about as exciting as a
can of beer Europe has its drug abuse
problems we have our drug abuse problems
but in Europe they measure the
effectiveness of their drug policies not
by how many people do you lock up but by
a concept called harm reduction how do
you minimize harm that this drug causes
to a society and they found that if you
take the crime out of the equation take
the violence take the money out of the
equation then it becomes a health
concern and an education challenge my
friends in Europe constantly remind me
that a society has to make a choice
tolerate alternative Lifestyles or build
more prisons here in the United States
we've decided to opt for the latter and
my friends in Europe always follow up
that comment by reminding me that we
here in the United States lock up more
people than anybody else in the world
[ __ ] we lock up eight times as many
people per capita as the Europeans do
either we are inherently more criminal
or there's something messed up about our
lives now our drug policy is based on
fear and
misinformation for how long has our
government been spending money on Reaper
Madness propaganda consequently there's
a whole bunch of people that are really
afraid there's a lot of people that
think there's a whole reservoir of
people that just they could wish they
could ruin their lives if only it was
legal well in Europe they've learned
that there is not that reservoir of
people that would use marijuana if only
it was legal in Portugal they
decriminalized the consumption of all
drugs 10 years ago they just did a
review of that policy and you know they
like it use does not go up the crime is
out it becomes a little more boring and
life goes on there's a lot of Americans
that are also afraid of this gateway
drug notion one to of marijuana and
you're on the way to heroin addiction
well Europe has learned it's not the
case in the Netherlands it's been 25
years since they arrested somebody for
spoken marijuana and what they found is
that there's not an increase in hard
drug use their drug taking population is
staying the same in numbers and it's
getting older in demographics because
people want to experiment with drugs
which is something that kids do they do
it in their 20s and then they get over
it and they get back on with other kind
of things that are exciting to them and
it's just a way of life in Europe the
only thing Gateway about marijuana is
its illegality because when it's illegal
people have to buy it from criminals in
the street who have a vested interest in
getting you hooked on something that's
more addictive and more
profitable we need to take a hard look
at our drug laws and it's so exciting to
have a celebration like this Hempfest is
a great celebration of cannabis culture
but I'll tell you if we want to legalize
this we got to mobilize we got to get
serious we got to stop preaching the the
choir and take it out to the subs where
people are afraid of this stuff we have
hardworking in uh advocacy groups I'm a
board member of normal I've been that
for 10 years these groups are fighting a
dogged and difficult campaign on each of
our behalfs they're not Charities
they're services and they're doing our
work for us and you know there's some
initiatives going on I am so proud to be
a a co-sponsor of initiative
i502 now I know that this discourages
and disappoints a lot of ideas that want
marijuana to be completely free and
legal but that's not going to pass in
the voting booth that would pass here
but it's not going to pass out there we
need something pragmatic as a first step
please learn about this this is a smart
law this is a law that has elected
officials behind it this is a law that's
not scary it deals headon with the
reasons Prop 19 failed and if we can
stay together we can pass this thing i50
to as a booth 100 yard right over there
you'll see it I'm over there later on
today we'd love to get volunteers to get
out there and get signatures we got to
get 240,000 signatures to get this thing
on the ballot and trust me once it's on
the ballot it will pass most people out
there want to know about driving
problems and they want to know about how
you going to retail and all these boring
facts this is our first step towards
legalizing marijuana it's going to
happen in Washington and then you can
tell your grandchildren you help change
those laws that's
[Applause]
exciting now we're at a Crossroads in
our society think about the 1930s when
courageous people were stepping up about
the laws against alcohol and saying you
know this law is causing more problems
then it's helping and maril LaGuardia
said back in the 30s if you got a law in
the book that you don't intend to
enforce consistently across the board
the very existence of that law erodes
respect for law enforcement in general
today got along the books that is
eroding respect for law enforcement they
got no intention of enforcing it if they
locked us all up tomorrow would be one
less interesting less creative place to
BU to call home wouldn't it oh
yeah I want you to know that I'm a
hardworking kid raising churchgoing
taxpaying citizen of the United States
and if I work all day and want to go
home and smoke a joint that's my civil
liberty
if you agree with that get with us make
a difference we've got a window with
i502 all right and then we can get
Beyond hard on drugs and soft on drugs
and as a society we can be smart on
drugs all right thank you very much
Happy travels even if you're just
staying home all right