Federal considerations we have you know
Federal considerations related to this
and you're all aware of this and the
OLCC is very aware of this marijuana
remains illegal under federal law all
right so it's a business risk right so
we just point that out to everybody
however on August 29th 2013 the US
Department of Justice issued guidance to
the states that have legalized
recreational marijuana they've issued
guidance under what is called the coal
memor
c l e so the co memorandum provides the
guidance to states that are putting
recreational marijuana into effect the
coal memorandum um doesn't have the
force of law it's merely an opinion of
the US attorney's office under the
current Administration Administration to
Administration could change that so it
doesn't have the force of law if you'd
like to look at the colle memorandum in
its original form go to marijuana.org
Federal guidance this is the main points
of the coal
memorandum so the main points of the
coal memorandum are to one prevent the
distribution of marijuana to
minors two prevent revenue from the sale
of marijuana from going to criminal
Enterprises gangs and
cartels three prevent the diversion of
marijuana from where it is legal under
state law to other states so we don't
want it Go in out of state no interstate
commerce four prevent State authorized
activity from being used as a cover for
illegal activity we don't want to be
growing things in the recreational
market and then W all of a sudden
they're all over the country so that's
what they don't want to have
happen five prevent violence and the use
of firearms in the cultivation and
distribution of
marijuana six prevent drug driving and
other adverse Public Health consequences
associated with marijuana use
seven prevent the growing of marijuana
on public
lands and eight prevent marijuana use on
public property those see the eight kind
of principal points of what the coal
memoranda says but again go to
marijuana. org.gov to take a look at the
original by
yourself in order to meet the precepts
of those eight points from the coal
memorandum both Colorado and Washington
and the state of Oregon is now looking
at right now and in the process of
preparing a request for proposal for a
seed to sale tracking system we don't
feel that we can comply with federal law
without having a seed to sale tracking
system all
right I already said Colorado and
Washington require it and the reason
they require it is so that taxes are
properly collected and that the
inventory does not migrate from the
residential Market into a black or gray
Market so that's the reason we have um
the SE to sale tracking system it's
designed for more effective Audits and
to satisfy federal
guidelines it's also for
efficiency we can't have people going to
every recreational marijuana grow and
whatever and you know individually
counting every single plant we'd have a
fleet of Auditors we need to be able to
go through and with a oneand with RFID
tags and be able to say how many plants
are here and what's going on and are
they properly where they're supposed to
be and those kinds of things it's for
efficiency not only for us but for for
the operations and that's what they do
in in a lot of the manufacturing
Industries today