probably be
uh at least another year year and a half
before we see stores open
in washington colorado what do you think
in terms of your state to
agua well i believe that five nanograms
is a totally inappropriate
uh standard that's free and they're
driving
and for yeah driving the to the five
nanograms because
uh i don't know your cameras can get
this yeah we can get a camera to close
in on that
they're trying okay but uh five
nanograms is solid still totally
inappropriate standard because
uh at five nanograms the driver is still
five percent safer
than a totally sober driver
now okay so you can see the line uh the
lower line is the
five nanogram
level this is uh let's see this is
sober driver
and there's uh five nanograms you find
that at two and a half nanograms a
driver is thirty percent safer
than a sober driver
and at five nanograms
they're still five percent safer
than a sober driver so they should not
be punished
for being at that level that's the
detectable level and in colorado they're
attempting and they don't have it in
place yet they're attempting to
establish that the presence of five
nanograms of
thc is used as evidence of other drug
use and they're basing that on the
washington law which just kind of
plucked it out of the air
it's totally inappropriate uh alcohol
this is the level of impairment at uh we
you know 0.8 at point zero eight zero
eight at .08 blood alcohol
um there's a lot of evidence that
drivers are six to ten times more likely
to be in an accident or traffic fatality
so this is the level of impairment that
corresponds to 0.08
blood alcohol
the voters said that they wanted to
regulate marijuana like alcohol this is
the level of impairment if somebody's
impaired to this level they should not
be on the road no matter why and that
was colorado's law that was the actual
name of it regulate marijuana like
alcohol that so that was the main
central battle cry that's what voters
were calling for yeah and that's
amendment 64 in colorado that's right
and so it's an amendment to the colorado
constitution doesn't they give it a lot
of extra weight and judicial proceedings
well it means that anything that uh
departs from
regulating marijuana like alcohol as a
violation of the colorado state
constitution but i don't want to wait
until you go to
an appellate court in order for this to
be torn down it should be stopped where
it is and uh when that but it hasn't
passed in colorado's legislature yet
correct the senate uh voted it down they
said they're very concerned about
impaired drivers but they're more
concerned about punishing non-impaired
drivers