that festival drive gone I mean ass
cockpit open up [ __ ] our son there
anywhere it ain't nowhere to hear the
we're going with I birth to his miracle
machine you're the greatest drill bit
the world ever seen now you'll suck down
in the mud leave my love you was blood
and you ain't going anywhere well they
were gonna be able to come from here
there no matter what the cost there was
money everywhere so they stuff their
brains down a corporate just sold with
their empty heads together and they came
up with a proposal they were high fire
them they were kicking it on it was all
better roses until something went wrong
now with my birthday you beautiful the
team you were the greatest drilled if
the world's ever seen now you're stuck
down in the mud please money like it was
blood
anywhere public relations and vanity
devices corporation lawyers raised
depresses the bankers have insurance and
a loophole to Greece and a band with
making money kick their pockets priest
and the mayor and the council have egg
on their faces but they'll just wipe it
off and put it in from safer places with
fiber for your miracle machine you were
the greatest drill bit the world ever
seen now you'll suck one in the mud
leave my lucky the flood you ain't going
anywhere we got billion-dollar stadiums
and billion dollars teams billion dollar
feeling there's seven billion dollar
coffee beans celebrity hip hop who can
wrap it up in style shiny brass
skyscrapers here to see him for miles
but the greatest and most famous that
they all talk about is how the drill bit
got stuck in out of never getting out so
if I birthday you miracle machine you
were the greatest riddled if the world's
ever seen now he'll suck down in the mud
bleep money like it was blood
so let's seal it up and leave it for
history define as a testimonials or
disconnected state of mind or let's
stick it up and put it in the EMP as a
science fiction laughing stock for
everyone to see for the vanity insanity
of the bloated dollar bill and the
corporates you just have to keep their
copper still with my birthday you your
goal machine you were the greatest
drilled if the world's ever seen now
you'll suck out in the mud please money
like it look blood and you ain't going
anywhere history's full of some ideas
they happen all the time somebody's
disaster with someone else's part of
mine for everything that goes up most of
it come down a half wave every gold
miner to the hole in the ground and
sometimes it's right when things go
wrong so let's all get together and sing
this song with our birds are you miracle
machine you were the Raiders bill that
the world's ever seen now you'll suck
down the mud please My Luck it looks
like you ain't going where revivers are
you medical machine you were great
I've seen now you [ __ ] down in the mud
meet my lucky with blood