it's time to stop the rape
of our freedom the violation of our
personal rights our civil rights our
human rights
it's time to realize that the cannabis
movement is a peace movement the
cannabis movement is a human rights
movement
the countess human movement is a civil
rights movement
they've been laughing at us they've been
ridiculing us they've been making fun of
us
they've been denigrating us they've been
ridiculing us
they've been arresting us they've
actually killed many of us they shot
many of us
they have stolen our children from us to
be raised by
foster parents that tell our children oh
your parents are bad
your parents don't love you your parents
are criminals because they had a pot
plant
in the same house as you and they're
swilling there they're swelling their
alcohol
and they're smoking their cigarette and
you know cigarettes killed 400 000
people every year
alcohol kills 40 000 people every well
alcohol kills forty thousand people from
a toxic reaction
and from from disease how many how many
wife beatings
how many murders how many rapes how many
suicides how many car accidents
from alcohol it's how many millions of
people die from alcohol every year i
want to know
i mean it's it's a disgrace and we're
just talking about america i mean all
over the world how many people
die forty thousand people die from
tobacco in america what about the world
how many people die from tobacco right
how many people died from marijuana in
10 000 years of use
zero zilch nobody's ever died from a
toxic
reaction or an overdose of marijuana you
could eat
you know in 1988 the dea
administrative judge
francis young thank you bro i had four
hours
is this the national stereo underground
valhalla has arrived
all right you didn't know i was nervous
but i didn't think that the last band
was going to show up
um anyway this has been an incredible
disgrace to our country it's
these laws are un-american uh judge
francis
young said that marijuana is one of the
safest
non-toxic therapeutic substances in the
world
you can eat if you eat 10 raw potatoes
did you know this 10 raw potatoes could
kill you
from a toxic reaction but you could eat
10 pounds of marijuana and you'd be sick
as hell
and you'd be throwing up real bad and
you'd be unable to walk but you ain't
gonna die
you can't die from marijuana it won't
kill you man because it's an incredibly
beautiful
wonderful loving peaceful plant it's a
friendly
loving healing herb it's a herb it's not
even a drug
and they have lied and lied and lied
and lied and lied to advance these
these disgusting laws that are enemies
of justice
that are undermining a general respect
for the rule of law among millions of
young americans
that think well these laws all screwed
up so i shouldn't obey any law
and if you know i smoked pot they said
it was terrible and they were wrong so i
bet cocaine must be okay too you know
that heroin must be okay
methamphetamine must be cool too because
they lie they lie
they lied about pots they must be lying
about heroin they learn about cocaine
and uh and you know how many people die
from all that stuff man i mean right now
while we're having a great time there's
somebody hiding in their closet smoking
a crack pipe man
freaking out in the dark you know
hearing voices and [ __ ] there's somebody
smoking meth right now
right now man probably probably within
earshot of here somewhere
there's somebody shooting heroin there's
somebody's doing crack
right and the drug war actually promotes
that stuff
you know they spend more money putting
people away for cannabis
than for methamphetamine cocaine heroin
ecstasy
all combined 90 of the
money spent in america for the drug war
it's a war against cannabis uses it's
not a drug war
drug war excuse me drug war the
pharmaceutical companies are selling
billions of dollars worth of drugs
they spend five bucks on the drug and
they charge 500 bucks and it kills you
and it's addictive and it's toxic and it
ruins your liver and your kidneys and
your brain
and they call it medicine and they call
our medicine which has never killed
anybody drugs
because the drug war is one big ugly
rancid pus filled infected lie
and they used that lie to destroy the
lives of decent wonderful
chilling brothers and sisters who are
irie and who are cool
you all make cool people are in prison
getting prisoner raped by somebody man
over pot
it's a disgrace and that's why i'm
willing to risk my life
when i say risk my life i mean this is
so stressful i've just had three trips
to the doctor to the hospital thinking i
have a heart attack man from anxiety
attacks over him fest
i have developed what's called premature
atrial complex of my heart skipping a
beat stuff
because of the stress of seattle
hempfest i'm not kidding man my ears
ring every day of my life my ears ring
so
bad that i'm a buddhist actually i'm a
tibetan buddhist i can't go to the
temple anymore
to the monastery because it's silent and
my ears ring so [ __ ] loud from being
up here for 20 years
right that i can't even do that because
it drives me crazy it's a sacrifice
and all of our staff members have been
here for like 12 hours 16 hours in the
same sweaty shirt that they were
yesterday
because they get one staff shirt for a
three day hemp fest and they have been
they got blisters i have blisters on my
toes last night when i got home and i'll
be here until wednesday picking up
cigarette butts when we're out of here
we'll all be here for days after you're
all gone ninety percent of our staff
will leave after tomorrow
and then like maybe a hundred of us will
be here tearing all this down
packing it out if we don't get
everything out by wind by by tuesday
800 a day for every item left in the
park every day
it's very intimidating it's very scary
and uh and we do it anyway because it's
the right thing to do because we're
americans and we love our country i love
america i love this country
where you can have it for him fest
because of our constitution our free
speech
on our freedom of assembly and we do it
anyway man
and we never know if it's going to
happen it's a total leap of faith i'm
like my god it's three days
what's going to happen are the
volunteers going to be there on friday
we're going to have a step
well let's get this out of your way man
we'll get that totally out of your way
oh you wanted them yeah that's different
i could roll with you
i like that so anyway i'm done preaching
to y'all man i just want you to know the
reality that's my heart song
because you know we're doing it my
brother we're doing this man
it's crazy but we're gonna do it and no
matter what it takes
and uh when i sign the permit for
seattle hempfest i'm going oh my god
what am i doing
it says you will take full
responsibility for everything that
happens in seattle fest
and i sign that bugger every year
and you guys have never let me down i
love you
the greatest science in the world