this is my first time ever at Hope says
so really excited to be here thank you
so much for coming out to us cinema I
feel honored to be up here to tell my
story it is really surreal to be up here
I know it's a little cliche but if you
would have told me like a year ago or
even a couple months ago that I'd be up
here on this stage today talking all you
about marijuana I probably would have
believed you and that's because I've
only been talking about it for about
three weeks up until then I was a local
news anchor in eugene oregon and i know
that was the job i dreamed of having i
went to college for it but it was
abruptly cut short when i was forced to
take a drug test and I failed due to THC
most of you probably agree that these
sort of drug testing policies in the
workplace are ridiculous but
unfortunately even in Oregon and in
Washington in other states where it's
been legalized it's still perfectly
legal to have these sort of drug testing
policies it's a complete double standard
and we just need to keep talking about
it the fact is no one wants an unsafe
work environment we can all agree on
that but if people are allowed to use
alcohol or pharmaceuticals or tobacco or
what have you in their free time then
they should be able to use marijuana in
their free time because it's a safer
alternative
the fact is I was fight I was fired for
having an active THC in my system even
though I was one-hundred-percent sober
at work every day that i recorded to
work if i would have stuck to you know
the encourage devices of drinking or
using pharmaceuticals i would still have
my job today as a local news anchor you
and I probably see that ridiculous
double standard but a lot of people
don't understand that still and it's I
think our responsibility to point it out
so that people do understand that's the
only way we're going to ever see more
changes to policies and laws we're doing
a great job right now but there is still
a long way to go obviously when you're
familiar with cannabis and you know it's
a Saxon you keep thinking you're exposed
to it I think that it's kind of hard to
even understand how people can be so
against it or you know even understand
why we're having this argument but I
think they all comes back to a lack of
exposure if we just expose people to the
truth more about canvas then I think a
lot more people would understand and
support it I don't know maybe some of
you have even changed your views on
marijuana over the years I know I was at
Derek kid I you know was ten years old
being told all these facts about
marijuana that I just took at perfect
because I didn't know any better and I
was so young but then as I got older and
as I show exposed to marijuana and
exposed to people who use cannabis I
realized that it wasn't as scary as
everyone made it out to be but it took
that exposure and I really truly believe
there are a lot of people out there
they're just like me that if they were
exposed to it and they knew the truth
there'd be no way that they could
possibly be against it
you can be part of the change if you
just talk to your friend in this family
here if you haven't already about your
cannabis use actually just tell them
that using marijuana doesn't make you a
bad person and that seems like kind of a
fact that we all understand here but a
lot of people out there don't there's
still all these misconceptions that just
using this plant makes you a bad person
we need to keep talking about it and we
need to put an end to it if you're
thinking about coming out of the
cannabis closet I've learned a few
things so far and i just want to show
them with you number one I like I said
it's only been about three weeks and the
response has been overwhelmingly
positive almost everyone who's reached
out to me individually has not only you
know been so supportive but they thanked
me for talking about this because
there's so many people out there that
will still lose their family lose their
jobs maybe even go to jail faith and
talk about this so I think that you know
here in a state where legal if you can
talk about it please do because the
overwhelming support shows we have
strength in numbers but just need to
keep talking about it number two the
haters are still going to hate
unfortunately but it's not necessarily a
bad thing because fortunately all the
ignorant 0 comments have been
outnumbered by a ratio of about 15 to 1
and even though they're talking about it
and negatively they're still talking
about it and that leads me to number
three even though the skaters have
spoken up coming out of the cannabis
closet is totally worth it because even
when they're using their ignorant
remarks it's in the end the story is
getting everyone to talk about the facts
and if you know the facts about cannabis
the facts are in our favor therefore I
believe because of the facts
the social acceptance of cannabis use is
inevitable it's going to happen it's
just a matter of how fast it happens and
the only way it gotta happen is if we
keep talking about it so take it from me
a former local news anchor now marijuana
activist you will not regret it so just
keep talking about it thank you so much