I first came here in 1994 I believe and
I brought this board which is the first
modern hemp board that was made uh of
MDF that was made at Washington State
University's labs in 19
9992 so literally we we brought through
the first real modern uh product at the
highest level of cred credibility way
back then and Washington the state of
Washington has been involved ever since
as far as I'm
concerned now the truth though it is
like you say we still can't grow it here
but I will also say that while I was
doing this work the first
experimental uh contract was given to
the first Canadian farmer to grow hemp
there was a Proviso in the contract and
it allegedly said that they had to take
the actual raw star and make a finished
production prototype out of it the story
I'm told is that 20 guys signed up all I
know is the stocks I arranged to have
the stocks sent to our lab at Washington
State we created a board with their
stocks we sent it back to them and when
the farmer put that board in the hand of
the Canadian government representative
hemp became legal in
Canada so Washington is directly
involved Washington state in the
legalization of hemp and Canada and
supposedly that's how it
happened now I did this all because I
wanted to make a product that would show
to the whole population what hemp could
do and what we could do in the area of
building materials and to save our
forest the problem is that this takes
domestic growing this takes where we
want to put the factory right in the
middle of the field we don't have that
yet