I like I think it was G who said first
they ignore you then they laugh at you
then they fight you then you win so it
seems like we pass the laughter stage
and people are starting to take cannabis
a little more seriously that's why you
see a lot of documentaries you see a lot
of shows and like you said the slant
because they are going to fight it the
slant has kind of changed a little bit
it used to be a little way more
open-minded in the first couple years
but the last one they just had on front
line I thought was tilted a little more
toward the DEA who was clearly lying
than than toward uh an or even balanced
or even more Pro cannabis and ginger so
I think that's the challenge I say to
create the good content for that and
also I think you know even not just
National programming but uh like local
programming I used to do a show called
cannabis planet and it came on in Los
Angeles and Sacramento I tell
you I was shocked at the amount of
response that I got from people that I
wouldn't even have thought were pot
cannabis users or just people who watch
television they're like oh I'll go watch
that show so there's things like that
you can do to spread the word so put
together your own cable access show
that's my advice