thank you so much for Hempfest for
inviting me Hempfest 2014 it really
great to be here Michael crowz Executive
Director of Veterans for medical
cannabis access and I'm here for the
United States military veterans in the
house it's here for the US military
veterans in the
house and uh it's been a I I guess I
don't need to tell you all it's been a
tough road for veterans dealing with the
VA and that's of course where the
veteran gets a lot of Health Care uh
assistance and Healthcare you know
benefits uh and treatment at the at the
VA hospitals and God it stops me in my
tracks just thinking about the
horrendous outcome we've got death I
mean we' got mayhem out there as a
result of the government programs gar Ry
and I guess like I said I don't really
need to tell you all about that you get
that in the news but I want to give you
an update the last year we've worked
really hard at the national level
Veterans for medical cannabis access is
involved in you know several different
things working with the federal
government work with the VA make sure
that veterans can go into the VA and not
be harassed for using medical marijuana
outside the VA it's a simple thing to
ask we're not asking for much just not
be hassled for using medical marijuana
for State program when we go into the VA
hospital and get the rest of our
treatment and thankfully as a result of
our work uh many veterans across the
country come culminating in 2010 and uh
being reissued in 2011 we do have a VA
policy that allows veterans to use
medical marijuana in a state program and
not be harassed when they go into VA
hospital and that is really a good thing
and that we appreciate all the help from
everyone that helped us get that done uh
now we're making sure that you know
ailments that veterans suffer from you
know there ailments that everyone might
suffer from at one point or another in
their life with some bad luck or just
maybe some age uh but you know veterans
maybe suffer from these things at a
little higher rate you know
statistically post-traumatic stress
chronic pain traumatic brain injury Etc
and we're working to try to make sure
that those things are covered under
state laws you know the VA has handed
this off to the state now we're making
sure that the states pick up their end
and right here in Washington state we're
working on trying to get post-traumatic
stress added as a qualifying Condition
it's really important that we get this
done anybody out there that can help
anybody that knows A legislature anybody
that hasn't talked to their family or
friends about cannabis for veterans and
how we need to be able to have that
added into the state law do so please
help us out with that when we get that
added into the state law then you'll be
able to go to the VA and tell them that
I'm you know participating in a state
medical marijuana program I'm using
medical marijuana and you'll be able to
you know integrate that into your
treatment you can't go the other way
around just so everybody knows you got
to go to the state doctor first not the
VA doctor first I just want to make sure
everyone gets that clear so thank you so
much everybody it really does my heart
good to be out here with yall um you
know I think that a lot of people come
up here and they give you a lot of jobs
to do you know write a letter I was just
telling you tell your friends and
neighbors yeah it's all well and good
but I want you to know that just being
here just the beauty of you all being
here and enjoying yourselves and just
your existence alone you know as just
the the Cannabis people the Cannabis
tribe getting together enjoying the weed
enjoying the music and then just going
home
I think it's like miraculous to some
people in this world and I think that uh
Your Existence alone is really saying a
lot to the world and they're listening
they're listening I'm out there I'm
telling you in Uruguay they hear you
they hear you man they're they're
listening so thank you everybody