i've developed a product called hemp
shield
which i introduced last year here
this is the world's first hemp oil
containing
uh wood finish and deck sealer
it may be the best one ever ever created
it was introduced right here it's a year
old today
this is this is our new color line
which by the way uses the best tints
that that are available on the market
they're not like the normal ones they're
actually
processed on this microscopic level so
that the light rays the uv rays are
reflected off and you can see through to
the
wood and to the color
and yeah and they use it on
fancy cars and places like that
so in every way this is a revolutionary
product
it turns out that it that is better it
has more durability
and a better uv resistance than anything
else out there on the market and it
beats most of the
current uh sealers for decks by
magnitudes not 5 or 10
but but hundreds of percent
and as adam educated me last year the
reason why it does this is because of
the hemp oil the hemp oil molecule is
the smallest of all the kinds of oils
that are used in coatings so it
penetrates into the wood and it also
makes all those other oils
work
better together so we now have
probably the best deck sealer ever made
it's totally environmentally green no
vocs in our clear
it has no fumes whatsoever
so the truth of it is that because we
have called it a wood finish and a deck
sealer doesn't mean there aren't a bunch
of other uses for it i'm having my first
furniture manufacturer
come online in in the next coming weeks
we think there's a tremendous marine
application
for hemp shield