[Music]
[Applause]
how you doing
Seattle I can't imagine a better group
that I would rather have on my side so I
want to thank you so much I am from
Ohio and we've got a few good things
beginning in Ohio of course I've been
working on this for a long
time but we have a couple different
ballot initiatives going on or
attempting to go on that we're Gathering
signat
for and then we also have a medical
marijuana bill that I have personally
helped
right
um my whole life I have not been heard
when I was a little girl I couldn't
speak until I was
five I finally found my
voice you guys have given me the courage
to find my voice
[Music]
I have a laundry
list of things going on with my body but
let me first give you a little
background on
Tanya Tanya Davis does not have a
criminal
record Tanya Davis is not a drug
addict Tanya Davis has uh just found
out that I have massive calcium deposits
that are on my brain two weeks ago I was
hospitalized so the laundry list don't
even matter anymore you know I got all
past that I've learned to deal with
that
but the mass of calcium deposits on my
brain it's not like I have cancer and I
can go have
chemotherapy and they'll take it
away my calcium deposits are causing
severe brain d damage and before anyone
makes any comments no I have never done
methampetamine
um so that is not the
cause I just found out that causes
crystallization or something someone
made a smart ass remark so but I am not
about all
that what I am
about is
fighting for my right to use this
medicine I choose to eat
it I am a medical marijuana patient and
I choose to eat my
medicine okay back to the calcium
deposits on my brain it's causing severe
damage and medical marijuana may be the
only thing that can save my life or give
my part of my brain that isn't covered
in
calcium a chance to protect
itself so I truly with all my
heart if you need a
reason to stand up for what's
right use
me please use
me because I believe I can be utilized
in this movement in a positive way and
that's honestly you know when they told
me
that I was going to speak on this
wonderful main stage I was scared to
death but then I got to thinking in my
mind hell I'm just talking to a few
hundred of my own friend 200,000 of my
own friends love
you
so that got over that a little bit but
I'm still scared to death guys we love
you we love you love
[Applause]
you I
I love you
too
um marijuana might be the only thing
that'll give me a fighting
chance and I'd be damned if our federal
government is going to stop me from
making this choice because don't I
deserve to have a fighting chance at
[Music]
[Applause]
life you guys just gave me chill bumps
by the way
[Applause]
[Music]
it's the right thing to
do bottom
line and yes so what if it makes you
feel
better if you're not a patient so
[ __ ]
[Applause]
what thank you for having me in Seattle
than you for please go to uh look me up
Tanya Davis Ohio in on Facebook friend
me uh find out what's going on with me
if you want but I promise you that until
I have my very last
breath I'm going to continue to
[Music]
fight God bless you and thank you