know I want to personally thank every
one of you for coming out today and
yesterday and on
Friday because this taste of
Freedom you can't get anywhere else
right I mean this is just
amazing so I want yall to appreciate
that because I'm from
Ohio and we don't get this kind of
Freedom so this is like going into a
Time War
you
know
okay I want to put my two cents in on
something and and I'm and I'm risking my
life here I'm sure because it's such a
passionate debate and I and I don't mean
that in a bad way you guys need
to support
anything that's going to bring things
forward now what I I know the patients
aren't happy with 502
but y'all C can take out the bad stuff
it's just something else to fight about
and fight
for but if we can stop the caging
up of
everyone for making a
choice that's progress now you're going
to have the cops that are going to be
going out there and are going to be
doing their thing and make and break
breaking the law themselves by harassing
the patients and the sick that happens
everywhere but what we can do is go
after those police
officers and try to protect our
patients you know understanding and
compassion is what this movement is
about so I don't say support or don't
support I say your
conscience but don't be so hard on the
folks that either support it or don't
support it because we all have to be on
the same
side now Ohio had some very good news we
just had
a our paraphernalia laws got dropped
down to uh a
misdemeanor see in Ohio we probably got
one of the best well at least one of the
top three
uh best marijuana laws in the country
we're allowed to have up to 99 G and
it's $100
ticket but now if you have it in a
baggie or you have the papers to roll it
you're going to jail don't pass
go uh which was kind of backwards but
our legislator stepped up to the plate
and they have lowered the penalties the
same as marijuana
use or possession so I think that's
amazing
um I've been an activist for over 10
years I uh stand up
for patience and everyone alike you know
I started out and this was just about
Tanya but now it's been so much it's
about the world now you know but you
don't know that when you first go into
it
last August I found out that uh there's
nothing that our doctors can do for
me I found out I've got massive calcium
deposits on my brain all over my
brain these calcium deposits are on the
very important parts of your brain so I
get to look forward to a
stroke I get to look forward to uh heart
attacks I get to look forward to
dementia and Alzheimer's
this disease by my doctors telling me
how very sick I was it's actually pissed
me
off you know my doctor I don't care what
state I'm in that I'm living in if
that's home that's home I'm you're not
going to run me out of my home for
making a choice to try to fight for my
life if there is nothing that the
doctors can do for
me and our government has patents on
this
oh my
gosh our government has patents on Canan
aboid as
antioxidants and
neuroprotectants so don't you think that
puts me in a pretty good position
because you know what nobody's going to
take me out like a
chop I'm not a criminal I don't have a
criminal record I'm not suffering from
drug addiction and I am not suffering
from mental illness give me a fighting
chance and don't make me leave my
home I will not leave my home but I
guarantee you that they couldn't do
anything more to me than what's already
going on I'm already in a prison of my
own
body you know my doctors gave me a death
sentence and what I want to do with it
is I want to fight and as hard as I
can until I take my last breath I
deserve
that you know just because my choice of
medicine is cannabis doesn't make me a
criminal it makes me
smart you know and and so I'm not pying
into the the
lies I really need yall help
I'm a mother I'm a grandmother and I'd
really like to try to protect what brain
I've got left so I'm I'm reaching out to
the big dogs in this movement I'm
reaching out to everyone that is
participating and taking the time to
listen think about Tanya Davis when you
or think about cash
hide you know do searches on both of
us I have a Facebook account you can
email me at Tanya Davis is
hotmail.com um I'm G to be around all
day I'm staying at the Edgewater come
come talk to me if you want to talk to
me you know I'll answer any questions
you have while I'm still in town thank
you for having me in Seattle thank you
for attending remember be good to each
other we're all in this for the same
reason we're just all going get trying
to get there different ways
thank you