when you bring in the economic needs uh
of e of an economic crisis I mean
consider alcohol would have not have
been uh the prohibition against alcohol
would not have been stopped had there
not been the Great Depression because
they realized it was a stupid waste of
money I mean it's unfortunate from my
point of view because I'm just really
into the civil liberties aspect of it
that it would be an economic crisis that
legalizes marijuana but I guess I'll
take it any way we can all right now
what I want to talk about today is just
uh let's just look at my my notes here
it's not very uh
uh it's it's not very uh cohesive or or
U sort of like a pep rally thing I've
got a very cohesive little pep rally
talk I'll give them the main stage later
today but people who are sitting here
out of 100,000 people are interest who
are kind of interested in how do we
bring this to the public and I just want
to share with you my experience lately
I've got uh a lot of different angles on
this that are kind of unique first of
all I've spent a third of my adult life
hanging out with Europeans who think a
joint's about as exciting as a can of
beer it's just not a big deal over there
they look at us I just kind of think W
didn't you guys get over reap for
madness like like before the war but no
it's still alive and well in our society
I've also had uh 10 years now of being
outspoken as a you know respectable part
of the business Community as a church
leader as a as somebody that that that
has some sort of a celebrity that you
got to take care of and uh against all
conventional wisdom I've been honest
about my beliefs in this I've come out
you know I mean remember when gay people
were coming out a couple decades ago and
how courageous that was well there's I
mean there's a there's 50 people that
love pot for anyone that's here being
honest about it that in itself is is
kind of pathetic in our
society you
know I'll be honest with you when I
first came to Hemp Fest the people here
scared me you know it's a freaky world I
mean look at these guys and then I saw
it differently I mean Vivian helped me
Vivian explained this is the one time of
year when we can take this part I'm
recording you know and that's a
beautiful thing and uh it gave me great
respect for Freedom the irony is we're
more into freedom and the Constitution
and what America is all about than all
these people that think we're problems
and we've got to go over there and not
scare them that's our challenge well we
don't that's that's so clear to me
that's why I decided to wear my dorky
jacket today you know I want to put a
non-scary face on this drug policy issue
and this panel that was just up here was
saying some very wise ideas about how do
we frame this issue when We Don't Preach
to the choir but when we preach to
people out there who need to hear this
I've also had some interesting time
lately just getting to know police and
people in law enforcement and respecting
their opinion on this and I want to uh
share that too so I'm going to just kind
of weave some ideas together for the
next half hour here about that um first
of all uh um Mr Kowski had one of his
guys kind of tracking me and listening
to all my talks and so on and and
because they were worried about what we
what we were thinking and then
apparently it was threatening them and
then you got warm Stamper actually
talking some common sense and so what's
going on and I got to know this man he's
a wonderful man very caring man and he's
diametrically opposed to us he just
thinks marijuana is the root of all
equal evil why is he involved he cares
why am I involved I care we both care
let's understand what makes each other
tick um and uh you know after a little
while we had dinner and he asked me why
are you into this why are you you're a
well-off white guy in the sub you could
smoke pod for the rest of your life and
you could email all your friends they
come on over we're smoking pot and
you're never going to get in any trouble
and I thought about it you know you're
right I I why am I in this because I am
in it just like you are what what is
motivating me it's not my own well-being
I'm just tired of lies in our society
and this is one of a million Crusades
you could speak out on and this is one
Crusade that decent people are afraid to
speak
people say it's courageous marijana all
right people say it's courageous to
speak out about marijuana and just the
fact that it's courageous to speak out
on marijuana if you care about Freedom
there's reason to speak out on marijuana
I've never said smoke pot I've said it's
the civil liberty to smoke pot if you
choose to smoke pot I believe very
strongly that it is the the the
responsible adult recreational no
apologies necessary it just makes my
music more fun
recreational use of marijuana is a civil
liberty and I had this long dinner with
this police officer who was the leading
narcotics kind of guy in Seattle and he
refuted everything I said except for one
thing he said I can't argue with your
civil liberties idea it's perfectly
Common Sense perfectly common sense it's
the civil liberties thing that really I
think can resonate as a matter of
principle if you care about Freedom it
is a civil liberty to enjoy getting high
I would never say you should get high as
a matter of fact I think it's really
important to be honest about the
downside of pot I'm speaking out I get
these rich women's groups hiring me
hiring me to go to Deep South and talk
about travel and I talk about
marijuana you know I mean they're not
inclined to hire a guy to come and talk
about drug policy but I talk to him
about Europe and I bring that into it
and what I really like to do is have
credibility by shooting off all the
Torpedoes am I saying you should smoke
pot no am I saying kids should smoke pot
no of course not am I saying it's okay
to drive while you're intoxicated no you
should throw the book at them am I
saying healthy no it's not healthy it
can be addictive it can mess you up but
that doesn't mean it should be criminal
you can take the crime out of it and you
can deal with it as Europeans deal with
it in the form of pragmatic harm
reduction now now for 8 years when Bush
was president as soon as you had any
kind of a proposal that had the word
harm reduction in it it was not even
read it was just thrown away because
harm reduction is code for legalization
now we can talk about harm reduction
there's a pragmatism that turns me on
about European drug policy they've got
the same kind of challenges that we do
you know but they they do it differently
they do it with the pragmatism so our
challenge is to get out there and not be
scary find yourself in a circle where
people go wow I never dreamed you would
be talking about marijuana in this
Progressive way and then get their
attentions ban and talk to them I've
done it on TV I've done it on radio I've
done it in churches I've done it in
conservative groups I've done it with
rotary clubs and afterwards people are
thankful for you bringing a little bit
of logic and Common Sense they don't
need to agree with you but all of a
sudden they understand this is not just
a bunch of heads wanting everybody to
turn in and tune out and drop out or
something like that cuz that's what
they're thinking there's a thoughtful
reason to be waiting The Crusade that
we're
waging so I said I'm I've spent a lot of
time in Europe and uh it's fun to be in
Europe and one cool thing about being in
Europe is you see your country from a
distance and you when you step away from
your country you see the quirky things
about your Society good and bad in high
Contex and all of a sudden you realize
more who you are and where you live um I
talked to this this uh this man who
spent 30 years of his life working in
New York like a lot of Greeks do it is
retired goes back to his home country
country he gets back home and it occurs
to him he never took a nap for the whole
time he's in the United States it just
wasn't okay and then he goes back to
Greece and it's okay to relax take a nap
I spent so many years taking my tour
groups to Germany and trying to get them
to just take off their clothes and relax
in the spa and Americans just can't do
it anybody else can we are so uptight
about so many silly things my TV show
actually airs only after 10:00 in some
markets in this country because we have
500y old marble penises and 300y old
canvas breasts that we're sh the
children this is
America you go to I was just in
Frankfurt and they have a place called
Cafe fix right in the main street and
it's where all the chunkys go to get
their their heroin maintenance Clinic
advice and counseling and uh and and and
deal with their habit that's a very
Progressive in your face ugly kind of
thing they prescribe cocaine in Britain
well they they have a Progressive
approach to hard drug problems in Europe
that would put to shame our our policies
and uh this is one thing that I like to
try to introduced to Americans as a
travel writer as a travel writer I feel
like my job is kind of like the medieval
jester you know in the Middle Ages the
jester he would go out there and go
around with the people in the in the
gutters he'd come back into the castle
and he could tell the king the truth and
the King wouldn't tell him because the
king needed to know the truth the the
king actually paid the Jester's room and
board to be anointed by the jester for
him to come in and tell them the root
jokes everybody was talking about the
king out there outside of the castle
well we need to be gestures we need to
go out there and find out what the rest
of the world's do and come home and
that's a beautiful thing about travel
and that's one thing I try to do in my
travel writing there's a lot of fear in
our society right now have you noticed
it fear is being used against us there's
fear about marijuana there's fear about
terrorism there's fear about everything
I mean that was just uh one thing I
liked in my travels as go places where
you're supposed to be afraid and just
see if there's anything to that fear I
was just in Iran I was afraid to go to
Iran I almost left my big camera in
Athens because I thought they'd be
throwing stones at us as soon as they
saw an American Film on the streets of
Teran I got there and all of a sudden I
realized I've never enjoyed such a warm
welcome on the streets of any city in
the world as when I was in Iran I was in
a traffic jam stuck in a traffic g with
my driver it's a big city 10 million
people I think in teron we're going
nowhere suddenly my driver just bursts
out death to
traffic and I thought wait a minute I
thought it was death to Israel or death
to America says no right now death to
traffic you know and he said I said well
what's with that he said here in our
country whenever we're frustrated by
something that's just out of our control
we say death to that so all of a sudden
that little experience for me let me
have a more sophisticated and nuanced
understanding of what death to United
States means in a rally outside of our
Embassy now that's how travel can
overcome some fear there's also that
about all sorts of alternative
Lifestyles and when you travel you have
that joy and as a travel writer as I
mentioned I like to to bring that home
and I can give you lots of different
examples of that when I think about my
interest in marijuana it goes back also
to how casual marijuana is in many
cultures I mean of course you go around
much of Europe and and marijuana is just
it's not a big deal I'm always talking
about it like it's a big deal because in
our country you can do hard hard time
for and the Europeans think that gets
get over it I mean most Dutch people
have never smelled marijuana they don't
care about marijuana it's just something
that's that some young people do as a
stage and a few people that they're
artistic kind of you know crazies and
they enjoy marijuana all their life and
that's just fine it's not an issue the
very interesting thing when you travel
and you're interested in dir policy when
you go to Europe is you find there's a
fundamental difference in Europe time
and time again my European friends tell
me a society has to make a choice
tolerate alternative Lifestyles or build
more
prisons they always they always are
interested in tolerance they're proud of
how few people they incarcerate in the
United States we incarcerate eight times
as many people per capita as Europeans
do eight times as many people when you
go to Europe you find that they have
drug problems they lost 8,000 people to
hero one overdoses last year we lost
18,000 it's a serious problem in both
societies how do they do it they've got
400 million people we got 300 million
people they've got Progressive laws
where they've got their Cafe fix on the
Main Street to give people their heroin
and and their counseling and so on we've
got locking people up how do they manage
to lose less than half the people that
we do and they've got more people and
easier laws pragmatism harm reduction
I was in Zurich a little while ago going
to a coffee just have a coffee I went
downstairs to the bathroom the lights
are blue what's going on with that open
the door complete blue lights then I
realized oh I can't see my veins
couldn't shoot up if I wanted to very
frustrating and
uh and I thought well that's interesting
so they don't they've got a public
toilet basically and they would have all
their uh junkies down there shooting up
if they didn't have blue lights now the
junkies can't find their so they won't
shoot up in their toilet across the
street I noticed a machine that used to
sell cigarettes and it's been repainted
and retooled and now it sells government
subsidized cenes I bought them they're
like one Frank each and they're just you
know generic singes nobody shares
needles in Switzerland there's no
discussion about it there's no
moralistic sort of political party in
Switzerland that says you shouldn't be
providing people needles it's just
common sense so you got your blue lights
you got your uh heroin you got your
needles dispensed from m cigarette
machines and then down the street you
got your Cafe fix your heroin
maintenance clinic and then what happens
there is people go there for their fix
they go there for Medical Counseling
they don't have this nervousness where
they have to top up and consequently
they consume less of that drug and they
get themselves back on track they've got
a wonderful track record in Switzerland
for being more Progressive when it comes
to that problem Europe found that when
you take crime out of the equation and
you treat drug abuse as a health problem
and an education challenge you have much
more positive results they find that if
you I just learned this from the website
at the European Union they figure for
every year or they put into education
and counseling they save1 15 on police
and health costs so they their very
Wellness approach to this and one thing
they've learned as I mentioned is you
cannot legislate morality nobody's going
to say smok and pot is good nobody's
going to say prostitution is good but
you can say it is feudal to make it
illegal it's going to happen it makes
more sense to legisl it make it safe and
give people some opportunity to learn
about the problem and get over it when
you look at the European Union website
there's no talk of marijuana as an evil
thing there is when you search for
cannabis the only cannabis reference you
find is quote problem cannabis use
problem cannabis use some people use it
too much they get reliant on it and that
needs to be dealt with in Germany they
think that uh it's um boys smoke more
pot than girls in their teenage years
and they think it's because socially
boys are more nervous with girls and
they smoke a little uh marijuana in
order to be more comfortable socially so
they give them they actually have
counseling centers where they give them
flirting lessons so they can they can
flirt a little more confidently without
the help of the marijuana I don't know
if that's going to work or not but the
point is they're thinking out of the box
they're being pragmatic they're being
creative not making it a crime but
making it an education challenge here's
an example of pragmatism in Europe when
you travel in Scandinavia in June you
find drunk teenagers in flatbed trucks
just making all sorts of noise going
through all the towns what's going on
it's graduation party time all the kids
are getting drun who's paying for the
parties the parents are parents hire the
trunks hire the drivers and host the
kers parents don't want their kids to
get drunk on graduation but parents in
Scandinavia are pragmatic enough to know
that kids will get drunk on high school
graduation no matter what you say and
they would rather make sure they don't
drink and drive now that would be a real
tough sell in America we would rather
have The moralistic Stance don't drink
and then kids will drink and they will D
drive and drink and they will die as
they do every year in our society that's
the American approach to us a form of
drug abuse teenagers getting really drug
F graduation time and the European
approach is more honest it's more
credible and bottom line harm reduction
fewer people
die the um blue lights thing I was
talking about that's another good
example of that and of course marijuana
is considered a soft drug rather than a
hard drug it's hard when you talk about
drug policy in Europe to make a sweeping
statement because every country has its
own um policies and we always zero in on
the Netherlands and that's not fair
because there are some countries that
have very regressive marijuana policies
but more and more countries in Europe
are making marijuana quasi legal you
won't find it legal anywhere it's not
absolutely legal anywhere except I think
in Portugal uh where consumption is
legal but sale is not and in my
experience that's because these
countries are afraid to enter into a
trade war with the United States
the United States has huge power on
Canada and on Europe not to legalize
marijuana and my friends in Denmark tell
me we got to be a little bit careful
with marijuana because every year we
have to arrest a couple of pot smokers
in order to maintain favorite trade
status with the United States of America
that's our country that's our
country because of my research chores I
have to go to a lot of coffee shops in
Amsterdam you know and um I just love to
find these coffee shops andam and look
at them from a business and it's it's
it's just an amazing thing um they've
got The Loner bongs if you don't have
your own they've got your email you can
check your email while you're there
there's no no miners they won't sell to
people under 18 uh older clients don't
like the edgy vibe in a coffee shop so
they just park their bicycle and get a
little marijuana to go and they'll go
back to their place and enjoy it uh the
police like the existence of coffee
shops in Amsterdam because they have a
bulletin board where they can post
information about what dangerous
chemical drugs are being sold on the
streets the police really see the coffee
shops in Amsterdam as a firewall between
soft drug use and hard drug abuse and
it's very effective now we're so honed
in on that gateway drug nonsense that we
can't hardly imagine that but Europeans
know that the only reason marijuana
could ever be a gateway drug is because
of its illegality it's the only thing
Gateway about marijuana it's nonsense to
say he smoked marijuana and now he's a
serial rapist well that doesn't mean
it's a gateway drug to something any
more than he smoked marijuana and now
he's looked on heroin but what is the
Gateway aspect of marijuana is that if
it is illegal people can only get it
from criminals selling it on the streets
and those criminals have a vested
interest in getting into something more
expensive more addictive and more
profitable than marijuana and that's
anything hard in the Netherlands they
don't have that as a matter of fact it's
been 25 years in the Netherlands since
they arrested anybody for marijuana and
during that time the hard drug using
population is getting older and not
getting bigger it's aging and and sort
of withering away whereas the soft drug
enjoying population is about the same
maybe 10% more because of its quasi
legality but a very interesting aspect
of the whole discussion to me is in
America there's a lot of fear about
legalizing marijuana because a lot of
frightened people out in the sufferage
think as soon as that's legal it's just
going to be one Hempfest hell all of our
world is going to be overwhelmed by
people with weird t-shirts and funny
hair and uh my feeling is that there's
not a reservoir of people out there
wishing they could ruin their lives if
only it was legal you know in our
society anybody who wants to smoke pot
is smoking pot anybody wants to be a
freak is a freak it's just a free world
and you can live your life the way you
want to live it Europe's Europe's
experience and they've got a 25e track
record on this between 10 and 25 years
depending on the country is use does not
go up when you get more easygoing on
your laws as a matter of fact by every
count and it's frustrating to you use
statistics in Europe because everybody
or in this discussion because
everybody's got an agenda who makes
statistics you look at a conservative
statistics like our police do and you're
going to see all sorts of stuff you want
to see you look at liberal statistics
like anybody in our camp does you're
going to see the statistics you want but
across the board the statistics in the
United States and in Europe show that
Americans consume double per capita the
marijuana that Europeans do and the
Dutch consume no more than the average
in Europe the conclusion you can draw
from that quite quite um clearly is that
how hard the laws are do not impact how
many people enjoy marijuana
recreationally and that's a fundamental
it's a little bit beyond the attention
span of the average just say no bumper
sticker person is afraid of marijuana
but you got to sit people down and talk
to them a little bit and actually they
find this quite
interesting when you think about the
situation in the Netherlands you know
the King County Bar Association is a
national leader in our country for uh
thinking about the reality of marijuana
and uh and the pragmatism of not
criminalizing it and they've also been
thinking about what happens after it's
legal I went to a 2 or 3 Day seminar
Roger Goodman and a bunch of guys in
Seattle put on and people from all over
the country came there talking about
okay let's have the hypothetical
situation that marijuana is legal now
how do we regulate it that's a very
tough thing the Europeans have been
struggling with this and they haven't
figured it out in the Netherlands you've
got that gray area you can sell it all
you want but just we don't want to know
how it's wholesaled and they they don't
want big wholesalers they like little
boat Boutique producers my friends who
run coffee shops in Amsterdam have told
me they don't import marijuana much
anymore like they used to used to get
fancy strains from all over Asian
African so on now they've got the
technology to grow it locally it's safer
and easier for them to grow locally and
they get those strains that they wanted
they've got you know they got the
Cannabis Cup and that sort of thing well
that's what's with that well every
different uh Boutique grower like micro
Brews or something is going to have
their own Forte and they have a contest
in see what ISM almost all that is
locally grown uh in the Netherlands they
have got to figure out how to regulate
the marijuana because it is essentially
legal for instance and this is something
that'll allay a lot of fears in the
United States a lot of people who are
afraid of marijuana legalization don't
want Billboards advertising it I don't
think anybody would want marijuana
legalized and advertised anymore than
we'd want hard liquor advertised
everywhere you look you know how we
control that very easy to control that
as a matter of fact in the Netherlands
you st to a coffee shop and I do this as
my uh in my research to try to think
okay I'm a little bit clueless and
overwhelmed as a typical Serv be how how
how do I know what to buy I steep into a
coffee shop I don't see a menu where's
the menu and he says you've got to push
that button so I push the button and by
physically pushing the button it lights
the menu and I can read it but the point
is I have to take the initiative to get
the information it cannot come to me you
see what I mean that's just a little
legalistic find point but that's the
fascinating way that they've dealt with
that in the Netherlands that's
pragmatism that's really thinking how
can I accomplish something they're not
going to advertise it to the outside
world they're not going to have a coffee
shop next to a school they're not going
to let miners have it they're going to
limit it to a small amount all this kind
of thing it's fascinating to see how
they do that right now the mayor of
Amsterdam is proposing doubling the
legal inventory for coffee shops in
Amsterdam right now a coffee shop can
still sell literally a ton of pot over
the course of a year as long as he never
has more than half a kilo in stock
that's one pound and the problem with
that is of course you have all these
little you know we're out it's 2:00
we're out bring some more it's 10:00 in
the morning we got to another delivery
and the the mayor just doesn't like the
traffic congestion caused by all the pic
deliveries so the mayor of Anam right
now it's a big discussion is promoting
doubling the allowable inventory limit
to 1 kilo 2.2 lb and that would cut in
half the traffic congestion caused by
little pot deliveries so uh that's an
interesting issue another interesting
issue is of course Europe has gone smoke
free tobacco wise you can't smoke
tobacco indoors in most countries in
Europe you go to the great pubs of
Europe they used to be so Smoky and you
had to put up with it now they're
completely smoke free it's quite nice
and everybody are sitting outside with
blankets around them smoking smoking
their cigarettes cuz you can only smoke
outside if you're a coffee shop in
Amsterdam or anywhere in the Netherlands
and you don't have a place to sit
outside your business is at a huge
disadvantage because it's illegal to
smoke uh tobacco indoors and Europeans
like to mix their marijuana with
tobacco so uh if you have a place
outside to sit it fits your clientele if
you don't you're in trouble curiously if
if you're a coffee shop in abston you
can boot your license if you let people
smoke
tobacco but they can smoke all the
marijuana they want I had this nice
dinner with a local policeman and I
learned a lot and we need to respect and
I'm glad we do respect the law
enforcement in our city especially
during hemp test and this sort of thing
I mean one thing about policemen is
they're not they didn't make these laws
they're hired to enforce the laws they
they don't even think about the logic of
Allah law they're trained not to think
about the logic of the law but think
about enforcing the laws and you got to
be thankful there are police enforcing
laws what we need to do is not be pissed
off at the police but change the law if
it's a stupid one that is good
citizenship to Advocate changing the law
that's
not I mean it's not our good citizen if
you recognize a law that's causing more
harm than the problem it's trying to
address to talk to people educate people
and change it and that's what we're
doing here in a beautiful not very fast
process but in a beautiful process um I
think that uh what I learned from uh
from my discussion with this police
officer is the driving mission for
police along with uh enforcing the laws
is protecting children and stopping
violence all right one beautiful thing
about us here at Hempfest is it's a
mellow crowd it blows them away how
mellow we are and nobody is trying to
get kids high I as as these guys said in
the panel before let's make that very
very clear every time we talk about
legalizing marij is it's not for kids
you can debate 18 or 20 and I think
there's a lot of wisdom in 18 just cuz
you don't want to force people to do
illegal things you want to be pragmatic
about it but laay that concern from the
start right off the back because the two
the two things I always hear is you want
all the kids to get high and you want
people driving when they're high think
of the children you should treat it as
serious as Europe does you know how
Europe is much more strict on driving
wall inasia than we are and they're much
more liberal about getting intoxicated
so they're able to give people the civil
liberty but maintain order and that's
something we can do also so again cops
don't care to evaluate the law they're
hired to enforce the law most policemen
just think if there's trouble it's
because those people have been messing
around with drugs alcohol hard drugs
marijuana and they put it all in the
same ball all right so marijuana has the
problem of being in there with the
alcohol and the hard drugs in the mind
of a police officer I'm not I'm not
saying I understand this or agree with
this it's just that's the reality from
their perspective and I think it makes a
little sense um they're a little
offended by the Mar the medical
marijuana thing because they think a lot
of people just say they got chronic neck
Plaines and uh they go get their card
and they just are making a sham of the
whole thing um I think um as I mentioned
when use the word harm reduction right
away they think you're just that's just
a front for
legalization and
uh and the reality is they told me that
the reality is uh you know if you're if
you're just using it uh responsibly and
in lowkey it's pretty safe my feeling is
of course it's a racist law and it's a
classes law if you're a rich white guy
you're pretty safe if you're not wealthy
if you're not well educated if you're on
the streets and if you're a person of
color you got a real serious problem and
that in itself is reason to take a hard
look at this
law I do want to talk just for a minute
about the parallels between Prohibition
in the 1920s and 30s and prohibition
today against marijuana because there's
we can learn a lot from that and uh uh
remember there was a a lot of discussion
back in the 30s and when they finally
made alcohol legal nobody was saying
booze is good there was just a broad
recognition that the law is more costly
than the drug problem itself that's what
we're doing today we're saying that the
law is more costly than the drug problem
itself I think um uh when we look at
what's happening today historically
we're going to see there's this perfect
storm that comes together just like that
which happened back in the 1930s and 70
years later nobody would argue that
alcohol should be illegal again um I
think we need to worry about our
credibility and I think I've talked
about credibility enough but it's that
kids thing and that driving thing that
comes back and back again my experience
a lot of people are curious well how can
I talk about this uh in public and I get
introduced all over the place as that
marijuana guy or the board member of
normal or you know with the ACLU and a
lot of people cringe my staff cringes
cuz my staff is worried about you know
are we going to be in business next year
um I've got when I get underwriting for
my team TV show I've got you know
they're all wigged out about what are
you going to say about marijuana uh and
uh when I get a gig to write for a big
magazine they'll say well promise you
won't tell everybody to go to Amsterdam
and get high uh you know people are
people are business people are really
nervous about this I think the business
Community is behind the politicians and
the politicians are behind the public
and it's just an evolutionary thing
politicians are learning you Senator
Cole Wells right here all over the
country I've been talking to politicians
this is not so radical to them I mean
they don't they're realizing it's no
longer political suicide to talk smartly
about this issue it's still they've got
a lot of fish to FY and this is just Why
do I want to get involved in this one
you know but I think that we've made a
lot of progress in that way but in my
experience it's the corporate world
that's so nervous about it and there's
no ethics in the corporate world I mean
uh I mean think about um Mark you know
Mark Phelps right well when he got what
was the deal he uh he was underwritten
or he was a spokesperson
for uh kellock wasn't it and and and
stuff sandwiches yeah so Kellogg was got
rid of him as a as a spokesperson
because he's a he smokes marijuana and
then Kellogg stock like plummets
70% Subway sandwiches was was going to
get rid of them also and they saw what
happened to Kellogg's stock and they had
a meeting and they said you know this
would be costly for us to get rid of
Mark Phelps in fact maybe it's a plus to
have Mark Phelps when it comes to Subway
sandwiches and and and Google this check
this out Subway actually after kellogs
dumped Mark Phelps Michael Phelps Subway
sandwiches started an ad campaign called
eat Subway sandwiches and feeli the
buzz it's serious check it out so but
what I dra from that is corporations
have no moral Stak in they're just
reading the bottom line and if they can
realize that it's not bad for their
bottom line they care less if
everybody's high or not as long as
they're spending their money in their
court right um
every time I'm on the media talking
about this it's amazing to me how
uptight people get and when it's done
the the mic's turned off they say thank
you for speaking out across the board
I've been on every station around here
you know and they're all nervous they
can't believe I'm talking about it when
it's off they go thank you you're
speaking about it they can't everybody's
worried about their jobs it's a scary
time economically and with this
prohibition and all the lies and and all
the cowardice in our public it's scary
for people when ACLU contacted me to do
that half hour video I don't know if
you've seen it but check it out and they
did a great job it's a wonderful
wonderful half hour historical
informational documentary about the war
against marijuana I learned a lot in the
process making this show have any of you
seen the show of the ACL you did on
marijuana time per discussion it's on
YouTube yeah well everybody who cares
about this should have a little
background on the whole situation and
check it out now we have three TV
stations in our state in our City three
three local stations we were going to
buy half an hour we're going to pay them
just what you pay for a thigh Master's
ad you know and they wouldn't let us do
it they would let you advertise thy
Master but not talking about marijuana
there's so much fear in the media about
this because they think you would offend
and scare away your advertisers so this
is a challenge that we have to uh deal
with and it's been a frustrating thing
for me in my own world I have to talk
about this really upfront with all of my
TV stations all of my radio stations all
of my newspaper syndications all of my
Publishers and let know I am a
spokesperson for the legalization of
marijuana I'm not in favor of smoking
marijuana I don't think it's for kids I
don't think you should drive while
intoxicated I think the law is causing
more problems than the drug problem
itself and I think bottom line the adult
responsible recreational use of
marijuana is a civil liberty you see how
clear that
was if you can get them to listen that
WR if you can get them to listen that
long and if they got half a brain they
see you're not evil all right but if you
can't get them to listen they just think
you're going to be uh taking all their
kids into some sort of a hemp is
Nightmare all right
so and once in a blue moon and in my in
my travels you know some my my travel
business somebody calls me up and they
say I just read what you think about
marijuana and we're not going to go on
your tour we're canceling out we're
telling all our friends not to travel
with Rick ste's Europe either and all I
can think is Europe will be much more
fun without
you
now we have tough Economic Times in this
country you know really tough and um I'm
surprised there's not more people who
are Business Leaders who can't have a
little fun with honesty you know what I
mean I know so many Business Leaders who
agree with us but because of their
financial nervousness they cannot talk
about it there are
Community leaders PL leaders respected
people that understand we're not pro
drugs we're pro freedom and civil
liberties and pragmatism when it comes
to dealing with drug abuse problems I've
made a point to talk with every one of
our Congress people our Senators our
mayor our governor my pastor they know
what I think they respect me for it I've
got my little lines down you know I know
how to shoot off the Torpedoes I want
them to know what I think we all need to
do that if we did that more effectively
we would be a lot farther along and we'd
be able to have a real celebration when
we come to a gathering like this please
think of ways to do
that okay I'm going to just uh wrap it
up here I think I've done through all of
my notes pretty well I want to remind
you um there's advocacy groups out there
I mean I can't keep track of all the the
won there's a lot of policy WS that I
mean just throw me away how they
understand all these issues and the
legislative initiatives and everything
but all of us who care about this issue
and all of us that don't want to be
criminals and all of us who have friends
that can't even come here because
they'll lose their jobs or they're
worried about theirs they want to come
here all of these people need to
recognize that there are advocacy groups
waging a hard and serious battle for us
as experts they're putting up lucrative
careers to be working in this civil
liberty struggle and you can it's a fun
thing as a citizen to shop around and
choose which one turn John everybody's
got a different take on it I love the
work of normal I've been a board member
of normal for nearly 10 years now and I
don't look at these groups like normal
as Charities they are services and
they're fighting a battle for me and if
you're not a paying member of some
advocacy group you're frankly not on
board it's 20 bucks it's 20 bucks you
can put on a funny t-shirt and come down
here once a year and we're never going
to get anywhere
join an advocacy group make a political
statement tell your friends make it not
scary and bring it out to the subs this
is good citizenship thank you very
much oh yeah thank you and I love to say
how many trou even if you're just
staying home
okay thank you