it is such a righteous message to the
world that seattle hempfest is taking
place on this beautiful day and we're
peaceful we're proud and we're calling
it out loud saying and marijuana
prohibition we will never stop
responsibly protesting until the day
that everybody goes free and that the
door is open from the prisons and our
brothers and sisters come out of those
cages into the into the Sun into the air
and that the patients can be wheeled
down with their IVs on their hospital
beds and celebrate the victory all of us
together it's coming it's going to
happen the whole world you know we get
we've had media a tempest central by the
way that's our story hempfest central at
12 351 lake city way northeast after 21
years of operating grassroots to our ass
roots out of our homes completely
decentralized we realized we couldn't do
as 22nd year like that and we have
offices now in a little storefront we're
trying to pay the rent and all that
stuff and pay this bill here
we've had media visits television and
newspaper media from
BBC al Jazeera English CNN ABC NBC
Mexican Japanese French Russian media
have all shown up it's amazing yesterday
I talked to Russia today on the phone I
was on CNN television live it's
happening folks the whole world is
watching Seattle leading the way proving
or not violent we're not a threat we're
not criminals we are a beautiful mellow
spiritual artistic community of
Americans were individuals and we're not
a threat to anything except a bag of
potato chips
[Applause]
and we're not going to stop speaking our
truth to power no matter how stressful
or exhausting or intimidating it is to
throw a seattle hempfest we're going to
risk it all as long as they let us do it
and one of the Rays are going to let us
do it as if we all can clean this place
up get out of here safely nobody hurt
thank you so much you guys for 22 years
a peaceful protest it's it's it's
frankly it's just incredibly it's as
beautiful as you all are