I need all of us to gather our voices
and let Congress know as soon as
possible put your joint down step away
from your B just for a little while and
let them know that you need them to end
cannabis prohibition
today let's not wait over
800,000 of us are being arrested that is
a bunch of
[ __ ]
am I right is that
[ __ ] well I'm calling [ __ ] and I
need you to call [ __ ] I need you to
make the connection and I don't mean to
score I mean let's score with Congress
let's make them start thinking about us
we are a huge constituency out here go
to your town hall meetings in the town
you live in and let your representatives
know that you don't want to take it
anymore that prohibition is not
patriotic it is not
patriotic prohibition is a
lie it is just like I said a bunch of
[ __ ] just like you agreed with me
aren't you tired of our people being
arrested I'm tired tired tired of it
every year the numbers at eek up a
little bit higher and a little bit
higher but you know what they told me a
year ago that I could not open the World
Famous Cannabis Cafe we were world
famous in 24
hours and it's been a year and it's
still going on strong every
day we give away medicine and you could
have a cannabis Cafe in your city but
it's up to you to stand up stand with me
stand with me normal go over here to the
normal booth and join us we fight we
have Keith stro who's the founder of
normal he is Papa normal he started
before any other organization and that's
why I stand strong with normal you
ladies you need to buckle up your bras
and get on board with the normal Women's
Alliance Pauline
Sabin stood stood her ground and fought
against alcohol prohibition and we need
to do the same thing women come on join
the normal Women's Alliance
please because your children are going
to be arrested your brothers and your
sisters are going to be arrested we must
take a stand
now does everybody hear me do you hear
what I'm saying to
you are you with me do you stand with me
go out there and sign these petitions so
we can change tomorrow so we can have a
more sensible
future let's spend our money feeding
people let's spend our money housing the
homeless we don't need to fight against
Americans let's legalize Industrial Hemp
so no other Americans have to die for
foreign oil we can grow our own oil we
can feed our
people we can save this planet we're
destroying it now
now help us out vote have fight for the
end of
prohibition please I'm the chief
petitioner for sensible Oregon and I'm
telling you if you're an Oregonian go
find us sign our petition please come
down to the Cannabis Cafe if you live in
Oregon and if you live anywhere come pay
us a visit we would love to see you see
what reality altering reality is really
like every every single day we give it
away and it's always
420 I love you guys you're beautiful I
hope that you will drop some money in
the bucket help support him
fast mine Martinez from Oregon
normal good up