I'm meline
Martinez and I am the executive director
of Oregon normal I'm on the I'm on the
board of directors of normal I'm um also
the owner of the World Famous Cannabis
Cafe in uh potland
Oregon it's a pretty amazing place a bit
of a change in
reality and um I'm also the chief
petitioner for sensible Oregon which is
a statutory initiative that we are
trying
to right now just Garner a ballot title
it's a real struggle without dollars as
everybody knows is on this panel you
know every every little dollar helps and
um you know it's getting out there as uh
Rick Steves and Allison said and
actually uh going to the constituency to
the town hall meetings and presenting
yourself in a different light taking the
focus off of your attire and the ring in
your nose and all these different things
and just try to look as much like them
as possible and then it takes that Fear
Factor away from them and you know I was
really um questioning
502 and I've listened to Allison and I
think that Rick Steves and Allison
really put a dynamic presentation
together to see the logic and the
rationale although I'm a medical
marijuana patient and so I'm very
concerned about growing your own I
wanted to say that uh right up front on
502 I think it's pretty inspirational
myself I was pretty amazed at what they
had to say but anyway moving on to a
we're doing in organ sensible organ is
really exciting it removes all civil and
criminal penalties for for the uh
cultivation the transportation the use
the possession of marijuana for adults
only 21 and older it retains the duii
laws and it also retains the orgon
medical marijuana act because that's a
huge concern for patients and we
certainly don't do not want to uh stress
anyone out let's say but you know all
the inspirational initiatives that are
going on across the country are quite
amazing we actually have um the Oregon
cannabis Tax Act I was involved a couple
of Cycles before with the Oregon
cannabis tax act so I've signed the
petition myself I think that any reform
is great reform any move forward we have
to um you know it's hard to have um
conflicting or a lot of people think of
it as con uh let's say competing
initiatives but you know we all have to
come to the realization I've learned
that um reform is something that we
cannot stop and even as our law
enforcement and um the attorney generals
of this country and even um President
Obama himself have found it's not a good
idea to go up against us cuz we're a
mighty Force out here if people would
stand up and vote and and let their
voices be heard Anna Diaz here in the
audience is one of uh the ladies that
I've T I mean she gets out over a
thousand uh Communications with our
legislature here at the state at the
state level as well as at the federal
level it's amazing what you can do with
your your members money you know they
they give you the money to join your
membership and what we do is we turn
around and utilize it to inspire them
andna write a short brief uh sentence or
two and we go hey everybody signed this
today we're going to make a difference
if nothing else we are going to teach
people how to be proactive as all of you
do I'm sure and so I think that that's
the most inspirational part of normal
the National Organization for the reform
of marijuana laws you can never change
anything unless you educate the masses
and that's what we do and that's what we
have to do even at the Cannabis Cafe
we've had law enforcement walk
downstairs and sit down with my son
Rafael and myself right in our little
living room we have little I don't know
how many of you have been to the
Cannabis
Cafe it's a pretty amazing place when
you walk downstairs and you realize that
you are in another world it it it is
pretty amazing the big puffs of smoke
that Rick talked about in Amsterdam I
get to go to Amsterdam this year I'm
pretty excited about seeing the huge
differences yeah it's pretty exciting
but um I think that um we have all have
to take from this Hempfest especially
this panel all the things that you guys
are doing I really like the lake I'm not
sure I didn't get your name but the you
talked about the no issue with driving
under the inflence yeah the Supreme
Court of Massachusetts rocks yeah and
that's pretty amazing you know and I
think that when you take all the pieces
of this and then the next cycle we work
on something different in our state we
have OCTA as I said it's tax and
regulate and I think that's a great uh
you know I mean anywhere you can get it
on the books I think is inspirational we
also have a constitutional amendment
brought by uh Omi the Oregon marijuana
policy initiative uh Robert wolf and
Michael Kleinman are bringing that to us
um and I think that's exciting you know
I mean if they can get it past I think
it's a high hurdle but if you can do it
hey I'm there with you I want to get to
regulation I want to get I don't use the
Alward anymore because it totally throws
people off when you talk about
legalization at a town hall meeting
everybody kind of you know gets a little
concerned but when you say regulation I
found that that is really an a good word
to use because everybody wants
regulation we don't want kids walking
around smoking at least I don't I have
grandkids you know but I think that we
have to really not whirl with each other
and be more united in the sense of you
don't have to like them you know because
we don't like each other I mean
Republicans and Democrats the
independent you know we all we all have
issues with you know with others but
it's it's just part of what we have to
do because that's why so many other
groups get forward I mean and you know I
don't happen to be a Christian but they
they have masses there's masses of them
if you you know I was proud and lucky
and honored enough to march with the
people that came out my people for
immigration and if you have seen a
Mexican March we had the horses out in
salum they the law enforcement was out
on bikes they were like well you would
have thought that Obama was there or
even worse you know uh Saddam it was
scary I was like whoa I've never seen
anything like this it was because the
Mexicans were marching on immigration I
don't know how you feel about that but I
sure would like to get those numbers and
I try to explain to them as I do
everywhere I go that this is our war
that this is the war against people of
color and we need to stand up you know
I'm also one of the co-founders of the
normal Women's Alliance this is a huge
step ladies if you're out there and
you're just kicking back raising kids I
know it's difficult but try to give some
of your volunteer time and if you don't
have that chip away a few dollars from
your budget so that you can help make
something bigger than ourselves
uh as I said anadas right here is this
year's winner of the Pauline Savin
award I don't know if you know the
history of Pauline sa but Pauline sain
was a woman who really LED she
spearheaded the end of alcohol of
prohibition which is a huge thing and as
we all know prohibition is not patriotic
and we need to get that point across
that it Wast away at law enforcement
dollars at all of our our country's
resources
at every level with uh Corrections I'm a
retired peace officer and I'll tell you
what right now as a speaker for law
enforcement against prohibition as I
walked the halls of the woman's
Penitentiary as we used to call it back
in the day state prison pretty high
security I mean we had some really Heavy
Hitters in there but there you could
smell marijuana wafting through the
Halls as I went to count somebody was
smoking a bowl or a joint or something
in the state prison and I was kind of
pissed cuz I wasn't but my point is you
can't even keep it out of a high
security prison with constantina wire
you know big old um Mini mini1 14s at
the towers give me a break we search
people coming in we search people going
out it it's going to be there and
they're never going to stop it and
that's kind of a point that I don't
think we need to scare them with but I
think that we need need to make sure
that they understand that point they're
never going to stop us from smoking ever
they're never going to stop us from
growing so when I listen to Rick and I
listen to Allison they're not going to
stop me from growing are they going to
stop you no come on but we chip away at
that law and that's what I'm saying I
think that every chip is a good one
medical marijuana I love it it's a
beautiful thing but it's really been
hard on the people when I see women come
to me
and this is a really sore spot with me
as a mom and she can't see her children
for 4 months except supervised because
she's a medical marijuana patient how
good is that law how good is that law
and all these laws are beautiful things
but we need to realize that somebody's
going to fall through those cracks the
veterans I see who don't want to be on
300 milligrams of morphine that's a true
story and they feel their cry they want
to die they want to commit suicide so
it's important that we all be protected
because a lot of these people can have
it uh if you're if you're a veteran some
of the veteran administration people so
it's just this huge thing so each chip I
like to just let everybody know it's a
really important chip so uh be
thoughtful when you criticize other
other initiatives you don't agree with
you know because we're sometimes our own
worst enemies as Donnie knows yes yes
and so I you know I have to say hul is a
wonderful person and so are all the
other people that really have thought
let's change it you know I people were
not happy with me when I open the count
ofis Cafe and some still aren't but you
know I don't really care I mean try you
the truth hey I'm sorry if you're
offended but oh wellow you know a lot of
people are offended by the smell of pot
that comes out of my house what am I
going to do you know most people were
just jealous that's what I yeah that's
what I think to tell you the truth but
you know I to have a picture with my
Mayor Sam Adams and he's not the most
popular guy in the world I must say but
I know he's done some good for the city
I think you know you weigh the good and
the bad that's with Obama now I'm not
real happy about it but I just chipped
off $50 you know because which my other
option I think he might still be
workable but you know who knows I don't
know it's a it's a scary situation but
you have to weigh in balance with your
options I'm trying to break in with the
um League of Women Voters all you ladies
out there join the normal Women's
Alliance you can go online and you can
find out how you can stand up buckle up
your bra or not it doesn't matter but
get out there and represent yourself
soccer moms we're all something I used
to be a PTA mom yeah I used to make
cupcakes and I used to be getting high
you know I'm sorry I'm sorry if anyone's
offended but we can do all these things
and we can be all these things we just
have to present ourselves and and if
you're going to go do that there's other
people that aren't going to do that and
that's fine and we need all the people
you moms that are raising your kids we
just need a little bit of your computer
time all you got to do is do some stuff
from home we can all do that right right
I mean let's face it but you know as I
always say put the joint down step away
from your bom and get involved and if
you want to know more about sensible
Oregon you can go to sensible oregon.org
or you can talk to our campaign manager
Anna Diaz or myself and um you know I'd
love to talk about anything else you
want to know