give me an
a it's pretty good almost good enough
give me an a a e e m p p f f e e s s t t
what give yourselves a hand you're the
greatest audience in the world we're one
Community you know there's this i502
stuff going on some people are for it
some people are against it in the
community and you know what that's
healthy that's okay we're One reform
movement when we start dividing
ourselves and being angry and calling
each other names and insulting each
other because we don't degree on the
very fine points we're defeating
ourselves we're one one Union we're One
reform movement we don't always agree on
everything but this is one movement man
there's not like a bunch of reform
movements there's only one so you know
I75 or excuse me
i502 will be historic if it passes
it'll be
historic and there's some folks that are
against it you know what they've got a
right to their
opinion and they and they've got a valid
perspective too we're one movement we're
going to have the folks from both camps
up here speaking because that's what
hempest is about getting all the voices
out there showing respect to everybody
treating everybody with dignity and
equal respect regardless of what the
fine points are we all agree on the big
thing we need to change the
laws so let's be one community
one movement One reform entity