when it comes to prohibition you have
the right not to remain silent and
that's why we do sell hempfest no man
I've guns or tanks or jails or prisons
ever going to stop the march of freedom
and the song of justice because with all
the warts and all problems that we have
here nine states of america us americans
we love our freedom we love our liberty
and by golly we haven't got enough of it
yet about ten years ago we used to hear
this theme of terrorists hate us for our
freedom I'm not necessarily sure that's
true but our answer as well if they hate
us for our freedom to let's really piss
them off and give us some more let's
legalize cannabis for real and that
means repeal prohibition on the federal
level that doesn't mean highly tax it
restrict patients closed down
dispensaries that doesn't mean his tests
be discriminated at your job that's not
our original legalization last year we
had two adult lounge is here out of
public view we're children couldn't see
people then stop the people 21 and over
to go behind the fence and smoke their
pot I love your kids don't we leave on
the state but state legislature passed
2136 Senate bill 21 36
making it a class E felony I have any
place for the purpose using marijuana
which means no marijuana clubs don't
private clubs no pot parties nothing
like that that's not legalization folks
that's the state legislature that treats
cannabis like it's oxycontin every day I
walk down the street the sidewalk people
smoking cigarettes like nothing with
impunity everywhere even though four
hundred thousand people die from
directly from using cigarettes this year
in America 400,000 people directly from
their use even more for secondhand smoke
drive down the street you see people in
front of bars on the patios drinking
alcohol even though over 40,000 people
die from alcohol-related illness who
knows how many people die from
alcohol-related violence car accidents
suicides accidents but you can't smoke a
joint that sound like legalization to
you sure note to me that's why we're
going to keep doing this and then you
know I've asked probably ten times for
the media this week well I have a hemp
fest there's a pot legal I mean is it
festers really need for it any of our is
really relevant let me tell you
something first of all I ain't legal the
federal government could shut this all
down at any time but over it now over in
Germany last year in October in the
oktoberfest where r 2 million people
celebrating at the culture of beer the
beer has always been legal in germany so
when pots completely legal we're going
to keep doing mfest because this is a
big cultural celebration this is our
community our family we deserve to have
our own festival this is but of Seattle
this is Tok like this is Barbara shoot
this is THC fan this is our party and we
deserve
who are the most peaceful nonviolent
non-threatening culture on earth we are
artistic we make awesome music we make
beautiful we make wonderful movies we
have beautiful families we raised
wonderful children we are one of the
most beautiful coaches on the earth that
we've been dissed on we've been [ __ ] on
we've had our doors knocked down we have
people pull us from our naked feet on
the ground stick their foot on us Jack
footed people wearing riot gear to the
laser beat on our chest put a laser our
children chef shoot our dog in our house
kill our pets in our front yard then
take us and throw us in jails and
prisons and cages like common thieves
and criminals and murderers and rapists
and pedophiles it's still going on today
we have 50 Americans serving life in
prison for marijuana life in prison for
a herb that's never killed anyone so we
can rain on us we can come up hundreds
of thousands of dollars shorten our
donation bins we can make eighteen
twenty cents per person for the whole
weekend in our donation bins for 140
bands 120 speakers 400 vendors offer
free sure we can have all kinds of pop
organizations and magazines don't help
us know they throw an after party or
they do something to try to prop it off
and infest the weekend or you know I how
about a convention in Tacoma on the same
weekend is us busing people to and from
our event that's the kind of support
weekend well it doesn't matter because
this isn't freedom this is not
legalization doesn't matter what we have
to do if we have to sell our kidneys
we're can I have hempfest here after
year after year it can read on us our
cars can break down on the way here our
staff can kill herself 16 18 hours a day
in the in the drenching hot Sun and then
in the rain give me her all night long
freezing it doesn't matter it doesn't
matter it it's not as bad as being on
chemotherapy and on having pot is not a
bad as being in a prison cell
and losing your freedom it's not as bad
as seen the old-growth forests
destroying eat lessly we're to keep
going