Gatewood Gil brai come on up here my
brother man all the way from Kentucky to
tell you some truth this guy's been
doing this longer than him Fest has been
doing this give him some warm love thank
you very much friend hey thank you all
listen I hope you all remember that the
theme of this H Fest is this one's for
you jack this one is for Jack ha for a
lot of you young folks out there it
wasn't for Jack ha you wouldn't be here
at this infest cuz there wouldn't be him
Fest Jack ha is responsible for it I'm
going to take a couple of minutes to pay
tribute to my friend Jack ha who passed
this past several months ago here's my
tribute to him jack hair is a social and
philosophical
tsunami the ripples from whose Splash
will forever Grace the shores of human
consciousness in every freedom loving
Nation he is a grand champion of we the
people and the natural cycle in our
battle with the synthetic subversion
which threatens the very concept of the
sovereignty of each human
individual Jack's tireless efforts to
eliminate the facts about cannabis had
furnished Freedom Fighters everywhere
with the tools of knowledge with which
to resist the fascism of the corporate
State as it seeks to subject everyone to
its economic bottom
line Jack recognized that cannabis is a
dateway to existentialism which
enlightens our existence and is the
basis of our freedom of choice he also
recognized the miraculous healing powers
of this herb and many sick and dying
people have found comfort in its use
after reading his wonderful Manifesto
the emperor wears no
clothes I am one of
them Jack ha's Grand Spirit may have
left his worn out body but he has
entered into the hearts and minds of
millions of us who will will forever be
grateful to have been educated by his
commitment to the truth God bless you
jack
ha brother the message that Jack and I
have is that your younger generation are
open to perils to which he and I never
had to conceive that there is a great
move of foot to take you out of the
property of sovereign human being and
put you into the property of the man the
man the chemal pharmaceutical military
industrial transational corporate
fascist Elite son of a
[ __ ] we see the Constitution and the
Bill of Rights as impediments to the
implementation of their new world order
and global economy and they are not warm
and fuzzy about you or me or our
children or
grandchildren and they they are afraid
to give everybody in the rest of the
world due process and Constitution to
right so in order to make it one world
they're going to take ours
away and the question of him the
question of cannabis is the most Vivid
illustration of how this government has
overstepped its bounds in policing the
private behavior of citizens when they
told us we couldn't plant a hip seed in
the ground they severed us from the
natural cycle that is what they seek to
do I call it the synthetic subversion
where they want to replace all the
natural products on Earth that used to
be grown out of God's Earth and God's
seed and replace them with synthetic
products and knocked our farmer out of
the agrarian society and The Agrarian
market and made the ghost towns of our
small cities and Villages across this
country we need to ReDiscover a cast
crop one that will allow our Farmers to
go back to the land one that will allow
our Farmers to compete with the petrol
chemical pipelines you plant us 7%
agricultural land in him you would have
to import another drop of oil we can
replace the spills in the Gulf we can
replace the uh environmental catastrophe
that the petroleum pipelines have cast
upon Mother Earth and instead let our
Farmers grow hemp as a fuel crop finally
in 1991 Willie Nelson and I poured hemp
B into my Mercedes diesel and drove it
across Kentucky in my bid for governor
that's why he started his b fuel plan
listen folks you all have been handed a
a torch Jack har blessed so past away
I'm getting old up here you know we
cannot make care of this ball much
longer you have to become educated you
have to learn the truth you have to
reach out there and grab the
responsibility of maintaining your
freedom every generation must rewin its
own freedoms and those very sacrif
places right up to the very last second
I've been talking to you made on your
behalf cannot continue anymore what
really counts is your all commitment to
what sacrifices you're willing to make
in the future to maintain your freedom
and it's right there in front of you I
encourage you I encourage you to learn
the law I encourage you to learn the
political process I encourage you to
reach out there and take responsibility
your own Freedom Live Your Life Like a
Warrior God bless you all thanks for
having me out here in
Seattle