we are making the hemp ice
cream hemp ice cream this is the perfect
cure for the munchies well maybe it's
not exactly a cure it's more like the
perfect accessory to the munchies it's
more like an accessory after the fact to
the munchies it makes your Munchies way
more enjoyable I am so oh let me get one
of those sir oh yes excellent go well
done and we've got vanilla Jasmine
chocolate mocha mint
mango we have 420 flavors five flavors a
season also have there's no Dairy no soy
no rice no whe and the really amazing
thing about the hemp ice cream it does
not taste a bit like a
rope and make you strong like a rope
instead there ain't no be cups there
we've
got we started out with
him we picked strategies that would let
us continue to generate Thunder for
American agriculture without having to
hold our breath waiting for somebody to
change some
rules without whining for somebody's
sympathy
punch your own ticket pick a product
pick the possibility and develop it into
a product food fiber
fuel with food we're making hemp ice
cream we started out pressing some of
the first hemp seed oil in the United
States since
1937 I didn't realize we were going to
be Pioneers I thought there were lots of
other people already doing
this we began making ice cream because
somebody said nobody could make ice
cream out of him there may be 10,000
uses but nobody could do that so I said
wait a minute let me think about this
and by New Year's that year I had made
my first hemp ice
cream oh yes well what we are out to do
is we want to grow 500 acres under a
center pivot on Navajo or Apache
land in order to be ready for the
success we need to have five acres
growing hemp seed for seed to plant 500
Acres assuming a hundredfold increase
each year and the year before that we
need to have 5 hundreds of an acre which
would be 20t by
20t and the year before for that we need
to have 100 of that acreage which is 2T
X 2T which is one plant so that means
we're four years away from being able to
grow hemp on a scale that could have a
real impact