it's great to be here
you know
I'm a travel writer and for me I've been
thinking about this high is a place it's
a cool place
it's a place where my speakers sound
remarkably good where suddenly I'm a
good cook
we're conversations Slither around like
Stray Cats
sometimes I just want to go to that
place you know it's a cool place other
people do too yeah but right now today
there's 80 000 Americans in jail because
they wanted to go there
and our government says we cannot go
there now there are cases when our
government can say we can't go somewhere
and I'll have and I'll buy it you know
but there's got to be a good
re and I've thought long and hard about
this and there's no good reason for our
government to tell us we can't go to the
place where a lot of you are right now
I believe the responsible adult
recreational use of marijuana is a civil
liberty
can it's not healthy it can be abused it
can be addictive kids should not have
access to it if you drive Intoxicated by
anything I think they should throw the
book at you but that does not get in the
way of the basic principle that enjoying
marijuana is a civil liberty
now our government is waging a very
expensive war against this idea the war
against marijuana is based on fear and
lies it's costing us billions of dollars
it's demoralizing our police force it's
corroding and eroding The credibility of
parents and teachers when they need
credibility to teach our kids how to get
through the pitfalls of their young
years
and it's also messing up hundreds of
thousands of lives in the last year
eight hundred thousand Americans were
arrested for marijuana they've got
criminal records now these are not rich
white guys these are poor kids and these
are people of color and these are people
who cannot get through life with a bump
in the road like that it makes it very
tough
now I bring a European perspective into
this discussion and I think we can learn
from Europe because they've got drug
problems too and they've treated not as
a criminal problem but as a Health
Challenge and as an education challenge
if we can take the crime out of this
equation we're going to do everybody a
big favor my European friends tell me
that a society has to make a choice
tolerate alternative Lifestyles or build
more prisons and then they remind us
that in the United States here we're
really into prisons we lock up eight
times as many people per capita as the
Europeans do and either there's
something wrong with our laws or we're
inherently more criminal people and I
think it's the former what suits
American drug policy is fear and we've
got to overcome this fear a lot of
Americans think there's a whole
reservoir of people that would love to
ruin their lives if only marijuana was
legal the fact is if illegal has
marijuana tomorrow not many more people
would smoke pot people who enjoy pot are
already smoking it it just doesn't need
to be criminal it's been 25 years since
they arrested a person in the
Netherlands for smoking pot and it
doesn't they don't consume anymore in
fact statistically we Americans consume
double the Dutch average 10 years ago
the Portuguese decriminalized the
consumption of all drugs they just did a
review and they think it makes a lot of
sense they take the crime out of the
equation and now it becomes a health
issue an education issue and people who
want to smoke pot responsibility do and
this guy why does not fall now the
spirit thing is really getting out of
hand a lot of people think it's a
gateway drug marijuana a couple of tokes
and you're on the way to being a heroin
addict well what they found out in
Europe is the only thing Gateway about
marijuana is the fact that it's illegal
because when it's illegal people have to
buy it from people on the streets
selling stuff that's more addictive and
more profitable
hem fist is an exciting celebration of
cannabis culture but I feel a little
frustrated because I've been working 10
years to try to help all of us not be
criminals if we want to support or enjoy
marijuana we need to have a fun party
this weekend and then we need to
remember to take it into the suburbs
take it to people who are afraid take
care out of it I gotta remind you we've
got an opportunity right now to legalize
marijuana in Washington state legalize
regulate and task now there's a lot of
idealists that don't like i-502 because
it's got a lot of limits on it I'll tell
you we got to get this thing through the
electorate and there's only one way to
do that and that is to be practical and
pragmatic and recognize and acknowledge
the legitimate fears in the electorate
because to be honest you guys don't vote
like the frightened people do we need to
vote and we need to present them
something that's not so scary and that's
what I 502 does we need to work together
to make marijuana not a criminal issue
just like the prohibition of alcohol was
overthrown we can do that with marijuana
I am a hard-working kid raising Church
going tax paying citizen of the United
States of America and if I go home after
a long day working I want to smoke a
joint that is my civil liberty
foreign
happy travels even if you're just
staying home thank you