thank you very much for inviting me to
participate and I would especially like
to say I'm very pleased that Hempfest is
held every year in the 36 legislative
district which I represent in the state
senate and a year ago actually August
20th former representative Toby Nixon
Republican and libertarian and I had an
oped published in the Seattle Times in
which we commended Hempfest in its
mission statement for quote uh saying
that the public is better served when
citizens and public officials work
cooperatively in order to successfully
accomplish common goals and while I'm
about I got 99 plus% positive that
people here at this forum and throughout
hempest have common goals which I share
I'm not sure that everyone in the public
has that common goal or go goals and
what I would like to talk about briefly
is my perspective as a
legislator in terms of providing and
furthering our protections for patients
qualified patients who are using medical
marijuana or cannabis uh with the
authorization of their doctors and other
licensed medical professionals and also
the issue of legalization where do we go
from here like to just give a very short
background on what we've done here in
Washington state as we know 14 States
since the early
1970s have provided uh the opportunity
for states to enact
decriminalization statutes unfortunately
Washington state is not one of those 14
States and uh we have tried the last two
years with legislation I introduced to
have that accomplished it's not worked
and so we have to decide now what we
want to do I focus on public
policymaking and what strategy may be
the most viable to reach the common goal
that we have I'm also going to talk
about the medical marijuana issues and
starting back in 1995 when I received a
call from Joanna mcke the Irreplaceable
phenomenal Joanna mck to get involved
with medical marijuana
I started introducing legislation my
sister-in-law had died a few years
earlier of cancer and she found medical
marijuana to help her with uh the
horrible pain and suffering and nausea
that she had from chemotherapy and
radiation and then in 1998 my best
friend died while we were deliberating
legislation I'd introduced on medical
marijuana which we did not get through
so I gladly joined with the the forces
to work on getting initiative
692 approved by the voters in 1998 led
by uh Dr Rob Killian and many
organizations which did get
accomplished uh since then I've worked
to try to make sure that it works
effectively that the law works and
that's when we get into a Nexus between
legislation that goes through the
legislative process citizen activist
which is essential and thirdly raising
the visibility and understanding of the
public and the mainstream public who
don't really know the ACLU had conducted
polls that showed that there was
widespread support of that and
eventually we were able to enact some
changes to make things more readily
available for qualified patients to help
out providers and
Physicians this last session
we enacted legislation I introduced to
allow for all licensed medical providers
to provide the authorization for
qualified uh patients to be able to
utilize um cannabis or medical marijuana
but we still have a lot left to do there
and with regard to the medical use of
marijuana I've been working with
organizations
individuals uh State officials to refine
legislation that I'll be introducing
next year in 2012 when the legislature
convenes in January it will be an
Omnibus medical marijuana cannabis act
because we know that there's a lot left
to do uh we need to provide for a safe
well regulated secure and consistent
source of marijuana and something that
patients and providers can access
without threat of arrest and prosecution
our current statute only allows for an
affirmative defense which is really not
much at all and as Dominic Holden
brought out in the stranger last week I
think it was that the arrests have gone
up dramatically even in the city of
Seattle which has an
ordinance that marijuana will have the
lead least priority for arrest in the
city of Seattle so that's pretty
shocking the bill that I will be
introducing will also besides providing
for
protection against arrest and
prosecution will change the limitations
as well that designated providers may
only serve one patient at any one point
in time uh secondly it will allow for
recip reciprocity for authorized
patients visiting from any state that
has legal use of medical
marijuana uh thirdly it'll provide from
restrictions of or protections from
restrictions of parental rights without
any proof of um excuse me without any
proof of uh parents not being able to to
provide the their performance of
Parental functions adequately it will
also provide protections from negative
consequences of for work
related uh
situations offsite as long as the use of
medical marijuana is authorized and does
not have any effect on the pay on the
individual's performance of work
responsibilities uh and also also and
this is another very important part of
the legislation that we're working on
that we will create a system for
licensing and
regulation of production and dispensing
of medical marijuana for qualified
patients through the Department of
Agriculture and the Department of Health
so really it's a big step forward if we
can get through the provisions but as a
leg legislator I know that what has to
happen is we have to convince a majority
of legislators to get that accomplished
which is where many of you come in to
help persuade legislators that this is
really really important to do with
regard to the discussion of
legalization I had been convinced two
years ago that the best way to go about
getting to
that stage was to have dereg
ulation come about first as I mentioned
earlier we're not one of the 14 states
that allow for
deregulation dating back to the
1970s and it seemed like too much of a
leap for the public to accept and for
legislators too uh that we go the full
legalization route but I have since been
convinced through the incredible work of
sensible Washington which has raised the
visibility in the public
dramatically and as well as other groups
working on this issue that we should
tackle legalization it's going to be
interesting to see what happens in
California in November with their
initiative and Douglas hayed who will be
speaking and I've had many conversations
about this this is a good example of
supporting the common goals but maybe
having a different approach I think it's
very important to work on this
legislatively first uh so that we can
raise ra the profile in the public for
the more mainstream public who may not
get it otherwise but secondly I wish
that the initiative that apparently is
being um offered in
2011 would do two things one provide
regulation because although delas will
say that the legislature can provide
regulation it takes 2/3 vote of the
legislature to amend an initiative after
it's approved by the voters after 2
years it's a simple majority but the
legislature
really very very rarely amends an
initiative they don't like to do that uh
so I'd rather have regulations within
the initiative Lang language or
directions to the appropriate agencies
or the local government such as in the
case with the California initiative and
secondly I think 2012 would be a better
year with more likelihood of getting the
measure approved by the voters because
it'll be a huge voter turnout year with
a presidential election a gubernatorial
election
2011 elections are city and county ones
they're just not going to have the pull
uh to get as many voters out but again I
support the goals we need to move
forward and if a citizen initiative is
the way to do it that's fine with me and
I will work on it but I want to make
sure that we're approaching it in the
most effective way thank
you