Rick Steves grew up in Edmond's
Washington he studied at the University
of Washington where he received degrees
in Business Administration in European
history today he employs 80 people at
his Europe Through the backd Door
Headquarters where he produces over 50
guide books on European travel the most
popular travel Series in America on
public television he also has a weekly
long national public radio show and a
weekly column syndicated by the Chicago
Tribune Rick is also a great advocate
for marijuana speaking around the state
and Country he is on the normal Advisory
Board Rick Steves lives and work in
Works in his hometown of edins
Washington he one of ours Give It Up to
Rick Steves give a warm
welcome thank you it's great to be here
andest yeah well I'm a travel writer and
for me high is a
place it's a great place it's a place
where I can cook well my speakers sound
better it's a place where convers
Slither around like straight
CS sometimes I want to go to that place
and a lot of people
do and our government says we can't go
there and today 880,000 Americans who
wanted to go to that place and went
there are in jail in our
country now there are scenarios where I
think it's okay for our government to
say you can't go there but there better
be a good reason when my government says
I can't go somewhere and when it comes
to getting High I don't think there's a
good reason for our government to say
no I believe that the mature responsible
adult recreational use of marijuana is a
civil
liberty it is a civil liberty now it's a
drug it's a drug and I'm not promoting
it I acknowledge it's not healthy it can
be abused it can be addictive it's not
for kids and if you drive Intoxicated by
anything they should throw the book at
you yeah but that doesn't get in the way
from the principle that enjoying
marijuana is a civil liberty that's
something we need to communicate to our
society now our government is waging a
war against marijuana a Perpetual
NeverEnding losing expensive
demoralizing to our police force eroding
credibility to our teachers and parents
war on marijuana it's a war based on
lives it's a war that cost our society
billions of dollars every year and it's
a war that messes up hundreds of
thousands of American lives every year
this year alone 800,000 Americans were
arrested for enjoying marijuana they've
got a criminal record now now I bring a
European perspective to the discussion
I've spent a third of my life hanging
out in Europe with people who think
marijuana is about exciting as the can
of beer it's just not a big
deal now when you think about the
European approach to drug problems and
they've got drug problems just like
we've got drug problems they measure
their drug problems or the success of
their policies on drugs not by how many
people do you lock up but they measure
it based on a concept called harm
reduction this is a radical difference
between our and their approach to drug
abuse and drug problems in Europe they
want to take the crime out of the
equation and consider it a health
problem and an education Challenge and
my European friends tell me time and
time again that a society has to make a
choice tolerate alternative Lifestyles
or build more
prisons and then they always needle me
with that annoying little comment that
and in your country the United States of
America you lock up more people than
anybody else in the world wow we lock up
eight times as many people per capita as
Europeans do wow
either we're inherently more criminal or
there's something screwy about our laws
and most of those people in our jails
are in there on drug
charges now what shapes American policy
on
drugs fear fear is a huge thing in our
society and it's a big part of this War
on Drugs generations of Reaper Madness
propaganda and lies have been designed
to make people who have not paid very
careful attention to this issue simply
afraid of it there's a lot of Americans
who think there's a whole reservoir of
people who would just love to ruin their
lives with drug abuse if only it was
legal now in Portugal they
decriminalized they they legalized
consumption of all drugs 10 years ago
and you know what they learn more people
don't use drugs it's just no longer a
crime that's a pretty big Revelation a
lot of Americans think that marijuana is
a gateway drug a couple of toes and all
of a sudden you're a heroin at it well
in the Netherlands it's been 25 years
since they've arrested anybody for
smoken pot and they've got a track
record they care about it as much as we
do and they found that not many more
people smoke marijuana and not any more
people are into hard drugs and their
hard drug taking population is aging
it's a successful thing when you take
the crime out of the
marijuana now if marijuana is a gateway
drug it's only a gateway drug because
it's illegal because that means there's
Criminal on the street with a vested
interest in getting you into marijuana
so you can get into more profitable more
expensive and more addictive drugs the
only thing Gateway about marijuana is
its
illegality now the United States is out
of sync with the world and we need to
wake America up and tell them that there
is a harm reduction approach to drug
abuse that is more effective and
pragmatic than locking people up
Hempfest is a wonderful celebration of
cannabis culture but I'll tell you we're
never going to legalize things un unless
you guys mobilize this is a great party
it's a lot of fun but you got to go out
there and make it not scary and you got
to get the truth through to people in
the sub who are scared to death about
this all right it's not scary now we
need
to support advocacy groups with our
money so they can wage our battle for us
I'm a board member of normal there's a
lot of good groups for 10 years I've
been a board member of Norman and I'll
tell you those advocacy groups that are
fighting against the drug war or drug
war in our country are not Charities
they're services and they're fighting
your battle and they're waging a
courageous and dogged struggle in our
state house and in our national
government we need to support them we're
at a cross routs right now in our
society just like we were in the 1930s
when we were taking down theug the laws
against
alcohol and courageous people are
starting to speak out now and it's an
exciting opportunity mayor LaGuardia of
New York in the 1930s said that if a
society has a law on the books that it
does not intend to to enforce
consistently across the board the very
existence of that law corrodes law
enforcement and respect of the law in
general in a society that's a serious
problem we've got that today there's no
intentions of enforcing our marijuana
laws they're not going to lock up all of
us if they did that tomorrow Seattle
would be a much less interesting
City I'm a hardworking kid- raising
churchgoing taxpaying citizen of the
United States of America and if I work
all day and want to go home and enjoy a
joint that's my civil
liberty this is not hard on drugs it's
not soft on drugs I'm just trying to
inject a little bit of European common
sense and pragmatism we need to see
drugs as a health problem not a criminal
issue and then we can move Beyond hard
on drugs and soft on drugs we can be
smart on drugs all right thanks a lot
thanks for being here have fun and happy
travels even if you're just staying home
okay come f
wo wooo